more and future
so what is OS
in like 20 well it's been around for a
little while
now be four a map people were doing OS
fingerprinting already
by doing things like tell Maddie to the
host
and looking at what kinda OST mission
was coming back from the banners
so it's not like OS fingerprinting
started
a map mile there's also me in your work
on our sins which is
three things like looking up postings
you know
email questions by people who work in
certain places saying all you know I'm
having problem with my ass
boson what can I do in you look at where
they posted this palm
home that place is using so personal
things like that out
in northern peso
came out and did after fingerprinting
techniques
really were the first people that do
that in they did a really good job
because 2002 it took those techniques
and develop
further into and now along with more
after fingerprinting technique and
dollars
really good as well passive
finger-pointing is a little bit
different
ideas the same but its you started using
after solicitation responses were
looking up
passive so you're sitting in sniffing
traffic does coming from someone else
and you find a big ol
what they are based on what you see and
we have timing analysis
which is pretty clever I think and
there was a proof-of-concept school
that came are called ring and the
authors
well a white paper they didn't
police ring solos with a concert but it
was still very good idea
because they say okay well what happens
if someone sons of
a response to a simpler happier we send
and we'd drop
and how long does it take before they
send another one
in only two of it in how long to take
sole
then we measure the time in between the
packets and based on that information we
can figure all
what they are so I kinda have covered
the history a little bit on the last
slide
but here's just to clarify k so
came out for Syneron you know and map
developed technique further and added
some new techniques
in them passive loss finger-pointing and
dunno for our can follow light oh you
know what happens if we
use ICMP packets to after
fingerprinting to see what be respond to
i cnt
missional happen so that I was also
really good
in ring
so why do you even care about defeating
OS fingerprinting
how many people in here had Don hunt us
or vulnerability assessment the poor
okay so some people have arm
when you go and you do one of those
perhaps you cannot stop into not working
you say okay
arm or you could do it remotely the
pending
you say okay wall what I wanna find all
I wanna find out as much information
about that not work with the host
as possible so you sit there you sale
paywall
let me do the scan on their host see
what ports open what they are also
that what they are information is
really important because that's what
you're gonna use
to look at your Arsenal your sports and
decide what you gonna use
against them so us one of the most
important pieces I meet mission that you
can
yet about her target post 0 us now our
scanners
exploit armhole so worst behavior
you know what I mean by that is you know
where you have TCP implementation RFC
is size okay if you know you do
arson path you respond with us in our or
something in
it %uh supplies how you respond to
certain types a path
that's really important except that it
doesn't give
details about every single big so there
are
lhasa papillion combinations for example
arson been urged course that if thou was
sent to the remote host
you know the staff implementation
wouldn't necessarily know
what to do with it so that's a pop
in Seoul arm every single vendor
duster staff implementation different in
doubt
these honesty by the last
and in return you know about the solar
scanners being able to figure out what
they are
based on their behavior but I don't want
to like dole weighty
you know this is the vendors fault
because it's not necessarily entirely
under spot they do the best they can but
in reality
RFC 793 doesn't specify
if you get a in packet it snappy how are
you
you should respond to it so for example
Windows
just up in Paterson batteries but if
OpenBSD get something packet
it's a softer facet doesn't respond so
I think there may need to be some
tightening down on some
you know artsy not really entirely
vendors I so now we get to more
what is more wall I wanted more
to be a user Lampasas now allows a user
to select whether they want to be
right now the implementation allows you
to select whether you want to be
OpenBSD Windows 2000 you cancel our
planet's yeah
but I plan to implement now
Hurley you can use fall more on a Linux
machine you can't install on any other
OS
and I do plan on implementing insulation
more
OS's a lot more Ford do
is it will hand Pando like olive your
inbound
path dealers and bone himmler an
the penny know what type of packet is
it won't either stunned the packet onto
the carnal
and another call or send the packet
backhaul to outbound himmler
in them to the mojos or
it will reply to Rocky to the mojos from
the inbound hander
if the path is something like you know
Dustin foreclose
poor in are going to a lot more detail
about that later
and arm
another thing I wanted to mention as
morbid
definitely not production quality yes so
don't go take morphine install it on
your production server
and you know like to be about complaints
about
you know the production server because
it's not there yet
no I predict that it will be for
production servers
arm the idea
well i'd you know it's relatively stable
right now
but I really haven't tested it on a
production server so I don't want to
you know you doubt any impression that
it will work on their
as full time line I really don't know
it depends on how busy I am and you know
how much time I have to implement more
for more and I do have a lot of future
plans for
amorphous
BSD license which I thought was the best
way to do it
me and they can be downloaded at the
synapse labs
larger website and actually a sudden my
synopsis for the talk to
more 0.2 is being released by actually
onto
0.3 so there's an axe all
now more first built on packet pro the
Tory library how many people here
were after two o'clock talk okay
all good soul I have some people in your
who already know a packet Pretoria now
packed a purgatory for the benefit of
those who are in here
is some aptos carnival large between the
OS coming on a network interface
and it makes it really easy for me
use packet purgatory to build more fun
in fact it probably saved me about 4,000
liza cold which is
me now
happy purgatory is built on Liberty Cap
Dina
summer you know and so into ugly
more thought to use the yeah libertina
more
users Liberty Tap whose in a funny
interface and uses libertina
to light wat you gonna live happy and
also to
manipulate the route table file rules
under
about I'll Mon
from a high level architecture
standpoint I'm going to talk about those
some
in ninety going to more detail are more
implementation
you can see that there was a lil mo
holes sending
either a response so ask more
or you know home initiating a connection
to more
so when the response when the remote
host sends the packet
packet purgatory is acting as though
words
and intercepts that path & Sons a long
slow
more involve him and more for look at
their path here and say all
okay on either going to respond to
roughly path to the remote host
or census catheters you know I love
certain type was all go into more detail
later all lower
over to the call right now and help the
condo work on responding to it and wanna
karnal
response to it then ascends about how
and PR have to prove the Tory
again Laveen that path here the package
it's unto the more
outbound himmler in than heads back to
the remote host
and in the next diagram you can see
support felony a little more detail
more in you can see there are more pads
and inbound handler
a state table and up on him which those
three components together make up more
so now you to see more detail that when
the Mojo send the packet
and more gets a incise I'll pay wall
last
say those happy is Dustin foreclose port
well sensors
Dustin foreclose poor I don't really
need to send it through to know
post a loss 100 alt just respond to its
wrapping
on the involve him in sale pain while
inbound hand the rice a popular response
the penny on the OS that you want to
anyway
in that packet does bathroom all holes
now lost say that packet was destined
for
open port sold on morphine bomb hanan
looks at that and say hello hope this is
orson packet
assist us in for open pore I'm going
does
you know save Dowson session in the
state table so that I can keep track of
the suction
in I'm gonna pass their packet along to
the host alaskan all
which will respond to that package
however the underlying Connell
is going to respond to it stunned about
well I'll panhandle which is going to
look at the packet in say
I'm gonna rewrite the relevant parts
up the Hatters to a flock to us that we
want to emulate
and then stunned about helpful hopes now
pappy approached the Tory
some love you were at the top so you
know more than idea
but this is more information about pappa
purgatory
those who work avatar and like I
mentioned
arm nope at a private or uses lipke
Kappa libertina
to sniff on the Internet %uh snap on the
interface
in our also duvall table manipulation
file manipulation nada como model
yes the licensing can be downloaded sana
club's website so
nah I'm going to go into detail about
pappa pose a Tory
utilizing sleepy capital if Tina and see
how they are
baths more in terms apart seem old and
new path by law
so arm those who most up at oppose it or
users
there's a party mode and Luca I'll
anymore
we used a proxy mode when
we have a firewall on a host of not
supported by libertina
such as I'll Libby now supports you know
I P chains
Ikea yeah so if you're not using those
file
use the past another advantage for the
party mode
cell your file warsaw just yet so I'll
okay but if you're using a loop to I war
mode
it back to be your file laws the put out
of the picture
okay here it is in detail or proxy mode
we can see that will mojos assay with
mojo sons in a packet
and in alarm deal lipke caps sniffing
on the interface packet purgatory which
is labeled here in those thighs Emma's
party I P in party mode so via lipke cap
Sun
the path along to the inbound handler or
more and soul
more looks at that path in Las Olas
thoughts and foreclose
or so more says OK I'm just gonna
respond directly to the mojos
I'm gonna do a libertina lied he lied.
arm back to the remote host suppose
poor or if it's for an open port
then more for look at it and say okay
arm
I'm gonna do a blog I P light deal
libertina
in Thunder packet along to the host a
law school
which will respond to that happy an
Sun the papilla long in be on the peking
up slipping on the interface
on packet posse was stunned
happened to al bomb which will then
Revit the packet
2 o'clock I'm laid it all out into a law
I P like yielded
not send about moguls sold out in a more
detailed pictures
home or office Hanley the path novel
Lubell file mode
were using packet proxy law you know the
holes
a law school on getting now happen right
away so lamar host and the path yet
and you know now we have papillion
purgatory sitting there as so
by law an arm be a low key cap their
packages
Sun in bone handle more was looked at
the path in size okay are
I'm either going to do a two-hour
response to the Alamo
mojos like we saw on the last scenario
all we're gonna do a live the not lie
like and send it to the loopback
interface pay an arm
if that happens then the whole so last
final response to it
and sons it along BR
the pick-up slipping on your face and
arm
that path it goes I'll
and all palm takes their path it and
does a lot you do not lie
this time can't do a vide he lied
had done it with no bathroom loopback
interface in Nanaimo horse get a
response
okay
there are some OS skinner's there are
more for four right now
this case so and now at school to
I'm still working on doing a passive OS
fingerprinting
cooling Anderson timing analysis
not have an idea how I would implement
their others
just not implemented right now
I think this work clean up some of the
other two also had tried to follow us
scanners and have north on salsa sauce
bowl
for example their staff Pia which was
written
as they local control module minutes
which made it
not portable I didn't like that aspect
of the tour
impossible some all over body because I
Tyler compile stolid thankful
about now I P personality
I liked the fact that it could I'm
really certain alas
again as a patch for the Linux kernel
so that makes it not be reportable and
I really was looking for something that
would be portable
and be able to do owe us Malaysian
a sidebar hey you know highlight more
and that would do both those I'll be
what I want sold us why more
was you know created
alright
now all other current OS fingerprinting
techniques
I can't defeat with more after
finger-pointing
passive finger-pointing timing analysis
acne I think all the city
defeated more I know how I would do time
analysis assist not now
before we do this last through the
tunnel
okay so I have those holes here was just
going to be running more
arm for says Windows 2009
as OpenBSD unknown funders holes here
I'm gonna run and map against it you see
on the screen
I'll put I'm them
runny nose Windows 2000
beyond to meet the on here that okay
okay so I'm gonna do that maps can and
just to save some time I'm a pic 10 p.m.
por
one close for and our whole system 004
oh I saw now sameness Windows 2000
Windows XP
okay so now I'm a changed those houses
August so open BST
alright through the skin again
okay so we have OpenBSD arm
now what I'm gonna do is our last stop
on the morphs
in and do a scan on this house again so
you can see that the underlying OS is
Linux
alright sold us to underline hosts
elastin
that's what I've got so far
okay so now I'm going to going to a
little bit more detail about the
different OS
scanning tools and homework deals with
there's case so
which I started work because I thought
it was a surplus
school to start with and uses a after
finger pointing technique an ass you son
some Southern packets over to the target
host
all of which are Dustin open ports
pretty simple not too complicated
nah I do wanna mention that the OS been
good points on nom
case or outdated I don't think they're
really maintain your very much anymore
only up to the 21 porno okay soul
this is the table that I put together on
homework response okay so packets
so you can see on the left hand side
that you know
the case or packet types a nap column
in nine the Moore family status is on
the right side
end up his sister inbound state table
outbound soul some packets you know such
as
been that's an interesting taste because
a
and inbound hando gets up in packet
than a la cena says wall in Miami
elating windows or not has a
I am I better be sunny arista now I'm
not only thing when nose and Milan
Linate so
opened the st. then I don't respond at
all that path
first then I mention a couple times as
another case
we're more looks at the path in size is
this Dustin for nope importer
close port in a fist Dustin for open
port burn
morphs under a long slow O'Connell
withstand
walter et al %uh staged a session
in the state table so we know that will
use under sin Apple in the Sunda
APB out there were no other that was
part of this thing
in action asan be very important to
maintain the state arm
the other cases are really about
interesting the Sun plus
that sucks a plus why why why does
source flags that are
not really used very often like EC on
sold us
whatever the emulated alas want to
respond to that
now those explodes to which I really
likes working with because
well I'm looking at you know
I spoke to fingerprints and i'm looking
at a map fingerprint
soon you know I'm a up is very
exile about what it takes that's so if
you don't match
is sappy a signature than a stop in know
what you are
explode to use I just
ingenuity is about it dollars
turnover fuzzy fingerprint larger thing
where it gets back the response in Ercis
oh this is a pile a seventy-percent math
so
this is the highest probability doubted
the Sola
lives sidewall for sporty clobber you
notes platoon of RTOS fingerprinting
thing but he's really making it easier
for me
hold I'm certain you're going okay
I either have to be really it's after I
don't so not having to be really is
school exposed to you
is a after fingerprinting at me arms
scanner anderson's four different types
of ICMP
packets to the target host one of those
packets that a son
is a informational us path which I
thought the heck is that
sigh look to you know richest even TCP
IP o's
traded volume 1 I just loved up or an
wanna stay a sub that information will
cost packet is obsolete like wall
who is using obsolete packet that an
silo to at school to spin their plans
Michael no no no yeah
was to AIS us like no
know what that modernized no her you so
that was pretty funny other side okay so
that's why
over even bother to put that in there is
because they are
absolutely on there so you DP packet the
Sun
as well arm ICMP unreachable
not a big deal and the final path is a
analog regular sim Pat with we
had already dealt with peso
and here's the table explode to and you
can see here that there are for
information
ICMP informational packets la and the
UTPA Anderson
mall so these responses are very
interesting since the ICMP packets are
informational
I just heard arm the impound hander
respond directly
to the mojos when they get that type of
packet
no point in passing are you DP
us panel we look at whether the poor
susteren
open four hours close port destination
and respond accordingly in same goes for
the sin
I'm now
a chose to go with now on last because
as the most challenging for the reason
that I explained earlier
period there and I can't tell you how
frustrated I was with you know
looking out the case is over and over
again tonight ass over and over again
and getting
all these responses back from a map so
ya know who you are
like I'm only one option of people
well made all the difference
fun a male Sun nine different types a
packet to the target host
in for those packets or
for close ports in bible does for open
port so if you've ever run and mapping
you see
masses is like you know hosts a last
prediction is going to be lost be liable
that's probably because I couldn't
either find an open border
close work so in that case it can't go
on like happen this
tests cases which would definitely make
it a lot more on
a lot last be liable arm
a map uses the most us cases I love all
the ones that I lost their
and they can be kind of a challenge
sometimes I
how to run a lotta TCP down you know
at some racism not know what's going on
so here's the table for now
a map and you can see on the law open
port close poor
high path if that is sending most of
these cases
obviously all the clothes poor packets
are going to be responded to
by in bal directly arm
I don't think any of these cases really
that interesting simpson urged push on
our path with us like no flags
us there
now the more state table
I wanted to talk a little more detail
because I really haven't yet to mojos
will send a path and
must say you know Sun say happy Scott
sequin number some sort annual ass you
underline the Owasso
more random about generating 30 number
according to an email
then your I'm related the last two years
time
only Windows without in you underline
the OS is Linux or BSD
wall Linux and open the SEO a lot more
random
a policy numbers to Windows is so how do
we handle
and I think that's a very good example
to use for how the state table
news so when that happens
what arm outbound will do
lastly I initiated this ice under said
dual moguls so I'll pound notes about
papito now
inside I'll um the underlying hosts
generated you know
wall palmists going to generate a
sequence number but their sequence
number is going to be
define in randomness
and online host so I'm going to take the
of that up those two numbers
and stored out of Sir in the state table
what I wanna do that's because otherwise
to a mojo sis wanna look at the numbers
and a nap number data
just a on the end on the a national say
all the southern make any sense not no
very random or spear %um should
first-order
of such missed a table and remember that
information send the packet along to the
mojos with census in an hour
now in in the acknowledgement number
arm then I subtract the of stuff on
there
acknowledgement number be 4i send it
back to the poon also took on a wall the
often
use no sodas is situation with the state
tables really be
use advantage the sequence number thing
is
some stuff in the ER complicated issued
a
has to be handle so we have
other OS scanners there you know need to
be four
the water for more to be more complete
but school
one of those is the passive loss
finger-pointing
I figure it out in order to for doubt
mean there's really no mom captive
solicitation
by the passable ass finger pointing
toward so what I need to do is be
really good about things like sequence
number generation and making sure I'm
consistent with what I say I am in
as long as I'm doing stuff like that out
and also timing analysis
if I'm doing all those scenes corruptly
then are passable as fingerprinting
should be
now the packet timing analysis
re bass another issue that I'm going to
have to use the state table
for I'm going to have to know okay since
I'm
emulating miss all last in another
really talked about Halloween
works firings or Sun a simple app it in
then when I so no sir now
we'll take that happens too often so
after a set amount of time
according to what a loss I am all son
another one another Sina
because I'd don't think they ever got it
in there to opt out to
in this just keep doing now no calculate
the tiny
difference between those our subsequent
happier
in and figure out what unless you are
based on now
because you know I love you know a
thousand different so in that case what
I'm going to need to do is I'm going to
need
for survive no what I'm emulating and I
know what the expected time
deploys for happy retransmission what
I'm
emulate solo self-doubt this amount of
time
and ice una cena in
they drop it and I never hear anything
back so after
the somalia time my son another so now
according to what I want to emulate but
in the case of if about time passes
be 4i you know wanna send another packet
then I have to make your that is double
the original time that I was going to
meet
transmit Indus going to be useful to
have a state table
do there's a tool calls
nap time that I didn't really look at a
lot
but they sat on their site the what they
were doing was
since ring was proof of concept in North
number release
they're going to take the techniques
farming
that was discussed in the white paper in
there are going to add in some other
passive
OS finger pointing to meese and put
together snap times
so us one other tools that I want to
take a look at more
there was a talk at cancer loss earlier
this year
I think it was people and I don't know
how many people here
cancer class up
I you on those atop on new OS
fingerprinting techniques
so I think this guy works for Anna far
in
arm develop some new techniques for what
currently existing a lot of what he's
doing
is some absolutely expanding on timing
analysis
he'd also seen various creative ways for
example
no use layer 7 information two-time
analysis
for example hole Sun a TTP
yet happy over to the mojos
& the mojos cool on 18
spahn and um
no look at that no profit and then
after certain amount of time post
restraint
that path again and he'll take all those
timing differences
up this is still us because this is how
they deal with application lovell
restraint which apparently
different I'm them like regular TC
like so that's very interesting
and he expands on the timing analysis
sold out
stuttered just dropping a synapse Intel
relating how much time it takes for
another one held slop other types of her
and see how long it takes you know
respond again without one no also to
things like measure the window behavior
so you've got your you know your son
offer in Hill look at that no wholesale
peso you got your son buffer you're
standing me this information
while I'm just not you know going to
tell you that I've got this information
and you're gonna time send it again
in after a while I'll take the timing
differences between those in helping
colliculus
soul in yes she had like 37 testes
think about this a map at like nine soul
I think I'm going to be spending a lot
of time looking ahead to
cases see what I can do about that
okay so we set out there we talked about
all these
alas finger-pointing at me those
bad thing now implementation lucky you
really do
to avoid being fingerprinted while
like a subtle yours not really vendors
fault entirely there are really
legitimate gray areas
im staff implementation so
arm maybe what we need to do is have
another RFC
words to find more clearly is sappy what
kind of behavior we should I stop
under certain conditions so that
everyone can follow the same
specifications
now
another thing that you can do is if you
really paranoid
you can take your server in you can
make that a proxy in unlike you can have
your
high-value target behind in Seoul
your posse all those post behind so
if someone tied to stand on the number
figure out what they are
they only know what your party post is
but if you really paranoid
you can't do something like this store
more on your party holds and don't worry
about the high-value targets your party
obviously hardened them into all those
for additional security
things more for its just a layer by the
way is not going to
save you from everything and then
by doing there you know you can't just
avoid
having people think well us now
there are a lot of challenges defeating
horse finger-pointing
and I think it's important to share that
out first of all
if you're going to be advertising a
different window sizes and what you
underlying OS is supporting
very careful about that for example
Linux arm the window sizes no
5.7 K bytes when does a site 60/40
so if you tell somebody you underline OS
is Linux
and you're trying to emulate Windows
2000 you tell somebody
all my window size a 60-45 gonna push
back 6045 softie
you gonna go way my underlying OS is use
because not you know it's not ready
so are you gonna do and what I've done
is I'm going to last
save that information in the state table
by so they put me 64
he bites with a star in Icesave that
information
state table and then I pushed of that
information of the state able to the
online
alas at a rate batters comparable with
so does not we use now arm
I'm one into this all year but having
the distinguished between normal and
abnormal connections
using a state able to figure well all
well someone's a sudden you're so now
was that because I just sent them a sin
or did they just on your so now without
any solicitation fun
and I would use a state table
to figure that out read of the state
table and
if there's no arms internationals
reported the road I'll be like oh this
is a legitimate I'll just have these
are the inbound hander respond to upbeat
now even with all the challenges
even if I do more you know completely
equal roughly
in a works perfectly the problem is
if someone wants and now against me la
teleport I have opened and my underlying
OS is Windows 2000 and I'm sane i'm open
DSP and they stayed
know they see that I help 137 139 up I
also open
up in a war so this
OS been appointing arm defeating happy
isn't going to help against a
what it is useful for though is for the
casual
skin let's say somebody you know is
standing a large block
I P and just want to see what post out
there
are running Windows so that they can
target more
later so in that case they would do the
scan no sale
home wall these hosts a the window signs
a sin to focus on these
IP's in that case I would help you
but they're not looking for you as a
target to a
arm also
there are some automated attack like to
name the warm
they don't hear well OSU running no they
don't go and knock on every single door
end of up to morph isn't going to be a
little help now situation either
you underline your sins window what's
you know
name doesn't care what you say
alright there's a lot of work that I
have to do for more
still and one of those is that I'd like
to support more
and relational OS's for example would be
cool to be able to emulate
limits sole heiress all these other OS's
I am also it would be really great to be
able to get more
to install our windows because I figured
that most people would be using tools
like this to be
running Windows
now arm also the timing analysis and the
passive
OS fingerprinting tools would be really
nice to be able to afford
dole's as well I'll be working on a
now eventually
farther down the line when I have more
as a much better package
there's poly more that I wanna implement
and that's going to look more
into cooling applications not
necessarily
closing the ports for those application
messing around with them layer 7 mission
so that the application standard for no
necessarily what's funny and of course
everyone logically
on Sina put in Italy support more OB
pretty easy compared to the
the other stuff that
near some people will help me I'll I
really appreciate it
either by riding you know library that I
can bill more fun
or by you must live or
suggestions for the slides any questions
yeah
the question was why is it important
only other
operating systems is that it's just math
in your home
well you're kinda masking your own
operating system with more
I'll
I am
client like I mentioned a few other
casual attacker who's doing the Mastan
on a block of my pieces see how many
Windows
machines there are out there this is
where can really help
use more now if you do something like
you wanna tell them what you are at all
you want to give them any information
they might get curious in target morning
lolol wow this is a puzzle here
well I think most sought-after right now
focus on Windows
not OpenBSD so you
okay
while arm I think that if you're very
targeted
as you know someone already knows that
they wanna
to nor machine I don't they more can
help communities
so it doesn't even matter that they just
wanted to a poor CNN
no see what applications are running
because if they get to that point burn
I don't think more can help you
are more pricier does kinda another
layer of security that you can think
about using
as not not by any means
a solution the solution I had a lot of
fun working on this I think this is a
really fun research project well
I wanted to do something you know
contribute to the community
and I thought that this would be a legal
way to do it
able to
maybe emulate like other post arm
have you looked too honey D year okay it
seems like it's
a little similar life this is they arm
thus completely takes over your house
in honey D is hun over South up
many virtual machines on your host so
your house is still
Friedel apply as it wishes
far more fit the complete takeover holes
so yeah
to to understand it correctly that more
is only
responding to active probes it's not
scrubbing
like all traffic it's coming through
it's waiting to see annex program map
packet for scrubs traffic so you're
asking a far more Phys
a battle against at school
know is it scrubbing all traffic that at
Caesars only scrubbing traffic
when it sees and map pro x-pro
always stopping traffic
for every single pack it up comes into
their homes
it doesn't have to be relevant to our
scanner at all
okay yeah a completely takes over the
host in
arm more for comp we use
on according to what only OSU wanna be
are X so can be a regular traffic
happen an ass to you know what I shoulda
done mode is a
associates connection into this post
while more is one but that'll work too
such as one nation without work
because that means that you can still
too regular and options in
sup over there