my name's Fred I drew the Big Brother
posters I'm doing an adaptation
in comic book format for a George
Orwell's 1984
order
I'm I'm benign and I'm responsible for
the arm and so
should you can blame Pune Paul
your I well at least
responsible for thinking all each
and idealize and
propaganda artwork they see hotel
or don't I work in my day job life as
designer and I work for advertising
people
corporations so I'm
propagandists and many was laszlo
I write and produce and host a
nationally-syndicated radio feature
called a technophile what's on
eighty radio stations nationwide as well
as XM Satellite Radio
om and I've also worked in advertising
age to work in an ad agency
I'm creating propaganda and find it out
you now how it's created public data is
everywhere I others all the
the mass media is very clever former
propaganda
%uh which is unlike the state-controlled
media
the former soviet regimes but
produces time new means obtaining some
the same goals
so you won't see a lot of things in the
mass media that they're not forbidden to
say
million don't say some kinda
great conspiracy up just this kind of
agreement that there's an acceptable
realm of discourse
from which we do not fear so
as we're talking about some the examples
a propaganda over the course of the
panel
I think it's important to keep in mind
that the
the most effective propaganda is the
stuff that we're not
about because it's just everywhere in
hand
I mean these these like these great
banners that we have around there so
obvious and their silly
and they're fun up but the Bud Light ads
block the windows on the on the
mezzanine like people don't think twice
about them so
so that's began I just first fred is
going to talk about
his comic work the comic book idea came
after watching a lot of TV yes
and
a I was adjust amazed boat what was
going on in american television for
smaller
may have to mention that I'm from Canada
so
we get a lot of lot of French TV you get
a lot of international news
that I don't see in the United States I
was here last year in New York upstate
watched just before the war started no
people or
down the streets protesting and I was
with the client know we were just
in for the TV and all we're talking
about the whole night
was this guy who wrote a book on how to
be cool they would like showing this on
repeat
and there was this tiny little stream
under the TV
on said lotsa people protesting
New York City but they told the weather
several times
yeah might be was working so
and and yes oh
ninety-four's a book that hear about lot
in Canada
its mandatory reading some floss the
courses and C chip got there
so everywhere everyone around me had
already red
I just recently read it last year I was
amazed
but the similarities I saw in the book
compared to
what I seen TV when he seen the news
what I read on
newspapers and the Internet so I thought
in our
other people gotta read this you know
but I don't have the time to read it so
nobody has a time anymore is everybody
zones too busy
so I thought not heels to in comic book
form
notes easy it's quick and kids love it
eat
the markets so
well as some other process well first of
all I had to get some funding
don't pay the rent eat food and well
we're lucky in Canada galan
social programs and I applied for a
grant
and it was accepted so I can launch the
the project you know I've got like a
couple of months
good survival time to get a starting in
two
put it up get a couple of demos running
and try to find some magazines
and maybe a publisher Woodward wanna
take it up so if you know anybody
now I'm presently searching or publisher
is going to be in comic shops think
eventually I
I hope so definitely
you know where the the things about
propaganda
it like micro same the things you don't
hear a
had some amazingly frustrating times
with a gateway laptop
looks in the back three times over the
course two weeks and lost my temper on
the phone
numerous times and so I started to
talk about it on the air these short
technology news minutes that
are on the radio stations a talking
about how much gay wastes
sucks and I got a call from a radio
station
in Virginia that said dat to see you
know we're not airing the house
and as I can you know why people can
find them to be a little funny
because you know you us what you hear on
technology
technology journalism whatever's like
this is new cell phone and there's other
stuff that's really great and it's
expensive go by it
am so what so when I can go this is
ravished
and its its in quite annoying it and
they said you know gay we spent a lot on
my
spend some money advertising on the
stations sell anything that's not
not pro gateway we're not gonna run and
sy said you know whatever do what you
wanna do
awfully a few those people out there you
know would see me babbling about it
online
might website as well but its it's
things like that and
my when my good friends I'm is DJ for
the big rock station in Philly
om and I made he has me on the air like
every other day
I'm and I made some comment about
mumia and he ended it out and
he said there we've been told not to
say the word mumia on this radio station
and I said really and I mean this is a
rock station at the other place like
Metallica I'll cell I'd didn't think
those
a whole lot of for but you know really
socially aware folks listen to it anyway
but I am
sis commercial nonsense but he said that
the at CBS
had told the radio station to Billy
don't talk about me because when
the it you know if he actually does
get the death penalty in terms of you
know yet it does die
they think that bill is just gonna burn
down from the riots
and they don't want any part of it so
you can even talk about it
which is mindboggling to me
yes Pina censorship downstairs hit me
Ronald McDonald has been censored
yeah it was great couple
panic mode conference coordinators come
up to me in a day
and say we have to take your paintings
the front
said it's because millions like them
I know they're kinda cock now was that
the did the ROC government to condemn
the balkan take another one that I heard
complaints about
was the ass one which if any have you
seen said the top
squares right now it depicts an
astronaut
standing on planning planet Earth
holding upside-down flag
51 stars and apparently upside-down flag
is more upsetting then george bush Ron
MacDonald
makeup setting in France in Iraq flag
which is still up which is still up
well it's it's a it's in the lobby now
but that the one that was complaining
that
was the upside down black this is the
most
upsetting thing people in New York
walking the Huntsman
happening apparently the hotel was still
getting complaints
even after been taken down by people who
are so offended that I have ever been up
it i dont they were supposed to do about
this the site
get a time machine or something but to
so would like everyone not to mention
there ever was a poster with an upside
down flooded
you i think one other the big
transitions that that has happened
with propaganda is went
when I was as talk about this one time
accidents Italian
Walter Cronkite was on the highlights my
career is talking to him
cuz he's amazing I'm what
when propaganda in the news
really begin to appear in in in my mind
is when it be
moved from I something that every
station had to do
was their duty as a station to have news
and they lost money
the news departments lost money the
transition from losing money
in the news department to making money
in the news department means that you
must target messages to a certain
demographic
whether it's forty-plus wealthy
whether it's extremely conservative
whatever when you begin targeting news
that means you begin filtering news and
when you're filtering news
you're creating propaganda because
you're only showing one side to the
story that you think that your
demographic wants to hear
it's like I was in Oklahoma visiting
relatives
a month ago and I was at a party and of
course
you know bush and and carry came up
we started talking about it and there
was a lot of things that
that it was is in the discourse that I
was bringing up that they never heard of
and I said you people
have to be watching Fox News net not
unlike this and I was like because
you know you haven't heard any these
things and bring in after like now
am sell you know targeted targeted news
i think is one have
I don't know how we solve it i mean
because you know you can't really bash
commercialism too much
I'm by its it's to the point where
you know when news became entertainment
its it's over
difficult problem because it's really
kinda art
looking at people sheep him and
what you have to do is figure out how
many people are gonna be looking at
whatever it is you're producing
and try to figure out what they want to
hear
and so when you're counting heads and
said dealing with
you now these are people with human
emotions well I got five thousand people
in this demographic
500,000 people in this demographic
then you have the problem dealing with
people's numbers which
is unavoidable I mean obviously this
there's so many people that you have to
group
and what's worse or what's better
depending on where you're coming from is
that it works it's very effective
like demographics stereotypes
everywhere and their true but I think
you got the sense that you can market to
you
a demographic you can market to
stereotype but I think the government
has to lead the way
I mean if you look at the if you look at
the BBC in where the amazing news that
they can actually
covering this thing shockingly and I'm
the be look at the BBC me. I think a
mandate on news
and has to come from the government
and there there was a mandate in this
country
all radio stations have to air public
service broadcasting
tomorrow morning if you're conscious
turn on the radio at seven o'clock
every radio station is bearings their
public service programming on Sunday
morning
every radio station in america because
Sunday morning is the lowest grade
de parte because everybody's hungover
when the you know methadone clinic or
whatever and
am sales the church same thing
it so they so they have so they
that's where they bury it and I think
that its
it there's a solution to propaganda and
you know actually getting
real news in all the information out
there has to be dictated by the
government because
if the commercial landscape is left to
its own devices
you're gonna get segmented and targeted
messages
did job is not to to inform
its to sell commercials I'm other hand
in the a.m I love it that's an
interesting claim you made by so that
the
that the government is to be the
purveyor neutrality right
I think the government should get out
propaganda
out but I think that it's the people who
have to regulate the commercial space
and like like this manner and here we
are media
this yeah even media plant
it's all about us and we all have voices
and we are the opinions and
the more people who are out there saying
their own stuff in
producing their own media that's how
you're going to regulate the commercial
space
and the government this is you know it's
a small group out
media and put bigger group but if the
government says they're
that one company can on 1300 radio
stations I mean
that's a huge government doesn't belong
in propaganda
now the government has to regulate media
somehow
I think the peak the people have to
regulate the media and the government
I mean thats wat the original setup was
right we're gonna have three branches of
government that regulate themselves
and a fourth branch made above the
people and the press
regulate those three but there have to
be rules I mean if you have one company
that owns thirteen hundred radio
stations the antithesis
that is that the government sets rules
that one company can only on
eight stations the something thus the
assumption you're making is that we have
corporations that on radio stations
Tom this corporations are of course a
total legal fiction
and we can change that system without
making the government
do it for us we can create alternate
and we do and we'll talk about this
better tomorrow
on a ban on in the media we can create
alternate
medio without the government's
permission without corporations
permission
that's the whole point checks and
balances and
its its its very productive to think
that either the corporation's control
the media or the government does
when there's obviously other means also
a return to a previous
point that was made this is kinda
assumption that a lot of people make
that
neutrality is is good or even possible
up
I've yet to see a a neutral newspaper
think if one existed
very boring but it would be
certainly very long if you wanted to
cover all sides view
there's all there's more that resides if
you read a newspaper article there are
there's
the person speaking and if the person
speaking as from the government
there's the opposing viewpoint I don't
know how many issues there are other
where there's only two viewpoints but
you'll read exactly two
every newspaper article %uh so this
notion of neutrality tell both sides
the story I don't think it works I think
what I prefers people who are up front
with their biases
newspapers and your by and large
have have identifiable viewpoints
read the such-and-such paper its I'll
alright
whatever and people know about that it
can take that into account
doesn't mean of course lie but a
this this notion that we can mute wrong
we must be neutral on this
serving the objective truth there's many
objective truth
and choosing which one is I think
something that
people should be aware that people make
conscious decisions
I disagree it and well then
it while Bieber what's the solution
everybody has an agenda
course but the Jersey come up front with
your gender so at the beginning my
article I should say
I am I I really hate the MPAA
so but here's a story about it sure you
could do that haha that's called the
features and journalism
up but but you can tell the truth
without for 10
without lying race Fox News other thus
like
giant ugly banner which i think is far
more fans have any john's work
over there this is fair and balanced on
and maybe they're on now with if you
consider balance like the republicans
and the people even further
writer I'm sure they're fair balance mom
I don't know
well but to us they're not fair balance
but some people they are
its objectives it said
to
that many it's a fact good
alright who is fair and balanced and
right well democracy now's not fair and
balanced a lot of my friends worker
termites in how they're very nice people
and they will tell you they're neither
fair nor write as many
they're not balanced
I agree I think the responsibility for
having fair and balanced information out
there's
in the reader I think it's your
responsibility to read different
viewpoints to read
you know the media sources that you
agree with
and the ones that you don't agree with
well I'm yeah I think that's it
what are the greatest things that ever
happened to getting other viewpoints as
is the internet I was being interviewed
honest
radio station during the war which I
guess for still
during the war whatever I'm and they
said you know what are you
would even check it out online lately in
a city not actually been
looking at Al Jazeera and I like what
you look at that stuff for a sec
well look at his at as many opinions as
you can and try to discern your own
your own thought process from there
because if you take one book
are one magazine are one Bible or
whatever and say
this is the key to everything in life
i'd I
I think you're setting up your own
propaganda filters okay
I think we're we're gonna opening up to
the ensena many actors
raise your hand CNN that sorta like
crazy
you know deterministic nonsense
okay will you can you can walk around
out soon
do do some work to do yeah I think
places RI I am
open it up Arthur yeah
because others they're attempting the
film this and basically on
on the film it's going to be like of
that for not
you're wrong sir her okay
looks area
is that on on I said
1984 are the copyright laws
you got permission to translate into a
cartoon
the question at George Orwell's work
is public domain in Canada Russia and
Australia right now
but I read on the internet that they're
trying to buy it up in Australia
so you might have to wait a while to see
it here
to lakes smuggling
with the cubans rising with each other
microphone
yeah hi I just wanted to come back to
what level said about the government
the government's been hijacked by these
corporate interests so
agree that that you have to be rules but
it's not the people who is setting the
rules
you know freedom in the press is belongs
to those who own the press
right so way we can counteract that
is somehow register the 100 million
Americans who are registered to vote
and maybe bring the government back you
know so it does represent what people
want and
be it's more diverse city in may be set
some rules that way
I i mean i created they disagree with me
but i i think the government
fundamentally has to set up some kind of
game planning
grid know but who is the government the
corporate in 20 right way
in the great is freedom of the press
right and
the whole point is that you know that
different branches are supposed to
regulate each other
and the press is supposed to report on
all this and regulate the three branches
so
that which ex announces means is when
one guy goes outta whack
other guys gotta come in and say you're
going outta whack it's time to fix this
rate so if the government and the media
are all outta whack then it's the people
and the media's responsibility to say
well who you're outta whack let's fix
this I also want to mention that
early American history the
government-subsidized
the Postal Service so that people could
send
newspapers out free or at a very low
price
and there with thousand newspapers all
over the United States
with very strong biases you know lease
we had a big marketplace
these and so I think there is a point
here too
you know government having an influence
you but I think
the we have to the attention to who's
hijacked the government we gotta get it
back again
and now they just give discounts at the
J Crew catalog eat
well the Internet is very cheap
cheaper than ever forget about postage
so
there's maybe some bold on and get back
to you know be
if if you've been the previous
conferences until the office as governor
about being the media
mean blogs as dopey as they are
I love going to one other be blocking
web sites at this point up a random one
and reading it's like to get my haircut
today Brian
am but some other some other ones that
are well done are spreading
knowledge and I think lot of times
people are more apt
pop around on those and share ideas and
opinions than they are to sit read the
NYTimes
home page laszlo you are commenting
on the whether government should be
regulating the media and that stuff
I think that can be summarized by two
saying that democracy
is conducive to capitalism but in return
capitalism is not conducive to democracy
I and I think I might be
stealing that quote from someone else um
Mike you're talking about down how
in some countries like its obvious that
people who
people who consume left-leaning media
are aware that people consume
right-leaning media are aware that and
in this country
what I've noticed is people who consume
left way
left-leaning media are very much aware
that the people who consume
right-leaning media think that its
neutral
and you know I mean how many times can
you repeat fair and balanced before
people start believing it
and that's the thing is that people who
watch people who
watch box is the primary news source
they don't consider it to be
right-leaning
they honestly believe that its neutral
and that
i think is the dangerous part where two
people just look at it and said
yeah it's it's right-leaning but that's
what I watch then it would be less
dangerous
my to say that the wrong means like all
these people believe it om
no I certainly have my biases I think
fox's like I'm watchable
om but but you know
there's as many viewpoints and you can't
inherently rejects any of them as
invalid
it's alright as stupid as they are
shouldn't
the there the strategy is repetition is
true
repetitions as ruler have I heard that
is true repetition repetition is true
so wished and so it's
in and that's like that certain the
strategy behind
any propaganda campaign whether it's
fair and balanced or whether its
left-leaning or whatever so
if you hear anything repeated too many
times it's time to start asking
questions
you know any terms their propaganda
posters
when we were doing research for this
conference and I'm
actually the SOM people in attendance
that help worked on one other at his
other 20 anniversary t-shirt
that is partially in Russian one other
designers
that shirt is in this over there Jamie
official goodness but when looking
through all that
all that stuff and looking at propaganda
posters from from days all these
really interesting and there's a guy
name i think is names Micah right
that's doing now the propaganda
remix project any takes old workable
posters and makes them
Apple to today's events insists on them
downstairs
yes right and I was talking to him
and what's really bizarre about
propaganda is when you go so far out
that people del see it because it there
to some of us the so blatantly obvious
making
you know and an ironic statement but he
will
have people come to his pages and send
them emails that are amazing to
reconnect absolutely agree
like right on man you know shut up
Downey by the doesn't believe us just
move out to the country
and and and it's so funny when you throw
something out there that's
kinda ironic poking fun and is in them
you know
is a is propaganda an obvious propaganda
but but people sees on it because they
believe the same
isn't trying to make a point about the
about government regulation
media we actually live in society right
now where the media is regulated by the
government
and I think part of the debate is really
the people being able to inform that
debate right now
media regulation is all about major
media controlling
Mesa policy this that busy the rules of
the SEC
you know the free market the that
they've set up to regulate them so
the people us we need to be able to you
to inform that
and you know it degrades to get rid of
government intervention
media gather but that's not a reality
right now so relates shipping a bounce
away from the mass media and those
control it to you
the people being able to actually
control the
that remark that agenda so I believe
there's a site Free Press that net
that is really big on me activism and I
would have incurred people check that
out
a lot about us localism and going to
because he's very assisi meetings
happening around the country where
with Michael how as
his finally buckled under to pressure
from like this
be surrounded year yes happen last year
in a free press that net and also as far
as propaganda goes I have
stickers that are very reminiscent of
that was putting them up
with that you're not putting I'm not
actually I don't know if these are the
same ones you're talking about but I'm
give you these me and now I'm
these are the ones with your the state
but you're usually accomplished
this he's wearing one of those
Nazi military to lighting bolts
capped his golf cap this is his
he's getting Hitler mustache I'd what's
interesting you
what's interesting about and yes the
ferry I forgot what the
what it is but it's like effect
discussion goes on long enough
somebody's gonna be compared to Hitler
what your endochondral
right so and it's interesting that
you know move on .org which is a clear
agenda
I when they had a contest where people
put together short films
anti-bush that bush in 30 seconds thing
that a couple of people brought up the
hill you know product comparisons
Hitler but if you go to the Republican
National Convention sigh
and the bush reelection campaigns
they're comparing
gore and other people carry and
neck and the whole group to Hitler
interspersing video from different
democratic candidates
with hitler's army I hit me with him
both sides I
equipment this is the text field
grr I think your argument starts get
lost as soon as
you start making references because it's
just so
field riders when you bring up
reminded me actually an anecdote which
is only tangentially
related but I'll sell it anyway other
Republicans are coming to town
unfortunately
month or so I and I i thought oh this
kinda fun to cover this convention for
26 magazine
I am so I went to this kind media
walkthrough I got it or
and I store the hotel Pennsylvania
occurs if the republicans
an so I I filled out the form for press
credentials
and there's this office somewhere in the
senate
why building which is in charge of media
credentialing
for the democratic and Republican
convention and their
they have this kind of arbitrary power
to decide who's me and who isn't
and I was told that if you work for a
quarterly publication
then you are not media and please don't
come
hours so there's time like arbitrary
division
who's allowed in who isn't they never
heard of crisis
magazine are some things so they just
kinda like reject this based on some
silliness
the independent media center on the
other hand was on the blacklist
and was told to talk to the secret
service as soon as they showed up
so out arbiter it's it's you know
especially you so
I get two things relating to move on the
first having to do with this commercial
on which is website arm so initially yes
there were two commercials that were
submitted to the bush in 30 seconds
our contest on one's website that made
comparisons to
bush and Hitler or you know the Bush
administration in the Nazi regime
on neither those commercials were
produced by move on they were produced
by independent individuals were
submitting to the contest
the one at the commercials had at the
end in order to save the people that
move on time should the
must be selected the word sponsored by
move on da toward
the video that interspersed Hitler in
the
commercial on bush's website is actually
the footage from that commercial
submission to move on website and so
what they're trying to do is
show OC with these democrats say about
to see how you know they
make these absurd contentions that were
like the nazis but the problem is the
majority people and how many future
how many here no you know what happens
with this whole move on controversy
with this commercial you know these two
commercials actually originally
appearing on
I move on website very few people
actually know about that so when you
actually see the commercial
you're getting this impression that
they're making a comparison to the
democrats
%um between the democrats nazis like
anybody who is aware a bit like
understands that they're trying to
make this you know not make that
suggestion but at the same time
anybody who is aware which is the
majority of the public is getting that
impression from
and so they're doing precisely with the
criticized Democrats for
great you know I'm confused already
you've just told me I've already
forgotten the exact details of who did
what
which is exactly what they want right it
on the second thing is our regarding
media ownership on there was another
incident
relating to move on downward I'll the
winner of the bush in 30 seconds
commercial contest
whispers Heather commercial aired during
Super Bowl and CBS refused to hear the
commercial
at that the reason they said that they
wouldn't have the commercial was because
they didn't wanna do any type of
political
ads during the Super Bowl meets on the
iran commercials from the Office for
National Drug Control Policy
and also a commercial from Boeing if I
recall correctly
so there was clearly like an agenda set
for who they would allow on
at the same time there's also another
thing they stopped they ceased a
the presentation at the reagans
miniseries that made you ronald reagan
looked very evil
wanted of to Showtime at the same time
buy.com CBS's parent company
I had a 30 percent stake in the national
market
which was over the FCC limit for what's
permissible
to the FCC try to pump up the media
ownership limits forty-five percent
and then you know concerned citizens
freaked out contacted the congressman
the senator said no way
you know like there should be like media
ownership over 35 percent
hell even over 25 percent and so
congress lower the level
and then what happened was I after the
Super Bowl the Senate passed through
attach the writer to another bill an
increase on the captive
39 percent to that viacom was able to
keep
I you know their share the national
market a tale what's really interesting
about
media ownership and censorship is at
I don't know if anybody here listens to
howard stern but aiight
it with all the cheerleading that he did
for the Iraq War II
never thought we would be where we are
today and
is seen this East as soon as he started
getting clamp down on by the FCC
air he was went out anti-bush
in Clear Channel shut it down Clear
Channel had been defending Howard Stern
left and right
they're making amazing money I on the
markets that he said
an eight flipped 180 degrees
not howard stern of in those markets and
then just said
you know that he's offensive have it was
right after he started going to get bush
and so now we've got howard stern who is
I
complaint center for a decade well but
who's complaining he's complaining about
Clear Channel owning all the radio
stations and how he's getting censored
meanwhile his show is responsible for
taking
morning shows at their more morning
shows that have been fired nationwide
because they bring an issue now
took up a satellite dish in and and feed
him and
but I it's just such as such a bizarre
situation
that and and the republicans laughed it
off at first but I think
that they're starting to really see the
effect that that that howard stern could
actually throw this next election
because
let's talk about propaganda list which
show now in the morn it's not
it's like two percent you know lesbians
and ninety percent
screaming about the FCC censorship in
what's going on with his country it's
just bizarre yeah
it's a good point I mean if Howard Stern
is distracted from lesbians we have a
problem
right I want to make up on that
situation place in China much bars
you know they the government controls
everything
media control again Department
Andaman facing caught the Department
and ministry true
the people they are really don't have a
choice because like internet them
they blocked sites like that thought
call
watching times and the
they have TVs TV station like a
people watched like
BBC which is British what cast
cooperation and when BBC has some
reported on like this
dollars mission our satellite on that
channel holiday
and it's really really bad talk about I
radio
who sat on the radio over there you ppl
lit and we have friends went
when to China you with helping 25 set up
something like that and
jailed for three years US citizen
you know he's Chinese chinese-born
me with them for years
I'm either gonna start filtering text
messages to because they're afraid that
people are spreading
dissenting opinions by a technology has
been doing that all the time
you even if you can quit message this to
have a way to do it
so if you sent a text message to
somebody that says that the
to current parties Sox it that'll just
disappear to the either
it disappeared yeah well emails to and
website and proxy the clock block it
and you at like that though many are
network box in China and they have
surveillance system investing appears I
of
you F decryption the PS screen somehow
they can recognized
and this Salaam
good
yet sentences yourself vices
great not only to be selling prices
Coast Monday
now so what how do you a deal currently
live in China
icon on your okay I have friends and
in there and how do you get around the
propaganda how do you how do people
learn how with what the real deal is a
good they just not mine it's very hard
very hard because everything by garment
and
they unit they do you twist everything
in the US it's much you there because
we have a lot use losses like Jenny
whatever that's why I'm here to you to
talk about this
I know the people there left line
and every over here if you can help to
penetrate the Chinese
firewall year it big picture
IQ is dropping quit plugin for anybody
listening
can translate 1984 to Chinese I'd like
to make a couple
PDF so it's it's contact me 1984 coming
dot com
it was a great reminder that government
should
media regulation
I mean it's one thing to get your pain
taking out the front tell us anything
killed versace happen
let me what else can can can people do
do you think
terms if turning things around in China
doing is a trade sanctions is it what is
it
the they make okay and China
economy fast
I think
they don't have the concept with
the concept up
its like a when I was in college
I I read in a textbox from
text books like a yep talk
everything depends and all the time
and I was inspired by English textbooks
but island that I was like are in there
everything was calm you don't know
anything
same
today the its look the part look like
more all a steal the way the ed
people the way they controlled by mine
its
both I think that's the only place left
in the world
before Russian now
only world best deal has touchdown
it's really bad
well hopefully it'll turn around at some
point I think hong kong by
might be an issue that makes
change their now think on Kong's gonna
go down without a fight
that's so
thank you
lou
make well two questions really
this person is I wanted with we could
expand on the way propaganda as opposed
to censorship
so if I went to the message used to hear
what you have to say about propaganda
when I was
16 in high school my English teacher
she's gonna jim DeMint
here this thing was to try and educate
assess the definition a propaganda
and she said things like propaganda is
when they take a complicated issue make
it very simple black-and-white
comp propaganda in a they take it
complex social dynamic and turn it into
you know his name you know like turning
things into
any next thing or auspices damn thing
and propaganda is when they take
something
you know political and turn it into a
very personal
you know individual person Mike I that
the leaders in individual as opposed to
huge state apparatus or the the person
who perhaps represents you know like
some poor bosnian mother with the baby
in her arms and
no like to or on you know you know that
the marine having
it cut off is very very emotional and
it's very very individual
and you know obviously both sides doing
their propaganda
but its that's what propaganda is as
opposed to
units in ship not citizenship as well so
I wondered if you guys could expand on
that
you have any comments but house on I
think it's difficult accepted
discern what the difference between
propaganda censorship is a mean if
if if a new station is now reporting the
full truth about iraq
as they want to keep you know somebody
bedded away or whatever I mean is that
censorship urs a propaganda
listenership to cook the two sides
calling
kinda I mean property and is
course active part going out expressing
an opinion
course withholding opinions me people
can express their
opposing opinions is right to send when
I was
when I was taught propagandize
propaganda unit in my eighth grade
English class
and beaten what they taught us
which I'd later when I became fascinated
her in collagen
dropped out wasn't logical fallacies I
I guess my eighth-grade teacher kinda
mixed up but what
wat we covered in that you was things
like that ad hominem attack
strongman attack in basically these are
ways
approaching an argument the XOR
different methods techniques that you
can use
to direct people's attention year here
right let's talk about this let's start
this kind
argument and censorship is
wanted us so what you can do when you
want to spread your opinion
is say this is my opinion these guys are
liars
or these guys have a battered these guys
you know United so I think he's really
I think you know sometimes talk about
the good old days media and
and you know perhaps a little days there
were some rules upstand discourse that
you weren't really allowed to do the ad
hominem attack and %um you know
whereas nowadays it seems like anything
goes and I think that's interesting can
I get my pic can
yeah clippings or another time but it
can wait appoint om
if you if you when dancers in the movie
room last night you saw some
North Korean property and very it's very
silly
I mean there's like these people million
people marching through this
streets of Pyongyang to celebrate the
fiftieth anniversary
great dear leader whatever they do in
Kyle
and that one works here I because were
were more savvy up so I think
banana hours worked hard it would it
would
marge is it was just his other day it's
a totally absurd
but so it's or more savvy than that but
them
the the propaganda some our server then
that too I mean so they they come it was
tough but does work
and the goals and methods are largely
the same even if
it doesn't fit into like the three
simple rules for determining propaganda
the first which is
is no simple rules something we get the
next question is about Louis next
question is with
if I hear love people who is talking
about you know be the media and and
and i'd I do believe in you know the
internet as the way around all the
censorship the problem is
that you know it and I work within the
media with alternate media and the
problem is that
you can I don't think anybody in
in this room within for instance invest
money based on something they read that
someone had posted on the intermediate
so
because you don't have you don't have a
condo deception up the accuracy of that
whereas
I mean I don't know obviously it's all
relative but this whole post Mon kinda
believe that everything is relative but
there's no
workflow you know amongst the Internet
as a whole to
find a way whereby we can we can
evaluate whether someone's
just making shit up because people make
shit up all the time and you get these
rumors on the internet
and we never gonna be the media that
anybody's gonna trust into we can find a
way
and we have to say I think in a way to
make make it possible to discern
someone is making shit up from someone
who's a really hard-working reporter who
went
and interviewed the widow and you know
found out the spec conduct this up and
can be trusted so it so much
the New York Post make sure there's a
look I'm in the car with my cover the
other day with that
carry had selected someone else as vice
president again
you get with commercial media yeah if
you can have your propaganda filters up
with about anything online but I
me think where things up in the media
whether it's with the blog if you're on
the radio or
creating sound for video game whatever
you're doing is just throw some stuff
out there that makes people think
cuz that you can throw acid is a people
all day long but if you get one now
getting further had that they go
investigate
I they can go make up their own mind to
people needed makeup
trusted media sources who ask you to go
check their references
to answer the question directly yes I do
think it's possible to create
democratic structures accountability I
am
it you know the the the newspaper put 0
by the next independent media center
which I guess we'll talk more about
tomorrow
a you know there's editors and they
check fax and
there's people I trust to check fax I
but the you know it but do it without
the corporate structure and
you know doesn't mean after believe
everything you read
let's get to the next question smart
people the media talks a lot about
were the hearts and minds people
and i think thats that speaks a lot
about propaganda how much
disinformation again in other parts of
the world as well as
in our own country so me being a
technically minded person I get really
frustrated
bosko's have a meeting about how they're
too many meetings at our company
you men's I just want to get it done and
see
defect get fixed and on I get so
incredibly frustrated
with the way that our country works
which is why things like Jen's artwork
is so appealing
when I see it yes this is exactly what
I'm feeling
by 10 Jan as an artist how do you feel
when
other people on the street go by in
their their offended by it
they're not like no this is how I'm
feeling there they're like takedown
it %uh Jennifer briefly as electors were
just about all I make I think it's
hilarious
um a if you saw these paintings they say
on the top
this is not propaganda right I mean
irony is already here and when to me cuz
brian says
your sign of distress offends me the
irony
levels just kill him to the top so
I mean yes it's unfortunate that lets
people get to see it but I think it's
a sign of the times it's a sign that
exactly what I'm doing
is its typical if they didn't ask to
take it down then they would have been a
very good post exactly
exact awesome thanks everyone for coming
we're out of time
sorry I am here