start again tomorrow
at ten
and we do have some really fascinating
stuff signed up in the sea
session room
and uh... which probably even
no i'm not gonna try to grab my pad
otherwise normal one-dimensional does
work but we have are one thing right now
nothing at eleven o'clock at a bunch of
stuff scheduled for a more so be sure to
check out that schedule over the sea
area room
without further ado next talk is ten
years of practical anonymity here's once
asked
bystanders
a few of your heroes
blood to see the uh...
the late scheduling of the talked
instead skirt all of you
uh... i'm going to
here without slides
go over briefly
of the history of
anonymous
services deeply email services on the
internet last ten years
so if you have any questions at any
point please
stick your hand up and i a m ido my dear
option
and i will take the stalking whatever
correction we uh...
we feel it is to go
the starting point
edited on internet i'd
believe has to be the on dot
dot if i remember which
wasn't what we would consider
fully anonymous and isn't the first
mention of
anonymity
in the literature or
in the context of networks
is the first time that that a wide
internet audience had the opportunity to
experience something uh... remotely
equivalent to anonymous
email services on the net
pennant was
probably
accurately describe as any
sign-in server rather than avery mailer
users were able to register themselves
with this
mail service ag create an account
that was
something of the
equivalent one on one two three apt
anon dot uh... high
for the use of
the basic tools for step to retrieve
their mail
by setting up forty between the uh...
the kind of server and their actual
real address
uh... this
had one major flaw security standpoint
which is you've got to take out a base
of mappings of real addresses too
sydney's
on the server at that a base and that's
out
easily attainable through
packing attacks or
beaufort was legal attacks
cut subpoena records
that that is if one wants to avoid
britain the longest breaking in and
taking them which uh...
i have purple
people say that
during the time to penetrate
was an operation the early nineties
finally checked on it believe it
while parent was
gaining in popularity now member at the
time dependent with offer and we didn't
have petty things like uh... yahoomail
or hotmail hotmail
what sort of again talking ninety-five
so
uh... the idea of a
an email address that one could attain
that wasn't lead to severe
real name was
pretty far in there was
very little of away a free e-mail
services out there you
how do you get the using nice p
uh... or
you had to be going to a school where
you had
eagle account and i
internet login
as part of europe
that as being a student
the server
seventy-fifth is
and anonymous
mail service
only anonymous insofar as
your real name is attached to it but
when
we in the computer security
feel pop
applying something much stronger dot
the talks with vanity
is to find as
the state of being indistinguishable
within a group
within a certain set
other like individuals
if you are to be
truly anonymous
you are in player
in a group of
other actors that are
not significant view hand
vice versa
early
anonymity proposals
well before habit or before any of the
uh...
the real research into
the issues involved in the movie
shortly after
the discovery of publication of
the concept of public key
poverty
excel but i didn't get a chance camel
with
very simple method of
using public kika poverty
created a construct which
allow people to have
truly anonymous
medication
for cultural described in a moment
was a time to be resistance against
more tax than just
keeping your name sever from your
postings
having
idea of different threat models
knowing that you have
very threats depending on who you are
who you're hiding
yourself from uh...
leased it understand how
an important distinction here between
using panicked or using a uh... hotmail
throw a cap isn't like your name it
for instance you
have they concerned dept
there are
potential adversaries that are
monitoring
the flotilla list is on the internet
or watching internet traffic
idea that you are hiding your name by
using hotmail or by using
yahoo mail
does out the window
you dial account to be linked to you and
you're going to a website
an observer on the network
will be able to
determined that
bala hotmail dot com belongs to you live
in the evenings bob
we want to be that
uh... we also
want to avoid
a large creature tax which i'm going to
brush over because
nick map since going be talking in or a
bit more detail
about tax in particular on and the
systems
in addition to the the concept of a
global passive
attacker or
omniscient observer
just sits a monitors the
looking a traffic or living centers
with identities you can do member of
different
more active attacks which
allow you to determine
is behaving
similarly twisted name and then
when sent together
again i'm going to
let me put it because of that
the principal concern with
system what pennant
not even the the idea that there would
be
an observer
network traffic
you have this database uh...
real names
they're really addresses to s
scotus addresses
somebody could post
some controversial material
for the past email
around have
years later someone else
attain
the database
and records of
once built
you know address and correlate that back
to a previously so-called islands
posting
and burbulis identity
uh... this is a problem
this is a problem not only for the users
but also for the operators
certainly don't want your
don't be stupid have to give up power
the before
feature provided by the serbs see yet in
the video cell
knowing that this
potential existed
a group of
programmers in the the early nineties
artists like punks
started to
look at ways countering this and they
got up
uh... some
david charms works and said hey this
problem bought up before we can
we can do this
and implemented a
proximate renault what tom was going for
with number of
uh... serious shortcomings
refer to as the type one we don't work
for the second for milk
the way this works
interest the concept of change requests
rather that having one rebel which you
had trust i was not a problem with pat
it was
not only are you
yourself to the risk the picnic broken
into or
the records subpoenaed but you also
haptic here we trust that the operator
is honest doing sanctity
generally not something that
many people are going to be able to
put into their
so if u
want to avoid having to trust a third
party you can do that
number ways feed
the simplest way is to
assumed that you can trust anyone
third-party
but that you can use multiple third
parties and
make the
the best guess but they're not all going
to offering if they're all
individually untrustworthy
they're not as a group untrustworthy
of more four different retailers
and you've changed your message through
hopeful hops
then you have a iraq insurance that
you're not going to have to
worry about any one of them out at you
the whole of them all getting together
and agreed to break unanimity
now there's again the problem uh...
ball care for forwarding messages
through multiple
what's stopping one
reading the contents up
message and figuring out whose courtroom
where it's going to
that is a problem
due to the
prevalence of
the early introduction out
acceptable public policy
the internet
in the early nineties pgp
this problem was
roughly salt
that procedures support you take your
message
reidmiller uske
picturesque hitched to be
the final reidmiller
and then take that cricket
pgp message in trips
back to the second collapsed we met with
instructions sent for the on could be
plastic mylar
work backwards to the chain as long as
you
do you need to be
encrypt d
second alas lob tutsi insect
second block to the first remember me
mela scripted
message out to the pressure norwich
receives it and then works four through
the chain
stripping off the encryption
finding a new being cryptic message
which
that we know it cannot be
simply saying from this on to the second
miller
it does that
and so forth
comet last email or strips off the last
may production and defend literature
message
is that clear
any question with that
this is the solves the problem of
individual
re miller's looking at
message contact and charming whose
using watch
you who decided to whom
they can only tell
now the first a look and tell who's
doing sending blast millie tell who's
doing the receiving
and all the imagery retailers can't tell
anything except that there's nothing
with what we know we're going to another
and no one party knows both the sender
and the recipient
infrastructure is still in place today
because there's a anymore
addition to this which allows people to
receive messages
anonymously
give out exam
public key
actress mapping refer to supply plot
allows you to receive messages acting in
server address which then
forwards to your message
along with
this reply block which is actually a
nest of
instructions to other email alerts on
them
quickly over this
but the
this is important to mention because
uh... it has
one serious problem and it has a
major feature dick
people want to be able to receive mail
anonymously and not just send it
reno systems are not really
nearly as useful if you can only send
mail not mislead cannot receive
anonymously that's a major
feature deficit if you just only does
sending
uh... however
the way the type one system
designed
allowance for reply blocks for
return messages through the system
opens up
major security problem
index
are receiving messages coming back to
the network
multiple times
each time send it reply back with a
reply block
you are basically
setting yourself up to be
observed as uh...
it's rosa replaced
somebody observing the network ken
witness
replied lost with him or all times and
realize that hey this this message you
always get sent these emails after it
sent through
let's watch this and let's see
is there any pattern to whose receive
email whatever
message i sent the supply block
dispute times and your cable to
determine who's sending
there who's receive masters at a given
nim address
additionally because of the allowance
for this feature
the
type one system has no
built in
prevention methods
general replace
if you wanted to intercept a message
going through the network
and you have the ability to watch pieces
of the network can determine
that message is going to multiple times
you can then re inject that message
patent
observe it going to rig and i'm not
going to
too much detail here either because had
to leave
nick talk spot concept of replace packs
a major distinction between
the type one system in the
that had to system which will describe
in a moment
take-two
which is
the network that
a couple free miller suffer packages
mix master most notably
and reliable
implement
the typo insistent had no real standard
way of doing
uh... message reordering part ways
i'll get the padding in a minute
with uh...
who are you by the way
people would know about having their her
have to be off there
when you're dealing with the with
re mailers you
have the opportunity typically with
layer encryption to uh...
order number of attacks
if u
hotmail coming into remailed
you can we want that mail to go out of
three millimeter order bennett arrived
some whatsoever punks type one
implications do this others don't
there's no real shortens the somebody
watching the reno network and just track
messages going in and coming out in the
order they go through him
annalise
watching it backwash the ball back on
something you know
with the center is that the serbians
in the uh... anonymity literature others
multiple different approaches to doing
delays
method
that is
in use
most quietly is what's referred to as a
poor max
where you have that's just come in and
they landed bucket basically you've got
for tax year
messages coming to the network and when
they
you know to debug it fills up until
there is sufficient messages in that
packet that you start sending them out
date gets sent out in random order so
messes coming in are mixed with
autonomous just copy and and
than the ones that have delivered are
consequently leading intelligent working
their rights
happens every node in the network
and you have
good reordering h hop so
adversary that's what's network camps
simply cannot trace the uh... the
masters going through
mix master software beheading
a scene way of doing reordering whereas
cyberpunk systems at the records had no
we will bring it all and the
supporting winds
did something less secure
methods of doing reordering
petted being generous but
for some adversaries that works
sufficient
aspect is padding
with
pgp
do you have
couple problems
it's generally
can be assumed that as much as travel
for the networks are going to get smog
because removing layer concoction
and you have
consequently for removing envelope from
package you've got
smaller package
the way mix master
deals with this every packet it's the
same size
messages are
either patent altitude fixed size or
they are split into multiple chunks and
last one if it's not of the
normal sized pat about
you have each message ice excise and
as they travel through the network
padding is added in a way that is that
it's in trouble from the
blah
all packets joint network
are identical
they're all carpet garbage and they're
all up the same size
adversary camp watch individual message
and
assume that
dispatches coming in is that it's going
out based on the sides duction or
clever techniques that
politics cust next hour
there's no real way to get this with pgp
which is
white mix master with its own
fiction scheme
uh... there's also the cuts that packing
attacks which allow
an attacker to
manipulated the secretary stand such a
way that the message will still be
old possible
will have some
visible
alteration in the resulting plaintext as
a message travels through system
salvaged
flipping one bit on a uh...
dramatic before enters
i know it will result in you be able to
determine
which message that was as a leaks
that is very easy to do with the pgp
network still possible with an expansion
at work
don't reveal
the way peter message format it's
designed of course p_g_ was designed not
as a
a printed for reno networks but as uh...
estrogen
protocols so
these are attacks
against pgp it
for a use that it wasn't like that
it should be
i'm not poking pgp here
but uh... this is
a problem with trying to use
pgp is a general purpose
p_g_ which is general purpose a caption
call for a very specific application
there's
one major problem
nexus at work
most read models it is
it is perfectly secure
there are
it's hard to prove its that
are being made on it
biggest failure it's had is that it has
not replace the type one network
there are still plants and still really
felt that was operate the sacrament
network even though it is inherently
very insecure compare to
the effort somebody puts into using it
and that is there's no way to do
return messages next
because mcmaster has
awareness of the replay attacks and has
built in
protection mechanisms against the flat
tax
it has been a method to plot ox
so if you want to be able to use
and in server
based on a plot blocks like and and dot
earliest dot net system
mighty
you are stuck using
type one system
because of that there are still tightly
miller's exactly clients
and this is
overall a bad thing
funk network
was based on software that
a couple of hackers in the bay area for
together in a weekend as occurred
concept
this was back in ninety two
patent
it's still being used
nextlast has been around since late
ninety four
phased out type one system
because of the
parents asked the apply blocks for the
users
it hasn't
is still usable that what the sent
forward messages
that is a a small minority
compared to people that
use the type one system's reply blocks
and further compared to the people that
use keypad system
because of its ease of use
so
the goal in recent years has been to
build a system which is
at least a secure or more
that mix master
allows the utility of
return messages in some fashion
and achieve the greater ease of use
that's
the question was what's to prevent
encrypting or throw email address in
message to send out through mix master
and then
somebody else manually reply to that
there isn't anything rent that however
it's not all the medical
when a message comes out of the mister
network it comes out as
the i disagree mail are saying do not
reply abt we know that work
so
short you could put in your message hi
this is
deepthroat w_b_ to contact me send me
mail at this address or
i think nick that's used fairly
regularly is uh...
corresponding pgp key which has the
actresses
all autonomous dot messages
where uh...
its use that group and you bc accepted
messages
perfectly easement group and
ben canh
obtain email
in a somewhat anonymous fashion
however there's
this problem for the problems with that
that the first problem of just like a
hot no account by receiving mail at
again
you're going there from here
akki address of your
home computer or out the the proxy
server a proper to rip extended you
found or
your again not rich in security that you
could she do with the
picture we know
ed and somebody watching the network can
observed
your traffic for
uh... your email traffic
and different
simply by replying to the throwing all
address
your uh...
you are the owner of that email address
likewise the argues that solution is not
the greatest either uh...
it's more secure
in order to be truly anonymous you've
got to be hitting like everyone else
people that are
accountant it
in order for this to work
in a perfect world everyone would
download
the contents of
all thomas passages
everyday at the same time
and
they went cherry pick which
which passes they want to be would look
for particular rest easy to certainties
or certain subjects they which is crap
everything
and fold you grab everything
one person when standout as
looking for
they give a message
in actuality the way it's our work is if
you're expecting a message early
check-in
hopelessness if you're not expecting a
message
they're not going to check it or you're
going to look at it depicted subject
lines and not ever download anything
less
what you want is there
but you might think you're clever and i
want a whole bunch of other things at
the same time
an attacker who is
watching this behavior can
pretty quickly determine
when you're downloading when you're not
based on
when a certain
he has been positive
you've identified the debbie problem
there outside of not on the ability and
laziness
and
key problems anything that assumes
that the system is only anonymous visa
does the right thing
is broken
since have to behave
properly by default
there needs to be
one standard way of
operation
standard with operation everyone behaves
the same evan does the right thing to do
it a turtle offered to him
incorrectly
type to not having
phased out type one after
nearly a decade now
the problem
has become
blatantly obvious that we need to do
something about
getting rid of this type of type one
network and providing
eminently solutions which addressed
uh... address that the problems that's
type two addresses
preserving a minimum level of
functionality
that type one system had preferably
improving upon back
enter the type three network which is
currently one software
program called mcwethy in which is also
written by next
implementing a protocol which
i'm not going to go over into too deeply
as well from some pressed for time but
it has the
did as cheap scheming
goal which is to
provide a secure method of doing applies
so that there's no
there's no longer any
functionality requirement to keep type
one network alive
however anonymity in addition the
addresses a number of
problems that i can ever that
come into play would be stricken from
model than just somebody watching
messages on the on the network observing
tricking packets and so forth
nicholas still
rather important
mix of tax talk will
cover those more details please
keeping for mating are
usable clients
type one system has been around for
almost a river over a decade now so
there's
a number of different windows three
applications out there for them
uh... but in order for
picked reidtemple discuss polled room
will need to have
again usable
systems i'd like to see something far
more usable we have for type one
already perfectly
plug-ins for
there is no clients and so forth
that opens up
home of the layer of
adjustable poems
are moving toward
recognizing
in general in the privacy and security
world
recognizing that usability
itself is a security issue
users are
eight to daunted by pat
the prospect of using
an additional program to preserve the
privacy
though what not going to use it at that
point the program totally failed in its
mission it does not look once priced all
it's it's
never used
and then the second problem of people
using
programs incorrectly due to bad you are
designed
the ability to take shortcuts
is an existing problem
i'm going to
briefly cover some other
jump back of a key away from email for a
moment
and discuss
other anonymity systems
many of you are familiar with some of
that amana name some programs and if you
can raise your hand could hurt them
nike of which my with mailto engage one
of the more detail
have you heard a free net
you heard of freedom
zero knowledge freedom
yeah i knew about her
pure heads at
what about speed java anonymous proxy
actually numbers jap
felt the same
band
uh... cover
everything that
most of your hands went up for free
pets at since fina makes a lot of claims
either
utterly incorrect
i must get freed up for a moment
and move on to
zero dollars freedom system which is
wives it's no longer the networks want
an operation help source code is still
available
review since they travel soul wants to
start operating one um... once a
network level uh... encryption
and anonymity system which allowed you
to do premise the same sort of
nested encryption and fourteen through
mutual intrested
proxy
scheme as the
reno network only
when you're dealing with
network protocols are with us you have a
much
requirement for
low latency than you do with the e-mail
the fact that i knew using
anonymity system
right now and that therefore increases p
length of time a message
can get delivered via email
a day isn't necessarily a problem
if it takes you know extra half-hour
extra twenty four hours
i really don't care because my it's just
going through and i was cheating and in
the as a trade-off
that performance
albert i don't think any of us here
would be willing to wait
half an hour
or a day for our web pages left
or our pop three login
there are a whole new level of
requirements added too
dealing with a in network level
and in the system
based on the need to do it quickly
at this
has de facto either drastically
decreasing the amount of enmity that
you're going
to receive
vastly increasing the amount of users
you need an orange to achieve equivalent
activity
began in the de sakti is
the number of people
that are behaving
just like you you are
anonymous within that and except
with email it to be
every person who's sending within the
same rough time frame that you sent
a network level
and in the system gets everyone who's
browsing the web at the exact same time
you are
within
more again roughly the same time which
is that it being roughly by a few hours
either direction it's roughly by a few
seconds correction
so you need to have a constant stream of
users on all-time or the ones that are
on win
few others are on
have very little and
implicit problems with that should be
fairly obvious
this applies to get your router
system as well which
handles the approach to doing this on
apac level slightly differently but in
effect has the same sort of
limitations
based on
necessity to do things quickly
and
lack of users
zero three two system by
i've heard a couple numbers as to the
company uses they had the the most
frequently
spoken number is three thousand
that's thirty thousand
itself
so you can live let's be dinners and
assume that ten percent of their people
rely any given time
and let's assume that there are always
the same ten percent there on any given
time with each other
that's three dozen people you're hiding
undoubtedly discuss
in a few minutes out
you can google that number down
quite quickly by and number of
different methods
and
the update probably end up
about this room
now the number of people in this room
that you're having
as a very generous up
on a really good day
note about city is five hundred
twenty six we have
what forty people in here
you'd offer in on the stand
tripoli s
external
factors can be taken into place
suppose you're talking about
uh... your experiences with eddie
occult that wants to um... make sure you
don't spill their there
their secret killing the function uh...
recipes
and
tax people
in this
and amy said trimming the rumor
ab
happy practicing catholics
that's an external factor that
eliminates them from everybody sat that
the attacker could actually use
not based on
technology
often people
suggested welll
if you have any mails you know what what
i did all this trouble with the
you know enemy systems you can just use
pop three over
now they're saying pop three over
toward encounter
and send all your mail over these lower
level
minimizing that works and you
solve the problem injury to parade d
you know activity
the problem here is that you don't cheat
the same level anonymity in high latency
or in the low latency in a fast
then you can reasonably expect to
achieve they highlight system
which is why we are building these
harleen systems which is what we are
focusing on improving them
even though there's something its work
on the floor level
approaches
most people
that have a strict threat model
uh... too
protect their attended when the course
funding
via email
are more serious about what they're
needs protecting people that
are doing
casual web browsing yet don't want
web browsing information the
legitimate uses for thieves
one way to systems that don't by b
level of
anonymity as as a highly in system
began it all comes back to you
what individual users threat model is
who your attackers
what motivation they have
why they might be targeting you
who you're out
what the capabilities are
so if you have
if you could surges
simply
hiding your
present activity
disconnecting your present identity with
munications met publicly
conversing about
a lot of mailing list or usenet posts
and so forth
tightrope lawyer too
wink you discussion about
legalizing marijuana
you might think that using hotmail would
be sufficient anand anyway that could be
however
if expressing anything that
is now or potentially could become in
the future
illegal
prospect of in trusting your
future
safety to be
presumably inherent anonymity of hotmail
is dubious
there are logs there are
i could just correlations
between accounts
and uh...
your messages could be traced back to
you
threat model is only incorporating
future attackers that are looking at the
output
of your messages
a post to mailing list
and not monitoring the network not
monitoring
you actively understanding
you have a much less the skit attacker
you otherwise might
a system like the type one system
totally sufficient for you
there's no tweaking back
your real email address to debate not
restricting
as panipat
and there's uh...
there is future liability
you've sent your mail for that
it's been delivered
andy norm was looking when this happened
you've got what you want to keep that
anonymous posting went back to you
after the fact
you're hiding you're you know this is
not being posted
and at the
equilibrium message
however there are toxic and
again prep model if you are
potential attacker
your adversary
is someone who is
capable of watching
the network when you send your messages
or is expected to be watching what
you're sending messages
then there are toxic come into play
that ten
allow him to determine
however if your
merely concerned about someone in the
future
looking at
mailing list archive and
messages back
after the fact
type one is really no worse off than
anything else out there
does strip layout that you know headers
it does high trivial
email address
doesn't give you the same level shirts
that
you might want if your attacker is
someone like
like at the outset
presumably able to watch
blessed trapped in real time and
analyzed
getting close to five years thought
south texas questions
west actually allow you to remain
anonymous using
using the cases it now what do you think
that you are using the question was
regarding uh...
what happens if you are
cooking this for the state
what happens if you're in a scenario
where u
not only have to hide
your identity
but need to have the facts to using
and anonymity system as-is referred to
as they come out of him
the enemy systems that i've described
that we're talking about here don't
provide this this is a separate
security access
right now if you're in a situation where
even using in any any kind of
privacy software is going to get into
trouble
there's really nothing you can do about
it
uh... there are number of projects that
attempts to
allow copper kettle creek ation but
nothing is
practical at this point
the only thing that you can
really help for is uh...
again blend in with a large crowd and
only four
chinese dissident using
hotmail is
lengthen the can stand out
hoosier attacker what is your threat
model
urinated
jurisdiction of repressive government
who is
comfortable with
eight ross
conviction that
anonymous poster belongs to this real
like identity
and doesn't need a hundred percent proof
you're in a lot parcel position then if
you are
irrefutable proof and the court
for lawsuit
they're willing to round up some specs
and put them in jail for unsanitary time
because they are
quite likely the person that looking for
but not
necessarily
and and make them so they're going to do
that
expertly bad idea to make yourself
suspect
expedited to use these systems are all
however nevertheless sort because if
people are afraid to use in a distance
and no one will then you have a small
anonymity sat found
you don't
blended with anyway if you decide to use
it
i've perceived the course in courage
people to use the energy systems that
are out there buch
i think we end up
talking about the necessity of
armed revolution when where
dealing with garments that are that
oppressive
which is entirely separate talked and i
will
stop off on it tonight
in the uh... you mentioned freenet
system
that said
uh... and
the will
the biggest problem with free at isn't
isn't even
from its apparently architecture but
defect at the protocol has changed
many times over the past few years
date there's
i don't want that this could
i could have an entire talk on problems
in free net i don't want that become
what this is
my reason for mentioning it was that
the the
strong in the system's that are out
there
tend to be very cautious claims
because the more you learn about it and
get the harder you realize it is to
achieve it
more casual
anonymous
vacation systems that
haven't rigorously evaluate their
anonymity
are more willing to make
ball claims about what their systems can
do
because they haven't realized exactly
what
what the limitations are
so what i mention
and to be systems that admission free
not and most of your hands go up
it is just an indication of
marketing the women you know over
practicality
personally successful anonymity proxies
commercially successful in the muddy
proxies
well there are number of
i'm natural successful but number of
a number of commercial anonymity systems
out there which are all
which all basically with exception of
zero knowledge freedom which is
sadly dead due to
practicality issues
the overhead cost of running a
mclean c network level system when all
users one it down looking keep pouring
ault same time becomes astronomical and
if you're charging thirty dollars a year
you can't afford to do it so they shut
down
with exception of
zeke ass all the commercial anonymity
providers out there are trusted single
hop proxies
so damn i get back to the problems
with pat you have
and you have to trust the provider
you have to believe that it's not only
are they honest ingane
that they're going to be hiding your
again before you
but they also have to
not happen or compromise
haven't been broken into and
had some
had your adversary backdoor their system
without their knowledge
so you can literally on a single proxy
that's split worthless to you because
it's been owned by the people you're
trying to hide from
then of course there's legal tax which i
mentioned beginning as well
which or
door number of the commercial additive
waters take steps to
be able to avoid
in that day
orgy walesa subpoenas because they need
to go through
extra measures to
hide the identity of their users from
themselves
uh... again all the squeezed onto a
matter of trust if
it using your threat model that you can
trust a third party with your identity
you could use them but you're probably
better off using
three systems
and not paying for them
at this point to do your your
probly better off using tor
denon rubber
something else on this one from
entrusting this third party
that that that go where you want to go
i think you uh... already answers but i
ask you what is your
prefer system
if all you're concerned about gays
i could say my old enemy opera house in
the web here
not worried about anyone significant
city adversary ted
we cracked packets but you just don't
want all information before now we don't
want your traffic necessarily vehicles
bc we're gone
well if if u threat model was greater in
east orange crop web browse the web i'd
say you're out of luck
it's good that you're only mildly
concerned and you want to
browse the web
so you can look at
because it or which
in its current state does not have a
large number of users
so you to keep in mind that you're in
the senate is extremely small
particularly given adversary watching
you and realtime rather than somebody
who is
simply watching on the ends if or you're
really worried about is hiding
your identity from the websites you're
going to
you get away with a lot more
then if you are
or not hiding yourself from you know i
espy or from
your
employer or from the government
your your committee proaches are to use
denny rudder system
or to use a commercial anonymity
provider
have any of you heard of any commercial
and flutters answer
one hand
prox if i
i've not even heard of proxy fight
do they make money
graduations of them
no one else has heard of any commercial
interests
that's a surprising
other questions
uh... have you heard about
proxy changed and what do you think
about
what's it changes the um... way of doing
inline
you open up one open proxy connected at
the proxy
changed maybe
for five proxies
you kicked back to
decide
okay unchanged source port
again this is uh...
depending on his threat
what the fellow it's either
p cheap way of hiding here
happy from a website you're going to are
completely useless
because
if there's no way of encryption no
remix ingo users
somebody washing their purchased
sees we are going to doesn't matter
which one to five hops
under their hand if
you are trying to hide yourself from
from a uh...
uh... website
sure you do that but i'm not certain
what you'd want to do it through five
different dropped in just one because
any one of those five ten
see where you're going to and who you
are and
reveal your identity
uh... in fact it would be better gifts
pick one that you trust rather than five
but you all have to trust
and a chain system with no encryption
it's not
you're not making the bet that
at least one of the
ones you picked will high trade and that
you make of that all of them will
hydrate entity
this turns out
somewhat counter-intuitive to realize
that using more is worse in that case
but
turns out that if you're using
fiber that you have
five times jets that one of them will
reveal your identity
they didn't the problems any one of
these parties could look at the met
trafficker passing through and
figure out what your final destination
is
whereas within the
with all the other systems you have
player decryption
while one proxy might be bad
and i can look at uh... the
you know if it's the first topic and see
who is sending
or its last topic and see where those
bitches are going to do
it doesn't see both at once it sees
who is sending and
disinfected blob
that he knows to pass on to this next
top
it doesn't see
what the compact law barred which
include the final message amt
material that uh... writing material in
there that determines where it's going
to be peter neil addresses an email
message or a final website request
commute home
when the status of expanding
mister
the old man
uh... idly bike and and you can drop in
creek pieces because the developer
next alien is
in
deployed data right now
crack or
it's easy
it's nato trust this pretty thing really
serious at this point because we're
still testing it and the protocol is not
one hundred-percent solid yet
but everyone should download and play
with report bugs stage
um...
uh...
uh... p_p_i_ is likely to change
under their hemdie command-line
interface is pretty solid
although we'd need for the a_p_ i to get
stable would be for
someone should come up with nice clean
interface
israel in python right now so if you
need it
be written in c then
um...
you need to do your own
intimidation there's a four x see that
you could look out
monarchy dirt is a speck on an artsy
level of detail
that you could you look at sdi
compatible implications
one of the mix master developers tried
over the course of a couple weeks jude
you a compatible java library and he got
to send messages so it's not hard for
the call to clone
notes right now
and speaking of cloning we're problem
we also that mix master four point oh is
slated to speak type three particle
so it will operate with next again
the uh... the idea is to have
seem like a religion external cell which
can then be used
in other programs ads
ailing coble library on cross-platform
basis so that
hopefully people could be encouraged to
write like it's fort mill clients and so
forth
that would speak type three
how many elf beta notes do you have
right now
affirmatively aftermath of the word
health data
for the currently active reno network
cartoon network a mix master network
there's uh... felt fifty active notes
and health forty of those at any given
time our
functioning properly
all typed on exp
did rectitude
or at the
edge
what let's put it
okay so that was a day for a week
high-level brief
intro to the the
past ten years of history of
low in cedar eileen c_n_n_ recessed in
the email
and then we touched briefly on the the
lower latency
less secure
more usable for
general purpose applications like web
browsing and in the systems
and
i guess i would reduce
pick matheson here who is
going to be talking about attacks on
the various additives
yeah might help yes your questions
thirty nine
and