Benicio arm first things first
on I've been doing photography for a
number years this is a sort
side project that I stumbled on on when
talking to somebody
I at black hat was giving talks on
covert channels
so I mention s and people were
interested in it so I wrote some code
and hear it
I it's very very interesting hopefully
I'll get something from it
I try to make my talks as technical as
possible
are so that you can actually get
something from it I also
I am also used to giving talks
in academic settings so basically what
this means is if you have no idea what
I'm talking about
raise your hand and be like hey over
here I don't know what you're talking
about can you explain this
arm so if you have a question feel free
to raise your hand and get my attention
and I'll try to explain things better so
get up again are there gonna be are two
main parts:
and answering questions the first part
is
an explanation %uh digital signatures
obviously what they are what they do
arm in a cover to specific types digital
signatures
el-gamal signatures and then D'Sa or
digital signature algorithm
very creative name signatures them in a
look at the subliminal channels
are these channels at are able to recall
isn't nice information to people
I'll give an overview tell you what they
are how they work
I'll explain the subliminal channel in
the essay
and then I'll show you some fun things
that you can
do with the subliminal channel that some
people might be very concerned about
and then at the end arm
I'm not just talking out my ass here I
have a program that will do this all
and actually show you just how dangerous
this can be
on now this summary and take questions
so starting of digital signatures
arm what our digital signatures
basically their numbers anything
digitally can be represented as a number
I'm when people think of signatures they
think of something that's hand-written
usually
with a digital signature it's just a
number
it's attached to some sort of message
it's bound to the message in some way
and it's created by the
person who's doing the signing in such a
way that hopefully nobody else can forge
it
hi there used implemented
with public key cryptography so anybody
who wants to make digital signatures
will have a key pair public key in a
private key
use the private key to make the
signature and then the public key
think about everybody else and its use
to verify
whether a signature is correct or not so
what do they do basically digital
signatures try to recreate
all the functionality that handwritten
signatures
if you all the things that signatures
were created for an active were used for
I wanted the things that they are trying
to do is
authenticate so if somebody signed a
document
you can's look at the signature and
hopefully how whether this is
actually their signature not it binds
some sort prove I was here
to a document for a specific person in
this case
signatures also handle verification of
the data integrity
usually you'll sign a contract when it's
all done a sign a document when it's all
done
and you put your signature at the bottom
after you've looked it over and made
sure everything is cool
arm and then if any changes are made to
the document hopes way
you'll be able to tell that they were
made after the signature handwritten
signatures on terribly good at this
digital signatures are if you put a
digital signature
on a message and the message is changed
in any way
the verification in the signature will
fail so the signature
is bound to a particular message
document
the last thing that last primary thing
that digital signatures
do arm is given on creation basically if
you sign something
and then later you try to be a scumbag
and say oh I never saw that
then it's your signature you put it
there
and in this case not only does it prove
that its you to somebody else
it proves that it's you to anybody who
says hey you really were here if you're
trying to back out
so let's look at the first-ever
signatures el-gamal
digital signatures I'll bring this up
because
el-gamal is the algorithm
that TSA is based on a number of
similarities between the two
I'll demain can be used for both
encryption and for digital signatures
by in practice the digital signatures on
use because I'm number
I love flaws and the other than that
make it not optimal
the essays a variant I love all the mall
and
the subliminal channels that R&D essay
they also exist in El Gamal signatures
but they're not as strong
I it's hard to send messages through
them and you can send all
possible messages through them and
sometimes if you send a message
you won't be able to recover it on the
other end so it's not as good for this
purpose
or as bad for this purpose is the case
may be
here we get into the technical stuff how
you generate a key pair
arm who is familiar with public key
cryptography at all
excellent excellent okay so it's a
discrete logarithm problem
based algorithm are basically the
premise
I love anything that is GOP based
is that when you're working over a
finite field
numbers its easy to do exponentiation
so if you're doing modular design may
not know models is
where you dividing you take the
remainder I'm so he do exponentiation
and then take a modular us basically
you're chopping off a bit of information
that you can't get back
so to do exponentiation it easy you do
the exponentiation first
and then you chop it off and reduce it
and you have your answer
but to do to take a logarithm
to do the reverse exponentiation
it's really difficult because you've
lost this information to begin with
and you can just go backwards have to
come up with some way off
taking guesses until you figure out what
the right answers
so going forward is easy going back is
hard
and that's the basic premise the GOP
based algorithms
when you have a public key you're doing
the exponentiation
when you got the private key you're
trying to use secret that you know
to go backwards and circumvent that's
the simple
explanation so this is a general the
keys
anybody has questions can find you later
I'm not gonna get too much into
detail here signatures
arm the basic
way to explain this is that your putting
I to values are an ass your computing
them
in such a way that there's a secret that
only the signer knows
in this case is this value K you pick a
value K
you do some math you get these two
values are an ass out
and because it's based on your private
parameters this math the person who made
the signature can go
forwards and basically use the random
variable to wind
a variable in there so you can't do math
your winding it by putting another
variable into the mix that only you have
and they don't everybody sort of
understand that
yeah okay so you pick your Anabelle UK
use it to buy in the process and you get
are an ass out
as your signature to do the verification
then you do a basic check to make sure
that the value is sane
if it's not thrown out otherwise use the
public key to
go backwards and just check whether the
signature is about
about at the signatures valid then
it's good if it's not then any number of
things may have happened
maybe it wasn't created by the right key
maybe the message was changed
you can tell just by knowing that the
signatures in Ballard
bite somewhere along the line something
so digital signature standard
I contains definition of the digital
signature algorithm
again very creative names here by the
United States government
are managed based on these alqamar
signatures
I is defined as part no DSS and
the federal information processing
standard
on number one 86 I it was originally
made in ninety four it's been updated
twice
once in ninety eight months in 2000 I
basically they've added
extra algorithms and made a few changes
and
tried to keep it is current as possible
for people to be
using it actively and adopting the
technology and spreading
all this is public information it was
all put up for public
peer review there are a lot of
discussions about it
all the details in the system are open
so there's nothing being in here
so the essay very similar generate key
pairs
make a public and private key the
related to each other
and again I won't go into too much
detail here
but if you're wondering the math there
it is
by TSA your keys will be anywhere from
512 to 1024 bits
that's why that whole T value is in
there it scales up
your key and multiples 64-bit
so it has to be one of these sizes this
is actually a problem
with this particular algorithm because a
lot of people are starting to wonder if
1024 bits is enough these days
and TSA cannot go over 10 orbits
everything else is very similar to the
mall and you end up
with a public key which has a
large prime P and a smaller
1q a generator
alpha and the public itself why
and then a private key which is just one
value which is axe
but in practice whenever you have a
private key
II being you still have all the public
key parameters
included with the private key suck you
got the private key voss about access to
the public key obviously
when you wanna make a signature again
you got this random K that you pick
and it's a lot simpler than all the mall
munis compute
these values are an ass again
and in the %uh the mall case you have to
take the hash
a message when you put a digital
signature on message
general you're not putting it on the
entire message you take
hash one-way hash %uh message
first and what that is is a one-way
function
hopefully that will go from an
arbitrarily sized
message to while a smaller text size
but large enough that it's hard to find
out
two messages that will hash to the same
value I generally hashes are like 128
160 256 bits so trying to find a
collision in that space is still really
difficult because
to the 128 is a really big number by
you're dealing with 128 bits as opposed
to you know
megabytes gigabytes however much data
you you have
so you affectively making one-way
compression
your message using a hash function and
then you sign
the hash young actually sign actual
message and hashes are made so that
hopefully you can find two messages that
has to the same thing
on anti essays case there's a very
specific
cash you have to use Shaw 1 again it's
not the United States
standard again it's opened again it's
been for peer review
it's fairly commonly used and it's been
out there for allow
so everybody thinks it's pretty good so
you have message am and you get a
signature Rs
to verify the signature again you to
basics any checking first make sure that
numbers are okay
and then you compute these two values
and then crunch out something else
compared to the signature and if your
basic number crunching using the public
key works out
then message is good
if it's not again you can tell whether
is made with a bad key or
was changed you just know that something
is wrong it's not good
don't don't trust
some thats digital signatures now look
at
actual subliminal channels bet you're
wondering what they are this point
ask
yeah yes on
inverse is are multiplicative inverse so
the inverse asses one over ass on
thats it but it's also a matter notation
because you're working with integers
over a finite group here you can
actually just
do division as you would normally think
about it because I'll give unionized
number whatever there's actually an
inverse
define for any possible number system
where
ass times s inverse Eagles won
however you want to find multiplication
inverse is based on that
are
on he was asking if there was a way to
make
TSA larger based on its restrictions I
don't think
there is but I think by the way that the
algorithm is defined I think there there
are few things that you would have to
change
in order to scale it effectively I'm
pretty sure can be scaled
but by the way this standard is in place
you're not allowed to scale
and as a result everybody's using this
algorithm that is
week or not it's now week but it's not
as weak as
it's not as strong as it could be sorry
why can't you shall 1
okay excellent thank you
gap arm okay thank you
arm there there's the bottleneck I shall
inspect 260 bets
arm which is the size of Q arm so if you
want to expand
you'd have to use different hash that
would allow to be bigger now arm
key activity use a different hash then
you can expand it thanks to somebody in
the audience pointing out something that
for not
on if you use a different ash they can
get larger
then shot one which is fixed at 160 beds
then you can scale
TSA but the standard itself tss
cannot scale because it requires shot
one much what
I yeah but it's not sell
yes
all rights among all channels
so you're wondering what it is at this
point and basically it's a way of
embedding information
in some sort of public communication in
a way that's not detectable
unless you know what you're looking for
unless you have some sort of secret
that you know is there you're not gonna
find information on steganography is
one form I'll a covert or
you can call the subliminal channel it's
very similar
okay if you have a question you want to
run up and use my
can do that too home so it's it's a
modest economic free in that you're
putting information in a public
channel by you're hoping that only the
person on the other end
knows what it is and in steganography is
case it's basically how to look for it
with a someone on channel in the essay
another trick to it there are two types
possible channels and digital signatures
broadband and narrowband
I basically when you look at the amount
bits you have in a digital signature you
can
make a nice information-theoretic
estimate how many
bits are being used to actually do the
duties of a digital signature
in terms of making the thing resistant
to forgery or attacks
other sorts on it but usually there's
extra space in
because if you look at it information
there you might say no they're this many
bets
and this larger number of bits but that
doesn't mean you can isolates a 79 to 25
this it's actually smoothed out 17 get
some information in the 25 so there's
extra space in
broadband channels use all that extra
space
figuring out absolutely what is
nonessential
and using narrowband channels
don't use all use a much smaller amount
maybe
one bit or two bits per signature and
the advantages to not using nearly as
much space
is that you get a poll also to other
neat tricks with
maybe it's hard dated
back to detect maybe has other
advantages
in terms the verification signatures
by there good reasons for using so let's
look at the subliminal channels and ESA
85 man by the name of
estaba Simmons found a subliminal
channel and el-gamal
why the notable things about this a
little channel
is that the recipient the information
needs to know your private key
now if you want to communicate
information with somebody else
out there you can generate a key pair
and give the other guy
your private key and him view it as some
sort symmetric
information hiding safer but it's got
one drawback
and that is if you're actually using
this key pair for signatures or even if
you're not
they can generate a signature which with
whatever identity
you put on it and if anybody tries to
verify
it will come out as being you and
if you say oh well Mikey was compromised
people say why are you still using
if you pretend your key wasn't
compromised then you get stuck with the
blame for whatever they sign
and this is a little more bothersome
today
because digital signatures are actually
starting to become legally binding
do you wanna give somebody else the
ability to sign documents
as you without anyway telling whether it
was actually you
signing it or not if I don't want to do
that the other problem with the ElGamal
subliminal channel
is that there's only a fraction of a
possible messages you can send
some messages just fail you won't be
able to do it mathematically and have
the signature verified
the same time and some
messages you can send buddy is
computationally infeasible
to get it back out so the information's
in there somewhere but the other person
Kampala on he asked approximately what
fraction of messages
I don't remember off the top of my head
its it's a fairly
decent amount I mean you can still send
things whatever you can still some
whatever you want as long as you're
willing to be creative about how you
phrase it
it's not that terribly restrictive
it's still there are a lot of messages
can send
I can look up the numbers after est like
so +91 DSS including the digital
signature algorithm is proposed
I'd put out in this proposal or the
ships publication
by the National Institute Standards and
Technology
two years later this guy I find one
broadband into narrow bands
someone all channels in the algorithm so
it stop a review at this time he's doing
is now says
you found something before he sees that
they're related he finds min TSA
again the broadband channel requires
sharing the private key
all messages can be sent consent any
message you want
the narrowband channels you can maybe
only send a few bits at a time
but the other person doesn't need your
key so anybody out there with just your
public key
which everybody would supposedly have to
verify your signature anyways
they can all pull out a few bits of
information from each signature
that is absolutely hidden in the
signature
and you can only find you know you're
looking for
and
94 one year later after he
makes a run of conferences I in america
elsewhere give a nice talkin Italy I
believe Rome
on the saloon all channels and basically
said hey look
these things exist not only do they
exist its
really easy to use them and it's really
easy to use them for whatever you want
and this is possibly a very bad thing
94 DSS is accepted as the first digital
signature standard
by any government nobody's really
heard much about this sense so the
question is are the subliminal channels
a bug or feature
so we want to use this I'm a look at the
broadband channel because
you can put a lot more in it you can
show off a lot more with it
and it's simpler and the airmen channels
what you want to do is just stuff some
information in the signature
such that the signatures still valid
anybody with
your public key was no idea what's going
on can still
verify the signature everything looks
good and
they have no way of actually proving
that the information is there or not
there's also the problem I'll without
the shared secret they shouldn't be able
to stumble upon your information
they shouldn't just be poking at it and
pull out its 1379 in
you'll find a message whatever terrorist
plans have
there has to be some way of knowing a
little more than that
to be able to actually reconstruct for
message
and the best part is the math is really
simple
so remember that random variable K used
as the blinding factor
remember that so if you know the private
key
you can backtrack and figure out what
Ky's
so all you do is you give the private
key to somebody else
and they can go back and they can find
out what Kate
case a 160 bits so it's pretty hard to
guess randomly
so your private key is generally safe
somebody's just trying to do an attack
by something else has a key then they
can pull 160 bits out
and as long as you distribute these bits
and messages fairly well
then chances are somebody is not going
to be able to
tell that you're working with a specific
pattern if I love your 160 bit numbers
star with few particular bytes then you
might run into problems because you're
reducing
the amount space you have to go through
for brute force attack
songs are smart about it you can get a
hundred and sixty minutes each time
no work as long as you're willing to
give up your private key
unfortunately this also works the other
way around
if somebody knows K they can backtrack
and get your private K
it's actually pretty simple you know all
the variables but one
and you just solve for the private key
acts
so all you have to do is figure out some
way
knowing what random variable act k is
that they're using and you got there K
now you might think
all sorts of ways of doing this weather
by putting some sort of backdoor into
their program to
playing with a random number generator a
random number generator is bad then you
effectively reduced the key space any
sort of attack
there also is a great things that you
can do with this if you want some
buddies K
people know it dis look like how online
source code my changing here
I'm changing one-liner source code where
you pick a random line
and to two lines which can be reduced to
one if I'm not being terribly lazy and
want to change
some other things here and there
compress a little so that it doesn't go
off the end of the slide
by changing 11 source code to two lines
and send a pic Inc a randomly you just
allocate
the memory space for K and then set it
to something in particular
in this case let's edit to the value of
the hatch
simple easy to remember it works
cell you know noah K is if you are using
a patched version
GPG that shouldn't be using
one-line politics
cell say you want to get there key
from this value axe which technically
makes up the private key
well it's actually pretty easy to do yes
South Trax
poor the parameters on their public a
then you go through all of the OpenPGP
def
defined star for encapsulating keys and
turning them into
however you want to use down whether RFC
whatever compliant ur ASCII are murder
however you want your key whatever
flavor you want in
all you do is you take the key
encapsulate the Kenya Certificate
you make a key block you put the
certificate in the key block you copy at
the user ID
put it in the key block put a signature
cell signature
on the key which you can do because got
the key
added to the key block armored if you
want write to a file
you've got their key wanna see how this
works
everybody see this I mmm
how to do this
I don't think that'll change the size
the font
can kill the lights keep the lights down
a little so make it his
control right button
I didn't do it how
is that now it's not much better
yeah Yemen today right now
arm
okay it's just highlighting
I home
I think I'll just have to do that is
this
any 0 you go
go alright so this might not be as good
a demonstration as I was hoping
oh well I'll while my but see
the I
haha you rich
there we go thank you very I've never
I've never seen that many before thank
you our rights
so wets
generate a key pair so we wanted TSA
know the marking
1024 bits is fine
am generate a key generates and
generates
brand new key
alright now it's make a message
have a nice simple to test message and
let's make a signature on
let's use the bad version GPG to make
the signature
the patched version
alright so we should now have a
signature and there it is
cell looks like any regular signature
everything's gone for okay
everything's gone fine let's see if we
can verify the signature
good signature from testking the
signatures fine
so everything looks normal you attach
the signature to the message you send it
out
on in an email or to use net or whatever
you do with your digital signatures
and Brandon people grab your key and you
go through the whole
he signing process intent 5 o'clock
tomorrow
intent and then you verify the signature
and sing okay everything looks fine so
what's the problem here well
so that this program called some DS a
key are written in Perl
using the crypt OpenPGP prolonged
very nice said models by the way I
highly suggest using if you want to do
anything with OpenPGP keys
and you run the program and it computes
and values
and a look key armored and written to
disk
I wonder what's in XD well let's take a
look at it first
actually was it do up top
you'll see that reads the signature
first on this case it's a v3 signature
are typed 17 which her response to TSA
somebody's trying to use an RS air other
signature
it will abort and say hey sorry this
does mark your User ID in time stamp get
a hasher the message at the signatures
on
and get the values are an ass then it
goes and grabs that public key
looks it up pulls out to the public
during file text the fingerprint on the
key
version four key it's not a subkey and
it pulls out the public key
PQ outlines case G and why
checks the signature to make sure it's
valid it's a valid signature
then it figures out what your private
key is overlook their Zacks
and then just to make sure X is correct
goes through the process to make sure
that when you do the exponentiation it
matches up with the publication
yes it does in fact matchup and then it
does all that stuff
just