folder that extra mIRC I not tiles
and should only have one copy for each
version
fire zp installed its
Jim immediate access anything which is
that you need to not program just need
to do decision players
and have it sort of a different polymers
nice
really easy to change its that's what's
up wat
spot these things just into the process
and click filed in the palms fun in the
process
and making sure that its starters and
anything else they haven't
caught that's still related to the bot
on
Joan take anything into the pot because
you never know if people hadn't
as a trojan he had been discovered a
mystery everything
119 on don't use but for chat not right
there sweeeet
is dead to you will use it for chatting
to Chris triple-a done it all before
its done horrible things to me sheens
home
and then so that those GT but the other
big golden bikini is St but which is
more or less the same thing
does pretty much the scenes stuff
all the old rules to keep
applied st and this is the demonstration
portion
had the slick demonstration
3 dimensions
get infected nice sons
who was working before
wasn't working now
so I am go with you into an imagination
journey
free you can pretend like you're seeing
this demonstration work
and what you'd see is
deeds on the screen here there would be
IRC channel
and it would be called like I like
hiking or something
and okay
anyway and then home over here in this
window
UNC everything Windows 2000 desktop
which looks perfectly normal except
thirty-year
file on the desktop called like cheeky
Potter
something like that and this
give a copy on this just up to you you
basically
you would click on the cheeky but
application to Disney image before we
know it flush out and nothing will
happen looked
the system manager you couldn't see
anything and then
few had speed of running you'd see a
buncha traffic going from that victim
to port 6667 on tires answer
which would be polite she
which unfortunately we've had stick to
it University
Jersey just so many sheen's you have
people that will look full time
for these kinda for these bought herds
and
dole hang out on channels a look for
hidden journals
on IRC servers stuff like that and then
bill
tried to get a list of all the IP
addresses
the clients that are on that channel but
a lot of times the IP's are hidden
so either they also used to like even
say he you
88 you've got this pack machinery or do
something about it or the I'll say this
is the IRC server every look for the
flows going to this r/c server if
your committee src sorry probably
infected and that's another way to track
it down
own their own home with things like
first which is like the
it sounds like the forensic and incident
response
team something is that
you need to pay them to be part of them
which is like good for old people that
work for corporations but not so good
for
people would have loved one year young
the mostly looking older
people like on their forties so if
you're into that kinda thing you should
definitely check them out I'm
also there's uni Saudi inches
kinda it's got a funny name for its
University
security officers group think and
sometimes you get botnet reports on
there but misleading
University people so we can assume that
they're lazy and Sinhala trim parts a
lot
I'm but the still occasionally come to
and
tell you that you've been hacked also
we'll tell you things like a there's a
Skeeter bite you should check it out
communications port or whatever user
really expensive piece of equipment
called a package here which looks at all
the packets
on your network and will do you should
have not
exactly trend analysis but it will do
things like
tell you who's been sending the most
files on IRC
or the column the top DCC talkers
usually few
iPhone University work the people who
like a big difference between
hacked people sending DCC trafficking
regular people so the
stick out like a sore thumb and high
traffic usually includes a
IRC bot in it may or may not be a Diaz
DDoS but heard but it could also be
people's treating movies and things like
that
for purses at the University the both
the same thing more or less but
it's not necessarily going to be but not
if that's what you're looking for
also you can move from shins not survive
RC traffic in march to the pier ICMP
traffic which indicates are talking with
YouTube here I ICMP attacks does
eliminated school in the bottom is
attacking
so we need to use a like of people who
use ours here are bad
and just look for all those people and
see if there's traffic and see who
they're talking to you when there's
intricate stitching
people or just ignore our see all
together and wait for your that were to
fall over
which is what we've adopted as your
policy
so to take my network please
own
so yeah I'm different ways depending how
you 1 I'm
manager network you can own
uses two different ways of finding a she
but general also if you're on IRC
you can tell if the entire team but mere
presence will have
usually some weird character combination
name it'll be like
x2 Museveni 50 967
and then go that's a button to get off
will join again in only its name will be
XTZ 59 60 and we'll keep kicking off
I'll keep you reading is number by one
and its uniting in the usually have to
like family IP address is coming from
but since they're everywhere
prolly change in usually do not as much
for public nuisance anymore because
people have figured out
you can set up their own IRC series
pretty easily so you don't have people
hanging out as much on dollar enough
metal it'll happen a lot then it makes
your car also
so this we do board online
it's like a internet which board we've
got like basically a number pad
regions like an IP address and use
things like warm virus never
on I haven't seen it like made
manufactured
mass now split if you're into reedy
boards the paranormal
and helping you psychically fine hack
machines does that
probably a regular review board we're
trying to do with the numbers
optimizing your way out too much take a
little longer
0 actually and if there's any like
really
did there's dead anything attackers act
that is
ESC admin X alive but then would he
really hope you for good or for evil
said yet similar discussions also
on you can look for DNS traffic which
known as talking about the problem
orphaned machines
people have gotten the fix that by using
dine DNS he's got din dins is it looks
like to me
am you look for traffic
going to time DNS host names that have
suspicious really obvious names like
packs or dot
Indians dot or evil dot Indians outward
and the reason for that is with the they
got the C&C methodology which is another
military term meaning
command-and-control
and world music military people come
into the hacking world
like let's bits and sure but anybody
other than that
issues like only it spitz region good
Shipley and things like that
but these people have decided definable
Camberley for us and what they've
decided to call this is a command
control methodology
and with that is your
IRC server is your your command in
control
she and so that's where everyone goes to
get commands and
control and normally
you configure year parts of her before
you redeploy it
you there's like options like uses
prolly menu option
that's like preferences options and you
go there and you say I want
everything to connect to evil dot
tendons that word
as my heirs user and the great thing
about dined yes is dynamic dns even
update the IP address any time you want
to
you go out in hugh in fact love machines
you make them you tell them to connect
to the host name instead by Pierre s
like evil dot dime de estar Lord
and then on if you're command control
machines ever found
it's not a big deal because you just
comprises a machine make that commanding
changing the update your
DNS record which I think updates on the
matter
like 12 minutes or something so it's
pretty easy
everything is become such a commodity
you know it is in terms of the zombie
and the
packed machines and the command control
machines that everything is very mobile
operation
very desert storm anything and
more military a things to
night ready to kiss a Daily Show but
they're backed up for like six months
since a live picture Johnston save but
what's
new in the last year isms
ago Barton fat but we're to missed
YouTube arts written by this German guy
I'm anybody who knows with his name was
is uses
and he brought these like super
efficient evil
network killing machines and being
arrested
in the east got arrested he stopped
doing tech support me stop doing tech
support
people really amazing I girls I want to
use this so it back to the old
goodies that have goodies but all these
which have documentation
usage statements GD part and AZT thought
and no at the time to anger but was like
the shit because people
was like slimmer but then it wasn't and
is really hard to
figure out what was going on with I do
but is basically a
is an IRC bot like any other IRC bot in
it
comes free with this can compromise
engine suspends in like fashion see
don't
need to
yellow card six other thing i think is
anyway so you don't have to go through
the trouble installing an module to
compromise
it to scanning income rise because it
comes with it to its
very much more appealing to the AOL user
who wants to be accounting
fat but used peer to peer to talk to
other
machines to the buyer see which is
another thing that confused
people who look for the certain things
you like but it doesn't use IRC happen
in the inner city but
uses peer to peer we don't know how to
regulate that's within
own the din all that stopped
when he got arrested I'm sure there's
people using it people who like wanna go
to the terrible thing you know but most
people don't
so and use old stuff University pitcher
Jon Stewart
and which is if you're seeing ring first
for peace talks is got naked womens
my answer to that fit you've got
also rx Potter Arbat which was another
like brand new but
which isn't very nice ago but that
probably also was not
as popular anymore just cuz it's very
ago but group ago but really
was good tax per guy he fix our problems
he was always
taking new suggestions for features
things like that and could
on the cool thing are by is it scans
really quickly
fast enough to know if something changes
by scanning it
and also this is perking up there called
La Brea like deliberate
markets where it will keep all the
connections open once you connect to it
is kinda like a honey pot was like
really sticky honey
and so if you're trying to scan machine
or scanner
like 1000 jeans at once your counting on
the connections close
enough memory in every band with their
ritually memory ins
CSU cycles and network stack space the
innkeeper
scanning more stuff with the breeders
keeps everything open and then
your scan takes forever like wasn't
returning
soon this follows Libreria by if you
text
too long a responsible chill threads and
so I guess that's kinda cool well I
don't know anybody who
use I'm sure people do and you do then
people for you haw a also
spam is another really irritating trend
you see a lot of people
paying spammers will pay hackers
breaking the machines which
now is really easy with make something
everywhere
just his PC peacekeeping everywhere but
you have spammers paying hackers to
break into machines and then saying
here's in three million copies of my via
out everybody and then the hackers will
use their
botnets for profit not necessarily good
and just since been to people's known we
see spambots
on our network key its generally
probably going to be something else
compromise with an IRC bot to use if you
weren't looking at people there's an
online support 25 traffic
its sometimes way now to find RC by
plans we have URL's
for further reading where you can
download things like
shitty but St by on the
think it's link at the bottom like
weblinks orztech.com such spots
response to it you know has like three
thousand different kinds bart's
people were like 300 but its settling
archive workers back
a while and you got your different
variants and people are is
talking with things and uploading it it
is more cool stuff
admin those and drop speedy fine because
it's not people
and BNC
your own thing but yasser I for one
welcome our new about masters and
speedier James minsky
said that's that's the talk
see any questions or comments
stones
yes we do 0
it helps just yom's good stuff
not take down the network for people in
a shooting donor network without that
but now its oxygen bring the thing if
you don't have it
and family investor networking guys and
installing it
I don't it's enough to live off from
what I hear
ain't probably yeah I mean it
is the place in like free market thing
we're
the spammers knee-deep in less than what
no its parent pay the hackers
less than what they're making from spam
but it's probably like
dollars and his people that do make a
living off the grid
car owns definitely liberal arts Windows
machines
the sea as people have like now it
continues just kiddin
its ciskei taxes rootkits cuz those are
so much more skin
branded stuff that the Lord
hun
okay I'm think the large spot love scene
was
I haven't seen but approve it is but
something like
maybe a hundred thousand parts or
something like that I don't know about
the connection to organized crime
wouldn't be surprised wouldn't surprise
me if there wasn't a connection since
they're always organized crime is being
on using encryption that the evil
technologies
that the government doesn't want you to
use but could be
d went to the organist when people do
with the bud
yeah that's another good business final
the PIP
heating people paid to spend people or
people pay you not to attack them
yet Sons Inc
again well thank you
thank you for waking up so early