their electoral responsibilities is is
another question
yes sir with the No Center
information repository do you ever
believe there's a
need for anonymous information
submission
or should only the right people be able
to figure out who the actual submitter
I think everybody well there is a value
to anonymous sources that are
consistently proven right
arm I don't have any hard rules
are on balance I think being open about
who you are and what you've collected is
right because if you're if you're
if you're stealing information and
posting it that's not really I'll send
that's theft
arm and so I'm not looking to
inspire I mean I encourage
whistleblowing I encourage anonymous
whistleblowing
I encourage the reporting have any
violation by any corporation
above its responsibilities to its
stockholders to its clients to the
government and so forth I don't have
any hard and fast answers but on balance
I think that openly identifying yourself
with data that you touch is inevitably
going to make the system self-policing
K now with all the information that also
helps gather
with bleach all the keys to its and you
believe that those people
our secure enough to hold that
information and women I think you should
hold keys to it I think it should be
public intelligence
are you know actually 06 should be
completely public no scent is when you
all-cif is broadcast all centers what's
created for
for a person and obviously if major bank
wants to
wants to put a billion dollars of
investment into a specific
point in Indonesia they want to keep
that secret
until they've bought the land and cut
the deals and all that and so the OHS in
supporting
that is unclassified in the raw form
and proprietary in the senate for and 10
things we've talked about some Swedish
companies
is that it may be that you want to
release that to the public domain after
you've done your business
so the year adding to the pot arm this
is not about
keys this is not about control if
anything it's about bottom-up
bacteria like self
propagation networking and on the fly
discovery I mean I i I don't feel I'm
hittin right
to someone explain to me what is
question was you wanna add to that
I mean with the information that
07 does help gather now
there's gonna be valuable information to
it let me give you an example
let's let's say I have this vision it's
in my second book
I want you to be able to sit down and
type in your zip code and immediately
see a list
issues that are important to you
education water
whatever disease and then I want you to
be able to click on let's say
water and bomb and so for your zip code
it shows the past water disasters in
violations
and the current ones in the near future
for future to the extent that
that is being protected by anyone and
then you can click
and say see a map of water in your zip
code and then
all of a sudden you'll see a citizen who
is downstream factory who was just
reported an effluent discharge
and this is like near-real-time citizen
intelligence
and all this stuff rather than being
lost in to the bureaucracy
is open to you for the creation a public
intelligence
so it may be that based on that warning
a bunch you get together in OC meeting
and say hey let's have some undertake
a sample the water every week or every
day
are or where you see where I'm going
with this it's it's kind of like
and I don't wanna say this is original
to me i've I'm the one that's made the
transition from government to public
intelligence but appear
tell her to shut down I have the concept
of new spiritual
well said world brain a Howard bloom who
was here in New York
the Road global brain arm Pierre Libyan
France's written collective intelligence
Howard reingold is written smart mobs
arm Tom at Lee is written the TALF
democracy
a the subject to something like alcoa
intelligence can
make a better world for all of us to
live in I don't see all centers
as a restricted club I see it as a
process
love sharing and and informally
acting in assigning one of the reasons
we're never gonna beat terrorism with
the FBI
and and the Department of Homeland
Security's is there a command and
control hierarchy
and you cannot do top-down up prevention
you have to do bottom-up are
awareness and and surge II after 9/11 I
was interviewed by BBC
that I said he gonna happen again and I
said why not I said because the old
paradigm was be can see cuba
okay the new paradigm is kill the
asshole you're gonna die yourself and
maybe inside a large building
are business classes figured this out
okay I don't think we're gonna see
another hijacking of the kind that we
saw 911 now I'm worried about
the ease with you can put suitcases
loaded with explosives under these
planes and we still don't have the
Kevlar parts
in on all the planes and stuff so we'll
have more disasters
but I'll send is about a self-organizing
our community event wrist in the true
sense of the word
next person are you guys okay with these
questions
would you rather have more spy stories
spy stories alright you two guys you two
guys for questions and I will use a spy
stories
um I'm I really think that this is a
good idea however
I don't think that government would be
willing to
changeover especially with stuff like a
I don't care what government wants
that's what you want yeah I know it's
what we want but I mean like
get on with it the government wants us
to be
you know in prison basically with Supply
Co Intel pro where you know they
in dade ger the minute you get me 75
percent turnout at the polls I get you a
new government
yeah I understand that and but I think
that
most people are raid rather than willing
obviously 8338 your people here
aren't afraid we're we're trying to I
think people are less afraid than
apathetic
are the supreme court to my enormous
surprise has concluded that enemy
combatants get a right to a lawyer
arm this is good it took them too damn
long
ought to get to that had i been chief
justice an advisor to Chief Justice I
would have demanded that case the day it
happened
I mean Padilla shoulda had the supreme
court's interest from day one and it's a
disgrace that they didn't
arm look
one other really cool things about
american democracy
is the only get screwed as far as you
wanna be
okay are this country is apathetic
on and I think
the the democratic party's gonna rue the
day that they screwed Howard Dean
up because he was really developing
momentum
and he was getting people energized he
was getting new people into the process
arm a will take another 10 to 15 years
but you know what these guys can only
steal so much
before the rest of america notices and
if we have a combination of another and
Ron I mean look at the last two years
every major institution Americans failed
Congress failed to control the purse and
prevent war
are the media failed to report honestly
in turn down fully funded anti-war
infomercials fully funded informational
academia stinks by and large are
at least in my area of expertise in
foreign and national security
arm what
yes I agree with you we agree on this
the media is controlled
I agree with you but that's one of the
cool things about the Internet
alright later okay later
later please you're being disruptive arm
I the thugs are coming I up
I don't beat the shit outta just cut is
here arm
okay I I give you five minutes a
personal attention
when we finish okay are
every institution has failed our
corporations
RR I mean and you know ninety-five
percent of Americans hard working on a
small business
okay it's just the big dogs that are
really feeling Halliburton
arm Citibank I in fact is a book I
recommend all you cold warriors
by Peggy in Sterling see grace goldwater
uses about macarthur discovering all the
japanese cold in Japan
that could not get through the blockade
and it became the world's largest covert
slush fund
for buying corruption worldwide and
reasonably is controlled out of Treasury
not at a CIA
arm bottom line for me
is is a Jonathan Schell has a right
Gandhi had it right
non-violent informed resistance wins
every time
you know jonathan shell has a great line
in his book he says violence is how the
few control the many
non-violent resistance is how the many
control the few
okay and so I advocate non-violent
former assistant we can take this
country back
and it starts with electoral electoral
reform
carries a damn fool for not making it
his number one issue
thank you very much okay next
this is more just to
comment I'm several years ago I was
helping a friend read a report
about arm %ah money laundering
and the topic came how do you get
communication from
to unconnected parties so that you could
lead to a gifting network from one
person to another and therefore
you know in exchange for something like
money or something the helices yeah
and a got to thinking about systems
alike
you know posting an eBay auction that
you're at it as their attic on things
like that
but real big thing that really came up
was what better way to communicate with
what a sleeper cells
then with spam i like it
a spam email message to be sent
thousands
fifty of them are you important targets
that's very good everyone else is going
to delete it and it I want outlook
and most fans we should let the guys
don't delete the spam
I love that we will yeah
our what we really need is anyone who
replies to spam
or also I like it but frankly they like
playboy
more are also began offering it as a
large division
federal agents whose wonderful job it is
to read
every spam there there are reasons there
is a let me tell you where the federal
government is focusing the federal
government is focusing on cuba
are your boat or airplane can now be
possessed without trial if you have a
chart cuba
on it and are suspected of being
interested in violating the embargo this
is a major
cover article in one of the yachting
magazines okay let's move on I love it
both have the ideas last question and
then I'll try and do some spy stories
high or answer questions about spying I
arm
I really like the idea social
intelligence
system are do you have a particular
vision for
I mean as far as I understand its in
data integration system and
a system that the last seven tries seven
standard seven issues to start with
okay are there any working prototypes
that we could take a little on
collective intelligence
one of the things I like about
collective intelligence is
some other concepts they're on on wisdom
the crowd knowledge management
validation and so on you can also go to
my website
read the oh said story which is inside
of the OSA portal
arm but it hasn't happened I think it's
about to happen
%uh ohs into meet up which only has
88 people signed up in 54 cities right
now
but is potentially huge are also sent
out meet up dot com is my best shot
trying to get people to self-organize
imagine what would happen if here in New
York City
OC dot meet up dot com created a water
committee
a fire committee law a
tunnel committee or whatever and then
got people from police intelligence
military intelligence
labor unions I mean these labor unions
can communicate with everybody in that
tunnel
you know and and so then self-organize
and so what kind of weekly report you
want to create for
water risks in New York what kinda
distance library what kind of
distance learning what kinda virtual
library I don't have the answer
I I think this is gonna be
self-organizing from the bottom up
and so I would say to you whatever
issues important to you
use a the Internet these collective
intelligence initiatives for instance
the collective intelligence weeki was
just opened
and it's already got 279 pages on and
you can you can
Google for Intel for collective
intelligence week you can just go to the
collective intelligence blog
don't look to me as a leader I'm a
provocateur
arm an agitator you guys are gonna have
to lead yourselves
K alright spy stories while
what kinda spy stories do you want
what's at
alright what he suppose most important
skill in spying is
listening
when he suppose the second most
important skill in spying is
typing
I am NOT James Bond
I've carried a gun arm but let me tell
you something for every hour
agent meeting you've got four hours a
typing and if you're handling a terrace
live you have to do what's called I said
he said transcription you're the only
one that can do them and that is a bitch
up because with the terrorist usually
end up having a forty eight-hour meeting
up because it's so hard to get in and
out and so you end up having to
transcribe it 48 hours over two to three
days
it is a real pain in the ass we didn't
have IBM's Voice thing
at the time this was back in the
mid-eighties
so listening and typing are the two most
important skills
now spying
consists love spotting assessing
recruiting handling and terminating
which means a cash settlement not
execution although we have terminated
with extreme prejudice
which to stand for murder arm I haven't
done it but basically spying in theory
in any given country you're supposed to
be looking for things that are really
important national security
that's not what actually happens are
across most of the world's even up to
today although today iraq is just
consuming everything
but across most of the world we've had
stations in Africa and elsewhere
primarily because that was the easiest
way to get a soviet to drink booze with
us
and soul spying has been mostly about
drinking with soviets
arm okay I'll tell you what you don't
ever wanna drink with the soviet
arm
I mean I never did it because it was so
disgusting
but the recommended protocol is to eat a
bar butter first
a I am works I'm told but it's not
something I want to do
I'd just rather get drunk and fall
asleep
%uh put but anyway that's the main
reason the clandestine service existed
to chase obviously didn't give a shit
about what was happening in africa
we didn't give a shit about who to and
and and these other ethnic divisions
are we didn't even give a shit about
internal policies
that were extremely corrupt and
committing genocide
I mean you know how can 18 genocides go
on in this world in the United States
public the United States Congress United
States
White House thinks it has other
priorities how can Lake Powell
in arizona go down by two hundred meters
and Las Vegas
is about to lose water talking about
selling the mall Himachal for to Los
Angeles
okay Las Vegas is gonna Berkman five to
seven years and be outta water
this is what I would call a real estate
disaster okay
on nobody's paying attention to this
actually I love the movie
decis movie climate change I've invited
them to speak at my next conference
arm we're really not serious about
not only global warming the global
freezing we're not serious about
controlling bacteria
all we are going to have plagues in the
United States
we are going to have a lot of these
these troubles
on so spying spotting is you're supposed
to kind of say okay let's say
I wanna penetrate the new york city
mayors office
arm first thing I want to do is figure
out who works there
and i wanna figure out who the key
people are who are the key communicators
handle every piece a paper that goes
into the mayor who's a scheduler
arm who the people's vulnerability since
eat a lot of homework and these people
are and you a recruiter called axis
agents
soul let's say you want to get into the
mayor's office maybe you start with
getting there
really great looking blonde that's
covering the mayor's office for the New
York Times
actually they're prolly to well-paid for
some ragged you know how someone could
use an extra thousand bucks a month
and he said looking arm false
this is called false flagging say I i
represent a major corporation is trying
to get a contract with the city at like
your help in understanding the mayor
okay that's how it starts and once they
get used two thousand bucks a month
and your real nice to them and you know
they they they get used to committing
treason
and and i think thats
thats how we do it and so spotting
assessing
recruiting recruiting is basically
dressing it up
a in a way that's acceptable to them you
understand the person well enough so you
can make a pitch that they'll accept
arm and most people can accept money in
return for betraying an employer
by March especially if you make them
think
that is being done in a way that doesn't
actually conflict with their own ideals
and
and what not this is why we like false
flag so much arm
or what I call commercial recruitments
arm and then handling in theory
handling includes asking the right
questions
getting to and from meetings without
being seen on
various sources and methods for
capturing their information in a way
that it can be destroyed if you're
rested
one of the problems with CIA is it's
it's lazy about security
are its case officers don't live cover
they live immunity
they all carry diplomatic passports so
that
the worst that will happen to miss the
be thrown out of the country
occasionally they'll get
beat-up in russia they like to be to
some first
arm and
you use these people use access a chance
to put in technical devices
arm for example in the overhead
Minister's Office
arm or in the back seat of his car when
it's
at a service station are but a lot is
technical stuff doesn't work
you have what's called a path loss
distance about a hundred meters 200
meters and if you can't get out be on
that path loss distance you start to
lose
you tactical however because fiber and
all these other things are an essay is
starting to go death
so close in remote is getting popular
arm
which is to say putting stuff and to
specific tactical locations
are so that you can capture the
unencrypted a conversation before it
goes into an encryption system
on that's very labor intensive
it's a lot easier to read newspapers
and and one of the things that I've
discovered is a pattern analysis from
all sent
beats the crap outta classified
intelligence tell your real story where
I took on the entire intelligence
community
it's not a spy story but it has some
lessons
on the 5th of August 1995 I think it was
the the aspin brown Commission
had four witnesses on open source
intelligence one of my classmates from
Harvard intelligence policy course fills
Provost macneil
got me in which was a surprise on tony
lake testified and I think he says
he said something like I call my friends
at Harvard whatever
arm the rand corporation testified and
they said the Internet has everything
you need to know no sin we know how to
get it
this is back in 94 95 arm
and David Sarnoff lab at princeton which
is partially funded by the National
Reconnaissance Office came and said we
don't know what does
is but high definition TV will make it
better
okay that was their pet rock that year
are and then I came and I said remiss in
eighty percent of what we need to now
and I made enough of an impression on
the members of the Commission
so the General Allen asked me the other
day if I'd be willing to take on the
entire US intelligence community
in a benchmark exercises china problem
and so he turned a bit sizes 5 o'clock I
was actually on my way to Def Con
to speak are and Eterna Brett Snyder
who I think will be a future leader of
the intelligence community he's the only
guy is one of two people it served on
both the church committee in the ass
brown Commission and he was staff
director and if I were to be put into a
position of power today the first person
I would call spread
all he knows his stuff arm
but anyway said brandy its 5 o'clock on
a Thursday afternoon by ten o'clock on
Monday the Fed Ex delivery time
let's have everything the US
intelligence community has every image
every signal
every clandestine report wherever
they've got
and then he turned to me says do what
you do at the time I had an assist and I
called her from the car
and dirt older where to send five faxes
and then she said the six packs with the
phone number to me
and so on Friday the day before my
speech in Def Con I spent the day
twisting
455 CEO's arms into giving me a hundred
thousand bucks for the free support
by ten o'clock on Monday morning
LexisNexis identified the top ten
journalists in the world reporting
number on the rhonda based on their
byline
all of them immediately available for
debriefing journalists only published 10
percent what they now
and the best stuff that they knows the
buyer graphics the corruption
all the personality and networking and
contacting details
from the Institute for Scientific
Information Philadelphia the top 100
people in the world
writing reputable academic articles and
foreign affairs and other articles about
branding rhonda
from Oxford analytica in England which
is run by David Young who worked with
kissing on the national security council
attended Oxford
his harness Oxford University's little
many think tank
from them I got twenty two-page a
executive summary suitable for president
or prime minister on live around here on
the world portent
in terms of geopolitical references at
the US State Department trying to avoid
coming to grips with
are from issue publications 100 percent
a brandy
in 150 combat charts from Russia
all which we don't we don't have maps
for ninety percent of the world
okay we do not have maps below 100
hundred thousand two hundred fifty
thousand level for ninety percent of the
world and it turns out
it's the ninety percent were all the bad
stuff happens okay
arm and then belatedly from
up I'll from Jane's one paragraph
summaries every article that ever
written
on bronte in the military situation
there and then for me they went out and
created one
page orders a battle for the tribe's at
a time when see I was still counting
just the
the uniform army and brandy are and then
belatedly
from spot a much 100 percent a brandy
cloud free lesson three years old
already in the archives
and therefore an expensive CIA had one
of those cute little maps
and a regional economic study in the
chapter from the world Factbook
no shit okay
it was no contest we weren't paying
attention
arm that story repeats itself every
single day today
whether it's genocide or water disease
whatever now I I don't you think
compassion CIA because the analysts I
just a press release
that was critical senator Roberts recent
findings I think that he bashed the
analyst too much and he didn't bash the
clandestine service enough
he also completely overlook the fact
that see I can't process everything it
knows
are he overlooked the fact that they're
not doing open sources
are you overlook the fact that DOD
controls three of the national agencies
are which are completely disrespectful
the CI's guidance
and several other things arm that's a
real-world comparison
a fifty billion dollars for sis 502
million
are in gross annual operating costs
arm I can generally beat the crap outta
anybody within 48 to 72 hours for under
ten thousand dollars
arm I've perfected this is an art form
okay spy stories I had to carry a gun in
El Salvador that's not very usual
I used to teach a rules of engagement
from my battalion it's a long complex
processes when and how you can kill
people
are with specific reference to innocent
civilians
and my chief the station handed me my
nine military bases you
use this when you don't really care
about losing your job
understood that one that was my rules of
engagement
for combat in El Salvador on someone
asked me a question
yessir spy story questions now
move away from us okay arm this might
sound like an inappropriate question but
I'm not I'm gonna frame nothing's an
appropriate here as long as its brief
it is um could you talk a little bit
either whether you had direct
involvement or just the history you now
love really badly botched her badly
conceived
CIA operations most wish that have come
from
policies of politics at the very high up
Sharma Central America
or and then we can go on to Afghanistan
in Iraq arm
you know I I am one of the un-indicted
members at the Central American Task
Force
arm I was to junior to really be engaged
in drug running money laundering and
murder
arm but there's a wonderful book by John
parry called lost history
and what he's talking about is is all
the bad stuff that came out a set amount
also vietnam I mean george allen has
written a book on vietnam call Tom
none so blind and the basic thing is
it's about cooking the books in saigon
and and ignoring the truth in washington
I don't think we need a Warren Central
America I think we have really miss
understood the power food and water I
think we should lift the cuban embargo
in flooded with the Internet
okay I it's just flat out stupid
to have an embargo on cuba it's the last
clean beach in the Western Hemisphere
okay I want that beach
a II yessir
compliments I'm it's almost like tenure
system
people don't well hang out headlight
I haven't really answered your question
what was it I'll
look after vietnam in fact as a result
to vietnam we learned how to run drugs
and launder money
K vietnam taught a whole bunch a case of
just how to be bad boys and girls
are we repeated that experience and and
are
in Central America only we use Southern
Air Transport and let them make the
money by running drugs
aren't we funded contras who turned out
to be
really murderous corrupt assholes arm
and I don't think we needed that work
you know if we would spend half the
money we spend supporting people
on peace ops I think we get a lot
further
now Afghanistan nobody thought through
the implications
alls creating a global Islamic Jihad
are I will tell you CIA did not find bin
Laden he had his own funding from Saudi
Arabia and in fact they were
major frictions between the Arab
jihadists and the legitimate
Afghanistan military and no pierde Jack
diviner both friends of mine
on and I think we really fail to think
through
what it would mean for russia to lose
control over the central
asians front now there are six fronts
that are in play now arm Central Asia
where Pakistan's government is actively
exporting terrorism
saudi Arabia's actively are tolerating
terrorism as as a price for stability
which is false
simply a central asian if western Africa
which is mostly muscle
you've got the Pacific RAM running down
from southern Thailand through Malaysia
Malaysia is a successful muslim state
it's a model we should be point on some
money into Malaysia
and not a single American K setting up a
special operations training camp in
malaysia is asking
for a disaster arm and then Philippines
and so forth are you've got Latin
America
has an increasingly Muslim population in
the Tri border region
down by Argentina and stuff you've got
increasing connections between ethnic
criminal gangs and terrorists and so
forth thank you very much
arm and so I don't think we thought
through Afghanistan we sure as hell
at the policy level did not think
through Iraq
because a rock first off was an
unnecessary war
arm saddam hussein what
well i i kinda know how you feel about
this but I stand on my record
if you go back over my website over the
last two years you will see if you just
google for impeach Bush Cheney
you'll see the stuff they haven't seen
yet and I deliberately decided not to
delete anything now that I'm making
progress
with certain elements the administration
arm
intelligence field the policy feel too
you know Paul O'Neill in his book the
price of loyalty says
under reagan and bush line arm
policy started with its ideological
preferences but at least considered the
fax
in the bush administration call rolf
decides what the outcome is going to be
never mind the fax
and then dick cheney's the enforcer arm
so
I think we made a lot of mistakes and
what I would like to do was CIA is clean
it up
to the point that every secret
intelligence report has a public
intelligence counterpart
and the people are treated as a
constituency as is congress
okay let's go to another person spy
stories
this moral message question can you
confirm or deny
that the agency user still uses
shortwave numbers transmissions to
to message its I assets
this wonderful directory of all US
Embassy radio communications
frequencies are around the world
the last time I was involved in and
clandestine communications
involved a number group
all and it involved all radio
frequencies
all one-time pads
and usually the first digits had a and
indicators to weather was a real message
or filler message
ninety-nine percent commercial arrest
to the traffic is constant just to avoid
tracks data analysis exact thank you
you're welcome
K anything else alright
will have a question here please feel
free to take a break I mean
are I realize it's it's hard but enough
love you seem to be interested
yes sir I don't know if you spoke about
this just kinda what then
been from the CIA analyst of in
previously
previously what is your stand on the
polygraph
and using it to actively the polygraph
is is first off not reliable
the polygraph can be beaten the
polygraph
is not a science is more than art
the most effective use the polygraph is
in the pre disclosure
face are when people are inspired to
reveal things and and talk about that
having said that I will also say that
the polygraph is a valuable tool
there's a book called spies in lies by
one of the CIA's best polygraph
examiners in vietnam it's a wonderful
book
and if you do nothing else read my
review of that book arm
the polygraph is one of many tools now
the problem that we have
is that Washington is dominated by a
security bureaucracy the guts to it
got to its a gust Frank after twenty
years
checking safes at night these are not
rocket scientists on and they tend to
thank you SO
are they tend to arm
they tend to be
ninety percent to lax and 10 percent too
hard
on ames was too lax
I mean how much does it take to figure
out that the guy pay cash for five
hundred thousand dollar housing was
driving a jaguar
on a GS for teens pay which at the time
was
65,000 a year arm
on the other hand they can be like an
inquisition
and they can castrate you without trial
arm
I just came from dinner with the case
officer: that was basically
thrown out at the agency for sleeping
within israel
israeli and not breaking off the
relationship when she was told to
she thought she was in love I'm pretty
sure he wasn't lost
are and based on the conversation I'm
inclined to think that the israeli may
also have been saying things that were
picked up by signals that she didn't
realize he was saying
sometimes israelis will justify the
expense account
by claim or others will justify the
expense account by claiming that someone
is a recruited agencies providing
information
may be completely false but he managed
to screw this lady and
more ways than one arm
shell the other promise security is
an intelligence careers dot com really
understands this problem
corporations are allowed to hire ten
percent love
the people to work on a and a contract
that requires clearances
without Clarence's but they can only do
that for six months
but it takes 18 months for this
incompetent government to do a security
investigation
okay and that's one of the reasons why
they prefer white boys from kansas and
and virgins from West Virginia
arm because they've never met a
foreigner
are and as a result they're getting the
wrong kinds of people into the system
they're also getting people that are way
too young are if I were changing things
today
I would take 150 the people from the
under 35 population
I would try not to kill them with
grenade accidents are
in training which just happened a year
ago
arm and then the rest of them are
mature US citizens have spent a lifetime
building cover
I can crack any cover inside a week to
30 days
you cannot build a false legend today
with all the computers and everything is
just too easy to check
so what you do is you get guys that have
been forty to fifty years old with an
overseas have a rolodex speak the
language have unwittingly built their
cover
and then you bring them into the spiking
are and tell us your caught you're fired
so they'll take security seriously arm
you have what are called career agents
which are very well-qualified
venezuelans pakistanis whatever you
treat them just like a sauce is we don't
have these anymore
treated just like a saucers in the field
but they never come back to headquarters
and they never touch secrets
or sick again or anything else are you
have
field stations are multinational this is
how I would run it
you feel sessions are multinational the
DEA has figured out
how to make you some honest Mexican cops
and the way you do is you bring them out
of their system and you put them into
your own little
Brotherhood group and that works
leading Mexican headquarters tell you
what they want you to know doesn't work
okay so we need to go after Francis the
French really good a penetrating the
arabs
they've managed to create a second third
generation of arabs
that are both loyal to france and able
to penetrate the the Arab communities
we should be using them are and the same
thing with israelis who have some really
fine
Arab penetrations arm and then
I'll last but not least it's just
business
we persist in treating spying as a thing
that requires
you take a polygraph you be recruited
asset
there are some cases where I just want
to be able to talk to tyson look I want
to put this technical device into this
thing going to this place
I'll give you a million dollars in you
never hear from me again it's just
business
okay well you gotta be gone at exactly
the right place
arm but the point is we're being very
on imaginative and the polygraph
unfortunately I think security has
become part of the problem
arm if I were advising a new DC I won my
first directors would be to completely
revamp security
are security is now part of the problem
not part of the solution
and that's true cross all of the
agencies
NSA polygraphs are better this is good
news for you I'm sure
an essay polygraphs are better and CIA
polygraphs
an assay you get a bigger softer cheer
and their kinder and gentler in their
probing
cell II Kershaw love you to consider
working for the US intelligence
community
even if you only do it for couples years
it will change you forever
arm and if you can't work for the US
intelligence community then
DoD intelligence career stock common
pick up a job at SAIC
or any one of these the Beltway bandits
that is making a fortune
pretending to do intelligence arm and
and have a little fun just like you only
get to be an infantry officer once in
your life
arm and it's something he can only do
when you're young
another question so we take a break
yes sir
we handle incompetence by ignoring it
you know part of the problem is it in in
the agent in the aged the Internet
in theory you should be able are our
approach at least the the CIA approaches
once you have your SAT K
CIA Baba clarence you can pretty much go
anywhere in see anything
arm and it shouldn't be that way I mean
you should be
able to only see things in your area and
at the same time you should not be
blocked from seeing things one of the
problems we have is over
compartmentation
I invented the reverse search it see I
precisely because this
what was happening was analysts were
asking questions are the system
like say what do we know about Libyan
T-seventy two tanks doing this
and the TIO was refusing to tell the
analysts
and so I invented the concept of a a
reverse search
which would which would tell the deal
that this analysts at this question why
they needed to know
when I was taken by my chief of station
up to talk to the else before I went to
my first feel station assignment his
marching orders from
mean work keep your mouth shut dot com
anything arm
now we're trying CIA has tried to merge
analysts and collectors
look what you have is good-hearted
people who are being hired by the wrong
model
managed by the wrong mindset to the
wrong hands
arm you don't create a world-class
intelligence community with young kids
at a Kansas
and really shitty technical processing
and no clandestine service and no
attention open sources of information
are and excessive reliance on foreign
liaison so what you have a systemic
incompetence rather than personal
incompetence
are every person there wants to do a
good job every person there is also
helpless in the face both decades
other naw supplied industrial your
system
that basically demands that you go
through the motions and pretend
everything's fine
up when in fact the system is an is in
terminal phase of its collapse
and all the snow this in 1985 are in
fact when I review janine brookner's
book on litigating intelligence
community
what CIA like to do to its agitators was
sent into a fitness for duty physical
with the emphasis was on calling them
nuts and then threatening them
so that they would resign in order to
preserve their options for other federal
reemployment by not being labeled knots
by CIA arm in fact is I look back at the
five or ten people five to 10 people
that I know that had fitness for duty
physical experiences and then resign
they were nuts they were the ones who
had it right
in our john gentry Road wrote a book
called The Lost promise I think it is
about all that's wrong with CIA arm
analysis I've written a book on
intelligence which is all that's wrong
with the entire community
arm others have written similar books
and yet they were labeled as traders
outcasts
the you know and so forth had they
listen to us in 1985 to 1990 I'm pretty
sure 911 would not have happened
okay we brought 911 on our own hats
yessir
me stories about into reliance action
the US UK degree manner being yes yes
the US is not allowed to collect on US
politicians so the British do it for us
and we collect on the canadians and it's
like a round-robin so we break each
others laws on our
on each other's bf yessir area
questions or even as a slight I'm used
to being ignored when I was out I know
on 911 on
mean there was in place norad system
would basically when interceptor
aircraft the street at bears airspace
and
system actually work pretty good before
9/11 the mean
hundreds airplanes it had gone of course
in
the way intercepting within 10 minutes
on this day
the Air Force miss all or gets or
is I understand story how could that
happen
well I think the best account on record
as Dick Clark's
although I believe the the Commission on
9/11 wall
will come out with some other stuff
are guy name Charles power i think what
a book called normal accidents dealing
with high-risk technology
he talks about how simple systems have
single points of failure
the failing easy to diagnose and correct
ways
complex systems have multiple points of
failure that that interact
%uh in their multiple cascade that very
hard to diagnose and fix
and the US government as a constellation
of complex systems
don't talk to each other very well I'm
willing to believe
that 9/11 was a catalog love
errors across a number of points
including Bush is not coming back to
town arm
I also think it's very important to
emphasize that a large part of the loss
of life in 9/11 occurred
because our police and and fire
communications in New York suck
are there not designed to be reliable
and high rise buildings
they're not designed to be interoperable
are there not designed in fact this is
still true overseas as Marines are
flying in to rescue an embassy they can
talk to the embassy
from the helicopter okay we have just
basically bill
you guys know the word kluge okay this
is kluge on steroids
okay the US government is a mess
are it's got many good people everybody
I think tries to do a good job and it's
just
its just a total mess command control
communications computing intelligence
is Cascais ask
every other airplane that street from
airspace people that
I don't know that I don't know the facts
but but I think here we had basically 20
to 30 minutes
during which half of it was wasted are
they're also Konami's the Pentagon has
been gutted
people are no longer doing strip alerts
arm
I just I just think everything that
could have gone wrong did go wrong
you just refuse to believe that
conspiracy in
no you show me the fax and I'll believe
it but I don't think the fact that their
arm you know there's this urban myths
about the israelis told every june the
World Trade Center not to show up for
work I don't think so
%ah look a let's go back to the basic
fact that all k to hit the world trade
center with a car bomb in 1993
they have a track record of coming back
to the same target they have a
they have a fixation on cultural targets
that were in fact
several airplanes I I think the
grounding the airplanes immediately was
one up the
in wretched I wasn't smart enough to
think about this on the day of the event
I think what I would have done was sent
out a broadcast message from the
president
every single airline offering immediate
presidential pardon to anybody who
murdered an asshole on the way the
cockpit
okay and and let the planes continue on
their path exact cost us a lot of money
to ground the aircraft
but grounding the aircraft actually
prevent it hits on Sears Tower
are in Chicago and Bank of America and
CNN atlanta bank American San Francisco
on CNN atlanta
which are also on the list I think there
was another plane designated for the
white house in the capital
okay a surrounding the airplanes
actually prevented several other
things arm I mean when I look at the FBI
I know FBI Special Agents in their good
dedicated smart people who are trapped
in a really rotten system
if you look at Special Agent rallies
testimony
she's got shitty management should the
data processing
arm shitty relations with the CIA
the whole systems broke it you know and
and so
if you want to talk about a conspiracy I
will talk about a conspiracy of
inattentive Publix in an attempt to
politicians
and intelligence professionals who
haven't been willing to speak up there
were 15 books
by intelligence practitioner authors
published in the two years prior to 9/11
that's unheard of
number of books all of them advocating
jerk on Intelligence Reform
and nobody prior to 9/11 wanted to
listen to me or anybody else
very quickly well basically I just wanna
one you thirty-seconds government night
just you don't feel comfortable I making
authoritative statement about the
technical details
involving the airplane honey I would be
willing to believe that dick cheney
incall roles
understood that Franklin eleanor
roosevelt won at Pearl Harbor to happen
in order to be able to mobilize America
and I would be willing to to believe
that dick cheney in car rolls if they
had some inkling of 9/11
would have downplayed in order to allow
it to happen and don't think this is
unusual
Jim Bamford and the puzzle palace wrote
how the JCS the Joint Chiefs of Staff
proposed a covert operation to kill
Americans on American soil
are in order to justify an attack on
cuba
do not underestimate the idiocy
of people in power but on balance
I think 9/11 was a catalog error
spanning multiple years
all of which can be traced back to are a
combination of political
irresponsibility and professional
incompetence
across the board okay
next I was on a review if you could tell
something about numbers stations
number stations yeah
no I what I can tell you is that I have
to go to the bathroom
I
are just recycle
I right one quick question and then I'm
gonna go to the bathroom will take up
ten minute break in
but I'll continue with whoever wants to
survive and if I can ask the staff to
supervise the Pens
for 10 to 15 minutes any %uh view that
haven't gotten a piano repeaters are
taking your photo every single one again
on
K I'll this might be a dangerous
question however
let's say you were a terrorist
organization planning United States
what would you attack and more to the
point how would you
as the United States defend against
that's where schoolkids
and shopping malls across america i'd
I'd from it by scaring the crap out of
every single parent okay
are tom ridge hasn't done it RC week
week we cannot do top-down protection
we have to do bottom-up protection arm
for example I was asked to review the
Marine Corps counterintelligence a
counter-terrorism plan
up by Colonel that that respected my
work
and I said Tom all you've done is triple
the guards and double the cement
I said that's not how you defend
insulation what you have to do
is have an eight hundred-number or and a
website URL I said you have to go up
fifty kilometers
around your perimeter and you have to
brief every waitress in every truck
driver
and every rental car guy and every hotel
motel clerk
whatever and you have to tell them what
you worried about what you're looking
for
and then when they call you shouldn't
hang up on okay so that's kinda pushing
out this concept of neighborhood watch
which is a perfectly legitimate
voluntary concept is not
about total awareness and and peeping I
am by the way in Iraq
we're jailing and killing people who are
being declared as terrorists and
criminals
by jilted lovers and people who want to
get out of debt the same thing that
happened with the Phoenix program
in vietnam we are naive arm
I don't believe that we are any safer
from the Homeland Security expenditures
on first responders
it doesn't help us do preventive
counterintelligence
inside America given that I've said
we've already got a thousand sleeper
agents inside America
are and second everything we're doing
our foreign policy
is essentially aiding and abetting been
lot george bush
is a bin Laden wet dream for sure
sorta by quick all the
information that this would generate for
all the all the calls it you're gonna
get
deluge nation is the answer sorting
through this information more money
or what is the answer to sort through
mindset we've got plenty money in
america
I'm gonna go to the bathroom I will be
back in 10 minutes
and if the staff can tryin makes sense
in these pants please i ask you to be on
your honor
not come another pan if you've already
got