completely different topic lockpicking
there will be an ongoing lockpick
demonstration and training downstairs I
don't know how to call that floor I
think gorby your
affluent okay the the second floor a.m.
so I will be here one hour of two deuces
over
so at two o'clock from 225 I will be
downstairs
and people can play would lock screen
pick locks but it's completely different
subject but
seems that many people are interested in
that so
I just had that mention a.m. also
there's a special picture made for this
conference that's available only in a
very limited edition
and it will be sold I think one hour
after the show
where they sell the t-shirts so if
you're interested in that
it's going to be 25 dollars but
depicts a really excellent I tested them
and it's it's really become a very nice
at its
am hmmm this is not the look picking Ben
Leah
I could her tried to grab one out of
mind
well anyway I think just just go check
here where they sell t-shirts 15 minutes
20 minutes after stock
and they will be for sale there but as I
said is going to be very limited edition
so
grab it fast if you're interested in it
because they will probably be sold out
pretty quick I don't think that will
make it with the supply we got till
before tomorrow before to look back
panel but
we'll see what happens but definitely
after dats
over after this it will be gone that's
for sure
okay where are you at it's a it's
also I'm very happy to see so many of
you because
on the other side pollution Irish
talking known go
but Bruce Schneier stalking and I really
expected it to be much less crowded as
it is now but I'm really thrilled to see
so many people interested in this
interesting topic a.m.
and and I going to cover the the radio
spectrum that sexually
what it's about and and what's there and
what you can do with it some
some things you can do with it are quite
amusing government is trying to encrypt
more and more
their signals so there's much less
interesting stuff for us
but still that there's many interesting
things to be found and even when
encryption is used on the signals still
some intelligence can be gathered
from that and I hope we can we
we can show you will cover a whole range
from
normal scanners leadership thing
yes give them an applause finally made
it
okay
position yes
yeah we had some problems copying files
from my
to its machine because that's the one
that's gonna be playing
some captures that I made in the
Netherlands and in Europe
some interesting signals I think you'll
find
hopefully highly amusing problem is of
course that the a lot of the interesting
stuff I kept it is in Dutch so it
doesn't mean anything
do you so therefore I made a selection
of some of the encrypt it signals and
we'll explain
how do you Krypton is done if you have a
chance for bypassing it or not
and and Anna brought some some video
clips
our police helicopter in Amsterdam EC's
transmitting
actually it's for internal use boats
if you have the right receiver it's a
nice broadcaster she was going on
in in that area and this does a smiley
interesting and entertaining video clips
but he said
is it working okay I am it's very told
you I'm sorry in Leawood
as I said technical issues on the
there's something called the
electromagnetic spectrum that I don't
know how many people here familiar with
its its makeup but there's a
there's a
broad spectrum of what we call bandwidth
but it's floating around in the air
everywhere from DC are very low cycles
per second
up to microwave in like frequencies and
we're talking about hundreds gigahertz a
band with
and there's a lot of low around there
live in his
easily intercepted Andy modulated in
either analog or digital modes
and I we want to show you some these
interesting signals that are floating
around what's out there
am well can be modulated what can be
what can be learned from things that you
can to modulate pictures from doing
traffic analysis as sorting
so our we're gonna show you our I what
looks like a time line really
but it's a a a graph showing
the US frequency allocations
and use a different somewhat in
different countries so what applies here
%ah are FCC equivalent in
benevolence may not necessarily show
show the same so
for instance a police frequencies that
Dutch police may use
will be used by maybe a television
station in this country so I'm gonna
switch over to
the spectrum see
can we get a
switch
resource
thinking video here now
wrong one special app
media a little later
used spectrum of the US alright in this
country the FCC
and certain other aspect to the federal
government here dictate
what goes where and I recommend you do a
you do a search for this if you're
interested just Goa go online to a
search for a
I US frequency allocations
or spectrum chart and you'll find it's
really big PDF honest
blow it up here and Jason details what
where
I can you read as I can see from here
okay
I am right to
right here you're seeing a megahertz
frequencies I
for instance a you have a TV
broadcasting in this country from 614
megahertz up to 698 megahertz
I you have cellular telephone
frequencies
right up here and
further down we
navigate around here bit
we have lower frequencies these are
international sure way frequencies
anywhere from say a %ah 2 230 megahertz
there's a lot of interesting up
international programming floating
around you can
listen to that on a regular shortwave
radio unit 50 get for fifty hundred
dollars
arm there's a above that you have the
VHF I which is about 30 to 300 megahertz
that has FM and TV broadcasts channel
maybe 213 in this country
option aircraft medications I
the federal government uses a lot of
frequencies in a VHF frequency range at
federal law enforcing agencies typically
in 160 170 megahertz region
secret service FBI DEA some analog some
digital some created
and like stuff you can hear and clear
above that you have UHF which is 303
3,000 megahertz or three get hurt if I
caught that those are would be your UHF
TV frequencies such an awesome 1369
I cellular and PCS a cellular
is usually in the 800 megahertz range
and PCS frequencies in the 1900
megahertz range
at GPS status GPS satellite navigation
devices
%ah there in that range was called the
l-band around 1.5 gigahertz your fifteen
hundred megahertz
microwave ovens wifi around 2.4
gigahertz
and wanna things are gonna talk about is
a microwave video surveillance
signals R&L band also which is around
1.5 gigahertz give or take a few hundred
megahertz
about that you got really high
frequencies about 3 3 gigahertz
up to several hundred gigahertz some
satellite TV stuff is in there
for gigahertz up to what's what's a KU
bencher cape and like 12 gigahertz arms
likely get DirecTV receiver that about
12,000 megahertz
up your satellite found sheehy reporters
in Iraq is over the asians at like fans
they're up in that rain shower lot a
military intelligence satellites
very hi several hundred gigahertz radar
I'll let defense military stuff in a
really high ranges
on a show of you example devices that
can be used to
airship somebody signals
okay a.m. what one other interesting
things
s as a radio spotter as you think we
we might be called is that I'm always
watching
at antennas on rooftops on cars on
us on CB radios or on two-way radios
and always trying to estimate what's the
frequency of that
and at one moment sure you're getting
really good at it because all these
manufacturers
they also make it more or less clear
that thats what type of antenna as usual
time
band and I'm I'm always interested in
if I see somebody walking around with a
radio two-way radio I think what
frequency could it be on
now the most excellent tool to
to find that out is what it has got here
it's an
optoelectronic scouts and s the name
mentions
it captures frequencies and what it does
is
it sweeps an entire band and if
I'll signal is above a certain level it
will display the frequency of that
which is really nice feature and also
the Scout can
memorize 400 different frequencies so
you can
stick it in your bag and and walk around
in an area and it might be
secured or whatever and you're
interested to listen to dis
communication
but if you're walking around there with
your scouts people Wednesday
what's going on but you can just carry
it under your pillow
and
you know look look at what's being
captured later
and also the nice thing is that you see
the frequency dats
capture but also the amount of times
it was captured which which also is a
nice features you only have one
if you see that a certain frequencies
only done one is probably a taxi driving
by life you
she people talking for 10 minutes and
you're standing next to them
you should have at least 50 Council that
same frequency
now at edges did is he triggered device
with his two way radio I don't know if
you can see
the oh yes you concede this is a is it
on the radio is the organizer using at
the conference
and they're just a few what's on UHF
frequencies we chose these frequencies
because they're at a ranger some of the
year
two-way radios that day amateur radio
operators can use which can be easily
modified operate at a frequency so we
chose as frequencies
said the latter range modified radius
and change another channel here
and key at the mike you can see the
are grafted bottom shows your signal
strength I'm broadcasting
raising a low free low train no signal
level now
and this thing will be Taylor you that
it's
its grab the frequency waiting 25
rematch if you're walking around
miss even get the beep a go
I'm we can put in vibrate mode so you
can just have it in your
in your coat and if you feel a vibrating
you can look at it discreetly in
see this transmitting near you now I
leave this thing on my ass all the time
on the windowsill
and it has a locking feature see if I
can a
Shea some frequencies lot on
see I have a special mound for this in
my car so when I'm driving in my car
it it also records frequencies of things
around me
which can be pager systems cell towers
whatever
but also nap sometime undercover police
car
dats is maybe following a suspect you
capture a lot of
very very interesting frequencies with
this thing and you can add MRR
are not interesting but you can find
frequencies that normally
nobody would ever find out because it's
either a band like it is doing now
I mean when I look at as radio I would
have figured it would be somewhere
between
440 and 470 but he was clever enough to
June it all the way up to four and in
ninety
a and if I wouldn't have a scout I would
never searched
their I don't think so at least well
yeah wouldn't wanna things very I do is
look at
we look at antennas you can judge for
the antenna generally what frequency
range
your your target is a is transmitting on
if you see someone to a radio
on and you wanna listen with their
they're talking about whether
whether I commercial amatuer
government whatever on if you have one
of these things you can
you can galley grab the frequency the
transmitting at and plug it into a
receiver and listen to it
if it indeed if digital transmission I
you need special
even more specialized equipment but on
this also logs frequencies and allows
you to download them
she can do some frequency analysis so
after a few weeks in this sitting on my
%ah I'll windowsill I could see that
um cordless phones
I am see %ah
that a taxicab frequency this is a
cellular
I secular found was nearby
these are visionaries misery said the
other day better
I didn't alice is a few months ago after
monitoring for about a month
an there something like a two or three
hundred at Philadelphia Police
a transmissions that were within a
couple blocks my house I picked up
things that are very close by which is
good you don't want to pick up sup
miles away cuz it be just too much
information I there is a
to FBI frequencies on lotta police
a political service frequencies and what
they're doing in my house
on alotta taxicabs
I miscible government on Family Radio
Service
I you know the SEL cheap two-way radios
you can buy their UHF
so anyway this allows you to see what's
being used around you
and you can program these frequencies
into a scanner or
I love scanners radio receivers you can
plug a cable directly
between this counter and that and he was
called reaction tuning so will actually
turn the radio
to the treatment she she can hear what's
going on in real time which is
a real pleasure personally I don't have
that because I don't like defector
it also choose to signals that I already
know I bogus
like better systems or FM radio stations
animal driving around and hearing all
these
signals that I'm not interesting in so
I've become very fast at
entering a frequency while driving and
maybe on the phone
but still still get it okay and and
I'm not as fast as the cable but it is
is close close
is a nice example of for beautiful small
receiver
dishes th right I it's actually a yeah
Thur
the R five hundred take case your GT
there
again
on that happens to be a sure way
frequency
that off the hook broadcast on simulcast
see
in here off the hook North and South
America on this frequency 7415
killers but on you can a
you can program any frequency into this
thing from from very low up to thirteen
hundred megahertz which covers a lot of
different users and it's very small
smaller than a pack of cigarettes
and you can keep in your pocket and a
live in FM but really I them
radio broadcast as well and runs out of
normal better couple a double A
batteries and it's very
very efficient power wise to a dozen a
doesn't rain a lot of her
power yet it's that's what I like in a
receiver that your
able to always did that you need to
change a battery pack
you can just pop in a few batteries
because it just happens that the most
interesting things
you better is empty at the time so I
really like getting a receiver
this is urs %ah as single-use
to receive nada not many different bands
on this but it
it's a shortwave receiver you can buy
these
at Radio Shack or other stores they said
there's a lot of signals
between a three in 30 megahertz she gets
more like here now
but these disciples radios are also
used by spy agencies and
you think twice by agencies since the
internets
there's been less and less of these
around but there are
on on shortwave there are stations very
high power stations
that only broadcast numbers and very
short
messages to don't seem to mean anything
but these are actually codes for
undercover people in the field or or
special agents in foreign countries
they don't wanna pick up the phone and
say hey you know I've accomplished
something or
where you have to go to today these are
prearranged
coach that are set and I hope that it
can play
sales are ideal rate you're doing it's
yeah I did a small one-time pad stats
that indeed correct it's it's
cryptographically secure
that you just prearranged a random
string and then
know if you can you can just plug it in
just
this is getting less
now it is going to try to find some of
the samples made of these
shortwave transmissions but some people
actually monitor all these messages even
though they don't seem to mean much
some of it of course is just filling up
space so people cannot by traffic
analysis see
when things are getting really
interesting so the broadcast at the
several in 24
or a certain interval I'm gonna play you
a a Cuban spy transmission
the a cuban intelligence agencies are
notorious for using this method is
transmitting
encoded messages one-time
you lucky that one time he's and a
this is a this one you can pick up very
easily %uh next
I
feel 50 full
better be at the hero
it be maybe been it
theme
I your 50
way baby call Peter
pretty K that's a cubans
I here's a MI six British intelligence
on
is kind of interesting will turn the
broadcast before this to their field
operators can
can recognize that this is the signal is
intended for them on
ended the chain is an all-british folk
song called the latent Lincoln Shire
poacher and after after the a-ten
you'll hear some coded messages
the the fun it's really kinda boring to
listen to but it's
what's interesting is a you can use in
traffic analysis on these and they found
the to
occasionally a there's there's an
increase in
in the level traffic in these
transmissions up
just before or during major
international incidents
on for instance at the MI six
frequencies are a little more active
I'll this before the the go for invasion
this is a
next on a place them aside Israeli
intelligence
ass you could hear you you can help ease
yourself
all right here if you don't have to
share my radio
made in Mexico DX trainers got and
activators but it's a couple shoppers
you control right
for free
ass
desist letters and numbers
yeah dark wanna play this one now which
is
my favorites we nicknamed her Cynthia
because she has a letters in her name
see II
a the
there where r
or there are 0
there are
uses your tax dollars at work tomorrow
monitor along here there
you had the you're also a these are
aren't not all of the year country to do
this
doesn't the countries around the world
and I really found it this is the most
effective way
to get messages to the field operatives
on you could have killer Robert feel
operatives out there with a really
compact devices that had a satellite
receiver to receive digital messages
but you know what other way to to like
blow your cover them to be caught hold
one of these things
in in motion the world have English a
portal shortwave radio is
is the normal thing the everybody has a
radius are we waiting for listening to
news in this country people always
ensure we very much been rushed the
world that's the normal
there stayed on most people in the world
get their news and information
entertainment over shortwave radio now
this country but so
never country and if you have any sense
it's not a big deal so it doesn't blow
your cover
you enter america yeah exactly but on
you can get is pretty regularly on a lot
over shortwave receiver here's another
one
okay there's another I've receiver
on you can't buy this receiver in this
country this is actually the control
head
for a a for Sony shortwave receiver
which air
I ordered from a the United Arab
Emirates Dubai
on several 2600 staffers had this radio
in the car
suck up a hundred dollars at included
the shipping on
its regular am/fm cassette stereo like
20 watts per channel for your car but it
also receives all im
international sure way bans so it's
kinda like heaven XMR
or Sirius Satellite Radio om as far as
diversity programming available
in your car behind to pay a subscription
fee and you can even listen to
spy numbers transmissions if you're so
inclined are you driving around late at
night
here's another receiver
that a that has unique feature that
it receives a video transmissions not
just a TV
but a not just broadcast television but
television
that could originate from my I covert
spy cameras the UC see around
love his cock damages your router wired
but some of them are wireless
and mary has an interesting examples
over
wireless video from outlets but Dutch
police helicopters
yes correct we could go into that
the only thing I want to say about this
icon receiver is that it doesn't work
well
on 2400 megahertz band 24 megahertz band
probably rings a bell because it's the
same band were able to 11 is
it's a band open for a lot of
usages and dams and police has been
using it for many years to transmit
their video down
from the helicopter to base where day
coordinates shortened
activities very insensitive it's not
very sensitive receiver
if you have a preamplifier and an
external antenna
on you can do a little bit better but
this is really designed for a
arm really weak signals like from a
thats police helicopter
well your not gonna receive it here
anyway know but but
if you if you're interested in in
receiving
them
digital cameras in 2.4 gigahertz known
by dish receiver because it just doesn't
work
I'm not sure if there is a handheld
receiver did us a better job in
on there isn't yet you think there would
be but it's just an upmarket I think you
need specialized equipment its
few thousand dollars generated to do
that sort of thing now
I i jus border separate receiver at
radio flea market
for I think 150 dollars but it's been
definitely
worth the money of course when you buy
such a thing
when you buy receiver the police doesn't
work a lot with these
helicopters maybe in the Netherlands to
do it ten times a year
eight times a year so you buy this
receiver and to just waiting and waiting
and waiting
and watch in New Jersey you know there
was something with a police helicopter
and then I miss it because I was at work
so a but the the first video I captured
actually was like personally like like a
wet dream you know did you
turn on your thing and and and and
images you see
really is really really cool I hope I
can
share it with you now but what what I
heard was that there were some
ask what the riots that some squatters
courthouses
and the police was we're going to force
them out
and the circumstance Qantas you know
that they don't like that so
the day fight to police and one of the
tactics they use is that they climb on
the roof
and throw stuff down most the time it's
not heavy stuff it's not
tables and stuff there pretty pretty
nice guys
but but but they throw paints and what
you going to see here is a small battle
between the Dutch dams and police I was
a water cannon trying to blow these
people of
the no really and these people trying to
blind
the want to throwing device with paint
and diz what you're going to see I'll
Lexmark after
okay talk about the other
the other me job and there's also
another video data showed
later after dirt's
that is from an anti-war
demonstration the
American consulate in Amsterdam there
was going to be big
anti Iraq war demonstration showed a
food a large amount of red containers
arounds that building to make sure that
nobody would get
even close to it and yeah people came to
these containers and
just protest and at the ends
some riots broke out and some stones
were being thrown to the police in
stuff like that and then what I hope to
show you later on
if its computer works
is how'd I don't know how you call it in
English
SWAT team okay did a SWAT team
they have special small units did go
into the field into these
and a target to certain individual you
know they say
get the guy with red trousers or
whatever and then day
will arrest him grab him and
drag him into a policemen in a secure
area
and and it's all being taped by this
police helicopters I'm just sitting at
home you know
having this premium channel the now it's
it's really is very very nice
a.m. and I hope I can share it with you
keep talking your
come on a.m. yeah
now we're just just have to wait said
yeah okay and another topic that and I a
very interesting
is once you get to know to spectrum you
also see
blind spots you she spots that are
supposedly
unused or unmarked or you know people
say well there's nothing to see in this
part of the spectrum just
you know keep on walking nothing to see
here discourse the most interesting
and most the time you will find its
okay don't have come
but but but I'm not talking about
finding bugging devices
it's it's one of the things that is
logical once you know the spectrum I
want you know how to find receivers
a.m. that you will be able to find
hidden transmitters
even if they're small and low powered
its interesting to find out
where are people hiding in what part
frequency spectrum people hiding these
devices
and what type of people are dead of
course the criminals and people who
don't trust their wives
but also the government's they also use
bugging
I think in the states to use much
Morrison in Europe although in the
Netherlands
laws have been passed in in the
law enforcement is allowed now to to
book your house and to pack your bedroom
in
it's it's yeah it's not getting pretty
some books already have been found in
the Netherlands
they operate around 850 megahertz in
spread spectrum modulation which means
that
with the normal receiver you will not
find it means that over a large amount
of frequencies
the signal ish smear doubts and it's
it's
yeah it's very difficult to to find
these kind of transmitters
at this got a very beautiful device
would spectrum analyzer
that we will demonstrate little later on
and it will actually show you
in real time what's going on in a
certain area frequency band them
squatters
it's not ans is not on screen i think im
source
ok
issue
but it's not showing
we don't see the image its in the the
box
missions
anybody with some knowledge about video
assistant
bear with us bear with us
yeah or something okay X displaced
screen
okay what you see here is
the video helicopter a and its
did this this is actually the first
image it I ever saw
so I was you know tuning it and then
finding it and then I heard
on scanner I heard some people say your
move a little bit too dry to dry just go
to that
area there and you actually see
somebody on the roof drawing small
pellets of pain
in in in in in a little while there
there there we go
a.m. and there's yeah
no but really this this this is
so rewarding that the do did you get
this device
and then all of a sudden you know you
see this and I i had the biggest smile
on my face
since a long time that lineup and and
and and the funny thing is
that the
the funny thing is is that is the the
the water is slow so this guy sees it
coming and unjust then there's ducks
oh you had record ok
go back fullscreen here you can actually
on the top corner now you can see the
car throwing the
the the water to this guy I okay
this
I'm okay so that that that that was
throwing the water
a.m. here you can see the helicopter
that actually was a part of the
helicopter
flying into 22 damn samaria sorry bout
the encoding of the video its
it's not very welcome
them but you can actually see it fly
over Amsterdam
then it's getting its direction that
people say you know zoom into that in
that area
so it's going to look where am i exactly
and then go into this area where did the
consulate is
know you can see the red containers in
in a line
thing its Hui cedars human capabilities
of this
camera I mean just you know just a few
seconds before
we had a big part of Amsterdam but now
and and what you will see now is that
they will put an extra lense
in front of the camera so you will see
blur for second
and now it's huge in even closer
and and they can release you mean to
to yeah videos hang
slow
I'm afraid we're facing a blue screen of
death
okay
a.m. okay
thing is a.m. I i feel bad about this so
if people want to see the clip date they
can get a copy from me just
all put a CD here and if you see me
walking around to make a few CDs and and
put
material on and feel free to distributed
I mean has been broadcast that so I
don't feel
okay
the actually I'm not sure if it's legal
to record it so I'm
well
the there actually is a radio emitter by
the name of
for scaling-up who was a Dutch guy
whose recording all this he says that
you know it's an open band
and he's a radio ham hamintor and
therefore he's allowed to record it and
he makes
all the samples available on the website
so check on
on the website for or take on Google at
zulu
double 0 a and Selinger and and you will
find a whole lot of
of Dutch police
camera that that that that he recorded
and you can download Eclipse
as you see them you but I i would like
to give it another try
if possible okay we could try my
guns
well I i don't have the weapon this but
it's
saludable 0 zulu 00 that's the call sign
of
the helicopter and the guys name is
Selinger
or livingstone i think is his name yeah
if you and a police helicopter
shoe you will definitely fines
gonna see if my laptop does a better job
of playing these
video files for you anyway now it's your
turn
later
what we're looking at here is a year are
receiving station where
this the transmissions we're just
looking at could be received from
are typically a finest tops have some
government buildings
on this was a supply by manufacturers
this equipment lotta times these
video surveillance sources on coming
from a helicopter for coming from a
fixed
a fixed place it could be hidden camera
on the high demand a lot of interesting
things now shows an example to that but
here's a
here's what on top a French answer a
federal on fortune building here in
here in the States is another at
picture a bit what's interesting is this
aside from different from this
and a satellite in tennis is not
pointing up in the air this is pointed
to
horizontally or sometimes in a downward
angle the target is now the picture from
the side
%ah this is a picture I took it a few
days ago in philadelphia
I miss him in on this this is the
federal a
Federal Building in philadelphia
and if you see in the top right here
that's a microwave video surveillance
I'll antenna and if you're on the ground
look up you can barely see this thing so
a this is pointed certified Northwest
so %ah the last time the fed in
philadelphia were using this thing
his picture they were monitoring had
been monitoring
video surveillance transmission in
Northwest Philadelphia summer
northwestern
just our site
at another shot
ground another shot at it and
sometimes these are hidden in a common
looking objects that you don't think
twice about seeing stays
sure you've all seen these
our company transformers %ah
sometimes used on me cans like this on
telephone poles
and I show you couple other examples
hidden platforms
the teaser these hidden
%ah things are and here's a
this is from a a law enforcement
conference
took some pictures at that a box it has
a disorder things is this box be mad on
utility pole
I am disagree box
and here you see a microwave antenna
similar WiFi antenna
there's a camera Anna high-power lands
in lands
here is a a a radio use to receive the
signals to control it remotely
I make a turn on/off I'm zoom in
sometimes point in different directions
there's another shot over
differ model and hear some more
interesting a
hidden closures this is one that used a
at hidden inside what looks like a blast
concrete cinder blocks
here's a you probably all seniors
pedestals word cable TV company your
phone company hasn't wanted these things
in someone's front lawn
well not necessarily is there a junction
box inside there could be one is
on these hidden cameras you can see the
air microwave antenna here for
transmitting a signal
signaled
maybe sure your show 1 more video that
was a
it was taken locally in Philadelphia
from a a see
these
here
okay ago
women
this was taken in South Philadelphia on
a loop this thinks it's not very long
this was taken from a utility pole
and it's a surveillance at the net an
organized crime
suspect and it's interesting you can see
when he leaves the year
when he leaves the building your is
looking a left and right
and all around to see if anybody's
watching him but in fact that he's not
looking up in the chilly palmer this
camera's
and this was a intercepted
mmm not too long ago in a in South
Philadelphia area
and this guy is in prison right now but
a
but a this was used as with a lot of
other evidence wiretaps and so forth to
work
to put together case against organized
crime people in philadelphia to
the signals are floating around you
don't realize that there's probably
active surveillance going on right here
right now in New York
on probably gonna be a lot going around
the RNC convention here coming up
and a lot of it is not DigiLink ripped
it because it's more complicated
do that and less reliable than discrete
and analog video and
receiver to pick the stuff up on
something go to Radio Shack and by
so on by let you know that this the
stuff's going on all the time
and have to be aware try to
good I'm me
with binoculars if you look very
carefully and some of these boxes on
polls
if you see a a small hole arm that could
be there
the lentil but frankly think they
conceal these pretty well so they're
hard to tell
I'm there's other types of equipment out
there on is a company called a
Wavecom that makes easy consumer video
link units
and that you can modify them %ah
otherwise issues jackie is very
specialized test equipment okay I'm
going to
keep it this mod because sometimes the
image freezes
and I manually have to drag it a little
bit for but as you can see here
Shino few of the area and 20
what you actually she here is
the van with undercover police
just targeting suspects
to all these people you see here are
actually police officers
and at this moment you know that just
watching the scene and pointing out
world is one guy might grab later on
and what they do indeed grab somebody is
actually quite interesting they target
him then they walk behind him
and for about 50 meters and then with a
team of
people they start running and when they
run
day grab day decrepit
suspect behind and drag him around but
you'll
she did happen later on a.m. here to
just zooming in on somebody who hasn't
done anything
anti obviously finds out that they're
watching him
and he s got a sign that says please
stop this
which is
which is rather funny but but but you
can see I mean this this is digitally
captured show the actual quality is is
even a little bit better
and you can definitely from this police
helicopter identified
people okay here we go the
some this is okay here here to bringing
in a
suspects you can see the middle of the
Scream
Dez on the cover the day catch someone
and they will
deliver him to one of these events she
will see
and a special knock on the door to open
it signaling
we're good guys open up and
and their egos and then you will see now
some police tactics on on the top of the
screen that the running here on on the
left of the screen
the running running in grabbing him did
it did you see I could go back
just get a running start so when they
grab them
you're done okay up unscreened ago
running running running for the guy with
the white-run bank and you really don't
stand a chance and
and this is actually quite interesting
to see all these police tactics
through their own eyes actually think
you guys a.m.
and and yeah it's it's but but
you know being able to see this is
really really interesting now damn some
police has bought
scrambler show they're scrambling a lot
of these video signals
I think our time is up but that will not
prevent me from
keeping this video playing so people can
see
just for a few more minutes while the
other person is setting up
stop the what you will also see
cock
just that there's one more as one more
coming up and as you will see one of
them will get away
and actually throw throw something away
the guy with brown
shirt here is going to throw something
away right now
la jolla a you know
so even even if they arrest him he
thinks that they didn't see that the
through something away a.m. the
other shot that you will see but I will
not be talking when you see it a
is when they switch through im to
infrared
these helicopter cameras also have
infrared on them
a.m. and they can select if something
did they go if something in white is
a is in hot object or if something in
black is an art object
us you can see now a.m. so I'm just
gonna let this play for for a few
seconds to a few minutes till its
those run out Chuck
yep