up next we have Paolo loose enter from
kpn we will talk about building traffic
matrix traffic matrices for supporting
during decisions Paolo
so good afternoon my name is Paolo
shonta and among the other things I'm
lead developer of the VMS ECT software
and this afternoon I would like to speak
to you about traffic matrixes and
expression in the context of peering
agenda for today a brief introduction a
couple of slides about PMS ECT and then
we will get into the details first of
all why is speaking about traffic
matrixes or rephrase it and trying to
waste your time today my answer would be
not of course I'm here so what else you
want to need to say and I think much
traffic matrixes are very useful to a
number of network operator activities
and for example capacity planning
traffic engineering better understanding
traffic patterns and of course hearing
and this is where we will be focusing
today still traffic matrixes are
important to a number of activities but
they keep behind the scenes topic like i
was browsing some archives and all i
could find is very few contributions and
most of them were formal contributions
and the others were saying about a
buddhist of traffic matrixes what you
can do with traffic matrixes a lot of
things very nice but i would like to say
with this contribution like where you
can what are the challenges and try to
answer the questions that you see over
here so with a very technical count so
back once again to square number one
building traffic matrix is preparing the
decisions what is needed what is our
shopping list it's a about bgp telemetry
data soil net flow as flour or similars
a collector infrastructure system
storage and of course maintenance and
the post-processing scripts while
supporting some operators worldwide
building traffic matrixes what I've
recognized is that the first challenge
is not a technical challenge its an
organizational challenge and yeah the
800-pound gorilla project because you
can already see that the shopping list
includes something very different things
and they may be in a larger organization
they can span across departments so you
can already see multiple people involved
different background may be a project
manager and things like that so I mean
that's the first thing to take into
account it's from an organizational
point of view maybe you have to gather
few heads together and that's not very
easy speaking about so let's start from
the tool what is a good enabler to build
a traffic matrix I'd say p.m. CT which
is open source free software p necessity
here very poor choice as a name it's an
ipv4 ipv6 accounting package and with
the nexus light it will become more
apparent maybe why I think it's a good
enabler for the task but essentially in
this slide you can see on one side
number of the traffic collection methods
solely pick up net flow as flow and
things like that on the other side you
have a common open source relational
databases but also memory tables emesis
it is me sitting in the middle it's not
just writing to the backend what it gets
from the network instead it also uses
offers some data reduction techniques
like a spatial and temporal aggregation
filtering and sampling or subsampling
and also tagging
Luke house one of those lookouts is of
course bgp what happened last year in
2009 is that MC city was just regular
net flow as flow collector yeah just
introducing things like writing to
database and Bob I mean regular
collector what happened is that it was
introduced the BGP demon within the
software has a parallel tried to the
collector so now you get to two parallel
threads one death telemetry data the
other gas and handles the BGP sessions
features of this bgp demon are it
behaves as a passive bgp demon a bit
passive busy being neighbors sorry and
that's also nice implication that we
will see in the next slide and the other
thing is that it it's a multi rate which
should be demon implementation so the
why is that because you want imagine you
will have a very big network and imagine
that you are appearing with the same
people yeah various part of the world so
you want to capture localized bgp
information you don't want to work out
any global best spot or anything like
that you want to capture capture all the
local information and look at look them
up so why introducing a bgp demon in a
net flores flow collector the idea the
vision if you want was that yeah
telemetry protocols should report on the
forwarding plane so should help the
accounting of data but telemetry should
not report on control plane information
they don't should not try to transfer
over and over the same information right
so that's that's what would happen if
you embed a lot of bgp information for
example in a net flow every micro flow
is attached by the same information it's
a much more optimal that you get your
collector
peirong will you be appearing with your
bruders so that you know the control
plane is there and it done afterwards
it's just keep alive right so get
approaching our shopping list that we
said before we said that one of the
things that we will need is getting vgp
to the collector so the advice would be
to get the collector to BG ppl with all
the P devices facing fierce transit and
customers know best spot computation I
mean that means that you have all the
BGP tables scalability is preferred to
memory usage and during the some
experiments I mean full bgp feed is
around 15 mags of memory that means that
if you want to yeah let the collector
pier with more than 75 bgp beers so more
than 75 Reuters you should take her into
consideration compiling it 64 bit
because you will get beyond the four gig
barrier just as a note here I mean there
is some tier 2 and the CDN scenarios
that have been taken care of and in
these scenarios there are 100 plus P
devices sending a full bgb table and I
mean two to 300 gigs of traffic sample
the not very highly and occupation of
the CPU was around five six percent on a
commodity intel dual core so i mean i
think there is a room to scale over here
the idea is that the collector should I
bgp beer with all the p devices best
configured as a route reflector client
and here it's the implication of that i
was speaking about about the passive
digit being able a nice implication is
that because you get all
is an open message from your router from
your Reuters essentially you can see
what is the remote AES and you can
always reply with the debt the same
remote a yes to each of your Reuters so
that means that a single collector can I
bgp peer across sub is boundaries or
across a s boundaries if your routine
domain is spanning across multiple
iesous the most important thing when
building a traffic matrix in relation to
be GD is that the next stop has to
represent that the so-called remote edge
of the network right so we you need to
know where traffic is getting out of
your network this is a yeah very typical
scenario for many MPLS Network not all
but I mean a very classic side of the
scenario but of course there might be
some corner cases or some cases that
might require some more smart thinking
in this sense and which is a yeah pop by
uprooting vgp Confederations or maybe a
large amount of Reuters with default
gateway or partial routes what happens
is that in these cases you the beeping X
top that you see at the router where the
flow is entering your network is not
necessarily where the it will exit your
network and so in that case you can
follow up remember that you have a
multi-bit multirate implementation so
you can jump from where it to the other
until you reach the remote edge of your
mat and then switch into a telemetry
data so Annette Flores flow the smart
thing is to export once again from all
the be Reuters facing Pierce chance and
customers but ingress only measurements
I mean why is that because traffic
routed to destination so plenty of
information where traffic is going
and that's enough but instead it's
crucial to understand where traffic is
coming from especially if you are
interested in to who is injecting
traffic into your routing domain and in
this sense if you do ingress measurement
at the Pease what you have is for sure
okay that input interface but if the
protocol allows for that and
implementation of that protocol allows
for that you might also have the source
MAC address which is very handy for when
your period public is changes so when
you have cases in which you have one
interface and multiple neighbors off of
it and of course a net flow or s flow
can implementation can ya give some data
data reduction techniques available at
the p for example sampling no problem
with that dritz also sometimes available
aggregation and that is also fine you
can strip off things that are not
required at the p but be sure that you
carry a IP prefixes source and
destination IP prefixes and why is that
because still you can ya doing a lot of
bgb but still you can be landing part of
your IP address space to customers or to
other people and in that case of course
if you are aggregating and removing also
the IP prefixes then you don't know
anymore yeah where traffic is coming
from or going to or very rough
indication of that about the telemetry
export I can see ya a few scenarios over
here first of all let me be realistic I
mean I'm myself a developer of telemetry
collector and my personal opinion is
that there is not a single collector
that fits all the bill and yeah and i
think that the toolbox in this sense can
be extended to a to some tools let's say
ankles and
in this sense I mean what I can see is
that yeah you can export the telemetry
to old young collectors from your
Reuters you can involve multicast it's
always elegant and neat and nice and
smart or you can also resource to a mood
to a duel tire sort of solution so you
can perform the export to some
replicators let's say to replicators
mastering as 10 master in standby
fashion with a heartbeat protocol
running between them and then they will
find out the data to the collectors and
in this sense I mean on one side there
is a things like flexible net flow which
are which is rapidly picking up which is
very nice to see but this is not a very
wide deployed at the moment so it's
crucial that collectors can discriminate
the traffic because what can happen is
that a trafficker that you are sending
is not for all the collectors so very
important that for collector developers
and to capture with the yeah with a
workflow the telemetry data bgp
correlation we have a workflow in four
steps let's say that when everything is
done from the perspective of the Orange
Bowl which is the observer the routine
domain and stuck number one would be
that all the PE routers send be cheap
food bgp tables to the collector and the
step number two would be that there is
some traffic flowing through and that
triggers step number three which is yes
sending the telemetry data to the
collector step number four is looking at
this allometry data into the collector
to see if there is a corresponding bgp
table where yeah pgp data control plane
information can be look it up against in
the most simple scenario most basic
scenario this is though just by
comparing the source IP address of the
for example netflow agent and the source
of the address
the bgp beer of course i mean all sort
of mapping is possible in this Suns
getting to the storing a part of data I
mean things it would be it is wise to
agree to employee aggregation right and
aggregate both spatially and a temper
and the temporal dimension before
writing things down so what I'm saying
is it's not always the optimal solution
if you are not doing security or
forensics for example it's not wise to
log to the disk every micro flow or
every sample that you received from the
network and so I mean by aggregating you
make an optimal usage of system
resources and you expect and when you
are building rapport you're avoiding
expensive consolidation of the micro
information assumption and it is very
suitable for project driven deficits
what I mean by this is that I mean you
build data set which are good for a
project for a task or for a small set of
tasks and then of course if you have
something different like you have to do
billing still with net lower as flow and
things like that then you build a
different data set maybe also with a
different tool and that way yes you
waste a little bit more space because
you're building several data sets but
then you have a very you know tighten up
sort of system for all your needs open
source relational databases appearing
natural choice for the task right they
are able to handle very large data sets
by themselves they have a flexible and
standardized query language so mu need
the for a developer of a collector to
reinvent the wheel and one very
important point is that yeah the offers
solid and evolving storage and indexing
engines so once again there's no need to
invent the wheel once again and yeah
that is a debt all sorts to the
scalability because essentially if you
use relational
database you can always employ
clustering or partition once again both
in spatial and temporal dimensions just
to touch a little bit ground this is a
bit of an ass SQL schema don't take it
too seriously I mean don't have an art
attack because of SQL at nanog but this
is just give you an idea right this is
how your data would look like once on
the disk like a tag because it's always
nice to target things bgp primitives
counters and the time reference and of
course this is an example only because
you can always freely mix and match bgp
primitives with the layer one layer 7
remedies that's processing a few
examples like just to let you see how
simple is to retrieve data out of out of
a relational database and what you can
do with it for example you can see very
easily traffic deliberate to a pier per
location because you are appealing with
the same people in multiple locations or
maybe you want to see / location maybe
not all opportunities are available and
then there is a nice example aggregator
yes parts to the second hop imagine that
you are a CDN or you are a tier 2
provider and you are buying IP transit
from somebody and of course the first
thing you want to do is that yeah your
IP transit provider is never a friend it
carves money out of your pocket and they
are bad bad guys so yeah so essentially
yeah what you try to do is yet to
aggregator yes up to the second hole so
you try to see right the common
denominator right after your IP transit
provider who you can peer with and gets
the most of your destination of the
traffic instead of trying with the
appealing with everybody which maybe
it's not always an option and then it's
also very easy to focus yeah
on peak our data for example you want to
see for the last month every time what
happens at 8pm right you can do that
very easy you can do every sort of top
hang yes statistics for example here
there is an example of grouping bgp
pairs of the same kind for example using
the local preference to do that order
three but traffic matrix are a subset of
it purpose being maybe you want to
inject data into a 30 party tool it's a
nice to play with the traffic matrixes
like in the last like I show you in the
last couple of slides but it's always
nice to be able to inject data into
third party application so if you can
integrate the tool that does that
produces you the traffic matrix so if
you can do that with the 30 party tools
you can have some very interesting
things for example you can integrate
that traffic matrix into traffic
planning and traffic engineering the
application like the carry than one and
what happens is that besides playing
with the traffic matrix you can also
play with the what-if scenarios which is
also very interesting what harridan says
about integration of a net flow or as
flow-based traffic matrix with the
traffic planning application it's very
interesting what they say is that
essentially yeah interface statistics
are always the gold standard and that's
because it's what you base everything in
your network like traffic engineering
but also policies and things like that
on the other side I mean net flow or as
flow they are a very commonly sampled
and so they will never have
there will never be very precise there
there will be always an error so what
happens is that you can use interfaces
statistics as scaling factor as a span
fancy scaling factor for your net flow
or as flow traffic matrix information I
this is a very interesting topic but I
felt to put a pointer to a previous non
presentation about this because you can
spend another half an hour just delving
into the topic so essentially interface
counters are the most reliable source of
information and that means that you can
collect net lower as flow as convenient
so it means that you can do a sort of
best effort try best effort to talk over
yeah your network with the traffic
matrix so you can just have a subset of
the Pops or subset of the Reuters
coverage or use some more spare sampling
that's because you have still your
interface counters and then use a
regression method like the one that we
said before like the carrot angle demand
deduction or similar I mean there are
also other applications out there doing
the same last topic for today
scalability because I mean it's true
that yeah you can scale it up very well
because you don't do a very fancy thing
in within the collector but still at
some stage you will hit a barrier that
can be memory so you can store all EGP
food routing tables into a single box or
CPU because you have so mad so yeah you
because you have a lot of telemetry data
so davida et impera approach is very
valid so you can assign he still
coupling telemetry and bgp never have to
decouple them so you can assign these
two collectors and in turn you can
assign collectors to databases or you
can clock
the database itself tricky scenario in
this sense is when there are be tipping
except followers because of course
imagine that you are splitting things
among multiple boxes then it can end up
that you want to follow up the next stop
and the neck and the bitch beer above
that neighbor is on another box so you
can either have or gateways or route
reflectors peel with all collectors or
put all the eggs in one basket or do
some bgp pierre mapping because that is
also some valid approach intuitively the
matrix can become quite big and of
course some data reduction techniques
can be used at this for this purpose so
you can keep smaller Reuters out of the
equation but it orbs in specific pops
out of the equation because they are
negligible to the traffic matrix
essentially the whole purpose of the
tank is stripping out negligible and it
is to read us in this to reduce
dispersion while still keeping a very
good overall picture so you can also
filter out the specific class of
customers maybe you are a very collapse
of network so you are already running up
everything out of very big boxes and but
for example you can steal us throughout
serial customer or things like that and
then you can also sleep down things
which are not essential to your specific
scenario for example you are CDN you are
very interested in yeah in upstream
traffic but not very interested in to
downstream and the vice versa is true
for an ISP you want to know where
traffic is coming from and not really
very interested where you are sending
traffic to maybe of course you can also
in yet do some more spares sampling or
yeah put thresholds on traffic relevance
and then let's not forget a project
driven data set because somebody can say
a but if I use the
approach so a traffic matrix for
building security whatever well you are
saying that it won't scale at some stage
yeah that is a wrong sort of
consideration because if you are trying
to do something different maybe you
would aggregate the data different you
would not use the traffic matrix in the
first place and to conclude my
penultimate it slide it's just to give
some further yeah some pointers because
essentially because just because of time
constraints we can't approach all the
topics so there are so many topics yet
to be a project like yeah yes Petraeus
communities filter automatic routing
that is very important one but also
entities on the provider IP address
space so you can look up a previous
presentation down at the UK off 14 and
of course you have also other yet
pointers for examples or implementation
roles thanks very much for your
attention any questions
good thank you something section