I
while those of you who are with us in
heard a very interesting talk on all the
difficulties of implementing the
internet on the island of Haiti after
that presentation the Dominican Republic
things in Haiti actually got a good deal
worse with a huge earthquake which I'm
sure you're all very aware of and so now
we're going to hear a little bit about
the current state of the Internet in
Haiti we have a panel here see we have
I'm going to horribly which of these
names i do do apologize but we have
Reynold gori a yes I was the least close
um here and he's going to be chairing
this panel and i have several people
here on the panel of well at least two
other people on the panel we're short
one is he not going to be there not here
ok we have a slightly reduced size panel
here
good morning everyone um we were
supposed to be four on this panel
unfortunately the others they couldn't
make the trip to San Francisco for
personal reasons just before on before
starting I would like to take David
mayor for his invitation to present this
panel and for his report to unload this
trip here I will be talking about the XP
the internet exchange point we just
launched in Haiti last year it was in
may and or this or it's it react during
the earthquake and right after that mr.
max loss on my colleague will be
presenting the state of the status of
the nick got HD the HD the top level
diamond right before the earthquake in
Haiti the internet infrastructure was a
picture like that we have a 1 gigabit
capacity for the internal international
rank all those like for at least three
providers because he go to the Dominican
Republic using microwave link to the
Dominican fiber we had the 10 gigabit
submarine network in paw prints but it
was used by the incumbent
telecommunication company the state
company and it's a joint venture between
the battle co from the state-owned bamas
batelco and with tellico we have four is
be in haiti running wimax networks and
ordered a wireless technology
particularly the license free networks
for the 5.8 2 gigahertz in the 2.4 tree
mobile operators to gsm and one cdma for
a total of three million mobile
subscribers for total population of 9
million and the incumbent silico my
dream of the state-owned company in the
process of recapitalization and there
was an offer from via tell a vietnamese
company they were willing to acquire
sixty percent of the state-owned company
and about 60,000 internet users still
before the earthquake we have an
internet exchange point or personal we
launched on may six 2009 and currently a
before the earthquake we had for isps
that were connected the to the exchange
point two connected via fiber optics
nights and one which the IX location by
radio like and the other one via
ethernet cable because they are very
close to the data center where the high
XP is located this XP is a result of
cooperation between networks terribly so
center at the university of oregon and
the local ICT trade association eric the
management of the dot HT government is
done locally since the rededication to a
local organization in 2004 that mr. max
represent here and the dns servers are
scattered on the 3d five continents and
we are using a shadowmaster outside the
country
on the January 12 at 453 p.m. the herd
quickstrike and what you are what you
are watching now it's the network
operation center of Telugu due to the
destruction of vegetation and cell tower
telecommunication were badly hit mobile
operators were the worse with limited
services but the content and
infrastructure survive as well as the
axpy because of the extensive use of
wireless technologies telecommunication
work is too rapidly but I speed has lost
about forty percent of the cliental and
I've Regan about only twenty percent of
them it's believed that since their
capacity has been restored at
ninety-eight percent but you can you
still have some breach and a lot of
congestion at peak hours but could a
leak communication between operators now
you are see you are watching crossing
the the city it's a google hurts image
from tellico where the knock was I don't
know why but it was the only one
building that has been collapsed in the
whole area it's this is a view of the I
XP is located in booty game for those of
you was already visited eboot yeah it's
he'll power prince is like a city like
San Francisco a lot of heal and Bolivia
it's a real that surround the city of
paw prints so every all the ice peas or
internet service provider or cell phone
operators they all has facilities in
this area during the hurt quake I team
has played a key wool because of its
distributed architecture and coordinated
intervention of icon community and the
dot each manager the dot HT domain sir
the service never stop working during
the herd coin and neither the XP but
during the aftershocks they did we add
the two of the hospice that were like to
the data center with fiber they had
their fiber cuts during the hurt the
aftershocks and there were two the the
one with the wireless connection and
multi make with the the claw the closest
to the isp they are still connect to the
SP but the traffic drops from two
megabyte to only 128 kilobits per second
since then one fiber access ad is now
fixed and we are working to reconnected
to this to the facility people was able
to send a lot of messages from their
cell phone while they were on the
wobbles and did what it was
very amazing what technology can do
because people they were under the
wobble and the only way to communicate
with others was the cell phone and as
communication was very difficult we use
the the just send text messages using
SMS and those messages has been relayed
on Facebook and Twitter and Stefan Bruno
a color a colleague of us with the help
of Steven author from Anasazi relate
them to State Department and which in
turn sent them to rescue workers that
were on the field lesson plans and
perspectives the earthquake has
emphasized the need to distance is the
policies of the state and the public
administration inhaling that rely on
paper created that has created awareness
on the necessity to modernize and to use
more technology in the management of the
states now there was a lot of money that
is being poured into the country and the
international community is teaming up
with Nationals for the management of
those funds there was an ICT task force
that has been created to lead a project
with the IDB it's the Burbank to equip
the public administration with an
information technology where service can
be plugged in with an emphasis on mobile
applications it's also time to these wop
vocal contents and develop the local
austin markets implement geographically
distributed system
exploring and exploring the potential of
other cities like a cape ation Jacmel on
which is a CD for tourism among others
building more resilient and more
stronger infrastructure there was a lot
of ongoing initiatives particularly the
annual a national research and
educational network and Max will tell
you about it a little bit error the
landing station for the undersea cable
was a completely destroyed during the
earthquake but we tell the company that
was willing to buy a part of tellico
they they are concluding the deal and
they state they are still interest in
the deal and decide to move forward
veetle say they will restore the railing
station and put the cable in service
again and they also say they will
install five thousand kilometer of
fiber-optic to build the National fiber
backbone a second cable is said to be
bored to 80 conquer concurrently
operators are considering creating a
consortium to manage the second table
and on our part at 80 we are convincing
the big players like digital voila and
via tell to join the eis p one thing i
would like to UM to say here it's in a
li they are cell phone or telephone
operators and there is peace it's
different license for each of them when
you buy when you go to option for on a
telephone license it's not include the
internet it's a big difference
with all the countries there's a lot of
people that I need to take for this
report when the herd cook strike Haiti
even they didn't know us and they have
shown a lot of concern about all we were
and particularly there there is a Boomer
Williams I was expecting to meet with
him here but unfortunately II didn't do
the trip to San Francisco we have we
receive a lot of supportive words from
all acne colleagues and that I've
decides people from IC to give us an
anycast a food server that will be
installed in Haiti in the coming in the
coming days thanks to our friends from
IC and the tanks to Waka Gagliano y will
achieve area Francisco visible for all
their support to make it to make it
happen and we also receive a lot of help
from the Nano girls when it happens um
from the US military from South Cobb the
soft com company and with the support of
a lot of you from the Nano glee's have I
got my family ever created to Miami now
I'm getting I'm getting them back to 80
thanks and state fan or colleague he got
his nephew that has been badly hurt
during the earthquake and he has been we
have been able to evacuated with the
help of the Dominican regulator that
centinela copter to to do that and we
receive also fuel and food from the
Dominican embassy in paw prints text to
the Googlers to UM they have sent us a
lot of support stands for
the technicians for the telecom
technicians that have their house
collapsed and marks with zo with us as
his house collapse and he also received
from those nights but after all those
assistance I have been talking about I
think it's time to move forward to move
to another state assistance is good but
its assistance is not enough to help us
reconstruct the country and what I'm
doing right now is to invite you to come
to a li to invest in Haiti because with
the earthquake it's maybe sinnism but
they have been a lot of opportunity
because when you have a lot of building
that have been collapsed there is
opportunity for construction and and we
construct with we have to rebuilding in
a better way there was a lot of change
our painting right now in the telecom
sector there is some acquisition by
example digital with an cell phone
company they are acquiring ACN the one
of the ice be that is participating in
in the internet exchange point I take
its time to building synergy between
international particularly US investors
and local companies it's a for me it's
the best way to build local capacity
with knowledge and technology transfer
the puffs quake period as well
tremendous opportunity of doing business
in Haiti and at the end of this month
will be a roundtable on the telecom
sector in Hailey in June on jun 29 and
30 in Barbados it's an initiative
sponsored by I you caricom invasion
regulator cannot oh it will be an
opportunity to be some matchmaking for
business-to-business and to know about
variation government perspective for the
telecom sector so I take it off being
there on jun 29 30 of this one that's it
for those of you want to do some
contacts you can contact math class on
Henry or colleague Stefan we know who is
not here and myself I just launched this
company HTG itt daily technology group
we are very young company but we are
very open to do business with every one
of you that's it if you have question I
will be glad to answer them at the end
of Max presentation and I've also a
surprise for you and I will tell you
what is it at the end of Max
presentation thank
I will take a few seconds to think nslc
and Steve hotel to help us coming here
and share with you guys some of our
experience during the earthquake
regarding the Asian ccTLD dot each cedar
Asian ccTLD is managed by the a
consortium of the Faculty of science of
the State University of Haiti and the
Asian sustainable development network in
terms of infrastructures before the
earthquake two of the DNS servers
authoritative dns service was host at
tellico facility the incumbent in haiti
and the blue primary and one of the
secondary the other one are located in
inferential here in the United States
and in Canada and the last one in fact
is the part of the anycast cloud of 15
notes operated by PCH the registry
application is hosting Australia along
with the shadowmaster in in Australia
also so the gender earthquake the the
server was collapsed along with tellico
building the tellico are building also
as when i mentioning was a landing
station for the only one fiber optical
fiber that give us access to
international connectivity along with
the microwave links to the Dominican
Republic so the tellico collapse and two
of two of our service that was locked
out stood in Haiti and was destroyed
during the earthquake and
telecommunication was unavailable to for
us to reach the operators of the
secondaries
and ccTLD staff was some of them was
injured and they need to secure that
their families so but the service
regarding that HT continue to to be
operational during during the earthquake
thanks to the the manager of the
secondaries who took interesting
initiative to make sure that the the
service doesn't stop warning a showing
of the during the earthquake so what we
learn income of service kenichi best
common practices disaster recovery plan
and community collaboration in fact a
lot of talks regarding the earthquake in
haiti ongoing communication on under
under nan ugly so i'd like to take this
opportunity to thank you guys too for
having offered us the opportunity to you
know to receive help from from you and
for from people other people around the
world so what we learn in the case of
the haitian ccTLD is that geographic
diversity is very important you know to
avoid single point of failure the
shadowmaster re sauce in australia has
been reconfigured so that the cylinder
is pulled the zone information from from
it and also the zone information from
for me tht people networking is is
important it was very difficult
impossible for us to contact the
operators for for the secondaries but
they took the initiative to you know to
make sure that
the service continuities is continuing
to operate and dot HD consider two to be
alive it it was very important for us it
is important also to learn from previous
incident I in fact three years ago we
have an incident that the Calico
facility that constraint us to modify
the expiry fill in the also a soft so
that we put it to two weeks instead of
one weeks so that prevent the residents
to still during the earthquake while we
learn also is DNS is strong in his very
words put talk about CL as a community
running critical internet infrastructure
willing to apply best common practices
that HT now what we are trying to do is
acquire a numbering resources i c'n and
ipv4 space to negotiate chancit links
with operators in haiti and host our
servers in close to the exchange point
and have also we're about to plan a
contingency plan so and have more
graphic diversity more a shadowmaster
outside of the country we are also
engage in developing some other project
with the local internet community
renault talk about the anycast a foot
which is a collaboration between between
IC lack Nick and the Haitian internet
exchange point it should be operational
next next move we are also engaging
capacity building because as we are
winning a critical internet a fractious
restructure it cannot rely completely on
one or two people and the problem that
we had during the health quake is
a lot of competent people on network
engineers went to the u.s. in Canada and
we are naturally going to come back in
in Haiti so we need to do a lot of
effort much more effort not to to create
a critical mass of copper ball engineers
so to sustain the development of
Internet in Haiti I'd like to thank you
guys the Nano community and along with
other community and that helped us
during the earthquake that's it thank
you and thank you both very much truly
amazing the work that needs to be done
there and hope you'll appreciate the
point of doing things which can have
long-term impacts you know fixing things
that are broken is one thing it needs to
be done quickly but making changes that
will provide for long-term growth and
stability are probably far more
important in the long term in any case
we're ready for our break you like to
thank for ten networks for for
sponsoring this break and we are just a
few minutes behind schedule but we're
due back here oh that's all right oh we
got one more point here yeah I just come
back for the surprise some of them some
of you might already know but the Asian
famous wrong eyebrow I brought with me a
couple of bottles for some friends there
is one extra so um would you like we are
going to drink it tonight or I can
tonight
not for right now okay let's let's go ok
I read it tonight at the co side party
so we will enjoy thank you very much