good afternoon my name is Mike Jam
Goshen I'm with Alcatel Lucent and
welcome you all to this session of nanog
49 understanding OTN and the path to the
future really appreciate the man-dog
giving us the opportunity to speak on
this subject this afternoon and
hopefully it will be informative for you
and really welcome any questions after
my talk so if anything comes up please
jot it down and come forward to the mic
when I'm finished
what I'd like to do is spend just a few
minutes giving a background on myself
and where I fit with in the industry and
alcatel-lucent been doing
telecommunications work for the last 25
years and worked for MCI and
alcatel-lucent almost split half my time
between the two and in that time I've
done a lot of with optical transmission
and predecessor to that electrical
transmission and radio transmission so
this subject is pretty near and dear to
what I do on a day-to-day basis
currently I'm part of the business
development organization for the optics
team within alcatel-lucent but
previously I've held a number of
technical positions within that company
and MCI so my roots are in technology
and just moved into more of a business
role so this afternoon not knowing how
many of you are familiar with the
transport end of our business dealing in
the output alphabet soup that is
acronyms on the transport side then a
history lesson of
where we've come from from a transport
perspective kind of give you a rap
background as to what led up to the
optical transport network standard go
into an OT n101
look at some network applications the
hierarchy of OT OD n of OT n excuse me
and a concept that is new to this
particular standard and that is OD u
flex and what that brings to the IP data
environment that has not been previously
available in the transport arena and
then look at oten from a business
perspective what's really driving the
need for this new standard and where the
industry as a whole is going many of you
and your companies are really driving
the need for these new standards and and
their higher bit rates that they bring
with them in the transport network
whether they be with transport with in
side a data center or transport in a
metro area or transport long haul or
even globally we're getting more and
more global tie-in so every piece of
this puzzle comes together within the
standard alphabet-soup show hands how
many are familiar with the transport
side of the business that's a good that
fair number as you guys may be aware and
sometimes I find even even myself having
just casual conversations and talking in
acronyms and friends that don't know
about the telecommunications industry
are very puzzled by it but there is a
plethora of acronyms that are a part of
the OTN and for those who aren't
familiar itu-t is the standards body
that is driven the OTN standard with
participation of over a hundred various
vendors and service providers
contributing to that work not only here
in the US but globally so this is for
probably the first time so far we'll see
what happens
that this is truly a global standard
every operator and vendor or driving to
the same standard unlike previous
standards of sonet and sdh some key
elements of OTN are the optical
transport network is the overarching
standard that ITU has come up with
looking at trying to put more
intelligence and we'll go into some
detail about that into the optical layer
of the network and then oth is the
hierarchy that's underneath the OTN and
then ODU opu ot you are various units
and I've got some slides to talk about
how the hierarchy is is built up the
optical channel which is truly the
information and is put over the light
down the fibre and that is built build
up into these three components make up
the optical channel forward error
correction is pretty key in the optics
arena being able to send information
along that allows you to correct for
problems impairments on the line and
improve the the bitrate that is
transmitted in the quality of that
bitrate we talked about low order and
high order and the ODU standards and
we'll describe what those
are in a little detail and driven Eric
mapping protocol and that is the way
that IP Ethernet data information is
packaged up into a particular optical
channel and transported across the
network some other of these you're
probably familiar with but the key ones
are over here on the left and we'll
speak more in detail of that history
where this all began and I only went
back into the 70s because that was
probably the culmination of and where
the change really began up at to that
point everything was in an asynchronous
environment running over copper and then
over time they began to see analog elate
a radio as the transmission medium but
you know this was dominated as we all
know by AT&T there was very little
competition and very few advancements
other than what AT&T was bringing to the
environment in the late 70s early 80s
MCI came along and challenged AT&T and
one in the courts and opened up the
floodgates to a new business model
within the transport arena and brought
in with it digital radio and fiber and
drove a change from the low bandwidth
that was delivered at Killah bond and
moved into megabit transport and drove
that and in the 80s and 90s and that
allowed a number of other companies come
along and begin to provide services
on ever-increasing or ever decreasing
cost of bandwidth and then as we all
know in the mid-90s the Internet
explosion began which many of you
participate in today and a lot of that
was wouldn't have been available to us
if fiber and the associated sonic
transmission hadn't been brought into
the fore of the telecommunications
industry so in the late 90s the drive
was as a transmission medium pure fiber
making the interconnects over fiber
Metro and long haul and globally so that
is the dominant transmission medium that
we have today in the office stronger and
stronger coming along or Ethernet
carrier type quality Ethernet but also
because of the high bit rates seen some
offices go to fiber to carry the the 40
gig type rates today and looking to 100
Gig particularly if you're in a campus
environment fiber is used more and more
as we move into the higher bit rates so
sonic transitioned Ethernet became a
critical standard to the business as
we're all aware especially in the
enterprise and in the data arena and a
lot of standards works was done in order
to drive that into backbone networks as
well so with the advent of a the split
between TDM type services for voice
private line private line data
that really wasn't ip-based and then the
data play the ethernet the IP video as
we've seen over the last 10 years video
is becoming a dominant whether it's
YouTube or the IPTV from AT&T or files
from Verizon and similar products from
other service providers video is
becoming greater and greater Drive of
bandwidth within the network what those
two disparate technologies and standards
really drove was the operators to ask is
there a way to be able to get all of
these various types of services onto the
same transport platform because as we
see today many of you may be involved in
the difficulties of being able to drive
bandwidth across a particular carriers
network and being able to get efficient
costs in prices for that bandwidth
because the carrier's looking to try and
consolidate and if they can't
consolidate into a single data stream
from LA to New York
than the you know the pricing for
various services that we all try to
acquire is more expensive there needs to
so the operators really were driving is
there a single standard single type of
platform that could be utilized to carry
disparate types of services in their
native form and be transparent to that
because there's a lot of intelligence
that already exists in the native
service but it's very difficult to get
the proper bandwidth consolidation
across a larger network so you know some
of the services work extremely well and
are very inexpensive within
local area but when you're trying to go
from LA to New York with particular
service it can get quite expensive
because bandwidth is driving most of
that cost plus the performance can be
questionable at times just because there
isn't a lot of intelligence at the right
levels within the network today so the
standards bodies took this up with a lot
of input and that's why today in the
last several years we've seen the launch
of OTN and the likes of alcatel-lucent
cisco juniper Nokia Siemens beginning to
deliver equipment that will support OTN
and the vendor are the operator
community also taking up an interest in
otm so the standard that is used for OTN
was really started back in 2003 and it's
an IT itu-t standard G 709 which really
drove what OTN was - an Operations
environment described what the
functionality was wouldn't you know how
the optical carrier was to work and
really was driven at the DWDM
environment because that's where the
high bit rate at time optics was and
that was the unintelligent part of the
network so trying to drive intelligence
into that network to be able to deal
with different types of services whether
they be data services or voice TDM type
services
so what the standard does at its essence
is developed a encapsulation methodology
and what they coined is a digital
wrapper that would be put around the
particular serif service that was trying
to be transported across the DWDM
Network and that is what that digital
wrapper allowed for is to maintain the
inherent service in and of itself it's
protocols all of the information that
was necessary for equipment on the ends
of the circuit to be able to process
that whether that was routers switches
or voice switches to be able to or video
equipment to be able to drive that
service across the network in a manner
that is has a structure to it but does
not impede what the underlying service
intelligence is that is being
transmitted so this digital wrapper
technique allowed for that encapsulation
and then the aggregation on top of that
to bring other services into the same
optical channel as with any standard OTN
specifies framing conventions and
methods of doing performance monitoring
so that the operators can get a sense of
what is going on with their optical
network at DWDM layer and provide
information that wasn't there previously
prior to OPM being available basically
all you were looking at is transmit
power and bit error rate those were the
things that you cared about and that was
very little intelligence built in also
the for error correction algorithms were
simple and straightforward and did not
allow for a lot of coding game as the
higher and higher bit rates became
available you needed more complex
algorithms to be able to handle those so
a lot of the work back in 2003 was
focused on two and a half gig and the
burgeoning 10 gig but the standards
bodies attempted to leave room for
higher bit rates and as we've seen today
a lot of 40 gig services are available
40 gig interfaces on various equipment
and we're beginning to see 100 Gig come
available here this year you will
probably see a lot of announced
announcements on true 100 gig type
interfaces and next year services to go
with them so from a practical
perspective taking the basis of G 709
then the standards bodies looked to how
do you develop architectures in which
you can utilize the OTN and digital
wrapper and that's where g 872 came from
and in conjunction with 709 really lays
out the total framework for this OTN
network it also gives an evolution as we
touched on here beyond SONET and SDH
SONET was very very good for TDM type
services was not but was not flexible
enough for IP based services and clearly
struggles with video tape services so in
the transport arena really needed
something that would drive
not only higher bit services but also
video and IP based services also this
was driven towards a capex and OPEX view
of the world and being able to give the
operators the ability to put as we said
various types of services onto the same
wavelength
I am being able to drive that and if you
can drive various services of different
container sizes onto the same wavelength
then you can drive the cost per bit
overall down and if you're able to drive
the cost per bit down then you begin the
this spiral of positive growth for the
services that are out there what the
carrier's were really looking for and I
believe has come about in the OTN is the
commonality that was required as I've
said and being able to drive to a
wavelength based type of optical network
being able to put high data rates on to
the wavelength and being able to do that
in a flexible way so that you can
potentially come out of a router and go
right into the DWDM or depending upon
the size of the network as you get into
much larger network being able to have a
OTN switch be able to sit within the
network bridging the network between the
IP data services and the TDM services
onto a single backbone network
transparency is the next key that the
standard delivers as I've said the
ability to maintain
all of the underlying intelligence that
an IP service has coming out of the
router and the optical layer not
impinging on that particular information
and not corrupting or having to draw
from that information and the optical
layer thus having its own intelligence
and not reliant upon the router domain
efficiency just from the network
monetization what it's going to take to
build these networks in the future
because you'll have a single standard in
which the DWDM platforms are based on
and the ability to be able to take
varying different types of services
across the same wavelength and
maximizing the use of the wavelengths
and we'll talk about how ODU flex does
that on the maximum maximizing
wavelength and being able to support the
evolution of data rates being able to
handle 40 gig 100 gig as we're seeing
coming out this year and next and having
a framework in which 400 or terabit
rates can be supported going forward
that are probably three four or five
years out in the future so let's look at
the network and what how OTN fits within
the network and what OTN is able to
bring to the various aspects and various
layers as you see up at the top of this
diagram at the highest layer within in
the networks you still have the IP MPLS
routers and switches in the SONET SDH
year driving the services
those can be voice services for cellular
phones landlines all the way up to a
video service such as IPTV your FiOS
being driven across the network and
anything in between all of that traffic
needs to be able to be aggregated down
into the layers zero of the network
across the wavelength and previously
this was all done in segmentation that
the IP MPLS would be driven into this
network and the SONET SDH would be
driven separately into this network and
they're either overlapping or
inefficient wavelengths developed from
that because the two really never mixed
you know SONET extremely highly
structured needing to have all of this
subdivision and you had away with
virtual concatenation to try and stuff
IP MPLS into that network but it was
very cumbersome and very difficult to do
so a lot of times these bandwidth were
driven straight down but then drove in
efficiencies because it was very
difficult to mix them with the SONET SDH
bandwidth so the OTN really sub divides
into two pieces a low order rate of
being able to depending upon what the
bandwidth need is in the intelligence
layer driving a particular container
here in the low order of that is two and
a half gig 1.25 gig or you know smaller
containers and get them in to an OTN
container with the digital wrapper
no matter what their services and then
be able to aggregate them up into higher
order ODEs tengo 40 gig hundred gig and
be able to put them on the DWDM network
within the wavelength so just as a
graphic being able to take IP Ethernet
SONET video and being able to put them
into payloads and add forward error
correction information and a header to
provide information about this container
now and be able to pass that through a
multiplexing arrangement and then out
onto an optical Channel and you can have
that multiplexing functionality here or
not and it really is dependent upon how
large these containers need to be if
you're talking about a 100 gig container
that is coming from a router and needs
to get from LA to New York more than
likely there isn't much multiplexing
that needs to be done the router has
already aggregated everything for you
god and gotten it up into the highest
bitrate and just needs to be put out on
the optical channel but if there is a
lot of one gig or gig e traffic that is
in these payloads then it may be
advantageous to aggregate those up into
100 gig transport rate and be able to
pass them on to the optical Channel so a
a little bit further down there in this
optical overhead there's frame alignment
so that the equipment understands where
this particular container fits with all
of the other containers that are being
passed
there's also overhead
that is associated with this unit and
for the data unit there is also overhead
so this is the full o tu that contains a
payload the data unit which is the
payload plus its overhead and then the
FEC so I'll have a couple of slides that
really show this in more detail of how
this is built up this one in particular
so you're taking whatever the client
signal is you're putting that into a
payload unit and that payload unit has
an overhead associated with it that is
then built into a data unit and that has
an overhead associated with it and you
bring in the forward error correction in
that overhead as well and then the
transport unit is the combination of the
data unit and the overhead for the data
unit and it has overhead and then that
is put in to the wavelength and then the
wavelength is put out onto a line system
and depending upon the bit rate it will
dictate what information is stuffed into
the overhead so the rates that have been
defined are here at the transport unit
and this is the actual information that
is put into the wavelength and then put
out on to the line they also define the
data unit and in order to support Giggy
and ODU zero was defined so that you had
enough room within the in the payload to
be able to support down to a Giggy
and then the associated rates as we go
from one point two five gig all the way
up to 100 Gig you'll probably see people
interchange otu and ODU when they talk
it just common habit I think everybody
likes to get to the least common
denominator so you'll see people
reference one or the other whatever
they're comfortable with but really the
distinction is in the OT you what is put
out on physical wave length and then ODU
is what's the data unit that is
underlying what's out on the physical
wavelength and then what the true signal
rates are and that includes the overhead
for the ODU and then what the payload
rates are within each of the generic
rates so you'll also see a lot of people
to speak to marketing rates but know
that underlying they're very specific
rates to be used as a part of the
hierarchy this just gives you the
framework as you'll see with ODU flex
you'll be able to cross between these
payloads and be able to define a
customizable size by aggregating various
different payloads together
the G 709 standard as it stands today
with amendment three was ratified at the
end of last year and what amendment
three had brought in were the ODU zero
that previously wasn't there the ODU
four which is 100 Gig rate which was not
previously there and also set up that to
be able to move towards higher bit rates
by defining a ODU for is either high
order or a low order so it can be the
one and only container that is in the
wave length or it is a high order or it
can potentially in the future be a low
order which is then mapped into a higher
order container and ODU tui rate was
defined and we'll speak to that here in
a few slides that was something specific
coming out of Asia driving for
particular flexibility in an rate
structure to handle some IP services 40
gig 100 Gig base are four parallel 66b
interfaces some transcoding was included
for fibre channel and that relates back
to the Opie u2e
and delay measurements were included as
well what I want to talk to first is the
blue area and unfortunately I've
converted this in to to send this in I
ended up using
Adobe Acrobat so and it's in PDF form so
didn't didn't attach the animation but
the blue really talks to where G 709 and
OTN started the objective to begin with
that I apologize for not stating this
upfront was to be as simple as possible
to be very straightforward in the
mapping arrangements that were defined
and not make a very complex hierarchy
being that as it may a lot of you have
may have been involved in standards work
find over time with a large number of
participates and a standards body things
change and not always for the simpler
but for more likely for the complex so
what we've seen over time is the
addition of the red items in the mapping
and going from something that is fairly
straight forward something that is more
complex and in what this drives is
equipment to be able to handle this
complexity vendor community was really
going for a simple architecture in order
to drive overall cost down but still
being able to provide flexibility
however varying operators were driving
for their special need their niche type
products that they wanted to in services
that they wanted to provide so you begin
to get a more complex arrangement so
just simply this is where we can clearly
define a low order and a high order ODU
and the subsequent OTU that then is put
out onto the wavelength so you can have
a ODU one as either a high order or a
low order and really the differences is
does that have any underlying low order
if you're a high order you definitely
have underlying low order services as
part of your container and you have had
them must up into you so an OD you can
be machst up into an OD 102 - OH - you 3
or 84 and the only differences is the
number of ODU zeros that then are
contained in each one of these but
they're all ODU zero-based OD one if you
are the low order then you go straight
in to an OT you won but you can also
then be multiplexed up into an OD 3 or
an ODU 402 through ro - you four and
then put out on to the appropriate line
system and so on so then also there is
the ODU flex that comes in and that is
only able to be put into an OD u 2 3 or
4 because it's all based on ODU ones are
it's actually based on OU's IRA's excuse
me but they precluded the ODU one from
that because this was really driven at
the 10 gig and above multiplexing so I
want to spend a little time going
through each of the containers the ODU
zero is the smallest container
that is defined but as I've said it
cannot be put on to a wavelength an OD u
0 has to be then multiplexed up into a
higher order OD 1 3 ot
four before it can be put out on to the
wavelength so anything that Giggy and
below that needs to be aggregated up
will be put into an O 2 u 0 and then
placed either into an OD 1 or above uh
they've also defined the number that can
be placed into the various ot use from 1
through 4 and the types of services the
underlying services that the client can
provide and I've already stated that it
is not a physical interface or physical
container that goes out on to a
wavelength and OD u 1 is the first point
in which the OT n is then put onto a
physical wavelength we've talked about
these rates and it can either be
subdivided into two 1.25 gig slots or be
the full data rate and it's really
driven for these types of underlying
clients OD u 2 is 10 gig so we were
going from one gig or gig e to two and a
half to ten ten gig same kind of
arrangement it can be subdivided or have
the full bit rate and then this is where
you introduce the ODU flex so you can
have one to eight time slots defined
within the ODU
- for building up specialized containers
and so if you have a 12 or an eight
gigabit service that you want to
transport you can use ODU flex to
encapsulate that and treat that as a
contiguous piece of information and then
still have space for a couple of ODU
zeros to be put into the same overall
ODU - container so you have that
flexibility of being able to build up
these specialized containers with ODU
flex and then also multiplexing back in
to fill up the whole container so that
you're not wasting bandwidth ODU to e4
the fibre channel and this was coming
out of Asia as I said specialized to be
able to better handle the fibre channel
same structure with the ODU 3 driving
towards these types of services and you
continue to get an increase as you go up
the hierarchy of the capacities that are
supported and similar to ODU 4 and 100
Gig and being able to drive in that data
rate so ODU flex on this is something
that was a recent addition there's still
some work to be done on oh do you flex
the basic framework has been ratified so
you can construct an OD you flex
container
the thing that is still being worked out
is the ability to dynamically size this
container as bandwidth needs change that
is one of the ultimate goals to make
this totally flexible is that as a
particular flex container is set up as
traffic herbs and flows across the
Canadian container being able to
dynamically size that container to the
bandwidth that is needed within a
particular time frame so that work is
still ongoing there's some challenges on
how you dynamically resize this because
one of the key goals is not to impact
the existing traffic that's running over
the ODU flex container so being able to
set up protocols to allow for this
dynamic resizing still needs to be
worked but that I think the key is is
now having the ability of a container in
this space that can be sized
appropriately for varying different
underlying traffic needs and as you can
see you can have ODU flexes in a higher
ODU container so these contain these ODU
flex containers can be of different
sizes and then multiplexed up into a
higher order container so with the drive
to more and more hundred gigs services
on the backbone be able to better
utilize the hundred those hundred gig
services with
you know the drive of video or IP
particular data center needs the
fluctuate depending upon the hour of the
day so those types of services that you
know change over time can be implemented
within these containers and the
containers can be segregated into either
circuit based containers or packet based
containers and this gives you the
flexibility of making sure that those
two networks are serviced as efficiently
as possible I've spoke to this and just
as a recap there's still work in to be
done in the resizing arena that is the
ultimate goal of the standard is with OD
flex is to be able to dynamically resize
but they're still working on that so it
may be a few years before that
capability is available
so as we've we've talked a lot about
this afternoon is all of this all these
services are really putting pressure on
this overall backbone and the current
backbones that are deployed with
sonet/sdh are just not capable of
sustaining and supporting the growth
that is coming at them from a service
base that is so varied also you know one
of the things that you begin to have
trouble with is when your growth begins
to outstrip your ability to generate
revenue and we see that more and more as
we move forward on each of us as to
consumer are not willing to pay very
much for the services that you know are
delivered to us the free internet though
as Democratic as it is and as open as it
is does create some problems for being
able to be a sustainable model because
what our customers are all looking for
are higher and higher bitrate services
at lower and lower costs so if you
continue on on the path here and you've
got to despair traffic growth and the
cost of your network continues to follow
the traffic growth then you've got a
disconnect and the model no longer
becomes sustainable
so what we've what we've seen - is this
hierarchy this inverted pyramid where
the IP routing has always been extremely
intelligent extremely robust but it also
bears cost there is a cost to that and
as you move down closer to the lowest
level of the network the cost per bit is
extremely low so really you know not
only cost but we're seeing a drive and
power consumption floor space everything
is driving a very costly overall IP
network and really the objective is to
figure out what the traffic underlying
traffic really is and where that traffic
really needs to be processed I've been
working with a particular customer right
now who's struggling with this their
entire network of data traffic is being
processed by their layer 3 switches
every layer 3 switch touches every piece
of traffic within this customers network
and it's extremely large network and
what we found was when you really dig
into it about 40 to 60 percent of that
traffic at any one given node is never
processed by that layer 3 node it has to
pass through that node because you've
got a fully connected mesh network but
it never processes it so this customer
is driving their IP vendor to build
bigger and bigger routers to handle
larger and larger traffic but a majority
of the traffic just has to pass through
the nut that physical site it doesn't
have to pass through the router so one
of the advantages that comes about with
an OT n type architecture is the ability
to look at something in
layer two two-and-a-half area to be able
to deal with that traffic that at a
particular site is not being processed
by the layer through and take and
utilize the layer three for what it does
best for that traffic that is entering
that node and then having to get out
onto the network but if there's traffic
that's just passing through bypass the
router get away from the router process
it somewhere else and only let those
routers deal with it that actually are
processing that underlying traffic so
that's where I n comes in is being able
to allow you to rethink this
architecture and and get some more
efficiencies in and also drive the
overall cost down because if this IP a
layer is truly as costly if it continues
to be truly as costly as we've seen
today and the switches and routers
continue to get larger and larger for
processing less traffic you can actually
remove traffic that is not requiring the
layer three processing and now opening
up capacity for traffic that really does
require layer three processing so that's
one of the key drivers to OTN in this
new network also you know what we find
is the facilities that the customers
each of our customers has in our vendor
community are constrained by the
physical HVAC the power that comes into
a building one of my past jobs I did
facility planning and you know you could
be in downtown New York and con Edison
will tell you your cap they can't bring
any more power into that facility so
what do you do you end up having to move
which is even more costly
so one of the things that you know a lot
of us in the vendor community begun to
look at again around the high consuming
power equipment is there a way you know
what is it and is there a way to better
utilize that equipment for what it was
designed for and in the case that I just
talked about with the routers if truly
forty to sixty percent of traffic and a
given router is bypass if you can remove
that then it takes the power consumption
down substantially and gives you a
longer time on a growth curve to be able
to support layer 3 based traffic this is
just a comparison of the varying
different technologies and their power
consumption and a breakdown I know it's
an eye chart I'm sure you guys will have
this available to you so you can see the
breakdown of varying different areas but
as you move down the technology
hierarchy power consumption goes down as
well and you get more efficiency so
again you know the key here in designing
and developing networks and equipment to
go into networks is trying to figure out
architectures that balance these
technologies you may not use all these
technologies but you may pick you know
two or three of these technologies and
play that balancing act to get the most
functionality out of a given network but
also the most cost efficiency to be able
to repair as we as I described in that
previous slide the traffic growth cost
per versus your revenue curve
so you know carrier applications that
are coming up we're seeing more and more
optical wavelength type services
financial institutions are taking
advantage of these from our customers
video is also going to take advantage of
that optical wavelength service being
able to transport video across a network
you may find that the likes of AT&T or
Verizon may offer optical wavelength
services and smaller operators would be
able to then utilize those services to
pass their video across that also you
know the key in any business is to
differentiate yourself from someone else
and with OTN you've got enough
intelligence to be able to offer SLA
being able to go to your customers and
guarantee certain performance and being
able to get information from the network
to you know be able to prove to the
customer that you are in adherence to to
your SFA's also OTN brings in the the
ability to integrate in multi domain
networks so you know varying operators
can now go and interoperate with each
other across a common standard
architecture and be able to you know get
traffic from one place to another you
know particularly some of the smaller
operators and now in their consortiums
be able to utilize this to be able to
pass traffic across the country without
having then to acquire services from a
larger carrier thus you know also
keeping control on their costs
I think one of the things that you find
in a lot of conferences here this
probably in the last two years is being
able to build off ecosystems and
sustainable ecosystems where you have
various vendors operators customers
being able to exist at all levels and
have a method of being able to provide
you know services up and down the chain
in a way that brings back into control
over all costs no matter at what layer
of that eco chain you're talking about
in order for us to be able to as an
industry be able to support the
continuous growth that we've been seeing
in the dynamic growth that we have seen
over the last several years that's all I
had for this afternoon I welcome any
questions that you have on this topic or
anything in the core transport arena
he's the updated presentation on the
website
I will check will make sure I had
submitted this presentation and
apparently there was a mixup so we'll
make sure that this is up on the flights
that you had read more recent so thank
you any other questions
all right well since I'm standing
between you and probably dinner I can
give you all half an hour back in your
day appreciate your attending this
session and have a good rest of the
conference