the weld
the
there
very happy I was able to come
it's been very interesting and they're
good people in
three words blood sweat and tears
I brands pack animals
and now the fun awesome people
threadbare
fun even great mixture
I'll deep tech as well as Susan makers
place I
I'm really enjoying it this is my first
time it repaired but definitely not a
lot of time
the
on
for
true
hey the
Lois a
good just some a couple of
say logistics organization other
things fossa please collect your
certificate the one
you remember to put under on your wall
to show to your manager are to show to
your grandkids
at some point of time I was there at
that time
arm plus Picasa please approach
played here in case you are up a
transfer saga rearranged
not yet arranged marking your calendar
everybody this is the date of two of us
the planned date of two of us
2015 same week like this just shifted by
one day
evidently I mean does I could do the
prime factorization of free
65 now but term II was kept that
a let me be might have somewhat I have
the idea of
a for next year's tour bus to include
something like a challenge on prime
factorization on on powers of two
are we'll have to figure that mark this
date
some stats two-plus 14
GSM thats ideas and they walk
consisting of %uh to base station said
those were mainly idling
I everybody a could connect to you make
didn't bowl well now on that won't heal
them a dawat
I'll made aware that
traffic was on a trip that which could
happen in real GSM networks
as well in certain parts of the world
and you you're not made about the app
22.6 subscribers connected to it
adjuster because it had the best signal
in some parts of the building
a number of us the text message it was
sent
just by replying you could have got into
open and there was a metallic and show I
where you kid could get additional
tokens interestingly
that there was a nombre are look at this
this gives an idea how into
actually I'm very happy to see this how
international to a process
I i mean okay they are so you'd show up
offering of the subscribers from Germany
ourselves from all parts of the Walt on
I mean there were some maybe not
represented here but
%ah most part of the what a including
I even Africa I'll
well on there is a special relationship
of my family and to of troopers with
Africa obviously given we
we on a this money is for South Sudan
put you in a cheer camp a cell phone
when does this was a bit surprising for
us submit interesting that the
the highest numbers I'll some song and
devices which
reflect see it a kind of thats you can
find everywhere still we had expect that
i in particular I i mean in the ipv6
network we saw a lot of
a on and DNS staff
on Google crap as I call it um
saliva from that angle I wouldn't expect
that
to the highest number on on the
Knepper delight us which is not a case
some
you can get this info if you want term
for
any type of way such officer 26 next
packet loss from what I hear
I went to bed early I'm I am are have a
reach a certain age but some are
for packing why was a blast from what I
hot and this is an integral part of a
this must be a troop us us theoretical
and practical and to pack it was provide
some
practical element I had it all off for
second
to you brian yes a second more I know
between us and the rest the day so
yes we had great battles last night um
the
the yarn double team there and the games
did great and I'm
our scenario this year was a really this
nefarious
organization called the GSA who's been
spying on the peoples of the world
arms or pack or urs united to
to take back the privacy section 11
but absolutely um
this was out this marked a couple
different the things we
we finished on time we start on time to
finish on time
you know first and we had six teams
they're here with their team captains
I team we own you up square roots who
have played many years
DMSO ER W Rookie Team a green power
a and the rookies a who will be from a
company unnamed
so it this year we owe so dance the
slide
a two-way tie for third place
could see these guys appear so they did
very good everybody did very
very well the battles were 30 minutes
apiece these are very fast tax
with lots of intricacies so it's it is a
challenge regardless of your
level of skill a we had a three way tie
for second place
and you know I expect square roots be
back next year
I'm sure they don't like displacing but
everybody did really well and I think it
also shows the level of competition
so you don't have to be a hacker a
mathematician or be able to
to prime numbers in your head to figure
out to
who actually won and by God it's good
that they did with a name like her we
own you
so if i if i could get him to come down
here see you guys can all give around
applause
this is the actual scoring
course they're apparently top
and notice battle 3 was underscored in
this was really where we beat the GSA at
their own game so
it's a stalemate but we need to do
better maybe next year but they did
great this year so
just congratulations and now we've got
some swag for you
and of course we expect you back next
two to fend era
and we'll see you in Dayton on that are
you
seen congratulations great job
and I hope everybody who played had a
good time in and possibly learn
something cuz that's really what it's
all about
up to make the world a safer place so
again
when I had what these guys
woodruff thing some
brian i mean up I seventy role
and so so I can in this case I'm not
null it depends I mean I live in a in
that dirty all mountains
but with one leg in Germany in Bavaria
so when I'm drinking with the variance
II like alive I'm
I'm in the right to leave until I don't
have the accent but right now I'm proud
to be a
from Austria a like 11 Aussie I saw this
at compatriots of mine
not just that this mod guy it's a
yeah I I okay I did that this was lame
II said to
II said that just look up
a okay dead ass anybody out there I but
for us
when it comes so packing in Austria
those guys we should look
they are not do so like did the German
something but there were some
best live in that nothing in Germany and
Austria
so they won they we get back to Vienna
tomorrow a so and they we like only
member
78 cry uncle up
isnt know what cop they still have posts
us of other 322
that hun Strongco Scott in the 79th
minute
and it will be like oh yeah
at once again be dead to be defeated ap
congratulations I
that's another ceremony going on right
now to pass
the the challenge arm
overall 89 a trooper submitted at least
five tokens which was the entry-level
to be a a to have a
at a ticket in this box Adele
lost some cheating somebody tried it
that tried to cheat
a acting left behind a unique on
um tried for like two to increase some
tokens related to run the simple thing
%uh so unique on
next year a he has to be in the run I'm
it gave len this year here
he pretended to be to %ah
welcome i'm i'm i'm happy to see that
next year overall 2006
talking about something that 117 97
lottery tickets for print at
the site in here arm
that's the thing
the next flight I mentioned Konkel
78 losing and
the feeding us and packet loss and I
mean look at this
a puppy sites that plus the hood
somewhat
was in was often the some activity is so
that we sorted out
i mean there are sup again
of ca1 I me we'll see
we'll see I mean you're the your
you're leading a scarring side it
doesn't mean much said it just means you
have a higher chance
a of being on a
method committee member a whatever from
the math angle
army
iight shots the to be a
a select that from this box which iz
what we're going to do now I austin
enough from the NW to come up
on la Sierra
I we call a I asking you like what a
what us it looks a mean in English I
forgot to add something i cum
I fortunes made not so arm
she
took 21 arm
its unique on in
new Nikon in
an outcall
another note how I possibly cheated on
him I didn't tell you if it was for the
second on a first price
at Saks a side effect which was planned
from the beginning of Kos
a of cost Kong regulations
man just got turned here I like was
review
have fun love it it's a %uh latest
greatest sumsung galaxy note
if you don't gotta Apple upcoming glad
it's a smart man
%uh so and now he kicks major ass and I
got what I want that in
have fun
but I mean he played very well here he
always caught
other to be as we honor so that's a
family not I mean everybody's a family
now
nom ass fortune doesn't to make any
difference essays net
I know that I S
actually are
a passenger bus on I did the same period
last year
I i mean i i looked at it and it was a
name which
apparently exists on are several times
now I could start the like India in
those game show saw
selling shows some tell you stories some
I was told after the auction I should
talk ha stock
like to drive people but on I'm trying
my best okay if this is about the on
its second name has 10 let us so
who who possibly could wife in a Rome
with her family name ever first time to
bust out and the family name befor 10
let us
so why what's hot I
nada a mad Cup
up so I
for any chance you a family name
s Zimmerman coming here
the
congratulations the latest greatest
iPad app live at troopers engraving 128
gig of ram
have fun with it yeah
other you're right I okay say
as possible
see i i mean I don't think I have no
idea of those
got shut out as wats up let's have a
look up I ES he's here
so this show us there's a fat chance a
regardless how many top
his summit I you can you can still win
on congratulations again talking about
dollars
boxer us I have another one here and SS
to on this is right I'm the kind of guy
I am
incredible this
in here Darius of hours and 107 you ross
in
actually from all types of countries
like it with the euro's I mean that's
with the coins to you might able to
identify
are thank you this a cell
all love you have for a contributed here
and this is why to Bob when the wrong
one from you not see a
first contacted me it was like okay I'm
island
in all we have that cost for this had
led them for phantom
that wasn't the same numbers into India
email exchange
but the expectation well my
estimate this was like in their fight on
two thousand US range
and SSR incredible on
took thanks
and thank you for coming here thank you
for being part of troop us
us through process just being here and
directing
and so on you notice up
saw thanks go to you all thanks goes
well %uh speak us
again particular thanks a you make this
eve and happy
its you standing in front of people and
percent annually such
are you inside a cell um I don't know
why I do need
thank you
and hours actually I'll a number of
people being and left into a bus it's
just because
sending down front its many many sa1 NTS
it's a guy from outside Loblaw
thanks to you for the year very smart
stuff in that gonna
thanks all pop nice Andreas it's always
a pleasure love you guys
and
up same for I'm of cost Friday II
I try to spot him I didn't some and
a your own W you guys rock
call it a in
on
in
thin
I that's a that's a SAS a doubt for a
second term
I okay know you are allowed to I know
that as a that not all of you like this
a being exposed to the public can
someone who prefer to
up 20 gonna back to you in a few love
this he went
without those guy s all the olive and
why would be a
I wouldn't what happened there was no
way how this so
could be done with a all of you helping
hands and
I it's a cruel
it's a team a as a whole I have to
privilege
and it's a real privilege to be part of
it so I'll
usually this up I saying thank you.
procedure is not about
singling out individual Parsons still
to West now it says it's a seventh-year
trip us is known has a reputation and
also if you left me now
here for the first time hopefully you
Hewitt
a sense that we take
in we do our best
from several angles to provide a a good
experience a good setting
good education setting arm
and but this
actually does one cost in and it's not
me without whom
troopers wouldn't be what is this
troopers in the seventh year has reached
a certain level of maturity of
of fun maturity of reputation and
that there's their surname I who's
responsible for those who see it
the hot and the spirit and the call of
our of
what is called a trooper spirit like us
not being
Mela maybe being a bit different than
other conference s
I and that s
flaw in
in
signs I across the
same here failure process I mean why do
I tell you
upon this so flow anna &
and the on W and and I we have been
talking for together for a long time
his still a very young man are
in
up
applauded site at to takes out
directions in his life
he won't be pot of year in W in the
future
as he set him up his own business in the
freebie printing he's a visionary
and the freemen d painting area up
my in a hoe pass he will save us
at least for troop us this week I and
a holiday for me okay yeah but I I
cannot thank
the I cannot say a thank you flaw enough
fun
we have a come up with for sonal I know
that
you like playing with Harper I know that
you will take good care of it Ste
so up
%uh in
that's it there is a
just one thing I i just because there
was a a key for college phone so if you
miss one
show up at it with this team you have to
provide opposite a
them manufacturer and and and the model
but there was a key if you miss one
show up to Alice see you all
next year have a good and Safeway
home I mean does so there on time
tomorrow fall on us
safe trip home see you next to
hope you enjoyed it thank you in