writer star from hello everybody
can you hear me up now okay so first
um I'm sorry for the delay but that was
in our team going on
so i thought id would be good too up
delayed the start of professional a few
minutes okay um
my name is Daniel and today I'm gonna
talk about then
USB host drive a puzzle which are
developed in the last couple of months
um
actually little distraught disclaimer
so businessman implementation talk this
time um
we r deal finishing the test on the
software as well as the test
in fighting against the both stacks and
both drivers
so no exploit for giving to a given
today
I'm sorry but still it can be a %uh
interesting to see
first song I'll use people think it's
done
what you can do with it okay let's have
a look at the agenda
from I'm gonna talk a bit about to use P
basics
for basic stuff you need to know through
understand why
one would do host ronna pausing what you
need to do post-trial
then I'm gonna talk a little bit about
the hardware amusing
it's called based on support are
produced by our very neighborly neighbor
I'll also I'm gonna talk about the busy
putting toolkit I'm using for
Papa the input than I had to make some
conditions through the
pausing framework to get it song capable
of using
use be as I'm as an output and in the
and I will show some
examples for actually running use be
pausing
and none will discuss a few results we
already have
rate okay so
let's start with the basics who've you
have ever cared about USB
K
so I am yep
actually it's or so I guess I could hear
no is not here he would tell you use be
stands for Universal Serial Bus but
actually it's not about the network
and you will see why when you see a
what what goes over to USB cable okay a
few
basic so long let's start with his three
the
development abuse be started in 1994 I
was 20
first working started to be specified
band and was released in ninety 96
this was to use based on up 1.0 then
shortly after 1998
they updated the standard arm what's the
release 1.1
in 2001 they really from even faster
the super high-speed USB which issues be
release 220 and a few years ago they
were
release version 3.0 um
Moss finished armed is not widely spread
in
your hardware okay
um this is based on %uh is
developed by or was developed and still
is developed by a group of companies
on just listed the companies who started
arm defining though 1.0 specification
and so the standard is
on written by hand forum the
use be implementers forum or use P if on
with the operation you will find in all
your documents covering
anything refuse peace than about the
issue okay there are
mainly three different versions abuse be
still use today
which is burdened 1.1 with I'll 1.5
megabits per second version 2 with for
innovating megabit per second
and the new awesome
a fast use be free with for a
gigabit per second transfer rate
so this talk will only cover USB version
1.0
1.1 and 1.2 2.0 peco's the
hardware I'm using is only capable of
those two persons
so um all loop
for two wickets all the hardware is not
able to
a fast specific use be free elements
are but maybe if the neighbor releases a
new board
it will have to use be free support we
will see okay
so to understand the process abuse
before thing you need to know a little
bit about the USB descriptors
um Gareth burr
main descriptor the USB device
descriptor or
which itself identified through USB
device better stop in like
I'll this device this from
a given vendor id: and it has a given
product id:
on go through values are youth
arm by a host operating system to
identify the device
and also in the device descriptor order
wrong is a number all additional
configurations
you can request from the device so you
also
have a country ERATION descriptor one or
more configuration descriptor
so your device can run in different
configurations
arm then inside of the configuration
descriptor you haven't interface
descriptor:
which describes arm the interface to
using
on if you're devices in
I don't know external keyboard for
example you will use a
human interface device class a in the
interface descriptor:
and the operating system will
automatically know or care
I know HID You Me Too Faced device I can
do that
I don't need any proprietary driver
let's just load the USB keyboard driver
okay and there are also some other
descriptors like the young man point
descriptor
which describes the direction of the
data flow on you know it used to be and
point
and from also some capabilities of the
endpoint
to also you can request some strings
where is for example the vendor name
about it order to buy some mean what a
serial number
okay this is a short overview how the
descriptors are
I'll encapsulated in each other so you
first have to device descriptor
are in there is that number of
configurations
and you got that number of configuration
descriptor you can
address and they again have a number of
interfaces
and the interfaces we can happen number
of people
been okay
so from
on use P enumeration so if you plug in
the device through your notebook
what happened if first the operating
system will request the
device descriptor are read from the bike
to
device descriptor to number of possible
configurations
and also appealed which is called
default configuration
then it will request the
default all the selected configuration
descriptor
and inside of the country ERATION
descriptor are all the
other soccer sup descriptors and better
tho business the huge
arm or can be huge a bunch of data
um and once this configuration
descriptor
is parsed all the strings are the up
so inside after descriptor that's just
the reference
which says like okay on this point um
there should be a string but instead of
a string
I give you an index like 5 and if you
request on string descriptor with the
argument five people get
the string I'm referring to
okay this can be I thought that for
example that many factor in the name of
the product name
or a serial number
so if you from sniff on you use period
on you Universal Serial Bus than
you would get you will see something
like this saw you can see the
post booth requesting device descriptor
and the device on sis with the device
descriptor
and then the whole three quests a
configuration descriptor
again 35 on to sweep the configuration
descriptor
about not you see the same step again
the only difference on both to
descriptor request just 11 of request
because and USB protocol
the holst from
if the whole three quests and a script
or to host has to define how long the on
thrus
if the descriptor anyways is too big to
fit
into the size the device will just on so
with the
had of descriptor and
will also give back the full length of
the descriptor sold that the whole snows
okay I'll the last month was incomplete
I need to ask again
the big Europe a lot size:
and after what you can see all the
string reconfirm
descriptors are requested from the size
to concede goals are
different answers so both are all
different strength
okay from another point of use be
especially in this context appalling and
you guys
how does it stand with security what do
you think it's
news be all lost you spew and a secure
in the past
no you're right after
search for somewhere abilities from the
last year
and I'm we go there are some Windows
Phone abilities
on positing USB device descriptor
are bare walls I'm Linux kernel driver
with a bottle overflow
and among use be handling
cold also found
nice arm Stack Overflow on Salon Iris
and there also you the space tools that
are
vulnerable to attacks from the
you spin doctors
target but this isn't surprising that
it okay so much for the basics
arm you know it's all about the
descriptors
and the first way and after wats when
the driver is loaded
there are some communication channels
established arm
we can also addressed up okay let's talk
about the hardware
I'm using some external hard work to do
the use be filing
this allows me to send wrought use P
pp to use so I'm not bound to any
a AP I am i operating system whose a.m.
exposing to me but I can just give raw
data to the hardware and hardware sense
at all
on you speak on the harbour I'm using
the face dancer
consists all first and use be too
what ship which is the whole connect so
my notebook running to father is
connecting wireless news be in the face
then the UART interface is connected to
an MSP microcontroller
and the MSP microcontroller again is
connected 2 a.m.
Maxime use be controller and Beth
USB controller if the target connect so
this is where r
connector post are one of us
and your about it it's not a lot of
stop on it looks like this so you can
see this is the host connect
you got to on Muse busy route to
you out connector and trip then you got
the microcontroller
and this is the maxine USB controller
which connects to the target ago
Arctic if you on talk to Travis he
on signs all about the PCB's
so if you're interested you you can get
them for a very low cost just for two
shipping cost I guess um and if you sold
for it it will look like this
so I just got to mini USB and
to stop on the PCB
ok it it tho the face the answer is
controlled
from PC host and the PC users
a Python library to excess the hardware
and to deliver content to be
on to the target USB chip so all told
you gonna ride is in Python which is
really nice
because I'm developing and debugging on
an embedded system
both always painful and costs a lot of
tight
so its way faster and easier for me to
ride
the parting coat in Python and run it on
a
arm on a notebook on
instead of putting all those cold
microcontroller
I also the you spiel I really the Python
library that comes with a stance or
implements on some basic layout of the
USB protocol
so you don't even have to go all the way
down
to arm to be a exchange and all that
stuff
this is here you can just do that you
have to implement
some a little bit of code you have to
implement new USB device and the
interface but that
it all the other stuff is already there
you just run it
and arm the nomination can happen
okay you will find peer a Saltcoats
and hardware arm stop
on sauce pot
um take a look at it its
really nice project
so this is just a screenshot of
the use P protocol layer so you see down
here is
the arm the
be a though layer one which is
link layer and BO link layer
up to here where the green border is a
is implemented in the
Maxim Hot which ship so this is way out
of focus we don't have to care about
getting bait on the cable we just cedar
rock pick up
paper you its then this up alia
which is orange I guess arm
is implemented in the faced anther use P
library so all you have to do is
to implement your device called and all
the functions you want to run
on top of you speak
ok so the next point
is the parting tool kit um
this is the father I'm using to generate
although for the payloads
and up going to stop the condition of
having here I'm sure
most of you will know it because it's
the first mention
all a positing and academia
so I just skip this we're already
shopping time you can read later
um so busy is a piping base-closing
toolkit
press release was in 2011
it got a quite simple packet the
Commission syntex
which is also piping and it boss
stateless filing as well as state for
putting
obvious link to the latest release
up just downloaded play around with
up so you're there you are I'll adjuster
yeah I quoted you before alright if
I said when second would be here he
would say use P it's not a
past its network indeed
actor so I am
this is the smallest packet definition
you coulda
think of so it contains just a variable
called name
and after what you have to lists one is
called object and one is called
functions in this example it's
completely empty this is just a
bare skeleton you need I'll the
object a rare contains the single few
of the packet so if you look at your
Wireshark pick up this sector you will
see packets
I'll are split into different feel
let's say oh aversion peel the type you
to Glenfield
and once you know your packet a
structured like this
you can also put both free fields in the
object array
from now I said okay there is the length
field so someone in the generation of
the packet
11 has to be calculated and put in the
right place
so these stuff goes into the function a
raceway say
on after generating the packet you need
to call from functions on it
run some calculations
market away double objects are I we go
into a little deep on the next flight
but this I just
objects you're able to put in there and
also there are
some functions dickens they're all
described in the
read me file in them more detailed way
up
but I will give you shop introduction
you know so
let's take with packet description file
this is my
typical example up that's why it's
called example
and then you see again the Object List
and the functions list
this is the packet I just mentioned
before with a Type field
a bell length field and a value field
and that's exactly what process okay we
got free feel to you
one is called type I could have called
it whatever I want
than this field have a static land of
8 its also it has
defaultValue of 0
and when I stop putting process I want
to
I want this field to be mutated
in every possible among every possible
state so from 002
at and this is what wire put fall in
here so this field should be
fully fast after
so its almost the same for the next
field but this is called lengthen got
the default value of
on 6 and the last field now
is a value field it hath no static land
so it can but the length of the field
can barry
the default value is the thrilling
father
so it has in default lentil 4-byte
but a while iterating over the field
its not but just called up wats from 0
to 0 FF like the other fields but
in on in this place in the packet there
is
from for each iteration a given
fostering
putting like used to kill injection 3 or
some code execution strings
or just yeah I'll pounds or
something like that arm both rings are
defined in
you know text file and just red line but
I
so and then in the end there is also
Island
function which is called after a packet
this generated in beta
and what this earth is please put
contribute Len
the land of all
fields from type to value
so the length all both three fields
miscalculated
and put into this destination feet
okay this really easy the just contains
field a plan
um this is what you will see in most of
your packet descriptions
smoth I could just carry a land
somewhere
um this knows the real world example
this is just another
a and up reply
so you see all the field up your up
package
in this case there is no function
because of have only state
static long fields and I got some
default values in here so this is up
absolutely functional stripped on you
can do up posing with pets
up just to show you a real world example
then there are even more object you can
use
for example the random object this one
just has a
name and the lawn and in each iteration
the whole length will be filled with
rhyming data
are then there is a list object
which again takes the name takes a
default value
and take the path to profile your
on your system and and each iteration
one of the lines of the file will be put
in
band um this is just nom appeared again
as we saw amber first example and on the
and
Harrison link object which just
got a name and a sauce and the content
all this object the content and the lamb
will be the same as the content and the
land of the salt object
so in this case I'm just copying the
random generated data up here
on their aka
okay ban there is also a petting
I don't want go through this in detail
up but you can also
pet beta aka so far
Baldor pick up prescriptions are with
picket descriptions you can only do
stateless father so you just go through
one packet and send it all out
on millions of times with different with
with small iterations in the packet data
but um what if you think about stateful
father
if you have to log in somewhere before
you can
on address the target the one of us
than you need well some kind of
multi-step
function you first need to authorizes
I'll
go through the login procedure with
validate of course
you too doesn't make sense to start
causing you because you want to be
locked in and father something
of the works so arm
I figured alt kind of an interaction
concept
arm this earth
represented just by a serious of packets
or in this case packet description files
both pickups on both both pickups
I'll send out and or so I say
my first pick up this like the first
visit of the page
this one a set outdone on the on side
back the second packet this like my
authentication data with username and
password and stuff like that
and beyond sore is let their not
indication top
from I sent out this packet and read the
answer back
and and i need to put this up indication
talking an
my next packet which is the actual
causing pain or because no one of the
right some other stuff I can begin
holding I'm but I still need to copy the
authentication
beta and this can also be done
and the interactions so I can copy parts
of an answer
and use it in proper transmissions
arm to describe an interaction I use a
stimuli up a in
description file so you gotta
name again and you got some object and
you got functions
objects in this place are this object so
do you get them name and you just
reference a packet prescription fight
so in this example from but who would
just
send out the first packet will read in
between
discard the right they took and signed
out the second pick up
okay this is just some made up example
let's go to more real-world example this
is beyond
authentication and just talked about saw
you happy or first visit of the page
which is
a pic description let's say HTTP GET
you can just were describe the nature to
be get in your packet description file
on and turned it up so
up to what status right back but nothing
happens
at this step then the authentication
data is sent out
a so this contains to you the name and
password
after what date 03 back and in this case
because I got a copy function
referencing for second repeat Step
um data is copied to be
more precise the date or from the on
ther
from offset on direct turned 20 X 20
is extracted from the on for office hour
and is transfer into the field name
all in the next this so we need
a field named all and Beth pick up
prescription pile
and this field is automatically filled
each time
um you read back you up indication coach
and done the last one the Kaman is
arm where I want to put my housing
payloads
so a this file will be
iterator with each %uh step through the
interaction
so arm beef
free packets us and our each time I'm
going through one iteration so
I'm visiting first I'm authenticating
ban and sending
that the fault packed than on
are mutating this packet soul a I
somewhere to change a value of Meyer
off the field I'm currently farthing
that I'm going through the whole process
again and sent into perspective I'm up
indicating
and I sent the mutated come on packet
and so on and so on so I'm only mutating
the last pick up
in this case because um I just wanna
party
the arm the authenticated come
okay so far for busy
and disease packet descriptions
from now I had to at some
use be additions to do the to get it
work against
use be and
I had to modified the main program and
at to new output types so you can now
instead of
just raw Ethan at the CPU the P&S ATP
you can also select on the USB
descriptor ought to use P and point
as an alt
so also I at some busy to face than to
glue
which is implemented in the you speed up
I and
this mainly implement the from but the
Bison USB interface
required by the paste and so Python
library
um to emulate the USB device
and also there is the class implemented
to which is used by busy to
start/stop control to use the threat
delivering you pay lots
okay arm there were
the coding part up
anyway if if you if you're interested in
the cold just have a look at it
at some on the website is: showed you
before
if you have any questions 22 your in
place of the code just
drop in the mail I'm always happy to
answer questions about cold
um market but not less see how this
would work
from in the whole process salt
okay I know all this you implemented a
lot of new stuff you can do use be no
but
how do I do it our kids so
first you have to choose your target so
they're on
many targets on use P so you could
address the device descriptor you could
address for example configuration
descriptor of some string descriptor
or on something in the extended
descriptors
or you could just target one and point
so and points are the connection to
actually data is transmitted
arm in the example
i jus just a are one of two descriptors
for these topics
but um the script of causing
targets the use peace take up your host
operating system
where the endpoint farthing targets the
use P drive attached to your
USB device so this driver might a puppy
from the operating system vendor all
from pop pop
at yep this is the interesting part
old all scrappy USB Drive us delivered
by
thought parties running inside a few
karnal
on does I'll be interesting us
okay but well now I want to Foss
some USB device or the driver for
some USB device but actually I don't own
the device how to get
the descriptor sunny I need to see a
religious
descriptor before I can from start
splitting it up into fields and put it
into a pickup description and stop
putting up with the script
a purse need to know how it looks
originally so
this earth while we are currently um
setting up and online collection
all use the device descriptor and
configuration descriptor
um arm register the main use be
descriptive third Kong
their is no content yet but there will
be
a paper base with use be tooth a.m.
use the descriptors you can contribute
to the collection a pic by submitting
just the output album
LSU's be which almost every Linux user
could do um but you can also
in a in the case of a more complicated
descriptor just
delivered to the script a raw Justin X
arm but this would require additional
tools
okay so wants you
230 bias are you driver you want to
address
and you somehow manage to get to an
original
on get your hands on an original
descriptor
saw you know got the descriptor the next
step is
you need some hardware you need are and
host PC to run
opposing tool unit B famous faced and
support
you need to use P cables to connect both
and of cause you need
some target then
you need a bit of software I which means
for new Python interpreter and
but the the framework on the host unita
use be device file which in this case if
the
from values be descriptor
you 84 did get got from real device
art from the database online and then
you need your actual hopping payload
which is the packet description file
after Sol let's go through it step by
step
you choose to take to descriptor from a
really hot
from from from real hardware so you need
to attach the hardware to your system
you need to find on which part to
disconnect that and then get
the output of the other issues be then
I got them my own kind of idly
postscript who tries to possibly
LSU's be output and got it into
something
aren't busy can use with
which is then your use be descriptor 5
are the script is not perfect
it's not working for a very complex
descriptors
so does you should some take
raw from the device
techa the second step would be to
create a modified to paleo you're
putting payload
in this case I to stir
configuration descriptor um
packet description this file already
comes with busy so I wrote this to
script once
you can just use it on modify it to you
two units arm
for example if you set every
fields to full funding departing will
never end
it moon both the way too much iterations
on too much mutations to go through
so you have to decide okay I'm gonna
I'm I'm going to target this field on
this run and maybe the other two feel
for the next run
okay saw once you got their payload
ready
you just need to attach the hardware so
put the paste and support in between
you host and target
and than just run the but the public
in this case the surfer to the command
for starting
use P descriptor fathering and
you using this 'em use be
descriptor file to emulate the device
also you gonna target the configuration
descriptor not the device the script
about
the configuration descriptor and he goes
to pay told
so want to launch this command
it will take a while because um
use P take some time to I'll
connect itself to be recognized by the
host that there is a new device attached
to be enumerated from the host
um some systems to it a couple of times
other operating systems just do it once
so
it also depends on your target how long
this process will take
up and then again bizarre in my tests I
came about from there
for 25 seconds parts right
which is really really law
normally I'm fathering something like
but there are no
at the layoff tenths of a second between
the packets
no one talking about 425 seconds
per iteration so the funding process
would be will be slow
got and the last and final step would be
you have just two attach why a shock to
you you spin 180
and watch the process happening
you don't have to watch it a while it's
running but you should recall
it in the case something crashed
but you can see what happened act or
what pic it actually got some out and
how to host responded and
on which step of your arm
maybe more click multi-step I'm set up
the host crashed okay
I'm to sniff use be in windows: use be
packed in a pick-up is needed
on you will find it here
okay so this was a
real-world example that's exactly the
methodology which currently using to run
abuse befuddling
but as i sat it's really really slow
it's running for a long long time
and so we don't have any spectacular
results by now
but we got some results those are mainly
from the
development face when I was writing the
cold and testing at the code is working
arm some stuff happened
so yes i sat with didn't perform all
white skin following
or white scale of I'll when ability
analysis on USB devices
um still I triggered some
unexpected behavior for example
host or use piece that crashed
this happens on Windows seven and
Linux on both systems in are
a recent version so ten-point her
3-point and it's not too late too strong
but it's not an old one
also I think the windows 7 was nearly
fully patched
I'm not sure for if there was
the update published on there are not
that was why did why do you develop
but both where recent systems
and get be crushed also I saw
software crushing running on the target
so
Skype for example whatever Skype us
listening to
your USB interface then I also tried to
attack about July system so in this case
our youth the Ember to brought to life
the host
and then just attached taste answer to
this
virtual machine so I got two cables from
Meyer both connecting to the face that
and
on mi amor for example after a few
iterations
I got this little arrow
Sol but true be amber wasn't able to
connect the device
Nole to virtual machine
and after what I couldn't attach any USB
device at all
to the virtual machine so I somehow
crash
be at work should use be spec I guess
put it we nor we are I been investigated
those precious
in creeping into because it was just
while I'm testing the implementation
and implementation in this case what's
the main preview
but no worries we will investigate
both crashes in the future we're
currently
on running a Sat of 'em
news be fathering instant us against
a series of targets but as I thought
they were
run for a long time
okay now I'm have to conclusions
um first from
you have to see in the past um use be
fussing
was really expensive to do because you
need
specialized hardware you need a a big
use BBD bag in box or whatever but
from by now there is low-cost hardware
really cheap artwork um
with which you can actually do use be
father
and test you use be implementations or
the implementation of your
operating system so up
I'm from my perspective would say expect
the pontiff
new use beautiful new bilities to show
up in the future
because as more people start looking at
this topic
there will be more fight mix
okay so that's it for now
well thank you prototype
and other any questions
mister
I him
are not currently its more like
up free both machines
I'm free target machines so I'm
targeting our
windows 7 current Linux and the
to thousand what is that
the new server consultant
12 yeah 2012 pres so
the desktop windows to sell a Windows
and Linux box
any more questions
we still got some time
no
okay well
a this period she
you rover on you know
whether the you
whose was 1
yes it was hyper by the white so there
wasn't there is one process which is
responsible for the
the use be virtualization so
per parts of two software which take
takes care
to attach the physical device that about
a machine
and this is just the daemon running on
the hypervisor and yup
apparently this demon didn't crash so
too were
was still running but the doesn't do
anything at all K
so I'm thanks very much
thank you