welcome everybody to the second talk of
the recipe security track on day two of
troopers
actually SEP security a trooper started
already
yesterday yet these acts up security
book shop with
I'm 7 sup security specialists talking
about
pariahs topics in the SAP security area
I'm
we also had a very nice networking
dinner and very good discussions about
various aspects of ACP security
including some of the speakers today
JP from on up sis was there martin
Guptill was there
surprise guest very welcome surprise
guest and also some guys industry and
from universities
so I'm if somebody doesn't hear me throw
big things that may I notice you can
hear me
I hope I'm loud enough not laptops
please I'm
you know what I am SEP security I'm
Aksana Polyakov already mentioned in his
talk earlier
that I'm the this started troopers in
2010 and
actually attack from Nepal your cough
really had the first talk I looked it up
it was the first talk
but on the second day of that same
troupe was not your fault also gave a
talk so
same event but not the first talk so the
credit goes to russia you're definitely
I'm yeah and now we're talking I'm not
so much about
vulnerabilities exploiting but rather
than I'm
a specific topic of hosting SAP
environments hosted SAP solutions
or use a little disclaimer if you have
time and
feel dizzy and have trouble sleeping you
can read it
I'm otherwise the proceeds to who we are
I'm sure and myself are doing at 8p
security research
both for quite some time we've been
talking azzam
various events on things the fines I'm
yeah I'm we also try to get scores for
all the old days
the report the same way I'm of friends
from russia do of course everybody tries
to get the high score it's a
sort of a recipe security researcher
competition going on here
and I'm yeah so I'm
our mission is SEP security beer
SAP security company virtual forge
and focused on more more on the upside
down on the job aside
I'm as on the shoulder area he's an
expert on the job aside
definitely I'm we have been doing a lot
of research
around up about code analysis were
abilities and stuff but
this year we going yet to move it a
little bit more on a business level on
on the
context level of hosting saw
I'm earlier aleksandr already asked how
many people know ASAP
I'm I don't know if the rules have
changed probably most of you know SEP
but still I'm let's talk about why
should be protected SAP systems in the
first place
any ideas my should be protected SAP
systems
part why not good idea let
we have time I'm not also protect the
SAP system okay other ideas why Cissy
p.m.
something worth protecting SAP systems
protect business that accident thank you
very much
this is exactly the question they dance
i've been waiting for
I'm because I'm according to a city's
website more than 200
eighty the forty eight thousand five
hundred companies runs up this is
a lot and let's look at what kinds of
companies these are and how much we
depend
on them so for example a city customers
transport over one billion flight
passengers
each year seventy as sixty-five percent
of all the TVs are made by customers
runnings up seventy seven thousand cars
produced every day
and 52 percent of all the movie some I
got what if it simply goes down I can go
to see my name or
but the first thing and that would be
something you would notice
two-day at the evening I'm dinner
the worst thing that can happen if SAP
customers get attacked
seventy-two percent of the vote be a
production depends on SAP
so if not
for any other reason do it for the beer
saw
avert on statistics 'em her
in every talk oil many talks with the
interesting statistics about
how things distribute what kind of
things happens
I'm home anything saw of of this column
that flavor
whatever statistics are a very
interesting thing
I'm how many of you run SAP
just asked a few statistical questions
oh an outfit is go up a lot how many of
you are running on host third SAP
systems
who 3 open
way okay you've been warned so I'm
statistics it's basically like that I'm
a hunter is
looking for a rabbit he shoots at the
rabbit he misses the rabbits on the left
side by 5 inches
he shoots again at the rabbit and he
misses the rabbit on the right side by 5
inches
statistically the rabbit is dead now
this a statistics
so basically you what I wanna say is you
can't run statistic in any
in any direction you want to miss your
presented the statistics
all this think about why is this guy
showing me some statistics
and especially my favorite don't risk
the district in for the fight yourself
talking about all this statistics close
disclaimer
let's talk a little bit about statistics
from the SAP environment
I'm so this statistic
I make this up myself this is the
disclaimer
depending on which security company
shows you that the colors all the
association with the colors the rise
let me explain how I fought the fight in
quotation marks this statistic to make
it look better but
the bottom line of that this anyway no
matter how you distribute account this
stuff
if you look at all the old days reporter
to SAP and this is what the statistics
is about credits for security advisory
since 2010 minutes apiece started
crediting
you notice that one two three four five
companies in the world
own seventy-five percent of all the
credit for
SAP 0 days which means the know-how on
that is
pretty much focused I'm
unexplainable across Europe you scan
they own the day leading the statistics
if you count by security notes then they
are the clearly dope
no issue with that the green guys the
SNC they'll eat the statistics if you
count the number of notes they submit
clearpoint and virtual forge our claim s
I'm that be base this on the number of
credits per individual researcher
why did he do that we looked at some
security notes from SAP
and compared them to the advisories the
sense to SAP
and it happens that sometimes to send
three different will be a tease to SAP
and the pet should with 1 note well
we're screwed we don't get credit for
the three so we said well
it may not be correct to only come to
know what it may be
better to at least look at the be such
as credit because
if three different people issue and am
an advisory and the three other and
credited in the note this morning flex
or this may more reflect
actually what's been going on
behind-the-scenes
and yeah another disclaimer on
on this specific pages just a minute
make a little bit more ridiculous I'm
and that we are not really I mean I mean
just the point is we are
one of the three that too a lot of
research here
so don't trust the statistic too much to
the point I want to make with it is just
five companies
on 75 percent of all the SAP old days
I also did some counting I'm in this
area
so what is that this is the point
January 10 2000
January 2010 when SAP started publicly
crediting security researchers for I'm
yup for their only if they are
responsibly disclose Tracy
I'm actually I think many if not most of
the leading
the search company started mcveigh
earlier to submit orders
recipe we did that first in 2003 but we
found a buffer overflow vulnerability in
the possible Department of
SAP's internet Transaction Server which
was actually the first step in a bit
server
and yeah we got a nice email thank you
for Mississippi but never a public
credit and
over the years we have submitted various
problems but these were never credited
but
let's not talk about that too much and
the points they they started doing that
in 2010
and there's the interesting trend if you
look at that so what we doing here's
I'm we r we're dividing the number of
advisories
submitted by researchers by the number
of security notes per month
to see how much I'm share how much
percentage do the research itself in
contrast
recipes own internal research NBC
and the first three years till December
2012 that
the researchers clearly lose against SAP
on the average statistically
blues so but then something happens
in generate 2013 be crossed the line of
fifty percent
and only once since then the researchers
drop below the line
so looking at this more closely the
average before 2030 was 16 percent share
of the
advisories and 0 days found
with 61 notes per month released by
sippy
on average again this is all statistics
if interested in
enterovirus forms and checks it's just
one
view of of false on on these information
and since then in 2013 you can turn
around the 16 and get the sixty-one
percent
ever its share of the researchers but
the number of notes has dropped
to slightly below 30
so now we can discuss what's going on
here other researchers
getting better SAP no longer finding
stuff
with their own methodologies I have no
idea I'm
they also some rumors not confirmed
rumors that maybe SAP is not
I'm yeah communicating all the security
vulnerabilities
in security notes anymore us sometime
people say they might be
all the the less a problems might be in
the service packs I don't know if this
is true
just something I for I've also written a
block on that
am if you're interested you can have a
look at it
to get more details on that so
just about sadistic not its let's talk a
little bit about more what we have
in mind with this talk I'm first about
the motivation widely built this talk
and then
two different scenarios which you one
present
a multi-system installation multi-system
hosted insulation and a
single system a shit system installation
and of course
a demo so much aggression
and this all started with
'em security incident
I'm with a hosted company in the United
Kingdom
I'm there was an interesting report I
can open that
the QR code is also link doubling
love you
this wasn't article like I came across
I'm
just to summarize its roughly you can
get your
precise on picture by by looking at the
stuff
later it's it's it's a rather lengthy
budget the point is just being that
the UK posts for some UK pop
the UK police sorry UK police I Met
Police
I'm they were hosted I'm and they did
some kind of on it and the audits turns
art
or told I'm told those guys that they
are
while there may be just to be this to be
a safe site security issues with
the host that applications they have
been this may be an integral
insecure way of posting and this a lot
of discussion
going on later on a.m. potentially also
including comments by Sapa
I'm not really sure there's I'm and SAP
guy
making common see I don't know if this
is somebody with SAP knowledge or
somebody from SAP it's not as close to
your
again you can have a look at that if you
like and that made us think I'm
what I actually the risks if I am
customer in a hosted installation what
can happen to me
so let's show you
I'm 20 different ways of SAP
hosting that can be applied first one
being multi-system hosting
so I if you on a multi host
much a system hosted environment you are
one of these boxes
one of these boxes somewhere in the
internets
at the hosting provider may be in the
cloud I have no idea
the only thing that is relevant to this
year
your books maybe your own which the one
you have holes that
but the box is maintained through SAP
Solution Manager
so Solution Manager it's one of the mmm
newer components in the SAP landscape
that basically managers all the
installation
allows you to deliver pictures and stuff
like that
it also allows you to get information
about the SAP systems
that are maintained get collect data
make
I'm statistical analysis of what's going
on in the system's
and stuff like that so now we have to
know
in order for this to work in order for
solution in order to be able to access
all of these machines what is the
requirement the technically we climb
into the ticking a precondition that
Solution Manager can actually talk to
all those
host its other clearly
yet
network traffic and use them systems
thank you very much
first-line so there's basically a
connection from the Solution Manager
going to all those holes that system by
bitch solution is a can connect
it even gets better these connections
technically stored in SAP transaction SM
they have credentials associated with
them so
the username and password for those
connections is in
the connection stort on the Solution
Manager
which means if I am on the Solution
Manager I can simply
if I have the authorization to go
tourist attraction to to do something
I can access all systems from Solution
Manager
all of the connected systems in the
entire hosted environment
maybe on this one is company a company B
Company C if I'm here
I can excess all of them demo
had let's have a look its among those
up about to to mention something in
order for
for the state exchange to take place
because I said it collects information
and stuff like that
there is to substantially large
packet of cold with in the bases systems
within the bases installations of all
SAP Service
I'm which is called the solution is art
with Lakin
STPI answer a plaque in with I'm
a lot of functionality that solution is
a can leverage in its in all
these systems on Etsy 55 my solution
managers
up it's a call to other so
so and for example
bf this object this is one of the
packages
part of the STP I'm just to give you an
idea about
the magnet should be sought sup packages
of this component and this %uh packages
again sub packages
and be looking at
on the specific Wong functioning
so and with in the functional groups
they are
function modules which which is code
that I can call
and this is basically mostly all code
that can be called remotely from the
Solution Manager
so it's a lot of lot of court within
just this
individual functional group and if you
have a closer look just at the
description of what these things to
get the list of involved RFC connections
SQL buffet race read to retrieve SQL
buffet race
a what else but has to be half year I
wanted to show you
the the pub possibility to call in SAP
transaction through this
of course you all this read
authorization to do it but the technical
potential is there to execute its
retrace for example delete
the %ah trial let's have a look at the
source code of this specific function
module
just left some idea
so what the first up is it does
remove RT of islets click into that NBC
very
very well done there's an authority
check and it checks
MI entitled to the lead the fight so
this is not an exploiter something it
just shows you what it does it checks is
the call authority authorized and then
just deletes the dataset provided as
input which means
on the other way if I turn this around
if I am authorized to call this
I can provide to find them and delete
whatever fight I want on
the posted system in brackets including
lock files
if I have the authorization so
was just to get an idea about that
that the software installed on all these
systems caller from Solution Manager is
a lot of stuff
of course I need the right spot I'm
customers
tense in order to simplify the
installation
to give the Solution Manager large
strides
excessive rights to do whatever it needs
to do on those systems
so the changes are that your hosting
provider may have misconfigured
the Solution Manager with to extend the
bride's allowing
somebody on this box to basically doing
nasty things on all those books
saw
let's look at this little closer the
solution
up at sorry I forgot one one minor
detail
I'm if you look in now on a single
installation on the left side
if I'm in a host the books there's also
at the back
through the Solution Manager it's not
that the solution to call its me and get
something I can also call the Solution
Manager and ask him to do other things
so they are also connections from each
of those books suspect to the Solution
Manager
which means theoretically I can on this
box
helped the Solution Manager because I
have a connection to it
from the up pic into all the other
installations
in your third environment as a risk
so therefore Solution Manager has a very
high attack surface because
all of the hosted companies inside
they also environment can attacked the
Solution Manager because they have a
connection to it
if the Solution Manager falls that the
entire
system falls all the connected systems
fall with the Solution Manager
also many Solution Manager applications
which you can run on such major
object-based
you can call them from with with a GDP
and execute them
and specifically a critical audience
solution to can result in access to all
the it up
of the host the company's
let's jump over to a solution Manager
System
just again to show you a little bit
about
and just pick some components from
Solution Manager on
is all basically Rep
services
well okay this is the list of I'm
met applications on Solution Manager
that are available
I'm the grey ones are turned off good
sign the black one saw
accessible so there's just a lot of
stuff
again topic higher tech service of
course most have been switched on
however
the host the may do some something wrong
and made
turn on too many of them and these can
be then called
from the outside so
yup
and we also see there's a specific one
call it a GS book center and this is
also black now let's look
what you can do with that saw
just copy the couple of the ones we have
just seen
here to the presentation and now
what do you think it's them most
not intelligent thing you can do with
the Solution Manager
if you are a host up or a company
what is the most not intelligent thing
you can do with it
portrait on the Internet
exactly thank you very much let
the rest my presentation so I'm i'm too
lazy with this link
are
thats let's just use this one
the 80 S Works and I'll room
ca
through Google search simply one of the
patterns that I can find
in in there on ICU
logon on made on which means logon log
on
these are Solution Manager on the
Internet
accessible via Google very easily now we
can
I think visiting the lock on page
doesn't really hurt
arm let's take some summer
maybe this okay bad luck
tell us that that take another one that
one again without any specific
means and now I'm on a lock on screen of
Solution Manager
on the Internet which is actually I'm
not blaming the specific company or
person I don't want to blame anyone but
it is not really
the best idea to do something like that
and its even for us
if those companies then still have tea
for possible sector I'm not trying
anything is just
showing you that some people have the
idea
or maybe its negligence or whatever and
put their solution manager online
maybe also accidentally there was even
an audit with a customer and
I'm we told the customer a
you know that your solution is on the
internet that that's really not a good
idea guy
and they said we don't have a solution
manager but the hosts ahead
his solution is on the internet and they
didn't know about it and this is really
a big risk so
actually Solution Manager itself it's
like an empty box there's no business
data in its
its it's like a because with nothing in
it
it's just a technical thing and saw most
companies so many companies think
why should I put this thing there's
nothing in it unfortunately this
empty house has 10 minutes to all your
house as with all your values and your
entire city
that's why you should protect Solution
Manager there's nothing in it but the
that it's the key to everything else you
have
so this is for scenario 1: the risk
that the solution address unprotected
potentially in the internet you see this
is not a myth that happens
and even if it's not on the internet one
host the company can go through
through those the excess through
Solution Manager bitches all this they
otherwise it doesn't book
break into solution engine may be
through a zero-day
own solution manager and then all all
other host the company's
this is one way of a tech if you want
even if you an isolated boxes
well thing next think the signal system
I'm is means multiple companies
are installed on the same on the very
same SAP machine
this can be done by SAP's
way of client separation so SAP all of
you work with SAP know if lock in
I always look into specific line these
guys can only go to climb forty-two
these guys
only 223 and no one connects the Conexus
Klein 007
cell this is a a way of having multiple
different organizations
on one system without the ability to
look
at the other guys on the other
organizations data
this is a very good mechanism it really
works at least
inside companies in hosting scenario it
has certain risks so
let's look shortly how this works
so you have an idea how SAP is actually
enforcing this kind of
of thing not come close this one
so if I'm displaying any table
any client dependent able the first
thing I see is the first column in this
table
called months which is the abbreviation
of the German
got for clients Monday Oct no and
all the tables that have this this type
of day term
type they don't month in the first place
are restricted to a single client the
other clients can't get at the state on
either reading or writing
now how does SAP and force this saw
I'm going to show you this honest to1 so
I'm just
activating the database excess The
Secret race
by default it's usually off because if
you turn it on it will kill your hard
drive
I'm before I do that I switched to
transection CAD
and
okay what I do years this is a simple
program that simply select something
from this table
and you see in this select I do not
specify the column
month but the Klein column it's not in
there so
supposedly this should give me all the
data if you're thinking sequel
now let's see what happens aiight with
better now on this stress
database excess trace the execute this
program
it does something we don't care what it
does the trace of
and be analyzed trace me that
looks now we have out of
this was just one click a knife that
race like that
I'm let's have a look at where yet this
is one
my programs that hosted one if you look
at
at this cryptic stuff now BC that
to select is here and
it now includes away a restriction to
the month
so this is something that happens in
side the SAP kernel
the kernel takes all the sequel
statements checks are they
addressed to a table with which has
climbed relevant if yes I automatically
restricted to this Klein so
the court cannot get the open SQL code
cannot get and data
of the other clients so far the theory
which means if the host the companies
have their custom code
and all companies have custom code to
some degree
their court is supposedly not be able 2x
estate of the other with the company on
the same cell
supposedly sup
okay so what are the risks
I'm if you know open SQL from
mississippi you know they are
three ways to bypass the client
separation of the SAP server the first
is to use the specific explicit option
Klein specified in the open SQL
statement
the second is to not use open SQL in the
first place but
use xx esculent execute native see clip
which does not have the ability to
separate back lines and the third is to
use
the other database connectivity
interface bitch allows you to
yeah compile whatever stream and send it
through
to the database drive up so these
through have no implicit protection and
even with the implicit protection it can
be turned off
so let's jump over you know any
that one this time have another
Ford report the what is due
the first one just counts the entries
I'm
of the table so its only our client
because the month and is automatically
appended
the second one says I count Klein
specified
from a different client so I even say
I'm I'm inclined 900 I try to read from
911 on and the third one says
Klein specified which means take away
the client restriction
and I don't specify anything which means
I read all the date up if you execute
this BC
outline its fifty two datasets 911 has
and all together on all klein's the ID
two entries which means
technically if I can write code I can
get
at the data all the kleins on the same
SAP system
so
arm and this is the risk you have to if
you in a single system hosting system
any custom up quoting can access audit
of almost the company's
you're sitting all virtually in the same
boat if you are hosted in a single
system
if your host that allows any of those to
deploy custom court
this customer can then access all your
data read it
ride it change it whatever they want to
do with that and also any SAP
all day that allows cross Klein excess
can also resides in access to all of
your data
and what kind of o'day classifies as
allowing cross client access to your
data any up command injection
vulnerability on yourself up
qualifies for that any native secret
injection qualifies for that
and any generic Ross Klein vulnerability
which means
generic alt by SAP develop 2x estate on
other clients
I'm doesn't sound like
there's such a thing but it is in this
is what we're showing in this talk
there's actually
two functions as it be provided generic
functions
one function says I'm allows me to name
a table
and retrieve all entries of this table
from every client I truth
and the other function as the pier it
says I hefty
potential to again specify a table and
override
any data in the table I choose across
clients and missus
installed on all SAP systems and can be
even called the RFC
and now this is a time where where I
hand over
the microphone shoe kinda thanks
yes okay and now
I will show you how's this look like
being the real
assisting
okay we have a system 660 so
now
and again
okay we have to assist him twice
and once under 610 900 we have a
user name pair ca on the 100 and the
password is
choppers okay so
and as a side log on
with the client and I 111 Ananda
user is CIO night
111 so the password yet because the CIO
always think everything's Hickory
secret so the pass it on also supra so
snowing
where in both says 10
conducted okay you can see here
so we on the client 900
and on the right side on the client
911 so there's a chance action is he
16 up that can show that a both
there's a dummy
table we prepared celery
to some I made a tying site and way
there's no data here Siro
on a nine hundred so
what we do now is try to use to
and user here on the left side on
900 client tend to get access date
and to the date Honda right side okay
and is somehow boring to just show up
some lines thing the SAP you up
we so what we do a and Jess already
mentioned that we have
to holidays recorder to SAP two years
ago
and as a remote function and enabled
that weekend just called them without
writing a single
I have called so I will go
both sustained
were actually on there's a
there are a lot of prohibited and
ability to call a I
see remote function call so on
yeah we developed our own pool it is
better
is this a as a possibility like ma ko ng
Microsoft Excel or JavaScript VBScript
I'll possible so a/c see here this
we have Arctic sea's P persistent and we
this is really important we under
clinton i 100
we're using the user hecka 900
okay which had to connect
and we want me to date her
you remember that actually there's no
data on the
Klein 900 however
as the results that we have order date
her
pump other client here that means we
have
read access tool other crime so what we
as Kendall
yes there is somehow my name's here
and fine and mystery I'm not satisfied
with mister
on yeah so
what I need to do is yeah and put more
in K
okay
we can read it again
now my salary explode
HAARP
so what we
as can do here we could for example the
eap and we can change the been to mine
yet phone on my both change that you've
been for example okay
and now I will show you another exploit
'em
yeah we still stacking from the client
in a hundred
and what we want to do is to
find a pitkin so
but I do he s first is I won't get
order using this form and this is 10 so
from 902 911 where
I got the you the list at the CIA own I
have 11
and looks interesting so I want
attacked him okay
so with we have fun the user name okay
you remember the password fonda CIO
night hun
111 it was thicker so what what
but I want to do is I want to make it in
secret that's the
user CIO 9 and a okay
so exploit walks I will show you that
they explode really works up
okay some
problem with Windows ok so
which had to abandon on client
911 and the user both CIO 9
im so now eating Syrian
crew okay wearing
here
on our when Chinese testing the system
that means
your the CIO has today his company must
shut down the system for five years
as they fix said so
that's not enough i hecka because the
hecker yes so that the CIO we'll
notice it and that so what we do is
okay in Pennington and the function has
restore
okay we want restart the postulate fonda
from the CIO it works again
now which I to log on again
Ste stay under and 911
to you this CIO
now I tits euchre yeah
wearing me again so
actual weekend restart the password at
the ASI I want
notice it and his account was hijacked
yet for your attack
could to everything what he want yeah
that this was
with me thank you great here so
basically this just making the point
that
in such an environment I'm you can
actually
either with custom code or with your
abilities in sub-standard
excess other clients data so now I'm we
did a survey on
almost two hundred different custom Colt
installations by SAP customers around
the world analyzing their cold
and how much custom Colt performs
crossed lined excess
in there no in in their own internally
developed court how many
program so how many occurrences of cross
client excess
do you think is common inist in the
average standard custom installation how
many times do you see this
unusual way of passing crossing the ball
to another client
explicitly in the cold rally
okay it's seventy six times on average
custom installation of
around 200 systems this happens this is
we can debate if it's really or not
against the two sticks can be used on
Verizon but this is the number
I'm and again how many occurrences of
the explicit
Robert Klein specified to BC in the SAP
stand out
what do you think of many other more or
less than 76 I hear more
first second someone else
2000 plus occurrences in the SUP Stand
that the Jews last
I'm not saying hello SAP I'm not saying
that the supportability I'm just saying
be so occurrences were caught
its accessing data on a different client
so now let's have a look at
CVSS guide from first or
who is familiar with CBS thank you very
much
quite a lot of you I'm CD assessed on
its supposed to give people an
an idea about how severe a problem if
if you look at and what their
confidentiality impact this partial
there's considerable informational
disclosure access to some fights as
possible
but the hacker doesn't have control over
what is obtained on the scope of the
date of this constraint an example is a
vulnerability that the values only
certain
tables in a database certain tables
complete
there's total information disclosure
residing in all system fights being real
the attackers able to read all systems
data memory fides et cetera
this is the advisory
for the vulnerability related to the gym
Eric cross client
read access by ASAP you can download
this and twice as notes
we Senate recipe 13th of February 2012
it was fixed 14 of Martin
may in 2013 page time for 151 days
I don't know if the slot
or not I don't I only work with SAP
security re
I don't break other things just a sleepy
so I don't know if these numbers on
industry average
original not just fact these numbers are
there
I'm the CVS s rating for this cross
client
information disclosure we showed you
before is 3.5
and the confidentiality impact is
partial
I don't comment on that is just one SEP
put in the note you can think about this
yourself
whether this what make you install such
an old quickly or not
let's look at the integrity impact CVSS
again partial integrity impact
modification of some system fights
information as possible
but the ticket doesn't have control over
what can be modified mmm
on the scope of what they take a can
effect is limited so if you know ASAP
you know that 99 percent if not more of
all the information is
in the database genetically to access to
the database cross client gives
me access to 99 over nineteen percent of
all the data
generic write access to the database
gives me write access to ninety-nine
percent if not more
all the date on the SAP system so now we
can debate if this is a partial I this
is a complete integrity impact if I can
delete
or modify and corrupt data as I wish the
same
for availability
what can happen these you can read this
stuff later that is already online the
talk I'm
if you want it you can download it right
after the talk
I'm again here's SAP's note that fixes
the specific right excess water ability
again center ASAP on the same date 13th
of February 2012
fixed a up April 2013 415 days
much time till till it was available
CVS educating 6.0 impact
on integrity partially on availability
partial end interestingly
confidentiality partial for right excess
attack
something so summary
no statistics no lies I'm
if you are a host that make sure
that your host that a installs all SAP
security notes in a timely fashion
otherwise you are prone to this kind of
attack
it specifically ask him if the two North
we showed
the earlier are really and start because
if they are not they are like the Swiss
Army knife for an attack up
check if your holster allows custom call
probably yes they do but
how do they deal with this custom court
how do they prevent that
one of the other hosted companies may be
a competitor of you
is just at the hosting service with no
data
some custom code and wants to break into
your stuff ask them how do they deal
with custom called how do they make sure
the other custom code does not affect
your data
also check with the holster if you're
not in a really shared environment in on
one system
how the host that mitigates risk related
to Solution Manager how the hosts ahead
in Solution Manager connections
authorizations is it really hot in town
to the necessary minimum
other services offline and froth and
foremost is the solution engine of the
whole certain not
online so and also ask if the host
there's
performing penetration testing security
audits on a regular basis
by SAP experts by sup security experts
like I'm Alexander Paul your call from
from Russia or
other companies like virtual porch re:
SNC or
I'm whatever the ones on the on the list
so that other companies that have most
sup security know how you take someone
that really knows what they're doing
Mike Gatto sorry I forgot you in the
back you also an expert
take some guy that knows what they're
doing that's %uh not some penetration
guy
cell I'm if you have further interest in
SAP security topic here's the link to
all block
if you have I'm interest in this
specific talk it's already available
as PDF or download you can try now to
scan the QR code if you like
download it otherwise it will be
distributed after the troopers
conference
no QR code scanners okay then we can
skip to the last slide
if you have any questions now would be a
good time
thank you very much for your attention
yes
ok
every hotel bus who is this
means the Rams his
here is all
almost every company it has my blessing
this is also has the most lead
also very common you would say no
solutions manager his
K is no excesses through a single point
said you entitle as don't live who
doesn't
the Internet you
courses minutes important SM
59 with all the other person who makes
you see all this is a I'm
world much nice
much more usable posted jules is
his strong full
this could be an interesting approach
I think I'm its where law
II really I don't know if this is
possible
house
holes
is
I'll holes
on
Ross
I'll
is
all home
loss
school
moms
his
cool
school
you holes
summarizes well in a situation where
your cell
called for other companies yes this is
exactly the case
his these officials even more insecure
here but there definitely is not her
either once with my lines
and depends on walls castle exploits for
you are individuals is the solution I I
don't really know it's possible
have solutionsr and her client
11 next I don't really know well
home
or
yes right was it destroys the
grill holster yesterday via
interesting secure discussion white
people weapons
soils were here from her eyes thanks
what sponsors
there well companies are only a trickle
all kind of attack this is a test score
the audience
for their they talked on this is not a
Whore
us because there's yes all the different
things because
role there are very many as a here
bread yesterday's sup
10 stuff take back towards
yeah haha supposed
in the whole environment its even more
problematic because it is a
because other companies have that power
to deploy
close and Ron custom call with that look
haha we have I one this
her well here
writer their was any other
their his
and
yeah candles low privilege were
for all the different individuals
systems however
sis solutions as calling loss all
different functions
it's very the growth finds these
says authorizations that makes sense
since the
make a system operation with this this
is
there's it means his
its it can drop read other
ger
also ours
is an hour he doesn't really matter
sexual this literature
bills running with these are exempt
workers
you can simply access
we did Bieber looking to the button is
also her
if it's OK for the best all
good chance that your or
old
court
soon
right
I mean definitely you cannot stop
his Ruth residual
should not be exposed positions began
also discuss of both world
people any other
okay thank you very much and Bon Apetit