welcome and good morning welcome to talk
about what happens when the Sun stays in
the summer
we gonna talk about their abilities
today a
and how to find them identify them as
are whether it already introduced us my
name is very much like
and my friend who is not the Joseph I
work as a mofo analysts and in my spare
time I like to the reverse engineering
expression before the challenge was
particularly hard us we all know that
there are so many females
in that business that to chance was like
howie overran by
participants on know this project that
we present today
and tits can you feel it for me but they
think
Maltese more specialist Center
bio focus Inc a my spare time a day to
day there
and that's it basically right and today
we have a long list of the 10 tell you
which the gun
tried to speak up because not everyone
sorry on we don't talk about
vulnerabilities
most particularly well how to find
in passed on that offer and gonna
percent
approach to came up with to ultimately
spot vulnerabilities in binaries my
particular
be focused on Windows binaries
especially when the seven
am gonna show you a solution for
approach
how you can fine for her abilities 17
leveraged by
dipping them with whens it like this is
all concept
is not that new somewhere no what's new
with our project that we tried to
automated and make it fast and easy to
use are we can show you them lie about
how to use our 20
and financials our results potential
police that we found without tool and to
the church
why would we want to find
vulnerabilities in software some might
have heard that there's a
can shady business a being serviced on
a little Billy's just people who find
them as people who want to
by the hospital want to so and those
people who want to exploit them
so we have a virus people being
interested in 10 billion the big group
of people
actually working on that business and
well we have that right to percent
solution
for these people to make their work
faster weather so this is what on their
abilities
home I put water on that flight from
very famous security researcher muslim
chick North
more have to kill his names first layer
who wrote place definition of Billy's
and how they
are being created basically i the brady
misconception
or about programming but some problems
and that they can actually be used to at
TEKsystems
I'm pretty sure everyone in his family
with the term exploit Mayo
posts how to use exploits to actually
split that its systems and her systems
and should not worth and eventually
maybe effect systems are still
information
and as we all know there's another box
up 34 the news
there's more and more vulnerabilities
been discovered and exploited and
detected
and maybe even patched but in fact
there's love them
%uh still on pitch other um
particularly no pets available for
specific abilities
or systems with their abilities which
what
actually already have available purchase
but I'm not patched
in the end and so stable level on the
Internet now for people to know
Chuck Norris's we found a very good
PULTURE him under in trucks a particular
like this one
ripped it from a website where you can
actually by T-shirts
with printables not make marketing
thought that's a pretty cool idea don't
let him decide those shirts and self
pretty awesome alright how to find
vulnerabilities
home this is actually
abrasion some racing like almost
not everything that you can do to find
vulnerabilities just the most important
fact
all feasible way will be a vacation
penetration testing
are balls including fussing which is try
to morph
input for specific interfaces
of an application an ounce tried to get
ok we're behavior try to find crashes
actually
so if an application crashes it's always
a good hint that there might be
are fuck in there that could eventually
maybe exploit another approach would be
reverse engineering
which is kinda to this issue ever tried
to reverse engineer binary
on takes long time and it's hard to find
in
animali in there as usual your physician
you're trying to find
functionality not arm functional
shouldn't happen
in a binary other physical approach
source code review
are very frequently than by a dedicated
companies I think this
as a security service to review the
source code
of standard application to find bucks in
there
and to allow the vendor to fix them
incapable source of threat to Salisbury
possibly
being used by hackers to find
vulnerabilities in open source software
and eventually heck that's
or wheels listed some ideas I could be
more advanced
on lyrically search which I thought
pretty creative ideas
to simply track softer box being
reported
the might get patched at some point or
stay on past for a long time because
then it just doesn't care
but still people publish information
about books
so if his invention exploit being
written for
nonce of a book but I than ever
gets patch or is not passion again
system
the state's know people who believe it
could eventually be exploited
arm also might approach will be to
introduced boxes software
as you might know that there's a some
money you could eventually make with a
little Billy
it might be useful to just simply
bright the programmer to enter this box
and software that it could eventually
exploit later
and getting more money than you actually
paid the program intentions the book
and d approach that we concentrated on
for
our research was overseeing security
purchase
as you know if there's a will reduce
sound touch written for a
sometimes he's purchased themselves are
vulnerable
or even worse not being applied
to every system that is out there which
happens very frequently
so for our research we concentrated on
missing security patches
on when the Sun systems too good maybe a
plate
to winds late already but didn't reach
you in some platform
we didn't %uh directly reverse engineer
security patches
themselves the concentrated on the
library to def
for missing patches that were present
in the end by the entrance another 17
and get back to the box who's interested
in finding bucks
well as a mission for those brought
range people actually want to find
softbox all most fallen initially it
were
Packers just want to play with binary
and try to break stuff
brake systems for are not so much
financial motivations but just for fun
than their software companies who
actually want to find vulnerabilities
mostly in their own
products to be able to catch them and
not have the end user being
vulnerable to attacks by hackers for
example
home we have a third group on that
flight that I'm not totally sure if the
term actually
is to crack want to apply which will be
criminals we use
billy's or build exploits to
at Tech businesses or governments to
excellent read
data or arm spy
on the dedicated victim
which as we all might have hers on the
media today
yes not necessarily on the criminals
buying businesses but
something's this is a spy and
governments government spying
criminals or this is a spying private
persons
bro persons governments
some fifty much for the media might have
noticed that there's like a broad
spectrum of
interests in hacking motivations
redness and talking about it the with
group witnesses on there will be
governments
who well we don't actually officially
really know what they're doing with it
but there's got out there I believe his
name that would slow the ninos
up did more than we do about government
action to the
police arm
I'm not sure if this is openly
available information and lost when on
the move the media
I at them because I really like the
media very much into it.
actually very creatively right about
security issues that are out there in
the field
arm beyond the Rosary interested in
their abilities and belief
cuz every time once discovered their
civic report about the
from several different sites
on finally why was interested in it
although no doing it for fun maybe sets
to Hector
with Moses on ranches in some sort of a
venue
because as you heard everyone got to
stick a disinterested
police and there's actually market
involving were
pretty huge sums of money actually
change owner every once in a while
followed by a vulnerability
because usually with these on their
abilities you can make
even more money so
this is Mark Price most probably the
most trying power plant
ability research much
so let's say you found a Zillow they
invulnerability
the onto said it in and this lady is so
that basically
missus devices you can get
you can get the spices an even more but
it's oh so simple
is local eight if you adjust to develop
a
in don't have connection with no one and
you would think the Google Instant
Fiat with to sell its you going in that
with website like this CDI day went back
to zero there from you
even if it's a with with one they're
gonna pay you much money
you may get 10k mocks
and so what you wanna do
if you want to get much more money the
problem is that
the people that we link to pay the big
money want to stay
an onerous then don't want to know the
bite and usually the developer
don't want to know that he said the
black market so must be a
situation to put it within
between each other each other so this is
where Boca
come to the business the book a a is
actually have a good relationship
with the clients plan to use any big
eyes
governments organization at work with
the government's
so that does this guy developer
doesn't have so much deep information
with a balky a
but these bitch chance to be the big
money so he trusts
to give the book it touched so basically
the book here get this deal a day
from the developer the developer give
with us
the developer didn't get paid anything
give everything you have
to the Booker the Boca has fed
information
to their client day if I that everything
as requested
and then the payment is touted there's
one issue
left the money issue the clients want to
pay two hundred thousand five hundred
thousand dollars
give the money to bait mighty want to
make sure
it's not going to be patched after a
deal to
both least its exclusive see usually
a pain chunks they said let's say
every month you get 50 K if it's not
patched
so basically that day basically says
okay if it's we want it for six months
if it's a touchy with all the money
every month you with a little
so developer is happy the book is happy
because they get percent from the said
usually 10-15 percent and the client is
happy because he got
what they wanted deal with these usually
the place
use it immediately it don't waste time
because basically the by
on-demand so
what actually happened when d0 they
go to the black market basically
is being used and every time usually
ninety percent of the time
when you see this kind of thing is it's
because one of the black market
both eat in use it to have the system
and eventually
day period of time indicate discover
this is a perfect case of an office that
was used
a year sometimes two years to exploit
web sites
and eventually get out so
can you can be sure that is do it is
though their that actually four years
riding day public but not get
discovered so this is basically a little
how this system walk rights now I
understand
why people interested in with their
abilities arm
where she tried to optimize the
these interests and automating
are approached find vulnerabilities
faster I we want to be faster
arm as records we couldn't
break Morris were in the grayscale we
could make more money as
we might be in local governments began
well
can tell you arm and
just in case we would work with the
media which we don't we could
right about more cell
became up with an approach that we
believe it's pretty
also pretty simple really scary simple
and faster that actually searching for
their abilities by hand
so what makes it did worse
different different versions of when the
sled race
to spot missing patches he only slight
you can see a simple example that we
found
all by hand fan searching the court
still
which is involved with some processing
going arm
which for sure as it is involved with
processing is gonna except they did at
some point
and through some up with some point and
this is X actually
a actually exactly the library type that
we want to find something that accepts
input from somewhere
and processes some point so well we can
spot in those functions that process
user input so we could maybe
all tweak the input values that specific
political functions would handle
to eventually cause I'll for example in
touch or floor buffer overflow
or in touch on the full on the flow or
whatever modification the couple hours
to corrupt memory
in service function so here we have the
question lol
were we spotted by searching it
with I have pro all missing
safe function we face a function ass
functions that allow to check input
values
if they actually fit a given size that
the shouldn't
bigger or smaller than this concise so
in the first example you see the win7
Britian
where memories okay that's and its last
call on their
and decisive moment it's gonna be okay
that is received
by the function through the CL
through dcx basically so if you follow
this
some the cold there you can see that
EX not modifiable never but eventually
if you could manage to modify
dcx he could maybe get TX to have
a seis or to indicate a size that could
be too big for the
of its gonna be located on the Second
Sight
you see it when the situation were you
long Mott
used to actually checked size of buffer
size
that is gonna be okay that which insures
that
this size is not going to be bigger them
a specific value
shouldn't overrun so how did we find
this
very simple idea opening up by the pro
am
doing string search for the skin
function that we once
spot so we saw her I the pros
am count simply the functions
though we fund leverage: also there's a
difference so we come to the Windows 8
we have 46 appearances want
only one always equal say function
and when the when the sun's light we
found forty-four examples of this
which told us that the right to missing
the when the southern side
I have to say just because we're only
say functions missing several these are
missing
doesn't indicated there passive even
their ability
other this definitely a good hint the
there's some security missing
on the side where the counts lower
so with a simple idea we went all and
spotting to function in the library
where
on the ones eight sites thus a function
was planning on the 17 site the function
was not present
we managed to find the specific function
that will actually
eventually provide the vulnerability
so for an idea automation we
concentrated on the safe functions
was actually praise simple
and fun easy some up in
to help files like to live with that
provides us a function so when the
switch is influenced wrinkly
these definitions are provided us with
signatures with indicates a function
binaries
which occurred about type conversions
home
secure mathematical functions like
modifications or divisions
and of robotics on strings for
my location for example so concentrating
on this
so signatures we collected 130 progress
on examples here
of mathematical functions for example
who
provide secure safe functions four
editions
or modifications provide
functions to check buffer sizes for
string location
so do these functions we had
the text representation from the hell
fast
and will do nothing else than try to get
extra presentation after leverage that
we're searching
actually search for to getting
signatures in these libraries
then simple I'll just def
number of constant found of getting sick
functions
so this is our approach %uh away from
the windows library
to the dipping in checking for the
vulnerabilities
is pretty much up the middle in our
system so we take the library
and to compile it with up Rhonda X-rays
plugin
and parse the compiled version of the
library
into the database so we have all the
own signature hits of the safe functions
and leverage in the database
enough to us just simply defer to with
well simple SELECT statement database
was like the most
is to push ever soft or else we have def
Inc
of the library's and just see where arm
the constant for so we're we have more
appearances say function
and were eventually in which function we
could
find missing say function
so here's the solution the finally
implement notice
graphic is very beautiful because I
he signed it myself arm this particular
shows the whole process
of the thing that we produce me have
the library's on the left top corner
induce the pro
actually to tolstoy we produce ourselves
to decomposing Cy Falls physically for
some very short time I heard
all the source code when the Sun Winslet
leverage by
computer speakers feeling
done we nothing simpler than
parsing these files like going through
the files in searching for the safe
functions so we find for
and put them into the database just
simply the
names to function weren't found that's
the name to face a function
and eventually the council two hits to
the with her one specific
when this label function
it was really just that simple richest
conduct and put everything
into the database that uses signed on
here
don't I'm gonna talk about low that more
children
arm in there we collected all the hits
of say functions which we find the
signatures and when the slavery
and little to nothing else than just
saying but the application mention up
there
for producing diff things yep that is
actually in CSV formats so
we could very well just put it back into
database
amply their own future approach at more
when those russians to loading approach
to did
I'll between more version still
to so
was mentioned we would get the see your
presentation at the completion
using using I'm a pro and eventually up
with all the source code other ones
levers
which within put into our parsing
application which is an open-source
pipeline project
released on my get a profile that can
take all the superstitions
put them in a database and eventually
produce a diff and the civil
see later we now you can have Greek
for user justification specially
more about this in so this would manage
a lower labor reason functions and the
signature its
close to the things this against
little bitty sign so we focused clearly
on the its
is really simple it could very easily
extend the but this is actually only
need
for following the post we have arm
we have a presentation of leverage and
all their functions
and eventually all the hits of say fuck
system we find these functions
family where the differing this %uh
an example how are the things look like
sorry just very simply counting the safe
functions
into the kids functions %uh low-risk and
check we find a difference in their
very much text this would be how you
could compare our total
this is actually the most experts
documentation that's there is so far
summer as well these are the
come on plane statements that could need
if you want to use it on the command
line
there's a more Mullen statements back
here but whatever she wants she was
the gory
I'm very very proud of her color scheme
love her I'll this actually polls
follows growth arm
I admit I was too lazy to implement
multi-threading and that application
tomorrow that so I just
put everything into one going want to
face this is all the functionality of
the is
justify that by five books that we have
on their and I used to color so you can
actually say
all right now and the other books there
is all the configuration you have to put
yet to collectors and database Jeff to
arm configure the interfaces to
databases if you want to connect to mike
is a skill for example
need to put extensions right for this
can do this you can do in the
configuration dialog
alright that's a function are the most
importantly the blue box
there you can do a generation
of safe of she changed
when it goes straight either the Glee
prison
like huh works the Pink Party can do
the parsing of c-fos you can switch
between 7 and Windows 8
and in the form originally had St still
implement for people
don't have the X-rays plugin
like me for example can parcells the
first
but if as you might know like to for the
compulsion to see file
is like sicko and does tea stuff is like
assembly
which by definition is like four to five
times bigger than sick old
so as a tool which is the fastest yet
arm this country slow in Seaforth it
will take forever to use and I'll see
files for
all the ones leverage that's why we
cancel the traction
and furthermore most important pars to
defend
where can produce says we file format
the things for the
when these levers alright source if it
re: into the future and I'm gonna show
you
hold toll actually works
I hope
alright small okay so this is the most
beautiful
we ever since
call cell actually wanna say in the
beginning with tweaked a little bit
because person takes really long with
that already and
field are database before they know any
we now show you
over exam week I'll generate an ID in
the CFL
because this is actually pretty the
fullest to see other witnesses in the
probe popping up
closing down again so in the first place
you have to be fine
director if I the pro count
which DLL versus France you actually
wanna parse
yeppers here
I'm gonna go on parcel in the same
system house
should be colorful ones popping up now
if this works
alright soundly credit no yeah it'd be
generated of or when the Sun system
process and I can generate
seafront up region we have to the
protector
and now
should in their daily basis to win 7
sis faster we propose for them and now
we see how
art instruments and a pro to
decompile ATP
faster we produced before saw this
process
we should have running mates arm windows
7 source code
in I'll that they will directory and
the dot C four months it's should
devotes it cope
more or less as x-rays those numbers
were great
arm wish I could use later on for
parsing will start parsing engine and
check for the 130 signatures
there will be fine in our database as I
can maybe show you know in the meanwhile
I can't because the mistress actually it
would be the configuration dialog
where you can like
break and see the signatures do we have
the database and actually modify them
so if you find any other function you
would find interesting
for security research for under the
research
you consider here and have to to a
search for the slow or even find more
intelligent signatures
ventures the strings for having more
a profit alright
nose to toes finished we should have see
fast
in Arthur Terry can chick
in there
ISO here's all the stuff that the toll
produced
we see in their is C source code found
in the Caesars
so use to leverage for the demo actually
this is how it would look if we clean up
to 30 Torino
we'll have the celebrities in their
secret presentation as tax raise output
all right now oh do it starts the person
so
I within certain type of of my c-fos in
here
start arm yet the cation in the
background
to the parsing for Windows 7 and Windows
8 30 the pace
output which going to be a because it
takes
hours not I seeking something else just
takes like 20 minutes which is
too much for now but
if we finally did this we have a
database with another hits right
so we could start searching the database
for
are compiled library which in our case
was
once K-sixty and mr. x& Beats
10 which are not in the database a
concession stand look and see
we have these two levers with I these 13
slacker dorm
and start addition on the sled race
which means I insert celebrities here
first if it and this is your part this
is like ship it bring up cuz I admit
because it is just an one result in
there but actually pretty clear reset
that muddies not gonna show you how you
could use this to spot a potential
their ability that
physically me ask you a question why
there's a different
if michael says edit this if function
Windows 8 why so that this new window 7
there on the Edit that dialysis for this
one is saying that
money the americans love don't want to
waste
development I'm on undo oppression
system
and no one know about this issues just
then
and they want people to move to I'll
operation system
so does that isn't that still exists in
your 7
imitate and I this budget what was the
goal is for that anyway
how you can be fine if it's useless or
not if we get
10 they from this project sort it now
one assist some example
about the resort's just
likened keep talking okay
so basically is this is possibility we
find one good Zealand is
MOT now when you def
you have to choose what they wanna def
use a lawn mower
mothers ok nm others we started with New
Zealand motherless
bytes we know that there is no big
chance we found something there
in the can and there was much more
possibilities because if you get
something you can get this cation
the village so this situation is just an
example
in the Canada the thing in the userland
add
by the way I did not design ago said
yeah religious discussion about the
color seems agreed
didn't see any is not making string
sign
to run on just generating the I
be false for Windows 8 driver says it
didn't do this before
for being able to opening them up and I
the Pro and show you the actual
missing security functions which
huge crews nothing was gonna show you
some results that we
fun without dipping of
missing security
works so now I should have I DB files
the def English before Ash again
this was a K-sixty dessous
driver and there should be a potential
vulnerability in this
get a copy of identity function which is
indicated thing missing
you long at functions and
him right we have he pees in there
now
good thing
attempt
yes the basically the resort as you can
see we took on the mother's
of Windows and it gave us slow the
finest
you can see I love them specs wise
inch dick sweat and there you just open
a wonderful example
each one would tell you okay this
function appeal
one time in Windows 7 developed I mean
it's so one two three four five six
and again here in again is so basically
now your job is basically
to go 111 and check which one is a
relative in which one is not exploited
in
so the stick a few clues most of the
results
snake here is in pain CNG
you can see here in this function
convert Alice a 58 in Windows 8's
this function appear 8/9 in Reno 7
four times so first you want to verify
that this is the case so you take this
fight this
actually in this case to Divya CEng
so first thing you want to know it is
either is not in the system
just can use simple
the interview and CNG
can see it's here to see something about
the people there feel free Windows
so this night is loaded now you just
gonna go
and open FS versions of Windows seven n8
go this function and see if there is a
difference sorry so that's
in in
well
so this is seven vision Singh
you know I'm the Windows version of the
Windows 8 version of this Inc
love the same time to open
no limiting the function space into a
just to SF 6
happen
so this is in Windows 8 can see one
to the for by seeks
7 89 dysfunction was a day and if you
open the same thing
in Windows 7
you can see it's only 12 34 in
downstairs
there is no anymore continue of this a
function
so something is passively Wong if it's
exploitive in our notes
now it's another issue basically what
you do
basically tied to figure out who could
this function
in these cases export for Alice eighty
see go up in go again so this is
BK export key you go up again again
until you get okay BK
export K especially in export function
so we're here
so now your job is to figure out how
this is Tim
call this function and if you can go get
to it for me use an end
then can you get escalation the village
this case
and only if text but they were not I
know that is either case actually
exploited
even remotely in our gonna show some
other example
musician
so example here this is it the ANN
models
you can see this be caped nested
function name
here you can see in Windows 7s was edit
few
chicks in Windows 8 didn't again
this is a big day ahead net Logan though
the alleged
in Windows 8 you can see a lot of
career out at the end unknown ed
sets a function with aidid to this add
to this article
to something for and 107 no sense
function exists
exploitable not we don't know yet
but at this point it's not again
now this another the alleged DW
extension
you can see unsentimental is unknown
after
este s down and check and in Windows 7
you can see that basically not check has
been done
and again after this year than any movie
little about
shit taking what's happening divas and
you can see this
CNG the cryptography did I fail you can
say that there is few checked in with
eight
but none in Windows 7 and the one is
this
copy identify in Windows 8
Microsoft actually at the security check
well in Windows 7
they didn't so the entire idea is
basically to figure out
how to trigger from use an end to these
diverse
in the discussion P village in again
so there is a lot of a result that
actually
give us this stuff but
I can tell you that not ninety-nine
percent of them
popular sport event but one person it's
worth it for sure
you know the one this is the usual and
you can see this function
K because object stin main corporate
directly or indirectly
in here yes make sure that the thing
is not too big or expand a little about
how you figure out effect how delegates
this case
is keep DNG so basically some diana
books
that do some kinky option show you some
kitchen stuff
if any the function is the code what is
the coding
some so the fifth attributes so he does
go been here and there
and tell you about what it is came to an
end function if you do with that for
every month or something
so it's basically it's show you some
stuff about the
certificates this is the function name
him because object FBI so basically you
just need to Isis
the entire function to figure out if you
can dish it or not
and this is example the certificado
actually grow to this function so each
owe you
if that is the case certificate
information see if you put a very long
stink
miss a thing to get it's possible you
would trigger
people the flow or something like that
that's the idea that
you feel you have to figure out what is
it a good point
so the entire research was basically
just
to find the issues how to trigger them
is another issue so
next writer closing out talk
I want to tell you some think so we
plant
to implement the pitcher actually to
extend their tool
to did more than just when the 70 when
the same arm
we know there's no windows 8.1 other and
we could
very simply at this to our datasets and
create something that's living up picked
it up but medium-size
data and shit characters for their
abilities
in Windows 8 we could targets we could
very easily extend their signatures
to have more intelligence anxious than
just strings say functions
to maybe in that some intelligence to
evaluates the potential vulnerability
that
were spalding by searching
for a possibility to
traced in pavilions function that with
and first potentially vulnerability
or ideas like that
arm I also heard symbolic execution will
be an interesting thing to add to our
application
I'm not sure yet if this is actually
implement a law
and the phone we have it now but
definitely put some research on that
and were actually want to myself
is provided transplant database leverage
because right now we depend on
Microsoft's SQL
and as his life michael says the skills
not available for everyone in this July
is really really slow we try to find a
way
somewhere in the middle which might be
pastas and we have a love known issues
us we mention her a lot of us for this
like really
a lot of holes for this and love to pick
eight hits
that week tweak with signatures
you're really really slowing the thing
butter out made it so it's not really us
were slow
but tool which can work on its own
clip and the output this in CSV format
its not that hand yet to handle like
I would love to put more information for
the reaction generate
to be able to evaluate the potential
other alright well that's basically it
with our talk
I hope fun and interesting and if
there's any questions