so I'm just fooling about this supposed
to miss speakers lock what speaker
asleep and one of the speaker's wasn't
able to make it out sort of country and
you know where he is right now
it was so my topic is about clarity is
neck-deep with apology and attack
service agrees so just just a little bit
of description
it also submarine about this though I
already presented this one at DEFCON 26
at the boat level of sheet back or
academic village so we double shout when
I use your body but you know maybe not
be done soon I hope you will you will
listen or learn something from me so my
name is Gina I work as an application
security engineer at Brown
I'm a real good human since we put five
security tools open-source mostly and
frankly a lot from at this point they're
gonna be a slaughter people say that I'm
the creator of Florida millonarios
that's my last name
but I'm not that one so I receive a lot
of tweets detoxes Twitter is more like
in 2013 and I said Bill American Russian
Filipinos so I love to party and if you
want to party with us you can go to our
party and the post-op party is the
registration still going on just a
little bit
can they bring drinks - drinks - ok so
that's it so before anything else we
need an inspirational quote from the
passage of furious it's not that it's
not the right it's
the ready it's okay much nothing happy
boy this is up yet so about the Scopes
of limitations so it's smart about
people team it wants it in its attack
services indicia not totally guarding
over but thinks that you can find simple
ones that you can find in your car's
inconsistent sometime but not back today
with another DC 3d box but not cool Z
over the car so kind of similar to Jason
Haddix the bug hunters with anthology
it's actually a smart reading but it's
not it's not about 20 boxes more unlucky
box I know it's not about what the box
is an accent level well or in most web
applications but it's mostly not the car
so I don't want to miss out on that
services so if if you get after to stop
it I missed up attack services do let me
know we can talk about it maybe you can
let me borrow here if you want the
government services like breaks yet he
wasn't a note speaker Jackie and I or
Emma got our fanboys of great so we sort
of attack services some lower Wi-Fi
Bluetooth GPS ski is but we will not be
talking mostly about this attack
services will be talking about the
attack surfaces for an entertainment
cost
now we have the Bluetooth we have the
lifeline we have the USB ports we are
the SD card ports see me roam over them
even your own to talk about this one
right so I'm just gonna skip the floor
but touch screen and other inputs that
allowed to control the console quadrant
Jack maybe but I heard from Jamie there
you can actually reset but you can
actually short the audio jack and it
allows me to access the console or very
routine I haven't tried that one yet
reset the see sympathetic so it's still
an attack service so we have some of our
connection ingenious okay so let's try
to reflect on this attack services first
we have the blue thumb
because it's blue it has a couple of
abilities that's a couple of weaknesses
in fact like a month ago the new
vulnerability was discovered for this
one so things that you can do if there's
a loses it you're inputting you can jam
the Bluetooth you can not enable the
leading the guy who wants to place
Justin Bieber song on his car you get a
jam you can generate or maybe some of
the big ones yeah think you could also
do we did execute some code we haven't
seen a PLC on this one yet maybe to
research more then we have the equal
bluetooth pairing numbers yeah 0 0 0 1 1
1 1 2 3 4 so very easy to identify right
if you if you first connect it to your
car you are presented with a with the
parent numbers right
so usually those are our pool covers and
then you can set muffler or four months
free vulnerability stripped by the
device so you can break the device you
can possibly void your warranty
depends what what's on your warranty and
we have memory corruption you can say
mouth work packages to the head unit you
can actually I may have seen a POC from
B&W what about red zones that we value
so you can actually grab the blue to
snack on the car and you can override
the Eid or that of that step so here's
your simple scenario so you can you can
actually crash your a BMW car the person
X or person C for monthly specifier see
that device name address name song title
so for example your own date of your
murder devices like under some person X
person X and you increment I pretend
characters it's possible that you can
you get crashed it whether you get rip
the device the CD 2017 was assigned to a
BMW BMW that so three three zero lights
who doesn't have a car we're in a
researcher from Atlanta a really nice
device with formats prints the suppliers
so learning on it pretty resistant so
that's that their own risk
what if it makes you it's off Jesus it
will make you messed up
beep-bop options so what it after
crashing the console or infotainment
system it actually makes you to the
desktop environment or it takes you to
to disable the debug options of your
time so it's possible that if you have a
stylus and the other input signal system
you can if it takes you to the desktop
environment you can click on some of the
icons and rock on the right method movie
you get the shelter so obviously this is
the kind I'm talking about
he works at ioactive and he named the
slope minus one and connected his phone
to his feet w clark an afternoon and
breakfast device I don't know what
happened to mrs. Higgins's them but I've
seen his tweet that he wasn't able to
make his people didn't call so a console
or device running yeah
being a minute or maybe if you can do a
mini if you couldn't wear it or
diversity here please don't try this or
the one of your friend star but if you
want to try writing please don't
at least from they don't learn and Jason
Haddix github repository you can see
some pillows that you can try to connect
to donate your home phone me for you
order about the subtitle of your phone
of your music mp3 file or you can also
well that was public address if but if
you have a full address where in the
nameís versus beepers that feet versus
be and then the car connected to a small
net someone told you off with that comes
our name so you can
the difference and then we have white
wine okay most difficult even consoles
of white Mary that's the firmware update
where it over to internet so in most
consoles there's a setting where you can
see them it allows you to update the
firmware so if it does like that
try significant that work or replacing
it with a malicious sprinkler so you can
run wash art then if there is no
signature validation on the firmware
update you can change the contents of
the firmware and put it back to Myrtle
or if you can see where the the update
is the beta this and you get a check and
it may mean reverse steam for an update
so what's next
first thing that you do connect to Wi-Fi
and then it fetched up the HTTP IP
address then you ran an map then you
need to check one service doesn't happen
does it have FTP that's it counts on
that that's it SSH okay so thus have
these kind of services so here's the
scenario you are connected the part is
connected to your to a network and
something will click
but it's a lightweight what's the
historic like connected to the Wi-Fi
network so you need to find the host or
the IP address of everyone then
scattered signal and if you know it's
kind of dirty you can check if he ends
to his infotainment we have telnet or
FTP American snippet productions so some
of these interfaces of no law or no
authentication and notice your breath
Cortana is your preference
and if there are services running it
because older services you can actually
exploit the services like older older
versions of some services and yeah next
from my part so
yeah yeah no that's not my party the
stomach you miss a little bit you need
to get to know the default password of
accessing the system so it doesn't
provide you or me access and as what you
can see my car is actually running the
message and this is not a Buick this is
messed up
that's those are old passwords you have
the JC JC JC JC I use the username does
the master and I am exceeding the new
name space minus a and B are not see any
so Madison is running Madison Fatima
clocks all racks on Linux you know what
you can do with it after that's right
so I've also found some good plc bro no
not only a cool opieop Siva that
different that I'll be made from pocket
escape access to the Ivy on would you
say I di
it's the umbilical entity systems
remember most log n + 1 so they weren't
able to share the music but this is what
they did based on the spread that they
have they were able to access the show
and it's running at Q and that's because
most people DeMuth runs with limits you
annexed and some new brought with us or
blackberries the UNIX for with those
those were usually
flirt arming third party in whatever
cost
and here's another one that's from
Auggie that he was able to dentists
plugging in he was able to gain the
channel also knowing that the full user
even faster so that white people your
doors suddenly have strong passwords
they have people passwords so you can
reach for cells you can use hydrilla
really confuse some Metasploit plug some
garages for example telnet service for a
station service then we have some gigs
the waste from target alert so they look
at 2015 beagles this is a big difference
between Kentucky and same browser happy
2015 is an old browser but still 2002 be
a monster
you got for me in are still very diesel
cars
forget about at the end whether but it
is filling a second in fact you get
three dots of that Clark's unlike
browser happy so if the Buckshot ran
away
it's patch rapidly and returns only a
few weeks from now your ex what was
before it with four cars it's not really
like that
so eat the more you should represent
this multimedia me on Twitter and he
said thank he then did before included
his research on the s my end of duty
vinyl with in addition so we connected
the device over TCP port without
authentication and executed the men's
soul but now we're not gonna implement
some Wi-Fi in every net he's young the
services or the network
maybe I'm interest and was able to get
Java service RTC by
neck notes and env which
and because their stomach so we try to
tone it to the IP address of the scar
and there's no authentication no
password right away tell them in the IP
address that's it no indication so it's
very insecurity and you know this is one
of his findings so USD were previously
undergarment achievement you can excel
to have score of malicious types you can
update the firmware via USB
now you can do Marcy via the USB spec to
buy the eye or if you have a killer new
speed with which if you look like
introduce me to your laptop it will
Brian order immediately or erase some on
your issues you can use this one at one
of the car set and if it detects there
at you you just be like for example
without any nomination so you can it's
possible you can destroy your enemy none
and then if there's no internet on the
car one of the recommend is to have a
USB to Ethernet adapters by default so
adapter because subsystem support unity
community to either this is another way
for me to get the interests of your I
really so romantic my case since I'm a
mess developer myself so people are
supporters the makeup and Molly and
falling caps quarter in putting with
using little bit up and exe file called
messed up all-in-one
so I tried to turn why don't we but but
like
read some soft medium pile not provided
my messed up from the internet so he W
media I wouldn't wear a kippah
must not get that vote so you can see
the instruction is that there's actually
a website before that allows you to
update or forget some data on your
master to getting us meet so try to
check on how palettes done and on one of
the textile is actually executing notice
this line on line joining so s finish
maybe have well this is not the actual
strip it's from the strip tonight don't
want to fight so messed up as a sprint
that allows you to get some bigger so I
tried to check out that script and
created leo script just to prove that
you can actually create the RC easier or
execute something that's year ago and
that's the one it's open source right
now
a beetle see that they USB port is it
back surface yep it's either it's
running analytics and because of when
buddy if you if you mill to the Salinas
a slide something this is the first SMS
commanded read that was used to see that
they actually give apprentice to the one
that I wrote so and then it known that
they use also my script in order to get
not together
the the rap to their caller
yeah this is the sh pilot they have the
railroad yeah this is the video but now
it's done okay so sorry for the chicken
but the video not snip it off so I
copied a clone the VLC that I did and
there's the USB where it works them but
they are there they're still here and
unaware that canary came from so you
need to wait for like a few seconds and
it will execute the file so we wait wait
so yep it was able to write necklace rip
and yeah execute this one so execute
unique space by the C business yeah so
yeah yep
so this is the o because of the one that
I I did one of the guys who created the
SMS rap they presented this party
village they provided more info about
what I did and that's it they created
their own SMS commended rap so remote
administration too
another the suretrend the one
responsible for it but you know it's
just a plc for them it's just a fuse and
that's where I rest my case
if you're glad to report me to the
police
you don't need to uh I won't get to jail
as I read even part of his celesta and
everybody talked to them during the bar
tacking village Lassiter
not this year so now I guess the case
people from kids security lab also found
local code execution UST they haven't
provided PLC for it but it's what you
can see they were also able to execute
its elements meaning space and of your
this is from we have TT also so so BMW
did you can it currently runs a smooth
soap sdcard another attack service so I
don't have an exact POC for this one but
it's basically the same thing but what's
this custom gave us before so you can
you can explode accident you can remote
something and there is actually a
open-source application that allows you
to test or great apps for your mess them
so custom application SDK and get write
your sinful dashboard create their games
I want a great boom but I don't know how
blatant regard but they don't know
next is touchscreen interface 30 seconds
that's not my card that's wonderful
you can make this Wi-Fi to establish IP
address and you can connect to your
interface that wish I'd be addressed and
you can perspective well don't multitask
first of all so if you do hold an S key
there is a possibility that you could
over 200 or or it costs a crashing
territory and so what you can see one of
the there's a problem that means that it
runs on Windows that maybe does what it
does that it's much like I mean they'll
see were forgot what Bridget look
wonderful one of the moons actually when
you were still ripping Ennis a certain
company that is where I worked in
jammies so he just like consoles on
first look for his implicated console
see that that's not requirement and
there you can that means that the
infotainment console is face off a son
sandbox applications reportable agency
spot so after that he must people to to
interact to the imitator he just needs
to click but the exe file there's
actually a YouTube video where you can
want your course level one or other
cards when you get three easy steps
have you heard of this news so we're
gonna put it but I make though so you
can see there's a poster design you so
it's not true you getting this under
course right if you just push the the
factory knows about reset that the
factory of spa settings you can it will
take you to the console if you have a CD
but it's not true it's pretty much like
minimum X so we have an outlet character
next aircar so this is one of the attack
service for GSM cellular connection on
active our
they so most cars if yeah an implement
implement a consular device you can
actually enter it it's usually paired
with a mobile time right it's usually
carry them Obama so I don't have an
exact you'll see because that's what
this kind of things and I know my
dominated submissions related to some of
this next weekend I can't show it but
just to give you an overview before that
Troy one actually pointed out that his
implement the Thurston at for me sound
[Music]
but I mean so yeah before I get some
description on the application for
reverse engineering Freeman actually has
a PLC that he tried to intercept the
request from his mobile app for recently
because they simply allows me to control
the steering wheels of your recent deal
because it's the hybrid electronic it's
the electronic car that went black red
color
it's a spiritual art and he tried to
intercept the another request from the
app so we're here at birth and then
conduct request he was able to see them
it doesn't mean authentication so as
long as you know the bid number of
someone's listening you can think over
the car as long as it's connected to you
an LG energy pretty much very dangerous
so you can each run with the connections
as well if it's like I said I don't know
about PLC would have to reverse engineer
yeah but it's very easy to do so I don't
want to break or to be fired is a
company that I work with but if you get
anything out if you like it out you can
reverse engineer it
for example if it's running on the apk
you get an actually see song API piece
that allows you to
interact with some of the features of
their car that's it
[Music]
if you are interacting you can actually
report box to xe8
it's a background app called /fc name so
we hear it too far I reckon please do so
submit their box and if you're into
happy Tesla you know if you own a Tesla
you can also submit bugs to our network
if you have Jacob and you also want to
have your car you get submit so dr. Wong
comm / JD Erin so why are you so whether
it worth it what are the companies and
you get okay so maybe eh so you know the
cornice one of the ones is a one point
one quick development like the interest
and there's JCI the reason why I was
able to get to know why haha
echo what you just commend it to your
car is because the gzi allows you to
input something not sure what the GZA
means but it's one of their
manufacturers or infotainment so
fortunately that allows you to do
something so entertainment will like
echo what you did or echo what you did
not get one
well when the demo on 815 bleep up so
dancing these are my references and I
really attack way up great so if they
don't make some you know memes from
Google and of it must uh as that weeks
and some could be a song snakes that you
can reference if you want to research
more of course and that's it
do you have any questions my question
what open networker questions
[Applause]