[Applause]
[Music]
this isn't right but we are a start-up
Commission the National piracy
commissions were prevention
because researchers challenge for us
because awareness was low in the general
understanding practicing in the practice
introduction on dated by the sea was
know about information security breath
InfoSec very fine cuisine very nice and
Russia and we confusing so in the past
you usually never need to do in Ba Sing
where yeah but you've also probably
murdered the depart is being race now
normal this course even in us Dennis the
drug was response center so in
corporations possible big the privacy
that departed from server room ladder to
reach the warden agree
may be talking about that those of you
coming from the corporate I think you
would agree navajo must be the
consummation yes
but Stephen had a lot meaner to repel
why we're doing this as Kapalua country
wants to go it's ambition pretty
important he provides that the gun toe
is a high dress society where everybody
in the security in their physicality to
the lines in leading in the simian
communities this include living in
society recovering at businesses are
trusted those actions are pretty less
where everyone enjoys the boots of
individual autonomy surely is going to
be a fully digital society by 2014
but it's not only our stay in this room
in fact some of our neighbors of the
Asian region the guy ahead of us in
tracking his path to develop this is
already costing the partnership of
economies measured in how wealth is
created the scientists study mean and
teasing the global theta e century world
fortunes were made by those who saw
[Music]
[Applause]
all right but going back let them speak
all right I'm gonna say they don't even
know me well but the event per century
receiver an opportunity well used to be
was water the price we global economy
per century the super an opportunity
commute man Stephen comes the most
important resource in worldwide markets
transformed by fast changing digital
technologies you have the world's
largest accent compañeros weakness yeah
it's largest media over there Facebook
the world's most viable leave me there
and power in the world's largest
accommodation for my creativity this
community that was this company so much
an opportunity fortunes made but nearly
two decades al-abbas and just not indeed
has become the reward traditional
industries all necessarily they can cite
in the McKinsey study all national
advantages like desirable locations on
growls superior logistics and even
incumbency could use their brilliance in
their laces will be digital skills
centering and generating using sharing
and securing new countries that will
appear red shift will be left behind
quickly and countries who can grab this
opportunities kept cashing their me the
country's Department of ICT plays the
biggest role in Bishop the program's
lead by Adi I see from building is
infrastructure strengthening capacity
and support to startups lesson in
transaction costs in Barbara will all
lead towards making the country even
more effective in today's digital
markets the National privacy Commission
has a role to play as digital perception
expands so are the risks press and Mars
to individuals protecting citizens have
gone beyond patrolling the streets and
the country's borders data is the new
asset and personal data is the new
target from 2005 to 2014 cross-border
low heat has ruled 45 times reaching a
peak of 210 terabytes per second let's
pivot about 1.6 billion selfies per
minute the tech analysis company Kroger
is estimated as of 2017 eight point four
billion objects are projections of this
McDowell by 2020 the Internet of Things
is right it arises every conceivable
object to
to engineer a struts for Derby the Blues
replace traditional treatments clothes
globally the clarion call for this for
the responsible and accountable use
security data especially personal data
within Africa demeanor Privacy Act of
2012 we deploy the community of nations
and other jurisdictions the operate
under privacy regimes to protect our
citizens na the subjects through e we
are remember international conference of
data protection and privacy for
missionaries there are 119 piracy
jurisdictions all over the world today
information about legal food evils are
being processed
meaning Aladdin use share story and
dispose are mrs. F degrees currently in
wider effect on the individual with the
introduction of the cloud the potential
to process information about practically
everything and about anyone this year of
course there is much potential for
delivering this information can be
stored and accessed in this morning's
environment
matched and community this has resulted
in repeats in healthcare government
services and more efficient
constructions that brought modern
conveniences in the lines and I mean one
but there's also potential for miss news
for wrongly Selina an authorized
disclosure they were Street unfortunate
news miss users could lead to
discrimination and fail decision-making
loss of reputation and personal autonomy
especially when sensitivities about the
race in
orangie well religious leaves are used
to come up with assertions about there
and he was too merciful when I read in
the United States
sixty percent of human resource managers
admit that meaning the maitre d readings
when deciding whether to accept a
person's would be employed there are so
many other cases and three acquisition
making a loss of person ain't anything
that earlier the decision Mossad a ride
somewhere
also as three thousand everything
thought they had mr. Kunene to direct
what my identity was the record about it
was to an individual harness also Center
in the dynamic of a citizen's right to
exercise the truth or radius or heard
and personally like the denying to write
to be ported right axis blocking order
issue these are some of the 21st century
rats by present generation on Chavez as
she serve citizens and consumers need to
fill the watch and they expect
government to be a nuisance but in that
international weather they demands now
turned it well our lawmakers as women
that they are the people's son the data
privacy active magma coming out for all
the noble letters with a positive ID to
protect the security impact
silently all the personal information
before and by doing these were called
assuring a journey knowledge driven
economy this race will lead secretary
Carter I'm very sure strikes a chord in
what you are doing right now as a
professional as a hobbies doing it
forward to us to support it up
completely
okay but definitely this sector has a
role to play in promoting insistently
privacy so for better for worse
discipleship is not the necessity and in
this global technologies for the period
of things were actually at the base and
seen since the Industrial Revolution
those who never ago when a spiritual
reality I knew more services in fact if
you wanna see this vision as a life
lesson in fact when the general data
protection regulation took the attack
promoting rhetoric
emails announcing changes in these
processes protector inspiring the launch
of a thousand means signal or the GDP
GDP are is an amending the law if you
know business make their defy
classification started receiving so many
no disasters of conditions magnets and
you know practices of assess privacy
agreements being forwarded to this is
because of the general dental profession
speculation that we see a professional
in information security when we drove up
and preach about the sanctity of data so
that it purposes only
according to agent gobbler serial of the
EO ee is not credited as an information
security officer
never
so much protection in big information
security and the matter of that change
detection is magazine and he's investing
that we need to these corporate spending
on information security is being given
by privacy considerations this change
emphasizes the circle of growth the
information security ladies in data
privacy
Google's marketing product receives it
can be a bit in point you cannot have
privacy without security
yes you can have security without
privacy but you can never have privacy
without security as semantics peril and
years of space between privacy reverses
the loss and recognition that required
personal information controllers and
processors was a committee representing
some methods used to protect our data
security is about the impact of an event
or incident on the data that's why we
got confidentiality integrity privacy is
about the impact of an incident on the
people it was the principal actually
this but really if security is about the
CIA did not and in talk about policies
is impact of the people we talk about
the collection use storage sharing is
also if you are an information security
person and you want to our privacy as
one of the feathers on their car from
cieariy you just need to October a
mentality in 13 we have between two
police accountability in assurance
information system security is the
provenance of the unauthorized meaning
is opening balances bus there are
parentheses about governance
all the other words those who are ready
inside the organization so sometimes
when I try to explain what's the
differences with information security
what are the intersect intersects
between of intersect practices they
respected this limitation security and
data privacy delue the one who Sierra
Nevada the Muslim people guarantee is
the governance of the operands because
this is sure that all the pieces of
breaches us here 53%
well 47% are caused by pernicious
attacks from outsiders the decision this
was we studying since the bonneville
Institute forty-seven percent of global
breaches were caused by Alicia's
outsiders while typically Brissette were
caused by internal causes in Blowing
management system which things that
could have been prevented integrity if
we cover those who are authorized in 30
brother
certain impunity so many years your
industry your contact to look into the
47% but now we have to be the magazine
somebody start to look at the different
3%
somebody's got to teach employees where
the password existence protection how to
manage the emails how not clean or
authorized attachments or mysterious
attackers were suspicious-looking
attachments in a cocoon unit or one in
wallah
one thumb drives youporn yahoo summary
survey the prairies so with anything the
sheet covers data privacy beats us to a
new paradigm in productivity as I can
see area of their - agony therapy we
must stop ability and machines what is
it about ability mean the responsibility
for doing our utmost to protect the data
within more responsibility to steal
security engineering professionals when
they say assurance we mean that we
should be transparent and responsive
enough for our stakeholders for them to
know what all their data is going to be
so this is my mystery
all up in here Monica bio as the party's
leading experts on the offensive and
defensive aspects of data security you
all of you here as hackers and buyers
are in the center of every production
protection effort it is you who will
design implement the structures that
will keep our data safe when it comes to
defending the critical infrastructure or
debate that applies to be there
Norman don't worry about that you doctor
will be done some heroes keeping our you
will be in the binary
keeping threats and hazards of day so
that their Hamas leader will remain save
me but change is inevitable in our
government is no exception
the ability government is determined to
never be better as he undergoes
small and large digital
formation movements it is not enough for
government now to simply report
government must pursue rocky robust
sometimes full transformation it is not
not for us in government to just report
but we must dress worn in he must
respond digitally I think the biggest
challenge right now Martha buyer he said
our people expect government to to give
or to implement the see amount of the
kind of efficiency that they are getting
from the private sector
you know expectation this is to the
morning news it's all about citizens
complaining about global net
inefficiency needed and easier maybe a
little selfish oh very clever because
everyone the financial become okay
exactly
convenience not a domino dominating more
fruits of the digital age there will be
a no no paper anymore
they didn't matter a misdemeanor
hospital what I mean
politics is at some point over again is
to stop was a boot attack on Spain even
this you know we need to go back one
become more efficient just
we have to digital so that means again
about Musa I have been doing national
light over the next few months you will
see is being rolled out as the national
operating system
the national ID system was a pharmacist
named Sebastian pack for basic services
they'd be producing at night he takes
the very why are they ready for that
means the prevailing notion is that a
national ID system indeed the privacy
and security are in opposition to each
other the National iris sister but our
leaders to the parents of be the privacy
security this is possible this I love
you
he beat recently their mindset where our
rights that we are parenting harmony to
the needs of the patient prevalence no
we didn't have a national IV system
immune because you bust enough laws and
policies structures in place and that
experts on here to make sure that our
privacy minds and our diversity and
everything our jobs are jumping at IDC
my job as Privacy Commissioner is to
assure that the lowest follow not that
the father had decided to implement a
national army system so lastly when he
participated in the right shop for the
implementing rules and regulations of
the national body system law we were
very to advocate for the right of the
people to take advice which includes
providing guidance in the crafting of
state policy and proposing measures to
mitigate risks to people's rights
our group in the National Isis Islamic
we provide advice make sure like super
know both laws the national ID Boeing
also debated Pakistan then three
necessary enforce it due to selection I
insisted that the militias disclosure
someone inside the national ID system
maliciousness insurance possible or
Alicia's processes it's punishable new
system but so the story is an actor we
can do more debatable top of the
fiercest processing and you can do your
part in it I swear as hawkers minor and
they need a stronger issue to help us
make this right on this the need for
your voice will be more acute your
country needs you
whatever be the privacy is not so much
for creation company or quality it
should be manageable asset or resource
that custody does exchange information
up in a see big battle system so this
week next the natural diversity mission
and abilities business authority by
launching a program to help those fast
to implement the national baby sister to
understand the risks that B is a basis
in running theses and being aware of
those risks the appropriate missus
action and innovation strategies we call
this program
papaya papaya is a dentist I'm the first
lady that runs the forest for me two
minutes the results of this study will
serve as a time
for securing the most vulnerable are the
existence today so we hope that this is
the pressure of AD cigarette DVDs to
help fortify our digital institution
papaya we go we need not buy herbs to
help us ignore our systems involved for
the national ID means the first program
we will be asking 30 of you here today
to participate in story
but we can only have space for any time
for 30 dose of you are going to be asked
we understand that were asking you're
applying and you know that is available
we would ask for you to see the
vegetation to see Bonnie since they
cannot announce movie cream giving
back but mean these are the first 3d all
appear here consider my enemies but
movie I hope you give us the time the
very valuable resource of you possess
give us some time to help us because the
whole village to see your egos needing
graduation services
[Applause]