miss Alex and I'm here to present
software tax on different type of system
former x86 and arm before I will start I
want to say thank you organizers of HTC
to having me here it my first time here
to some of you who may track what kind
of research we published last years you
may notice that all of them most most
all of them was x86 research related to
the virtualization or from any 36 and
then this year we published first time
some research an arm and hypervisor
exploitation for the arm for some
specific associates and then there was
some before we will make that research
we were thinking about how we can apply
vectors which we know from Exedy six
systems to our system because we read
about different attacks and we see
similarities so that's supposed to be a
multiple different attacks which can be
applicable for different architectures
and that was the motivation for this
presentation basically after we
published a bunch of research for x86
firmer attacks then we'll be making
investigation for arm from and
hypervisor attacks we was thinking about
let's combine this the one presentation
and see like where is there similar
methods what what kind of vector
applicable just week city six what kind
of method applicable just for arm and so
on so during the presentation I will
switch from x86 to our multiple times it
will be confusion I will try to make it
less confusion but basically the idea is
it will be like blocks of x86 and then
blocks for arm and then back and forth
multiple times depends on the area which
I will explain so I will start just with
introduction really brief result details
just to making sure that we are in the
same page of the terminology then I will
go through some of the details about
hardware configuration and how it done
in different platform and then it will
be a bit about reverse engineering and
that part was interesting specific
because before they have the
research in arm it didn't have
experience with arm at all and this is
sort of will give you the idea how to
start investigating new system which you
never have investigated previously some
new york attack sure where to start what
kind of matter to use and so on so may
may be useful then attack vectors again
which one or click above a different
system with some examples so it will be
example for execs bypass windows 10 vs m
technology using some of the hardware
interfaces and forearm the the the
result which is to be published in
blackhat about exploitation hypervisor
in some specific as you see so x86
typical system we have user mode we have
keno and then there is a hypervisor
important point is that in x86
hypervisor is context switch technology
meaning that inside the hypervisor it
also has the privileges level and every
time when you go in to the guest and
coming back to the hypervisor you switch
in the context of entire CPU and every
gas has the structure which is contained
all the necessary data to date switch
why it is important because this allow
much more flexibility to the hypervisor
technology allowing the software use
hyper visor for many different purposes
pepper visor privilege level or
technology so then we have the SMM and
bios come SMM is basically a system
management mode is and the most
privileged code in the system which is
basically runtime part of the bias so in
x86 system the bias has to part their
boot the boot time part and runtime part
boot time part is basically the code
which is running really beginning after
the system is on and the runtime part of
the bias is the part which is basically
supporting some functionality during the
runtime if there is any issue with the
system it's supposed to go and drop even
to the SMM and then SRAM should handle
isms and then because the cpu peripheral
and
CPU peripheral PCIe bosses and so on in
this presentation that will be attack
related to the hypervisor and attack
related to the SMM and a bias then I
already mentioned there is a boot time
of the BIOS well what this mean is so
when the system is powering on the first
instruction which is fetching this reset
vector and the way how does it fetch
work is pretty interesting because at
the moment when this instruction is
evasion there is no memory no caches
nothing but you need to somehow
executive first instruction so what
happen is that when the vendee cpu tried
to fetch the the there is a tractor is a
tractor always in a constant address and
then that that transaction go into the
memory controller and memory controller
see the undressing and knew that this is
andres of the rosette vector and it's
send transaction to the PCH PCH receive
the transaction and see okay this is the
there is that vector and it redirected
to the spy controller that's the way how
does there is a tractor work
when you when you have the instruction
which is executing even without memory
without caches without match then what
happen next there is a sec phase or
first sort of first code which is
basically run in the system which is
makes some basic initialization for
example in insulation of the TPM
initialization of cash making cash using
as memory copy some sum as a part of the
boot part of the buyers part of the code
to the cache and start executing the
cache and then it's redirection to P I
face VI faces bicycle pre-installation
face this face is responsible for and
it's always necessary Hardware tomb to
set that to set the proper configuration
of the security features and all of the
necessary features which is supposed to
be initialized for for system Putin
correctly so then it go into the Dixie
face Dixie face is one of the biggest
face in this 86
during the boot time that face is
responsible for initializing all of the
protocols all of the necessary
components to support operation system
services because buyers provided some of
the services to the person system which
is basically an installation in this
phase and then I'll go into the goal of
going and calling them loader of the
operation system and then the purchase
system is large and the interesting part
in the before the after Dixon before
person system is exit with services that
special event which is indicating that
the boot part of the bias is done and
now the runtime the buyer is supposed to
be use it and and boot boot part of the
bias is not available anymore like boot
variables not available boot service is
not available and so on that sort of
speech man all of the security
configuration should be set but by the
before you the BIOS called exit put
services so in army it's a little bit
different in in perspective of the
privileges level and in perspective of
the boot flow so in perspective the
privileges level we have classical user
modern colonel but then when we come to
the hypervisor there is already
different because hypervisor in arm
implemented as as exception level or
privilege level so it's not a context
switch technology it doesn't have inside
the hypervisor any other privileges
level just a privilege level and it has
the instruction which is triggering the
code from the hypervisor so meaning that
hypervisor is less flexible but in other
hand it can be more is related and
configure it better in security purposes
because you don't need to care about
about that much stuff than in the 66
there is no VM CS national reaches rely
on context switch there is just a
privilege level but as you as you
remember in exodus if there was SMM
which was as a privilege level in arm
there is at resident and trans long has
a bunch of privileges level inside so
basically there is a trust list which is
running in a l0 exception level 0 for
further inside the secure world inside
the transient world there is
the secure canal which is running inside
the trans old world and there is secured
monitor so basically in the perspective
of flexibility they secure world much
more flexible and has much much better
capabilities then SMM and how does this
boundaries work the boundary work works
and two things is relation boundaries
there is one is memories relation which
is done
in the memory controller so every time
when transaction going from the normal
world to secure world overall from
security secure role it has the bit
source and bit destination and depends
on the the source of the transaction it
go press or not for example if the
transaction going from normal mode to
secure boat the trans actually bill
dropped so and this is the way how does
the isolation and memory level work for
the for the transient world for there
and also there is a card reservation
meaning that the interrupts working in a
way that all of the interrupts form the
normal world can be delivered by
specific way to the secure world there
is no mechanism how the normal world can
trigger any other code except their
specific exception vectors we shall
explain later
so compared to x86 and the difference is
that hypervisor is working as a as a
privilege level and the transient world
working as entire technology which has a
bunch of privileges level inside so if
we will have the slides for that I will
come back to that so now if you don't
talk a bit about boot flow in in Arma
sources so first of all for our message
caesar is all specific for specific as I
seen so it's not like a standard way
which is always working this way because
every vendor may implement them own way
to put the sse because our machine it is
more insulated system because you you
have the system is title specific
operation system and there is sort of
all the devices ill is
directly to the to them physical on your
spaces there's less flexibility and
because of that the booth flow can be
defined by vendor differently and this
is one is for Snapdragon 810 so it can
be different for some song for example
or for iPhones so everything starts from
air PM there's power management unit so
that Union basically running even before
the main CPU starts so then the RPM is
initializing the main CPU main
application CPU and triggering the code
from the wrong part of them of the main
CPU which is basically and then the
memory into into the CPU or on somewhere
so it's not accessible for software at
all you cannot read it you cannot dump
it you cannot verify how does it work
there's just there and it doing some
things for initialize the hardware and
for verifying next step of the boot flow
and next step of the boot flow is SBL
secondary bootloader which is basically
first part of their code which is
accessible from the software this is
basically the code which is making them
in each initialization of the first
trans and monitor privilege level and
some of the memory and so on so if you
will see that the left side is just
read-only memory meaning that any
vulnerability in that part will be not
really easy to fix because that memory
is controlled by vendor and it's not
accessible for software all any part any
vulnerability in a readwrite part can be
updatable and when update will be
delivered them they're a read-only
memory verify readwrite memory and and
checking the signature readwrite memory
before it trigger that code in the
readwrite memory
so then SPL you will continue : the
trust on monitor which is responsible to
initialize and and set all of the
protections for the trans own so after
this point after the transient
monitoring installation kernel and
applications that razón is locked and
not modifiable so if there was any
possibility to create a DMA attack
during the boot time it's supposed to be
done during the SPL or transdermal
interface and then after TransAm Colonel
there is there's low chances that they
secure the configuration will not be
sent so and then this is all done in for
initializing secure water president and
then the first chord which is an
untrusted code which is running the
system is the hypervisor so basically
the trans don't kill the president
monitor actuators on Colonel will
trigger them and the hypervisor code to
continue the boot flow and then the
hypervisor will initialize the operation
system and so on so forth
that's the boot sequence for their arm
as you can see it's look like they have
more faces than x86 but in reality there
is less faces they are more straight and
because they're the platform itself
doesn't need that much initialization
because in answer C compared to the core
technology there is a bunch of stuff
which is constant and you don't need to
configure them that's why there is
basically I would say two phases one is
read-only which is some code which is
very fine I read white part and there is
just couple faces in the readwrite which
is much much simpler than the x86 and I
will have example Y so anyway we start
talking about different racket action
there is sort of summary what I was
mentioning from the beginning of the
presentation so first of all the route
of trust as I mentioned their route of
trust for arm is prettiest pretty
restricted and rely on the OEM
configuration Orion fuses so if the OEM
want to lock the phones or any arm
system they just program the fuses and
then the system will will just support
the boot flow from that from their
read-only memory to the person system
this specific vendor signature so there
is no one can just put the binary there
during the boot phone if the vendor is
not locking the phone then meaning that
you can reset the defuses and after some
point you can load your own a person
system root your phone and run test
button which
but that's supposed to be is supported
by a me not supported this then there is
one way to do that is find vulnerability
in trans own Trussell has accesses to
the fuse you and then you override the
fuses that's the way how does jailbreak
works and unlock your cellphones is
working so 486 a root of trust was more
flexible because you can learn any
operation system you can run a bunch a
bunch of different software and there
was no really root of traffic except
secure boot but secure boot was sort of
software way which is relying on
integrity of the BIOS so the bias was
compromised and then the you can bypass
secure boot and the rest of the boot
flow there was a new technology from
Havel called a boot guard we just make
it much more badass on it it is close to
what arm is doing because the root of
trust is in a room in our own memory
which is controlled by the platform
vendor meaning Intel and but that money
required that om who is using the
technology is supposed to use this
technology correctly meaning that they
need to program
fusers need to log the technology if
there is just enable technology and not
lock-in the technology or enabling it
not properly then it is definitely an
issue and can be used to bypass them the
entire boot flow and compromise the root
of trust and the process of the boot and
like all of the technology which is
reminded so about gene transit execution
environment as I already mentioned the
arm has really good flexibility in a
there is a privileges level which is I
would say in the perspective of
technology similar what is a retro
ization in x86 doing and because it's 86
civilization also has privileges level
and separation between them
so that's why in Windows 10 there the
VSM vectorization basic technology
what-what was built at base it on
virtualization not basic for example on
sm
or something else because there was
enough flexibility to build a technology
on the top of utilization and you cannot
do that an arm because an arm there is a
there's working as a privilege level so
that's sort of the brief idea why this
is important at all when we built our
attack for x86 will we will use the that
flexibility which is vectorization
technology provide to compromise the
hypervisor in the Windows 10 and for arm
there is a bunch of vectors which is
really similar will be for their trust
own which will apply to the
vectorization
anyway let's go and talk a bit about the
hardware interfaces so for each 66
hardware interfaces I splitted it for
two categories is CPU interfaces and SSE
interfaces in the CPU perspective there
is a CPU state obviously some general
purpose registers and other stuff and
there is also a mess are a model
specific register is basically some
register which is storing configuration
in x86 system and sometimes it's even
working as as a control registers when
you write something and you trigger some
action that basically allowing the the
vendor creating a bunch of features and
communication to that features using
that registers and the software has the
instruction to access the transistors or
even write to that registers in the
perspective officer see there is a bunch
interfaces I your PC and so on the one
of the interesting for us for today will
be a memory mapped i/o memory map MMI
your interface it basically and the
interface which is allowing to talk to
the PC devices through memory so every
transaction to the MMI your of the
device will go in directly to the device
through the memory controller and PCH so
it will run there if you will enumerate
all of them on my your bars a moment a
bar basically and the register which is
defining a memory arrange we will find a
bunch of edges a bunch of ranges that
register rate ranges is
represent some of the device in in the
system bill we created that the tool
which is basically doing this
enumeration so you can under this tool
which i will use basically all over this
presentation this tool is basically
doing a lot of accesses to the card when
inclusion and the accesses to the a
memory of the devices and as we will see
later there will be a different in
implementation of them my offer arm and
x86 and one of one of them will be used
for attack one of the attack scenarios
so you know in arm there is a little bit
different so you have them in general
purpose registers and some of the
special control registers also you have
the registers inside the core processors
and that registers it's accessible
through the specific instruction it
really similar to what is a massage
Ismene for x86 except this interface is
covering much more registers from much
more different units so I would say that
all of them necessary core interfaces
accessible through that interface in the
perspective of the associa there is also
less interfaces than x86 because MMA yo
in arm is it's a constant constant
addresses list because in sse you don't
need to have relocatable a memory
arranges because in associate the
purpose vs e is make everything on chip
which is meaning that everything will be
on one die or in one chip and in this
case or if there is device that device
has the the MMO artisan that are just
always constant and even if there is an
any PCI device which is implemented in
arm they will be implemented remember
you're basically there will be the PCI
controller which will have the constant
address and then there will be then MMA
or all that we say device which will be
define it and that we say controller
after omame on
anyway then the main idea is in arm
there is there is less there is less
flexibility because the SS you don't
need a flexibility and because of that
there is less attack vectors so that is
the example or what's going on exactly
so that's in in the right side we see
there is a list of the MMA on a mama
arranges for the devices and that list
is always the same so if you reboot the
system if you take another as I see this
specific this specific associate you
will see always the same always the same
list of the addresses for all of the
devices what this mean that they are not
relocatable they all they all constant
and and basically because they are not
relocatable there is no source for
attack and then what what will what will
what we like to do with this MMA
arranges so we want to investigate and
see how many of this register is
accessible so we may just create a
simple tool which will just read and
write this registers and depends on that
we can we may figure out multiple
different things for example if we read
it from the different time stamp like
after the system just boot it and then
later on we'll figure out that there are
some registers may be accessible right
after boot but not accessible in a run
time what what is talent was that and
that there is a two different phases for
for SSE tobu there is a boot time face
and runtime face really similar for x86
but the differences is not documented so
we don't know how does exactly this work
because there is no documentation which
explaining these two phases we just by
experiment can figure out this and
another interesting part is it can be
used for attack because if there is any
register is supposed to be locked but
its accessible after the system is boot
it may be used to some of the attack
scenario when you for example this
register is contained the address and
then we you use this underst overlap
with more privileged code so that is one
thing another thing is you
may read their register from different
privileges more to say from hypervisor
and from the kernel and see how many of
them will be accessible anyway you can
you can make a bunch of different things
to understand how doesn't that remember
your work and in some case you may
figure out that there is some security
issues for example if you figure out
that one of the device supposed to be
trusted minion just accessible from the
trans owned but it's accessible from the
normal world that's sort of issue which
may cause some problem for the system
and the interesting part is that it's
not really easy to find the commentation
from the SOC and from all of them and
other devices if you think about that
the arm is not providing the in
description of the all of this I see
because it's it is vendor specific but
vendor doesn't provide this as well so
in some of that so to find that the
commentation you may want there's one
way you need to send for program which
will which will ship to you that
developer boards and when you gather
developer boards you will figure out
that that developer boss has also
documentation with the description of
the registers and then you can map the
which of the developer boards represent
which of them SSE for the for the phones
for example from I've bought from Nexus
5x and 6p developer boards and then when
I figure out all of them Emma may often
that devices but interestingly that it's
not really accessible so you cannot just
google it and find the description of
this the consequences of that it can be
two things first of all we cannot verify
it configure it properly or not
and second is we don't know exactly what
is going on in the system so say when I
make investigation and the Google pixel
I figure out that the system has more
than ten different farmers and in the
interfaces for the farmers is different
some of them spy some of them I to see
and so on but there is no documentation
so ever when you can find all of the
exponent in description for that
interfaces how does they work registers
and so on that was sort of interesting
point and experimenting with them a
memory of the devices may give you some
ideas about what the device is doing
anyway let's come back to x86 we already
got the idea that x86 has much more
complicated boot process because it
allowed better flexibility and so on so
because of that x86 is reconfigurable
minion that there is a bunch of things
can be configured differently including
security configuration and over the
years we collect in different when their
abilities found by different people
including us in a different interfaces
of the firm including configuration of
the firmware and this is the list of all
of the vulnerability which we found by
2015 in x86 from in the most of them is
configuration like some of the registers
supposed to be locked by they not locked
and because they're not logged there is
some accesses to some of the region
which is not supposed to be and if you
think about that there is like more than
like 15 of them different
vulnerabilities which were found it's
fine it is fine because the system is
super flexible and allowing you a lot of
reconfiguration the vendor just need to
take care of all of this and making sure
that the configuration is set that was
supposed to be done then four years
later in 2017 we maintain our system to
check one of that vulnerability which we
disclosed that in 2013 how many how many
systems still when arrival to this
vulnerability and we were surprised that
even in 2017 for some of the really
common type of an ability which is
allowing you direct access to the bias
region in a spy controller there is 500
different modulus laptops and desktops
still variable to this reliability so we
started the talking about this from our
built in 2013 and then even in this year
we still have a bunch of system which is
venerable there's the vendors is coming
a little bit better because some of the
vendors is making progress if you will
see like Dell they have just 11 system
which still variable which is not bad
because they have a thousands of systems
and they may not just update that 11
because there was legacy or old system
so they are making really good progress
but some of the vendors still have a
bunch of system even even modern system
I've bought recently some of the Lenovo
I don't remember issues that I know
about latest ones from this year brought
valve on and that's still vulnerable to
the classical vulnerability which is
allowing to get the access to the frame
so that's sort of things which we need
to think about so in arm there is a
little bit different story as already
mentioned first of all as I see is not
documented so we don't know really
what's supposed to be set what the
security configuration need to be set we
don't know how to check it we know that
some things we known likes a bootloader
supposed to Lord just silent binary we
know like basic stuff for the boot flow
and one of the basic stuff is the fuses
so we definitely need to check that the
fuses is program it and lock it
correctly this assumption which we know
about the boot flow and the security
protection of the boot flow also you
know that when the trazadone
initialization going there is some
register which is supposed to be set in
the corporate specter that something
which you also know but we don't know
what exactly in perspective of
Association supposed to be said to lock
the firmware accesses to the to the
interfaces of the from different from us
and what I noticed this when I when I
bought that developer board and I had
that spec from like many a thousand
pages I start to read register from that
pages and I figure out that a bunch of
that register has some hiden
sort of lock configuration basically the
register is telling that this register
is relying on lock to known as a
register and then as a register is rely
on some other locks and what this mean
is the domain this mean is that in
associa there is also a bunch of
register which supposed to be set to
make the platform fully protected and
locked but the point is this data is not
really accessible easier because to find
is that it's not publicly available you
just need to go through them special
process and what this means for us its
meaning that we buy a system we buy our
phones and other devices arm-based
devices and we
no does they properly set it or not
because we don't have the good test for
these registers we don't have the
information about this at all so we need
to just sort of trust vendor that vendor
is doing the job well if you're not
trust vendor then there is not easy way
to I've tried to do that but I figure
out there are so many registers to which
I need to count
so I finally didn't manage how make it
automatically to check all of that
registers in the system
and the one thing was really important
that some of the register I found that
they are not locked so they're supposed
to be locked they're not locked I didn't
find figure out the security impact of
that registers but the register which is
supposed to be locked by the spec is not
locked it's not really a big problem
unless there is impact of this and for
some registers maybe impact of that so
how we how we can start reverse engineer
con the former because we already talked
a bit about interfaces about boot flow
about the configuration so on but we
want to go on deep and see what is what
is inside the from the inner city six
there is pretty easy to dump the from
our interface dump the froma through the
spy interface and there is a comment in
ship SEC you can just call ship
security'll spy dump and you down the
firm then you can decode the from an
extract all of the compressor on the
promo and then you can analyze every of
that components one by one
during the either or make some
automation using the some of the ufi
runner tools there is a bunch of
research done right now about how how
does it how does it work from meteor
Aleksic from other people from snail a
snare I will not stop too much here but
basically if you want to start analysis
of the system from an x86 system you
just need to Don them decode and analyze
the binaries which you find and the
binary which you find it will be just a
regular ECG 6bi files so an analysis of
the bias in x86 from it's really similar
just for analysis any other binary ntdll
or whatever binary you want so I will
focus here a bit on
how can you build how can you start
reverse engineering and analyzing armed
systems first of all because it was
pretty interesting when we did this and
another is it's it's sort of one of the
first presentation for the 64-bit razón
analysis so it may be interesting as a
methodology and as a result as well so
to start analysis of the trans own you
need to find the binaries and there is
two ways to do that one was to dump them
from her from the system but the point
is again there is there is one interface
which is accessible and that interface
was working until until recently and
that interface is allowing you to dump
the firmware from the system but then
later on that that interface was
disabled so you cannot do this anymore
so but how can you how can you find the
firmware
another way to do that is find the
factory image from the vendor basically
images which is using to restore the
system for the from the original
container state from the state which was
supposed to build after manufacturing
and then in the factory image you can
extract the bootloader which will
contain all of the binaries including
trans non-binary including hypervisor
binary including some of the s BL a
secondary bootloader binary and you can
start going analyze that damn for
example if you want on OS hypervisor and
see how the hypervisor work and so on
one another important thing is the
hypervisor in that specific SSC was
enabled like recently from from
generation of snapdragon 808 it is
basically the time of a nexus 5x so
anyway you take the trans non-binary you
load that in HIDA and you will see
there's a bunch of section some of them
is represent tourism kernels some of
them is represent as a monitor so
basically you have entire code of
tourism Kino transom monitor from here
you can start reverse engineer now
analyzing the functions the entry points
and so on
also you want to have the dynamic
environment to run the test and
especially if you have a phone for
Nemec environment there is you need to
route your phone and rebuild the kernel
to allowing the Lord drivers and then
with that you can load any drivers to
read physical memory to read the memory
of the devices and so on so forth
there is a bunch of tools be she's
already doing this so there is a matter
of time just to compile the kernel and
the compilers tools and then from here
you can run there's an analyze the
system so now after you load the
binaries the the transient binaries to
either and you have the dynamic
environment you need to start looking at
interfaces where is the entry point how
does the colon convention working how
does the argument patient from the
normal world to transient world one of
the thing which you can go and take a
look is open source implementation of
the trans own it will give you a lot of
information about how does handler works
what is what the security configuration
is supposed to be said and where is the
sanity checks for different conditions
that was really useful to understand
especially one thing we witches was an
entry point of the vector table which is
basically the main code which is running
whenever any exception happened and more
local digit code so that was I was
mentioned right now that vector table so
first of all how we can find the vector
table the pointer to the vector table
should be stored in the V Bar el34 the
secure monitor so if you find somewhere
in the code that someone set or read
that register and you will find the
constant of the address of the table
then from here you know the entry point
of this privileges level so from here
you can find all of the handle from smc
and some C is the event which is going
from the normal water seeker world and
from there you can analyze the entire
flow and find various the input input
buffer handlers set how does it work and
find some software vulnerabilities there
so here here is the example of that
vector table and here is them SMC can
learn as some Sikandar is basically one
of the main interface
to that razón and this interfaces often
use them to compromise the trance on
itself form then they secure in the
secure monitor in at razón it's doing
just one thing it's with written request
from the normal world to secure world
and for and then someone need to handle
that request and there is this the
transom colonel doing this so transom
Kimmel has something which is called SMC
services which is handling their
specific requests from the normal world
and when when the normal world trigger
this requested go into secure monitor
and then secure monitor know where
exactly to call secure canal and it will
call secure canal and a secure canal
will handle it will figure out which of
the SMC handler it want to call and then
call them so they're supposed to be a
common convention between their security
that between the normal one and secure
world because if there's any services in
trazadone like say you want to get a
random number from random random number
generator in an enormous machine it's
not that tree well there is no
instruction which has given you this
there is a random number generator
device but that device accessible just
from trust on so if you want to get the
random number you need to send a request
to the trans own that ransom will talk
to the device and you'll provide you
that number back to the normal world but
you need to know the column convention
between normal boat and secure role
there's two ways to do that you may want
to make a reverse engineering and figure
out how does the arguments is passing or
you can just take a look an open-source
implementation of the transom drivers
which is basically implementing this
interface and you will see how does the
arguments pass on them and they're :
convention working like this if you have
less than five argument they will pass
on from their general purpose register
if you have more than five argument they
are passing through general purpose
register and the buffer why it is
important because we need to understand
we need to understand how does it work
for their attack purposes because we
want to build the pfizer we want to fast
this interface and find the software and
abilities inside the SMC handlers so
this is the SMC default handler which is
basically chicken the argument
and call in the specific SMC handler to
to manage the services the interest in
part how does it work that SMC default
handler has a bunch of sanity checks and
one of the checks is basically checking
that the arguments which a person is not
other sizes which is overlapping with
stress on so basically it assuming that
first argument is address and second
argument is size and it in this slicing
through arguments to making sure that
they are not overlapping with stress on
memory that is really smart check
because if we will compare with x86 in
SMM implementation there the default is
assume handler doesn't have any send you
checks at all so we just passing
arguments to specification see handler
which is making code less secure but in
enormous machine specifically in
Qualcomm implementation or threads on
this and this entry checks is pretty
smart so then I already mentioned there
is SMC services which is a normal what
can call that SMC service is stored in a
table and you can find a table in in the
binary and then from there you can
reverse engineer every of the services
one by one and this is the example of
one of the services the interesting part
of this is that if there will be no that
checks there is a write primitive so
this handler takes three arguments it
callin subroutine and subroutine making
a right to one of that arguments so in
the case if there if their system
doesn't hit that checks which I've shown
previously it will be a definite
venerability but because they have that
really good sanity checks in the
beginning of the SMC flow that this code
is not vulnerable it working fully
without any problems but they still have
a right primitive you just can override
anything outside the all the trays on
everything which is not protected you
can override by using this and this is
MC handler which we'll use later to
compromise hypervisor and as a really
interesting part and a really important
trick is SLA dimension the SE C is the
constant address and a memory of the
devices is the constant addresses in the
arm
see because of that you can find the
addresses of the specific device and
then you can restore what exactly this
is MC handler is doing based on
information from the device so you kind
of increase your knowledge based on
understanding of the addresses which is
using as a constant inside the SMC
handlers another another important trick
which may help you to build analysis in
at razón is error code so different flow
has different error code and when you
send input to the SMC handler you can
basically depends on the error code
figure out what kind of flow you execute
and depends on that you may see the
coverage you may adjust your input you
can find the bad coverage
unfortunately there is not there is not
unique error code for each flow so some
flow has the unique records some of them
is not but it's still useful information
anyway and the last point when the last
point which will help us to to run tests
Pfizer's and analyze the system is the
reverse engineering of the hypervisor
the idea is pretty much the same we need
to find a result vector and we need to
find a vector table and we need to find
a configuration of the hypervisor in a
binary after we find this we can restore
that configure what what exactly
hypervisor said what paging could use
what kind of translation and so on that
is example for example a GT BR l l1 is
the register which is showing us then
stage one translation table entry from
here we can restore all of the stage one
translation stage one it's like similar
tomb in the x86 we have two level of
translation from the guest virtual
address to the guest physical address
and from guest physicalist to the host
physical address here the same but it
just call in stage one and stage two
stage one is from the guest virtual
address two they call intermediate
physical address and then from
intermediate regardless to the host
physical is a stage two so anyway we
already know details about something
about hypervisor
something about razón but
we need to go and take a look G player
on the attack vectors and we start with
zigzag ec2 six run time attack vectors
is pretty pretty straightforward you
want to compromise the SMM code from the
from the hypervisor or from the kernel
or you want to compromise here now we
want to compromise hypervisor from the
kernel
oh you want to compromise from the
kernel SMM and then redirect the attack
to the hypervisor so there is two main
two main classes of the attack surface
one is Carter configuration I remember
when I show you there 15 different when
your abilities which was spawned
previously I called hardware
configuration because it's basically set
in some registers and another one is SMI
handlers SMI handlers it's really
similar what is SMC handler in the
Army's it Jacek aliy supporting some
services which is necessary to have in a
platform and we will see an arm there is
a little bit different story because arm
has more privileges level in a secure
world there is much more vectors attack
is here one of and because it Allah it
creates a lot of flexibility also
creating new vectors of attack for
example translates translates is the
transit application which so which is
part of the entire secure world so if
somehow you can compromise translates
then you can build attack inside the
secure world which is completely arm
specific use cases there is no analogy
in x86 and that was interesting research
published this year which basically
allowing you to load the vulnerable
translate inside the secure world what
this allows you to do as an attacker you
want to release the update for the
translator you take this update for the
Translate you lower you
you take them vulnerable translate you
load the Venerable translate to the to
the secure world and then you can
compromise now that variable translate
from the normal world and then you can
build the attack from the translate to
the to compromise entire secure world
and interestingly that these attacks is
not really well investigated because
no good methods how you can make an
investigation of the secure world if you
compromise already translate what I mean
about that if you analyze security
arnelle mostly they try to make a checks
from the input which is coming from the
normal world but there is not well
well-tested the interface from the
translate to the secure canal and even
in either this simple analysis you can
find the buffer of our vulnerabilities
from translate to secure canal and
interestingly that if you compromise
secure there is no need to compromise
secure monitor because secure canal
already have access to all of the
devices so basically even with all of
this flexibility it still has a bunch of
issues related to them architecture and
specifically because there is not too
many tools to validate the 4 interface
between trust translate and secure canal
really interesting to research so one of
the attack which I will fly really fast
which is applicable for both
architectures DMA attack pre-boot attack
when you inject some of the boot
component during the boot and you can
own the system
this attack is applicable for both
systems and in x86 there is a couple
different scenarios for this attack as
well one of them is if you want to use
the DMA attack without any external
device there is also integrated graphic
device which has DMA capability so if
you build in the attack and you need GMA
capability you can use just the graphic
GMA 2 to run it and for armed is
basically completely the same but for
armed I didn't find any integrated GMA
capability so if you want to run DMA
attack you need to have external device
now poison pointer box we call it like
this the vector is applicable for both
architectures the vector is applicable
for both architectures the main idea is
you pass untrusted
buffer from low privilege level for high
privilege level and you pass the address
of the high privilege level and then and
then if this is can you do have any
question excuse me
do have any question okay yeah so in
ecstasy six system that vector was
investigated a lot and in a decade too
there is a comb buffer which is
interface to the SMM code and there is
an e TK one general purpose register is
interfaced to the SMM code was a bunch
of research about that the main idea is
if the attacker control in the address
just overlapping with the decimal code
and it will allow to have a right
primitive which is basically in many
cases making privilege escalation to the
SMM there is a reference to the work who
if someone want to get at more deeply
what what happened next
if there is if their hypervisor if there
is SMM call this vendor of making the
fix which will check that the pointer is
not overlapping with SMM it's still not
fixed and fully the problem because in
this case attacker can find samsung else
and point the pointer to that sensitive
piece of thin and making the right
primitive to there and you may ask what
their scent is sensors your thing is and
in the x86 it can be hypervisor for
example because SMM khan doesn't know
the layout of the hypervisor and guest
and in this case if you point in the
pointer of the hyper if you point in the
address of the hypervisor to their samam
SMM doesn't check it it just write it
there so in this case if there is any
guest has access to the SMI interface
can trigger SMI SMI event it may
override the hypervisor without even
having any issue in the in the firm
itself so initiative six there was a
really good investigated vector and then
in arm there is really similar vector
for the trans on a runtime interface smc
so as some CSS elements
has also interfaces a general purpose
register when you pass arguments through
that and for example if there's some
sick and are supposed to write output
buffer you pass the address of that
output buffer to general purpose
register exactly the same scenario as in
x86 one and there was bugs which found
previously in this in this specific
vector couple times in 2014 and 15 we
create the Pfizer to check this when
this vulnerability and in Nexus 5 fixed
6p and pixel there there there is really
good sanity check so that that vector is
not really easy to find vulnerability in
then another vector in arm was the
double fetch or race condition so if you
pass in there big buffer Essen as an
argument to the SMC Handler and is this
buffer store it in the memory then there
is there can be a case when this buffer
can be modified by another CPU and this
is really interesting vector because in
in x86 this vector is not applicable at
all because when you call in the SMI in
x86 system the SMI is waiting until all
of the course will go in and twist some
M so this vector is almost not
applicable to 86 but in army that's
really a really good vector because you
can find you can find by static analysis
there buffer which is passing from the
normal world to secure world and figure
out is there any window between using
and check between chicken and using that
buffer another vector which is also
applicable just for arm is confused
deputy attack when you pass and the
address of the trusted device as in the
general purpose register as already
mentioned there is two type of device
transit an untrusted trusted devices
device which is just accessible for the
secure water fortress on there not
accessible for the normal world but what
attacker can do because attack you know
the address of that secure device it can
pass the address of the device as an
argument and ask
smc handler to override to make a right
to that device a really interesting
vector
but unfortunately we are on the Pfizer
and they have Santa checks for this as
well
Google pixel actually has really good
from that's why this vector is not
applicable as well but really good
vector may be applicable for different
as Isis and different different system
another vector which is really
interesting but it more applicable for
the x86 and so that you mentioned about
MMA you have different devices and the
difference between x86 and arm so one
more quick recap you have a member your
range which is basically a transaction
to that range will go directly to the
device and every time an operation
system on someone else want to talk to
that device they talking through them
and we arranged but in x86 MMA arranges
for PC devices is relocatable and the
address phone for this range is storied
in MMA your bar inside the piece a
config space of this device so basically
operation system has capability or any
malicious driver has capability to
overlap MMA arranged to any other
location in the memory if this is if the
MMA your bar is not locked but in many
cases a Mario bar is not locked because
they allow an operation system are
located in the bars full for increase
the flexibility of the system because
it's not as I see and as I see you need
to have a constant but here you don't
anyway because of this attacker may
overlap this MMA your bar with the SMM
and billet built attack on and built
attack on top of this so when the
transaction going from the device or to
the device in this case it will not pass
through because of the T SEC protection
but as Sam M itself has a bunch of
right-handers which is region and right
into the devices and because of that
when you overlap the MMA your bar visit
them a mama your range with the SMM and
trigger a surmise some of the semis may
read or write to - the to them s mmm so
basically you have sort of right
primitive to SMM really interesting
attack for two reasons one is this the
concept is really applicable to anywhere
so every
time when you see the register which
contained the address you always can
overlap it with more privileges level
and see how this memory controller
handles tracked this transaction another
interesting part of another interesting
part of this attack because in x86
system it can be really applicable for
example a spy bar which is relocatable
spy and not lockable you have really
good control of this bar and you have
really good control of the data which is
using to this bar so with this bar you
have really great right payment tree
which you can use to make a pretty much
escalation to the SMM code and in arm we
can try to apply the same attitude ology
we can try to find the registers overlap
with resume memory and see how does the
memory controller handle it but because
we don't know all of the register which
contain the addresses because we don't
know all of the layout of the SSE it's
not really easy to apply this vector
with all of the variation of this vector
to the arm system now we come into the
first two the first sort of attack which
was done in x86 system to the Windows 10
so Windows 10 has the technology VBS
realization basic security or VBS is
also sometimes called VSM retardation
security some something so the idea of
that technology is Windows 10 you can
enable the hypervisor and the hypervisor
will create the secure VM which is
really trusted small VM and inside that
secure VM there will be some secrets
like credentials of the domain or
something like this and the idea is if
the attacker will compromise normal
world and compromise justice system
which user use then it will not find
that that credentials it will not find
the domain credentials the idea is
really awesome and the way how they
think about this technology is really
great because you have the retinas Asian
technology why not use this technology
to make an insulated container the idea
is really great
the issue is implementation because the
normal world has all of the excesses to
the former interfaces it
access to the MMA of bars it has access
to the SMI handlers it has accesses to a
triple screen so any attack through the
through the through the framework can't
compromise hypervisor and the secure VM
and especially the one which I've
explained it previously that's my
pointer then damn mio bar overlap all of
them is applicable but even if there is
no issue in the firmware itself there
still can be the framer can be used as a
confused deputy attack to the
compromised hypervisor because again I
said what you mentioned a couple times
SMM doesn't know the layout of the
hypervisor and the VMS and if you have
access to that so my handler interface
and the normal world has Dax's to that
interface then you can trigger the SMI
with the address of the hypervisor and
over and over at the hypervisor and
there was an attack demonstrated in a
couple years ago the interestingly is
that Microsoft related update what
dimension is they created a CPI table
which is basically having their
configure storage that this table is
represent where is the buffer supposed
to be for the output for the SMI
handlers what this mean is that this
table is basically a sort of colon
convention between the operation system
the hypervisor and the firmware where's
the buffer supposed to be and this is
really good it prevents in the assumed
I'd poison pointer attacks but it's not
preventing as attacks for example
attacks when you can overlap them Emma
your bar this one is not preventing so
there just as a partial fix and another
point is this is just a spec now all of
the vendors all of the BIOS vendor need
to apply this fix and deliver the buyers
updates to all of the system and then it
will be it will be fixed it but the spec
is just explaining how it's supposed to
be fix it now let's come in back to the
arm so we got a lot of knowledge about
x86 about flexibility of the harder'
configuration different attack vector so
on and as I mentioned and not all of
them almost all of the vectors which we
tested previously not applicable to arm
for some reason because they have sent
each X or architecture is not
or something like this then we start
thinking about okay
we we want to investigate a little bit
the hypervisor and that was really
interesting because we want okay let's
find the hypervisor in the memory in
arm-in-arm system there was a Snapdragon
808 10 it basically Google Nexus 6p then
we find the hypervisor in memory we get
the address of the hypervisor we used
the address in assam chief handler and
then we override them the hypervisor
using this and it was asking why why it
happened in the first place and then we
start thinking about this more and one
of the one of the things which which we
asked ourselves why we even find the
hypervisor in a memory because if you
think about that we run in our tool from
the kernel and care no not supposed to
have the access to the hypervisor and he
was thinking ok maybe this is some old
copy some some legacy copy of the
hypervisor which is was not real 1 then
we write to the hypervisor and the
system was rebooting so that was really
hypervisor so in in Snapdragon 88 and a
10 SOC s the hypervisor is accessible
from the kernel and this mean is all of
the phone with generation of this like
Nexus 5x and 6p is variable to this
vulnerability what this vulnerability
allow us to do so because we have the
read read read write primitive to the
hypervisor we can make a privilege
escalation which will demonstrate in
later and and also we were thinking
about why in the first place when we
read the hypervisor from the original
address we read the real hypervisor
because if there will be a second level
of translation the other is supposed to
be different and we make an assumption
that the second of the second this
second stage of the translation is
disabled and then we confirm it at later
so then we build the attack scenario
like this so from the from the malicious
keyer know from the malicious driver we
compromised the hypervisor we look down
hypervisor so now the hypervisor is not
accessible
was and then be a backdoor hypervisor in
a way that malicious application can
talk to the hypervisor through memory
and ask accesses to the kernel from that
interface to doing this we need to
somehow patch the hypervisor because we
have a writ primitive but it's not code
execution but remember when I mentioned
that vector table is the entry point to
all of them exception coming from low
privileges level so in vector table
there is some entry which is calling
periodically like periodically every
couple seconds this interface will call
this handler and we just find this
handler and we'll patch the handle with
our shellcode so we put our shellcode
right to the right in the end of the
function of the older handler which is
periodically calling then what we what
we do what we design it we design it
protocol between application of
hypervisor so if application will store
some magic number then we know that
after this magic number there is a
comment which isn't supposed to be
running in the hypervisor so now we are
in exploit exploit basically find that
hypervisor is open from the kernel it
patch in the the vector table then it is
checking that the shellcode is stored
there and then it just leaving like as
is then we run our application and
application basically storing the
comment which wishes which basically
asking to read the kernel memory from
that common common buffer and then the
hypervisor scan in memory periodically
because it callin periodically because
the the patch itself is calling couple
times in a second and then it find this
magic number and know that them after
the magic number I have a comment and
then we execute the comment but what is
what this demo is about then you can
purge the hypervisor and runtime you can
lock that and backdoor it in in the way
you want in in the to specific
generation of a shiva Snapdragon a zero
eight and eight
so then we reported this back and then
as a result we got the respondent this
is this behavior it's not exist anymore
in next generation so if you got the
next of them a Snapdragon 820 one which
is basically a Google pixel and that
behavior is not there so meaning that in
a Google pixel they am making super good
separation level between the kernel and
the hypervisor and then this vector is
not applicable anymore and then it's not
applicable through SMI handlers through
SMC handlers as well so if you pass the
address of them with the hypervisor to
the SMC handler it will have the proper
check as a result there is still two
generation of the phone which is
vulnerable to this vulnerability which
is not fixed that at all and and the fix
was just in the next release they just
change architecture anyway conclusion so
increased awareness about architecture
and different issues which was not
budget or partial badly
another is sort of supposed to use
hardware really properly meaning that we
need to have a security guidelines for
the BIOS configuration for there's a C
configuration to making sure that all of
the configuration set properly and have
the mechanism to check that
configuration and x86 and arm has a lot
of similar vectors and architecture
contingent architectures can teach each
other to understand how to make security
better with this I'm done
[Applause]