Mangia the rest is English but there
will be some surprises so our agenda
today would come be consist of two parts
the first part I'm going to talk about
authenticated encryption in some new
features and pitfalls and I'll connect
this to the recent a wpa2 attack that
has just been released a few days ago
you will see how this is connected and
the second part would be don't encrypt
without authentication I've been going
around in saying these things but people
keep thinking that encryption is also
safe when you have an adversary can
change the ciphertext so the answer is
known and we will see this all right so
I go on now feller a we do a detector to
open - so first part would be
authenticated encryption I'll talk about
the rise of AES GCM I'll give some
historical account and I'll talk about
the brittleness how dangerous this mode
is if you ever repeat the norms sounds
familiar from the last few days of
attacks and I will talk about how you
can change the mode and propose a
different mode that would be nonce
misuse resist resistant in a sense that
you can repeat nonsense and nothing
would happen and this is the AES GCM
sieve sieve is for synthetic IV and it's
efficient instantiation all right so
let's start so first of all it is very
important to have an efficient
authenticated encryption scheme for
example the most prominent example is
the client-server TLS communications so
every time you open your browser and you
can
to a server you hopefully are initiating
TLS session and with some authenticated
encryption and by now a yes GCM so a is
the encryption and GCM stands for Galois
counter mode is already the de facto
mode of operation that is used
everywhere for authenticated encryption
it is already today part of the current
TLS version 1.2 it is planned to be one
of the only two supported AED schemes in
TLS 1.3 that is coming soon so a is the
authenticated encryption with edition
Edition authenticated data and it is the
preferred server preferred server and
client choice for leading servers and
browsers especially for the client the
server always prefers the AES GCM
because all servers already have
hardware support for both the galois
counter mode NBA es by two instructions
and clients the 64-bit clients already
have these instructions or similar
instructions so they would also choose
as a first preference AES GCM the
advantages of this mode first of all it
came it started in 2006 around 2006 it
came out with the security proof and
this was a novelty and it has excellent
performance on modern CPUs with AES
instructions and carry less
multiplication this PCL Mulk udq this is
the instruction that that speeds up
polynomial multiplications so let's see
how did it get so attractive so if we go
to 2009 up to 2009 the dominant ciphers
were AES in CBC mode rc4 in h mac sha-1
these were dominant so 90% of the
traffic was with one of these two
combinations and AES GCM did not even
exist in any practical sense all right
so let me give you some account of
performance so rc4 for the cypher in h
moksha one for the authentication had
performance of two and a half cycles per
byte on a server CPU so lower is better
a yes and H moksha one was approximately
23 an Aes GCM is a pro head
approximately 22 cycles per byte so of
course if you want to choose the best
performing mode you would go for our C 4
and H moksha 1 and this was the dominant
mode but there were starting to see
problems with the security of this mode
so then the ecosystem moved to choose
AES and H Mac sha-1 and then there was
some problem with the CBC mode so back
and forth in AES GCM really didn't show
any performance advantage right so
nobody would try to push the ecosystem
to change the preferred cipher suite for
no reason for no performance reason so
this was the situation up until 2009 and
then around 2009 Intel announced and by
2010 there were already CPUs with these
instructions so AES and I these were the
instructions to encrypt faster with AES
and a 64 bit polynomial multiplication
it is the careless multiplication and
this was built for many purposes but one
of them was to speed up the AES GCM
because it is built on polynomial
multiplication not 64-bit polynomials
128 bit polynomials but if you have this
component you can write a piece of
software that would do a wide polynomial
multiplication for you top of this since
2009 there has been continuous software
and algorithmic optimizations for
implementing AES GCM better and better
and also after the architecture of this
in these instructions were announced
then the microarchitectures have been
improving so the AES improved the
latency and the throughput and also the
careless multiplication so with this
process
shall we where we are today so this is
the 22 cycles per by this was before
there were hardware instructions to
speed up yes and GCM so it's not even
reaching the 22 just the 22 is up there
but that's the end of the of the graph
so in 2010 this was the first generation
of processors with this instruction so
from 22 it dropped to 3 around 3 cycles
per byte so this was already a very good
reason to start moving servers and
clients to use AES GCM the next
iteration was 2 years after the Sandy
Bridge processor in 2012 it dropped a
little bit to 2.75
what happened was that the throughput of
the AES was improved but still the
authentication the Galois counter mode
computations we were not sped up because
the careless multiplication remained the
same so there was a modest improvement
and then we see a drop a beautiful drop
right so what happened in 2013 the
careless multiplication was also
improved so it's like 2
competing elements of the mode so you
improve a yes then
then the careless multiplication remains
the tallest pole in the tent and then
you improve this so so in 2013 it was
dropped already to one cycle provide the
year after the shrink the Broadwell cpu
point 76 and now start in 2015 and on
skylake and they're already newer CPUs
it dropped the performance is point 65
cycles per byte so remember we started
the journey from 22 and here we are at
point 65 but what is so special about
point 65 this number so this the
performance of only the counter mode
only the encryption is also around point
65 cycles per byte so this processor in
2015 is the first generation where
authentication and encryption is at the
same cost of only the encryption in
other words this is the top performance
possible on this type of CPUs you cannot
ask for more you cannot get less than
the encryption if you are doing
encryption and authentication but now
you are getting encryption and
authentication for the same cost of only
encryption so this was the ultimate
target so now if you compare this and
yes you see a big reason why move to a
yes sir GCM and indeed what happened so
I'll show some evolution so in 2012 TLS
1.2 was announced and this was the first
time where AES GCM was officially part
of the cipher suites that the server and
clients could could
choose but there was a very slow
proliferation so only maybe 1.2 percent
or 3 percent or something like this of
the traffic really used TLS 1.2 right so
you have to use TLS 1.2 if you want to
use the AES GCM so this was
proliferating very slowly the majority
of the TLS was 1.0 which was broken and
then what there was a strong push to
upgrade this to TLS 1.1 so most of the
effort was invested towards the first
update of day of the protocol and I told
you before 90 percent of the traffic was
with the old good old or maybe I should
say bed old AES CBC or RC 4 with H max
sha-1 now let's see what happened in
three years
the instructions were introduced there
was already one generation next
generation of improvements the AES GCM
in December 9 2015 I was tracking I was
tracking this so 55% of the traffic was
a yes GCM 30% was a CBC and there was
another one cha-cha and Pali which is a
third a cipher that emerged and it was
designed for the low-end CPUs the 32-bit
CPUs that do not have the hardware
support for AES and for the GCM so for
these processors this is a faster a
faster mode of operation and 2016 we see
this picture already so 64 percent of
the traffic is AES GCM and a CBC dropped
to 20 percent remember it was around 90
percent
and cha-cha Paulie stabilized to 15%
more or less this is the share of the
low-end CPUs the phones let's say more
or less so this is why it stabilizes on
this on this value and the trend is
going is going on so basically we can
see the evolution that most of the
traffic has already be to grind server
traffic has already moved to the modern
cipher authenticated encryption and is
enjoying performance and security so if
it's so wonderful why am i giving this
talk here you can sense that there is a
but coming
so what happened what happens if
something goes wrong so the AES GCM
needs to have an IV initialization
vector or we call it in the
cryptographic language and nonce and the
most important thing is to never repeat
a nonce so this is if you want to use
this mode securely never we use a nonce
of course with the same key so it sounds
very simple so what happens what happens
if you repeat the nonce by mistake so
the counter mode the privacy party of
the encryption is gone with you and you
lost these two messages that you encrypt
it with the same notes but this is a
small disaster an even worse disaster is
that the integrity is completely broken
it's not only these two messages because
if you repeated their nonce twice then
there is some computation that can be
done offline it it will reveal the
authentication key of the AES GCM
so from that point on an adversary can
forge any message not just these two
messages that were compromised because
you repeated a nonce twice so you lost
the integrity so you really should not
repeat
Ananse and you ask yourself if there is
such a crisps warning why would an IV
repeat right so I will tell you so so
let me give you a brief history of plate
randomness so first of all it is very
difficult to get real good randomness
and for this for example there is
nowadays a new instruction by Intel and
it's also already in other processors -
by now it's our dear and and our DC
these are two instructions that can
actually give you entropy from an
entropy source that is built into the
processor hardware ok but until there
was this instruction it was very
difficult to actually do this but then
there is the conspiracy theory you have
this wonderful instruction but there
were many who refused to use it we
cannot trust Intel maybe they plant at
the back door and and the entropy is not
good so although there was a good
instruction it was still not used by
everything and people libraries still
used the Linux dev random that is just
collecting some randomness from the
system but this is not really pure
entropy coming from from a real physical
entropy sauce well eventually by now I
think that the eco system is already
agreed to this novel idea if you have
a source of entropy and you added to
this there is no damage right so you
enjoy both both worlds so today there is
a collection of entropy from multiple
sources including the Rd rent and I'm
just giving some history so there was
the famous bug in 2008 the Debian Ling
Linux in the R&G receiving so it turned
out that many random generators were
actually predictable and in the 2010 the
PlayStation 3 right the private key was
recovered because there was no new
generated random source for each
signature so you can see that getting a
random a random random IV it's not it's
not trivial there are many mistakes that
happen with this here is a nice story
it's a it's a paper by Lenz Ryan other
authors in 2012 they collected they
collected six and a half let's say six
and a half million RSA public keys so
everyone can harvest it's just a matter
of time and to write the crawler that
would grab the public keys from any
servers and this is what they found
the 71 thousand keys were used more than
once by different servers right so if
two servers have the same public key it
means that they also have the same
private key and it means that one can
compromise the other and vice versa and
you ask yourself how is it possible that
somebody generated let's say 2000 bit
key and got the same public well the
answer is bad randomness
they didn't choose the Prime's correctly
another interesting thing so this is 71
so 71 thousand were just you know
negligent generation of a private-public
keeper and around 13,000 had a common
factor and this is also amazing you take
two public keys that are completely
different from different servers you
compute the GCD the greatest common
denominator of and you get something
that is greater than one
voila so you have factorized both keys
so both of these servers are hacked with
this so this was a big deal to take so
many million public keys and go over all
the pairs so they did a special
technique to actually do this in
feasible time but that's a fact
so you think again how is it possible I
mean how do you how do you generate in
our n RSA private key you just get two
random primes right now if your source
of randomness or the way that you apply
it or the way that you use it is not
perfect then you're most likely to have
not really random Prime's so not all of
them so if both Prime's are common then
you're here in the 71,000 cases very bad
cases but this is a very bad case as
well right
so so we can see actually that that
getting random Ivy's and random Keys and
random seeds it is a difficult task and
there are failures again and again it is
just interesting to say I'll just show
some some computations it is interesting
to actually to look at these data 6.4
million keys and 71 thousand were
compromised plus 13,000 and do some
computations of how much entropy is in
this
key in the public key so we did some
computations and it turned out that the
average RSA key has only 32 32 33 bits
of entropy this this is the the abstract
conclusion from this experiment right
now 32 bits of entropy is not very much
right it can easily today be brute force
and we will see later how easily you can
brute force a 32 bit entropy source so
again and now in May 2006 16 there was
another paper by these gentlemen nonce
disrespecting adversaries practical
forgery attacks on GS GCM in TLS and I
just this is from the abstract we
identified the hundred and eighty-four
HTTP servers repeating nonces ok and I
explained there the worst nightmare when
you're doing a use GCM for privacy and
authentication is that you repeated a
nonce so you lost the privacy of these
two messages and the authentication of
everything
so just so 184 cases where we're not
really we're repeating nonsense and also
they discovered over 70,000 cases or
HTTP servers where
where there is a large risk of repeating
repeating denounces so see again and
again this problem of randomness is
appearing failures with randomness
appear again and again and especially in
the AES GCM case were the worst thing
you can do is repeat the nonce all right
so the conclusion is that randomness can
repeat and it does repeat so what can we
do this is the this is a s GCM it is now
used everywhere there is dedicated the
hardware instructions and devices that
have dedicated hardware to speed this up
everyone is using this and it is by far
the best mode if you use it correctly
it's the best mode compared to
everything else so can we find a scheme
that would be resistant to nonce misuse
nothing happens if you repeat repeat the
nonce you want the same performance
benefits of the AES DCM so you want the
security you want the performance you
want it to be a small change compared to
a yes GCM because all the libraries and
so much hardware and devices and
protocols are already using a s GCM so
there are highly tuned assembly routines
that do implementations and Java code
and whatever so if we can find something
like this that would use the same
building blocks we can at least reuse
reuse components so deployment would be
easy and it would be very efficient so
we can we find something that has
security performance easily deployable
and very efficient with reuse so
wouldn't it be excellent if we can find
something like this
so yes there is there is something like
this int so we can have the cake and eat
it so this is what I'm going to explain
and I will just just just go in and
explain something about the SIV
encryption it's it is actually a general
concept SIV stands for synthetic ivy it
is from a paper by a rug away and
Shrimpton they had some proofs about
this and they are saying you have two
keys one of them is going to be the
encryption key and one of them is going
to be the authentication key and you
have a message and unknowns and the
first step you take some PRF some
pseudo-random function whatever you want
that uses the first key okay the first
key is the authentication a key and you
compute the result let's say that the
result is T and in the step the second
step you encrypt the message m using the
second key the encryption key and the
nonce T as the nomes and then you get
the result this is the ciphertext and of
course decryption is the other way
around so the trick is actually that the
nonce that you chose in the beginning is
not the nonce that goes into the actual
encryption because what goes into the
actual encryption is the result of the
nonce and the message and the first key
so so the the IV or the nonce that is
used for the encryption is synthetic in
a sense it's not the one that you chose
for the encryption it depends both on
the nonce and the message so so if you
repeat the nonce and you have a
different message then then then the IV
that is at the IV that is going to be
used for the encryption is going to be
different so we all if you repeat both
the nonce and the message you'll get the
same T but okay and the same encryption
but this is not
surprise right because this mode of
encryption and authentication is
deterministic of course if you use the
same nonce and the same message you'll
get the same result there is no security
leak from that except for the fact that
the message is the same message but this
is inevitable this is part of of
deterministic of over deterministic came
out so the problem with that paper was
that there was no efficient
instantiation to to actually do this it
was just something theoretical and
whatever was proposed was actually
performing at the level of the CBC
encryption which we wanted to abandon as
you saw previously so in this is work
that that I've been doing in 2015 with
you the Lindell from bar-ilan university
who actually wrote a paper with we
called it nonce misuse resistant mode
for less than a cycle per byte so you
can and and this this was published in
2015 and in 2016 we teamed up with Adam
Langley from from Google and we had an
improved version and it was submitted to
the IETF as a proposal for a mode this
was already in 2016 beginning of 2016
now we are in 2017 it has gone through
several revisions and I guess that it
would become an RFC very soon so in the
next meeting or so so it's underway so
what what is this wonderful mode so you
can think about it for simplicity it's
like doing a yes GCM but in reversed
order so in a yes in a yes GCM you take
the message you take the nonce you have
the key you first encrypt the message
and then you apply the authentication on
the ciphertext that's the definition and
then it means that if you repeated the
nonce twice you're lost both of them
vacation and integrity but in AES GCM
save the synthetic ivy we just do this
the other way around we take the G hash
and this is the component the hash
function that goes over the message and
the nonce and we apply some universal
hash function on this with some good
properties I'll skip this so we have a
value T that depends on the message and
the nonce and actually also on the aad
and this is being used or 96 bits out of
this so technically actually 95 beats
out of it because we want one bit to
differentiate blocks for encryption and
blocks for authentication so 95 bits are
used as a randomized synthetic IV for
the counter mode and then we just
encrypt so you can think about it it has
the same properties or the same
underlying elements of a a s GCM but
nothing happens if you misuse an unsafe
use and on spice unless you are using
the same message twice and the same
knowns and then ok somebody who is
looking at this traffic would know okay
you've done twice the same thing that's
all the clicks out the improper
important properties that the underlying
elements are identical to the existing
hdzm it means that we can take the same
we found some you can take the same
library like open SSL library and call
the same primitives and get this this
encryption another element is that was
added to that was added to this is a
derived key the right key mode and this
is to extend the lifetime of a key
because this is now becoming yet another
problem you want to use you want the
server to have a key that would last for
a long time and with high volume
encryptions
nowadays and so much data the kids are
wearing out quite quickly so for example
if you are using with AES GCM or with
with the GCM sieve you're using a random
nonce or a synthetically random nonce
and it has only 95 bits or 96 bits it
means that after 2 to the 48 times you
will repeat the nonce and you're back in
employing problems you might say 2 to
the 48 is not a problem but it is a
problem especially as the specifications
of of NIST require that the probability
of repeating unknowns in a randomized IV
implementation should not be more than 2
to them - 32 that's the requirement so
this means actually that you cannot use
AES GCM and also GCM sieve you cannot
use it more than 2 to the 32 times ok to
the 32 times are exhausted quite fast
right you can imagine we'll see later I
build up some some tension for for the 2
to the 32 so what we did in the AES GCM
sieve
we also added a key derivation so this
is just a scheme that is saying the
following you have a nonce you have
added date and you have a message and
instead of going and using the
cryptographic schemes ECMC or whatever
you first pass the nonce
through a key derivation function some
pseudo-random function and the
pseudo-random function would spit out a
key that would be used for that nonce
and then you continue as usual so
basically you can apply to any
encryption scheme you just prepend a key
derivation function before with the
encryption of course you need to do the
same for for decryption right and this
extends the lifetime of the key so just
without getting to too many technical
details
a s GCM sieve that uses this mold or
this trick can encrypt up to two to the
64 messages there is some restriction
they cannot be too long
you cannot encrypt to to the 64 messages
each one of them is of length 2 to the
32 blocks but nobody really wants to do
to encrypt so much data I mean typical
messages are much shorter so for short
messages you can encrypt up to 2 to the
64 this is basically the limit of of of
encryption in general with 128 block
bits a block and this is what we use for
AES so bottom line
okay so this is the compact the
comparison oh there is some line here
that doesn't show on so this is the GCM
sieve the encryption and the decryption
and you have on three CPUs but what we
are interested in nowadays in 2017 is
the skylake and processors and and
further where a es GCM is at point 65
and as I told you this is where you get
authenticated encryption at the same
performance cost of only the encryption
so you cannot get better than that
and we can see that the encryption is
point 94 so the promise was less than a
cycle per byte and magically decryption
is also a point 65 so for decryption you
can decrypt at the same cost of of the
corruption and check the authentication
the reason the surprising reason why
there is a difference between encryption
and decryption is the mode in itself
because when you are encrypting
theoretically you cannot do better than
first pass over the whole message and
compute the hash function and then start
so there is built-in serialization in
the mode itself whereas when you are
decrypting you can interleave these
operations and and do the same trick as
in AES GCM so this is the reason why
encryption and decryption are different
so in summary in summary a nonce misuse
resistant authenticated encryption at
extremely low cost almost as the AES say
GCM this is something of value because
we saw that there again and again
problems with generating entropy and
with making sure that IVs don't repeat
and we have a proof of security it's
easily deployable because you can just
use the same libraries and and it is
already ok here it's soon to be
integrated but Google is already using
this mode in in boring SSL this is their
own their own version of open SSL and
they are using this this mode and they
are reducing it for for a certain
application today so this concludes the
first part in the second part is is the
the part where we are going to see how
easy it is to brute force 2 to the 32
bit entropy let me just see how much
time you might have how much time do I
have what is the how much time do I
still have for this
all right well keep going until you you
throw stones at me all right so okay
part o is don't encrypt without
authentication for the audience I even
wrote this in in Portuguese so that if
you if you remember anything from this
is don't do this and keep seeing
technologies that come up with
encryption so I'll just give you a short
a brief account a historical account of
some progress in this say in this so in
this work that I've been doing for some
years already with what we go is there I
guess
because he's going to explain there is a
video and I wanted him to explain the
video in Portuguese so so it we call it
the blind at random corruption attacks
so what we were demonstrating is that if
you have memory or you know let's say a
let's take memory this was was the
attack and the memory is encrypted but
there is no authentication and you are
the attacker so you can read and write
the memory that's yeah you can read
there if you can read it you can also
write it and the reason why it was
encrypted to begin with was the
assumption that there is an attacker who
can read the memory and we want to
prevent you know the protect protect the
privacy
so although the attacker cannot decrypt
the ciphertext that he is reading it can
still make modifications and the
modifications would cause something to
change in some unpredictable way and
there is a like a belief a naive belief
that since this is so unpredictable and
so so much not controlled but by the
adversary that maybe this is good enough
so we already know that this is not good
enough if your hero nasty
make we made the demonstration that
showed that we can log into a locked
system with the overriding the memory in
I'll just remind the this type of of
attack and in the principle it was based
on and there was also another another
paper that I published with a different
team that we actually injected fault
attacks okay this is a fault attack you
changed something in the memory if you
just do it in the right place and you
attack the right code and the code was
really negligent enough not to check
then then you can make the fault attack
on on RSA and we were actually able to
grab out encryption the private enable
the private key of of RSA from an
implementation from some some library so
ok I will skip this I just want to to go
and okay I explained this I just want to
just to show how this was able to how we
can be a root on a locked system with
the blind that random block corruption
attack so if you change if everything is
encrypted with a block cipher and you
modify a single bit somewhere it is
going to corrupt a whole block of 128
bits with something that is
unpredictable but we looked at the the
way that the login probe program of Fame
of Linux was working and actually if you
look at this there is some free
authentication flag that if it is set it
would not ask you for the password
anymore because this is built for cases
were you already authenticated yourself
you just want to repeat something so
that that's the way it really works so
what we see that if we can just go over
this
pree authenticated flag or the region in
memory where this where this
authentication 10th occasion flag
resides in memory and we can just hit it
randomly we are with probability of 50%
all right going to be able to flip it to
yes all right
so within one or two such experiments we
will be able to log in to a machine
without having the password so you're
saying ok who cares we have a machine it
is locked and you can maybe maybe maybe
it's a machine maybe it's like a small
phone it's a soldier than so forth and
so forth then they but the actual threat
if we want to look at this is the is the
cloud situation the cloud situation
where you have a hypervisor and the
hypervisor controls the VMS of the users
and the hypervisor can enter a VM into a
debug mode that's a privilege of the
hypervisor so even with the technology
that has been recently proposed by AMD
they were saying we're going to encrypt
the whole memory you can still do the
same thing because because the because
the hi the hypervisor can put the victim
VM into a debug mode and the same login
program is running in the background the
user doesn't login with this the user
would typically login with with an SSH
application but the login program is
running in the background so the
hypervisor that can identify where in
memory these very precious variables are
residing
enter a debug mode and can write
something so again the hypervisor can
read the memory but since it since every
VM with this technology is going to be
encrypted with a different key it is not
going to be useful because the
hypervisor would read with its own key
so there would be a decryption with the
hypervisor key of something that was
encrypted with a different key of the of
the VM of the guest VM so it's not going
to help the hyper-v hypervisor is going
to see garbage and this is the this is
the promise of this technology but the
hypervisor can overwrite and if the same
login program is running in the
background
well the hypervisor can login as root
into the guest VM and then if the
hypervisor is root it can just copy
everything it doesn't need to go through
memory so all of the memory the
encryption of the memory is no not
useful anymore
so again as we see this is the result of
encryption with no authentication so the
old video I'm going to Rodrigo we are
going to show a to videos so one is the
previous attack and the new attack and I
am going so so we'll go we're going to
show the videos and first I'm not just
going to show the new so what is new so
what is new week we call it a single bit
flip right we were able to attack a
conditional that happens to be a
critical and just flip from one from
zero to one actually something from zero
to one and this happens with very high
probability so after one two three
attempts you you'll get what you what
you want so in a sense one could say
that although these are frequent and we
were able to demonstrate it's a weak
attack in a sense because it
only be applied to a conditional to a
conditional bit that happens to be
critical okay so guess what I have this
now watch this this but we will show
that we will show them the video later
so what we are going to show right now
is actually that there are ways to do
more not only on a single conditional
bit so here you can see a memory and we
just look at the memory addresses and we
count 128 bit blocks because that's the
standard encryption and we just view it
this way and so just imagine that
everything that goes out to memory is
encrypted and when it goes back it is
decrypted but every VM has its its own
different key so what what happens is
that we can look here we can see many
variables so we take three examples a
variable that is a nine unsigned the
character character so it's a byte it's
a it's an 8-bit so another variable is
sixteen bits and another type of
variable is an unsigned integer 32 bit
right so you can guess where I am
getting it instead of just looking
instead of just looking at the
possibility of flipping a single
critical bit we can allow ourselves to
go further so to find some some place
where we can brute-force a block that we
will just change a value of an integer a
32-bit integer to something that we want
with many attempts and assuming that the
rest of the bits will not affect the
rest of the computations and if we can
untie identify something like this then
we are able to attack much more than a
single bit so just here so this is just
a now there will be this
the famous so it sounds okay I'm
unbelievable right but if you look at
the way that the Linux kernel is built
so so then we see that the structure of
tasks has different ideas different IDs
and guess what the effective UID right
is a 32-bit value so wouldn't it be
wonderful if we could take the effective
UID
of a guest VM and change it and change
it to the hypervisors ID right so in
that case you can just escalate escalate
the the privilege of the process and
okay so okay I'll just skip here so did
we find a winner candidate so yes and
will now show that that it works so you
have many data elements with different
sizes yes this isn't in the kernel can
we find something that we can fully
brute-force something that is a 32-bit
integer how long do you think it takes
you to just do two to the 32 attempts
until you succeed not too long we will
we will see it right now so yes the
effective UID and you can if you the
successful attack would elevate the
privileges and what happens if others
other variables are changed okay we
don't care and and is it going to
succeed so I will just skip the
limitations and now ask Audrey go to
show the wonderful video with this
attack on 32 bits and it would explain
this in Portuguese it would be easier to
follow
all right where is it is running in the
background I think one of these yes okay
so we'll show this
okay okay so let let me try to explain
what are we actually doing here so we
have two VMs when one of the VMs is the
attacker VM the other VM is the victim
VM what we weren't is in the victim we
have a process that will be running that
process has no privileges it's just a
normal user the way that we show it we
show the output or the ID commands to
show that the user has no privileges and
we try to read a secret and basically we
don't manage to do it then in the
attacker what we do is like we connect
to this debug mode for the VM and we
start brute-forcing you see that in the
output it will show a new value for the
effective user ID every like 10 seconds
actually that's millions of tries okay
like in those ten seconds but we only
print every 10 seconds and you will see
that at some point that process will hit
zero which is the value for the
effective user ID of the administrator
in Linux and then basically it stops
brute-forcing and just like keeps the
privilege so the cool thing here is like
it's just one process that we need on
the victim but that process has no
privileges you will see that in the very
beginning what this process does besides
being like wanting to be elevated it's
actually it spawning multiple processes
and the idea to do that is so we can
locate wearing memory is our victim
right because the memory is encrypted as
an attacker we know that we could brute
force and bits but we don't know where
they are so what we do is like this
process is spawn multiple process that
basically forces the memory allocator in
linux to be in a certain behavior then
we start killing processes and creating
new ones
so finally we created a gap in the
memory location we know our this child
process are adjacent in memory so we
know that when we're hitting we're
hitting our process that's why even when
we fail we actually just give the wrong
privilege to the software so
you see when the program is running and
printing it will start printing many
different user IDs and it only stops
when it actually succeeds and gets zero
you wanted me to say that in Portuguese
well whether there is some English
speakers in the audience so it is
running as you can see this is the
victim so the process just wants to be
elevated it's gonna be very hard to see
it's very hard to see right yeah well
it's gonna be hard to see I'm sorry
oops
okay a little bit better so I will share
the video later as well okay so
essentially here I just run the command
I will basically read what is going on
on the video then so here I just run the
command ID so it shows that our user is
BS demon with like a user ID is a
thousand one right so that's what we
want to basically choose somehow change
right so when this user tries to read a
secret it's just a fire in the EGC
directory and it has no permissions even
though nobody's seen believe me so or if
you want you can come closer to this
screen okay I'm sorry for that so the
user don't have enough permissions so
it's basically didn't like a I just
listed the directories so you see that
this process that we executing is not
sweet root or anything is just a user
process something that the user can just
run on the machine when you run it the
very first thing that happens is all
this Forks that I mentioned so the
processes are creating a lot of childs
to basically make the memory in a
certain way and for us to be able to
identify where it is even in the
encrypted memory as you can see each of
this child process is to keep the same
effective user ID which is the original
user so a thousand one so when the brute
force starts so you say like I changed
the terminals so I start doing the brute
force so when the brute force starts
essentially what happens is like up you
see the regional effective user ID is a
thousand one so after some seconds we
print again right just like to see what
is the new value but now it is like it
it's showing like a big integer okay we
printing as sign of the integer so
showing negative but it's a no silent
value actually so it is a big integer
then again another one and it's all
random values you see like or or process
is becoming users that don't even exist
from that machine but in the way that
this system works if there you don't
that process don't try to do anything
that requires privileges it's all fine
this isn't keeps running right there is
no crash there is no nothing
we brute-forcing a data structure in the
kernel and
actually putting random values in that
data structure and the system continues
running as if nothing's happened and
then they're like you see like now it's
getting like more values more values and
again millions of tries are going on on
the background we're printing just every
like 10 seconds or so the matter is it's
a 32 bits it's random values each of the
bits are random independently because
it's through random property that
encryption gives to you so in a 32 bits
at some point it will reach 0 that's
what we went when it reached 0 the
process tells the brute-force search we
stopped and essentially it just keeps
with that privilege that it's just
gained it's it's going eventually you
will see that we end up with with root
so so now while we are waiting when
deceits will that's it
hello root so we're so again what is the
the lesson taken all right so no canny
we can get you see like once it's got
you a be 0 which is root the process
just called the shell because now that
share is root and now you can basically
read secrets you can do whatever you
want in that machine right it's a simple
brute force the fact that the memories
encrypted made very little difference
all right so so what we saw actually is
is an upgrade of the same type of attack
over encrypted memory we don't know what
the values that we are reading are we
don't know how they're going to be
changed by some change in the encrypted
memory but yet we can identify places
like in the first time it was a single
bit where a single bit was critical to
to flip from authentic a pre
authenticated or not pre authenticated
and allowed the the program to get a
login as root and this time it's more
it's not so so this type of attack of
unencrypted memory is not only on a
single bit you can apply this to other
things and you can just imagine that
this process ends after two to the 32
attempts on average of course the
sequence here was only showing after 10
seconds but this is absolutely doable
and in reality we see many many short
variables like 32 bits and which we find
smaller it's it's even better and right
so again again again
don't try to encrypt without
authentication unless you are absolutely
sure that the attacker cannot overwrite
and overwrite your memory or your
ciphertext but this is very difficult to
to promise something like this because
to begin with you encrypted your memory
because there is some adversary who can
read that memory so in most cases you
can think of if an adversary can read
the memory there is no reason why he
could not also overwrite the memory and
this means that you really need some
means of authentication even if it is
not a full proof a cryptographic
authentication even something that would
fail the system and
frustrate an attacker just imagine that
somebody wants to do this hack over 32
bits and there is some some kind of
authentication that gives you another 32
bits of authentication or even 16 bits
of authentication something very very
simple now something that took a few
minutes is going to take a very long
time
so I would say okay that's it and thank
you for your for your time
and I'm done with this
[Applause]