it was the same design firm that did the
quick and the tls one 3d logo so they're
sort of started builder no trying to
tell them it's a growing market it was
cool being in that design meeting
meetings um Rick where's Richard anyhow
that's right yeah I was sort of
interesting started you know took all of
the CA Thrones looked at the color
schemes tried to find something that was
different obviously wanted different
identity from you know let's encrypt the
original source so yeah help yourself to
you know couple stickers from each only
just got his stickers um the as with the
others the SVG files and stuff you know
there you go appreciate that
it'll be available so you can pull them
down you know the open source sticker
patterns so okay okay so let's begin
Thank You Yvonne for taking this picture
I just added the ITF 103 party here's
the note well sure you've seen this a
couple of times now hasn't changed much
hopefully because I just copied this
side from my TF 101 okay agenda so we
have blue sheets going around we have a
note taker in JavaScript okay and we've
seen the note 1 so we're going to talk
about document status and then
yeah one is going to talk about I can we
start Alexei is going to talk about
email certs and John and Will's going to
talk about any authority token so any
agenda bashing no okay so let's get on
it so since the last meeting we've had
last call start and July 25th last Co
ended August 8th made some changes based
on based on last call comments I was
tenth then we had a bunch of comments
and discusses from the iesg
yeah always ruin everything so then at
version 15 but Adam rotaries disgusts
was still in resolving there was a lot
of discussion the list about allowing or
disallowing gets as opposed to
authenticated posts finally October 12
we had version 16 with no more gets and
among other changes and finally and
November the second the document is
approved but there needs to be a
revision for some minor comments so this
is where I'd put the slide with ticker
tape and champagne bottle graphic but
we've already done that about a year and
a half ago so not jinxing it again okay
we've got acne IP publication requested
a quick point on that last slide Richard
Barnes I'm still waiting for my
co-author to take a look at the PR that
we have open with these minor revisions
so while you're sitting in the room here
you might pull up the github repo and
take a quick glance at that and see if
there's anything you want scream about
while we're still here I'll probably
merge it late tonight or tomorrow cool
so we have three documents in now late
stages acumen I came back me pls alt and
publication requested and Acme CAA is
gone through ID evaluation revised ID
needed some and J shall just posted his
revision so that should be good to go
now I think okay okay yeah pull the
statuses out of the data tracker
yesterday I'm sorry okay good because I
said the wrong name um just before you
know 24 hours before the IETF started we
got a revision addressing occurs issue
so we'll that's moving through the is J
again okay any comments about any of
these three because we're not going to
have any presentations about them okay
so now time for presentation and first
up is all right so I'm Aaron surfer I
will be talking about thank you I will
be talking about two documents one is
the working group document at my star
and the other is at master delegation so
studying with the working group document
[Music]
yeah so as we all know the base at my
document move move to use posters get
for everything however this is this
doesn't work in delegation use case
and therefore we added treatment of HTTP
GET in this document this is the main
change that happened in zero form we
made some terminology changes this is
one example some smaller changes as well
we clarified the certificate validity so
in the case when you have a certificate
that's good for say three days you want
to have it on available on the server
fifty percent so a day and a half before
it's before the previous one expires and
you want the new certificate to actually
be valid as soon as it's available
so we clarified all this all of this and
we we also talked about Reve occasion
and made that explicitly not supported
for this type of certificates next so to
drill down into the way we're proposing
to use get the server adds an attribute
so we added an attribute the server
needs to include in the metadata object
in that directory object and then it's
on a perl older basis so client asks for
this specific order so for the series of
certificates for in order to be
available we are get and assuming the
server's ok with it the there this
attribute will also be set on the order
object and of course the client will be
able to to use it through gate
other than that fetching the certificate
is unchanged from
what we have in version zero three of
the draft next okay so the status of the
document is it was actually past working
group last call and so on the verge of
being publication requested but we made
quite a few changes starting with the
get thing but also including other
changes so it's basically for the
working group to decide what we want to
do now we could rerun it through working
group last call or weaker we could move
it forward just so anyone in the room
wanna express an opinion I mean it seems
like there have been some substances
changing since the last last call so I
wouldn't mind it another we're here your
class called for ease in the Sun okay
all right we'll we'll start one pretty
much now and yeah well do this second
working last call thing that silence is
interpreted this agreement yeah we'll
post that to the list and the
expectation that you know since I think
the bulk of the changes were caused by
acne changes it should be fairly
straightforward like to encourage
everyone that please read the document
okay all right so we'll do it we'll
start a two-week last call and post it
on the list and then move forward again
for publication
alright next slide please
so moving to the other document and I
need a shepherd is anybody interested
in being a document Shepard this is sort
of writing up the history of the
document within the working group and
it's presented with the publication
request it's an easy way to disability
points you get brownie points comma
points if not it falls to working group
chairs but it's if you're thinking about
getting more involved and at some point
it's a good way to get experience as to
what's involved so if you are interested
and again we'll post this on the list
too if you are interested let want to
let the chairs now otherwise we'll flip
a coin and I think it's my turn okay all
right so speaking of document history
atmost our delegation went through sec
dispatch sec dispatch said yeah this has
to do with ACMA send it to acme folks at
acme weren't so happy with it because it
was sort of a very small rest api and
not an ACME protocol per se so now it is
we actually rewrote the document as an
acme protocol profile with some
differences of course which will list
later and this is now published as draft
chef and so on next so what this is
doing is we have two akhmet protocol
state machines one between the name
delegation client and they identify our
owner and another between they identify
owner which is a classical ACMA client
and the CF server there's essentially no
change there is no change to the
protocol between the I do and there and
the CA but the protocol between the NDC
and the I do is basically a subset of
their Acme protocol and the way this
works is the
name delegation client creates an order
requests to the I do identifies itself
or authenticates itself as an account
owner on the I do
and now the I do acts both as an ACME
server and an ACME client sort of a
proxy but not exactly and the document
goes into the specifics of what is proxy
than what is not unlike regular Acme the
CSR gets sent immediately and there are
no authorizations for the client and
then the doc is there protocol between
the I do and the CI server is just
normal like me or like my stop next so
like I said the MDC has an account on
the I do were the I do acts as an
alchemy server and this is how the the
NDC authenticates and science its
requests through the account object
there are no authorizations it's a
simpler state machine and one more thing
in order and you can move to the next
slide in order to simplify the
management of DNS delegations that
normally come in this situation we
include cname information into the
identifier object as you can see at the
bottom of this slide we add an attribute
delegated in a cname listing the actual
name that should go into a cname
resource record that will be created
assuming the I do has an auto
waited way to provision this record into
its DNS zone Richard Richard boys just
quick clarifying classes so this is
something this is what is sent by the
NBC to the I do in its order request yes
so clarify to kind of provide the
identifier owner instructions for how it
should fulfill the DNS challenge correct
not the DNS challenge it's simple
bookkeeping DNS bookkeeping to be
performed by the NDC Thomas would you
like to add something so what I was
understanding this is to say is like if
you delegate the the this the value DNS
name if you have provision to see name
to the cname DNS name then I'll handle
the challenge fulfillment for you so
what this is meant to say no no no the
the guiness challenge is run on the
value and that's it
and the cname is just in hint to for for
the for the middle guy oh yeah you to to
to actually fill the zone so to create
the mapping between value and see name
John Pearson the cname is basically what
you're getting a search for - right no
it is not okay the cert is value okay
okay and by the way this this whole
thing is optional but it's simplified
sort of synchronizes the DNS work that
you normally do with the certificate
registration so when the CA is on the
ultimate in
this goes to validate the indc dno dot
example name is the idea that there will
be a cname provision for that that will
cause the validation request to go no no
so we're at what cname is provisioned as
a results of this points from NDC 2 nd
CDN oh boy no points from dno to NDC
right yes this this is like when I want
my CDN to get a cert for me it's a
similar Yosuke so I I would assume so
comes from John Peterson he said so this
is like lurk so I think bumping up a
level I obviously need to read the
drafts and really understand this but
I'm worried that we're conflating two
functions here one is setting up a
delegation and the other is issuing
certificates that you've leveraged that
delegation to do validation so maybe
maybe he's okay I'm not totally
convinced that those are worth kind of
slamming together in this way I'll take
a look at the drafts and since
next piece the the document is sort of
on the face also on the fenced area
guarding whether this is restricted to
short-term certificates or applicable to
your normal long-term certificates and
this is something that I would like to
open with a group here we could focus on
short-term certificates unless people
feel that delegation is actually useful
for the normal certificate case opinions
ideas I mean this seems almost obviously
useful for the the short-term otter or
need case but I don't see a necessary
reason to conjoin them like that that
makes sense it's like I don't see a
reason to say you shouldn't do this for
long term stuff it's just that there's
not a much reason to okay at least right
now it's possible to to have them also
gonadal if if somebody finds a finds a
solution where in Crystal mints whereas
they're they're using them for long term
certs and it makes life easier I think
more power to them we should encourage
these sorts of solutions okay
[Music]
you have no it's no Hudson what if we
don't find such a use case before the
thing is published you doing publish
hoping that when such use case can was
it it's really appropriate because this
this has endangered looked when we that
at some point we would want to do
delegation as an overt for long term
certificates this one is not appropriate
because right now we don't have any use
cases like that
mrs. Daniel Kahn Gilmore I'm asking if
you are going to restrict the star how
are you going to restrict it to star
what is the what what specific cut line
would you use to make that restriction
is it based on expiry date requested or
other mechanisms
well the document could simply say that
if you as an ideal receive this request
you must include star related attributes
and that would restrict it yeah Tim
Holoubek
my personal opinion is that just makes
things much more complicated
I think if you if the if delegation
depends on something like the
certificate lifetime which is completely
independent of what you're actually
doing then you know everybody has to
keep in their mental models and all
their analysis that oh delegation is for
short-term certificates and that's a
special case that doesn't exist for long
term certificates I I I'm sensitive to
the idea of are we building something
that people will use or not but I think
there are lots of cases where you want
to do delegation and I don't think it
has anything to do with the lifetime at
the certificate it's more useful in
short live certificates but I think it's
generally useful and I don't see any
good reason to restrict it alright thank
you
seems like we'll have to take that to
the list like everything else but
without a sense of doom unless we want
to take a sense of it's not a working
group document yet it still came to us
for advice yes or request are you
requesting that we that we adopt this
that's on the next slide so do we want
to take a ham if we think that for this
document whether it is or is not working
document it should be restricted to star
yeah why not I think it's kind of early
before anybody has read the document
okay or they can
the draft okay so well humbly asking the
working group to adopt the document
richard bronzy and i'm gonna harp on
this scene anything a little bit more
because if you've delegated a cname if
the identifier owner has delegated cname
to the the end server effectively the
what do you call it the NDC then the NDC
can just run an ACME on its own it
effectively owns that identifier now it
doesn't need to go through the
identifier owner at all right because
the dns just points to it it can well I
can't do the DNS challenge but it can do
the the HTTP challenge maybe it can do
the DNS challenge but I can do at least
some of of the domain name challenges
just by having a cname pointing to it in
fact this is there's a lot of deploy to
art it has a very specific same name I
was asking Richard like how does base
acne actually work on this fitting
counters the cname when it's resolving
the challenge it just works so if we
just trickle through anyway okay my
understanding is there's CD ins today
that are doing this to do acne issuance
so so in the indication still doesn't
have the the account key is that would
that be a problem or no there's no
there's no inherent binding between the
count keys and domain names except what
you prove by doing validation so if if
no one's ever claimed ABC Don NBC do you
know dot example and some random account
key that happens to be that an NBC shows
up and validates that it can control
that domain then the CA will accept that
he has control that domain there's no
need to route the Acme request through
the domain owner because the CA doesn't
know who the domain owner is it's trying
to find out
so yeah I think this is the cname stuff
here it's pretty confusing other than
that the document seems saying so okay
remind folks that the document when if
we adopt it it doesn't have to come in
the door with every issue result yeah I
think this is more of a scoping question
of whether the the cname establishment
between a domain owner and the ultimate
serving entities is germane for this and
I'm not really seeing that as a
necessary case here although happy to
discuss John Peterson again so I think
the difference would be if you only have
an account with the intermediate write
that is acting as a back-to-back Acme
client server for you here and you don't
have an account with the end server
which is the use case you had up
originally right like then then you can
kind of see the sense of it right so if
your your account is only with dno is
that right the domain name owner there's
an idea in this case idea idea okay if
your account is only with the idea
that's running that then yeah like then
you wouldn't be able to prove it the
main server unless you establish some
independent account with that so at
least that's different it's not very
different but it's at least you know if
the argument is that this doesn't
actually accomplish anything
at least accomplishes that right it just
a boost does that like back to back then
yeah you would have to have a son of
yeah I find that not so convincing
because Acme accounts are cheap like you
just spin them up on demand
you know except where a CA is imposing
conditions on things so for example one
thing that's been discussed off and on
the lots and crip discussed for a while
was like you might say lock a domain to
a particular account so if you if an
account if a domain has been validated
by a given account you might refuse to
validate it to other accounts in the
future I'm not aware of anyone doing
that in practice with acne at least
unless other CAS might be doing
something like that and if you're doing
that there would be value to routing
through the guy who'd validate it so so
maybe there's something that reasonable
there yeah maybe
I want to make sure that topic was done
before I I just have a quick question
actually cuz on the star side of things
we have cases for delegated certificates
in a very similar model is there open
are you locking this DNS type or are you
open to having other identifier types in
the delegated model so first of all once
this is a working group document this
would be a working group decision just I
don't see any reason to like it
specifically to do dns okay yeah I
figured so but I thought I'd bring it up
just to make people aware of it hmm
Sanjay Mishra just a quick question here
so the cname that the string that you're
using here so the NBC is asking I do
that this is the cname I want you to use
when you are delegating to me is that
what that field is indicating yes okay
that makes sense yeah anyone else okay
so how many of read this draft yeah
still not that I'm going to have
adoption but how about we have Monday
question whether the working group would
like to do work in this in this area in
this domain on this subject and after
that we do the regular call for adoption
where people would be expected to read
before really give their opinion so how
many things that this document is this
subject is something that the working
group should do work on humm now
how many think that this is something
that the group should not do work on
okay that's pretty clear so we'll send
well we'll wait a week because people
don't really do any ITF work in the week
following ITF because yeah we're late
for stuff so in about a week or two
we'll issue a call for a doctrine and
see where that takes us from the five
people who have read it okay so next up
is Alexi thank you I did my slides and
expectation that people read some
version of the document how many people
have read email TLS document right
okay so basic idea is to issue
certificates rottmayer to email services
like a map or person to be submission so
the main changes in the late latest
version is basically the shuffling of
moving some attributes from jose header
i believe to the payload I think I
talked to Richard Barnes here she said
it's the more natural thing for it to be
yeah corrected some typos and I would
also edit SMTP extension registration
which is a requirement for sent EP
extensions so one remaining open issue
is whether it's useful to have a single
request that asked for single
certificate for multiple related
services I'm sort of on the fence on
this if people have a preference where
one way or another please let me know
but I'm tempted just to do it change the
list of ports and services to be an
array and then you can handle this case
Paul Hoffman I under I understand the
first question I don't understand the
proposed change we're gonna make which
way would it move it towards so at the
moment service is a single service name
yep and port is a single book yep so if
you want to issue say IMAP port 143 and
I'm a passport nine and three you need
to do two requests so if I want if what
I want is the answer for the first
question to be yes it's okay to have the
same I want you to have these arrays
correct yes so okay in this case you
will see you are changing it to
something that I want yeah okay great
cuz because I do think that it is just
fine to have certificates allowed to
cover multiple I see no reason not to
yeah I think the typical use case is a
lot of mail products come as a set of
related services mm-hm so it's easier to
have a single certificate that covers
IMAP open up exactly right so then you
will ask for several and you know only
one go okay great thank you okay
to clarify are we talking about one or
two arrays one array to port for service
it's going to be services one array and
one array for ports and they need to
match 101 I would if people prefer to
have a single attribute which you have
an array of pairs I can do that I don't
think it's so Richard burns now I'm
confused because the this
document is talking about authenticating
DNS identifiers and so the thing that
would go into the certificate that's
being issued is a DNS name so the
certificate would just be about the name
not the port's the owner you can issues
SRV certificate with a serving name okay
subject but that's not specified in here
is it it is mentioned in a document they
think oh okay I mean yes in the most
common case you you are going just to
have actually one DNS name covering all
services but I see sorry
so in that case yeah this might need a
little bit of refactoring I think it
might make sense to treat SRV ID as a
different identifier type that would
then get its own challenges basically
the same challenges you've got here but
then you'd not the identifier type to
you would you'd say I want to be able to
be able to say host name and port in the
identifier in the cert and then you
validate possession of that host name
important key key to you at the mic so
as I'm gonna agree with you Richard and
so it seems like if the only thing if
the ultimate thing that's being issued
is just based on name then including
this mechanism is too much complexity if
the it's the thing that you're trying to
issue embeds this stuff then obviously
you need it right but but but I also
don't know who's actually validating as
Harvey named inserts at all like so that
there's like several steps of the chain
that seem to be missing
to justify the inclusion of this of this
additional complexity if the name would
have worked anyway right right or or or
is what this is supposed to be doing
giving the giving the issuing CA in
different instructions on how to find
the response yes depending on the
challenge there is for DNS there will be
different slightly different DNS name to
check the challenge for it will be
service specific
and if you are using in protocol
challenge obviously smtps SMTP specific
box three specific so again if the cert
that's being issued isn't specific to
the service on the port then this opens
up some flavor of attack on the names
that are that are going to be validated
by the other but by existing clients on
other protocols right right this Trice
what currently people sometimes do they
start HTTP server on a host running
email system and just get the regular
certificate and it covers yes as a
side-effect I do that today right this
is trying to be tighter than that well
it's tighter than that except that it's
it's headed decided in that for issuance
but looser than that for use unless
you're issuing an SRV name search right
so Paul often again this isn't clear in
the current draft because I thought that
this was all about putting in like
attributes in the cert so the fact that
you're you know so I'm just saying
whatever you do here making a ray or
whether you should also be adding a
paragraph or two maybe with examples I
guess we've got a couple layers of
indirection here we've got the name that
appears in the search the thing you
validate the identifier you validate an
ACME and the challenge you used to
validate it I think what I'm least clear
on is the mapping between the thing
that's in the cert and the thing that
you want to validate for instance it may
be possible that CAS are willing to put
SRV names inserts for arbitrary reports
if you validated control the domain name
because you've proven you own the domain
so have all the port's you want and in
that case you can just use DNS
identifiers and you just have a
different way to promote it is that the
operating concept here I'm hoping that
CAS will issue a service by validating
specific port but the DNS name is a
fallback just okay so if you if you want
to see a to validate the specific ports
and I think you do want like I see an
SRV name identifier instead of using the
DNS identifier because that that way you
can have challenges that maps that
specific port yes I have no idea what M
do you guys do email certs at all you
can comment on the state-of-the-art here
Tim Holly that one not so much I thought
you were gonna ask me to comment to the
state of the art and SRV names which is
the names of your question
they've been discussed but basically
nobody's doing it the the other
interesting comment that I wanted to
make while I happen to be up here is the
assumption that all services on a
particular domain are controlled by the
same people and even operate by the same
server is no longer true and so that's
something we probably want to be a
little bit careful about and I would
like to live in the world that you live
in where if you have a certificate for
you want to live in as well let me put
it that way if you have a certificate
for a particular service it was
validated against that particular
service the server and port but it's
gonna take a while to get there well
yeah I obviously there is a catch-22
problem here so I'm developing server
software that use these or client
software that can validate these like
including a serving name but always
tendency is to start issuing this yes
okay okay and so I I think
speaking of previous discussion I think
Richard you're going to send some
suggestion about challenges and yeah
okay sounds good
so other than this chain proposed change
to array or you know array of pairs or
something I think this would be ready
for law school obviously you know that
discussion we had here
I don't know it might be sort of like
working group class call discussion or
maybe you'll find out that there is more
discussion to have on the mailing list
so say you know based on Richards text
the text you gotta write and then we can
then issue last call and really
encourage people of the working group to
read this these are very short it's a
short document yeah that's - I mean so
simple he's done told she got reading
[Music]
okay okay yeah I talked about this I can
also ask about one SMTP and I'm
appending lists who is interested in
implementing some what s mine this had a
little bit more work recently but it's
sort of far away to being completed I
actually got a couple of reviewers on
the mailing list commenting on the
proposal basically this is issuing and
user certificates for smile and the way
it works that there is a new challenge
half of
we're talkin arrives over HTTP that half
arrives over email and a special message
and then the client sends calculate you
know signature and sends the response in
another message so most of the most of
the work here was in recent versions was
done on specific messages and there are
some examples of this might look like
again here you know if you have a
particularly Malick's but geez feel free
to comment I'm sort of talking a lot to
myself trying to convince on one hand
it's would be nice to use the most
simple implementations so they don't
have to understand a lot about mine and
just maybe you you know parts that point
parts but in reality a lot of clients
are using and generating more
complicated messages like multi-party
tones of where they send both explained
in HTML or maybe the reason you to send
an attachment which can be processed by
external program so if you have comments
apologize I didn't tweet the draft but
are you expecting users to respond to
the challenge manually or are you
expecting explicit support in in clients
either so the idea is that the message
is simple enough that it can be handled
automatically by mail client because
there are special ways of recognizing
that this is special challenge it's also
would be possible for the user to cut
and paste token into an external app
generate the value placed into response
send it back wonderful I will read it
this is deg channeling for Thomas Peter
he says on validation Demark should be
used as it defines domains name to make
domains use of either d km or SPF right
yes so yeah one of the open issues is
well 20 years ago emails who are quite
and secure these days you expect a bit
more validation where they say no it's
mine signatures or g/km Demark all of
this stuff so I think the document
should be more specific on
recommendations again if people have an
opinion you know so yes my signature
obviously only works for the challenge
from the CA to the client because we are
trying to get a smile certificate from
the client to you know it's only work in
one direction but Demark dickham can be
used on both messages challenging
response so anyone else in the room
gonna promise to read these dr. stack
thank you Dan Daniel and Tim I have a
question I won't cook the mic because
I'll trip over the wires here is there
any provision in the draft about people
reading their email on different clients
multiple clients if you get the
certificate into one client and it's not
present on the other you're going to get
encrypted mail and not be able to read
it I don't think there is a case of
encrypted mail it might be as mime
signed wage K it should be which if your
client cannot verify signatures that a
lot of email clients once they've seen a
signature from you they're going to
allow people to encrypt allow the user
to encrypt to the mayor that's going to
you yes both that's yet another
what could be new when everybody had one
one client to read the mail one client
and one mode of actually implementing
all of these choices yes good question I
don't know thank you thank you
which leaves us with John and/or Chris
who's on first your final presentation
we will be doing this two-headed giant
snail come on man get inked in the view
[Music]
this is really short-range left hand
okay yeah so we're talking about
authority tokens and T n awfulest we
don't have much to say though so you
guys can pretty much check out in case
you forgotten what the authority token
is for this came out of the work that
we're doing in ster where we decided
there's a be way to do challenges with
some kind of a generic authority that
has some out-of-band means of
determining which kind of clients would
have the authority to claim certificates
or certain kinds of identifiers
telephone numbers or original use case
so the way that the TN off list is
defined in this as broader than just
telephone numbers des plies to some
telephone network specific identifiers
like service provider codes that we've
defined over and stir and so we put
together this document that tried to dis
make this completely generic to make it
so anybody who wants to prop up an
authority token service could do so
you'll be able to create a job and you
know basically have use this to prove to
the ultimate authority token that that
you deserve to be able to get or
certificate for particular identifier we
created a typing mechanism for that and
this really short range this is what a
challenge this might look like for this
this this particular type of a
touken here we have the token type
defined as ATC which is the version we
use for jobs and that's all that's in
the first one of these drafts and that
Draft has not changed a terrific amount
in this particular revision but we have
a registry for those types that so
people undefined other types for it they
could to use things other than jaw
that's all in there is amazingly short
range so then we did go ahead and define
a way to do this that is specific to the
telephone number option for this and
Chris can talk probably a bit about that
and what we've done with it but at the
end of the day really where we are with
this as for this revision we just did
some editorial fixes we updated the
examples so that they actually conform
with the latest version of Acme and the
changes that were made in that we put in
some errata that had come through from
from addis i don't you want to talk a
bit about what changes you made yeah the
only thing I wanted the only thing I
wanted to mention there was over in the
IP n and I that's the service provider
specific industry group that's using
stir we've put that into our documents
shaken and reviewed it over there so you
know first what I thought to try it on
this yeah and we've been kind of slow
slow rolling it a little bit until we
made sure that the people over at us
were comfortable with this precisely
because we're trying to get buy-in from
pretty large service provider community
that is not necessarily familiar with
the typical vocabulary of how we would
do things for approving things for DNS
names and so on so it's important that
we keep that on board in terms of what
we still have to do I don't think this
is ready for last call or review
probably at this stage we we do want to
patch in and we're just gonna
shamelessly steal this from what the
people are doing in at us the restful
interfaces are actually using for token
acquisitions we don't have anything for
that now in the main authority token
draft are in in our inclination that
though is not to actually make it like
this is the mandatory way to do it but
instead to have that be an example and
if people want to use something other
than this restful interface that'll be
fine but we will at least define one way
of doing this in the base specification
or at the
betoken we have a ton of housekeeping
still to do in both drafts though like
adding seconds to the the TN off less
draft so I think probably we do one more
wrap of this it should be ready for
review and hopefully for last call
there's really not much to it I guess so
this is not a particularly complex I
think mechanism anymore you add or is
there anything that people would like to
discuss about this document at this time
it's really fascinating document and
this is like all we have left I think we
get to go home the answer is no so
obvious a downer question how many have
read the draft shaking stir passport
folks have all been right yeah so that's
kind of when we talk about review over
it @s that's why they do shaken and it's
you know this is a pretty crucial use
case or for that in the sense of there's
actually like major agencies and
governments and carriers and stuff that
are spinning up the process that'll
actually create the seasons for this and
so it's not an insubstantial
use case right so this is cloud rich no
this is related to what the chairman of
the FCC just asked us providers to
provide it is yeah Sherman pie sent a
very polite note to the CEOs of a number
of carriers including that microphone
Chris asking them to please explain how
assumed they were going to do all the
stir shaken stuff and he has a pretty
aggressive timeline in mind for that I I
think this doesn't necessarily have to
be fully baked before we can start doing
things with stir and shakin and there
were already you know various kinds of
trials and test cases and labs and so on
that have been proven out for it but I
think the long-term operational plan of
how we get this deployed in the
telephone network is gonna require these
certificate authorities they are defined
and by the cloth authentication trust
anchor process that we all went through
with the FCC and so on so yeah this has
happened probably makes sense to say
that you know the effect the authority
we're talking about and the authority
token is being to set up as we
pick any other comments questions you
get to go home if not promises to read
the document so like I said I would
honestly before I wanted to point
reviewer eyes at it I think we should
bake a little more into it but then we
probably like has everyone signed the
blue sheets haven't we've got one right
here at the front all right make sure
you sign the blue sheets and whoever's
got the handful of stickers that are
left please bring them up to and if they
yeah so I handed them out with blue
cheese thank you all and we did good so
far
[Music]