alright guys about time to start but I
still need a jabber scribe somebody I'm
jabber
my laptop anybody
by somebody a coffee beer anything
hey Kevin do you happen to have Java
installed on your laptop I do not
I was hoping something else was gonna
show up and somebody in particular was
gonna show up and I was gonna recruit
them but they're not here so is Matt not
in the room who Matt I don't see him
let me see if I could do it real quick
[Music]
anybody who just strolled in want to be
a jabber scrub oh it's it's not hard at
all just need somebody to do it thank
you all right Kevin I think we're ready
all right
you want to drive okay all right
everybody it's time to get started this
is the CD and I are working group I hope
this is where you want to be so chairs
are Kevin whose remote and myself and
Francois we have one session it's just
today and just in this room I already
have minute takers minute taker I
already have jabber scrub and blue
sheets are going around so this is the
note well I'm sure you've seen this as
everybody like to say please note it
well anything you say in here is a
contribution so all right here's our
agenda for today the agenda bashing and
introduction from chairs a document
status update I'm gonna talk about URI
signing for a little bit and then we
will Frederic will talk about HTTP
delegation and then orys going to talk
about the SV AOC drafts
one of which is now a working group
document and then we're going to talk a
little bit about reach are during at the
end and if we need to or not and
conclusions the next steps so before we
go any further is anybody wanna bash
this agenda oh all right
Kevin you want to do this part yep
the slides are training really slowly so
I'm gonna assume you already have the
slide up yeah working group milestones
and published our season right so these
two lists haven't changed any of these
are our published rfcs you can skip
through those two pages the current
remaining milestone the only milestone
that we have currently is the URI
signing which hopefully will be done
very soon
we're gonna get an update on that today
on the next slide we have our beyond
working group milestones CD NIH DPS
delegation which Frederick is going to
talk about and we have an adoption
call-out currently which it's looking
like we're probably going to get an
adoption there the CD and I request
drawing extensions as Phil just
mentioned we did adopt that and then
there's the CD and eye control interface
triggers extensions which last time we
discussed might need a charter update
but we will talk about that at the end
we will be adding milestones for the new
documents that are not currently that
have been adopted or will be adopted but
are not currently milestones and we're
not currently pursuing the rate pacing
at this time
unless someone in the working group has
a strong feeling about the need to add
rate pacing metadata so next slide so I
think we're ready to go Phil if you're
ready all right
all right shout out to Brian Campbell
for his awesome pictures that he offered
up through for this so there we go much
better
alright so right now we're sitting on
draft 16 that's that's been that was
uploaded right before the deadline so we
had another one 15 that was just there
was a small goof in it so I just did a
16 so basically the changes since 14
added the critical claim set this is
something we talked about in Montreal we
also talked a lot about the sign token
death and this was actually what took
the longest I took the most amount of
work to get right so we had some
conversations in Montreal and on the
mailing list and on the issues about
this and the the final consensus on it
was that we would go sign token depth so
I didn't hear any more issues on that so
I merged that one in removed the simple
URI container that was non-controversial
that we talked about in Montreal and
some small knits so next steps I think
personally as editor we're ready for a
working group last call so and I would
like to hear comments as to whether or
not people agree if specifically people
disagree with that and that's about it
Chris lemons from Comcast on your on
your diff you missed the swap between
pcre and yari I wouldn't necessarily
discuss that as a small-knit we did talk
about it on the mailing list
yeah very good point I'm sorry I missed
that
so we we changed out originally one of
the URI containers was pcre and we
switched it to ER ye-yes which is a
POSIX standard and we did we did have it
talked about that on the mailing list
but I think I don't think there was as
much discussion I think that was just
agreed upon that that was the best route
to go yeah yeah thank you for mentioning
that forgot about that
and the second thing I actually opened a
pull request
yes github and made a comment on the
mailing list I found in practice 403 is
not always the best answer sometimes
when the token is out of date there is a
value in redirecting the client to
somewhere they can get a better token or
have a more useful error message or
really a whole bunch of different use
cases I think the the language I put up
is a potentially simple way to handle
that so we may want to consider some
error handling as we go into last call
but yeah I agree we want to get this as
close to finish as soon as we can okay
so to get to give a little more
background on what Chris said he he
wants to be able to redirect the user
somewhere in the event that their token
has expired that the token is invalid
for reasons other than then being like
yeah so the idea is if your token is bad
we want to know normally we just send
you a 403 but if your token is bad in
some cases we want to send you back to
where you can get a good token or maybe
an alternate version of the content that
doesn't require the token or some
fallback
a whole bunch of use cases that came up
in practice but we can't allow that to
happen if the token is not signed
properly because otherwise we allow an
amplification attack exactly yeah so
that's what I was trying to point out so
there there was no there was no other
feedback on that so I don't know
discussion yeah there was no discussion
on the mailing list and no discussion on
the issue
I've prodded some people to see if we
could get some feedback but I I don't
know so my my feeling on it is that it's
it's kind of an over complication but
I'm not opposed to getting it in it just
seems like I think I feel like we
discussed it at some point and we said
wow this is this is gonna be a lot of
extra detail to put in but since you've
already done the wording I think it's
worth talking about but I would love to
hear more feedback on that and whether
or not we need to add that before
working group last call or not so that's
that's my thoughts on it
agreed anybody have thoughts it did put
it up right before the meeting actually
technically during the meeting so people
may not have read it don't you put it up
last week or like this weekend yeah it
was this weekend so depends exactly this
meeting Ryan to sit depends what you
call the IETF meeting started people may
have been on their airplanes so I I
haven't read it yet is it is the
proposal a nuke a new claim an optional
claim what is it it's it's a as I have
it currently worded it's a pair of
optional claims a one claim for what
code to return and one claim for what
what the location parameter should be
and the goal is to make it as simple as
possible for implementers to handle so
it's an optional claim on signing but
processors must implement it okay and is
it likely to increase the size of the
token
significantly yes anyone who uses this
claim will have to pay the cost of
having the redirect location inside the
token but obviously if you don't use the
claim then you don't have that in there
right there there's no way around that
if you want something you have to pay
for it my other my other concern about
it is having to have enough state to be
able to have continuity for the user so
if if you redirect them back to some
sign-in page or whatever there's got to
be enough context in that URL that you
in that URI that you redirect them to to
also then get them back to where they
were so it's not it's it's gonna be very
it's gonna be very long that's a correct
observation in fact one of the requests
originally was that the tocut the the
the bad token be included as either a
query string or path parameter or a
cookie or whatever in the redirect
process itself so that whatever received
the redirect would have that and I felt
like that was probably an unnecessary
complication but it would shrink the
potential URI sighs so the other
observation I had was that currently if
you're watching a video online and
there's some kind of air it's kind of
like hey there's some kind of air try
this again later and you know exiting
out and going back and you know I'm
thinking Netflix YouTube that kind of
thing seems to be a rare enough event
and kind of an accepted user experience
yeah we could we could make it more
seamless but I feel right but streaming
video isn't the only use case here right
this is this is general-purpose and
generally useful I guess I kind of feel
like when there's an air we don't always
have to have this completely seamless
right but if I actually have a user
agent that's a browser at the other end
of this it would be really nice to be
able to redirect them to the login page
because there are multiple use cases for
this
did use were you just saying that it's
an it's two optional claims however the
the CDN is required to implement them
right I don't see a way around that
because it's error handling right so the
receiver has to have to know what to do
with it if someone gives it to them yeah
cuz because I feel like if it were just
two optional claims and there weren't
objections it would be easier to put in
but put it in a requirement that how
this whole piece has to also be
implemented makes makes the burden a
little higher but the brain is a little
bit higher I don't see a way around that
because the receiver a receiver and a
parser of the token has to be able to
accept anything any valid token that's
handed to it right there's no way for a
receiver to say I only implement half
the spec so if we put it in their
receivers have to have to be able to
accept it although a signer is obviously
allowed to implement any subset of
claims that it it feels is useful for
its use case but it's different to say
it's mandatory to understand versus
mandatory to enforce right you can say
you must be able to parse this but you
don't have necessarily have to be able
to do the redirect I guess correct and
there may be security reasons why one
CDN or another use case may choose to
refuse to do so right right it might
feel that for for excuse case leaking
that information is as a security
concern and so it's going to to refuse
to comply and certainly an
implementation needs to have the
flexibility to define their own policies
around exactly what they do once they
understand it
so I guess fill to your point whether or
not the CDN has to implement it it's
they have to not they have to recognize
that claim tag but they can toss the
data if they want does that make it more
palatable to you I mean they're still
parsing JSON and if they come across it
it's not a credit
yeah yeah I mean I guess so so so I
guess what it comes down to right now is
is its its it needs some time for people
on the mailing list to respond to it
yeah I don't have any other actions it's
not blocking on anything so waiting a
week or two for people to talk about it
and I you know if we decided to go with
it I merge it and make a 17 if not you
know you can you can still start a
Shepherd review or whatever on it if
that's the direction we think we want to
go with it so I I don't I don't think we
have to decide it right now but I think
that's kind of my feelings on it is I'm
kind of minus zero right I'm I'm gonna
propose as the chair that I'm gonna go
ahead and do the Shepherd review on
version 16 and there's gonna be some
period of time where I'm that we're
going to give me to do that and during
that time if we want to discuss this new
pull request we can if we decide we want
it and there's support for it then we
can add it in if not then we can move
forward with 16 we don't have to make
that decision right now and we don't
have to hold up the next steps for 16 on
it does that seem reasonable to everyone
I seems good to me okay all right that's
that's all I have unless anybody else
has any other comments on the draft or
the next steps all right
[Music]
so I think Frederick is up next so quick
status on the draft interfaces HTTP
delegation so quick update to remind you
a bit the purpose of this draft is to is
to propose extensions to the existing
cDNA interfaces to exchange delegation
metadata so based on the last comments
we had in Montreal we try to reflect all
of them so basically we the draft now
supports the delegation method objects
that the chaton automatically renewed
certificates that is that is supported
in the like me working group not so the
subset draft which is supported in the
TLS working group also we add a command
to remove the work large delegation
method from from this version so we did
and finally we we included the
delegation method in the past metadata
so I think now the draft is
ready for adoption so we know call for
reduction yeah I think it's been getting
a lot of feedback on the list
I don't know how Kevin feels about this
but I don't even think we need to do a
home here because we've gotten so much
feedback on the lists your thoughts on
that I think I agree I think we've seen
a lot we can do a hum if if people would
like
I think the draft looks good the updated
draft I sent you a couple of comments
Fredrik on the list but if you want to
take care of those before in the next
Rev when you switch do we want to go
ahead and just do a hum I could
definitely do one all right from the
audience that they would like to see
that so all right
please hum if you would like to adopt
this draft please home now all right
please hum now if you would not elect
like to adopt this draft all right that
was pretty clear there were there were
no hums against adoption and quite a few
for adoption so I think the the mailing
list will leave it to the end of the
week I just want to give it enough time
to give everybody a chance to get
feedback but I think it's good to go
okay since any comments
all right Orie I believe you're up next
which do you were nodding first okay so
this draft was adopted last last IDF
basically what we added here is the
ability to have redirect target
capability objects that allows the
downstream CDN to advertise to the
absent CDN where they want them to
redirect by DNS or HTTP one open issue
that was left is how to construct the
location for HTTP so what we have
proposed in the past was that the
construction of the location would be
based on a path prefix a host and a past
perfect and the ability to include or
exclude the redirecting host as the
first path segments and there was a
proposal from Kevin I think that we
might consider instead of having those
explicit fields having some kind of an
area of construction so this is kind of
a question for this forum if if you
think it's more appropriate to have
something which is more generic because
maybe an F instead of this object so
basically that's it Kevin maybe since
you proposed that maybe you can share
your view I think the I think the object
is fine I'm
yeah I could go either way on this one
it's it's something that I think could
be specified more more precisely I
suppose more generically and more
precisely but it's not really necessary
for this particular application so I
could go either way if no one feels
strongly about it okay so maybe I just
bump it again in the mailing list and if
there are no more objections or
proposals around that I would just make
this object to see this okay so that was
those are the only updates for that
particular document Ori right yeah right
so that was the only update actually I
haven't changed it since it was moved to
[Music]
document instead of one just about a B
and F I haven't read the document so I
probably shouldn't voice an opinion but
this is the type of comment I might
raise during very direct this review so
I hope it's not you know but this you
know if it's unclear I will I will tell
you basically I don't think it's going
to be big deal either way okay thanks so
maybe a general question before I move
on to the triggers is that we have
multiple new ideas for new metadata
objects and footprints or object the
same as in this document and the
question is how do we have introduced
more numerated a data objects in their
footprints as they come along
should we have different and separate
drafts for each and every one or what
what do you think should be the way to
go I I tend to think it depends on how
quickly you want to get these through we
can we can do them as individual drafts
if you have them all and you know what
they're going to be
and you want to get them all out
together it's it's a little bit less
work on our side to have to push a one
draft as opposed to five drafts through
right I think yeah I this a Sanjay
Mishra I agree with Kevin I think it may
be just easier to work on these
individually just so that you're focused
on what the topic is and what we're
working on so we're not holding up on
lot of different different things and
then you know if we have if you feel
like we have multiple drafts you know
it's easy to combine it that at some
point later on okay thanks right if they
if they all get to a last call at about
the same time you can just merge them at
that point right but you can put them
out as they come I suppose though each
have to be adopted separately or a
choice by the working group to go ahead
and merge it into the the existing
document this is the trigger extension
draft so just a refresher we added
versioning for the triggers because we
are changing the interface and we want
to have interface versions we added the
ability to select the content that the
children's to using regular expression
or video playlist and we added the
ability to add the generic extension
objects that pretty much like the
metadata generic objects it's kind of a
list of generic objects that one can
implement or introduce new new types of
objects that would control or restrict
the trigger depending on your what you
want to do and we introduced the first
two generic object it's a location
policy and time policy and also we
introduced
FCI advertisement for the extension
objects that you can advertise that you
support specific types of our object and
also for the for the visions so
follow-ups from my previous IDF we were
requested to replace the ABR protocol
type with a media protocol type so we do
that and there's an issue to consider
and I bring it here if we weaken if we
want to keep on handling also MSS within
this draft because as far as I know when
it says is it's not being used also
entirely in the industry so maybe we
should just keep it with HLS and - I
don't have any strong feeling about that
but maybe others do there was an issue
of implication of reg X complexity
attacks and I've added it to the
security consideration section one more
issue was adding the ability to use
local time within the time policy it's
kind of tricky and I'm going to discuss
this in a minute in a moment and the
ability to propagate errors and other
issues from all these things along the
trigger delegation path so you could do
back tracing of those and understand
where the problem was in which the
options in there so adding the work on
time through the time policies so this
is kind of tricky because the rationale
here is that when you execute the
trigger things like repositioning or
other heavy stuff you might want them to
happen in specific time slots but since
CD ends I'll distribute it across many
regions in many cases you may want to do
that in specific time sorts but in local
times of those regions not in your car
not in your local time or any specific
time just like saying I want to do that
between 2 a.m. and 5 a.m. in your
specific regional time
so currently without ads that could be
achieved by having a combination of time
policy together with location policy it
has the drawback that it requires
multiple triggers you have to have
different triggers for every every
region and there was a proposal to add
the ability to have a local time flag
that indicates exactly what you want
execute at these hours at your local
time so that was the rationale the
question is how to push all to represent
a local time so we cannot use the
existing time window object because it's
UTC and using unique set box and that
doesn't work for local time possibly we
can add a new time slot object something
which will be different than the time
window and the question is how exactly
to represent that time and I I don't
have a good answer for that because if
we follow our 3:9 internet time since
there's no notation for your local time
this notation for UTC and there's
limitation for a specific there's
nothing like that um 5:00 a.m. at your
local time so it's kind of an open
question because I don't have a good
answer for that yet anyone has if anyone
has any observation about how to do that
that would great otherwise I would just
introduce something new
is there another group another working
group that we can ask who owns time
objects okay I will try to figure out
that somebody written this RFC so I'll
try to connect with those people and try
to see if there's there if there's any
kind of observation of how to do that I
feel like if we put it in our own like
you create a string and a string format
and then we say this particular string
format is hours : minutes : seconds and
it applies to your time zone it's easy
enough to specify but we'll probably
getting somewhere for it yeah I'll try
to follow up with whether written times
back and say I don't know of any
anything to help you in this space so I
think inventing your own is fine as long
as it's reasonable I don't know it's can
be a separate boolean attribute or you
just do variation on our teeth 3 3 3 9
just for your force no times on case but
local local times our case because you
have very specific application rejection
requires this most applications don't
want to do that yeah so they they will
use a existing format so I'm trying to
think if we can generalize that if there
are other type of applications that may
need to have something like that yeah I
do something I I don't have a good
suggestion for you I don't think you are
in trouble because you already
researched and I'm not aware of anything
that ok this is an RFC for examples I
think if if we can borrow as much as we
can from 33:39 as far as the formatting
there there a B and F that sort of thing
and then just modify it to whatever
degree we need to ignore timezone and
tell tell them to use local time we can
make it as close as we can and then
maybe somebody will want it I'm now
starting to design and fly but you can
replace the Zed we do know with another
exactly it's just yeah and it's going to
be close enough that a lot of parses can
either be extended or you know yeah oh
they will
you know fail in a predictable way
hopefully so error propagation so we've
added a new error description version
two errors may happen in any day now
since at the end and on the trigger
litigation path so this was kind of an
issue even before introducing the
extensions but now since we have an
extensions and extensions may or may not
be supported by different and options in
the ends it becomes more of an issue so
we've introduced the new error
description version two and the arrows
vector is now error vector V 2 arrows B
2 and it adds the a property CDN to
indicate the failing DCD and the
definition of CDN is the same as it is
in the arm in the original RFC it's kind
of an ID that is indicated by a the a s
and when delegating triggers they
delegate obesity and must propagate
errors that they have received from
bouncing Citians down the delegation
pass and add these arrows to the error
v2 array and then you are I've added a
new error code extension to indicate
there was an error due to a jeweler
extension
status version two so a recap we already
have the status version two from the
previous draft provision because we have
a trigger v2 and they start to speak to
include the trigger e2 instead with
children and now the trick is this a
status version 2 must also include the
earliest version 2 of the error
description so that's it we bring it to
offer adoption and I understand it
requires a recovering I think Kevin is
gonna talk about that a little bit he
did some research on this and I guess
that's that's actually the next item on
the agenda so maybe we should do QA and
then if if nobody has any questions we
can move on to the next item in the
agenda and address that ok so I to
comment on on the draft or on the slides
your original the first question was
about whether or not we should continue
to have MSS is there any harm in keeping
it or do you think it's not worth it at
all I think it's still up you know it's
still up to the DCP and that's whether
or not they support it so it having it
in makes it somewhat more flexible I
think ok
unless there's gonna be a registry for
it but then we still have to go through
and have another registry entry at some
point there's anything we need to edit
anyway so yeah so yeah might as well do
it and then what was the other I don't
remember what my other one was so we can
skip it I'll remember at some point I
still need to do a review of that of the
updated draft and so I'll probably come
out there
ISO 8601 has a local time format oh so
I'll follow up on that
[Music]
Thanks so the next item on the agenda
here is it's amazing sorry was that we
are on time this is a first it's the
next slide in there there you go
okay so so last time we talked about the
need for recharging if we wanted to do
the the triggers extension for those who
were there back in IETF 84 we had made a
decision not to pursue any type of hass
optimisation used to be adaptive
streaming optimizations at that time in
an attempt to try and get all of the
base specs out quicker
there was an RFC 69 83 that listed out
all of the pass optimizations that were
considered at the time interestingly
enough pre positioning of past content
was not one of them one of them was
retrieving sim files but not
specifically pre positioning manifests
through triggers and so it's not really
covered there in terms of what would be
necessary or how it impacts the
interfaces our existing Charter does say
that in the event that any protocol
extensions or new protocols are
necessary we will recharter and so we've
been looking at the Charter and we
discussed it with Alexi the Charter
itself doesn't preclude us from doing
house optimizations to the triggers
interface we have existing text in the
Charter for
doing a control interface and and adding
some fields to make it more HTTP
adaptive streaming seems to fit within
that it's not in any of the things we're
not allowed to do in this working group
list so at this point in time we are
looking at it as we can reach our there
but it will be the same charter so we
don't actually have to recharter and we
can add an enhancement and enhance
control interface a milestone to our
existing milestone list
does anybody have any comments or issues
with this particular approach well I was
he have no objections I read the way
protocol extensions what region may
maybe it's ambiguous but I've I thought
it was about HTTP extensions and because
young you know I suppose the text is
slightly ambiguous but you know it
allows you just to add this and continue
working I think that's fine but if you
want to take other items which doesn't
clearly fit you know you might as well
reach other ones right it's supposed to
reach out to multiple times right I
think one that one question is would we
want to tackle any additional HTTP
adaptive streaming issues one of the big
ones was manifest rewrite which we're
not doing and I don't think that's in
our Charter today and I don't know if
this is leading us down that road but
just simply sending a URI with an
extension of m3u8 and hope and expecting
the downstream CDN to understand it and
support it I don't think is terribly
far-fetched for what the triggers
interface was intended
just a quick question here on the text
that you have now when we say submit
enhanced CDN a control interface should
the word enhanced be qualified as to
what what specifically the the Charter
would include so that the reader
understands you know what the the new
Charter is actually going to be
inclusive off because enhanced by itself
is not giving quite a to a reader as to
what what it is that we're looking to do
I had intended with hath support to
qualify the enhancement okay so yeah I
mean that makes sense for the has but
some of the other additional items as in
the Ori slash presentation that may not
be necessarily covered with that but
this language the right
no no so there will be other there will
be separate as charter of miles separate
milestones added for the other documents
and once we adopt HTTP delegation once
we adopt her and for the request routing
those are just additional metadata those
have always been considered something we
would do right the meditator interface
is there and it is extensible and we
agreed to be the you know standardizing
body for new metadata so within the
context of what they currently contain
adding new metadata i think is fine and
we can add a charter milestones for
adding those documents but in terms of
this is a change to one of the core
interfaces i think has to be specified
slightly more precisely yeah I agree
Thanks
any other comments
so it sounds like we're gonna do some
more milestones here and not have to
recharter them do we need to come on
that or is the home for triggers I don't
think we really need to hum here if the
Charter itself is not changing and it's
as long as Alexie's good yeah okay do we
wanna yeah I'm perfectly fine with it
you do we want to now move on to humming
about triggers document uh give me the
adoption they're out sorry
yeah the adoption of it yes since we no
longer have to recharge to do that and
we discussed doing that in Montreal but
stopped short because of the recharging
yes okay just so everybody knows what
we're talking about here hello it was it
was much louder before and I noticed it
got quiet so I don't know if they
adjusted it but is that this is better
all right
this one was working at the beginning so
sorry I apologize for that
alright so um believe this is the this
is routing right so the document that I
want to do a home for adoption on is the
CD ni triggers SVA extensions so right
now I'd like you to hum if you would if
you are for adoption of this document
okay and now if you are against adoption
of this document please hum now okay I
heard several homes for and no hums
against I will follow up on the lists
with an email about this and then if
everything is good there we can add it
any other comments or questions about
that
all right I believe that was that is the
end of the meeting do you have anything
else Kevin everybody go out and read the
documents review the documents and out
compliments on the documents other than
that we will continue to try and move
forward with these documents thanks
everybody for coming hope you're having
a great time in Bangkok village anything
else I miss going is there where's the
other blue sheet and has everybody had a
chance to sign in yeah anybody know
where the other one is okay is anybody
else need to sign it before we go yeah
the decision about to reach out to
enclose them yeah so so the the outcome
was that we do not need to reach Artur
because the wording that there was
concern around was basically loose
enough to allow what we were going to do
with simply milestones is there did you
have further concern about that I mean
is a room for proposing all the points
that you can add in the shorter to wish
shuttering
I heard that that needs to either the
provisioning you see of certificates in
the CDN and
this will probably impacts though
interfaces so do you have a concrete
problem that that we can solve I mean
the provisioning of searches is handled
right to go further I need to better
understand how you are going to proceed
with the shutter so yeah I understand
that you are not visually shattering or
correct okay good okay but then the last
point about the control interface either
the working woman going to modify if the
control interface for adaptive streaming
or not so the proposed document that or
he has proposes updates to the existing
trigger interface and the current read
of the Charter is that that fits into
our existing Charter so we don't need to
recharge to get that in and if want to
adopt it then we will do it and so on
the short term is a do we plan to reach
out or not not at this time we will add
the three new milestones okay good so I
really change about you made a with a
chair about there's a different point I
was speaking about okay and certainly if
you have ideas of new things that we
shouldn't okay thanks for finally girl
escape here but yeah just just to
summarize we're not shutting down the
chartering discussion indefinitely it's
just that we for the documents that we
currently have that we're talking about
adoption for we don't need to so in the
future if something comes up and we we
want to reach Artur for it we can reopen
that discussion and talk about it then
but as of right now there's no concrete
documents out there that we think we
need to reach our tour for so all right
amigo feel free to write a draft though
if you want
I send in one maid or to each other all
right I think we're good then
need anything else all right enjoy the
rest your days everybody thank you take
care nobody