[Music]
yeah good morning we gonna get started
quickly shortly
could somebody maybe close the doors
okay
good morning thanks for coming to icy
energy we are therefore ran by a woman
and I'm the co-chair this is icy energy
in Bangkok as usual let's consider the
ietf IPR policy so just very briefly
it's quite similar to the ITF IPI policy
if you see anything or present anything
that is related to IPR you expect it to
let the group know in a short timeframe
yeah we have a mailing list we have a
wiki the wiki is the place where we
typically store all the say current
meeting information this meeting so we
are super grateful that we already have
a note-taker thanks again now in truth
we not sure you want to use the ether
pet but if you do there you find the
link on the slides or on the ITF agenda
and also if any would like to contribute
to the minutes you free to write and eat
the pet directly if you want to add
something
[Music]
yeah all this all the material is online
already so somebody follows this
remotely you get all the material there
[Music]
this is our agenda for today so we have
two hours so we start with two use case
presentations so Simon is gonna talk
about ICN architectures in smart
buildings and then we have Kanchana who
will present a quality air quality
monitoring news case this is followed by
a block on ICN management tools CC an
info and so compared to their ping and
traceroute we have a brief update on net
me Ravi is going to do an update on the
ICN I wrote a draft and Thomas will
present an update from the ICN lope and
work any need to fish this vendor any
comments great those of you who haven't
been following every meeting recently so
we had since Montreal so last idea we
had two interns one after the AC and
conference in Boston in September and
one just last Sunday in Bangkok so I'm
not going to give you the total detailed
summary of all the presentations they
are so the everything is online I'm
going to talk about in the next slides a
little bit about you know work items
that popped up and so relevant things
that that happened there okay so if you
would have to describe what I see energy
is actually doing in terms of technology
so we thought a picture like this could
be helpful
so I mean I see energy is a same IT
project group that tries to do
continuous work on say ICN technology
development and experimentation and so
you could say we have something you know
like a core specification some things
like C T and X semantics and messages we
have you know work that looks a bit into
getting this implemented on specific
link layers for example so like Thomas s
lopen work for example h ICN could
perhaps be seen in this category and
then we have saw in the in this
so after core spec layer if you want a
couple of extensions so mobility support
things like let me for example or other
work outside of ice energy like height
we have work on named evolutions of it
like infrastructure services there are
some proposed extensions so rice what
method implication would be one and yeah
also say helping or say yeah extensions
like flow classification and quality of
service mechanisms and so on and so some
of those actually you know kind of
extend or modify things like the cost
cost specification or the the note
behavior for example rice and has a
curtain extended behavior met knee as
well so it's not actually not clear
layering but you get the idea on the far
right and we have things like management
tools info pink for example and then we
are we looking at applications and how
they interact with the system how they
could use make use of these different
facilities
so that's how we currently so in a very
high-level kind of would like to this
kind of describe the technical work here
of course there's also other work going
on things like deployment considerations
terminology and so on that not on this
slide let us really more the technical
work yeah I hope this explains a little
bit let us know if you have comments or
whether we missing something which it's
quite possible quick update on our work
items so you know we had these two
specifications so see any messages and
semantics so basically they passed all
the ports here in the group and also in
the ISSG and fathered me we are
currently waiting for the IETF chair to
move this to the next level that would
be reviewing the ihe and I'm finally
ship this to the IRC editor so we're
trying to progress this it's a it's a
bit slow right now that progress there
we had the the flip so this manifest
specification so how you could describe
I see an object that form a larger file
for example so this draft unfortunally
is currently expired so we're talking to
the teal office but I mean everybody's
quite time conference with Chris has
another focus now on the other hand we
think this is really really important
work and really useful and really like
to get this out at some point so if
anybody you know wants to you know have
a long lasting contribution impact on
ICN and is interested in flicking
maybe just talk to Chris and Christine
on whether maybe they're there they take
we need some help
and so by the way so when I showed this
other picture
I mean before so when I mentioned
specifications like CTN eggs for example
so that doesn't mean like for example in
an ITF working group context this is the
one solution that the group endorses so
what we are really doing here is
research and experimentation so we can
easily have thought several incompatible
competing proposals and still publish
each of those incremental our sees for
example so it doesn't mean that it's he
connects is the ICN actually
specification it's it's one and half the
things that people brought to the group
certainly I see energy is open to other
work as well okay we recently finished
in this group we thought the ICN in
disaster scenarios draft there were some
comments in the IR 3 review and so we
really would like the authors to
consider these comments and come up with
an update so that also hopefully should
happen in the next week's we have the
deployment conservation draft that is
basically half finished last call here
in the group we also can be waiting for
the ITF chair
to initiate the review at the iOS G we
recently adopted CC and info so Tasha
son is gonna talk about this in a bit so
I don't need to say much we also adopted
the IC an application to to lopen that
works with what Thomas is gonna talk
about later so let's get to this later
we also adopted two drafts on home
resolution
so one is called the name Rutan's
requirements were frenemies Ellucian
there's coming more the motivation and
requirements it was once
name and the other one is called
architectural Conservation's
of ICM using n is so bit more than say
broader picture and architectural impact
right please fill out the blue sheets
interestingly at the last so not this
Sunday but the Boston interim we had
invited people from obviously first to
give us a first say overview about the
global name service GN s that they
developed in mobility first and so we
think that could actually be a fruitful
discussion so there there's a solid body
of work in that in that project and so
the people we talk to I actually
interested to to see how that could
perhaps help ICM nor at least have our
discussion again we have the terminology
draft so but I'm kindly updated this
recently was like yeah actually updates
mostly we just discussed in a little bit
so Batson is kind of come back to you on
the mailing list to you know ask for
additional comments we think it's it's
relatively complete and it could be one
of the candidates that be for the next
draft we want to finish up here and
publish eventually we had the negative
lead moment of IC in ite
and that works draft so there was also
planted on Sunday and there is an email
on the - that is discussing next steps
so I just want you to that right now
and yeah rather later is going to talk
about the IC and I go t draft so how I
would he can leverage ICN features that
me so the mobility they could
support was updated what happened is
that Cisco declared their their IP arts
or recently on that it's the usual Cisco
policy so tapers to the update for the
author's who couldn't make it this week
ping trace route as well we'll talk
about this later so this is the say
about that simple or basic past
discovery and testing facility we have a
couple of things related to Q s so one
is the flow classification draft so how
to encode equivalence classes in ICN and
what consumers producers and folders
should do with it could be a basis for
us we had Gregg's and colleagues courses
draft on IP tunneling CCM so we're
actually interesting proposal to do ICN
provided multi-plane to IP without using
the existing or legacy that is something
where we could also sort the thing about
next steps so I think last time that was
presented people felt it was useful work
yeah
any suggestion from your side okay so
then let's do like this yep
so we let's initiate like a review on
the main list so please if you
interested in doing IP o wise CCM never
look we have the ICN over 5g next-gen
coop attack sure draft hasn't been
updated and we have the
dynamic inter inter domain which is
support framework for ICN they was also
presented I think one or two meetings
before and hasn't been updated there is
new work so I mentioned the flow
classification early amped so there's an
additional draft on POS
so that is petrov currently is
describing how to basically use it this
surf like model however there's a thread
on the mailing list discussing that the
other options and we had a really
interesting discussion on Sunday and
maybe please check the the presentation
and the minutes yeah there is a new
draft on remote method invocation that
we blended on Sunday that's intended as
a general basis for NS end like
interactions in ICM and we also have new
to have a we are so basically one
application of and then and a couple of
other drafts that I don't only do tell
about right now so they're also in the
data tracker hasn't been recently
updated please let us know if you want
to say anything about this or know
anything about it otherwise let some fun
and start with the first presentation
and then it's gonna be Simon thanks good
morning
so I will be presenting the use case of
applying ICN architecture in smart
buildings and the interesting
observation here is that we've been
doing that for a couple of years within
go to sick with the system known as
Bluetooth mash that involves both the
low-power short-range radio transport
technology including like multi hope
network and the application layer for
building automation as well and what was
surprising to me kind of maybe a year
ago is that many concepts that we
developed there we're kind of counter
wouldn't say maybe counterintuitive but
they were definitely against the
conventional wisdom because everybody
else was doing like a node-based address
routing and point-to-point unicast
communication and we came with the
concept of hey let's use let's optimize
the network for massive multicast and
let's use pub/sub paradigm and then we
realized that the friends at IC energy
are like using the same concept for the
big internet so that was very
encouraging and and refreshing so so
that's what initially brought me here to
this group and Bluetooth mash is today
it's not a an IP based system so we are
moving into that direction so my
interest here is as well to like figure
out how to merge the IP based approach
and whether and how the ICN concept
should be brought into that in that
system so did the highlights here are
that from the practical perspective we
were looking for simplified
configuration and named addressable data
really helps there we were looking at
scalability and no points of failure in
a network and we realized that we need
to use like at the transport level the
network must support multicast as a
primary method of propagating messages
and pub/sub is really the right way to
go and dealing with
bigger systems and bi bigger systems I
mean like building like this one it's
probably in the range of twenty thirty
thousand lights for example and it will
like buildings like this one will soon
have equal amount of sensors they don't
have there yet but but but definitely
like the trend is that each light points
in a building is equipped with sensors
and is a sensor itself because it can
provide maintenance data and such so
speaking about the lighting applications
so the the concept here you are on the
left side you have the traditional
approach Illustrated on the right side
is the the ICN approach so in a lighting
system so the square boxes are light
fixtures like office trophies and they
have little antennas representing that
they communicate over a wireless network
and doing ABC are representing sensors
they can have multiple sensing elements
in in a package and the blue box is the
controller so the traditional approach
has been that sensors ABC are reporting
some data and that data is collected by
the controller the controller runs the
control algorithms and then issues
control messages that control the light
fixtures so the lights first of all like
the basic scenario is occupancy so you
enter a room the lights come up you
leave the room and after a while they go
into didn't go off and that's how
everybody has been doing that today so
the first observation that we had was
that there is some necessary traffic
coming from the controller to the light
fixtures because if you realize that the
controller is a piece of software then
today you can distribute that across the
network so you don't need to have a
single controller that controls the
whole thing you can have a copy of a
controller embedded into each each node
so that alone saves a huge amount of
traffic on the network and also makes
the network much more redundant because
you suddenly have a completely
distributed system and the second
observation was how to easily match the
sources of information with the
consumers of information and of course
what is represented here by the hashtag
like Twitter like paradigm of pub/sub is
really applicable here because that
really decouples the controllers or
controller equipped light fixtures they
subscribe to given information like the
lights in this room are interested in
occupancy in this room so that's the
information that they are interested in
so they want to subscribe to that and
and if that the information is
addressable then of course the whole
system is naturally easy to configure
and the sensors they publish and they
publish again it's really not important
how many sensors you have in the room
it's important that they all contribute
to the whole block of information
referred to as occupancy in in room we
are meeting to write so meaning to
occupancy is our addressable info block
and many sensors in the room contribute
to that publish to that address
technically and the light fixtures
subscribe to it and of course you can
have more advanced configuration as
illustrated here so luminaire may also
be interested in subscribing to ambient
light level information so that's
referred to as daylight harvesting so
the luminaire is closer to Windows they
are dimmer and luminaires they're
further out are brighter to level the
light level in the room so in that case
you need at least two pieces of
addressable information what one is the
ambient light level and the other is you
can see of course in my
multiple zones so that depends on how
many how many light sensing elements you
have so you might have a zone that's
closer to the projection screen and the
sensors that are further out and then
you may want to set the thing that that
close the projection screen it is dimmer
because that makes the projection better
visible and also as illustrated on the
right side the luminaires themselves can
produce information because they produce
information about their status their
health their operating parameters and
that's very important and that
information goes to another address that
is like a system health address and that
may be subscribed to by variety of
system monitoring devices like little
boxes that display ok this is running ok
or the the network operating center that
that can display the overall health of
the entire system and of course you can
mix and match so it's really a
peer-to-peer system you don't have a
clear distinction between who really is
a consumer because the consumer is also
a producers so it's a it's a flat
peer-to-peer architecture that anyone
can contribute the information and
anybody can can subscribe to that
information and what's interesting here
is that this decoupling by addressing
the information gives us the opportunity
to really simplify the configuration
because like yeah I'll get there I have
one more slide one configuration example
that is also illustrated here and it's
color-coded so the luminaries in the
upper row they are denoted by the orange
antennas and they subscribe to the
orange light sensor and once at the
bottom the green ones they subscribe to
the green light sensor and in roman era
has a
occupancy sensor and they are all in the
same room so you can imagine that all
the lights although all the occupancy
sensors they publish to the same address
the orange light sensor publishers to
Zone one address the green light sensor
publishes to Zone two and then they
subscribe accordingly and again this is
a completely flat system with no
privileged host or a controller and it's
completely distributed so these are the
principles and Bluetooth mesh as I
mentioned it's been out there for some
time already and it's commercially
available since July last year there are
today about close to 100 different
qualified products and they are
interoperable with each other so the
installers can mix and match sensors and
drivers and and switches dimmers from
different manufacturers and it all works
based on on that part on that on that
paradigm so it kind of proves itself
because already there are case studies
that that showcase buildings that are
equipped with with exactly the cities
this system and the benefits from the
configuration simplicity and and
reliability are really huge so the three
highlights that I would like to
illustrate here is is how for example
simplicity of configuration and
maintenance is is achieved once you have
this indirect binding between producers
and consumers by the layer of
addressable information of operations
such as exchanging a broken luminary are
very easy because you just exchanged the
device and then you only need to
subscribe it to the information on the
sender side nothing he needs to be
changed so it's it's very from a
maintenance perspective very very simple
scalability comes naturally and and it's
even more natural taking into account
the fact that this is a wireless network
so so you don't have isolated between
parts that the information is going it's
always broadcast media
so notes are overhearing each other so
it's inherently multicast by nature
that's how radio systems are built and
and and by distributing the controller
application to the notes then we are
like having the the amount of traffic
immediately and then of course because
sensing is not only for one application
occupancy sensor can contribute to
lights it can contribute to Hedgehog
system it can contribute to space
utilization application it can
contribute to whoever who who knows what
and that's the beauty of that that the
sensor just published its height there's
occupancy in the room or there's no
equipment in the room and whoever wants
may subscribe to it and the sensor
doesn't need to be reconfigured so that
ends up in a very robust flexible and
simple to configure system so that
reliability aspect is also very
important because we really have
achieved here the no single point of
failure setup because it's hot it's all
distributed so it marries the concept of
ICN with the concept of distributing
which is the the trend that is that is
really taking up today and it really
makes sense to push the computing to the
very edge so each node has as its own
controller logic and it's capable of
subscribing to whatever information it
needs and then it makes its own
decisions and if it fails only one node
fails and the rest of the system keeps
operating so it's more like a swarm type
of an organism so it's a collectively
intelligent system where each cell is
just a contributor to the behavior of
the overall systems we are like getting
all the all the benefits of that
approach so that's it I'm sure if we
have time for questions or not and
please Thomas might have a handbook
question do you have implementations for
this yes I one now do you do
I see n over Bluetooth I mean that is
thing like the UCLA and people and we
are working on do you do this directly
on the alto coupling or how do you do
this we so Brutus mash is a new
architecture or topology available from
Bluetooth since 2007 t as a new cell to
cup it doesn't use l2 cut isn't this
based on Billy it's based on purely
radio but it only uses the radio layer
and then everything on top is a new
stack and where do you where do you sit
as I as I mentioned there is no IP in
that system so we cannot say it's icns
like we understand in this group it's a
concept that's very similar because it's
pops up it's multicast it's just
different addressing and different
payloads but but there has never been an
IP protocol but I mean ICN brings a
networking layer here and that is also
not foreseen by Bluetooth so you should
there should be some some interface on
on the Bluetooth where you put your ICN
on top spirit yes exact oh yeah we do
not run the night the protocols I
thought I made it clear but thanks for
the use of the concept in ICN style yes
and now what we are looking for is to
how to bring the two really together
because we find that architecture very
applicable to the area that we are
proposing Bluetooth match for like smart
buildings and now we're looking to how
to inject the ICN through ICN layer in
between the application and the
transport network differend one comment
one question to the question first so it
how do you think about how to design the
namespace for these things because
that's sort of protocol independent but
how the how the names get assigned and
what semantics get put onto the
structure of the names
seems to be something the whole
everybody could learn about you're
independent of whether you know you
choose one ICN protocol architecture or
another or actually bypass it directly
to the application so I'm curiously we
also can provide our names there's the
addressing space for the network is
short that resists 16-bit addresses and
there is also a concept for the of 128
bits addresses that can be used for the
pub sub relationships and currently whom
they are just randomly generated the
addresses themselves the long addresses
and we really at the network layer we
don't have a name space is managed by an
external config utility but this is
definitely something we are looking into
like how to solved it right so on the
other next one is a comment and may have
more to do with the actual product
design here then with the architecture I
was involved in the design of a system a
few years ago that was deployed at the
MIT Media Lab which had this nice
property that you could tell the
difference with whether the bulb was
burned out or the device was offline and
there were sensors on each of the the
fixtures they were actually monitoring
the other fixtures so the light sensors
weren't actually separate there were
light sensors on each fixture that could
figure out where other neighbors were
and whether they were working have you
thought about anything like that so this
- first this product here in the lower
left corner it's a sensor that you can
buy today it's in in distribution and
it's actually a combined sensor and
fixture controller
so the output of that device is the
light level so you can hook it directly
to the power supply of the light and it
monitors of it has an ambient light
sensing element has the occupancy
sensing element it has temperature
sensing element and yeah it exactly is
capable of doing so we have to cut the
line up after second whistling but you
mentioned it's like twenty thirty
thousand bulbs and you have a lot of
publish and subscribers but I don't see
I know you didn't talk about how these
multi casting routing itself is managed
it's broadcast
I can understand broadcast happening in
this single room so does it mean that
you scale you basically manage the
system by just localizing the network
and this network doesn't deal with
anything to do with the other network in
another room yes so it supports the
concept of subnets and subnets very
nicely confined the traffic because
traffic does not propagate across
subnets you can configure a subnet
bridges so it hops from one subnet to
another and the the flooding is
controlled with TTL and message caches
on on each device so it's it's confined
and so for example ambient light sensor
in this room it's unlikely than somebody
in the other tower in this interest in
informations there may be a gateway but
the scaling factor for gateways
currently we see as around 200 300
messages per second so if like ambient
light sensors are very talkative so to
speak they fire every couple of times
per second so if you have a number of
them in the room then then your air
space feels up quite quickly so that's
definitely coming into a hybrid physical
structure that you have gateways that
offloads to a faster backbone and and
the last two hops maybe are wireless so
you only have routing between the
bridges but yes subnet is broadcast yes
Westford occur I sigh and I actually
specifically wanted to talk about the
naming problem because I I've been
thinking a lot about that the way we
need to address names in the
communication world is often very
different than how we address names
contextually as humans and it's a really
hard problem and and things like you
know when we have 50,000 lights in a
building that gets much harder because
humans like to think about things have
please turn the lights off that works in
my house I can tell my local listening
device turn the lights off and it does
and if I tell my phone here turn the
lights off it might turn the lights off
in my house that's not what I meant if I
want to send something to John's phone
John is very contextual II dependent is
probably the person closest to me but if
he's on a different carrier or a
different network we don't have the
ability to do that today and that
particular really hard problem you know
really needs to be addressed for
situations like this and so there's a
lot of work to be done in that area
that's true okay thank you very much so
Simon quick question is there anything
that you would like to get from icy
energy for that I would have your work
well yeah I think because now we are
working on the design of this IP layer
because as I said we have the networking
layer and the application layer bound
together we want to inject IP in between
so the application like the lighting
control can run over IP as well as IP
can run on top of the mesh under
Bluetooth now of course there's pretty
straightforward to do using the classic
IP six approach now what we are looking
into are how do we take advantage of the
ICN concept because we consider it very
relevant and that's still a design work
so we are kind of more listening so what
this group is doing and and and that's
yeah looking for input at this moment
when we are ready with the IP design I
think that I will be able to share that
with with the group and then maybe
collectively we can come up with the
unified architecture because that's
definitely what we are after
okay very good thank you thanks a lot
okay moving on so we are extremely glad
that we have
Kanchana here today so Kanchana actually
previously pioneered the introduction of
the Internet to Thailand and she's now
considering to do the same for it--
thank you very much and this was totally
unplanned we met in the lobby and I was
asked what am i what am i working on so
this is you know a I'm working on air
quality monitoring in Thailand the
problem of air for it is very serious
particularly in in term not of Thailand
because a lot of crop burning and as you
can see that the previous Oh has put
very serious warning to ask that three
point three million deaths linked to
outdoor air pollution and you know the
the reason why am i get problem with my
my vertical respiratory system is
because of this so this is the the
picture of the northern Thailand during
the breeding season which is around
March April you can see that with the
debris the near the safety PM level was
only twenty five my
but what we observe in Thailand was over
100 in the north so it really serious
and problems mainly caused by hot spot
you know people burning their crops so
what happened today is that our
Pollution Control Department have their
own very big sensors placed around the
country but it is not sufficient because
you only is cost around three hundred
thousand US dollar store the whole
country had you know less than twenty in
a station that measure this kind of
information at the moment there are a
lot of people who are who get interested
in this area and a lot of them are using
I don't know what the unit sensor and
then upload data but the government said
is it this data is not reliable
now another observation that the
opposite you know the government does is
to use the satellite images to detect
their burning in this areas and they
also issue but banned period where any
burning is illegal during the two months
period so we propose to use sensors to
do ground level monitoring the PM 2.5
which is the other thing that costs your
lung to you know keep creating a lot of
health problem so
[Music]
with this one we try to try to make sure
that we can provide timely warning to
the local communities that get affected
by PM 2.5 so that people can stay indoor
not not going out today to to inhale the
PM 2.5 so in my mind I I was thinking
about in the end since I met Li Jie in
2011 when she I listened to her talk at
a conference and I think ah this is
something I've been waiting for I wanted
to use the network more than just
sending information I wanted to be able
to compute and using the network just
like you know very big distributed
computers so that that I mean the idea
of using Indian started since 2011 but I
didn't know what kind of application I
can try this and the end on so with this
particular problem I found that it fits
very well with Indian because we are
dealing with a very remote area where
then the network is very often
disconnected so you cannot rely on a
centralized system to do any data
analytic first you know feedback crew to
provide the feedback to the community
you will really have to have your own
decent decentralized system and you can
you should since you have this
centralized system in a village
nobody is willing to pay for you know
some for electricity to run centralized
system even innovation himself so if we
can distribute computation to every node
then the Lord is you know distributed to
everyone and I think the Indian concept
fits very well with that so another
thing is that we have you know multiple
data sources where each node produce
stream of readings and all the time so
if we can leave that in order to do that
job we can also always take the stream
and do some computation locally so this
is what in order to do this kind of
project you need to convince people in
the you know the domain expert in
environmental engineering or
environmental people to listen to you
otherwise that they don't they don't
think what you are doing is serious and
you need to get the help in order to set
up more stations so I spend time to work
with them and we we started by putting
our sensors in villages in the north of
time and on the Tiber mist border where
what happened did this year that was the
worst affected area so we set up these
sensors in so I can remember how many
villages but about 10 centers altogether
this is the PM sensor that we used plant
plant tower
p.m.
PMS seven zero zero three I think it's
the one that's commonly used by the you
know p.m. sensors okay so this is our
anode we worked with our colleagues in
University of Saban and I think Macau
and met several others universities so
this is our node you may notice that we
used hulu neo with one key because we
plan to run computation in each node and
we used we have SD card to store
readings even when the network when you
don't have the network you can keep the
data and then upload it when you get
connection our node has a Wi-Fi
connection but we are putting Lauro and
on this node at the moment there are
sensors that we have is 4 p.m. 1 2.5 and
PM 10 you just tell me when we upload
the data to the cloud and we have our
website that you can have a look at
least you know the data run all the time
7 24 hours this visitor URL now after we
collected data from the decision we try
to involve the people data and data
science people and environmental
researchers to analyze our data so the
but they found that we should separate
our data into
and for songs and then they analyzed how
they died and to be you know they used
our data to study the movement of the PM
2.5 with respect to burning sources and
with respect to the wind and finally
they work on prediction model where you
can use the data to predict what's going
to happen in any particular area which
is which could not be done indeed with
the existing you know an existing
warning system because the currently
when you want the people you give the
warning for the whole province not a
particular village and normally it's
very inaccurate so now this is what we
found you could predict the PM 2.5 quite
accurately from our data and we found
that the burning I'm sorry p.m. level
relates to the burning period relate to
the number of hotspot so you we are now
convinced and we are going to move
forward so we moved to step 2 now that
where I want to insert my idea of in the
end to system so and what we want to do
as you know as I said I when I listen to
this yeah I thought oh we can do
computation on the network so and then I
found you are talking about in network
computation so we match the air quality
you know
is meaningful for people in the affected
affected area so we need you know to do
computation even though the network get
disconnected and you can warn the people
in the affected area immediately
so what we need is the programmable
Network the what we need you know the
kind of question that we need to query
the network is something like to search
for a possible source of fire ok so if
you have this kind of interest you
instead of asking for a particular
stream of data you should be able to
stand your query to the network and the
network can find you know you can write
a program that say this kind of question
can be handled by searching for sites
with higher and higher p.m. at that
particular time and then you can find
traced back to the source of the fire of
course you can take you know learn you
can also use the wind direction to guide
your search so this kind of computation
should be done locally and the next
question that we can do on this kind of
network is that the each community
affected of community would be
interested to know what were you know
the PM level for tomorrow the very near
future not you know weeks ahead so they
they would send interest to find in
order to do that that note has to do
some you know some modeling and
prediction and in order to do that you
need to get
of data from the neighboring nodes and
you have to get the reading from the
wind sensor and then feed that to the
prediction model and then you can
provide a prediction so this is the kind
of thing we think that fits into the ICN
framework so what we are doing now is
that that we continue with the project
we try to expand sites we are trying to
scale and put our nodes in other
countries because there are many
colleagues are interested in using our
node we are trying to expand to allow
Philippines Indonesia and Malaysia as
well thank you thank you very much
that's super interesting so we have time
for one question make us much choice so
thank you very much for this inspiring
talk to my suite from happy Hamburg
actually first question is a simple one
wouldn't it be useful for you to have a
small energy autonomous nodes that use
harvesting when you of course would be
too small use smaller nodes then you use
in the moment yeah
these node that I just showed you will
be the node that you know they would
like it's like a gateway where you do
processing we will play we are building
smaller nodes and which just provided
reading hmm but the maybe the more
interesting question do I get you right
I mean if you say you're searching for
the highest pollution value or something
that you're actually asking for a
routing scheme that that I mean routes
along there's something like the
steepest descent or something like this
so you know Maxima and we found that
if you are sensor is nearer to the
source of the fire the PM rebel is
higher this so we can use in the end we
send the interest for higher and higher
p.m. then you can find a geolocation of
that particular sensor yes it means that
we want to find local the source of the
burning yeah I understand who wouldn't
this actually translate into a routing
problem so that actually your interest
is guided along the yeah yeah the
interest you increase the level of the
PM in your interest and the solution I
mean the once you send the interest the
note that answer to you would be the one
that is closer and closer to the source
yeah thanks again for bringing in this
to us on very short notice and making
yourself available please keep us
informed about the programs okay so we
now am entering the second block we want
to talk about management tools and
without further ado I am ok so hello so
today I'd like to talk about ok so we
published the paper with the name of the
countries and submitted the same
countries as an individual draft and now
it's revised with a new name
which is a CC anymore because the con
tres is a little bit too complex a lo
difficult to understand the real meaning
so we change a name and now last month
it's a accepted as a research acute
draft so this is a initial version of CC
n info as such good draft oh it takes
them okay so what seasoning one can
provide actually I already mentioned and
I already talked about a benefit and
advantage what kind of information or
what kind of status we can obtain using
CC any four so it's a really powerful
networking too and also precisely
because it's really powerful networking
tool we need to have some function to
enable some access control ports the
cooperation or information disclosure so
this is also included into this draft so
this is a basic behavior CC any info
consists of two messages one is a
request message and the other is a
reprieve message and a request message
is initiated by sinful user which is a
consumer usually and afforded toward the
publisher based on the Phoebe entry in a
hop-by-hop manner and the request
message includes request block and
report blocks I detail later and the
repair message is operatory initiated by
caching lauter or the first allow the
attached publisher or publisher itself
and hold it back towards 684 user along
the pit entry and this three primacy
include reply block and replies sub
blocks this one also a little later so
so this is newly defined the the message
newly defined the similar type values so
the CCNE for message itself is
compatible with CC NX 1.0 TLB format but
request message consists of a fixed
header this is Allegra
and message for mothers one and also
liquid spoke TLV lipid pretty arabic and
named clearly so these two requests
bhaktir by report bacterias on you and
the reprime message also consists of
fixed data as well as a fixed the
request block TLB report rectory named
Jared they are same of the request
message because we just use same message
and replace the type feared message type
are sorry miss message type field to
refer message and appended the reply
block or sub block chain based so these
are the new type bodies we need to
understand so packet type request reply
top-level type oppa hope type and CC
annex message type yes well I made
animation but it's already finished
ok my animation is not really bleach so
your point rendered in Roseau basically
so it doesn't show the animation okay so
okay so that this is not so meaningful
anyway so initially the consumer sender
initiated request message and the liquid
message type is specified into this
field
PT request actually but now it's already
animation is already done so it's now it
says reply but injury it's a request and
the intermediate routers insert zero
block
Lippo Tobruk inside hop-hop-hop headers
step-by-step and finally the last hop
lot over publisher itself changed
message type field to reply and appended
the reply block and repressive rock
infamies
the information that his okay it
actually runs faster than this hey if I
can yes I can hear you can you hear me
well great
I was curious even though the animation
didn't work presumably are you sending
just a single interest and then it is
generating multiple responses as it
winds its way through the network or
were you sending multiple that's a
multiple interests each of which goes
somewhere different so this kind of
multiples past March past support will
be explained beta so could you just ask
again later
sure okay so so because regularly Oleg
that it means that if there is no well
okay okay so this is a request message
and the new redefine several point
several several type field and several
type TLB every field and
I should quickly show this rider and
request broke reporter salt please read
the draft because it's a to detail and
reprime message it's broken the figure
is also broken so please read the draft
yeah yeah okay oh um sorry it's really
broken so anyway so CCNE for provide us
on unique behavior which is which means
that it's not regular intercept so was
this new Chromebook setup PDF is really
the best format to send us yeah so okay
so the request and reply communication
is not really same of the ordinary
interest and the data communication so
the question are the the lady asked me
so one interest may initiate multiple
reply message it happens but regularly
regularly means as a default as a it's
okay as a default
as a default so the seasoning for
message is works as works like ordinary
in terms of data communication
so the strategy even though the some
router has a multiple upstream interface
so some specific ok so I go back so
different so different operations from
the regular interstate require the
system if we could because it's easy for
request should not result in pita
creation into out during the message
transmission and the season for reprise
must not be catchment allowed us because
it's something like a measurement to and
the for march past support allowed us
should not leave me the pit entry
created by city i have requests on the
timeout bar expired this is a unique
point this means that even though you
receive the one request if you request
amount fully you want to fully discover
the potential pass for getting the some
specific content then your pit entry
cannot be removable so of course there
is timeout body so finally that some
message may be discarded
according because of the timer as
expiration but there is a timer so you
can have the potential to receive a
multiple requests or replies from
upstream louder's well i understand this
is a good point to discuss so can I go
ok so first the questions I mean this
seems to me like like a unique
opportunity for an attack I mean this is
a nice attack vector to to flood the pit
isn't it maybe
um so similar vein but maybe a more
positive cast making this a separate
message type means you don't necessarily
have to do resource allocation the way
you would for interest data exchanges
which means the fact that you're
breaking flow balance allows us to
rethink how we do the resource
allocation for doing these operations um
one thing you really like to know when
the request message arrives it's what's
the worst case number of reply messages
that might come back mmm
do you have something in the request
message that bounds that because if you
had that the resource allocator could
keep track of just how much bandwidth is
could might be needed on the reverse
direction to return the replies have you
given any thought to that so I think
there are several not definitive but
several solution one the simple solution
is something like a later limiting so
you can just vary some apollomon
you can stop even though there is
someone something like a bogus to be pry
happened then the love digest can
discard everything and he doesn't need
to reply back to consumer yeah the
problem we should talk offline about the
problem with the scheme like that
because if you want to do that these
these messages now have to be way lower
precedence for bandwidth than normal
interest data exchanges which means they
won't work when you need them the best
but most let's go talk about the other
fly again okay but in general my feeling
that laid control can help something and
also some if we have some doubts
something like a bailout a verification
mechanism inside this protocol then
maybe bogus traffic can be also
discarded so but anyway so this is a
very detailed so I want to go the next
right so this is a really important
discussion point and one of the
important open issues so maybe I will
back to that kind of discussion and I
expect that this kind of discussion
happens here so I already mentioned that
so how we can
enabling multiple support the legally as
a default so the CCNA in for message
exchange is behave as behave as
something like ordinary interest and
data communicate data communication
because CCNA will request as a default
comprise with the strategy and season
user you use a could trace the actual
boarding pass so usually if the strategy
allows a single pass even though some
router has a multiple fever entries
toward some specific content finally the
the consumer they see with a single data
because pit entry was already removed so
regularly if we follow that kind of
regular behavior then we don't eliminate
some program but as option we should
have some potential to capture the whole
potential voiding pass information or
the potential cashing places someone may
want to retrieve such kind of
information so as an option we should
have some capability to allow that
getting the multiple little apply toward
the to consumer and port information so
this is also okay just keep it today and
discussions so there are several so this
is a initial button of such craft and I
know there are several open issues and
the discussion do we need to discuss so
especially for March discovery and this
one is also a little bit of details so
we can just skip and no no go back go
back
yes and the neighbor modification so
actually as an academic paper we already
published how the neighbor can verify
each other without having something like
a CA so something like I say
central management system so we already
published a paper transaction network
science and engineering but and I may
have a chance to refer this paper for
the Levi's draft or if this is really
useful we also have a plan to submit as
a different or another document internet
draft and we can discuss more and as
maybe you have a lot of a discussion so
please keep in touch and let's start the
discussion and if we have some
interesting the comment and I'm really
happy to hear and okay so today I'm
happy to announce our new implementation
we call civil and this is a software
platform enabling CC and based
communications it's open source written
in C so you can just ask access to HTTP
safe or not net or just capture this QR
code now then you can vote no so there
are several interesting function that
interesting implementation functions to
be implemented and it's a there is a to
demo simple consists of two main demo is
definitely this is affording them its
basic demo and there's ICS monitor this
is a separated daemon which support
enables the content store and since F
initely itself is the right weight and
it can just connect to CS monitor D via
UNIX socket or T are TCP socket and also
usually I hope the many researchers or
engineer want to develop their original
implementation but they are usually I
don't know usually but some many times
don't need to care the pit management or
fit management itself so for example if
we some of the researcher engineer want
to develop the caching algorithm
replacement algorithm or some other
algorithm or transport mechanism allow
demon
they can all implement as a separate
plugin liabilities so plugging lava is
just built in the sample 780 or CS
manager D and they can extended easily
there and create their own CCN
communication between blocks and there
are several operational tools your keys
are also supported and also of course
the second safe point is this is a CC
and info already implemented so next
page so this is a very very simple demo
so we just capture the screen and CCN of
people CCN : rush newness science and
this is topology consumers here and
published here and that this is route
route in cash so and we set up a 10
millisecond delay for each and then the
consumer center request and toward along
the feeb and then the seasoning for
request is alive that are 5 then out of
5 reply back toward the consumer so this
is a one-way da he can see you can see
and this is round-trip time and there is
a cashier information here and this
content is so the sizes and cob and how
many interests he received and what kind
of a chunk here is stored and the
expiration time and so on and this is a
so someone just want to trace the
network condition and he doesn't care
for example caching condition and he
would know the march past condition
instead so in that case consumer here
and the cache is there r2 and r4 and
this request message is transmitted and
toward art were the publisher but
actually the album is split the request
message and the once
request message is sent to toward r2 and
once the request message sent twelve
feet
maybe or alpha or some somewhere here
and finally are the 2 and alpha reply
back to see so he received the two
messages after he received two messages
so why is from Delta 2 and the other is
route from route of all and each has a
RT key so this is a final site so season
4 is compatible with CC and extra format
and it's a powerful network to providing
various information and it's already
provided in c4 support surface of course
it's really ongoing until there are
maybe lots of back I know but we have
been working for to mature the quality
and we are really sure that we need to
others many open issues but maybe step
by step and we revise the ID and the
comments is always welcome thank you
fantastic that was a nice surprise I
have one question
happy concerning the scope writing some
kind of scorpion yes yes actually the
our specification already mentioned
about something like a expanding link
search something like expanding
advancing exists so you'd image the hop
count and then the new your request must
be stopped at that hop count and or
operatory if you already know the
caching information within let's say the
NEX the small network with which is for
example our hop count is 3 but you don't
know that from 3 to pop count 5 for
example then you can specify a boundary
between 3 and 5 then you can search the
three and five how many caches are
located for your content so it's already
specified and our implementation already
support this one thank you we need a
little heavy support here and I think
so I just checked the license for c4
that seems to be the special and I
should heal Eisen but it's like
permissive and mighty license like BSD
second close to so it's a very a circle
you can copy modify yes it's very right
right great
okay so why are we getting set up again
here and so Dave is not going to talk
about ping and traceroute so we're
running a bit behind one time so I'm
going to do this at Lightspeed some of
you have seen this work before it fell
into kind of a hibernating state but now
that the the research group has gotten
interested in really moving forward on
management instrumentation tools we kind
of brought it back what happened this
screen okay so on our view and you
toshi-san and and some of us have talked
about this a lot is that there isn't a
one-size-fits-all instrumentation and
management tool for things CCN info is
kind of your big toolbox that can do a
whole lot of things and get really rich
information back from from the elements
and in a nice en network the ping and
traceroute are much more like at least
conceptually the equivalent IP world
tools which is their intended to be
extremely lightweight and usable by
end-users to at least get some sense of
how things are working
so my the contention is where's the free
button no that's okay is that we need
some lightweight tools for
troubleshooting before employing more
heavyweight heavy-duty tools like CCN
info you'll see that these have a very
different kind of target and a very
different kind of approach to how
they're done
so the first of these is ping and you
can think I pee style ping in your brain
is your mental model for this what we
want to be able to do with ICN since
it's a richer architecture in many ways
than IP is to get information back about
the the targets of requests in an an ICN
world so the questions we'd like to ask
with this is is a particular ICN forward
or reachable is a producer application
reachable and is a cached object on the
path to a particular can produce err
reachable and in the process of doing
multiple of these just like we can do in
the IP world you can run several of
these and to get some statistics like
average and and dispersion on round-trip
times so one of the things we note here
is that if you want to talk about the
forwarder since we're in a and routing
by name environment for ICN you need to
give names to the things you want to
route to so in this case we're not
necessarily interested just in getting
to application objects but we need to
talk about the forward errs which means
forwarders need names now I would claim
independent of any of these particular
tools you don't have a manageable
network at all unless the the forwarders
have names on their own so these can
either be globally routable under the
name of their administrator or use some
kind of forwarding hint within an
administrative domain in order to get to
the forwarder what we've seen in the IP
world is that some operators don't like
to externalize the names of their
internal resources because it for one
reason or another may open them to
outside attack or competitive analysis
of how their theorem domain is working
but at any rate the forwarder names need
to be known in some way the second
question is is an application producer
reachable so we'd like to discover the
forwarder that has the local
connectivity in other words in the same
system instance with the application and
then because we support caching and ICN
we'd like to be able to
cut off one of these exchanges and
answer that there's a cached version of
a particular object that is available on
path at a particular forwarder the other
thing we'd like to be able to do and
this comes up in the CCN info context as
well is to be able to do our TT
measurements in the presence of
multipath this is this is a generally
difficult problem some of us have
tackled it in the context of trying to
do multipath congestion control
so we basically adopt the same since the
same group of people who designed both
we adopt sort of the same overall
approach to doing this so we use a path
ID identifier in the data message
package and then presume that this path
steering work that's been going around
in the research community for the last
couple of years we can import into here
and use path steering to steer ping
messages over particular paths the way
you obtain these path IDs is you can do
path discovery the actual packet
encoding is an echo request and an echo
reply now the interesting thing in the
CCN architecture is remember we have
both message types and packet types the
message type for this is still an
interest message but the packet type is
echo request an echo reply and this
allows us to emulate the actual
forwarding behavior of interests and
data messages almost exactly a couple
just minor points which is the user can
direct this directly to get further
management administrative information so
the information coming back can be used
as the target name for doing a CCN info
style deeper query of the network and of
course replies need to be signed here in
order to avoid any kind of reflection
attacks so I'm in the interest of time
I'm going to skip some of this it's all
in the it's all in the draft and move
quickly on to trace route now what we
did with trace route is remember in the
IP world trace route is done with
exactly the same packet type as ping
it's a echo
Qwest echo reply packet it's just the
processing is different we follow a
similar architecture here but there's
some differences so we'd like to know
what the path of the forwarder is what's
the path to a producer application and
what are the pads to cached objects so
we want instead of just getting reply is
it there we want to look at what the
paths are and do hop-by-hop RTT
measurements on paths so the differences
here from an encoding standpoint is we
have two new packet types although again
it's an interesting response and the
core message core mechanism is what came
up just a few minutes ago that it's an
expanding ring broadcast so we use hop
limit expiry in order to explore the the
diverging paths as would have been done
with with IP trace route the same way
and that's it I'm done
comments on the drafts they've been
adopted by the RG we we hope to progress
them forward over the next few months
and potentially get them get them to
last call thank you you can stay there
and do net me ah yes
okay and now for something completely
different so there's some work that's
been going on primarily at Cisco I don't
work for Cisco anymore in case people
haven't noticed but I still collaborate
with the team there on a number of
things this being one of them so since
none of them can make it here today I've
been sort of called into service to
present their drafts so this is not my
work this is their work so what what is
what is map they do very quickly before
I go into the updates is ICN needs
mechanisms to support producer mobility
consumer mobility is kind of naturally
built in to the CCN and Indian
architectures we don't need to talk
about it much when you do producer
mobility on a mobile network there are
only a few feasible ways to do this you
can do anchored mobility with a with
reflection point back in the network you
can try to make your routing protocols
converge so fast that you can track
directly via routing the movement of a
producer or you can design some kind of
custom mechanism and map me is kind of a
compromise custom mechanism it assumes
that your routing can converge
reasonably fast meaning in some small
number of seconds so this creates
volatile state that allows you to track
producers and deal with their mobility
during the time that the routing is
rican verging so this draft has been
around for a little while there is Cisco
IPR on it I think that's mentioned
somewhere but I'll mention it right off
on the top so I won't present the whole
draft obviously in the interest of time
and people can read it but there have
been a few changes since the last time
we went through this the first is that
the the original spec had sort of like a
full-blown retransmission management
scheme so it had its own kind of
transport protocol properties for the
control messages that were going back
and forth between the the diversion
elements that did the the bypass routing
these have been simplified considerably
it turns out didn't need all those
mechanisms after building it and trying
it out a bit secondly there was some
assumptions in the in the previous
version of the draft was that what you
were talking to as an output face was
simply a layer 2 mobile network
interface to the to them to a mobile
network this this scheme obviously has
much more broad applicability to that so
the descriptions have been broadened to
deal with any type of face including
tunnels IP you know IP tunnels UDP
tunnels any kind of tunnel so that
that's been expanded
last time there was a whether it was in
Cambridge or previous meeting we had a
presentation on the socket interface
that has been designed for H ICN and
potentially other ICN flavors and it's
now this scheme is now implemented for
that that socket interface so it the
code that you get is workable with the
with the socket interface that that's
been provided by Cisco for H ICN so
where we are here is that despite the
name of the document it's been missin
aimed originally and the chairs had you
know too busy to worry about that too
much
this is not yet an RG adopted draft even
though it's named as if it were although
it's marked in the data tracker
correctly um we'd like more feedback
where the authors would like more
feedback from the from the IC energy
community find out whether other people
are interested in taking the
implementation and using it for various
things and see about we'll talk more
about adoption of this and whether it's
a good idea at in Prague thank you
thanks a lot Dave if we're doing this
quickly yeah so we think this is a nice
useful mechanism that could help us
loose the mobility in some scenarios
please have a look and let us know and
that the other us know what you think
all right so we're moving on Robbie is
next update on the ICN IOT draft
[Music]
so this draft has been in this group for
some time so the basic goal of this
draft is I mean it is a modern
information in fact so the idea is to
basically present how ICN it would be a
good kind of network stack for those to
have to serve several IOT applications
and
so I what I'm I mean since it's been
there I hope people who are interested
would have gone through it at least once
and so I'll not go into the history of
the draft I search but just focus on the
changes that we are made so primarily we
have cut down on the authors list so
primarily to the set of authors who have
been actively contributing to the draft
and we have wrote a tight H - and who's
been contributing now so this is the
primarily the table of content of the
draft I could spend some time so the
basic idea is to as I said tries to
motivate ICN for IOT and I think it kind
of resonates with the kind of points
that Simon brought out saying that you
know I see IOT networks family
information sentiment they just
producing information so all you need
from an IOT network is to get that piece
of information or if you can talk in
terms of a consumer publisher model it
is fundamentally the same so so in this
what we try to do is to primarily in
section 3 is to identify some of the
general requirements of from an IOT
perspective so in terms of naming
security privacy and so and so forth
then then we in section 4 we basically
talk about how the current architectures
failed to scale primarily because I mean
you know IOT is it's a plethora of
stacks there and so primarily this huge
set of interoperability issues all the
age issues a final fundamentally handled
later the application get to a level and
that's a basic point that this section
four brings out and then section five is
where we talk about how the different
constructs of ICN can be used to meet
the requirements of the things that we
mentioned in section 3 and the different
design choices you could make within ICN
to meet those requirements so yeah so
that's about the the main meat of the
trap
so going into the into the changes that
we did I mean mostly it is about most of
it is very editorial I mean there was
some redundant discussion that we
eliminated and some and we kind of moved
some of the discussion into different to
make it more relevant where we felt was
it was lying further out in the draft so
in section 2 we have the this this
section was kind of hidden somewhere in
section I think section 4 or something
so pulled it up and so then we then we
have the Services scenario so initially
that was kind of the section 2 so the
main idea with services in are you again
you know IOT is a very siloed kind of an
area so at what we provide there is
discussions with on specific scenarios
and then see how ICN could help those
specific scenarios so then there was
some discussion on naming where we had
some discussion on particular this was
the requirements kind of the part of the
draft so we had some specific solutions
being discussed so we eliminated that
contextual communication in terms of
long term short term context and so this
was there's some kind of we tried to
merge kind of make the discussion more
kind of seamless to read and then some
renaming of this section so primarily
this is the the main changes that we
made to the trap and since we do not do
it in the last IETF we plant we were
happy we wanted to bring this back so
that people can have again a good view
review of it and provide as much
feedback so we had some feedback from
Thomas on some references and we should
I didn t trade because I I thought we
could get in more inputs before coming
up with a new version so so more
comments and requested for this thing
Thanks yeah thanks Ravi I mean if people
have more ideas please talk to Ravi
[Music]
that's okay thanks
so Thomas is next update on the low pen
specification okay so this is just a
brief update on on the low pen draft
which we have talked about a couple
times this has been recently adopted as
a research group item so it's the
version 0 now again and what has been
updated since the last the last version
of this document is basically the CC
annex stateless compression schemes that
haven't be hadn't been defined yet and
then we only had to find Indian and
others a renaming we then we use ICN Lok
and as a name to make it more inclusive
for the different ICN dialects and
security considerations were added just
a brief recap what is the objective of
this draft first of all may I say in
lopen compliance or had defined a
convergent layer for low power lossy
networks in particular a two 2.15 for
adapt the hello adapters to the link
constraints of this low power loss in
that word and then define a couple of
compression schemes which are first of
all that stateless compression for the
theories and second stateful compression
and I come to this in a second stateless
compression is basically about more
efficient encoding and the omission of
redundant information wherever possible
and that means first of all we try to
get the TV's to - smaller - smaller
encoding for instance a boolean bit
vector vector can be reduced to a bit
and we also try to remove a lot of
fields from the header wherever possible
if if they are not needed for instance
length if you have if you are in a more
or less confined
scheme then you can adjust this to
fixed-length and you don't need the need
to carry this also remove redundant
header fields and there's an overview of
the to understand missed that point are
you yeah anyway of the two flavors
Indian NCCN X so what you see what does
grey here is the stuff that is basically
attacked or or reduced by by the
stateless compression what we do is we
use the 6lowpan dispatch fields which
which are used which I need it anyway
because we want to make the slope
infantry they're compliant and we encode
bits and that's the lower line here we
encode bits about about the presence of
compressed fields according to the to
the protocol so what we see is and the N
is a bit leaner see see an X has much
many more options so that means we have
a longer dispatch field here so just
giving you an idea how this looks so in
ND n we have this long type length value
vector and that that can be reduced in
for the simple example that you have an
the name ACM Boston but yeah as you see
there then you see that we can can
reduce this to to a shorter encoding
here and that was basically cutting out
18 bytes in this case for the for the
interest and for the CC annex interest
in the same case even cutting out even
more but it I mean the original the
original encoding had been longer
saiful compression to recap there - two
approaches one is too similar to the the
6lowpan approach to put a context
specific state like prefixes or other
stuff in in common knowledge that is
identified by the by context identifier
so you don't need to carry it in the
packets because it will be redundantly
communicated for instance common
prefixes common suffixes common options
and the second approach which is that's
unique to add to an ICN approach is to
replace the the names in the in the if
you send an interest you send a name and
if you reply to this actually the name
is replied again at you you elide this
name by or we like this name by
generating short-short local ID so
making it sort of a stateful hop
compression this has a following as a
message much stronger impact here so if
you look at the the example of the
interest if you compress this only using
the common prefix out and you're in the
compression in this example by about 40
percent in the data case where you omit
the full name then we are really down to
to something that is very small which is
important just recap these these link
layers have very short NTU sizes and it
is a it's a real advantage if we can put
packets or if you can can construct
packets that that fit into these small
in sizes of 127 bytes or so
so this was more or less to give the the
overview and what we we are now at is we
we have a draft that has a sort of shape
and we have we want to stimulate a
couple of discussions first of all the
India and CCN X faults so the question
is is this actually this were these
other compressions as you like that is
it does it meet me the the the the
perspective of of the groups also
question that some type and length
restrictions in the compression so names
can be only a certain number of by its
name components and so on question is is
this okay just to recap we can always
send uncompressed interest in data so it
doesn't mean that we are where we are
doing onto the network but if we if we
compress them we have some restrictions
and question is are they feasible and do
they actually match the common use cases
are they actually that the useful things
to do and in our call to the community
is on the implementers we are working on
implementing stuff and we are originally
started at the collaboration with the
Indian Ooty team and you see a UCLA
actually the Indian Ooty team was
recently formed and the question is yeah
are we ready to implement this together
and others to others are they willing to
adopt this encode I mean making this
code yeah and to all of course are we in
line with hue with key use cases and or
did we miss anything that is really
relevant here so please please speak
speak up on this and our next steps will
be continue implementations get get more
code running get more experiments get
more real experiences
get an implementation for the CC NX
which is for us is just a pretty renew
and the question is do we have any we
only use of the CC and light so are
there any other people willing to work
on implementations for CC NX and
regarding the document I mean we are
planning to have a major editorial
improvement just to make this document
more readable make it better and that
should be soon that should probably be
released way before the next IETF and
then we are of course asking for
feedback to get this in a finish in a
contentious state with a research book
yeah thanks that was it okay great
thanks are there any immediate answers
to promises questions so what could we
say so we need to do all I can like one
or two revisions maybe get this done
before Montreal will be an optional
depends a little bit what the feedback
is I don't know you have very very
controversial feedback then we have to
deal with it if we converge quickly then
yes yes okay yeah sounds very good
thanks so just to put this into
perspective and this is a really
interesting piece of work because it
enables us to you know run the semantics
of ICN without translation was in say
convergence layer that is specifically
adapting to the needs of constrained
networks and very elegant way to
basically have end-to-end as in
communication on the semantic level and
maybe that's actually something that you
guys want to look on before you lose
work great thanks so thanks a lot
everyone for you know being so good on
the time so that gives me actually a
chance to do little exam with you so I
hope you paid attention for the German
speakers
after all has no bite so in the
beginning I kind of try to give you this
overview about the like the technical
activities in icy energy and so if
you're a networking person you will
surely see that there's some essential
piece missing for a comprehensive
communication framework and it's
supposed to do something useful anybody
so we have packet forwarding service we
have technology your management you're
thinking about apps mobility what is
still needed to prevent the collapse of
the ICN internet
[Music]
routing a congestion control right so
routing and congestion control so it's
not like there's no work on congestion
control there there's been really good
work it's just hasn't been brought to
eyes the energy so so in case you're
looking for a way to make a you know
dent in in ICN a nice energy it could
consider either one of those topics all
right think that that was just a quick
reminder I wanted to communicate by the
way yeah both of those are careers not
projects okay
great that brings me to the end so yeah
we are planning the upcoming meetings so
probably you will have the same set up
in in Prague depends on of course a bit
on what people bring to us and in
previous year not this year but we are
we sometimes did it interim in January
so we haven't prepared anything yet but
if people want to do something host
something please
talk to us
better quick internment in Tokyo not
sure whether we can align with that but
yep let us know the default state is
that the next time we meet will be in
Prague yeah so someone wants to meet
sooner than that
we'll work with you to arrange it and
make it happen
right okay thanks again for the good
presentations and things
[Music]
[Applause]