oh no and I had comments obviously okay
we're gonna get started I want to make
sure I have the details all right
everyone take their seat please or leave
the room
no one's listening hey Tony P and Alvaro
you could take it outside or sit down
one of the two could someone please
close the doors someone in the back if
you could close the doors
thank you yeah we could send them around
again I guess all right let's get
started
good morning I'm Tony Lee this is a talk
on creating better hierarchy in is is
next slide as long as you to PDF it
works cool all right
okay so one of the things that's
happening is that network architectures
are changing and lots of people are
starting to implement routers using lots
of littler routers we started off using
multi chassis routers a long time ago
and those multi chassis routers are
basically lots of little forwarding
engines wrapped around a network fabric
what we're seeing is that people are
moving towards a better topology where
all those little boxes actually are
independent systems and the fabric is
actually becoming the inner the data
center fabric now what that does do is
that blows out the system level
abstraction that we have with a multi
chassis router leaving us with lots more
routers that we have to manage we'd like
to restore some level of abstraction so
that we don't have too many entities
hanging around and in particularly in
the case of the iGPS
the way we create an abstraction is by
an area if we have a bunch of areas
level one areas for data centers then
maybe we need level two to handle the
pop you know we kind of want level three
for the land so almost certainly we want
level three levels three through eight
are available the folks who designed is
is were somewhat prescient and they very
nicely reserved more bits in the circuit
ID for us and did not use them
right now there are only three levels
three values that are defined bit one is
level 1 bit 2 is level 2 you can turn on
both if you're a level one oh it's l1 l2
but there's six reserved bits for
setting there I'm
that we turn those on and make those
levels three through eight here they are
one important note here I am proposing
that we make a restriction that these
bits are only set contiguously I don't
know what it means for a router to be in
level one and level three and not in
level two and that makes my brain really
hurt if you can explain it to me when
I'm sober I would appreciate it if
that's a comment please come to the mic
the other things that we need to do to
make this happen we need a new hello PDU
right now we have an l1 iah you have an
l2 iih we could go down the path of
creating l3 to LA I H s but I don't
think that's strictly necessary I think
if we just create a new one because we
don't want to have interoperability
backwards interoperable interoperability
issues but we could create one new one
that allows you to advertise level 3 3
level 8 IAH at one time I think that's
possible we need some new LSPs new PDUs
for level 3 through L a level 8 LSPs we
need new PDUs for CS NPS and pas NPS and
that the dad saw mostly this draft is
about a giant request to Ayane
for a whole lot of new code points less
skins burg so I'm still wrapping my head
around this a little bit but and there's
a bunch of knits here I mean do we get a
new mech multicast address for thing for
the IHS because we got to know
all our ones or twos if if we do this
I'd love to see us use 7356 in coatings
in other words we'd 7356 and Louds for
new flooding scopes for example so it
seems to me we could make this work you
get some issues this there's actually no
such thing in 10 589 as an l2 only
router so circuit type 2 is actually
illegal ok it's supposed to be you know
1 or 3
I mean we found use cases for - let's
strictly so I don't know these are all
kind of knits but to me it's more about
defining how this should be used I think
we have to think about the deployment
cases harder like answer I'd like to see
more discussion about that ok thank you
I have to admit I'm shocked I didn't I
don't realize there's no just l2
operation yes so by definition an l2
router is an l1 router in its in
whatever area it's defined - they have
whatever its area address is right yeah
but I mean there's no l2 only circuit no
no the there are many implementations
that have this is type l2 only or
something like that that's a convenient
CLI so that you don't have to go to
every circuit and say the circuit is l2
only right ok but the circuit type can
be able to only yeah yeah yeah sorry I
missed it yeah it's in an area but it's
not any circuit serve no l1 circuits
there's no one you can have that we
obviously have many deployments where
people just did everything's l2 they
didn't bother without one for various
reasons you Tony P Draper
so I think I've done the newest version
of draft which is slim my only question
would be so we assumed at the highest
level that gets configured or deployed
is still connected right so we don't get
any partition level problems you know l2
partitioned ok
and we probably do not care to detect
what is the higher level or whether it's
partitioned or not which is assume
people don't do stupid stuff like
partition area 0 and s P R I'm not
proposing anything you do stupid stuff
okay all right
Deadwood marry the clarification the
trough I think okay it's no observation
let me amend that I'm not intentionally
suggesting people to stupid AC Linda MA
Cisco Systems I'm I let me just make
sure I understand it right you are
keeping all the same semantics of a l1
l2 router except it would be a L n minus
1 level n minus 1 level and so that
you'd always have two contiguous levels
yes and possibly more contiguous levels
right and you could conceivably have a
router that's l1 through la right when
we router which circuits how a circuit
would be in how many levels the circuit
can be in as many levels as it wants but
the levels must be contiguous yeah yeah
my brain hurts too so so I brought this
up a you know outside I haven't thought
this through either yeah but I I keep
wondering if there isn't something where
we have to configure the area according
to the you know the in other words it
out say we have 8 levels level 8 would
then be ignoring the area but all levels
below would be some per prefix I don't
know if that's needed or not i but I'm
wondering for sanity's sake yes it would
make sense for the end sap to be
hierarchical assess your brawn so tiny
the the I think when you started you
said that you wanted to use one to be a
sort of confederation that became a
became a Rooter and right so it would
there would be some sense in having one
and n as the discontinuous pair if you
were building say a level four Rooter
then its subcomponents would internally
be in level in their own level one so I
could see cases where you might want to
if you only wanted to build a high order
then you you may use the lower one of
the lowest order in order to construct
it as a special case I think for
discontinuous I think les is gonna
respond cited so this is where it's an
interesting discussion deployment cases
right I think we need to flush that out
so people at least have some clue about
what are what's good ways to use this
and you know we could debate I'm not so
keen on having you know level n and
level one mud if we can figure out why
that's useful to me seem to be the
original sighted one which was one
becomes your inter the internal
components of the Rooter and it sits in
a higher-order level so so if using one
in the classic sense that it's a black
we using today then it doesn't make
sense but this sighted case was that we
were building riches a different way and
I think there is a case then for one
being special okay I'm not clear on that
but maybe if we talk about it somewhere
will it'll make more sense yeah I I
haven't found a case that I wanted to
use discontinuous levels yet but I do
want multiple levels just for creating
more hierarchy and more scale okay area
abstraction and so actually this a
synonym I was as speaking this chair I
think this would if we were to adopt
these giraffes this would be some drafts
before we could go to standardization we
want implementations okay area
abstraction so this is actually should
have come first because this actually
helps motivate why we need more levels
so
if you haven't noticed let's see we've
already talked about that the way is is
does levels is not very pretty if you
have a level one area and you want to
transit a level one area you have to
take those transit circuits and push
them into level two and they show up in
the level two link state database and if
your data center is going to almost all
be used for transit you effectively push
everything into level two that's a scale
problem we really like to be able to
build areas and have them really be an
abstraction so that we don't push all of
this data up into level two and cause
level two to congest so how can we fix
this what we'd really like to do is to
have a different level one abstraction
where a level one area just looks like a
single level to note we'd like the
internal topology the level one area not
to be exposed whatsoever to level two we
do need to have all of the external
connectivity represented right so
everything that the level one area
touches all the level two connectivity
does need to be there so a level two SPF
still works so what I'm proposing is
that we're gonna represent level to a
level one area has a level two pseudo
node a single pseudo node inside the
level one area will use the area leader
mechanism that we came up with with
dynamic flooding we're gonna just elect
someone to pick that pseudo node ID and
he's going to go ahead and advertise
that throughout his level one area on
the external links everyone talking
outside of a level an area we're gonna
use that pseudo node ID for our level
two I I H s ie we're gonna lie big time
okay everybody outside now looks and
sees that this is just a giant pseudo
node we want all of the our area border
routers now to tunnel back to the area
leader and use that as a l2 sir virtual
circuit and that's going to give us l2
flooding within the area and now after
that happens our area leader now has
full ideas about all of the level 2
connectivity for this level one area so
let me so you're going to tunnel the
traffic you said no not tunneling the
traffic you're going to that then the
level one is going to have to have the
complete layer level 2 topology D axis
transit not arc not apology but all the
routes right so what's gonna have to
happen is level 2 is going to exchange
LSPs across the tunnels okay and the
level 2 area border routers are going to
have to be able to compute transit
across level and area and provide that
transit but not and be able to transit a
one and only routers yeah so what would
that implies that the level 1 only
routers would have to have all the level
2 routes no I'm I'm gonna suggest
something even sicker which is that we
tunnel from area entry to area exit okay
that's that's what I asked initially and
you said no okay but not we're not using
the tunnel to the area leader we're
doing it a direct tunnel from entry to
exit okay and that can be sr or GRE I
don't care okay back to advertising
right information okay so the area
leader now has an l2 database that
contains all the l2 information from all
of his area border routers that gives us
the identities of all of the adjacency
on the air for the area and he can
cobble all of those up and list those as
adjacent to the pseudo note he uses that
to generate an l2 LSP for the l1 area
[Music]
that gets flooded into l2 as normal
flooding the other l2 area originated
LSPs that all of the area border routers
are generating those need to get
filtered those should not leave the area
and some of you are going you yak yes
that's gross okay but what's happening
outside of this area is that we're now
seeing a single LSP it lists all of the
external adjacencies and nothing more
the entire l1 area is just completely
hidden okay we actually already talked
about the forwarding problem all of our
area border routers are full-fledged l2
we've got connectivity are flooding
connectivity is to the area leader but
that's not where we want to forward so
we actually want to compute shortcuts
from entry to exit and srr GRE I don't
really care
whatever folks feel like is you useful
for tunneling today new mechanisms we
need a mechanism for advertising with
pseudo node so a simple TLV to advertise
that through l1 and that's about it
everything else is protocol machinery
any questions I could have benefited by
some pictures this kind of hurts my head
a little bit maybe notice next draft I
just I just had one comment from OSPF my
experience with virtual links has been
that and I realized this
exactly of difference you've solved the
problems different ways but I always
thought if we ever did OSPF before I'd
get rid of them because of the added
complexity so we'd have to really think
we wanted this and we couldn't just by
you know share you can just share links
like we are doing today having a circuit
be and multiples you to handle the use
case of transit
well again the sharing the links causes
a scale problem so if you've got another
idea of how to achieve the same ends
without the scale I'm all ears
yeah I'm just questioning the use case
of needing an arbitrary area for transit
mm-hmm that's pretty clear that that's
gonna happen sooner or later as networks
scale up if we don't have some level of
hierarchy then we end up with flat
networks and it has scale problems of
its own so really our only alternative
for scaling networks is to build
hierarchy donate I didn't read the draft
I'm sorry but I'm trying to understand
this so you want to be able to transcend
it changes a lot to know the Ciena you
want to be able to transit the area over
level area and then how do you set the
metrics for the pseudo node to the rest
of it right you want to be able to get
in here and get out there there's a
different metric than get in here and
get out somewhere else from the area how
do you set this up and if you are not
careful if you are inside in the middle
of the area somewhere and you want to
bypass this area and if you're not
careful setting these metrics can you
ever go back because you are doing
hop-by-hop let's assume it's an MPLS hop
by hop forwarding in the middle of the
lower-level area can you ever hit the
other way because you know you're
looking at the destination you don't
really know you want to exit that this
router in the packet in the data packets
right I mean maybe it might have
explained these on the draft arm so I
didn't read it just did not explain this
on the draft there are no metrics that
are advertised outside of the area this
is abstraction but we determine comes
the pain
of having suboptimal routing right we
know this can you look back can you have
loops you can't have loops because
you're actually getting the shortcuts
computed through the area that's not a
problem so you I don't get metric
information either so you must have an
encapsulation inside area for the data
packet correct because inside the area
there's some l1 routers and you're gonna
have to transit them alright thank you
just answer a few questions MTA and
traffic engineering so I don't see that
there's a problem with MT traffic
engineering obviously since you can't
see inside the area it's abstracted away
from you yeah you can obviously do tooi
within the area you can even do te for
the transit traffic at the area entry
but external traffic coming in cannot
control its path through the area again
this is an abstraction any ideas to be
decouple it so at least remember how we
did their CPP on the boundaries border
not would know what's inside and bus
places correct that border router can
manage a path within the area but you
can't do it from the head end probably
require some extensions to signal
particular capabilities and there's
nothing for csmp to compute because he
can't see the data but someone has to do
it
well again the area entry is the best
place Chris Martin arista I just wanted
to maybe help clarify if you think about
what this area I think this goes to your
point AC we're asking about a use case
imagine a you know because its own
though and leaf spine router like a
multi chassis router it's mostly folded
Clos or clothes apology so the leaves in
this case the hierarchies come inverted
typically the top of the hierarchy would
be at the root you know and then you
would have you know in a multi area case
the route routers would typically be the
ABR's but in this case the leaves are
more likely to be the inter area
connection points and so you need the
you know in terms of abstraction you're
going to be coming at it would typically
be like the level one router itself and
therefore you have to make the whole
area level to aware and so this
abstraction kind of hides that going to
the point about you know traffic
engineering within the area
imagine a complete graph that's got full
by sectional bandwidth or bipartite
graph for that matter with full bisexual
day with you don't care about the
topology just like typically you don't
care about you know you know we don't
talk about traffic engineering between
line cards and routers so the thinking
would be released initially that it's
just a complete graph or a bipartite
graph with full by sectional bandwidth
so to your point Jeff you can just hide
that information I don't know if that
helps clarify the use case maybe but
Tony P again so yeah I see first layers
of the onions being peeled so we took it
of course all the way in PN I and if you
do that stuff
choosing the ingress into the area is
something you simply can't resolve you
may end up on a bad ingress so the only
way we could deal to start with the
pinna and I were cranking back what you
cannot do here of course right so
whatever you try even if you try to
advertise some metrics you summarize the
stuff and you you end up advertising
this full mesh with some approximation
with sometimes am subtitles right it's
inherent limitation of abstraction
abstraction is controlled lying and
there is something you you simply cannot
change correct Chris Byrne Hurston let
me just reiterate you don't have to
traffic engineer between line cards and
routers right there buddy agree with
that so I don't think we have to crank
back so if links fail within the l1 area
you can compute a new route that's gonna
happen
any other questions all right thank you
I wish I was just gonna say I'd
encourage everybody to read these this
is these are definitely interesting
proposals and we really haven't you you
know we kind or the base mechanisms of
the protocol we kind of haven't really
extended them too much
you know we had always be 8 feet 3
extended L essays that was a big step
and then we had some experimental things
like TTC but we really haven't had so
this is this is this is definitely
interesting so that's I'd advise
everybody to read it and let's have a
discussion on both on the both the
mechanisms and use cases
ok Yuma hey go ahead come on up I'd like
you to say which I know you've had this
estándares track I read this and I was
saying okay what's what's Tanner track
you can tell me what you're
standardizing and what you're just
recommending out of this or whether it
should be just informational it's a
great question actually it was a mistake
if you see the Gero Gero wash snakes
informational but actually when we are
floating 0 1 I had a hit had issue with
what you call the what is that ID
uploading tool issue Oh idea uploading
talisha Taurus alchemy to fix that the
fun because waking up that time it's
something messed up there I'll fix that
okay so it is informational it's
information okay okay yeah okay so my
name is Emma from hobby so I'm going to
talk about the ice is multi topology
deployment considerations here next
slide
so we know this multi topology for last
ten years maybe so
I implemented multiple gene in my
earlier life so but what's happening new
what's new here is people are seeking to
use ipv6 only we have seen earlier
before you have e4 and say to people
want introduce v6 into the network now
people want to use ipv6 only topology
they so the use cases like you know
people are looking at III talk to
multiple people those are in the mobile
backhaul and yell 3l 3dc underlays so
what's the what's the issue and what's
the goal of this document goal of this
document is to lay out the nuances
around the SS ipv6 so there are multiple
ways you can do this ipv6 introduction
based on your requirements because we
have two ways to do this essentially so
but there are caveats in each each thing
as I'll just explain that so if you are
transitioning from ipv4 to v6 there's
certainly there's no question about it
you have to use is SMT to Mt RFC Phi 1
to 0 and but if you are using ipv6 only
then you have two options
that's the main point of this but if you
confuse on this you have a lot of
problems so but my goal of this document
is to lay out these various options we
have and if any folks you are trying to
do this and you have any problems and if
you have any inputs you can feel free to
contact me next slide and so I just go
back and just to two options we have is
we all know RFC pi/3 0 at the moment you
say ipv6 is s people think about RFC pi
3 0 8 I see some of the tarts for
example DC and or a draft when about
talking about ipv6 they mentioned this
draft but I'm not clear what they want
to serve both ipv4 or v6 this case is a
single topology mode so you compute one
SPF and one decision process you don't
you end up with both v4 and v6 that is a
key point here and the second thing is
RFC Phi 1 to 0 it is a multi topology it
has a TTL be 22 and through to 35 to 37
it is part of all
decision process and you come up with
the routing cable so but MPI d2 is
called ipv6 routing topology so that's
source of confusion which I understand
from a lot of people so so so the if you
if you are seeking to use five 3:08
so you have to think about network
congruence if you are only ipv6 you are
now going to touch before it's fine you
go go ahead go it with Phi Phi zero
eight no issues but if you are
transitioning you have to be very
careful one simple example I showed here
is you have a network with all links v4
v6 a except one link which is v4 between
rx to RT you have it since he formed so
packet will be the shortest path tree
will go to r2 using that link but
unfortunately there is no v6 you get
traffic black hole there despite there
is an alternate path RX r one r yr -
that's not going to be used because the
shortest path it is rx 2 R 2 so this is
the this is the black hole issue and
that the ways to fix this is only two
ways one is either you enable v6 there
are removed to empty because debugging
this kind of problems extremely
difficult in the big networks so the
main source of confusion here is it's a
topology our address family that's the
main source of confusion the terminology
is used is very confusing MT ID 2 is
called reservoir size topology maybe
it's a renters family I don't know so
but but say for example when you want
ipv6 only it's better safe to use I use
MT ID to multi topology then people say
I don't want multi topology I want
single topology I want ipv6 only but yes
you still have to use MT ID to multi
topology because if you ever use ipv4
you get into trouble that's the problem
next like this you mean if you ever use
ipv4 only if if you if you start yeah
correct
so I don't know I if we can do anything
protocol wise we can do anything to
mitigate this confusion but I thought to
put this a document so that that
conversation can be easier
so people suggested me to put in the v6
ops because a lot of v6 only stuff is
happening there there's issues there how
to deal with it there's an operational
issue so I just seek your suggestions if
you have any comments or solutions work
this you this is this is this is a
well-known limitation of the protocol
goes all the way back to RFC 1195 okay
there's nothing new here you know if you
look at Mt you'll recognize that there
is no limitation on an arbitrary
topology you can support whatever set of
address families you want
5120 did reserved particular values for
specific use cases so you said you said
aunt s family but it's called topology
there I'm saying a given topology can be
used for as many address families as you
want what we did in 50 50 120 or what
Tony did rather his he said these these
particular values are reserved for
specific use cases it places no
restrictions if I want to use mt ID 10
and i want to run v4 and v6 with some
constraints or what-have-you
it's perfectly legal to do so I'm saying
write a zero it can also be used for v6
that's one of the my point of this
you're absolutely correction yeah yeah
yeah that's why I say this is well-known
oh man loved a lot of folks but a lot of
folks don't know it I can gather I can I
could I'm willing to from a deployment
standpoint people don't fully understand
this always I'm just saying this was it
was clearly stated in 1195 there have
been proposals in the past
philip christian wrote a draft many
years ago to support tunnelling between
different address families never got a
lot of support but this has been talked
about a lot okay thank you michael
Abramson's so there is a mechanism
and I believe that if I forget to
configure ipv4 addresses on on a link
and bring up is is it won't use it for
ipv4 right so okay so so if I can if I
have an ISI as adjacency and I have no
IDE for or or ipv6 addresses on the
interface it's not gonna use the link
right right so can we do the same that
if you have multi topology and you have
two topologies you need both v4 and v6
addresses otherwise no okay no we don't
want to limit it definitely make we
don't want to require ipv4 the goal is
to be able to go only ipv6 I have a
question for you do you think you know
you know we I know a lot of people who
have lived if I Esaias all their lives
you deployed it do you think this draft
is useful you're talking to me I'm
talking to you i okay I've not read the
draft but okay but I think what I've
seen so far this seems very useful
because I'm sure that people are going
to run at this problem and yeah this is
a this is poorly understood people have
like I know I I do this and then it may
make it go and this could probably help
is this is this what I was hearing from
your presentation was that this was
maybe useful cross area or crossed like
in other words outside of routing to do
some v6 ops it's not right is it
people don't understand they're less has
convinced everyone knows Tony pj / yeah
Mia culpa Zhou was deadband against
putting reserved topology values right
and it was the sales pitch and
operational issue right if everybody has
to choose the same topology it's harder
than he was say in the draft you know
this is the use case we should have
probably call it the v6 transition
topology or something or maybe have put
something in the draft which seemed
utterly obvious
to us that the topology concept is
completely orthogonal to address family
concept no published 51:20 whatever it
was with addendum okay point I'd rather
than slap another draft that people
won't find because it's completely
decoupled okay just reissue this bloody
fingers at 20 bits and put this not not
not nice okay about the best I can say
thank you to reiterate and umas points
this draft is not meant for implementers
of SS it meant for consumers and we
spent quite some time with on my
building this is another company there's
so much misunderstanding so many errors
so it's really to explain people what it
is what they should do and I believe
there's a lot of misunderstanding
outside of this room how to use it this
is intense pure informational it is so
it would be kind of like writing a paper
in a magazine saying this is how you
deploy v6 in your network and I don't
actually see there being a problem with
this is sort of communal Kings working
group and it's similar these things get
lost people don't find the links region
and addendum especially because the not
multi topologies no beer sub domain
coupled as well right so in the sense
you have more use cases right but on
addendum and I mean I'm sympathetic to
this because the point is he's trying to
say if you're gonna hey you want to
deploy a v6 Network if that's in the
title I mean multi topology that you
know okay you know should I go look at
the appendix of multi departed I get
there yeah Chris point taken okay thanks
yeah yeah so I just make the I'm
sympathetic to the deployment okay but
people can get confused and it may well
be value in writing deployment guide
sort of thing but this problem is very
clearly discussed in RFC 1195
okay from 1992 whenever it was published
okay
would also make the comment that well if
we had thought about maltese apology
back in 1988 maybe the first version of
ISS would have had it we wouldn't have
had two different TLV types mm-hmm but
of course you know we didn't anticipate
that
so Michael Abramson again I think for
you you have to write different kind of
document for operational people who
don't know the bit in nanosecond of the
protocol so I think we should have these
kind of documents to tell you okay here
are the bombs don't step on them okay
don't do that and don't do that because
it doesn't work and you can't it you
can't get that from just reading
protocols but yes you can but people
don't get it because if you just read
you don't get the pitfalls from from
reading the protocols back you want
operational very clear things you know
five pages or something you know don't
do this best common practice away okay
we're out of time thank you
so Bouchard come on we've been doing
kyun tutorials and routing year after
year after year we go out to write nano
can people just how do you use it so
it's good to have a reference point
saying look this is what you read the
plate what she did okay this drafter is
it's not it after just nap date of the
preferred path routing that I present at
last IETF so the summary of what's been
happening last few months and I just
want to you know just give an update to
the team next slide
okay so what is this so this is a new
path routing mechanism and I I GP it
chooses the shortest path routing it
gives the same as PF but the value it
brings is it label stack Direction the
first value it brings in the label text
label stack reduction NS are the
extensions for discussed in is applied
draft because draft is getting bloated
up it's 20 pages then you know we put
two drafts up tightly because SPF
contents was per V 2 V 3 so many
encoding so we split it up two documents
there it covers the core protocol
extensions the PPR ID that's a
forwarding identifier and the path
descriptions of the LV and the
attributes optional attributes that's
the key key for this the the same
extension and also it also includes the
SPF changes required the small change
required at the end of this F for
installing the forwarding entry to get
the pen together dip into the parent get
the next segment next hop and install
the PPR ID and it also allows you to get
the path concept this is free om
transparent OEM because as and when you
remove the segment from the SR you don't
have the notion of the path so it's free
you don't have to put extra labels you
don't have to put MPLS special labels to
give the path motion next slide please
so why do we knew this yes so this I
touch base last year last idea but again
I'll and summarize here the first point
is it reduced the path overhead on the
data plane you you can put everything on
the data plane everything on the packet
but there are some issues with that so
for example you have the hardware
capabilities let's take about SR the
MPLS case if you talk about multiple
labels you already have without any SR
path 6 MPLS labels on the packet you
already end up in 4-5 labels how it is
that you have VPN label interests label
most cases 2 labels and on top of it if
you're smoothly tunnel traffic to dip
into the packet into inside you need
entropy label for and the path label
eventually so for filing fortify labels
and if you have Broadcom chips I'm sorry
for that
you cannot put more labels on that but
maybe in future new chips may be
available it can do more but if if we
put services if you put everything and
if you put in ring topologies everybody
every label you have to describe it's
going to be 10 to 12 watt 15 I don't
know how many labels one needs it so MSD
fixes is this in the sense like you know
it at least for the controller it will
help you to understand okay don't use
this part because I have a small router
here it cannot read these many labels so
it can avoid that path temptation so it
is a constraint on the PCE but it cannot
give the alternate path which is giving
the similar traffic characteristics you
are seeking to start with it also once
you reduce a packet overhead you
obviously get the line rate there are
line rate issues otherwise some
hardware's cannot do line rate if you
put large overhead it in the packet and
for a service 6 case it avoids
fragmentation it's a serious problem and
you hit this fragmentation issue it
should be seriously will be in trouble
and the last thing for the lot of Phi G
use cases em IOT and you are ll see
packet sizes are small it's 40 bytes 30
to 50 bytes packets you cannot put a
header tax of 200 vice 100 bytes for the
packets for that environment it is
sensitive for some environments it's not
sensitive yes if it is environment it
sends to then too much packet overhead
is a problem so it also simplifies so
a.m. it extends the data planes you can
you add more data planes and also it
unique fast gyro it can be done with
this next slide please so a lot of
people asked for the how it is backward
compatible or how it works with SR I
says it's complementary it's it's a
complementary control in work it works
great with a sir it's an optional
feature if you want to use for SR MPLS
and SH you can reduce the stack size and
you don't have to use it and if you have
to do network programmability and if you
want to do a extension it a lot of stuff
there you can go ahead and do it but if
you are using only for the path
information if you want to compress that
you can use this optional feature it
works there
fully backward-compatible next slide
please so there was a question on the
scalability there will be millions of
paths see how thousand no network
thousand links you have four million
part and paths so theoretically yes
there will be millions of flows not
millions of paths
there will be a few thousand parts in
some in some environment even lesser so
it is simply scale is PPR path road is a
scale number of routes a number of
routes into the IGP so you don't have to
scale the answer is yes you don't have
to scale yes there are possibly
theoretical possible but you don't have
to skin that much so the only thing is
we are looking for is how we can reduce
the global srgb usage the seats are
premium because global seats are very
few so that can be optimized so with
this we could introduce the new draft
the draft draft I'll talk about it next
slide so basically what we are doing is
in this instead of a linear path we call
this as a branch so we introduce two
bits one is source and destination so
for example PDE one is a source ingress
v pd v is digress PA so if you are
crafting a path PD on PD two you
describe the path but if you just put
add two bits like for example PDE one is
a source in the figure PD three is a
source two and the Green was the
destinations so four paths can be
compressed into one for example PD one
from source if for each source expanded
to each destination so every destination
should contain a forwarding entry so the
forwarding entry can be established so
simple with simple bits you can extend
it to you can compress it and if you
don't want to mean a scale you don't
have to use this but you know it's a
simple feature it can use it and also
you can the same concept can be extended
to build the graph and this will even
further compresses it is that the
details are in the draft so the use
cases we are looking at is actually low
latency use cases so low latent low and
deterministic latency use cases lot of
use cases the verticals these use cases
and requirements are covered in the HC
working group and GP working group this
was sponsored by water phone BT and BASF
folks and this has a lot of use cases
white is required and we
it is applicable why the stack size is a
problem next slide please
and there were questions on what is the
relation with the Phi G DM M working
group work and this work so I presented
the first draft DM empty a transport
aware mobility in ietf one or two in DM
and working group so what it lays out is
in the Phi G how mobility can be
achieved with the awareness of the
transport network in the Phi G lot of
small says new mobility scenarios are
coming up and with the new online
interface
so when mobility sessions are taking
care taken you need to account for the
transport path characteristics too if
the path is available or not so that is
one piece and also there are other other
work going on in the DMM to remove gtp
in the mobile core how SR v6 and
programmability can help there that's a
separate work completely orthogonal this
proposal assume say overlay and it's an
underling mechanism and it doesn't
doesn't try to remove gtp or something
like that so so in comparison test
service it's a different work and it can
work with SR v6 and the gtp replacement
there are a bunch of options they're
being discussed in DMM including lists
ila s or v6 there's so many proposals
for all these proposals if you use PPR
it can hit you reduce the stack size
that's so this still ongoing work it has
just started a few months back we are
still improving the drafts and you know
we are fixing some of the problems we
found and if you have interest on this
on this work please contact me and if
you have questions I will be happy to
help you answer so
I don't know where to start I think you
you listed problems that you're trying
to solve are not the problems so the
problem that you listed your line by
line are not the problems so I think
you're looking to retrofit your solution
into something that doesn't exist okay
the problem that isn't it you're looking
for a problem to fit your solution and I
think it's a reverse engineering can you
go back to your slide number three
please so I don't you've got a long
piece of paper there were sort of the
are behind I know I keep it short so I
mean you less the frenzy the traffic
counting there is a solution for traffic
counting without getting any additional
label at all okay and and how is that
that is you read my draft but I saw that
I'm asking okay so you're doing a matrix
so the problem the problem with that is
you will hit into if FRR happens you you
will you will mess up with your
accounting be careful with that if you
promise SLS you need to prove it
that is the debit discussion but it
doesn't it doesn't matter if the
accounting remains good and and I can
prove you this okay
Oh nm you're introducing additional
states in the network or additional
program in additional rewrites in the
network or whenever is going to be more
complex so you you think is simplifying
it not simplifying it's adding more you
you whenever you bring something you
keep saying simple simple simple but by
the time you're done with it is I didn't
I didn't say simple it fixes this
problem it's simple or not it depends on
person who is seeing it right so for the
network state we discussed this part
it's a binding sate bindings it also
adds network state it's a free country
if you let's remove all the fitment race
if you thin a routing and you call you
yeah I mean let you drop a scaling of
set it's all by binding city here in the
is I will take content allowed
Curtis is our next presenter so I do oh
why don't you initiate a discussion of
this on the ILS Arles
okay hello everyone I'm going to present
this OSPF extension for the prefix
originator actually in okay actually my
last ITM meeting we present another
draft about the inter area topology
retrieval and in that draft the sells a
prefix sells router IP is considered as
a general useful thing so this time we
modify the draft add more use cases
about this ID and here this is a new
draft okay we'll go through the use
cases for this new TLV the first use
cases are the we can use this mechanism
to retrieve all the entropy label
capability or the MST information of the
South's router which is in another area
because when the OSPF is our Traverse
across the multiple different areas the
source relative information will be
disappeared so when the ingress errors
our need to know the information about
the entropy label capability autumn as
the information of a particular prefix
he needs this TLV a new house router ID
tre to get this information before it
can encapsulate the appropriate label
stacks to the packet okay there's also
other possible use cases which is we can
also consider to use this mechanism to
collapse the inter area topology from
the Sdn controller this is because in
some situations the controller may only
have the PGP RS sessions with only one
or two routers in the backbone area
in this case it means mechanism to
collect an arm retrieve out a topology
of the other areas in a GP domain so you
see kiss-kiss this theory can also help
and this will has some limitations and
this has been described in the appendix
okay here are the TLB format which is
very straightforward
we need a new sub heavy to carry the
prefix thousand router ID and for OS
version - let's be tre will be carried
in the hospital version - extended
prefix opaque RSA and for SPF version
three it will be carried in the II inter
area prefix RC very straightforward oh
here's a procedure of the operation
basically when the ABR received the
router IOC in one in one area it will
need to generate the corresponding some
races and with this news subtly added to
the extended our sales and then it will
add word hi this summary carry to the
other areas in the on the receiver side
the routers in other areas who you need
to obtain this into a social I'll try
the information for different use cases
as described in the beginning of this
presentation okay I think this is a very
straightforward extensions a selenium
you are speaking as we had a lot of
offline discussions of this and the
changes were that we removed the there
were different encodings and there were
some non backward compatible component
encoding using the existing assays those
are removed and we only kept the OSPF v2
extended LSA and notice we have v3
not extended those we have v2 pre linked
at
buuuut let's say no yeah Kenzi for less
generation no prefix it prefix
attributed Ellis state that's why might
say and for those 53 we use just the
extended Ellis ace we took the non
backward-compatible once out of there
and then we moved the butchers name soon
yeah yeah I didn't butcher it alright
okay soon I had a use case that he
wanted to use and it wasn't it didn't
work for all cases it only worked if you
had all numbered links and there was
some so we didn't want that to be
normative so we moved it to an appendix
those are the major changes yes Justin
Sarah so himself works here the thoughts
about it with regard to use cases
usually around abilities are not meant
to be propagated across areas they're
there and that's why we G pls work to
get them up to the controllers at Bill's
full multi area multi level graph so
specifically for that reason we usually
deploy pair of BGP other speakers per
area level not per network so I would
really change the use case yeah that is
uh and that's why we pull this use case
into the appendix yeah some of us would
have preferred to see it removed after
the long protracted discussion on it but
my compromise was appendix so we might
be discussing this one a little more on
the list in if we can because I think
everybody agrees the tlvs are needed
because therein is is right now the same
thing the inter area propagation of the
source a router and I'm not sure
everything that's used for but I think I
think it's a good idea and you have a
BGP LS raft as well right there is a
debate did the BGP OS craft get adopted
yeah that is a different one
no but yeah I know but did it get
adopted yeah I think so it did okay yeah
so that so now we have it nice is it's
been adopted in BGP so I think we're
gonna
look for adoption here as well I might
not need to be an offer but okay I ended
up one based on our all our offline
discussions okay I guess we're done
thanks everybody sorry for all the
problems with the Chromebook I think
there's a couple things we've learned
that well the one thing the reef I think
we figured out that the reason we
couldn't find those some of those
presentations was those are the ones
that were in PowerPoint and those do not
show up on the agenda page you have to
go to meeting materials and also if you
don't convert the PowerPoint PDF it
makes it very hard to step through it
using the Chromebook yeah so I guess
from now on if you're writing a
presentation put it in PDF yes all right
thanks everyone
I'm watching you oh yeah
you