[Music]
rich it's falling and trying to get it
to work we'll keep playing with it but
if you write it's 9 this is the net cons
working group meeting I don't see anyone
exiting the room so I guess you're in
the right room then let's get started
with the meeting itself
right here's the note well if you
haven't read it before of course and you
can read it right now on the screen just
to be sure that you're aware of the fact
that any thing you say or do in this
group is a contribution to ITF we have
couple of people who have volunteered to
be on jabber but if you know how to run
jabber would appreciate your taking seat
near the mic so you can watch the jabber
room for any comments or questions while
you're up here use the box around the
mic and stay in there while you're
speaking the blue sheets have been
handed out I see on this side it's
sitting on the front row so someone if
can pick that up and pass it down that
aisle we also have etherpad up on this
linkage if you want to quickly take a
look at it and paste it into your
browser either bad tools that idea that
are slash notes / - ITF - 103 - Netcom
I'll give you guys a few seconds if you
want to bring up the ether pad we would
appreciate you adding comments or
Corrections into the ether pad as you
see people speaking will use the minutes
recorded in the user pad and of course
validate them with the audio stream or
any actions that are taken in the
working group before you proceed in full
disclosure I did want to let the
workgroup now that I've had a change in
corporate affiliation I am now working
for VMware
just so you know okay so just going over
the status of current chartered working
group items the zero district of course
is left the working group it's been
submitted for isg publication not sure
what the current status I think it's
been there for a month now did you want
to add in any update to this thickness
thickness bonus zero touch document will
proceed quite soon the next upcoming
telecheck is already full so that will
be beginning of December when that goes
into that so from a review perspective
there are few needs but nothing serious
great thank you them now and then
there's the yang pushed suite of drafts
there's for them yang push subscribe
notifications Netcom event notifications
and rest cough notif all of these drafts
have just completed their last calls and
for the most part waiting for shepard
right up we are of course there's the
closing the window the submission
deadline window which has just reopened
and some final dotting of the i's and
crossing the t's hey to occur but for
the most part they're moving out of the
working group to Shepherd right up state
and I I it will be the designee
designated Shepherd unless someone else
would like to volunteer to be Shepherd
the only reason that you that someone
wouldn't maybe like to do this would be
because for myself
it probably incur some delay I won't be
able to get to it until mid-december
possibly early January if it were to be
myself I took Nostradamus again so I
would really encourage somebody from a
working group stepping up into that and
probably we can have couple of shepherds
this is because the documents seem to be
mostly ready and it's understandable
that you have many things on your plate
so we might even have some with you who
is rather new to this process and kind
of try to train them into that so if
somebody is interested in that
please please raise please you put your
name forward yeah reach out to the
chairs or even Ignis great ed shares I
think is probably appropriate reach out
come we send us an email next there's
the Netcom restaurant client-server
suite of drafts these are still works
and progress we'll be discussing them
today okay and then also there's a you
to keep up channel also a working group
document then there's the yang push
notification capabilities draft and also
another draft notification headers and
bundles draft both of these are works in
progress but neither are being presented
today primarily because the authors are
the same authors working on the yang
push set of drafts and they wanted to
focus their attention on those drafts
rather than these other working group
documents okay from the agenda
perspective first they'll be the prison
presenting presentation of the
client-server drafts followed by the
gang push set of drafts followed by the
you to be public pub/sub draft and then
a couple non-cluttered drafts which
would be subscription to multiple stream
or originators and the in line action
capability for Netcom and then other
area business I should say that we have
plenty of time this schedule I think
with two hours on the schedule but from
the amount of time that the authors were
requesting we may have 50 minutes
remaining so lots of time for discussion
and if anyone else wants to you know to
bring up something that's not on the
agenda there's plenty of time for that
as well
okay hi Kent presenting the
client-server graphs since I 102 in
Montreal all the drafts were updated and
submitted at a set twice most of the
issues that we discuss in Montreal have
now been resolved and a few extra issues
were made as well there are two
remaining issues from that we discussed
in ITF one or two one being wanted with
that which was called should algorithm
identities be moved from the IETF SSH
client TLS common crypto type modules
sorry modules to the crypto type module
and the other being add how do we add
support for TCP Q lives so this
presentation only focuses on those two
issues as a quick recap the there is a
set of drafts
and relationship between the drafts as
it is on a screen I showed this last
time as well the only new thing is the
lines that are in purple because if we
call one of the issues where should we
move some of the groupings that were in
the keystore module to the crypto type
modules so those movie those groupings
got moved and so those purple lines are
just representing the using of those
groupings from the SSH and TLS
client-server graphs to the crypto type
draft all right so first we'll just
begin discussing the first item you know
should algorithm identities be moved
from the SSH TLS common module to the
crypto types module for this issue you
might recall we reached out to sag in
the security group several times
requesting health cryptology experts to
help us with this particular item and
last time we were fortunate enough to
have some
individuals from Huawei volunteer to
help us with this so I spent the last
two or three months probably engaging
with Frank and how long from Huawei and
actually I'd like to turn it over now to
Frank to present this particular update
how we're doing in this issue and I
should mention Frank is now a co-author
under strap
hello everyone his friends are from
Hawaii and I think he's we're happy to
work with Kanda we can we can proceed at
least this series of draft follows that
so I try to give a very quick deduction
although this time what we have done on
these drafts in general we have updated
a freak so from my side I have updated
as recharge the the basic way is the
crypto type straps it includes several
categories of the basic oh cripton great
accordance and between used for other
applications for infinite comp country
we used we apply the physical a Korean
on the net console based on the SSH and
the net net convict or TRS okay so this
has a street rafter we are updated we
are updated okay so so firstly the
crypto type traps like I just mentioned
we we reference a lot of existing and
very widely used applications such as
IPSec and a key version 2 and the T is
1.2 pantry and ssh we do our sorrow
story and analysis of this draft and
abstract of the widely used crypto
evidence and also very important they
are also very safe safe algorithms and
we try to divide them into six
categories so there you can see Oh
okay you can see the first one is hush
Aryan okay the second is the symmetric
second symmetric encryption algorithm
and the Mac algorithm and the asymmetric
encryption algorithm and the signature
and the key keeps changing okie
negotiation so our basic idea is that we
want these categories to be atomic and
cover most also widely used basic
algorithm and then can combine together
where is really for not only from that
conf we think that in future they can
also be used by other applications so so
you can you can go you can look at our
our tracks for the detailed definition
of the every algorithms identifier in
each each category okay and okay and
that's all for the crypto types but of
course this time we still have some
problems they need to need to be solved
okay the first one is we already have
the six categories of basical crypto
evidence but but for how to defy
identify a public key pair and the
certificate how to define there they are
ever even type for the public key pair
and an eSATA Kate usually it should be a
combination of equip ssin and the
signature right like what we always say
the I say Michael didn't or the ECC so
but can read you can see we already
divided the other algorithm into very
very atomic very specific or categories
so so I say it's not it should be as it
should be a combination of the some of
the basic algorithm so we are still not
not decided that sorry
we haven't decided how to how to
represent the public keep here algorithm
or the certification arisen of course
there are two way Rama is a fine great
way we can use our existing everything
combined into the present I say or if
you see other way maybe we can just very
simply to the predator so I think this
is a problem we still need to solve in
the future version so if you can help us
we are working okay and after finish you
the crypto types and then we we walked
up based on those crypto types and and
and those crypto types provided the
definition of the possible used
algorithms by the visor that comes over
SSH so so the left of question for us is
that we already have got some key from
the from the crypto types definition and
we also need to define the algorithm we
used for the Netcom for over SSH so
there should be some compatibility
relationship between the between the
Kiwi we used from the crypto types and
the definition we defined here in the SH
or in the in the in that comes over SH
just so to the Christ to clarify this
relationship we add some tables to to
justify what if the writer mapping what
is yeah what is a great matting the left
isn't the draw imagine okay so you can
see that this mappings are aware is a
very straight forward actually the left
of the left side is crypto types we we
use the on the key and the right side is
that we what we have defied in the in
the SH configuration so they should have
be compatible so kind
very easily because we because uh you
can you can you can see that the s that
comes always says configuration
configure every atomic algorithms on its
configuration so there's a one-to-one
mapping between the basic core crypto
types to the current SSH configuration
so this is a very simple example we have
for compatibility tables this is about
the Mac symmetric encryption and the
cheeks changer and the hash area and
signature okay so they are all the
netting they should be compatible with
each other
so following the same idea for the that
comes over here is there should appear
this kind of capability existed here so
we also do the analysis on the TRS 1.2
and the TRS 1.3 and also we looked over
all the tos and a page it's everything
and a page so we know that for TRS 1.2
the cipher the year here at Stifel feels
it's a most important part it includes
all the all the cryptographic mechanism
which is used over TLS 1.2 and the
fourth tears went off three there are
three categories of Crick grad
pre-classical acquittance fault for it
which is tra ciphers used here as
signature scheme and tears upon groups
so based on this survey we decide that
okay we choose all these three
categories for post the key is 1.2 and
1.3 but what is 1.2 only the fourth one
or which is the ti-84 suits can is
useful for constructor the competitive
mapping between the key and the key is
the configuration ok so also for in a
same way with the filer way we define
the
humidity a community mapping table
independently 40 eyes 1.2 and the tea is
one two three so the reason why we have
so many tables here is that because you
know kinda ITF chapter has the
limitation of the 80 or 82 right 82
characters in one line so so because you
can see the our our psychosis is too
long or too long stream so we we can
only divide the every mapping into a
table so there are five tables for each
category right
the for example this is the hash and the
and the signe and the signature evidence
it's just a two examples also we have
the equation we have the key exchange
imagine okay this is 42 and this is 40
are three also they have the we have the
PSI for a sting mapping and and the key
exchange a mapping and other meetings in
summary we want to we want to we want to
we want to give our capability mapping
between the key and the configuration of
the of our net count client or soul so
yes I think yeah that's all yeah yeah
just going back
sorry about that
good thing we have plenty of time on our
schedule okay right so back to this
you'll see the back button works it's no
good so the question was should
algorithm identities be moved from the
ITF as safety less common modules to the
crypto technological the answer is no
we're going to leave them there those
identities are going to be defined both
in the SSH AMT last crypto type modules
as well as in the crypto types module
and we've created these compatibility
matrix matrices that are existing in the
Association TLS modules to allow for the
mappings to be to be performed and
currently those matrices are only
implemented in texts there's not a yang
module level definition of these
mappings
we're actually undecided as to if it's
even possible to create yang level
mappings how would we do it maybe some
very complex musts expressions but it's
unclear how would we done but
fundamentally the most important thing
is in the texts that it says clearly
what the requirements are so that module
implementers can you know appropriately
implement the requirements if the client
submits configuration with edit
configure or yang patch then the server
can determine whether or not an
acceptable pairing has been provided and
provide the error if not so that's the
fundamental approach that we're taking
with this and I think on in addition to
solving this question that way were also
using the opportunity to expand the
amount and number of algorithms being to
the cryptid types module to be complete
a complete set of identities for all
cryptographic purposes would you say
that's first Nathan is that ferris yeah
yeah okay there is interest in from
other working groups to have other
modules depending on the crypto types
module with this expanded set of
algorithms and so that's where that's
primarily coming from but general
generally a good idea any comments or
questions regarding the this direction
that we're taking solving this problem
okay thank you
alright so now we'll move to the next
question that's being worked on which is
adding support for TCP key beliefs last
time we discussed how discussions with
the transport area folks concluded that
there is a need for people lives at
every protocol layer at the TCP layer at
the association layer TOS layer even NAT
Conklin rest cough layers if you wish to
test for the aliveness of the
application at her layer aliveness of
lower layers or testing for the
aliveness at lower layers really says
nothing about the aliveness of at the
higher layers so there's one reason for
why you may want to do both and
similarly aliveness checks at an upper
layer should not preclude the aliveness
checks at lower layers and I think here
Tim Carey was mentioning how you made
there be like a degradation where some
of the upper layer protocol has been
corrupted or disabled but you can come
down and at least do TCP keeper lives
and see whether or not it's it's up at
that level so the question that we're
stuck on currently is how to configure
the keep allows at the various layers we
have not discussed this really at all on
list
since Montreal so here we are talking
about it okay so I have an idea but you
may not like it that's my disclaimer
independent of this discussion for a few
months now I've been aware of gaps in
our current solution specifically that
we're missing the dependent or some
dependent protocol layers you know TCP
HTTP and HTTPS I withheld raising this
to the working group because I
envisioned much I rolling and general
exasperation but now it seems like the
time has come to broach this topic so
I'm proposing a draft restructuring of
sorts specifically adding in the missing
TCP HTTP and HTTPS client-server layers
recall at the very beginning of this
presentation I showed you a picture of
the draft current draft relationships so
in the light gray in the background is
that picture though parts of that
picture are in black so the ssh client
server and teals client server or the
restaurant client server were were in
that other picture as well but new in
red green and blue are the proposed
potentially new drafts last modules that
we could add to complete the picture all
right so that's the idea what are the
benefits
well first factoring out these dependent
layers would provide a basis for future
protocol models surely there will be
more TCP based models that folks in the
IDF will want to define so actually
defining that IDF layer would provide a
placeholder for over them to make that
extension
similarly surely there will be more HTTP
based models and HTTP based models and
so factoring them out would be sort of
goodwill to the community at large but
that's not how we got into this
discussion we really are here to talk
about keep a lives so back
that issue distinct layers would enable
the kippah lives to be configured at
each layer the configuration of TCP key
believes could be defined at the TCP
client-server models the configuration
of the SSH keep lives to be defined in
the s8 client-server models and so on
right so then we'd have each distinct
layer would have the configuration for
how to configure the keep allows for
that layer within its own model and
hence the issue that I mentioned before
that we got stuck on how when we go back
actually how to configure the keepalive
the various layers falls out naturally
and so that's the idea and the question
to the working group is whether or not
people think we should do this or any
other questions around what it wouldn't
take to do it in terms of timing and
effort anybody comments questions
Michael Abrams I just want to say I like
that we're not discussing if we should
be able to set keep lives because I want
to be able to configure it at all layer
so fully support the effort and then
exactly how to do it I don't have a
strong opinion but this seems good to me
so far
Jason Stern AB I just trying to
understand the the concept of having it
like turn on keepalive and TCP layer is
on a on a server you're gonna turn on
globally and then it's gonna have keep
lives for every TCP session or or are
you saying that every TCP session that's
using --neck --neck comp if the
granularity of the control you're
looking at well it'd be in a
configuration data model and these all
these are really groupings so whatever
you're grouping stack is in in the case
of Netcom for instance it's using let's
just pretend it's using the ssh client
server grouping which itself had we used
the TCP client TCP client-server
grouping so you would inherit some
keepalive configuration for the TCP keep
alive from that grouping and then
likewise
some ssh keepalive configuration from
that grouping and if ever we get around
to it some neck off level keep alive
from that grouping and it would only
apply to that particular configured
stack okay so that's not a combination
so you'd be turning on TCP keep lives
for this net comp session correct and
not not for the entire operating system
yeah okay thanks so this is Tim Kari
Nokia I will say I think you know the
approach that to having keep a lives at
every layer and makes sense because
again last time we talked about it it's
needed for that piece of it to answer
you know Jason's question as well as is
that indeed this is within the context
of the net comp session you know from
the TCP that supports the next comp
session but I will say that as we were
doing this for for some of the stuff
within the broadband forum work that
some of the implementations are that
when you turn this on you touch those
TCP q4 lives it's actually for all the
sessions that there's some limitations
and some of the implementations not that
the the approach still should be the con
the context should be the Netcom session
but sometimes the implementation says
that the only the only thing that you
can twiddle the bit that you can twiddle
is on me all the all the sessions just
on some of the implementations so the
refactoring might concern what the
refactoring is we've got modules coming
up I mean there's just a ton of modules
and I just and I get what you're doing I
just man I don't know you know I'm
saying it's just there's just a lot of
modules now if you're gonna do if every
every layer so I'm just wondering if the
organization and housekeeping gets
beyond you know the the benefit if the
work becomes more better than the
benefit right and and that's what i
meant by anticipating exasperation i
somewhat worn out the welcome here in
terms of the refactorings we've done and
i get it but i also see this as being
the best way to solve this problem and
we really we anyway Michael Abramson
again so us there is a bit like in Linux
there is a knob tutorials on this
and wide so you could test that and see
would whatever you come up with for TCP
here fit into IETF system for instance
or you know would it make sense there as
well as like a test of is this module
generic enough and if it is I would say
yes displayed it out because I might
want to support this or that assistant
level as default settings for also and
also just on the net called server
sessions and so that the net con server
would use the socket option to turn this
on for just its sessions and I would
also like in ITF systems model you know
setting for the entire system both so so
we could your ear in support of this and
also modifying IETF system potentially
I'm saying at least spend 10 minutes on
seeing is the the way you do the TCP
part is that generic enough that it
would be able to fit into a native
system and if I would support an effort
to do that for ITF system as well
because as far as I know there is an
system-wide settings and at least some
operating systems to turn TCP keep
relies on by default okay okay well look
into it
so just to speak a little bit to what's
been said the okay so first off let me
on this slide it said net cough keeper
lives could be defined at the neck
client server models layer so remember
last time we discussed how would we go
about doing that keep lives for
restaurant keep lives we kind of
concluded it'd be hard to do I mean the
neck off our PC model and the
notifications and especially when you
take into account call home actually
figuring out how to do that so it's
really TBD and I don't actually suggest
this effort should try to introduce
Netcom for restaurant level keeper lives
it's just a placeholder for if ever this
working group wanted to define Netcom
press comma keeper lives could such
people iOS be fit into the model at that
future date
similarly oh wow I don't put TBD there
there is such thing as HTTP keep it
lives but they're really for HP 1.0 and
1.1 they
it was by default she didn't have to
configure it it was just by default and
http2 inherited that behavior as well
but but also there's kind of a misnomer
in that HTTP when they talk about
keeping lives they don't really mean
keep a lives such as like actively
testing the aliveness of the remote
system as they do a hint that's being
propagated to the server to not close
the connection within 10 seconds it's
more like keep keep the underlying
transport open so with their religious
that with a really balanced so I think
HDPE keep lives is also effectively a
TBD not yet defined and this effort
would not intend to actually define how
configuration for HP keep lives truly
it's just the TCP association TLS where
we would want to configure this and back
to the picture so already we have the
keeper lives in the current models that
keeper lives are being defined at the
Netcom client server and the restaurant
client server so we effectively move
that configuration from the Netcom press
conf layers into the association TLS
layers as well as into the TCP layer TCP
all right so this kind of goes to the
scope of the effort we really didn't
would want to factor out TCP client
server it's it's like primarily what
we're talking how we got into this
discussion is because Nokia observed
that the open SSL doesn't implement
today TOS level keep lives there's an
RFC for they don't implement it yet
there's a discussion about that they
should implement it but it's still not
implemented yet and they meanwhile they
have to do TCP keep lives so so we
really need that TCP layer and
configuration of TCP keep lives do we
need to have HTTP client server at all
and you know similarly HTTP client
server at all I mean as the IETF goes we
generally are shunning non secure
protocols so maybe we don't bother with
HTTP clients are going to the comment
made about the expanding a number of
drafts so
the that green light green drafts the HQ
client/server is one that I think is the
least needed and also factoring out HTTP
from rest cough technically not needed
but you can see how it would probably be
better to factor it out there will be
other HTTP based applications and having
it factored out would be very helpful
for them as opposed to us bundling an
insight at the restaurant player so to
to that scope of the effort that there's
are there are some opportunities to
whittle this down pare it down a little
bit and maybe do less than than the full
complete solution but just want to bring
it to the workgroups attention comment
Rob Wilson Cisco so I think separation
Rogers probably makes sense but doesn't
mean SME has a separate Ross all of them
so potentially you could bundle some of
these modules together relatively small
and that may reduce some of the overhead
or process overhead here thank you and
then yeah and then just last I think to
to again to the scope of the effort I
mean in thinking about okay you know I
don't really want to take more work on
for myself here but in thinking about
the effort I would suggest that we
define minimal module right so if we
were to do TCP client-server it would
just be the minimal IP address port
number and a keepalive configuration any
other possible TCP level configurations
could be AB is some day in the future
I'm not really interested in solving
that further scope problem same for HTTP
I don't know how many configuration
parameters there might be afraid to pee
I'm not interested in figuring it out I
just want to you know have defined the
little bit that we need to define to get
this factoring out and so it'd be the
minimal effort I think at least that's
the way I'd like to approach this yes
Michael Abraham's it again um I wouldn't
I wouldn't even need it per connection
or IP or something I just need a knob
default on or default off for all
sessions early system no for world for
not conf the TSP keep alive for a net
compensation zone I would just I don't
even need that so I don't know is
someone else express the need to do this
on a per connection level I just
wouldn't want like a default set the on
and off basically that's what all that's
all of what I need is someone else needs
more than okay then we need to do more
but I'm just saying I would in a lot of
scenarios I think you just want to be
able to turn it on and off and you don't
need to set it for destination or
anything yeah understood where we would
put a global setting like that is the
question maybe ITF system but what leave
had a door opened default on and off for
the net called server for all sessions
that come in I don't need it to do it
per IP I just need to say the Netcom
server should default up tcp keepalive
on i don't need to say for this IP range
or something like that robust and cisco
so definitely support your suggestion
saying that if you do do this split out
to keep the minimal and the future they
need to be expanded that could be done
in the future revision just trying to
avoid features sorts of creeperface me
right and actually already that's the
strategy we've taken like for instance
with the cessation TLS we're really just
focusing on the minimal necessary to
configure the crypto stack so that we
can do it but if you look at various a
cessation TLS implementations there's
many more configurable options we're not
touching any of them so more the same in
that regard yes so tim carry nokia just
to make the comment from from Macau is
that you know we're using it for various
applications right so there's a TR 301
within the broadband forum that does
call home that uses TCP keeper lives and
so there's a the generic setting may or
may not work I don't know not sure it
works in that because it's on a stream
based and we've got multiple endpoints
that we have to talk to but we've also
started looking at the augmentation
because we weren't waiting what you're
gonna do right and so I think we can
work with you on on trying to figure out
you know how to get the best adaptation
possible to work in different scenarios
actually if you know people could
collaborate with me um you know it's
pretty much me doing most of this effort
but if I had some co-authors I'd truly
believe this could be done you know by
104 we would be talking about it being
done and were there any other things
that we forgotten I think probably be
going to last call around that time
frame so we're if we were to not do this
then we still have to finish up the
crypto types thing that Frank presented
and also we would still have to figure
out how to do keep lives and I don't
have an alternative proposal that's the
only proposal I have at the moment so
we'd spend some wheels I'm trying to
figure out what the alternative proposal
would be we'd be looking into February
time maybe March timeframe anyway this I
can see what we could do I don't think
the effort is huge if the co-author
could help me I do believe we could get
it done really with probably just one
more month worth of time so alright I
think there were that was all the
comments any more comments anything on
jabber okay great thank you
yeah
so hello everybody this is Alex Alex
come so I'm going to give a quick update
along with Rashad actually on this on
the sub on the speak of the subscription
drafts and as also earlier really
actually we don't have many updates for
this this should be fairly this should
be fairly short but I just take my time
sure okay alright so basically again
there are a whole lot of drafts that
deal with with subscribe notification
yank push and related things what are we
talking about here are the four drafts
there from the top the ones that are
basically in working group that's called
have to have just passed all the other
drafts are basically dependent on this
work and are yeah essentially pending
until later so so for those drafts and
some of the updates here so one thing in
key to mention we had a slight name
change for each of the titles of the
drafts it just make it more clear that
they are all related and related to the
same for the same topic area so first
pro strat is the draft ITF net con
subscribe notifications and so working
group last fall's complete and it is
currently in well since since Montreal
underwent three revisions we're now in V
18 which basically have all the group
last comments addressed okay there's
been the title change was an appendix
use case be how to extend it for
additional transports been added some
minor knits like renaming the
subscription identifier to ID to make it
less verbose and that's so forth and
various of in various in a variety of
minor editorial text journal and so
forth and tweaks and those sort of
things and there's one upcoming v.19
that this I think we posted shortly
after the obvious in all that they and
that the site has been real for this and
basically there was a thread in that mod
concerning updating the description of
the x-pyr yang object definitions are we
do that as well as some text tweaks
concerning basically the modification is
eating of subscriptions as a requirement
that they need to come from the
subscriber and okay so that's that and
thank you also actually for the extent
of discussion and reviews that we
received on the comment on on this and
Asha and all of those drafts so that was
very helpful so thank you
second one is the draft IETF net conf
yang push on this one also saying same
sorry very group last call is complete
it has undergone four revisions since
last time we're now in be 20 again there
have been minor updates to the to the
text some clarifications and so forth
some very mind very very minor updates
to the yang module itself so points we
changed the names of the object that
have a sink in it to to not included age
those sorts of things we and there's a V
21 also here coming up shortly to fix
busy to very minor editing their errors
and with this other remains I'll turn it
over to Rashad so the the changes to the
net cons notifications draft also were
relatively minor similar to some of the
ones Alex presented earlier you know
title change to so that to align with
everybody else the renaming of
identifier to ID there's been a few
discussions about the examples in the
appendix e dot two and a dot 3 and
somebody I forget who it was had asked
for you know subtree and XPath filter
example so those are the changes which
went Envy 14 and then G 15 which is
supposed to go in very soon is I think
it's only a spell and fix okay rest
content occasion there's way more
significant changes there I think
because that document didn't get as much
love as the others previously again
thanks to all the comments we got from
from the people on on the alias the
first major change was removing the
configured subscriptions that was the
main topic of discussion
- OH - in Montreal so we got rid of that
so it's dynamic only now secondly the
the document was very a bit of
restaurant a bit of HTTP 1.1 a bit of
HTTP queue so there was a fair amount of
cleanup there to align with restaurant
service and events for example we used
to start the subscription we used to a
post on the URI now it's a get on the
URI to align with our C 80/40 we remove
the bunch of H if you 1.12 specifics you
see way more restaurants in the names in
the various names now than HTTP similar
to the net conf draft you know there was
filter examples added there was a
discussion on the alias past couple
weeks regarding stream XPath filter how
to do that can Jason fix a dot one exam
appendix a dot one examples we aligned
it at all
with NAT coms notification so that's
what's out there right now v09 and vita
and what should go in today there's a
spelling fix but also what was mentioned
for the subscribe notification draft we
there was various discussions about what
does if subscriber or a client mean and
there was a proposal for restaurant to
tie that to a restaurant username so
that v10 with that text should go in
today what's next so the various authors
believe we are done or nearly done based
on the workgroup
last call comments we would like I mean
there's been discussions about this many
times key before we would like those to
go to the IHG as soon as possible as the
process allows us to and once those are
done I mean the first slide Alex
presented or the second one I forget is
a bunch of other drafts which are
dependent on those ones and then
progress on those ones that's it thank
you
any comments
okay I'll just make some comments Thank
You Rashad for helping with the rest
Kampf notif drafted it wasn't one of the
original three that we had discussed but
adding it I think was good
mostly because it actually helped us
find some other issues right in the
SUBSCRIBE notifications draft so I had a
sort of a trickle cascading benefit I
think beyond just sort of enabling us to
allow Netcom from rest count to move
forward together which is a general
goodness for the working group so thank
you for that and and also to the working
group as Shepard as soon as I received
these drafts you know one of the
question is in parallel to beginning the
write-up I'll also send out an email to
the work group just asking those who had
posted comments to just review that
their actual you know their what they
were hoping to see was is there and you
know to let let me know or they let the
Shepherd know if it's not me there's
anything amiss but otherwise great thank
you thank you right
so there's Alex of just one so what
clarification so when is it busy so what
is the process specially so meeting when
is it being centralized G is it busy
once the Shepherd review is completed
the Shepherd write-up is there does it
then Messi goat is sent to the IC review
so is a busy serialize like that visits
the process yes for the most part yes
the shepherd does the writer and then
and Shepherd isn't necessarily always
the chairs but but then the write-up
occurs and then the chairs discuss
whether or not it's appropriate to
submit for publication which is
equivalent or synonymous to going to the
is G so well but it almost happens at
the same time so the Shepherd right up
the concluding of the shipwright up and
they're submitting to the publication or
to dice G happens at the same time then
what but what that really means it goes
the ad Ignace in this case where it be
ad right up and he needs to schedule or
tell a chat which he just mentioned a
moment back you know it could be a month
out it's every couple weeks but you have
to get on the calendar so it gets on
calendar and then that occurs then there
will be a number of discuss items right
so the various ihe members will have
comments all of them will ballot on your
drafts they will be discuss items you
need you will need to resolve all those
discuss items this isn't really normally
in the view of the working group it
happens off the working group list the
chairs and the shepherds who are
involved in that process but that can
take as long as it takes it and I've
seen it sometimes go quickly a couple
weeks and other times months just
depending on how it goes then that
concludes it goes to RFC editor and then
there are Sierra will look into other
issues and they'll be more back and
forth sure those everywhere and I was
busy mostly concerned about getting it
really until the in front of the is G
okay thank you alright so next
presentation I think to run
hello Iowa amateur Angela Omaha way and
firstly there are many feedbacks from
the working group what's the difference
between the Marco stream originators and
the you'd be publication channel this to
draft here is the relationship the
multiple stream originators draft is
distributed extension to the yunkish
draft and the you to be public based the
publication channel is an transport for
that can be used for both young Busha
and the multiple stream originators and
this presentation we're going to talk
about the unity based of publication
channel firstly we would write i would
like to clarify the design goal we want
to produce a new TV base the transport
for the carrier routers there are many
advantages that compelled to UDP UDP
compelled to TCP and here we list the
some we also want to support multiple
encodings including the binary and we
also want to enable options for
extensibility and want to facilitates
the distributed data export we also get
requests from lustre meeting to compare
with some existing transport here it is
firstly the IP fix is designed for the
flow information export is it do not
support mark or other encodings such as
XML zebra and GPB so on and there's no
Yankee IP fix encoding and no mechanism
for block message fragmentation and no
extension mechanism and that the other
protocol is
co-op we I think it's a it's an option
for IOT and it's designed for resource
constrained device and network it's not
for carry router the message ID is
16-bit it will result in a frequent one
not for a large amount of data when used
on carry routers this this new version
we add part on how to manage the UPC we
augments the subscriber the notification
model just like this and about now it's
only apply for the configure the
subscription we need to consider the
dynamic subscription also here's the
next step
firstly we need to consider how to
manage the dynamic subscription we may
augment to the established subscription
RPC with the transport and receiver
information this this is not to existing
in current subscribe the notification
chapter and we also need to update the
subscription model by adding the dynamic
sub screen support and adds the encoding
attributed to the receiver and we also
well aligned the document name with
other transport document so that's this
sort so that it can be clear
well what it is and is there any other
suggestions so Kent as a contributor and
so so well actually maybe first just a
general clarification statement what
we're what this draft is presenting is a
notice model so we have like neck Hoff
Noda from ruskov notice this would be
udp-based transport notice yes how we
might characterize this draft
and like with all the other Notah for
the current note of drafts they're
really just providing dynamic
subscription-only support because we
never really got around to thinking that
we would want to have configured Netcom
for restaurant subscriptions but for for
but we do want to have configured
udp-based subscriptions and that's how
this draft came to be adopted working
group supported item and also I think
having dynamics descriptions make sense
as well so that's sort of the the the
sort of the clarification of I think
where this draft is second is I think we
need to be clear that what we're
describing here is a new protocol this
would be a new binary protocol we're
calling it UDP
I'm sure we have a name for the protocol
yet you don't have a name for it then
the name is the efface the publication
channel Oh what do you think we do have
a name for the we need to call it
something um but but it is a UDP based
protocol it has a new it's defining its
own message header or etc it can contain
different encodings particular so anyway
it is a new UDP based protocol with that
work describing being defined as a notif
so then finally getting to my question
is defining a new UDP based protocol
making sense relative to making use of
an alternative existing UTP based
protocol and I know you discussed IP fix
and co-op I guess with IP fix one of the
things he mentioned was that it doesn't
support different encodings but maybe
that's okay maybe just a single encoding
would be okay for co-op you mentioned
that the message ID was only 65 thousand
and I think the concern there is that
IOT devices their rate of transmissions
would be very slow but a high-end router
could send 65,000 messages within a
single second so you would it would lead
to many issues so so but there may be
the if that's the only concern there is
maybe there's an opportunity for this
working group to approach the coop
working group to ask them if there might
be a possibility to extend that message
header you know I know I'm just
exploring ideas other ways that we might
be able to solve the general problem
which the working group wants to solve
is a udp-based notification message for
subscribe notifications but how we get
there I think I think we should still
consider the solution space some more I
think it's my comment thank you yeah hi
this is Hank working on the concise yang
telemetry draft and we are using coop
and the message ideas for detecting
duplicates so if you expect having a
duplicate in a in a 16-bit space then
you need a bigger message ID but I don't
think that is a concern
it can rewind in that scope if you don't
expect duplicates in that dimension the
association between the requests also
the subscription to the stream is the
coop token and that's eight bytes I
don't think that's the problem
so maybe message ID via sort of
misinterpret idea I think I I don't see
that it is a problem but on the other
hand you want to have this inside system
like I heard like between line cards or
in this is not leaving the the data
store system component I I have the
feeling so maybe then having a listening
server
this is best Rest for co-op server is a
little bit over too much then you can
just establish a UDP stream it depends
on the application if it has it goes
through the internet probably co-op is a
good idea if it is just for high volume
inside a system
you can basically unpack
all of the overhead tuned for Internet
Protocol it's there now not not not
being the devil's advocate at the IETF -
just to say that we don't need internet
for the courts here but but you can
strip a lot of that off I was just
explaining that IP fix just leave the
box
it's generator on the line card itself
and it goes out the box to a collector
yeah this is and this is of course
correct but I thought IP fix was used in
a different place yeah for this purpose
and therefore has a different scope of
application I think because of corn
cooing I thought it was an encoding
alternative well just add that
conversation I've also done udp-based
logging where the log receiver was on
the subnet to the to the line cards and
it would receive all the logs and then
do aggregation and compression and
deduplication and then send them over
the LAN yes oh so I think that's your
point yeah that's my point it's over
over the land you don't really have to
tag it and besides if you miss one what
would you do about it anyway even
nothing - isn't that like the routers
gonna keep okay my last comment is
anything but binary representation
doesn't make much sense inside if you're
talking about burdened by TCP state
I think being burdened by something else
as a binary is even worse so I think
it's rather obvious not to use human
readable clear text formats like JSON or
XML I think it would defeat the initial
purpose I think I have the feeling of
the concept of the block okay I should
say those requirements are from our
customers so we designed for them and
they have the requirements
here from Google I find that the whole
section of this draft to do with any
kind of reliable delivery and discussion
of how you should only really deploy
this over reliable networks is it's
under specified so our operational
experience of having tried to put
something udp-based streaming into
production is there are no reliable
delivery channels like you have bits of
your network where you can't possibly
assume that all packets are going to get
through or there's no congestion because
it's just not like even the amount of
bandwidth you can buy there is not
sufficient and the the cost of having to
assume that the channel is unreliable is
the law of periodic replication of the
data on there on the chat on the channel
so that you can deal with retransmission
or dealing with retransmission I would
go so far as to say as soon as you have
to deal with retransmission you might as
well use TCP anyway and TCP and then
because you also get the advantages of
knowing that reliably when you sent an
event it got to the other end so you can
reduce the number of times you need to
stream data so we don't think that it's
actually possible to do over an
unreliable channel event based updates
because any system then can't really
rely on it and with any kind of latency
so I think you should probably add some
discussion to your draft as to what the
cost of doing this over UDP is and
really try and figure out how
retransmission works in in this this
model especially if it actually works to
a line card which is kind of the
motivation here right because you're
assuming then that there's a cash on the
line card to have any packet within some
known window to be agreed to be
requested my suspicion and operational
experience of having a few thousand
devices that run telemetry at this point
across number of vendors is that you
will just go to TCP again as soon as you
have to deal with these problems which
are kind of the operational realities so
I don't really think we should be
pushing the industry in a way that
doesn't really work actually the
reliability is the part of the industry
after is not the real reliability as the
TCP it's a kind of partial liability
it's a trade-off to anticipate and UDP
right but the the problem is now how do
I build any kind of system that relies
the data being there so I can if I'm
trying to do anything with interface
statistics and I know that there might
be fidelity loss because I've got lost
packets I can't rely on it if there you
can't do anything event based because an
interface goes down in my network and
then you don't have any way to react to
it you don't know that the state is
there so the the natural requirement
then is that you end up building a
polling system to make sure that you
have a current enough view or to Rican
to reconcile and our scaling analysis
kind of shows as soon as you do that
you're going to end up with
significantly more data than you would
via TCP so this scalability argument
kind of falls down so we've been pushing
this entirely tcp-based can't as a
contributor don't just jump in for a
second ooh what is the motivation for
you udp-based is it the reliability or
unreal I don't think that was it I so
much as the desire to enable the line
cars to send the UDP packets having the
same source IP and port ordinary not
port but at least IP address as the
routing engine you know that they that
for the other draft that we are about to
present the multiple stream originators
so the desire for UDP is to enable that
distributed source so we've looked to
this I think that there's a there's a
model whereby you have a distributed
system that has different components
that can each have TCP right like I
think you're going to end up going that
way if you ever care about reliability
if you say this is a hundred percent
unreliable then I think you can kind of
talk yourself into this UDP model but if
you say I'm one distribution because it
gives me more scalability point to be
proven as to whether that's really
required and then you you can still do
TCP it was a lightweight TCP protocol to
the to the line cards and you're kind of
inventing a new protocol here as you
pointed out so you've got a bunch of
room to be able to design it exactly how
you want the source IP and I would just
suggest for debug ability it's kind of a
challenge if you have n producers that
are all producing with the same source
IP it's kind of like it's we have
challenges around being able to know
whether you're actually in
synchronization with that system if
you've got n different producers one
line card stops producing data and you
don't really know you've got no metric
to be able to alert on say of this
source isn't sending mutator anymore
I think we're jumping into the next
draft but I think that draft is the idea
is that the configuration model would
allow you to configure the UDP to the
system and then the system implicitly
distributes to line cards and tells each
of them you know it's implicit but if
you do were to do TCP you'd have to be
explicit the configuration model would
actually have to configure we use this
IP address for that line curtain for
each language
yeah I'm suggesting a bit of
configuration pain is better for the
overall system thank you hi this is Hank
again if you are expecting to have
congestions you will have UDP Datagram
loss I mean apparently so so that that's
a fundamental decision you have to make
do you expect congestion with your
dreams or not if you have that
expectation which I think is likely then
you have to deal with retransmits and
then again you should not reinvent a
fundamentally transmitted mechanism for
UDP for every draft in the ITF there is
a good template for that in coop that is
a confirmable message you can basically
make every message confirm overages big
not not recommended or every thousands
message and you can then see how many
you lost and in that window can be
transmitted messages that it's like a
little bit like TCP but like the
performance TCP advancement and also if
you are ending up with TCP in the end
again there's I call it a reliable co-op
it's the name is co-op over TCP TLS and
web sockets or something very long so
I'm there's that alternative also but
then again I use mean there's a lot of
things you considered here and my
suggestion is to approach the thing to
thing research group that is meeting
here there are two drafts in development
they are the serious pattern draft which
talks about how to associate let's call
it data items that are somehow and
serious and there
the problem of retransmits discussed
there and if you have a problem that is
not solved in general and you want to
solve it with your draft maybe we can
create a general solution for UDP that
other people can also use so that this
effect of recreating some new things for
UDP to make it some more look like TCP
some our ends finally also that if you
decide to go with co-op there is the
draft non-traditional responses which
can do it but basically every exotic
thing you need that does not speak fire
at the moment satisfied with co-op so if
you need something you don't find and
current are cease please trying to thing
to thing research good for once and then
to look at the serious pattern and the
untraditional response props as far as I
know current currently coopera is only
used for IOT like domain but do you have
any real replicas ample or real
application that a co-op is used for
outer saw something I example for co-op
application is that we thought of
working group it does DDoS protection
working group we use a kind of our basic
transport protocol for the for the scene
or each other
that's our application if you want to
look at okay I would like to see and
only because something is was initially
intended to be used in the constraint in
order environments doesn't make it
unfeasible for the rest of the internet
observation and can't as a contributor
just a quick follow up on the discussion
about retransmissions I actually when I
first saw the message ID with the UDP I
never thought that it would be for the
purpose of knowing when or to request
for a retransmission or anything like
that I only thought it would be used for
won't number one ordering of the packets
received by the receiver because UDP
doesn't guarantee order delivery so at
least the receiver could do in order you
know reorder at least have order
delivery that was the number one reason
or motivation I felt that was
before the message-id and number two was
for detecting gaps now when when a
message was dropped but not not to
request just to know that you lock they
miss one and so I never would I thinking
that there would be a desire to try to
build reliability on top of a UDP based
protocol here any other comments good
prob again sorry I was a long walk and I
think that that's a interesting
operational like mode of mode of
operation right so if we've kind of said
before and so with with SNMP I can poll
the device I know I get some stats back
yes maybe there's some loss in them but
I know at what interval I'm polling in
this mode where there's no reliability
then if the device just shuts up you
can't tell right because you don't you
didn't get a sequence number to tell and
it becomes quite operationally difficult
to not assume reliability when there
isn't when there's no no guarantee that
the thing at the other end is sending
data so this is kind of I mean we tried
with this we looked at it as the
preferred way to start with and this
along with internal the collector
deployment things about how how you know
when it could can reconnect how you deal
with redundancy between collectors and
those kind of things I think it just
makes more and more challenges here so
that that's kind of why I would just I
think the draft could do with some
discussion of like how you actually
operate the system like this I agree
Justin sure just to interrupt comments I
work for a company we use streaming
extensively from thousands of devices
don't quite some time looking at UDP or
TCP and I also discussed with potential
customers UDP us no no it has to be
reliable otherwise you need to build
additional layer to ensure it
transmissions reliability you don't need
this here benoît class so that's
interesting because we were discussing
the same thing that the discussing was
IP fix for 10 years right yes the
message ID an IP fix was
just to know about the order and just to
know that you've been losing flow
records so the point is that for IP fix
it works fine records accounting right
so you sell information if you lose one
okay big deal by the way and expect a
router to keep information neurons from
Smiths sorry so here I think the key
point is that if you rely on this
mechanism for an event like Rob was
mentioning it must be reliable if you
just link to send like monitoring
information you can use UDP yes just to
add to pay no it's fine I think
fundamentally yeah sflow IP fix have a
different nature anyway because we know
that there's n flows on the device we
know that or n packets going through the
device and we know that we only expect a
sample of them therefore losing one we
can never build a system around having
get like that I don't know of any system
that's built to say with s flow or IP
fixed I'm going to do one to one flow
sampling and I'm going to guarantee that
I'll get every one of them whereas with
telemetry data if we're building systems
that now split the control plane across
the device and off the device then we
need it to be reliable just like you
would need some of this data internally
to the system like links going up and
down to be reliable for routing
protocols so but no again so it depends
what you call telemetry right if it's
telemetry I mean to push high frequency
all information from it's like IP fix
your sending flow records even if
they're not flow whatever right now if
you condense everything in your
telemetry so it becomes an event you
can't miss it so this is Alex yeah just
one of the busy in response to some of
the items here clearly a different
application like that maybe some
application maybe but you require
reliability others where you're saying
you lose one record it's not a big deal
and another question is can you how it
is being used so if you use this for
periodic busy for periodic updates you
know basically that you are expecting
updates for every period already anyway
so if you have a period missing you
would basically
to infer some of some of those things
well I do agree actually that we need to
have the discussion busy of these
operational things in the trade-offs in
this but at the same time I think I
think nobody is saying that this is the
be-all end-all transport for all
particular use cases this is one use
case for certain scenarios where
basically those operational scenarios
that you described yeah would be
applicable so Rob again just a response
that I think there's a few challenges
with those assumptions right so as soon
as you say oh I'll stream everything
periodically you're going to
significantly increase the data that
comes from the device and by hundreds
and hundreds of times right so actually
the to make this system scaleable you
probably want to only send things when
they change it gives you a significant
advantage for large data sets it also
gives you a significant advantage for
interfaces they're down on systems with
you know radix of a thousand or so which
which is kind of common in today's
networks so as soon as you say I'll send
things periodically you're going to end
up with these scalability concerns and
you probably are now having to deal with
worse scale on the device of your GP
periodic than you would be the cost of
doing TCP for reliable so yes I don't
entually
the other problem about periodic is that
you don't actually know what they
collect or what you meant to receive so
if a whole line card stops sending did
Glen Kyle get removed from the system
what did was it meant to send so it's
actually hugely difficult without lots
and lots of other accounting to know
what you should have been sent during
that period so I I see why the the third
thing I shouldn't say is we're inventing
a new protocol here to send telemetry
data let's know invent one that we know
is flawed and only works in like a small
number of cases because that that's just
going to complicate things respond so
regarding the unchanged versus periodic
if we certainly on the basic trade-offs
but actually they subscribe the
subscriptions both can support either
what I mean depending on the use case a
user or they will decide whether they
want to happy erotic or whether
unchanged is actually more applicable
for their particular application if you
want to have a continuous and telemetry
to do some kind of whatever
whereas statistics trendline analysis
all sorts of application you might still
want to have periodic right not not
every use case requires or change that's
true but the I guess the point is that
there's some data and an underlying that
you do want to sample like that right
but that still can be the this doesn't
mean that the system can't support
sending data periodically is that there
is a significant amount of data that
does that won't need to be sent so why I
would encourage people to go and look at
is to look at the data that is being
pulled from devices this is what we've
done and then look at what the
proportion of it that is event based
versus periodic and do some calculation
as to what the data data volume is so we
have this for some jet friends the
scaling analysis in the gr PC based
telemetry where we can show you know
significant reductions based on this but
even though that some data is being
sampled and sent periodically because it
needs to be sampled like that from
undying Hardware sources for example
related questions been a while since I
looked at the draft but I remember
there's previous message ID and that's
how the receiver knows that so messages
have been lost but if you're not
receiving any messages how do you know
that there's messages loss or we going
can we'll have to do a UDP keep a live
draft or maybe we can include it I'm
sorry I'm not sure I'm not sure maybe we
need this kipper life information I
don't know about this this is something
we need to consider but we also have the
in the other draft we have some
mechanism to solve this problem
partially solve the problem burn
worthless so in IP fix we solve that
with SCTP and get a perfect solution
where actually you would have a stream
which is reliable unreliable or
partially writable so depending what
you're sending it is monitoring it would
be unrivaled you miss a couple of
information fine no big deal you might
be something anyway on a router
partially reliable you do your best or
reliable if it's event base that's
how we solve that however a ctp didn't
pick up and it's an issue online Kahn's
right online counts of routers I mean
again you have an HTTP session directly
from all around counts or actually it
complex you an operational issue right
and I think Rob mentioned that how do
you identify your device a router is
like one IP address or it's a sum of IP
addresses to one per line yards sorry I
do not understand your question no
question part it's not a question it's a
no duration that we've been looking at
those issues like ten years ago it
becomes like more an operational issue
what do you want to solve right thing
about that and then you will have the
solution for your protocol there are
several as we listed here there are
several design codes first story we
wanna build a distributed data export
and then we want to we want to maybe to
speed up the the transport we may want
the the hardware tool to encapsulate and
to to process the packet so we need a
simple magazine not simple transport not
like TCP well again speaking as a
contributor I think the message that I'm
getting from the working group is you
probably need to look at the data set to
see a Danida udp-based channel and if
you if you need reliability then if you
and you're gonna build reliability into
this with the sequence number why not
just use TCP so I think if I understand
look at the data set look compare it
between trying to transmitters revival
II and unreliably and see what is the
impact of losing packets and as benoit
mentioned if it's monitoring data that
you're looking at
big game you lose a few packets but if
you're looking an event you can't afford
to lose it then you have to be built in
reliability into the protocol what is
the cost of doing that yes a cui any
other comments just as a contributor
just one more comment I heard or learned
last night that the I guess it's a co-op
working group but there's a an effort
that's been going on for a couple years
now to do a co-op based broker pub/sub
mechanism I don't know much about it but
we should learn more about it and and
see how it might be usable in this space
as well okay let's move on to the next
presentation okay okay this is about the
matos stream originators this one this
one is a generic lattice to build
extension to the yam push work we have
some of the use cases the first one is
the the router the Camerata is narrow
and we want to push data directory from
the line cars and the other use case may
be useful is the IOT is narrow and the
tractor first dream subscribe to the
border router and the distributed the
requester to different route he knows
and the Latinos can push data directly
to the tractor here is solution overview
the publisher contains two rows the
master and the agent and the master have
subscribed subscription server and the
agent that contains the component
subscript is over
a typical typical operation is like that
this the the subscriber first ascend the
global subscription request to the
master and the master will decompose
this request into multiple component a
subscription and send to the components
of screen server then the different
agent or master have pushed data
directly to the tractor here we to
achieve this there are many interactions
necessary between the master and the
agent for example the agent need to have
a registration with the master so that
the master is the well of them and and
and manage the lifecycle but in
Manzanero like like who we mentioned in
in the career outer the interaction
between the master and the agent will be
an internal implementation so currently
in this draft we consider its out of
scope but we listed there some possible
interactions one key point to to this
idea is the subscription decomposition
the master well assemble the disassemble
the global subscription to multiple
component a subscription and the
distributed them to the corresponding
temperature sauce too to achieve this a
reference the implementation is like the
the master may need a data structure and
typically our resource allocation table
to keep track of the mapping between the
resource and the corresponding location
of the subscription server and another
another key point is the publication
composition firstly
the receiver will recognize data recalls
associated with with one subscription
according to the subscription ID and the
second step the receiver assembles data
generated at the same time period based
on the recording Hutton consisted in
each data recall and in addition the
server may need to know the number of
component subscriptions so here we we
propose to use a list of a publisher ID
we will add this to the to the response
of the establishes subscription and
modify the subscription and also add
this in the subscription status and
subscription modified notifications and
this part when they need a young model
by augmented the existing subscription
notification draft the other the other
key point is about the subscription
state change in notifications we know in
addition to sending events or cause to
the receiver the master must also send
the subscription state change
notification and we here we were away
asked for all the subscription states
change in note notifications must be
delivered by the master publication
channel which is the session between the
master publication publisher and the
receiver there when another tape is when
the subscription in conversation result
changed the subscription modified the
notification must be sent to indicates
the new list of publishers and next step
we are going to add the young model to
how to extend the existing subscriber
the notification model and is there any
other issues you consider to be added in
this draft Kent as a contributor can you
go back to your previous slide the one
that said is the diagram and had the red
box that said otoscope yeah why is it
Eris cope as I mentioned in some
instance Naro like the like the Carrie
routers this this is the in this is kind
of the internal implementation so I
think must between the mainboard and the
like house right okay so I think that
this being at a scope is dependent on
the conclusion of some of the
operational requirements that we were
discussing a moment ago
going back to Rob's comment from before
a little more configuration complexity
may be warranted if were for instance
needing to configure TCP instead of UDP
in which case you would actually it
would have to be in scope you because
you'd have to be configuring what is the
TCP interface at least for each line
card to use so I think I think what
you're saying is it's out of scope here
because you're it's the expectation is
that from using UDP the routing engine
can implicitly can you know internally
communicate the line cards and yes it
hasn't okay so there's that assumption
which i think is not is still TBD is
what I'm thinking okay but my concern is
this this part is a little bit of
complex and may vary vary from
implementations so I'm not sure if it
can converge in English just that's my
concern
okay my she has a contributor if you
could go down a couple of slides I think
they you talk a lot
yes sir okay now maybe the next one I
think where you talked about being able
to reliably indicate a change in the
subscription I think it's either this or
the next slide yes yeah yeah all the
subscription state change notification
must be delivered now when you say must
that means you're thinking about a
reliable channel hearing or delivering
that change in notification that's an
interesting question and from the
messager they are no it's not we do not
consider it must be a reliable channel
so maybe in udb case maybe we need to
consider this is Alex also hostile to
add always he respond to that I would
not mix this actually with the earlier
transport discussion the gold certainly
busy for the for the subscriptions per
se it has always been to basically make
this busy make this well make the
fundamental mechanism reliable so that
you can avoid having to pull things now
obviously with this case if you have a
new component subscription that was
added or something that was removed that
is be an event that you would needs to
know or that you would want to know
certainly as a collector therefore
basically there's something that that
that needs to be notified we've had some
this some internal schedule whether it
should be subscription modified or
whether there should be another type of
notification but either way it is an
event and suppose it should be foreseen
vide as part of the control channel now
if you want to have making this busy for
the for the control part of this now for
the actually telemetry stream whether
this is reliable on offensive that's a
separate issue I would separate those
discussions but this one would be needed
for reliable control channel so to speak
so Kent as a contributor maybe it's a
chair I don't know the motivation for
the working group particularly to
adopting the previous strap this draft
is not yet adopted but the idea that
this draft was discussing was one that
was presented at the time that we
adopted the previous strap which was the
goal to support line cards to be able to
send messages themselves directly as
opposed to trying to fold them to the
routing engine in order to for the
routing engine to to send them because
from experience we know that that the
internal backplane the fabric is not
having enough bandwidth to transmit that
much data it's just not possible the
line cards have to be able to send
directly themselves and in fact you know
things like encryption actually it's
probably problematic and so you know go
into the operational requirements you
know are we actually thinking that for
these very high logging scenarios would
the destination be an internal receiver
something that on a LAN you know
something that itself would collect the
logs in unencrypted form do
deduplication and and analysis
compression even itself could convert it
to binary or the need for binary you
don't really need binary in the land you
need binary on the WAM when we talk to
customers you know their their costs for
bandwidth over LAN is expensive that's
when they care they don't care about the
bandwidth on the land so so you know I
think if we get our heads around what
are the operational requirements what is
the problem we're trying to solve maybe
some of this would become more clear I
still strongly support the notion
ability for sending logs out the line
cards directly that's important problem
solve but the motivation for being
binary the motivation for it being UDP
even I think we should go back to asking
if that's really important
to solving the problem here yeah there's
a comment Michael Abraham's and so it
struck me the whole thing about line
cards and it being on box i i've the
when use case where i might have a a
Wi-Fi access point that basically
doesn't have an IP address so i'm
speaking some kind of protocol to it or
i don't want it to send any thinks it's
going through me but it's a different
device and I want to like expose this in
yang so that the wife it's like I'm the
nighttime room I'm the Netcom server but
I'm configuring the guy over there and I
still want exposed to my NMS that these
are two different devices isn't that
kind of the same problem you're don't
want to like a more generic approach and
how to expose this in Yang and net conf
and how to handle this because isn't
this the same thing and like if it's a
lying it like line card that is like its
own computer sitting in the chassis or
if it's something else like you're
acting on behalf of that guy I mean I've
seen many different scenarios where you
need the same concept so can we make it
more general yeah I think you provide a
an interesting use case maybe similar to
this new style tea use case and so we
actually I think this this framework is
like a generic one I think my problem is
there are very like one we're talking
about like okay how do we what's in the
UDP packets the de stream is a telemetry
it's it's not a that's not a different
thing yes I know but but it's like so
this here it's talking about
subscription so but isn't this just
configuration it's just it's not me
specifically I'm doing this for another
guy that he's like near I'm controlling
him so it's not me don't we need like a
more generic approach that and do we
actually need to talk about what the
configuration is instead isn't it like
how do we do this generically isn't that
what we should be discussing like it's
talking about subscriptions here and so
on and how to talk to that guy or what
to actually configure but don't we
actually need just a best comment
this is exposing this entire concept of
you know different devices managed
through one net culture I have a
response but I think Rob does as well it
is for this question Rob yes please go
ahead
I completely agree so in the GRP sea
bass it's about telemetry and
configuration we added a generic way to
be able to make a path be addressable to
a certain target that they entered the
managing entity deals with and it's used
for both telemetry and for AM for
configuration I think having
case-by-case solutions is make the point
I don't think it's optimal I think
having a single way that you can say
there is this management agent that is
responsible for this other domain is is
super useful for many many cases ok so
up leveling the problem space great ok
and I think my closing thought is not
it's not really on this draft what kind
of to the other one as well it is you
know currently just the gang push and
Friends drafts are almost out of last
call and a Shepherd right up
we as working group we've only yet to
find support for dynamics descriptions
we do not yet have any support for
configured descriptions this draft has
honest path towards enabling support for
configured descriptions but I think that
there may be other paths that we could
explore that would get us there faster
specifically HTTP based push mechanism
is something along these lines I don't
know maybe somebody would be interested
in putting together an ID to propose
another notice right so the nice thing
about the way that we've constructed the
or deconstructed the the yang push
notification drafts is that we do have
all these note of mechanisms so it's
kind of a Swiss Army knife it's great
that we have a UDP based mechanism
available certain deployments will use
it for their use cases others won't
because it doesn't matter use cases so I
think though which should also consider
other notifications that would enable us
to have configured descriptions so
that's sort of my closing thought on
this um I think the idea is become Matua
and the the solution and the scope is
kind of clear so I am
I'm wondering if I can ask the working
group to a doctor yes doc but um I think
before we get to the point of adoption I
think we probably need to address the
question that Mike McAlister trays which
is do we need to upscale this problem
definition before we get to the question
of adoption maybe you should consider
all that first okay thanks great so our
last presenter chin good morning
everyone my name is Jim and I could show
you attention to this a new idea
actually this job has been around for a
while we actually submitted in the last
night a meeting I didn't get it
discussed and ivory but we have some a
few discussion on the list with Robo
virgin and about this idea in nine
action capability because here what we
like to do is to use this capability to
to provides a punk operation and can
walk aways together it's the protocol
position but some of many discussion
about whether there's some Atalaya
medicine we can use such as commission
template and so we do some Alice's and
and so before this meeting actually we
prepare the draft updated I missed the
deadline so we just post our new version
so sorry for the late so for this
chapter we want to recap a little bit
provide several observation the photo
action actually met a couple actually
doesn't specify how to handle this
action the reason is because the action
get introduced in young 101 after
medical for work I window one get a
puppy
and when we introduce a young MTA and
the option you know we add the
constrictor for this action they only
can be invoked on the original state
datastore so we think is a very limited
so we you know track the early
discussion on these actually there's
some statement you said actually from
the robber weapon and then this kinda
research can be relaxed actually can be
applied to some other convention
conversion latest also we that the
motive like what motivated me to rise
this job and so we try to investigate
how this action can be applied to as a
Korean datastore like wrong in datastore
or start-up datastore so here is use
cases and and we we have some men in
this country about this I think the
simple cases we bring here actually is
suppose you configure the win and hacker
branch on the champion the face and you
may leverage is the conversion template
if you actually configure the chung
interface with vein and tank a value one
by one actually that means that you may
you know have a you may need to a lot of
second in traffic actually you may but
we have some other other way you because
you you have the completion template and
you can define young data model to to
allow you to configure the trunk
interface ways pedantic rng with such
congratu you can maybe you can really
reduce these sickening traffic 'you only
need a one or the message you to carry
these conversion data but still actually
cause a larger packet size so so go to
the face further actually you actually
config chunk interface with several VLAN
tag around you labyrinth a garage
not a diss greater so in this case
actually you may you know do a lot of
beta retriever you know that cause a
even a lot of the protocol message
exchange so what do we like to do is
optimize the network net called protocol
to provide such a punk operation you
view kimochi the VIN and tag arranged
several
Bananagrams into one we rent a grantee
actually you only need the one protocol
message exchange so what do we propose
here is a u9 actionability here these
actually can be applied to wear a
different protocol operation like edit
config i did't paid her okay to date her
and the idea is to introduce the
operation attribute for example under
the edit configure surely we can
introduce two new operation attribute
were called record emergency recorded
split actually allow you to to merge the
way number of in an attacker range or
speeds up in an attacker ng if you can
allow such kind of feature you really
actually improve the Nanticoke for query
efficiency and you only need actually
one query to get all the information you
needed here we gave the example for this
operation attribute recall the record
emerge actually without the u9 action
capability suppose you need to configure
the tummy in the face with to win and
hack around you and but you really want
to merge them into one when an attacker
ranges so so you what do you can do with
the existing solution for them or edit
config actually you you need to delete
research to win an attacker ranges first
and then you created a new bin and tag
arranged with this one so in our
solution actually we if we with we have
the win in i action support actually we
can you know just the you know
introduces a week
Mergent attributed to indicate a new
server to use the completion and
temperature to merge the the renji into
the into one range in their server side
so also we want to compare the
difference actually you know for without
the in matching capability actually you
need two more climb the computation
because you need to you know figure out
how to you know emoji several via an
attack arranged into line ranges so
that's a the overhead we really want to
avoid another case actually is a
recorder we call the recorders breed
actually you may have when we nan tackle
Reggie you want to split into three or
four and with the existing protocol
operation you we also use at config
actually you may first I mean you need
to delete the Divina tank of value and
then you can and now you create a
another two or three vinegar ranges so
this actually is a cost actually you you
introduce that other ways in my action
capability actually you
you only need to actually indicated a
server to choose the VIN and tag arrange
it may not attack a range it's oblivious
so these can be happen on the server
side so so the advantage is you you
don't need to rely on the kleiner to do
the more Renji computation to speed at
the ranch so this is a basic idea I like
Joe your attention actually so the
summarizes what we proposed here
actually we want to use this in action
to embedding into the protocol operation
to improve the medical require in fishin
see actually we call this a Bunco
operation may be the solution the
example we provide here is very limited
but we think the intention is so you
know really impose these kind of nano
copy fishing with these pump operation
we may introduce some propriety actually
you can actually you know do the pump
operation with with this kind of group
so they can really improve the medical
call for query efficiency yeah that's
all yeah Michael a result so I don't
know why I don't read the draft if I
understood correctly is this only for
when the will you change the
configuration but the end result
operational State does not change is
that the only so you're splitting the
range into two but the effective you
know in effect configuration on the line
card or whatever it never changes is it
only for that type of configuration or
is it also or is this also it like you
split it and then you delete one and you
do that in one operation okay so you had
the example one two five and six is six
to ten you can merge you can merge those
and into one record yeah if this changes
nothing in in real life I mean the line
card the hardware doesn't get
reprogrammed by that operation you're
changing the configuration but the state
of the device doesn't change is it only
for that type of operation or is it also
for for deleting one of the villains in
the middle it's for both yeah I think we
right now we really support both
actually the motivation we can have the
you know merger that is created several
tag around into the one allow you to do
the better medical query you know but
actually we also support away we in some
cases you may need to delete a some of
the value from the VLAN tag arranges so
we provide such capability in some cases
actually we you know we need to support
post and and then we can actually can
you know optimize the actual to to merge
several rent into the wine wrench yeah
so yeah do you see this as a no is this
a optimation in number of transactions
or is it processing power on the server
or on the client or whatever we don't
want you add over here to the client
actually maybe you just need a one
transaction but this is actually
transaction you know you send a request
to the server server actually we are
actually you know using some existing
contemplator to actually merge you the
the range into the one actually all
happened in the server side actually you
reduce overhead on the client side
robertson cisco so i'm still not
convinced that this is that this
particular use case is actually a
problem I'm not convinced there's a
scale issue in terms of configuration
here even you split out the number of e
lands over and there are hundreds of
interface and then I still think the
amount of config is gonna be a 10k 20k
something that would be small in terms
of mister size and I'm consuming it so
don't I'm not convinced by that aspect
that's a problem here to be solved in
terms of if you want operations to do
more advanced feed a manipulations ie
breaking tags or inserting tags into
into particular strings for example then
yes that's okay but I think of those
maybe just be our pcs potentially on a
VLAN model is how I wouldn't prevent
those so then coming back to the general
inline actions I'm still sort of
conflicted is where this is a good thing
to do I think this more generally is
about transactions and saying I want to
give a sequence of events to the server
as one transaction effort to perform all
of these things and either succeed or
fail so that's the the guys I'd look at
this problem rather than just adding
actions into configuration requests but
even with that I still question whether
that's a useful thing or not I'm not I'm
not convinced this is a problem to be
solved at this stage but a you say that
you don't know we're giving actually we
use a edit configure the exam preview
you know you you really modify the VLAN
tag around you to the merger and a split
actually you may need because you may
operate on some list that leads to the P
key index cannot be deleted so you have
several disk rider Renny up to you so
you need to you know delete several
discs where the rent arranger first and
then you create then a new range with
logic rent rent rent rent you know so
that's a diffusion though the Nanticoke
we think we really want to address this
okay so that's a different problem
potentially to solve and I think again I
think need to look at the data model
that you're talking about so the one
I've been through right if doesn't have
that issue as in the VLANs interest
information on a sub interface so it's
not actually something where you have
this concern
it's just manipulating that string and
the ability of a client to mangle VLAN
IDs into string is it's probably bored
beyond trivial to do I mean it's that's
an easy thing to solve so it might be
that your data model is different and
then hence there's a different
requirement commentary from that so I'm
happy to look at what your specific data
model is to see what the changes was
different yeah we do have such a model
we can yeah
and show you of line about race yeah oh
my Asia is a contributor adding to
Robert's concerned fit why we might need
this is the problem specifically for
case where we're talking about a range
like we're trying to specify whether
we're trying to expand it break it up is
that the specific use case that we look
looking solution for yeah the case would
give actually maybe it's kinda imitates
but we really want to generalize this
idea the general idea actually we can
provide the pankration for Nanticoke for
protocols you know so you can actually
improve and then copy if you shouldn't
say and here we gave the Gaddafi the
VLAN tag arrange a value the value
actually is interval type type maybe
there's some other case actually in an
attacker value actually is is a string
type and you also do this a bit emerges
operation you know so what other use
case would you have in some case where
you haven't bring bring up actually so
you may transpose some learn completion
into the into that static congregation
or dynamic accommodation data by the way
we sink yeah we we only you know talk
about the focus on these cases but we
have some other cases with haven't grown
from prenup yeah okay I think maybe if
you bring those cases make might help
the workgroup appreciator and
I understand the problem a little better
yeah yeah we can do that yeah can't just
a contributor I agree with Rob I don't
understand the motivation for one insult
like I guess scalability efficiency but
it you know does it really get to the
level of concern that we need to solve
the problem that the solution seems like
a very point solution and the fact that
it's in that colony is concerning I
would request that we have a solution
that works for both the company and rest
comp if it is truly just a transaction
like mechanism I think that's what Rob
was saying then maybe enabling gang push
to be worked to be used by NECA would be
another way of enabling something like
this it going to Mahesh is coming right
here if it's truly just for ranges then
it seems like maybe we'd have to have a
data type a type def range and then this
operation would be available whenever
that type def was in play it's just
unclear at the moment I guess going to
my hashes last point two more examples
data analysis it's it's currently it's
not clear why we would want to pursue
this yeah I think in tension we we
provide such conservation Cober we can
generalize this cancer we not only apply
to the input but also can apply to the
existing medical operation you know so
not a limit to to the you know the
existing network of further operation so
yeah I'm push you can we haven't
investigated how these can be applied to
that young boys ship either that's that
that's a case we think maybe first we
need to clever the prominent Space Coast
and then we can go into a tip Oh about
that other other currency we don't
thought about I think we should go Cody
to look further to apply to that young
boys year you're saying yank push but
you mean say yang patch right
yum push not a young patch no Hank push
oh you meant you mention is young patch
patch right patch oh sorry I miss Norris
any more comments questions all right so
we're at the top of the hour
they're blue sheets are up here if
anyone did not sign the blue sheets
please come to the desk thank you and
otherwise great we used up all the time
thank you thank you