this is an aspirational photograph for
the working group
wouldn't you be rather doing this than
working on quick still let's get it done
sorry that is the neighbor I would
highly recommend it yeah although he
found a place last night that sorry
there's ice in a neighbor nicer than the
neighbor yeah there is ice in that drink
in as a no ice right no you said
neighbor that's the neighbor mine didn't
mind had asked him it mine did not know
they go maybe they just poured gin in
the glass for me you're perfectly happy
with that so this is the quick working
group if you have come for a different
working group you're likely to be
disappointed but you may still be
engaged
I haven't pre-arranged scribes do we
have any volunteers I won't pick on Sean
Turner because we picked on him too many
times in the past I don't how much faith
that echo would do it
Jonah no okay I'm just arranging it to
be evenly Patrick McManus is a hero
wait Jonah's gonna do it
it's a fastly production fantastic both
of you do it together good on you
and can someone hopefully near the
microphone volunteer to be jabbar relay
if in fact thank you Eric
fantastic this is the note well I hope
you're familiar with it by now but if
you're not these are the terms under
which you participate in the ITF
regarding things like code of conduct
and intellectual property please have a
read and you can find more information
on the ITF website that's not no we're
not using that we have the blue sheets
check we have a scribe check you have a
really a check we're ready to go so our
agenda for today we're gonna have a
hackathon report briefly from Lars and
then updates from the editors including
updates on the operation drives which we
need to start paying more attention to
then we're going to discuss a few brief
issues the theatres have identified I
think one of those may have been
superseded overcome by events Martin
yeah yeah so the version negotiation
wound is not gonna be addressed in this
room based on the discussions I've been
having with people unfortunately I do
want to still introduce the problem so
people are sure of what's going on the
Barents thing has already been addressed
but I think Martin seaman has some other
material to discuss regarding the
handshake that's kind of the same corner
cases that are exactly ideal ok I think
that's all the to change is there crane
and then after that we'll have a quick
discussion of the human right to review
document that came across the doorstep
and as time permits talk about making a
quick to play ball from me quickly
bouncing from Martin Duke and finally a
quick unreliable datagram Sir Thomas
folly we have another session tomorrow
and that session is almost
entirely devoted to the spin bit so if
you've come here expecting the fireworks
you have to wait a little bit longer at
the end of tomorrow we'll also do some
some housekeeping in terms of looking at
our Charter our milestones reminding
people of the upcoming interim and that
sort of thing after there's been bit
discussion any bashing on the agenda
okay I guess you're putting this at me
for the interrupt report so I don't have
any slides anything else oh did the last
few stickers are in the back you want to
grab them they'll soon be worth a lot on
eBay right so so as Mark said tomorrow
we're gonna do the housekeeping spoiler
alert right it seems highly unlikely
we're going to ship something today is G
this month yeah sorry Spencer you had to
you had to find out this way tomorrow
well tell you when but that'll be one
big part of that discussion so we're not
quite done yet but that'll happen
tomorrow um in terms of interrupts we
had as usual during the hackathon a
table we actually had two tables this
time or with people that are
implementing quick and it pays we'll be
testing the current implementation
drafts I think we had like around ten
implementations participate in some form
it's looking better in terms of getting
back to at least basic interoperability
in terms of version negotiation
handshake data exchange and closing um
there was a big sort of disruption when
we redid the stream zero thing and we're
still sort of seeing the after-effects
of that that there's a bunch of
augmentations that haven't moved to one
of the new versions that have to
refactor stream zero but so if we hear
that that's it's happening soon we don't
have a whole lot of experience or a
whole lot of Interop with some okay I'm
gonna call it advanced features but it's
actually pretty basic functionality such
as the key update or connection
migration
there's very few stacks that are doing
it and I think there's very few sex
specifically that I would call like you
know the ones that are going for a
large-scale deployment that are
currently doing it that's a bit
concerning it's one of the reasons why
that the milestones are probably
unlikely but it is the the spreadsheet
and greener is better of basically
darker green earth better more letters
are better clients are down vertically
servers are cross horizontally so you
can see there's some white just I try to
move the implementations that haven't
shown up sort of to the right so to
concentrate the information a little bit
there but there's and there's still some
white and some very light green and
that's not super good um but it's it's
looking better and I think the
trajectory is there we're gonna do
another interim meeting with an
interrupt event before it in January
hopefully it's going to look a lot
better then and then by Prague so
definitely we're Park we should be
interrupting around - 17 probably
already in Japan but I really hope that
on - 17 we're gonna see a lot of more
Turkey I know Alan wanted to say
something specifically about interrupts
around HQ I don't know if you're in the
room or remotely or if somebody else
wants to say something in his stead I
don't feel qualified to summarize where
we are with that but I think we were
somewhere Jenna Jenna I don't know this
is a bug and the I don't know if this is
a mistake but a I'm just curious to
understand how does that 80's manages to
have fewer features with itself then it
does with others
don't ask me all right Alan friend Alan
jabber would like to say that cue pack
had three implementations it didn't rob
those three interrupts I have an
implementation that disagrees with them
so we have some issues without so the
good the good side is right there's a
lot of activity and I think it's even
increasing right there's there's more
and more lines and columns on the
spreadsheet although some of them have
remain wide for a while now but but we
are still feeling the after-effects of
the street zero refactoring plus the
editors are really good at changing
other stuff and so I think the goal is
to have - 17 which is the one that's
currently open for a surgery be the last
one where we're gonna do large changes
that are not motivated by strong
interoperability problems so if the hope
is that really - seventeen will be the
thing that we're gonna let sit and
simmer for a while and let the
implementations actually catch up and do
some much wider scale inter up with with
the caveat and I just said isn't easy
p.m. so but which on the recovery draft
specifically I think we are still trying
to get more help from the TCP guys to
make the quick recovery as compatible
and comparable to what TCP is doing as
possible and so I think for recovery we
are probably gonna see some changes that
are not necessarily only going to be
driven by Interop however the recovery
is complex but it's not actually a whole
lot of code that needs to change for it
so hopefully changes to recovery will
not cause but they shouldn't cause
interoperability issues to begin with
but they also hopefully don't disrupt
the implementations too much christian
in christianism our loss when I look at
these metrics please leave it on when I
look at the metrics as you say there's a
bunch of advanced features that are not
tested at all like we have two academic
or prototype implementation that do
migrations right and pretty much nobody
else does
and that the test nisman we should
seriously consider at which point do we
decide that okay the reason but nobody
does it is probably because the spec is
too hard or something and just cut it
for v1 we should on my feeling I put it
this way is that we haven't seen a lot
of inner up around that because
the rate of change to everything else is
so high that you gonna spend a lot of
cycles as an implementation team
basically on you know keeping up with
everything else that lift gives you
basic interrupts that people just
haven't gotten to that yet if it remains
the case that people aren't getting to
that yet in the next couple of weeks and
months I think we should definitely have
a discussion on what to do with those
features and I'm gonna point out that we
seem to be migrating from a discussion
of the inter up results to the planning
of our future and how we handle our
schedule so it's just it's what I was
just reading the data and the data tells
me something I'm looking at the queue
behind you the data tells you you should
help other people with our
implementations which is closed now um
so I mean feel free to tell me I'm um
I'm not a hoarder and that you want to
raise another point but um the one when
I notice about this graph and also about
generally my experience and I've written
this first before is that things that
are easy to test get tested and things
that are hard to test you're not could
test it even if actually might be
implemented
um and I'm particularly I live in
particular fear of recovery um but um
but even like you know like my
experience has been like I mean there's
there's basically no difference between
14 and 15 and I like updated it to 15
like in like five minutes and like was
just too lazy they're like sit around
like try dinner out for everybody and so
um you know and that's like easy so um I
I guess I would be up for and I know
large deny bookends middle work
individually trying to figure out like
some set of arrangements that would make
it easier for you to test things um and
I guess only we're gonna let's us
recovery so um so like you know they
would like my ideal would be I could
just tape my implementation put in a
docker image and drop it into test
harness and we come back with this
matrix on May that's too fancy but on so
I think like if other people are like
minded about this maybe we could you
could have some sort of small like
discussion about what to build in
collaborative evil tool chain for this
cuz I just don't see like like literally
we could spend the first day in the
interim like
with even with Asians that actually all
work pretty well just getting this
matrix fall down I'll just note that
this is not a complete set of all the
features of quick so of course no I know
I'm just wanting to I think I should
have started with that I'm responding to
questions point we are nowhere near the
point where we are deciding or even
thinking about what to cut out of this
stuff so I I don't I don't think we
should be going down the path of
discussing that right now so I give it a
credit so it's a good topic for how to
automate some of this and and some of us
have some automation for their
particular stack but there's nothing
that generates that whole matrix and
that would be that would be very useful
the other thing that would be not so so
getting something like a packet drills
suite it's difficult for quick what
because it's encrypted but but that
would be very useful so there's some
discussion that maybe we should have
around one of the interrupts events
about what we can do I guess I would
think before then because a little as
will spend the around prevent writing
that test furnace so you know again I be
um I'm gonna raise my hand if there's
someone you know people be interested in
like working on this like come find me
or lose your hands now or something and
we'll try to like get together do
something I'm really super flexible at
what we do but I like to have something
happen because like I say it's just
incredibly expensive and and I'm really
quite worried about like they're I mean
there's got to be like nine thousand
recovery cases we have to test and like
every single one of them is getting
testing and like I don't see how our
pawsome we do that manually if your
professor has master students it's not
really a PhD topic but it's certainly a
master thesis topic you know that would
you know
eternal fame Jen Iyengar on this topic
there was a test suite that was written
by some folks they had showed up in
London
have we heard anything from those people
do you mean quick tracker they said I
don't know I don't remember what it was
all Olivier student is working on that
but that is more like a conformance test
it could lead to this but I look it up
in it yeah yeah thanks and there if you
need a repo for that or something just
ask
so mr. Thompson yeah don't be on the
front take the whole room is a pink box
interesting mucking around here alright
so what happened in 15 this is since the
last time we met as a working group in
clip that at the interim 15 has quite a
number of changes here there are a few
other minor ones that are not in this
list but these are the ones I think are
not-- even the first ones not really a
change i think we changed some packer
numbers as a result but we took the two
frame types immersed and into one so
whenever we talk about act now we're
talking about an act that may or may not
have ACN counters in it we litigated the
design of a head at some length and
decided that it wasn't worth changing we
have some signaling around the the act
delays we now insist on validating the
presence of the retry and having a
server prove that it was the one that
saw it that's new what it's also new is
that there's only one of them obviously
that design doesn't work particularly
well if there are there would be
multiple rate rise and though there was
a number of other reasons we got roof
retries we have the design team come
back with some recommendations about how
to deal with connection ids in their
ongoing management and added a frame to
deal with that there's also some changes
in there to prevent deadlocks i think
none siemens talk goes further into that
and other consequences of having that
that design so we're likely to see a
little bit more change in 17 around that
one
maybe HTTP and kupack had have you it's
kind of major changes settings and our
pirates
and this is the one that I hate our
largest reference is encoded modulo back
sentries I think I lost that one that's
awkward
and then we have a new static table but
I don't think anyone's really all that
happy with but it's it's there and the
next slide has all the changes in 16
right you'll notice the dish I've got
the table contents in the next slide
which is probably the more interesting
one so the transport document we decided
to flip on its head and shuffle
everything around so notice that there's
a lot of text moved there's a lot of new
text around all of it as well and we're
continuing this work in upcoming
versions as well but the idea is that
we're going to talk about the things
that people care about most first and
then talk about the stuff that
implementers care about most last let's
go
HTTP got a new structure as well I'm not
sure that's all that that different to
how it was before but this is this is
what it looks like it was it was cleaned
up a little bit and worked for reflow a
few Packers having a similar rework done
but that hasn't landed yet I don't think
we'll see that in 17 or along with 17
this is what that looks like at the
moment it may shift around a little bit
as that PA if I was I think Alan's
almost finished with that one so we
should see that relatively said next ok
17 fun things so we are going to change
the layout of the first octet in both
short and long header forms that those
changes have been held based on a number
of things so we had the great Google
quick migration event occur so that
allowed us to reclaim a couple of the
bits that we were sort of holding in
fixed positions during that transition
that seems to have been successful based
on the reports that I heard from the end
so we we have our fingers crossed and
we're gonna continue along this path
we're going to we're going to take those
bits back and we're gonna assign them to
things like spin bits if that's the
outcome of that it's discussion with
tomorrow
some people noticed some interesting
problems with the way that we were doing
stream limits and how then interacted
with blocked and then we went back and
looked at it and thought that probably
the best thing to do is completely
restructure the way that we allocate we
grant new streams to appear and so we're
doing that based on counters rather than
the maximum identifier which makes them
much more like the flow control than
they were previously it just means that
we have more frames now it also means
that we don't have crazy situations
where frames can have values that are
completely invalid in them so I think
that that cleans things up a little bit
: you had a question hi yeah it just
takes me a little while to get the mic :
Perkins for the first octet changes it
was a multiplexing discussion in apt
core this morning yeah I'm gonna go over
that bring her a little bit more I'm
gonna separate deck on that one okay
I'll go through that change afterwards
I've got the conclusions to the
discussion on the on those slides and
I'll just walk through them in a little
bit more detail Irie numbered everything
which which Lars was super happy about I
also put ease in reset stream for all
those people who have been irritated by
that and there's a bunch of other other
things that we're going to be talking
about here that might get me to 17 but
as Lars said 17 well it is our vain hope
that 17 is the last one we ever have to
make real changes in and so there was
one more that Kazu hope prompted us to
make as well which is we reshuffled the
order of the fields and a new connection
idea frame because they're a little bit
weird so things like that now's your
opportunity of about two weeks to get
your pet hates addressed and merged and
and looked at but the bar is going to go
up pretty significantly after that till
I think yeah I mean my my ass was gonna
be a little more time than that a month
since a little more appropriate given
the time of year that would be basically
I want to have given them in over 20
changes I won't have time to read the
spectra ferpa finish and make make sure
like I feel good I can make sure I have
my head think I'm all the way about
right what would you object to that to
us doing say two iterations if issues
we're kind of came out so it'd have an
18 I'm asking yes I'm just asking like
don't freeze just yet yeah that's I give
people time like pull their heads up and
just they get the whole thing in front
of finish that that's fair and so the
point here is this this is your warning
we're gonna start that process now I
don't think it's gonna be hard punished
to the other end of it it's it's just
that we want to make sure that come some
reasonable time before we made again in
Tokyo things are stable and we can start
to talk about things like deployment
general just to respond to what occurred
said to be clear also this isn't this is
it this doesn't mean that if there are
actually egregious errors in there we
won't address them right of course we
want to do that I think I'd expressed it
is the working group agrees I hope that
we need a period of stability to let it
be let us catch up and see how this goes
and I want to avoid egregious changes
after some point but but because request
is perfectly reasonable all I'm trying
to get at is that like um you know did
because we only these partial
implementations and because we have and
because every time we do an
implementation you find in Felicity's um
you know like I don't want to put us in
a position where there are things like
the futures better than the past and
where things that like just suck but
like aren't actually death like are
things that we say oh we can't fix
because like we like to read to Frieza
that's like right yeah that's not the
agreement we're making and of course our
right bugs will continue to get fixed
you have another one on the next one I
think you have one more yeah the idea is
that at some point very very soon
we'll have a
protocol this we need pretty strong
justification to make changes to things
that will affect interoperability my
suggestion is that when we that that if
we get issues open that a sort of
speculative or suggest improvements
we're going to be a little bit more
aggressive about closing those sorts of
things politely but if people do want to
work with new design issues because
they've found bugs I definitely want to
see those those raised and it but if you
if you're not sure whether this has been
discussed or what not maybe maybe
discussing with the list before your
your open issues then then that might be
the best way to do things of course
editorial stuff we take any day
especially in PR for I mean it's all
have can you go to the next deck yeah
unless anyone wants to talk about this
topic a little bit more yeah that the
packet okay zero are people reasonably
clear on that it's not that we're saying
we're gonna shut it down and not take
any more changes but I mean we need a
period of stability to get some
assessment from the implementations in
an ideal world we will prove that what
we have written down is a great
specification and then we can move
forward if we find problems then we'll
deal with that
yeah but then one of the one of the
sentiments I heard expressed was that
because things have changed quite a lot
quite often it's been very hard to get
to the point we've where you've got an
implementation that is good for
deployment and one thing that we're kind
of lacking is the experience in
deployment exam I don't want to ship
this thing as RC without considerable
experience in deployment and so we need
to get that process started pretty soon
right and and so you know change is
asking for well remembering or aesthetic
changes or whatever are not gonna be
helping us get to that yep and so that
that might mean that some things will
suck in you know indefinitely we're
sorry so octet zero place
because I think this is this this goes
to Colin's point and I think this is
probably the best one to to do yeah yeah
all right so this is the outcome of the
discussion in New York with colors and
letters so the the long header packet
will look like the first one so we have
the first bit saying that it's long we
have what I'm dubbing the quick bit in
the next one we have to type bits that
allow us to distinguish between the four
different types of long headers that
that we have and then the rest of physic
this is encrypted so the orange here is
we're using the packet number protection
scheme the short Heller we have the
short head a bit the quick bit we might
have a spin bit and everything that's
not those things is encrypted and under
encryption in both of them we have a
packet number the short header will have
a key face bit and that means that the
packet number encryption key won't
rotate as the keys rotate and key
updates thanks kazoo next so the common
part as I said there's not a lot of new
things there next this is just for the
record I guess I have a straw man here
for the allocation of code points to the
various types of long header packets
that's negotiable
but one of the desires expressed was
that people could use some combination
of bits in the long header to identify
things that have client selected or
potentially client selected connection
IDs in them so they can be hived off in
terms of the load balancers and routers
and things like that so I'll try to
preserve that as much as possible the
other thing is that the spare bits we're
going to when I say they need to be 0
and maybe you can negotiate their use
afterwards but 0 will be the defaults
and probably in the long header that
means that 0 will be the values
we're encrypting them so they'll look
random on the wire okay this must be
zero
I must ignore or must be zero much jack
must be zero must check okay that's my
that's my put I mean I'll take it I'll
take anything else but this is this is
really just a storm and if people have
an argument for anything else I'll take
that okay um I'm sorry
yeah gives you two more bits of integer
um so sure I anticipate a 30% chance of
needing to have one more take bit at
some point in the very near future but
you know yeah I don't have a reason for
that I'm just saying like like every
other time with like stats already the
entire space we would like actually the
idea but we have space yeah we have
spare bits we can take them back I think
if we really need them you there David's
cognizing Google um this makes me uneasy
one of the first one was what occur was
saying that like the type what is like
kind of a registry where today we only
have four values in there but it was
kind of nice to have it extensible but
with two bits we're not gonna be able to
fit a lot more give me one example
that's the point of extensibility is
that we can't think of it yeah yeah if
we do that all the time we have all
these extension points hanging off its
and then why do all you have with rain
types that are VA lies we could only
like limit it to five frame types you
know anyway so we have example frame
types okay
so first point second one I feel like
we're burning two bits on the packet
number lengths that are already encoded
in the packet number itself guess this
is moving them from the packet number I
see but that doesn't really allow us to
encode that many more values right
because I can't hide this meeting sorry
okay fair enough yeah I can see that
thank you
so yeah at the point that I can mate off
mic was that the the 8 bit Packer number
is much closer to plausible 6
oh it was seven but yeah that's not much
more plausible
janek's how much of this is going in
invariant anomaly this is just an
quickly - this is I don't know who's
doing quickly - if I know I don't know
I'd no idea you know you got rid of that
no yeah yeah so that all of all of this
stuff that we're talking about here is
entirely under our control so the next
version of quick whatever that's called
can change everything we decide so none
of this is invariant no no this is a
very look the the only thing that's
invariant here is that first bit okay no
I think have another one as well so
particularly the second bit your quick
bit is not the quick bit is not really a
quick bit I mean it's a joke but in what
in this version of quick that that bit
will be set okay I think we have another
slide I think and it's the same as I
described before
so we'll encrypt that will encrypt the
spin bit here if we decide not to do
spinning but otherwise the rules are the
same I think that's all I've got on this
slide is it only unless not worry about
this one for right now yep thank you all
right thank you
so that takes us running to the mic
yep stick around that mic maybe this
room is really big and it takes a while
to get to the mic
there's closer to the mic : so from a
very quick look while you're giving that
talk this looks to avoid the obvious
solutions where things like RTP and stun
please do coordinate with a bt car
because they have a draft on this
demultiplexing so just just just to make
sure everyone is happy with that I think
it would be really useful if we could
get the multiplexing with stun as an
invariant
from the bit patterns for that the
appropriate bit pattern so we can always
do that d-max
it's something we have discussed before
in this group July anger are you trying
to put that in this so that we don't
have to litigate that again in a future
was not quick I mean that's that's a
reasonable argument but I not should I
buy it for Lee but I think we're going
to want to do Pittsburgh quick which
means we're going to need NAT traversal
which means we even need to have an
invariant that we can deem axe or stun
or we need to reinvent that
functionality and quick I think it's
much easier to have an invariant that we
can dmax
just based on the first bits which which
we have if if we stick with those first
two bits I I want to I want to say that
good just the the whole notion of
invariance of things that we were
choosing to keep fixed so that we
wouldn't ever change them and and that's
it's a minimal set there are things that
can naturally become invariant just
because that's our deployment works
sometimes and I'm fine with Stan
de-multiplexing one of those I don't
think we need to codify it but my
feeling is it's likely to be extremely
important and we're basically making it
very into bits the first two bits of the
patent the packet and that's it yeah I
don't think I'm in favor of that um for
several reasons first of all that there
going to be an enormous percentage of
the correct connections the world you
should never need to be much was done
like all the ones between we have
clients and wind surfers basically um um
so that's point one point two is the
primary need for demultiplexing
is the endpoints of gene multi blocks
and the primary different variances
people are not part of the connection to
be able to do things with do things or
not do things with the wave packets and
so the endpoints are perfectly capable
of arranging like to only do versions
are quick which not the new Ghost is
done um and so I don't think the purpose
of invariance is not like nailed down
design decisions in perpetuity is that
instruct
people who are not part of the
connection how to manage the packets I
would expect that if we want
peer-to-peer to work it's one thing
which the firewalls and middleboxes will
need to understand we talk allow through
and there's already a lot of
infrastructure that understands time so
I think this may be something where we
we care about the unpassed devices okay
so now we have Miriah presenting about
the up straps and not Bryan yeah hi I'm
Amelia
so we updated both of these it's not
both of these drafts and we can go to
the next slide so the manageability
we updated them Philip based on issues
we had and github so the manageability
get one new section we added some
illustrations some ASCII art for the
quick handshake and we added some Texas
it's good use considerations but there
are no open issues in github on this
document anymore of course we have to
update the document to align us with the
protocol specification at the very end
but this is in pretty good shape next
there was a couple of more open issues
on the applicable ax t and we did a lot
more work we have three new new sections
which got written and reviewed and
merged into this version there was a
little bit of editorial work on
information exposure and connection ID
based on the changes that had happened
on the protocol since then and we have
two pending PRS for the next version
Thank You Martin which are also ready to
be merged I think yeah
the first one there will need to be held
I think because that's conditional on
that made some assumptions based on
in-flight stuff that will not
necessarily made so that'll need a
little bit of work I mean as I said we
have to rework a couple of things anyway
when the trends our transport draft
changes so we can merge it and change it
later we can hold it I don't know it
doesn't really matter that much
okay next slide unfortunately we have
some open issues and we need a little
bit of help there some of these things
are just questions about what to do and
if you want to do it at all and some of
these things we need actually people
writing text because we might not have
the best expertise for that
so there's issue 11 and 29 which are
still talking about giving more guidance
about how to create your connection ID
because you can encode information in
the connection idea for the network
there was a proposal or like a report
like a proposal to make a recommendation
that you should include a mech in the
connection ID so on past device can also
check that those informations are kind
of correct that has a question mark
because there was some discussion and it
was not T if there's something you want
to recommend or is needed or whatever so
more input is definitely needed here and
we addressed issue 29 to some extent but
there's another question if we need more
guidance there is an issue open that's
issue number 14 asking if we need more
guidance about application visible
errors like what should applications do
with those errors I don't think there
are many errors many different errors
visible anymore but it would be nice to
give some guidance doesn't have to be
much guidance but we would need some
input here like from HTTP people or
other draft authors there is a question
if we want to explain the idea of the
heck maybe that you can send if you have
a message based application protocol you
could send one message per stream and
then you can cancel the sending if you
don't need this message anymore which
would like enable some kind of partial
reliability so I mean this is the way
how to use the quic protocol and it's
it's heck to get some partial liability
and the question is to want to spell it
out or is it something we don't want to
recommend and I see people come into the
mic no please do not recommend this this
is not a good not recommend but I mean
it's so you don't want to even talk
about it I heard about it like I had to
like duct tape my head back together so
no people can't do it still right
generally I think it's completely
reasonable to do
for what it's worth I don't think we
need to recommend this I don't think we
need to say anything about it I mean
people who want to do partial to
laboratory know exactly what it implies
and I think they will do it I don't
think anything please by the way when we
do this I don't think anything breaks we
want to give some more recommendation
about when it makes sense to cancel
streams or like on a more general level
without having the specific use case in
mind I didn't look at the text but um I
think like like like I get I get that
the working group is decided not to take
on partial reliability as a as a work
item just yet but like we like know how
to do it we have drafts like let us not
like document things which we know we
know how better ways to do know but I
mean this is documenting the way to use
the current quick protocol right you can
use it that way if you want so I don't
so to be clear this is not I don't I
don't I don't think we should we should
really get in the business of trying to
figure out what applications should not
do especially on things like this
API use is always something that we
figure out how our application used
later but I if somebody thinks has a
problem in doing this I think that would
be good to document so actually yes if
you think that it's not recommended then
we should well I guess I'm certainly I
mean if you're you engage me here are
gonna have to do that I guess I will but
like um like I guess what I'm saying is
that these documents how force like this
document has force um even moral force
or instructional for educational force
then it ought not to do things that like
we know are like not not advisable and
like and the fact that like I think
every think they're like a bunch of
people here I've been working on
something which obviously is better it's
just this is not supervisor pool so like
I'd be happy to say we have intrude but
it's not gonna be removed like then yes
I'm happy to like sprite like some
screed about why it's bad I just said
one thing I'm gonna walk back to the I
think it's important to say why not just
what another one will litigate this
right now but I know that people are
doing this
the people who are doing the quick API
for the web are doing exactly this
inadvisable or not so actually if you
have real concerns about it if you can
give me arguments why this is bad we
should that's what we should document
like I think that's that's all you need
to do right now okay Spencer Tolkien
says the outgoing transporter II
director responsible for quick partial
liability and FEC and stuff like that
are still out of the explicitly out of
scope for quick as that is chartered
today so that probably has a great deal
to do why do with why the working group
stopped working right very much which is
good hopefully we should talk but but
that's the mystery of why it's not being
or started a quick working group is
because it was explicitly excluded in
the current Charter I believe yeah you
ain't sweatin Google I want to add that
I think it's fine to to say nothing in
this regard especially given Spencer's
comment I think that's totally
acceptable I also want to argue that
this totally works like you can deploy
this in a fairly large application use
like a million streams and make them all
unidirectional and make them unreliable
and like it like totally works you can
run a VPN over it you can do a whole
bunch of other stuff over it
so I think arguing that it's like
completely non viable is a little bit
facetious okay okay can you add your
arguments to the issue just like get
some comments there and describe what
your concerns are I mean one argument
would be that it'd be we are gonna
I think in quick version to well and in
the next version of the ITF will work
partial reliability specifically been
proposed as one thing to work on so it
seems kind of weird to have a nob
strafes
give a way to do it and then have
another way to do it in the future
version of the protocol the point is
we're not giving them a way to do it the
way to do it is
already there the question is should we
talk about it but personally I think no
because would you would you rather have
people do it this way or would you
rather have people do it a the way that
that the future protocol will offer I
mean this section could say you know you
can do it this way but like hold on we
will do it in the next version that what
that's what the section could say or
could say nothing
and so like absent consensus to say
something it says nothing generating
that I'll agree with that I think
there's a problem here
the problem is that when we talk about
partial reliability as a noun it's not
clear what one is talking about and ever
end up having to describe that and
that's the problem even when we talk
about something that was excluded from
the Charter that is quite different from
what thatis both of them are partial
reliability and that's where your
problem lies so instead of walking into
that mess it's good to stay out of it
and all our applications to do what they
do best use stuff and we learn something
from that
Tommy Polly Apple so I'm going to agree
with everyone what everyone's saying
that we shouldn't be mentioning the
partial viability hack in here partly
because we want to move on to other
things
partly because you like adding that kind
of sets a precedence for if we include
this could we include all the other
wacky things you could do with the
protocol it could be essentially an
unending list now - on the flip side I
think like things like how do we handle
errors in how should applications deal
with those are things that applications
must face and they must have some
behavior with so I think adding text
around that things that are part of this
is important so let's focus on the bits
that we do need to give guidance on that
are really current concerns okay let me
ask you another question does it make
sense to give more guidance on like
because you can cancel a stream of
transmission right giving more guidance
on that bit because that's what does it
is exposed by some interfaces so I think
actually to that point giving guidance
around when a given side closes a
certain side of the stream like do you
send your stop sending at the same time
you send your reset stream or do you do
them asymmetrically
talking about the strategies of why you
may do those things would be useful and
that kind of addresses this without
getting into the topic of partial
reliability the cue is claiming you help
with writing some yeah I'll give a PR
for that no it's closed had a lot less
room I must say that I'm profoundly
unimpressed by this discussion okay we
know for certain that this stuff that is
up on the screen and described in draft
is going to shape in product before the
quick RFC's actually make it out the
door we don't have a choice the only
choice we have is whether we want to
provide a forum for discussion of this
topic at this time or not if we do not
provide such a forum we have no
influence
we as the IDF over how that discussion
forms and how the consensus forms that
we will have to live with the
consequences of that consensus so Harold
nobody is trying to shut down the
discussion on what shape our will
rely really sure taking quick it's
specifically about this document I
understand what you are saying I am
saying that we have a minimal chance of
influencing what is happening and making
it sound like you're trying to push away
the discussion reduces the chances that
you have of an influence in the
discussion I don't think that's what the
discussion is about it was question is
whether a an archival RFC that is gonna
live for a long time should should
mention what what much people consider a
hack when there's some other version to
do things whether this shifts or not is
it almost doesn't matter right
our clientele RFC's we have a ton of
RFC's that we we have RFC's for st4 I
mean IP version 5 the amount of junk in
our FCC is is large and that's a
positive thing we should worry about how
we shape the discussion and how we shape
the community more than we worry about
getting yet another piece of operational
advice into the RFC serious thank you so
expensive Arkansas responseware director
talking about what I am curious about
and my curiosity does not have to be
satisfied here is if people are already
going to be doing partial reliability
with one message with prestream this way
whether there is what the what the
incentive for doing partial liability
some other way might be and like I say
that may be that may be a conversation
you all can have with me after the
plenary but you know I mean like or
anytime doesn't get doesn't care don't
want to spend working group travel all
right but as the guy who at least
theoretically would be doing publication
would quit yeah prepares they only
publication requests for stuff like this
at least through March you say I'm kind
of curious it may be that the person who
takes my place in March would also be
curious so said we closed the cues
awhile back that was an exemption for
Spencer but if you can make it brief go
ahead Saturday doe at an architectural
comment actually
and that is the way the Charter
describes how these things will be done
as is a series of extensions and so
there is an architectural decision
embedded in the way the Charter is
describing partial reliability and
certain other things as presumed to
occur as extensions and I think there's
a question then that's about this
document scope of whether it is
describing the applicability of cork
wick or whether it is also describing
the extensions whether they have
currently been specified as standards
track or whether they are available on
the wire because we know that this is
happening and I suggest that one way of
getting yourself out of being wrapped
around the axle on this is to put in
this document that the considerations
which derive from these extensions will
be treated separately and to create a
new document which can then handle that
in other words limit the scope of our
current ops drafts to the current set of
quick-like the current set of quick art
seats well so simply I put it the other
way listen create another document that
is for the extensions of quick and the
operations and manageability
considerations for the extensions and
then make a forward pointer that says go
there right there give your PRS there
when you have extensions because I think
the other thing that you end up risking
and the point that I think Spencer was
making is that if you don't do it that
way you end up losing partial
reliability fitting into this system
architectural II as an extension it
becomes something that an operational
practice rather than a protocol
extension and those are distinguishable
and probably not as good so that any
sort of manageability draft it's very
clear that we're only discussing the
specific version of quick because you
know we don't know what other words will
look like and maybe we can be more
explicit about this and the
applicability but I think the same
applies because like there are things we
discuss which are not invariant
they are very version specific so we can
only discuss the specific version I mean
like yeah I mean like if there are big
changes it just means that you have to
also all
new applicability statement or it would
maybe just be applicability section in a
new document whatever I don't think we
can avoid that okay
the last point on this slide is there is
an issue describing the problem that
even if you have configured your system
to not expose a connection ID it could
still be possible that your connection
that your transmission sends a
connection ID for example if you do pass
into u discovery so should we mention
this and explain this to the user that
this can happen ok so Martin Thompson
if someone provides you with the text
and that text is not bad take the text
yeah I think it's not a lot of texture
it should be possible so but we need
some input on the first two issues here
yeah I was just gonna say that I was
gonna put Martin Duke on the spot here a
little bit but saying that he's been
doing some thinking on the first one a
fair bit of thinking on the first one in
terms of its interactions with load
balancers and various other things and
it might be valuable to sort of figure
out not right now but as that draft
progresses has that effort progress is
it that doctor it's already some text in
there the question is if we're missing
yeah so month also know having a back
channel would tell me about this the
second point here my assertion here is
that if we don't specify error handling
for the application level errors in the
application the whole protocol we have
failed and so we're having them in this
document would be redundant I would
rather have them properly specified in
in those documents so Tommy asks whether
the transport level errors would elicit
reactions from the application protocol
as well and that's an API question I'm
not
or if it's quite I'm not sure if I care
about that but if I if I were to care
about that I would expect the
application level protocol to to
precisely specify what actions that
expected endpoints to take in the event
of receiving particular errors so I
would like to disagree to it but on your
first point and so far the HTTP mapping
yes you have to discuss those things in
the HTTP document but it's a
general-purpose protocol and I don't
think we will specify a mapping document
for every single application we find out
there so giving some more general
guidance might be helpful as well all
right we may disagree on that point okay
let's take this offline moreover over
time we need to be more active on these
drafts on the list so Gauri first path
MTU discovery problem what is it no it's
it's an interface question should we
because it can happen that even so you
configured your connection ID to not
show up in the packet that you might
still have it in the packet for for
example path MTU to carry purposes and
it should we want the application about
that this can happen I will think on
this but now I'll go to the path MTU
discussion next door in six month okay
we have some moral issues I put them on
a separate slide because those open
issues are more about like you know what
interface what things should be exposed
over an interface and can we give any
guidance and as we don't have an actual
abstract interface document it's like
not clear what we should do about these
questions for example the first one is
in theory it's possible that if you send
it's your RTT data and the sender the
receiver doesn't support your oddity and
tells you one round-trip time later you
actually could make a decision to not
send the same data anymore again because
they are outdated in sent new data
instead should that be exposed as an
interface of the application and if
that's exposed what guidance should we
give the application missionary Tamar
Mia I see a pattern there because you're
worried about trying to make general
discussion of things that really belong
in the application
mapping yeah I can easily see different
application making different decisions
there and I think that it does not
belong in a generic to have it be longer
if you want the purpose of what we do is
to ensure Interop sir this interim will
open at the application layer so if the
if the application mapping doesn't
describe what to do we don't get
application interrupt so trying to get
application into without having the
application specified that sums we have
a very stretch that that's I mean that's
the whole question if if there is no
general recommendation you can give it
doesn't make sense if you can say this
class of application should do this and
this class of application should do this
it make sense to give some guidance here
and I think like for the first point it
clearly is right if you are an
application that might have if you for
example if you send a request and you
might be in a situation that like this
request might not be up to date anymore
and you want to send a new request then
you don't have to retransmit the data
you can send you data there's a general
class of applications that can do that I
really believe that this is application
specific yeah I mean this this is a
question I have yeah I think this one at
least I'm not taking a general position
is application specific the within in
TLS we concluded that you had to write a
new mapping document fraud I handle 0tt
for like every single application so I
think probably this case issue a should
here as well for quick because quick
eyes like approximately the same like
RDG like properties as like you know um
as other applications I know they're
worse actually because like there's like
to pile of ways or did you keep objected
but like like one way Sergey congestion
is like a OPN mismatch right at which
point you certainly have to do something
that is not just retransmit so I think
like this is probably an awesome thing
you can make it generic guidance on I
mean we put like to say like TLS case
assembler we punted it suppose anger
like to Icarus point as well that is one
application might choose to do both
behaviors as well for instance if the AL
pn nacho
is after rejection it might want to
automatically retransmit however the ALP
end is not matched that it might want to
do another thing so an HTTP application
might want to do something if it's
supports do different ilbm types I mean
this is totally this is totally
understood the question I have is if you
have this interface you have to have a
quick application right you have a
library they provide to this interface
is it so obvious what you do what you
can do is its interface that we don't
have to recommend anything because
everybody will understand this or is
there something we need to tell people
how to use this interface correctly for
whatever application they have I mean a
more valuable thing would be the
considerations of an interface between
an application and the quick transport
see like these are the options you might
need to provide and depending on the
other aspects of what the interface
provides they can choose to express this
now where they want for instance like
use different words for this or
something like that like Apple might
have requests idempotency another thing
might have some other concept which maps
cleanly to these properties but one
might be better is like the general
considerations of like oh you do this
and this might happen these are the
you might choose one of these things
it's what I'm talking yeah I think it'd
be useful yeah so I we really do need to
finish this one up unfortunately but
Martin really quickly love Thompson I
was actually going to make that point I
was gonna say all these issues we have
not had any discussion on the list so
we're not really prepared to have a good
discussion here
thanks to Miriah for actually putting
them up on the slide so we can see them
but I'd rather not discuss any of them
yeah today and the question I have for
the folks in the room is put your hand
up if you've read one of the last two
revisions of these drafts okay you know
we need to have people take a look at
these more seriously so I have one more
general question here because we've been
talking about having a separate document
that actually discusses an interface or
an abstract interface or whatever and I
like yeah you have you have a mapping
there but like I'm actually talking
about like these kind of configuration
knobs or whatever that could be
described somewhere and I don't see this
coming up so that that's why this is
like all classic
slide because I'm not sure what to do
with this I don't think we I don't I
will not wait for this document anymore
because I don't think it's showing up
suddenly so I guess the approach would
be rather to you know a zoo more and
make a recommendation if you have this
interface you can do it right that's
makes sense I think that's kind of what
I'm just said so okay thank you okay so
let's go to the issues Martin do you
want to do this feet okay this
presentation yeah okay so I'm not gonna
take any questions or comments on this
one I think I just want to make
clarifying questions are only basically
we've had a lot of discussions about
this one the slides here are rotten but
they do contain some interesting things
that allow us me to describe the problem
that we're talking about so the problem
here is that we have the potential for a
server to be in two different states
over time so when you deploy a new
version of a protocol or roll one back
there's this period of time where you
can have connection attempts span that
change and you think you can roll out a
cluster of servers and you upgrade some
of them and have some of them still on
the old version you might find that
clients hit one so server instance and
get a version negotiation back and then
they hit another server instance and
that server instance is expected to be
able to produce exactly the same answer
and we've kind of rely on that for the
the validation process that we do
because the server's handshake message
the service transport parameters contain
essentially a copy of the version
negotiation packet and in the case where
you're deploying a new version you don't
so you just give forward a slide or two
slides even the problem here is that the
client will fail version negotiation
because the the two don't match
so that's that's problem number one
let's skip over the fix here because
that that's not necessary fixed
necessarily skip more now there we go
there we go back one so the problem here
the problem here is that we have an
incentive arrangement with the current
version negotiation scheme that that
says that the clients pick the lowest
possible version that they support all
the most widely deployed version and so
during the introduction of a new version
of the protocol the clients still remain
incentive to provide a an initial packet
in the old version because if they guess
wrong they'll get a version negotiation
roundtrip and that's you know round
trips and money and so you picked the
most widely deployed version and you
ultimately leaving the server with them
with a choice well you end up stuck with
the old version and you can sort of get
around this by remembering things that
if you talk to the server and it
supported a particular version last time
well maybe you'll try the newer version
next time it's a little more complicated
you end up in some sort of suboptimal
arrangements people thought it of course
that all service helps where you have it
but that's not not a guarantee and so
we're exploring a couple of options
around solving these problems and these
slides covered one of the options that
we discussed I don't think we're done
with that discussion yet there's I think
I've heard about four or five new ways
of sort of approaching this problem part
of part of the problem that we wanted
with one of the solutions was do nothing
even for the first one which is kind of
a little bit odd but if you think it
through it makes a bit of sense so just
wanted to make sure that people
understood that we're we're we're
grappling with this one at the moment
it's likely to take a little while
before we sorted out but this one's
pretty high priority for those of us
involved if you have a
idea that you'd like to add to the pile
I have a I have a pile already and we'll
be sending a note to the list with with
the list of the things we're considered
in the reasons why each one of them
might maybe good or bad Eck has already
started a list which is a pretty useful
thing so expect something very very soon
I hope to solve this in 17 but we'll see
how that goes one of the chain one that
several of the proposals change the
invariance so I'm a little leery about
those that's it thank you go for it
markku f5 so when we when a client gets
a version negotiation packet it is
supposed to respond the new initial is
supposed to have the same destination
connection ID correct okay so I think in
the general case that will be routed to
the same server and so we won't have
this problem so that the problem is that
if you think about the way this this is
arranged if that server is upgraded and
it still remains you know the same five
tuples same same destination connection
ID the routing remains the same you
could still have a situation where you
flip the flag that that enables the new
version in between the time where you
sent the version negotiation and then
when you continue the handshake and the
server doesn't maintain state between
those two points and so from the point
that it sends out the version
negotiation and the point that it sends
out its flight of handshake messages it
can change its mind about which versions
it supports and of course you can do
things I take the server out of rotation
and all sorts of other things like that
those are some of the ideas that people
have discussed but but ultimately you do
end up in that situation okay cuz of
Hawker my point would be there or the
destination connection ninety might
change because it's not in invariant
that the destination connection ID must
be
hey doctors it's a V one specific thing
okay so the variants of transport
parameters we were going to skip correct
[Music]
so to mutton do you have this do you
have mutton same in slide deck for the
arm I can look it up one moment
yes I know yeah but five minutes before
the meeting started if I recall
correctly I thought you'd got them to an
earlier I'm sorry mark I thought I'd yep
that's terrible here a tear will
probably have HTTP issues we can discuss
in the meantime well how about chair so
let's give it a second I I'm almost
there I think if it's where I think it
is
although the network is being really
slow yeah okay well well that's loading
let's do the HTTP issues Mike
plod so when I go back and compare what
the notable changes have been it
basically boils down to everything we
agreed last time we were going to do is
now in the draft so go back and look at
last times presentation and that
explains the changes next so a couple
smaller issues that have come up since
the interim in terms of exactly how we
want to handle things at HTTP we have
this nice spectrum where how do we get
the two settings frames from client and
server and what's the relationship
between them right now when you send
when you set up a connection the first
frame on the control stream in each
direction has to be settings frame the
client is not supposed to interpret any
of the server's responses until it's
seen the server settings frame the
server is not supposed to send anything
on a response stream until it's in the
client settings right so in the one RTT
case the server sends first as the the
half-heart et data and the 0tt case you
remember what the settings were from the
last connection client since the
settings frame in response to that and
then server will update it along with
its responses so in the declaration
style you send the settings frame as a
statement of your own capabilities and
that's it Kazuko had reached the
possibility that we don't actually have
noticeably more head-of-line blocking if
we make this a full negotiation where
you have to see the other side settings
frame whoever speaks first you have to
see their settings frame before you can
generate yours which gives us the
advantage that you can have the full
offer select negotiation but it departs
more from the HTTP style on the other
extreme if you
go to pure defaults then there and we
eliminate the head-of-line blocking the
currently exists slot so we can get out
of the head of unblocking box but that
has the drawback which is true of the
current system that when you have that
second settings frame there's no clear
marker as to when that takes effect so
you have some level of well this has
always been true but maybe I didn't know
it was true slot so basically where we
stand is we're using the h2 style which
kind of has both of these drawbacks and
if we choose to step in one direction or
the other we could get rid of one of
them
I don't know how pressing that is my
personal inclination is let's stick with
what we've got but both of these have
come up and they have certain advantages
so mutton Thompson I'm gonna speak out
against the two changes although not too
strongly against the defaults one I
noticed the full negotiation one you
have this situation where one side makes
the offer the other one makes the answer
depending on whether you're doing 0 RCT
or not and whether you've accepted it
which gets a little weird no client must
no server settings before generating
settings for him which is zero fut it
remembers the previous size so you say
the server always goes first right apply
it always responds correct yeah that's a
little weird from from the perspective
of the arrangement that we have mm-hmm
so I very much prefer not to have that
one I'm somewhat okay with having
defaults for the purposes of alleviating
the head-of-line blocking for things as
long as those defaults are really really
simple yeah so no header table use for
instance would be an it would be an
obvious one but we have some some
settings that are that are not conducive
to that like the header block size so
that leaves me back to the middle again
and I think that the head of line
blocking is tolerable and with
one walking behind the handshake anyway
so let's just live with it yeah I
hesitate with the defaults because the
default would have to be you can't use
the queue pack dynamic table at all
which is rather a drawback and having a
sufficiently small request sighs Jen
Iyengar I think I'm basically exactly
what Martin said I don't think that we
have given that the handshake packets
are already head of line blocking this
is just one more packet after that and I
think it's completely reasonable
I leave with one question do we have a
use case for the full of a negotiation
full offer select negotiation that is
pressing enough to sort of try and push
it this way
I know kaswell's gonna come up and say
something to that so I'm asking the
question and I walk out there's an
actual use case hopeful negotiation and
that is that the peer can wait for the
other
oh I'm the endpoint can't wait for
pierce signal about two particular sites
for example and decide not to create
Cuba can hold a stream or two called to
pack Dakota stream and that helps memory
constrained devices and my argument
uh-huh and my augment fall through
negotiation is that in the current form
we already have the head of line
blocking for the streams that sends
requests so having full negotiation just
moves that lock to when you send
sittings so it doesn't cause any
practical difference between the
implementations nor about how much we
see the heddle client booking so that's
my reason I prefer negotiation super
diner I'm kind of worried about given
the current state of as I've definitely
opposed to offer select offer offer
select semantics but it's and kind of
also concerned about the current state
of affairs where you have to wait for
the settings frame then I know there's a
lot of discussions happen a lot of like
considerations around this I must prefer
the defaults mode because the settings
frames we've said that it has
head of line blocking we have no idea
for instance right now because you have
to send it requires you to send like
coolest packets in point five RPG which
is more complex to do and some of the
whole nations might do it some the
limitations much is not to do it but by
default you won't get the foreign scene
and then HTP do you have this kind of
defaults mode right now where the client
speaks first before seeing the settings
frame so you know that kind of works in
this reasonable performance the other
point I wanted to make is that having
defaults might also unlock the ability
to have to use the defaults in 0rq T as
well currently when we're looking at
implementing the API to store transfer
parameters or sorry cube back parameters
and other settings frame parameters in
0rq do something it is kind of painful
to do it is doable but it's definitely
not for every not for the faint-hearted
so in that sense it might make it
simpler for people who are who want to
use defaults and who have not seen
settings for him to see like I will get
a reasonable amount of performance but I
won't get the extra performance I get by
caching the settings frame in case that
they are bigger than the default values
Alan and Dimitri on jabber
would like to say that in both
implementations they've decided to
default the queue pack table size to
zero if they need to send a response
before settings have arrived and as Erik
Kinnear myself there is some attraction
to getting rid of the head of line
blocking and doing stuff with the
defaults but again if that puts us into
an awkward case where you know yes
you've gotten rid of the head of line
blocking but you're now effectively head
of line block
doing anything useful anyway does that
really help so I could also see a world
where we go half way that we allow the
server to respond in case it hasn't seen
the client settings frame but we can be
pretty reliable that the client has seen
the server settings frame before
before it sends you requests so until
7:00 I'm hearing a lot of people saying
defaults are okay but I just don't know
how to implement it so if we if we could
see how that would be implemented then
that would be great but I don't know how
to do a default for header block size
for instance because I know that
someone's gonna want something smaller
than whatever default we pick and zero
is the only safe default we can pick and
that means don't send requests which is
a bit weird that that's not really all
that useful at that point so that's the
your back to end of line blocking at
that point so I don't know how to solve
that problem so Eric can hear yeah yeah
con that sorry different rules for
different settings which is scary
but not totally insane to to Martin's
point about if if you have things that
you can set reasonable defaults for that
brings you back to head of line blocking
does that mean that for cases where you
didn't need any of those values or or
that wouldn't have hampered you there is
some percentage of the population that
is now unblocked and everybody else is
just in the current status quo because
that may be worth the complexity of
doing it it may not be super nine Eric
doesn't zero mean that you don't
compress headers not that you can't send
any others no yeah so that's a block
size is measured by the number by the
size of the headers in it and so that
means you can't put any headers sudo
headers the works on the wire so it's
kind of awkward right yeah so if I can
interject to remind folks in h2 we have
defaults that previously exist but then
one
so you get the settings frame you could
discover reality is lower than the
defaults and so you have to be able to
deal with any setting reneging on itself
and there are cases where that gets
really ugly so one of the changes that
we decided to take early on was to say
you can never reduce a setting and
consequently you have to wait to see the
settings frame to find out what it is
prior to the settings frame it's simply
unset yes one of the reasons who I HTTP
to behaves the way Matt described
because is because it depends on the TS
version two which endpoints speaks start
speaking first because in tears I'm
going to the circuit the client speaks
facts and in one by three the server
speaks first
but in case of quick we know when the
waiter that the client speaks first or
the server speaks first so that gives us
the possibility of having full
negotiation and I'd like to also note
that quick transport actually uses that
feature to do a better negotiation so
the current way of using the
declarations form is actually contract
contract contradicting from what the
transporters and to me it seems to to me
that our I mean how we negotiate to what
the transport does would be a
simplification transport parameters a
declarative to this this is this is
currently aligned to what the transport
does for example tears are meters are
just to clarify you mean in TLS not in
quick right because quick transfer
parameters are declarative all right yes
a bit what what about what I tried to
point Hal was the transport parameters I
exchanging of quick is absolutely
exchanged in a request response way
because it's a part of the earth project
but we have
we have consistently avoided having
either side Sheen formulate their
transport parameters based on the other
side's transport parameters yeah so it's
a wild the transport mechanism for the
transport parameters is as you say the
semantics of the transport parameters
themselves are not of a an office elect
kind okay I agree with that but on the
other hand that doesn't sound like a
reason to not have a full negotiation
especially when you could have made
opening quick keep up the co2 stream for
example so offhand I'm not hearing
convergence on this so discussion
continues on the list Allen which is one
question outside of the cubic
negotiation is there any other feature
that could use office elect among the
set of things that we know about the set
of things that are in the draft now I
think the to me the primary use case of
this would be mutually exclusive
extensions so I support three different
varieties of priority scheme here are my
three now you pick one before you start
sending me priorities so clearly we
would not have that in the draft to
begin with I'm sure we can find another
way to deal with that yeah with the
hardscape yeah if you have like a
preferential if you have a particular
way of ordering things then you could
deal with that in declarative way too
right so then it boils down to basically
is the cubic question compelling enough
for us to move in this direction and be
inclined to say no but
do we want to hum ready I think we've
got the three-way split on this one have
a week I feel like it needs a little
more discussion I think we could take a
home now and go in the wrong direction
I'm I'm with you on that one
cuz I've heard people arguing for
defaults but we don't know what that
would look like yeah okay Kazuo arguing
for negotiation but I don't know what
that looks like
not really sorry I think I'd like to see
slightly more fleshed out yeah yes the
list we can compare well in the spirit
of the speed-dating thing perhaps we we
have something more fleshed out I don't
care whether it's a PR or a simply an
email outlining all of the design but if
we have something more fleshed out in a
well certain time that would be very
nice all indications are the spin bit
stuffs can take about 15 minutes
tomorrow so I'd like to check that back
for version negotiation and hopefully
solve that but we'll see
janae anger for what it's worth I don't
I'm not sensing a lot of love for the
for the defaults one so mighty does it's
a two-way split but I think we're on the
weeds at this point okay
let's move on for now but continue on a
list and flushed out of it yeah thanks
alright so next one all right so we've
also had it raised that we because we
have the length at the beginning of each
HUP frame there are cases where the
server application is going to be
generating data without a defined you
know size to end to payload but at the
same time having to write the header
with each chunk that comes out when the
chunks are potentially small in Kherson
overhead and there was a proposal to
have some way to mark that this is going
to be the end this is the header of the
last frame on the stream and everything
else on the screen
is probably data there may be a use for
this in hetero spit data is the most
compelling so next slide we can have a
spectrum that right now you length
prefix everything and the argument for
that is this is fairly late this is not
critical you know it's a it's a nice
performance win but it's not going to
change the world if we do something data
frames are the place where this gets you
the most impact but it's kind of weird
that data is the special blest frame or
we could do something entirely new in
framing initially I was thinking length
0 means runs to the end of the stream
for all frames for some implementations
that's challenging I've also heard the
proposal to have a new frame type that
says okay we're done framing and
everything else is just body well I want
apologize Mike but could you go back one
slide cause I think I just kind of like
lost the plot for a moment here okay so
basically the issue is you've got some
application above HTTP that's
dynamically generating content Sharpe
and handing it back to you in chunks as
it produces it and you don't know how
long that ultimate payload will be so
you can't just say you know payload
length type as data and start writing
but you have to take each chunk as its
handed to you length prefix it and put
it on the wire when right yes I'm with
you here but the stream frames do have
to have their length of L length right
yes but this is inside a stream frame
okay that's awesome
because they send yeah sure the apply
thing so you're talking about the
interior length here what you're so this
is saying instead of having two
wrappings that both have length prefixed
let's just let the stream frame be
sufficient
yes by Google yeah so I'm I'm a very
large fan of doing something here the
reason is I spent like the rash last
year trying to make quick actually kind
of fast and adding layers of framing
inside framing make it much more
difficult to make large content serving
fast I'm not saying I can't do it but
the the API is the more layers of
framing and lengths inside framing and
lengths you have like it just becomes
increasingly difficult on both sides to
get this right and get all the
abstractions right and and so mostly
from application performance perspective
like not having something here makes me
sad
I think the consistent rule is the most
obvious one to go with as it clearly as
a use case personally I'll also point
out that zero is currently defined as
invalid right now we're not stealing a
value or something we're defining
something that currently if you receive
a zero you are supposed to close the
connection so we're actually defining
something that's currently undefined
yeah this wouldn't be massively valuable
for it to us I mean it's nice to save
the bytes but it's mainly I think it's
gonna make a lot of implementations of
quick a lot faster and that was a big
complaint of h2 over and over is that
it's hard to make a fast implementation
and now that I've looked at ours I know
why yeah I mean I guess know that I
thought about it I have some sympathy
for this the yeah I guess I I sort of
feel like the fact that we're having
discussion needs were wrong somewhere in
the design earlier when we already like
had like this mechanism for having
frames and chunks and then instead of
like having these things which you
wanted to be Nandi machst I'm the door
on a different like thing they're like
going together and some long sequence of
bytes which it have to be MUX well so
the history for that is Google quick
puts the entire body on a separate
stream so you don't have this problem
but for covering the full flexibility of
h2 you have to be able to put a push
promise in the middle of the body and
have consistent would ring and the only
way you get
that and quickest to have it on the same
stream so you have to have frames for
the body as well as I say I have some
sympathy for this fish me I don't think
we weren't wrong somewhere like earlier
but perhaps this last thing is the right
answer given where we are the design
cycle I think I couldn't go at one point
right we went wrong somewhere in I blame
push as I think I think it is the the
idea of what special frame is very
appealing to me personally it's purely
additive for people who care about it in
terms of feet turning is of course but
it's more code and so on but I think
that it's a it's a it's a nice way to
handle the special case where you really
don't care for all the frame if you so
we just imagine a beautiful perfect
future world where there is no push you
don't really need you you could just use
all of your bodies could just be this
right unless you have to reverse yeah
you us too but language problem
yeah don't take my trailers yeah sorry
about that
if fair enough that but but even then
the common case is that you're going to
have just body on these on these streams
and I I think it's worth spending just a
little bit of time thinking about how to
optimize for the common case and if you
can if you can do the same thing which
is you know the the previous slide does
the length and I suggest that he use a
length of zero and a type of zero for
this new frame type thing it basically I
think size of zero is currently is
currently at the data frame right so so
this then becomes the length of zero for
the radar frame but anyways that's
that's that's that's encoding treating
this specially is I think valuable to do
because I expect that to be the common
case when you're looking at bytes on the
wire the other place we're having it
supported in other frame types may be
valuable was that do you can do the
headers client requests typically do not
have a body and so you just put a
headers length of 0 and then right to
kupack
yeah so looking at the time I'm gonna
cut the cue from Jabbar Dimitri says to
Ian that you'd still have to support
piers that frame data which means that
the complexity argument is moot unless
you advocate dropping size 2 HQ frames
cuz the hope I just wanted to point out
that server timings as a trailer is
there pretty much pretty useful use case
for trailers and I hope that many
service was supported here again full
Sun concrete proposal more more pleasure
data to diversity okay right now alright
one more issue that's been brought up
again something that we have somewhat
lost in the transition from H 2 and H 2
you have the priority information
embedded in the header screen and then
you can use priority frames subsequently
to change it we can't do that with quick
because you don't have a defined
ordering between things and so
priorities have to be on a stream that
gives you a consistent ordering of all
the changes to the priority tree now the
issue that that creates is until that
priority frame arrives you don't know
what priority the request should have
and it's possible that a request is
comes in gets processed and start
streaming back before you ever discover
where if it's entirely tree so I don't
really have a proposal here because
everything that I have been able to come
up with is still subject to ordering Ken
screw something up and so I think here
the question is how upset are we about
that and if we are upset about it does
anyone have any bright ideas that they'd
like to
[Music]
so Martin Thompson I wanted to add to
the piles about ask the question so
what's the default priority and in h2
the default priority is you're attached
to stream 0 because stream 0 is the
control stream yeah rule of three
whoops and so there is that problem root
of the tree is that is the answer we
have a default and I think we just have
to accept the fact that we have a gap
and live with it because ultimately I'll
use the f-word in conjunction with
priority just like Jonah did with push
yeah yeah fun so I think we just have to
accept it and move on ok yep does anyone
feel strongly in the other direction or
shall I close the issue
okay next is it worth adding a little
text maybe yeah definitely one thing
that we need to mention right now we
point to 7540 for the priority scheme
including the default priority of
request when they are first issued we
should probably at least clarify that
you're not actually a child of stream 0
you a child at the root of the tree but
also talk about the gap maybe right yeah
ok ok so next slide last question around
the HPP draft is about naming and I'm
kind of full so I'm going to pull from a
children's story that my cousin
introduced me to last week
Hicks lied where mrs. McKay has 23 kids
all of them named dave and she's really
regretting that choice and coming up
with all sorts of names that she wishes
she has given them but they're already
named and it's too late well quick is
not yet in the situation
we'd be--we'd really you're saying we
should name this Zanzibar buck buck
McFate I second that
but quickie make quick face so in terms
of what we call HTTP over quick
which does not exactly roll off the
tongue and doesn't have an obvious
relationship to HTTP 1.1 - please stop
calling that hb2 over quick it has
changed dramatically it's really not
that it's not really quick because quick
is the transport and when we discussed
in Montreal several of the changes that
we've made in HQ and whether we want to
bring them this extension stage should
be to the decision was no we don't
because quick is the future assuming all
this works out and we should keep moving
forward so that suggests perhaps a name
that does have a relationship to h1 and
h2 indicating that we're continuing to
move forward into the future first let
me see those eyes scare the pants off me
I'm talking pure about you know a pair
of pale green pants with nobody inside
them I mean I'm not gonna lie down the
road over this but I think it sucks you
know it gives the impression that like
nobody's like that like HTTP was
deprecated which it is not um it gives
the impression that like if we ever want
to extend HTTP - we're not going to
and I mean fundamentally what this is
it's a fork with one fork getting longer
and one for not getting very long very
fast that's what operationally is
happening um and maybe we decided not to
do a lot of maintenance on CB - maybe we
omit maybe we don't
but like this sort of like it's just
over your brand name twice but I've said
my piece I'm overruled then also the
forgot okay if I can just respond to
that real quick h2 didn't deprecated h1
so I'm not sure where you're getting
those implications and TLS 1.3 is not
deprecated what - I absolutely did
it's in its precise it was in the header
yeah well h2 did not obsolete h1 we go
around telling people they really ought
to use h2 like if you are we gonna go
around telling people to use quick I did
I don't think I think that like yeah
like I think I'm telling people like you
want like ought not to use h2 you ought
to use quick like universally know um so
again like you know I'm not gonna like
light on the river this but like I I
don't think it's great idea and I'd like
to see a homily tell people the same
thing that we actually do tell them
about h2 which is you should use h2
unless there's a reason you can't
in which case h1 is there and gen
Iyengar so many thoughts first that
totally looks like a sense above the
screen oh come on it's it's gotten my
creative juices flowing this is lovely
and ironically you said quick is the
future and this is ironical because it
depends on which quick you are talking
about right that is a quick which is the
present and that points us to a problem
here we already have a Google quick and
an IETF quick and we have trouble
keeping them apart so I think it's very
useful to have a new name first second
I'll agree with
a girl that there is a little bit of
signalling issue here it'd be nice to
have an itch to prime but we can't
maybe we can it is asking a presentable
can we do h2 Prime
the chairs are staring at me and given
given that everything else is a rat hole
I think HTTP 3 is the best idea that
makes sense but yeah I mean I can get
behind htv3 given that we might have to
make sure that the signaling is
meaningful around that sure and so I
want to emphasize when when I sent the
email out that instigated this I pointed
out we do not want a rat hole on this or
not we do not want to spend a tremendous
amount of time we want to see if we can
get to consensus on this proposal so
let's let's not throw other names out
please quite yeah and I will emphasize
one other thing from the email which is
that to call it it's gp3 I think we
wanted the HTTP working groups input
anyway but to continue their naming
sequence we probably want their okay on
the name change as well so we'll be not
probably yeah so we'll be discussing
that in the HTTP working group tomorrow
yes yes set her T and it was actually
getting up to ask a scoping question
right so there are places where this
string will appear in protocols and
there are places where you intend for
this string to be in the signaling
you're giving to the larger community do
you think those two actually have to
match because in the strings I can
certainly see a reason for doing HDB qv1
right hhq one as an indication in the
protocol string of where we are
this is HTTP over quick the first
version of saying that's different from
HTTP three but in a in a protocol
version reasoning it may be the right
thing to do I wouldn't go signaling to
people with HQ one because they're gonna
get confused with Amazon and HQ two
it's not it's not good marketing but it
may be good protocol and I think you
should be very clear here which scope it
is you're trying to solve here because
otherwise the rest of these rats in the
line and I'm counting myself as the
first rat in it are gonna be trying to
brush different colors on the shed
without knowing which it is they're
trying to paint so I will bring up an
email to answer that question and I
believe it states hopefully fairly clear
to go here we are we rename our hourly
HTTP document the hp3 and using the
finally appealant a OPN took an h3 and
just to respond to Ted there quickly
personally I think that having
divergence between the token and the
name that we use for the protocol is not
gonna help solve any confusion that has
worked really well for a TLS 3.4 yeah
Colin Colin so I don't really
care but why don't we just call HQ since
everyone's gonna call it that anyway
that's okay Pat McManus I'm I'd like to
emphasize that this more we will talk
about this in hte bits on Thursday yeah
as that the previous slide had talked
about this really is sort of an outcome
of HP misses previous discussion in
Montreal and sort of underline some like
questions people people ask like is h3 a
successor to h2 that we would recommend
I mean the answer to that would be yes I
mean we really do without deprecating
and but we are saying that we believe
this is superior and that's why we're
pursuing this work and similarly you
know it's going to maintain the
backwards-compatible semantics promises
of HTTP which are being better stated
with HDTV core right now but I've always
existed and that that is compatible
which is much more obvious to phrase to
b3 than it would be for quick right
because that's all so yeah this is this
is obvious and the
discussion we had about back loading
features underlines the fact that you
know the HP working group is willing to
take on maintenance of this and view
this as the place where new extensions
and things should really be focused
please PLEASE call it HTTP three because
many logging systems only accept
expected version number to change and
please please don't call it version 2.1
because we've already said that button
to we don't have a mine unfortunate
number and that's how people expect
spencer dawkins probably for the second
for the for this moment special honorary
director just as just as a thought for
the chairs and walk as the ops area
director who became the yang area
director had a proposal for semantic
versioning versioning and stuff like
that for yang models and things like
that that would be moving very quickly
it might be taking worth taking a look
at that and seeing if that was something
you wanted to come even close to touch
and I don't mean clicked
close to using I mean close to touching
but you know there are the places in the
ITF that are wrestling with version
numbers that are with versioning for
things that are moving pretty darn fast
and so just there's a personal
observation so speaking as an individual
I spent enough time hanging around
transport when transport
changes usually meant operating system
upgrades on a good day
to where the you know the idea that a
version of something could change as
quickly as quick versions could change
if the working group agreed on it
quickly
you know agreed to move quickly the
underlying for quick the underlying
transport yeah well hopefully rather
quickly but this is the HTTP binding
which hopefully won't okay okay cool so
like I say it's convenient it's
convenient that they are
see my title a couple together back to
speaking as an area director I'll sit
down whatever you guys decide as an act
of love and devotion
please make any needed charter changes
before the new guy shows up because I
think I think the new person may hate me
for other reasons but I would like for
him or her to like or it might be
because why is if you believe that we
need to make a charter change to change
the name of our deliverables we should
probably have a chat to make sure we
understand each other way into that of
one and I'm just looking at the line it
says beginning with HTTP two so like I
say I think it's all arranged running
the Charter or yeah and you know having
a chat is not a threat anymore than
having it discuss or the document is a
threat so you please let's chat I'm here
all week
okay I'm gonna insert myself in the
queue virtually as me so imagine I'm
standing over there from my personal
standpoint the the naming of HTTP needs
to stay within the control of the HTTP
community and so I would personally I
think that this needs to be driven from
them logically it's our deliverable here
so we need to have the conversation here
- HTTP is defined by a core set of
semantics that is not version dependent
and in my opinion calling the
deliverable anything but htv-3 sends a
confusing message about the lineage of
HTTP and how its forked you know it
looks like a fork if we don't call it
HTTP three so I actually I'm 180 degrees
from Eckler on that and so I'd ask folks
to keep that in mind that you know we're
not naming quick here we're naming an
HTTP version and we should follow the
conventions of HTTP versioning and let
that community make the decision so
London Thomson I agree with that apart
from the point where you said that it
looks like a fork which I agree with
but the implied thing was that that was
bad
but it is a fork well no a fork at the
semantic layer because while little
people in this room are concerned about
implementing what happens in the wire
99% of the people who deal with HTTP or
dealing from the other side of using it
as an application protocol sure and we
don't want to confuse them yeah as long
as it says I should you pay in the name
I think I'm Pepe all right so this is my
so are we ready to hum on that then to
get a sense of how people feel about
renaming that document with that
proposal on the on the screen okay so
I'll do - hums if you support renaming
to this and then if you do not support
renaming to this make sense okay so
please hum now if you support this
rename - HTTP 3 and please hum now if
you do not support
Renate this renaming I will let my
co-chair to characterize the hum it's
pretty strongly in favor from where I'm
sitting but there was some some nonzero
objections so I would say like 70/30
something like that maybe okay so
normally with this sort of thing I think
we'd say take it to the list I'm a
little wary of doing that I heard people
get up and say that they didn't like it
but they wouldn't lie down in the road
is there anyone who feels that this
would be an issue that they would be
incredibly unhappy about you could have
been do you want to hum if people are
okay to let the HTTP group decide
that's a great question thank you I'll
do again a yes I'm gonna no home yes if
you support that taking it to the HTTP
working group does anyone disagree with
this well I hope not but let's find out
because I could just come to them I can
say okay well the point of harming is is
that you can express the opinion without
you know putting yourself through the
drama
like I know it's easy for you you do it
a lot so if you support letting the HIV
working group decide this hum and if you
do not please hum that was nice and
straight cool okay thank you for that
we're running low on yeah we got five
minutes I did a quick agenda refresh to
make it clear that the if time permits
stuff we might not get to add to all of
it or or any of it today will extend
into the overflow time tomorrow where
hopefully since the spin the discussion
apparently takes 15 minutes we're gonna
have lots of time um but if any of those
presentations can anybody make useful
use of those five minutes you can Martin
okay come here optimistically and we'll
see so I was talking about initial
packets with Christian at the hackathon
next slide and we always talk about the
injection attack that yeah and on path
attacker can can disrupt the hinge can
disrupt the connection during the
handshake but not afterwards and it
turns out that as things currently stand
this is not quite correct so what an
attacker can do is he can send a spoofed
initial packet for example containing a
connection close frame or containing a
malformed packet containing a malformed
frame there endless possibilities how
how he can cause a protocol error that
would close the connection and what what
we currently do is we say that every
endpoint accepts initial packets accepts
and processes initial packets at least
three are TOS after all initial data has
been received and act and since at that
point of the
we don't have a good RTG estimate we
RTOS might be as much as 600
milliseconds even on fast connections so
this would be after the handshake long
after the handshake actually completes
if you look at the if you look at the
the diagram we only need initial packets
in the in the first flight until the
more precisely until the client has
received the server hello when the
client has received the server hello its
which is to handshake keys and it won't
need the initial keys anymore and for
the server as soon as it receives the
handshake packet it knows that that the
server hello was received and doesn't
need to be retransmitted so it doesn't
need to accept any initial packets after
after receiving the first handshake
packet so what we have here is basically
a three-way handshake and only during
this we where handshake are we can an
attacker disrupt you disrupt us if we
stop processing initial packets next
slide so the proposal here is to treat
initial as the specialist no flag that
it is we we should stop accepting and
retransmitting initials at the at the
points that I just described which are
different for client at server this has
a few implications for how we do loss
recovery because stopping to process
initial packets also means that we might
not receive an AK for a packet that we
that we send for example the server
might never receive an act for the
server hello that it's end so we need to
we need to make that might have some
text about that that the server should
actually stop retransmitting this over
hello even if it didn't get the act and
there are some some implications for
congestion as well because we want we
need to tell the congestion controller
to remove those those bytes in flight
this is something we need to do we need
to do anyway it's just make very very
pressing with this issue if we actually
stop aking yes thank you for using this
issue
PR 1819 was my attempt to deal with this
by basically allowing receivers to drop
initial packets if they if they disrupt
the connection in exactly surfacing as
you described that PR has died for a
lack of enthusiasm I guess I'm not sure
what the process is to resurrect it if
people want or as a wreck fit or if the
people who killed that wanted to explain
why that's fine too but I think the
issue was that you use with your PR you
would still need the AK right so you
can't just stop processing initial
packets so so another we just ran out of
time and and one suggestion would be
that since there are people that I'm
like be really quick and then also catch
Martin and maybe you guys can chat and
tell us what we're gonna do with this
tomorrow briefly but but going where's
the other blue Shh
anyone thank you as a whole we've
repeatedly had these up to this
discussion since May where we change the
contract design and I'm not against
having this information in the security
considerations but I would oppose to
changing this at a later moment why this
is living my vision no it's not it's
closing an attack service that we are
merging against attacks yes which is
different from shaving of by it's
alright so this is the end we got the
blue sheets thank you all come back
tomorrow we hopefully we'll get to more
of the if time permits things tomorrow
including a QA on them maybe twenty
minutes in the spin bit
[Music]