good afternoon this is the session you
were all looking forward to not just
because it's the last session of the
week but because it's the routing area
open meeting I'm just gonna wait for
someone to close the door then you can
all person to applause and cheers and
everything else nothing there we go
thank you okay so welcome to the roadie
rubbing every open meeting thank you
I am Alvaro
this is Martin and that's Debra so
please don't get confused Bob okay I'm
the other guy yes so just to make sure
yeah okay so this is not well
even though many of you think that
you've seen it many times
please look at it again first of all
because I've seen many working groups
show the all-russian of the note well
this is the actual right version now
this version talks about intellectual
property yes just like the old one
also has pointers to things like the
code of conduct how many of you were the
ITF plenary last night okay maybe six of
you so there was say a long set of
people too many for my taste one is to
many honestly who came to the microphone
to talk about not the best conduct in
the ITF people being attacked directly
people not being given the chance to
express their opinion and sort to
explain their ideas and so it's
important that we understand that that
is obviously not the way we should
behave in the ATF I have no specifics or
no knowledge of anything of this
happening in the routing area but you
know it's important for us to to be on
the lookout for that especially for the
chairs as we conduct our meetings to
make sure that we give everyone chance
to to speak everyone a chance to present
their opinion defend their proposals you
know whatever they're doing and that's
the other reason why again this is the
note well it's important because it
talks about intellectual property and
some of the links at the bottom are
about for example the code of conduct
and the anti anti harassment procedures
in the IETF
so please make sure that you read them
and you're familiar with that there's
also some links that we have here for
other materials in the routing area as
you can go take a look at absolute
meeting there's blue sheets are going
around somewhere is anyone on the jabber
room by any chance can someone please
get on the jabber room just in case we
have someone thank you drew well there
we have several people remote if the
remote people are listening which I hope
they are yes you can use if you have a
room if you want to say something you
can also come to the mic and we'll see
you from here and we can let you speak
as well so here's the agenda we're going
to talk about the area of course first
then we're going to have the routing
directorate report
and then we're going to have an update
one year later of where we are with DC
routing work and then hopefully at the
end we'll have some time for for any
other things that you guys want to talk
about so as always we want to request
that you review documents we s3 and the
rest of the is you have to read
everything and sometimes it looks like
the documents were not reviewed properly
in the working groups you have the
routing area Directorate which does a
lot of reviews and it helps a lot but
please make sure that the other are
people reviewing the documents through
adoption and that last call and
discussion if you need to grab
volunteers or volunteer someone please
do that to make sure that the quality of
the documents goes up as much as
possible Tony 20-piece the first comment
so I was like no I was thinking that the
Shepherd's were mildly useless I
completely changed my opinion disrespect
their excellent no I know specifically
in this respect right if you get a
volunteer especially your guy he will
just come through this thing thank you
thanks really good comment separates are
not only supposed to review documents as
well as the chairs they're supposed to
also Shepherd that's why it's called
Shepherd the document through the rest
of the process so if you're a shepherd
remember that your job doesn't end when
you fill out the Shepherd right up
that's just the beginning right you
still have to go through the whole
process in case you know there's some
stick up with AG or you know some review
later to you know help the authors go
through that yes we want everyone to do
reviews right we expect shepherds and
chairs to do it but we want everyone to
collaborate I mean this is why we do
working groups right we don't do in the
visual documents the the product is the
product of the working group not just
with the author's
one of the things that we notice is
we've been reviewing documents is that
not all of you are aware of the new
changes that came in in RFC 8174 RFC 21
19 is where all the normative language
is explained must and should and all
those nice words there sometimes is
confusion when we use capital letters
and non-capital letters in the text and
so 8174 clarifies that this is the whole
text that changed from 2119 which
bracele says that when you use capital
letters they mean what 31:19 says if you
don't then it means whatever the
dictionary says that that word is right
it also says something else that is
important in that not every
specification to be normative has to use
29 18 21 19 keywords but you can still
make a specification normative and clear
without necessarily using those words so
just the action here is please make sure
that the documents don't have the
alternate 119 boilerplate that we use
the one at the bottom here that lists
the key words it also makes reference to
BC 14 which is 21 19 and this new RFC 81
so 84 we're always looking for feedback
please talk to us about ourselves talk
to us a lot each other you know anyway
you want to provide us with feedback of
things that we're doing well or
especially things of me to improve
please let us know
this Center of the year is very
important because as you know the NomCom
or so I hope you know the NomCom has
been interviews for routing at the
replacements because Debra and I both
expire at the next IETF so please go
talk to the NomCom they're still here
there's several of you in the room who
are part of the NomCom
Carlos you guys stand up so they see you
Victor it said no one else and I'll come
here I don't see you but in case you
want to give feedback you can talk to
them you can go to the webpage data
tracker slash mount come slash 28:18 and
provide feedback there the feedback can
be anonymous if you want to I'm sure
that you can tell them and give them an
honest feedback and that they can
anonymize it for you as well usually
they use that not only to make the
selection for routing ad or for any ad
in this case but they have been doing
for the last couple of years they have
given us feedback and what the community
says so that we can improve so if you
don't feel like talking to us directly
especially bad go talk to the NomCom and
they can't take care of taking down into
consideration for selection and to give
us feedback later also this is not just
about about any of you once we get
feedback about some other ladies you can
do that if you want to get feedback
about the whole ASG you can do this well
the feedback is important because we are
of course a community yes and there were
just remind me the other slate that's
out there is the IAB and there's also
candidates for the new IETF LLC and the
ATF trust if you don't know what those
are please go to the plenary next time
oh the other thing they will say here is
that we are always on the lookout to
grow the leadership talent inside the
area it was important because we the
three of us are probably not going to do
the ad work forever
the chairs change once in a while so
we're always looking to to find people
who can do those jobs are willing to do
it this time
unfortunately 80 percent of the
candidates for outing ad declined the
nomination that means
couple things it begins the head there
was a good pool of people that were
nominated you know ten nominees were
outing it he was was a good poll but a
tips on the client which means that only
to accept it and there's two slots so
yeah you can do the math you can add now
that doesn't mean that it's an automatic
selection the NomCom is going through
the process anyways that's why I invite
you to go give them feedback because if
we are not the right people or
especially if we need to improve right
you know please let them know and the
two people that accept it of course
never and I so we're going to a third
term I don't know many a these who go
past a third term so we need to keep
that in mind right for the next time and
hopefully we have a lot more people who
accept nominations the next time around
so the area status is really simple we
closed one working group we finally
finished work insider and we published
all the RFC's and weari chartered one
spring we don't have any new work since
the last idea this is the distribution
of working groups hopefully you all know
who your responsibility is we routinely
meet with the chairs and about once a
month or so at least two or three times
between each HF there's a lot of
different things we do training
sometimes we talk about area things we
have obviously your management type
stuff you have always loved this meeting
because we used to give updates of the
working groups we used to lighten up all
the chairs that everyone will give a two
minute update of what they're working
was doing this year at the start of this
year we changed that a little bit where
we have been using some time to you know
socialize a little bit more which was at
the first ITF of the year when we had
the routing ad change when idea was
replaced by Martin
and we've been putting the status
updates from the wiki how many of you
know where the wiki is okay how many of
you who are not a chair know where the
way he is okay so we figured that you
know the the wiki has been useful but
probably not as useful as we would want
so in one of the last meetings that we
have the chairs we talked about changing
the the audience that we're making the
the updates for so what we hope you
start seeing now is a status update on
the page of the data tracker working
group yes so you should be able to go
look at that and get an update so you
know or more importantly so that
external people maybe people who come to
the ATF too much maybe people who are
not participating in specific working
group but do come to the ATF get a sense
of what the workgroup is doing what are
they interesting things that are going
on so we should start seeing that that
now this time we're running this is an
experiment we should still see the
updates in the wiki which is the last
link there at the bottom so that's that
questions comments nothing okay everyone
still there the other thing that we've
been talking to the chairs about and I
actually heard it mentioned in a total
of two working groups that I attended
this week we've been talking about
implementation requirement policies this
came from a question that was brought up
at the plenary in ITF 102 where it was
asked about implementation requirements
in the ATF as a whole
Thanks or the IAG had discussed that and
we decided it was really hard to have
one policy for everyone so we decided
that this would be better served working
by working group
there are working groups that already
have policies everyone knows that
everyone in the ATF actually knows about
ID arsh policy which is to interoperable
implementations and there is
documentation of that on the on the wiki
as well in the earlier wiki of them
plantation-style etcetera but not every
working group has an implementation
policy so we have asked the chairs to go
and think about that to consider what
the implementation requirement policy
for their working group is so we hope
that this soon will come up in a list
near you for that discussion this
doesn't mean that every working group
should require two implementations for
interoperable implementations or
anything like that this means that we
hope there is a policy for the work so
the work group may decide that the
policy is five interoperable
implementations may decide to may decide
one and may decide that what we want is
a RFC 79 42 type section and the RCS or
in the drafts it may decide that there
is no requirement there's many reasons
but we want this for the chairs and
hopefully in connection with their
working you think about this and
considerate so that you know we can
actually articulate what that policy is
I hope the working participants or by
you anyone else who is or by you know a
sir it's ever so Stewart you surely the
name Stewart III didn't realize he'd put
it there but I was really worried that
one size doesn't fit all in any working
group so whatever your policy is you
need the chair exception or the ADA
exception or something or other because
you know you know I'm there are always
cases where it's an information about
something or it's a correction that
everyone knows needs to be had or
whatever there always needs to be an
exception are you in history
and that's part of the policy writing
down that exception mechanism I believe
I think it's so universal it's a uniform
that it probably would apply to the
whole area regardless of what the
current chairs think because sooner or
later they'll discover there's some some
reason why they need to publish an RFC
and they may or may not yet be any
implementations of it early also but it
doesn't it doesn't hurt to write it down
explicitly okay yeah so there's been
several suggestions of where we can put
this it could be in the status update it
could be somewhere else on the on the
air tracker itself some worker groups
have a wiki page when we discuss this
with the chairs someone's just so that
maybe we could even make it part of the
Charter so one size doesn't fit all and
the ten here is for everyone to have a
policy you know we are the IETF we will
need an order code so you'll be good to
at least substan what the policy is
there are many reasons why we may or may
not require from the protocol that we're
that we're developing the market that
we're serving the type of industry you
know many many things why you would want
or not to have requirement
implementations in your working group
okay so now we're gonna go into the
routing Directorate report it's going to
be John or Amy
[Music]
just to let folks know I'm John has told
us the very bad news and he's stepping
down as pce chair and also for for this
so actually we're on the lookout to help
somebody to help Amy okay so if anybody
would like to to step up to this to help
out they can tell you what it involves
and we'd really appreciate it and we
thank John very very much for everything
he's done for us thanks Deborah okay so
the ransom to rights report and it's
Debra says it's my swan song for this
role so I'm one of the coordinators Amy
is the one you want to give away baby
yeah so just to remind everyone what the
Directorate does there's a panel of last
time I counted 49 routing area experts
who are awesome people who freely give
their time to help the ADEs in
processing all the many drafts that we
have to go through in the routing area
they're appointed by the ADEs they're
the purpose of having a Directorate is
basically to ensure quality of the
drafts so we review most of the routing
area drafts as they pass through ITF
last call we will review from time to
time other routes and related drafts at
IETF last call as well if you're a
working group chair you always have the
opportunity to ask the Directorate to
perform an early review of any draft
that you have in your working group it's
useful particularly if you feel that a
draft needs more review and you're not
getting that review inside your working
groups to get some eyes on that from the
Directorate and from time to time but
the rector will assist the ADEs in
making judgment calls about particular
issues although that hasn't happened for
a while you can find out more on the
public e I got some stats to show you
these are the stats for 2018 cover
the whole year so the graph there on the
Left shows the reviews have to come in
and reviews the blue column shows total
than the orange shows the reviews that
the 80s sent to the Directorate and the
gray shows the reviews of the chairs
sent to the Directorate and and you can
see but at the start of year we had a
lot of reviews because for chair of the
the 80s of a keeping is very busy with
with 40 reviews of the ITF 101 period
that's tape it off from the ADEs in the
next two periods but the the chairs have
increased for load that they've been
putting on us so it's nice to see where
we'd be getting somewhat early reviews
requests coming in from the chairs I'd
like to see more about because I think
it's actually useful but when Dawkins
comes ITF last call of the Directorate
have already seen them then we already
have someone ramps up on the draft and
the draft is presumably already had the
benefit of them looking at it but the
graph on the right shows which working
groups have been sending reviews to us
and as you can see there's a mixture of
working groups that don't send us
anything and working groups and there's
quite a bit but actually most of the
reviews or probably nothing like one
third of reviews come from outside there
at the razzing area altogether and
certainly no one working group loads as
much as the rest of the ITF so few more
stats what do we find in our reviews the
graph on the Left shows what do we find
when we actually review documents from
inside the area well half of those
documents we find issues and
occasionally we will send the document
back through the working group and say
look this is not ready where there are
major issues and we don't think it's
ready to be published obviously that's
the chairs in the ad to really decide
what happens to the document but it does
sometimes happen it must the
three-percent slicing the pie charter
sometimes we just think that reviews are
perfect and the rest of the time we'll
find some needs but nothing to block the
draft
part of the right is the same thing but
for drafts coming from outside
area so again but pretty similar I think
that generally we find slightly fewer
issues in those sorts of drafts probably
because of the background required to
review them in depth but but we still do
a pretty good job of haunting out issues
and one thing I think is interesting is
of these types of graphs are quite
stable across time so I was looking at a
presentation that I did one year ago and
the pie chart I showed there and they
pretty much look the same as us in terms
of the distribution of issues or not
clarifying question
I mean it's as in ID myths or are they
nits as in minor trivial comments yeah
thanks to it they on this as in
editorial and or minor comments which
would know a lot of Blocker publication
we think you know fix this in passing no
that's fine yeah
so that's it so yeah summary the the
rate read do do very useful work very
good at finding issues please use them
as much as you can thank you
so now we're going to go into an update
on that they are Center routing work so
if you remember a year ago we'd met in
Singapore and in Singapore we had a a
bar about DC routing the intent of that
bar was to talk about the requirements
and potential interest of the community
in working on new road and proposals to
be used in a data center that both we
asked you know how many people are
interested in a couple of the
represented there and the other thing to
be interest in that so now when you're
later would want to do is provide an
update or where we are and also at the
same time to try to renew the interest
in these proposals and you know people
participate in the work groups as well
so we're gonna have an update from
Ella's VR and from rift on
where they are and what the thing was G
is about so Gunther I think this one
percent this one hello everybody so what
I'm doing here besides freezing is you
know coming to the realization that I've
been blessed to entertain you all with
my you know least eight victor routing
you know technology so indeed we started
this journey about like you know about a
year and a half ago when we start to
explore this space and about a year ago
we started with like you know think
about charging this this particular
rocking group so I'm gonna be covering
like you know more like you know what it
is about and some of the topics which
you know keep us like an old you know
kind of warm and where we are right now
with the working group so initially you
know when the working group actually got
started I thought I gave is a very clear
message actually said like okay guys you
have like one year to actually you know
deliver like a set of documents and
after the year I will actually assess
how well you know everything actually
has progressed and if to also understand
if you like any real major you know gate
stops or something like that and then
we're gonna see you know what will be
happening and afterwards with a
particular work so I think at this point
in time so the actually you know that
gave us like the scare of our life
because it meant you know one year to
actually do anything in the idea that's
quite dramatical you know challenge so
one of the things we were you know let
me see if I can get okay so one of the
artifacts what we realized is that a lot
of work actually is happening each time
you know when people go towards the ITF
do a lot of work and then it's like
nothing and then you go to write you lot
of work again and there is nothing
so knowing out very short you know
timeline what we had available we said
okay you know in between IDs we have to
do some interim meetings so that is what
you know we are doing also and and
so you know from what I'm seeing it
really helps well in keeping continuous
evolution actually in your deliverables
so if you're not doing it actually I
would highly recommend you know to
really start not thinking about it it
really brings you know progress in the
work you're delivering so initially when
we started you know our journey in the
data center you know we were just trying
to understand you know why is data
center routing different from any other
kind of environments now about a year
and a half year ago we actually did some
you know some further analysis about it
now I think about like a week week and a
half two weeks ago there was an anode
meeting and actually it was a very good
you know overview by by Tony Lee and by
Chris Martin on white data center you
know routing environment actually has
some slightly different properties than
routing in the traditional you know one
networking environment so it actually
speaks about some of the problem and of
problematic since wards now at the same
time this presentation also has like
some no interesting comparison between
the different kind of mechanisms so I
put the link in here just you know as a
background set of information so going
to my agenda I have about like 120
slides have about 30 minutes so I'm
trying to keep up with everybody here
huh so also you know just be aware you
know make sure you know I am the chair
but I'm not the smartest person in the
room it's like it would be half if there
would be any person here with a very
difficult question then we have like
smart people that mean room actually
wrote those particular specifications so
they were actually you know give you the
answer and the one thought actually I
will give you is that you know the one
thing that is more scary than a question
is an answer so think about that one so
there is something I've learned you know
my journey here at IETF some very smart
people here so my agenda is first to
actually go over like you know where we
are with you know least I depicted
routing so what our milestones and an
embedded we are I know what are the
deliverables then I'm gonna give like a
very high-level overview about like you
know what is the technology about and
then at the end something you know I
only have like one slide because I
didn't really know you know what was
going to happen
exactly my working group today because
you know every day is a surprise and
everybody it's always like a miraculous
kind of thing what happens unite your
working groups so now I know I just lost
it so and that's still alive so let's go
on so this is where we are we started in
Singapore a year ago we are almost at
the end of our journey at the next ideas
we're gonna not really you know try to
assess know how stable is our
specification where are we and you know
and also try to understand like you know
where is the you know growing interest
in you know from the people you know
applying these kind of technologies so
going forward we have like one in two
incoming and then at the end you know
ITF 104 in Prague you know we'll see you
know what's going to be happening yes so
so from a milestone perspective we only
have a few because we only had a few
months work to actually you know given
to us to work on these things so the
main thing is we have an applicability
statement like you know we're you know
does it make the most sense to use links
that vector routing how can you apply it
because there are like different kind of
you know application models you know how
you can't really you know use this thing
and then we have like two other
deliverables you know it's like speaking
about like you know how to use links as
Victor out of extender to Dykstra and
how to use link States Victor you know
distribution using BGP transport so the
last two we put into one single document
just you know from a simplicity
perspective and from a readability
perspective and also because you know we
already had like some work you know you
know previous alternate space so it
seemed as a logical thing to do you know
to progress the work forward because we
only had like limited amount of time we
also were given the task to actually
look into yang and so we're waiting a
few dependencies there on some other
working groups to to progress also once
that is done or more stable we're gonna
keep on progressing at work also now the
good thing is that there is some sort of
an ambition to keep this thing living
because March 2019 was kind of like our
deadline but this deadline for this yang
thing is like in July so it sneaky done
at the door a little bit so we still
have hopes so looking into the LS of
your components so
the way we see link state vector routing
it's sort of you know exists sort of
like four different you know areas here
so the first one if you look at the
ground you know at the bottom one is
like each router yeah and I need to
describe itself me to describe these
neighbors and B to describe the cost of
artists neighbors and it's actually I
saw you know assess also some other
attributes to it but the minimum set is
like Who am I who is my neighbor and
I'll do you know what is the cost of
arts my neighbor so you need to harvest
that in some sort of a way so that is
something you know which can be done via
and our whole set of different protocols
we have been you know discussing the
solution space for that the different
protocols what actually are out there
the two most you know obvious ones which
actually provide us the right hooks to
that information would be like you know
link state over Ethernet or lldp and
right now you know in the in our working
group you know we actually are going to
start a working group adoption con for
the link set over Ethernet elements so
from the moment actually of harvest that
set of information you need to encode it
into something so and the way we encode
it you know we actually encoded into
what we call like link state vectors so
this actually is just you know an
encoding you know mechanism to describe
you know the router itself with the
neighbors and wanted to post well if the
neighbors as a minimum set so you can
actually compare this as the same is
like you know really nice yes like a
link set packet or like you know SPF you
can actually compare the two links that
you know total as a basically so that's
what you're doing now the mechanism what
we are using a link state vector routing
because we are you know looking very
close into like you know in some
previous art and what worked actually
well and what actually can be scrapped
already so we don't always have to
reinvent the wheel so we say okay you
know for these kind of things we just
use like bt pls encoding it's very out
there it's proven everybody knows how it
works and from my experience we can grow
it as big as you know whatever it's like
you know a big massive thing we can do
it whatever we desire right now our
desire is just put like only a few
things actually into it that is just the
encoding
now from the moment you describe your
router you link state vector you need to
distribute those things
I know those elements of the router
between all the
and routers in the environment so that
is actually our floating mechanism so
the way we are doing that and so each
link state you know victim can be
reflected as as an NL or I and so it can
actually be distributed by BGP and
that's what we're using so in our case
we are just using BGP as a distribution
mechanism now again from a link steady
vector routing perspective there is only
one of the choices why do we use BGP I
will explain later on but right now you
know it is seen as you know something
which is out there and it seems to make
sense at this point in time from a time
to market you know perspective and it
seems the correct thing to do at this
point in time now at the end so the only
goal is that each router will actually
have the links that the vectors from all
of the other relatives in the network
environment so that actually means each
router will have like a full view of
topology just the same as if the router
would be like an ICS route that having
all the other space you know the
topology looks like and for that moment
onwards you can actually start doing
dextra and if you do the dextra the end
result will be your routing table so
that is where we are so that is you know
what is happening and for what you can
see to top things here you know in the
red square i should not really use red
because red means bad in this case it's
a good thing is actually what we call
like links at victor out using bgp SPF
so it's a very high level
you know overview it's reasonably simple
so why are we using bgp because bgp is
probably one of the most cool protocols
ever invented it is because it actually
pays for a lot of people you know their
you know their salaries and things like
that it's like a never-ending stream of
like wonderful things you can do with it
so that's why we're using you know BGP
in our technology because it is just
ultimately cold now at the same time you
know it is you know it's robust and
simple now that is debatable of course
you know some people come up with you
know things to do with it which is not
really that robust and need of simple at
all but what we are doing with it is
actually you know we are using it in a
very simplistic kind of fashion and if
you actually read the specification you
know you actually will understand also
that what we are doing it's not really
rocket science it's actually just using
BGP in a more
simplistic camera version and if you're
looking to you know even spinning SPF
into it you know you will see that a lot
of the forwarding and a lot of the the
ways of you know distributing all these
pieces of information has been
simplified also so I will be covering
some of those elements so BGP provides
is a few things it provides reliable
transport is guaranteed an order
delivery it's incremental updates you
know there is like so unlike in link
state routing we don't have a flooding
problem here okay so there is no 25
different proposals for floating there
is one and it works really really well
and it's proven to work well it's loop
free and it's fantastic it's awesome so
and at the same time we also have like
different mechanisms to actually you
know bring this into the network so you
can actually use like router flex you
can use like controllers to actually
program no more information downstream
and then you know now the most important
thing probably from this slide is that
the way the the routing actually works
everything is tisha view you know it's
computed in a distributed fashion so
there is no one piece in the network
which computes the topology for
everything everything is calculated you
know from a routing perspective
distributed and each single node itself
so that is an important artifact and at
the same time you know a lot of people
you know running data centers already
using you know you know BGP so you have
some massive scalable data centers
running like I don't know like ten
thousand one hundred thousand boxes they
run BGP you have some other set P of C
you know some other set of people are
unlike massively scalable data centers
existing I look like 50 routers they
also run BGP because it's like really
really cool now we actually offer them
you know like a new set of technology to
actually know run with this so this is
another you know vo lots of text here
okay oh this looks very weird okay
that's a surprise so the high level you
know perspective from the insight vector
out there so the target use case for
reset vector routing is actually you
know the the massive scalable data
center so the plan is to actually you
know bring your
political awareness and to actually do
dextra in networks you know of gigantic
size to actually not speak about
networks of like $50 or a thousand
routers but like 10,000 100,000 and more
because that is the size of what BGP can
scale to so that is really really nice
now the advantage you actually will have
by having the topological in our
environment is you can do potentially
smarter things with your environment
because if you know the topology you can
do you can actually start doing things
like loop free alternates you know you
can actually avoid risk you know reach
between groups and so on words you can
do some traffic engineering know
whatever crazy thing you can dream off
you know if you know the topology you
can actually do this you know with this
by extending the technology itself the
target also is to actually use this as
an underlay routing mechanism and so you
actually will reduce the underlayer
outing and on top of that you will have
flow layer 2 VPN BGP and whatever you
know you know all the VPN things
happening layer 3 VPN happening on top
of that this is just underlay
from an encoding perspective so we could
have used or reused the BGP you know
Safi from bt pls now from a backward
compatibility perspective we said ok
let's not do that even though it's
actually perfectly possible we actually
select a real selector we get or we get
allocated like a new stuffy for this
just from our backwards compatibility
perspective it also means we need to
actually have like a new capability for
this you know to be exchanged so that is
important to be aware and now for the
rest you know we're not really changing
that much about like you know the you
know right distribution like if you
think you have to change but it's
morally simplified now here you see my
so the reason actually I was laughing
with this so I have like his new iPad
and it's actually you know iPad pro and
a pen you can actually make like very
nice graphs with that you know it make
pictures but it's not very useful being
a very pro in this if you make a PDF out
of your slider it looks like this so my
graph actually is gone so that's a bit
sad so actually what you would be seeing
here just visualize this close your eyes
so close your eyes you know dream you're
in this room you know fantasize apart my
picture okay and what you see here is
like another smalls
you know the different routers on the
left-hand side router one two three four
and five and they look like routing
logos and you have like a nice blue
lines between them and next to the
routing locals visualize you know close
your eyes take your time okay you're
like in Bangkok okay visualizer but not
out I thought about anything else and
then mix it around visualize yourself a
puzzle piece yeah and that puzzle piece
is actually your link state vector and
that is what I'm drawing here so I see
everybody's smiling you're probably
thinking about my puzzles I think so and
the important thing is that a puzzle
actually is encoded as you know in a way
of like you know like with the BGP
LS and low-riding coding itself you know
with the new stuff which is you know
plan to be proposed so that is my magic
invisible slide here which I didn't
really check I think of how to block my
slide is clicking on the button thing so
I blame him anyway so what sort of
peering models do we have so
traditionally you know if you look into
how massive scalable you know
datacenters are configured by using BGP
if you actually have like all routers
are not directly connected peer-to-peer
and your prefixes ago you know through
them so there is something which is
possible also here with the link States
you know vector routing you know
mechanism but it doesn't have to be
because if you know the topology you
know of course lots of massive scale
that is know the topology you can
actually download it it is actually very
well possible to actually not put like
you know like a route reflector in place
or a controller in place and P with that
one directly so that you actually reduce
the amount of feeding configuration in
your network environment so those
details and those specifications and
some of the requirements and what can be
done is actually you know this you know
documented very well in the
applicability draft so if anybody would
have a you know a nice question about
that be you know feel free to come to
the mic you know again we have people
here to actually answer your difficult
question so that is where we are so the
other thing to keep in to mind is
that what we are doing here is not a new
technological principle so what is being
done here is sort of like I wouldn't
call it reinventing but more
standardizing an approach which has been
used by you know which has been
disclosed already by Google in one of
the sitcom papers like you know which is
know like Jupiter rising has they could
have cost a pop you can see what it is
so it is you compare it's open source
it's all open available and what we're
doing here is actually you know giving
you the capability to go into the same
kind of you know you know technology
like technological architecture you know
to make that available by using eg this
picture actually turned out better which
is fantastic because I didn't make it
with my ipod Pro and my pen so that's
like a thousand dollars thrown away so
anyway I'll give it to my kids so so a
few things actually changed in BGP so
what you see it on the left hand side is
your classic BGP you know decision
process what we have done with link
stage Victor out them but Victor routing
we simplified that so I know everybody
knows BGP inside out you know in the
audience here yeah so face one normally
you know what you will do is that the
calculation of degree of preference so
all of the rights you get for one of
your neighbors you sort of like give it
a certain preference you know so you can
compare it later on in phase two you
actually strano compare off all the
previous you have with the preference
thing and you figure out the best one
and you put it into your local rib and
then at the phase three no you actually
start distributing goes round again to
watch your neighbors so there is a
traditional process and phase one and
phase two is what most people commonly
know or actually what is known as you
know the part effective algorithm and
that is what we are changing here so
phase one and two in this case is being
replaced by this new thing by the SPF
algorithm so that actually means you
know we're gonna be doing the BGP and a
right selection and at the same time you
know we're gonna do nearly in parallel
you know the SPF attached to it so the
route selection and node to it it also
means that our phase three actually is
simplified
so in traditional classic BGP phase 1
phase 2 and phase 3 they are consecutive
from each other in the Lynx and Victor
routing algorithm it doesn't really have
to be the case because we can actually
do those things in parallel which
actually makes it that if you have a
piece of information that needs to be
transported through the network it can
go really really really much faster very
similar the same speed as a traditional
AGP like a SAS or OSPF so some of the
advantages is already you know spoken
about is a little bit all the notes
we'll have a complete view of topology
so you can do like really crazy stuff or
you can do smart stuff and so up to you
and what you want to do with this it
another benefit of that is that if
something actually breaks in the network
environment just like with the
traditional link state protocol you only
communicate the failure of what you have
because SPF will pick up I will
understand and recompute the impact of
that particular failure you know truly
topology with classic BGP if something
actually happens you have to really
knows all the routes were sitting behind
that failure again which makes
everything much more heavy slower and
more complicated than you know a little
bit harder you know from that
perspective at the same time if you at
the same time yes if you know the
topology then you can actually make
smarter or more optimal routing
decisions you know for the traffic
through your network you don't always
have to go to watch you know the
shortest path towards your next hop
because you know the topology you can
make smarter decisions it is up to the
implementer you know to actually you
know to create a code or actually you
know do those smarter things so in
essence you know that reality is there
so almost to the last slide so what is
hot in link state vector routing well
right now you know I think I've the
impression that the draft section you
know or have it's me as chair of course
trying to you know market my products
here yeah so the draft selection of
incredibly good quality easy to read it
will make your day happier even if
you're in Bangkok it's fantastic yeah so
it's super it's wonderful
so the BGP you know SPF
draft itself so we're gonna be doing a
working group last column that you know
we're gonna be releasing that very soon
I invite everybody in a room here to
actually have a very good read on that
so what we actually need to further
improve these documents because you know
they actually went through the writing
Directorate I went to the operational
Directorate all of the commands actually
have been addressed but at the same time
you know it does really need to have
like more inputs from you know a lot
more people the more people who can
actually give like you know constructive
feedback or give information about what
you know can potentially be changed what
is good and what is bad you know please
let us know so we can really really you
know further improve the document and
make sure that you know what we're doing
here is developing the right you know
the right material so that's point one
two and three and then the other thing
you know what actually has been hot very
you know heavily discussed is you know
as a remember you know as you can see
actually could not see on that picture
with that you know with your eyes closed
the little puzzle pieces so that puzzle
piece needs to be created now you can
create this you know either by by some
sort of a divine resource probably you
configuring all of the link States and
you know identifying that but it's not
going to make like you know somebody
operates router is very incredibly happy
because you don't want to do that so you
want those puzzle piece so you want to
link state vectors to be created by
themselves and automatically so that
means you need to have a technology out
there that can harvest the right sets
and the right hooks of information for
you to create that link state vector so
we have been looking you know around you
know all the different kind of
technologies we have been you know being
pulling the ball left and right and all
the different things of what is
available we see the same kind of
movement you know I can you know in the
idea all working group and we started to
compare them now one of the key elements
here is that the requirements you know
of what we have from al instead vector
routing perspective are actually
different from the requirements which
there are from an idea perspective so
link cell vector out
technology is you know a little bit you
know little bit you know it's not really
deployed that much because it doesn't
really exist so we're not really
restrained by the fact that whatever we
do has to be a technology which proven
you know track record yet so we can do a
bit more you know we can be a bit more
creative so what we have decided now you
know in in our in the lsv our working
group is to actually know start a
working group adoption call for the
links take over Ethernet technology so
that is one of this I had to know just a
quick you know quick summary here on
what you know the ELA stories I don't
really want to go too much you know into
it so in essence you know it's a very
similar thing as lldp it's a simplified
version out of it and the simplified
means you know in the first phase what
we are documenting here is going towards
the absolute minimum requirements of
what we need from an ALICE of your
perspective so there is actually no
overhead which is a good thing now at
the same time what we want to avoid is
that it's very simple technology
excludes potential further innovation or
like you know re usage by other working
groups for other purposes so the way we
are doing this is by making it
extendable by using the magic of tlvs so
these are like wonderful everything is
with deal of each nowadays so we use
still these because it is almost as cool
as PGP so so we going down that road so
that is where we are and that is what we
have right now and again I love the way
it's you know it's it's almost over
trivial simplicity and there is no IPR
test which is something that Randy Bush
seems to love a lot really a lot and me
too
so that's fantastic so that is where we
are right now so that is a quick update
about you know Alice VR I hope that you
know I was able to entertain you a
little bit you know with my blessings
about Ella's VR so any questions please
come to the mic but don't expect me to
answer them because we have smarter
people in the room
nothing that's scary
cool thanks
now we're going to have Jeffrey talk
about rift I'm learning to drive this
thing okay so my presentation is good no
not going to be as entertaining except I
can say that the truth coaches are Jeff
and Jeffrey that's the only entertaining
part I can talk about so why rift
this is about data center online writing
protocol we have seen the evolution from
ICP based 3db BGP and what we would like
to see is that we evolved to reads for
scanning convergence and OPEX reasons so
the first I want to talk about the
issues with existing solutions why did
we move to ebgp the first place
the two main drawbacks with a GP in mstc
is that the first one is the failure
impact scope some people call it plus
radius a small change or link up and
down anywhere in a small corner of the
data center is flooded everywhere and
that triggers SPF recalculation on every
note and that applies to lsv r2 as well
another issue is the rich connections in
the data center network makes flooding
unnecessarily redundant and inefficient
so those are the two main problems with
a GP that's then people
move to the ebgp solution but there are
also two issues with that the first
issue is that with a well-defined
technology class network in data center
ideally the routing tables could be very
simple for example a leaf node all your
needs is a default routes on the next
level you only need a default route and
more specific subset routes to
destinations destinations south of it
that's under normal situations but if
you just if you do that only and then in
some situations you may end up a black
hole the next issue is a BGP is that
some because we have massive EMP paths
in the network for example and node
could have 32 64 100 128 years and for
every prefix you will learn the same
periphery from all those peers and you
have to keep all those so that's in the
control plane it's a lot of resources
wasted and lots of stay talking to keep
so how do we solve solve those problems
yeah enriched this is the hand-drawn
picture a picture hand-drawn by Tony he
didn't use a iPad pro my second point is
in the telling points ok so if you look
at this picture we have three layers the
purple purple layer green layer and then
the pink layer so we do linked States
and distance vector in two directions on
the right side where we are showing that
we're flooding the linked States all the
way from on the northbound all the way
to the top well actually on the on the
left side we do the same thing as well
basically link States
is flooded all the way to the north side
I'm not too the more spunk to the top
and it also the next ad is also further
flooded down on the south side just by
one hop and then reflected oh yeah so on
the side look at this pink nodes its
link state is flooded down south by just
by one hop it stops here and then it it
can be reflected back to north so that
this may note at the same level will
keep it what we're doing it same thing
the link state from this green note is
flat itself by one hub owning and also
reflected north so that the other green
node at the same level will also learn
it why do we want to do that it would
become clear later now anyway so because
we fly the link States all the way to
the north then every node will know the
topology full topology south of it and
under and then on the southbound with we
use link States we we do a distance
vector routing to to propagate default
owning by one hub for example this pink
note was Center default routes to the
green node by stops there and then the
green note was sent its own default
route south now we we mentioned earlier
that if you just do this to the default
routes plus some specific routes to the
for this destinations south of you you
will have a black hole knee issue when
when something happens and here is exact
because his example well this slide is
basically what I just talked about some
the
northbound reading state and southbounds
a distance factor so I'm going to escape
those slides now here is the backhoe
knee issue I mentioned earlier that if
you don't do anything further so for now
ignore that P don't don't you nor
anything just look at the picture we
have this prefix p1 here on this corner
and these two purple notes here they get
the traffic from the server's down there
need to reach here so let's say this
leaf node gets the packet it has two
choices you are following the default
route they can choose either a screen
note or the screen notes as fine and
let's say if it shows this note and it
again has two nodes a two choices to go
this one or this one
but if this link is down and this one
still choose to go this way and the
traffic will reach there and has nowhere
else to go so that's the blackening
issue if you don't do anything else now
how do I solve this problem we do
automatic the aggregation remember that
earlier we talked about that the link
States from any node is flooded south by
1/2 and then reflected back so in this
case the two pink nodes will know each
other's link States now this new pink
node down here it does
SPF calculation based on the topology
flooded northbound then it will realize
that he had a route towards p1 using
this link here he also will realize that
his body here does not have a pink to
this note here so his body will not be
able to reach p1 once he gets that
conclusion it will send a specific route
for p1 using the link using the distance
vector part of this protocol and notice
I also also note that this p1 routes
will stop at this green node is not
propagated further down it's just one
half it stops here
now if you have a packet arriving on
this nook trying to reach p1 and let's
say this node picks its node as a lookup
you find the default routes and then the
packet ends up here now this green node
here now has two routes one is the
default routes the other one is the most
specific p1 routes that this kink node
has automatically inject it now the
packet will follow the p1 routes
reaching this pink note down here
instead of going to the top so that's
how we solve the Brioni issue
so with this automatically aggregation
we can use default routes and plasti
were specific routes through the
destinations south of south of the nodes
and if link fader happens in somewhere
if there is a needs to do the auto this
D aggregation it will happen another
important component of this rift
protocol is zero-touch provisioning if
we go back to this picture the owning
these two top nodes we called top of the
fabric needs configuration
very simple convictions indicating that
they are at the top
other than that no configuration is
needed on the notes all you need to do
is to power up connect the cables and
that they were the nose will discover
each other decide to mean set up the
routing adjacencies and if you happen to
have me miss keep learning and the
protocol will make sure that the logical
topology that we obtain from from the
routing adjacency that we decide to do
that's the topology topology will be
still conformed to a strict north north
bound South Mountain a class type of
topology that way you don't run into
routing notes and that kind of thing so
this zero test provisioning makes DC
fabrics just like memory banks today
nobody configures Ram banks you just put
it plug it in a new work and what rifts
zero touch provisioning to does is make
this a fabric like a memory bank just
it's plug and play no provisioning
except on the top of the fabric nodes
there are a lot of other features either
peyote or ed ed on of the rifts of
automatically optimal reduction flooding
flooding reduction and not balanced we
mentioned earlier that either is a issue
with a valina ICP routing the flooding
are unnecessary unnecessary flooding and
that's is reduced here and it has built
in mobility support
key-value store and fabric bandwidth
balancing so sometimes you may have
links going down and now you have
different notes at the same level have
different bandwidth to reach next level
and we can know balance in the traffic
based on the available bandwidth it will
it will support segment routing we also
have participated prefixes though the
segment routing and politic IV prefixes
have been moved database back to their
own separate specs in summary we combine
the advantages of link States and
distance vector from the next stage
routing we get fastest possible
convergence automatic detection and
topology we have minimum routes and
information on that torus default routes
normally you know and so a removes the
disadvantages of big States or distance
vector for example you have reduced
imbalanced flooding you have
automatically per detection and you
don't have the easy NP burden there
there's then there's unique rift
advantage it's true zero touch
provisioning minimum for us the readers
radius on fader and so on so for a lot
of them I'll just keep those small
details
it's not yeah I guess that's the last
slide so I uh I thought I was only going
to give overview of the protocol so I
didn't put a steady-state there but I
can talk about it so the working group
was chartered immersed in London we have
we had one intern meeting in May and we
have been that the core team have been
working having having weekly sometimes
twice weekly design meetings that those
meetings are most of them are recorded
and announced we welcome open party
participation so but typically it's just
the core members of the team but it's
open to everyone
our original all the open source
implementation has been going on brutal
righteous men it's doing been doing a
fantastic job with his helpers and that
overall protocol we right now we are at
zero three revision that zero for
revision is evolving and our original
plan was to submit to iesg
for the pace based protocol in February
19 I are going to have to delay that by
one ITF cycle but we we are working very
hard on solving the the issues that we
will encounter and fascinating issues
and Tony and his his team can talk out
of those things endlessly it's but I
wanna I will skip those here so that's
just my report and Jeff at one point the
way we develop protocol we do it the way
IDF should do it everything
being prodded as we develop the spec we
found number of wishes in code that were
fixed in the spec so both going Marla we
make sure the stuff actually does work
it's not on the PowerPoint in beauty
another thing I forgot to put there and
I know that some Lara wanted to hear
about is the the thrifter model we
actually last time we actually talked
about this extensively in in the working
group meeting so the in O'Day's routing
protocols are specified with packet
formats and despite and that beats
reader for what for whatever and with
rift the pack we don't have packet
format the old-style packet format
definition any more everything is RIF
model-based that makes development a lot
easier you just use a tool to compile
the surf model and then you automatic a
general automatically generate codes to
handle the the coding and decoding that
speeds up the development extensively we
a lot of people were last time had lots
of discussions on that it's it's truly a
wonderful thing that's why I have all
right Victor coursing one quick question
how does any cast services work on the
underlay with the in within the Rif
model I say Tony's is standing up by
alright so Enterprise I mean lots of
stuff has been suppressed so rift is
loop free which means you can take any
path to anywhere so if you have a rift
is doing through any cast so not this
any cast like IP which is bound by a CMP
basically but rift when you see the same
address on the fabric doesn't matter
what the distance is
and you can split the traffic also and
you know based on the bandwidth distance
whatever you want more than that what we
have is a fast mobility because when you
start to move things on the fabric at a
certain frequency you start to confuse
mobility for any caste right depending
what gets an update first so Pascal
booted in and we actually change the
ipv6 low pan for the purpose because
they facing the same issues that if the
fabric has a clock and we don't care how
precise is the clock we can actually
make a distinction between a move and
then any caste and because we see the
time stamps only the newer direction has
to get there for us to flip over and we
don't have to wait for the fold for the
old address to be withdrawn so those are
all things which cannot be achieved with
normal IP protocols which rely on a CMP
and cannot do the time stamping so
that's so far for the anycast
I think nothing comparable exists
the questions nope okay so now we get to
the part of the agenda where we're just
stopping up before anything you guys
want to talk about comment on tell us a
story complain coffee's not there yet I
think we already had the last coffee for
today so no Anderson I have a real name
we got the mail or the working group
shares got the mail from the ADEs how we
in the future need to update the working
group status I think it's a brilliant
idea it's the right place to have it
though when you look at the working
group page it's extremely hard to
actually find the working group status
where you need to click the finally
would it be possible to talk to the data
tracker team and to move a new bottom
bottom up on the top line so we actually
can find it easily sure you can talk to
them no I think it's actually okay a
selenium Cisco Systems I was able to
edit the main working group change and
and put a put a link URL link right
there to the status on the LSR page so
so I don't have to have two separate
page so you can show us okay you see
that current working group status right
there you can push it click on that no
no no down
count up one no hop on there quick yeah
so what I'm saying I want that bottom up
on me oh this is fine contest is fine no
it's the previous page yes a Syrian yes
so instead by on the same level as a
brow yeah you see it's an it wasn't it
so if I talk to the the data tracker
team can I say that we discussed it in
the routing area and we agree that it
would be good idea yes actually if you
if you for those of you who I guess have
privileges on the tracker for the
working group I guess it's chairs and
the 80s when you click on the status
update to edit it at the bottom the
tools team put in a little history of
why they put that there and actually the
history has to do with with us with the
routing area it they put it in there
because we told them we were doing
summaries and so they they they they put
that there so we could put this on my
said I we had never used this so I
originally thought that what would
happen is that there would be a little
window like thing right here that would
show the actual summary so that's why
when I sent this was chairs now we said
you know let's do this a couple
paragraphs or something but I think a
tab is this a great idea and and since
yeah they do it for us anyway said it
would be especially a since you said
it's for people not kind of very
actively using the data tracker meaning
they need to find it directly and I
think it's a good idea but an
improvement needed to it so if you're
gonna find it where you expect to find
it in some ways it really belongs on the
bed on the bottom of the Charter because
the Charter has got the current status
of the working group it's got what you
what it's work our package is it's got
what it has done and
it's got what it is expected to do and
isn't that exactly you know status
information and where you'd expect if I
may be an amplification of the status
information well so I think we close
those PF at the end of the year right
the last time we reach our turd OSPF was
in 1984 something like that
so yes ideally that also ideally now
that you bring it up I think it's a
great suggestion for the chairs from an
active chair to keep your mouths tones
updated so that we can see that's a job
for somebody bring us a free breakfast
or just do it that so that we can see
the actual you know status of when
you're going to deliver things etcetera
so the intent of the status update this
we're talking about is that here's a
short summary because yes okay you go
read the the Charter you know what the
worker who was supposed to be doing
we want to know especially for as we
said external audiences what the worker
was doing now you know if I'm interested
in in in any working group let's say LSR
you know what what is it discussing now
you know said work for me to go to the
meeting what are the drafts that maybe I
should go do it now because otherwise
you look at the document agent there's a
lot of documents and it's not
necessarily easy for anyone not
following the work group to tell exactly
what's wrong so just you again may be
the right thing because you should
always do call by reference rather than
call by value so that young it
inconsistency problems may be of the
right thing to do is not of the Charter
paged have a pointer to current active
status okay so this is
obviously the first time we're doing
this status page thing keep the
suggestion scrubbing and we'll you know
experiment with this further uh anything
else anyone wants to say scheme amount
has been submitted and whatever was in
Miss Rhea for last 35 years is true so I
have a Stewart again one other comment
which is am I the only one that thinks
there are too many routing group
overlaps in the meeting agenda where
there are important meetings that you
need to be simultaneously at the same
time and is there anything we can do to
try and reduce this your first question
I don't know who else thinks there's a
lot of overlaps so yes there are many
things or there are some things I guess
we can do about them the first order is
of course the conflict list that is put
into the session requests and please
revise that we have tried unsuccessfully
before to try to prioritize that list so
that would be easier for the Secretariat
and for us to understand you know
conflicts that we have we usually try as
much as we can to avoid any significant
conflicts however you know there's
always gonna be something maybe we can
avoid more than we have avoided now but
but yeah that's those initial step the
other thing that would be really useful
for us is as the preliminary agent that
comes out if you see anything that we
should be avoiding those no and put it
on the conflict list for next time as
well so that we try not to keep stepping
on that but but yes I mean we try to do
the best we can this week because we
have on the last day or half of us they
may be there were a little bit more calm
yes anomalous yeah I'm personally
unimpressed with the Friday experiment
that's going on here this week and I was
hoping if the three of you have a
consensus on that between yourselves you
you bring that back to the next time the
iesg meets so we can perhaps avoid this
in the future any any one question for
clarification in which sense unimpressed
what is bothering you
I think it's a waste of the day there's
only like four small groups that are
meeting tomorrow with that based on what
I saw on on the room reservations I
think it's is it's a waste of the
resources that were paying for in the
hotel and I think a much better use of
the day is what we've done in the past
thank you yeah I do want to say that
there are actually more than four
meetings happening tomorrow there are
meetings that are not on the schedule on
the wiki or on the slides that ELISA put
up yesterday they just haven't been
announced they're still it's not a full
load of working groups meeting Tony Lee
arista networks I agree completely we
should reuse Friday if we took all of
our routing meetings and spread them out
a little bit more we'd have less overlap
for the obvious support to previous
speakers Gregory egt yes please
even their time we used to have on
Friday for group meetings helped to
relieve conflict and another plea to
work in group Cheers
please be very considerate when you
request working group sessions
listing possible conflicts with other
groups in the area at least in the area
because otherwise running from one group
to another to have presentations here
and then presentation there it's a lot
of stress say something then you can
answer my question - in this income so
one of the ideas actually kicked out
which was might be even more
revolutionary was that to just have one
hour sessions for all the working groups
said they more effectively made no use
of their meeting time and they could use
interim meetings you know for other you
know discussions but to go just and to
one hour and are grouting our reactions
one of the only ones that really
requested you know their two-hour
sessions to two and a half hour sessions
whatever so do you really feel right
that because I would reduce the complex
to it right if everybody just went to
one hours but do you really see the
utility right to have the discussions in
person maybe I'm leading in but right
that we have in person we have we're
here and that we make good use of that
time might have the two hour of sessions
david black let's tell him here from
transform them and i'm here to help you
i have ran a workgroup admit for three
hours total this week and we could have
used for and yes that's for face to face
discussion is to work through hard
issues not kind of support what David
said I belong are going to take a
different point which is that we do the
we use the eighteenth-century method of
figuring out conflicts right people who
understand what's going on sort of
figure out from you know what they know
what the conflict should be we live in
the 21st century with big data in all
those sorts of things so though it
should be possible to generate a
conflict terms hint using you know what
we know about who was in the meetings
and you know who is on the draft authors
are and the overlaps etc Stuart pegas
who
would be using information that we would
need to be careful on how we use that
information because that would
necessarily point to people and
understanding where people are at which
time and so on well even if you didn't
figure out from the blue sheets which
you probably could do only online I'm
not sure with near modern handwriting
techniques if you didn't do that you
could at least figure out who was active
in which area and try and minimize the
the overlaps you could do that from the
mailing lists which are public
information you could do this from the
author lists etc yeah I just want to
point out not one of more excuse but one
more circumstance this week this week
for the first time we added a conflict
with every working group for the routing
area working group so it used to be that
in the past we had other routing groups
meeting while deliver our twg was
meeting so this time we conflicted that
which of course you know that's how
things go ahead and then I want to ask
another question similar to what they
were asked before I want to give you
something positive food was great too
much but too much food but will take all
the credit for that
you know take the blame for the rest of
the AG will take the credit for the food
so we talked about you know the fact
that mostly the routing area of groups
some of them are the ones who select
some of the bigger slots one thing that
we have to do this week was have maybe
two sessions a two-hour session and the
one-hour session maybe later and by
couple groups met twice but at different
times in the week do you guys think that
was useful or will you have rather have
one bigger slot that one shot just show
hands who thought what bigger slot would
have been better and who thought it was
fine to meet twice
different times so one in one so it
doesn't matter okay great Jacob might
Cisco this is not a comment judges for
the routing group but I think the whole
of the IDF is when do we move on from s
key because every other standards body I
know yes the RFC editor made a
presentation about that last night
they're already testing non-ascii
characters you can do drawings except on
news colors so that's it so there's a
couple of our receipts actually they're
talking about the changes and you can go
to the RSC editor page and check it out
of all the working group all the areas
in this in the IETF
colors would be most useful in this one
because we have to deal with situations
where you have multiple overlapping
topologies and colors would be much
better than the other alternatives
I think the Ephesus RC - editor that
some are enough maybe RC and RC by the
way just in case you don't know the
people who manage the RC editor activity
or the IAB so sure we can tell them but
please you can tell him yourself as well
yep Jeff this from the IAB Jeff
anything so you should have been used
[Laughter]
Heather presented twice our plans with
regarding urs affirmative support colors
to support different formats to show
them properly and GML it's all coming
just be patient they're not if you
detect
you can't use colors otherwise you can
use colors you sure about that Jeff I
think its color anywhere its color
always full color days you could still
do PDFs and in PDF you could use
whatever you like right that's how much
better than that so please take that
discussion to the RCA record list
maybe there's something called RC and
interest or something like that anything
else that we can actually do okay thank
you so much and we're gonna see you in
Prague and then by the way we still have
another half an hour of meeting time so
you know stick around and talk to each
other tell each other jokes and what the
heck you're working on and all that
stuff thank you
[Applause]
you