[Music]
good afternoon
it's Thursday at IAT f103 Thursday said
my mail it's Thursday
I'm Chris this is care this is IETF 103
if you're not for the IETF 103 meeting
you're probably in the wrong place
it's the side Rob's me again I at HF 103
if United right for cider ops then we
could say it'll be fun or you could go
on to where you're supposed to be for
those presenting there's a little X down
here on the floor please stand on it
speak into the mic always speak into the
mic okay I think we need a minutes taker
and a jabber scribe before we can go
forward volunteers jabber for pen Oh
excellent
there's a seat right here for you if you
want reserved for the jabber scribe
let's say you get the good seat
note-taker yes thank you Tim are you
presenting to
okay I'll type while you present how
about okay paper oh my god this is cider
ops this is cider ops not cider boom
okay back to serious things there's a
note oh this is all of our oh this is
the note well I think maybe yes this is
the note well let's just say it is we
have an agenda here's the slides we're
almost in two or five minutes we have
two hours we should have plenty of time
for this but we're gonna try and keep
people on time on schedule as best we
can so note the time you have if you're
presenting except for George who has 20
minutes
let's take I think you there - George's
yeah no yeah yeah that's why there's an
extra space just think of it like this
quotes under there okay alright
first up is Oliver unless there's
anybody who has any questions no good
Oliver you're doing the thingy
what do you mean use a mic just so
everybody knows we're doing rpki origin
validation on the on the IETF Network
and it seems to work okay so last year
we did some work on testing route origin
validation there's different
implementations and we made some
observations what I thought might be
interesting for everybody of you and if
not then just doesn't do at all so the
first thing what we were looking and we
want
to see what is the impact on convergence
time we also very interested in if a
router is connected to one or more
caches what happens if the connections
break down if we have changes within the
connections etc and how does this whole
thing work we tested a little bit the
implementation of Route Orange
motivations and routers and if they
implement the RFC 1897 which is on ibgp
the transmission of the validation state
and also what kind of impact this has on
my BGP so the first and convergence and
so what we did we did not use any excess
of policy actually we didn't use any
policies at all we just sent around
700,000 routes into the router we
measure it how long does it take we made
it this one peer these two peers and
then we did the same there's a hundred
percent who are coverage what this means
is we had for every prefix origin full
match prefix and we got around an
average increase of between two to seven
percent I think the loss even was one
point eight so we rounded to South but
this is all relative because now if you
put policy processing on top of it the
the time stays the same our percentage
goes down so I think rendi at one point
made some statement that it's neglect to
Bill and I think we can pretty much
confirm that then we looked into the
validation caches which is kind of
interesting so we we used a combination
between the ripe ncc in our own cache
test harness there was a little bit
easier to fill in later and we made
these tests like where the routers
connected to a cache and all of a sudden
the connection goes down for example we
just put the cable waited a little bit
the cache crashed saw router crashed and
all these kind of things and we
interestingly we noticed that I mean
every router acts differently some
detect relatively
fast the loss of the cash and others
seem not to they did eventually but this
is all like configuration based and so
if the router detected the relatively
fast that increase the turn-on ibgp
because if only if you signal the
validation state because no the
validation state changes the attribute
changes and you have to reanalysis
selected it's not much but it's
something to to look at so eventually
what we figure out it might be good if
the router is not really that sensitive
to the loss of a connection to the RPI
cache or even if you have maybe more
than one cache connected to the router
then we looked into the signalling of
the validation state we notice that not
every router implemented it 100% the way
as the RFC specifies it we talked to the
vendors we got fixes for that so maybe
just you look into your own gear what
you have and check and talk to the
vendors there are fixes out there if you
see something some implementations label
internal routes as well it some allowed
to have the validation state configured
some take the validation state of it is
signaled we are CRC 1897 then we looked
into the a s set the a s ed is an
interesting thing so some routers had
issues with the ASM actually so when we
receive your ebgp in a sh if the prefix
we cannot determine an origin but if the
prefix is not covered and it's not found
from the algorithm if the prefix is
covered then it should be invalid
interestingly we found an awful lot of
not founds which didn't switch to
invalid we receive one fix from one
router vendor so but it doesn't
necessarily
need to be a bug because if the vendor
decided I don't perform origin
validation on routers a asset then the
RFC says if you choose to not validate
it set label it is not found so I don't
know if the internals of the routers if
they just chose to not validate it then
it's fine if they chose to them they
have a back maybe you should look at
your gear how this one reacts to that
right now so then we yeah I think I
talked about this already so I
immediately we have some routers
basically as I said label labor the
updates as well it if they don't see
anything else here the ibgp we as a
community string another router labeled
these as unverified what I actually
liked and they didn't do anything
and there's also kind of way how you can
configure it the interesting thing what
we noticed there actually we didn't only
notice it we we actually made use of
that for some of the measurements and
later on we thought wait a month it's
actually kind of an interesting behavior
number one is the prefix packing so if I
receive here ebgp and update this let's
say three prefixes and the validation
says two of them are valid and one of
them is not found then out of one update
becomes two so later on we notice this
because we were thinking we were
counting the updates that go in and come
out and something was off we were
wondering why and then we figure here
actually that it doesn't need to be
something bad it's just something what
you should consider if you turn on this
attribute but becomes more interesting
down here I have only one prefix and now
my connection to the validation cache
starts flickering it's up it's down it's
up its down so if the same prefix stays
stays selected I receive HC which is
valid then I receive it again was not
found this valid
and so that's why and not that fast
reaction to the lots of manipulation
cache might be actually not that bad I
always hated this work conflicting
validation results but I had to actually
educate myself a little bit because we
can actually have conflicting validation
results you can have the same prefix
origin in the router that has all three
validation states how can that happen I
have an S that has that has three
routers every router has their own
validation cache they are not
synchronized they pull at different
times and one router might say that's
this prefix origin is not found this one
says it's invalid
this one says it's valid and then if
they add this one is extended community
string then router one will have known
it's table prefix one origin one three
times with three different conflicting
validation results just something to
think about it this may be local
processing might make more sense even on
the ibgp side or if every of these
router maybe connects to a centralized
validation cache that might fix some of
the things so that at least see
validation results might all be the same
because what can happen now is if our
one receives traffic for prefix 1 origin
1 and a is a basically it might be a
origin 1 actually
or it might just provide through the
router it if the traffic comes in here I
would prefer that it goes out right away
to a say but if I now prefer well it
this link here is not found this one is
invalid and this one is valid so now our
one carries the traffic through its own
network to the west coast and then sends
it out to a say just something to think
about
same
some router limitation of our three
doesn't do any art from router
invalidation and router one then by
default declares this one is valid just
if you deploy this just think about how
you have to create your policies to
maybe avoid certain things or think
about that these things can happen I
don't want to say it's good or bad I
just say that's an attribute of the
beast so in general what I figured out
the number one documentation would
really be better throughout all the
routing implementation I have to include
ours as well more more examples could be
out there maybe they are I just didn't
find them but if someone starts really
fresh with that they're really on lost
lost grounds because we even saw that in
some router implementations we saw some
labeling that would imply certain
settings and I didn't find any setting
that could activate something like I saw
some using this primary and secondary
cache I did not figure out how how can I
say I wanna have primary secondary cache
I figured out that the implementation
all made a union what is actually a nice
thing maybe better than primary
secondary cache because now if I have
two caches connecting one of them dies I
don't lose everything right away other
thing that Union again the detection or
the detection of the loss to a cache I
think it's better to work with stay
daters and permanently have this
flickering the other thing is if I turn
on the rs3 eighty ninety seven I might
see more traffic on ibgp
I lose a little bit of prefix packing I
don't know if it is a concern I don't
think it's a concern right now I don't
know how this evolves over time and that
we can have conflicting router States
so the question here is is there an
interesting to create a document where
you start documenting these kind of
experience things for people who come
fresh and I think yesterday in the Grove
working group they were talking about
like a living document what can be
always updated maybe something like this
could be an interesting thing in this
regards because things that might be an
issue now might not be an issue in six
months maybe things that we don't know
yet are an issue might be an issue in
six months and something that has value
for especially newcomers I mean we are
still in the deployment stage many
people come in they hear this the first
time or they may be heard at ten years
ago and still aren't so mighty at set of
ten years ago but they don't know what
it is and maybe just can update things
so for someone who gives a quick quick
start something for the community there
you can exchange a little bit and have
some value not something what is two
hundred pages long was something that is
maybe I always hope for one but maybe a
handful of pages maybe some it's ideas
on how you can configure not that you
have to do it like that
but just what you have to consider
something like this so that is one thing
and we also think that we will we plan
on doing some more tests if there is
something that some of you really would
like to see drop me an e-mail or Shriram
or doc montgomery whoever and then we
can see if we can put this into this
test what we want to do or maybe that is
something where we say hey that's really
cool we want to do that I mean we don't
have limitless resources but if there's
some interest in testing certain things
what you think is valuable also for the
community let us know questions
I got two questions here Patel on top of
list the questions you have can you go
back to your slide six yeah yeah so I
know you made an observation be
interesting to get your feedback on a
set because in a said typically the Aces
are not sorted that means very hard to
find the regionís know but a s-set says
if you find any a said we don't even
have an originator exactly I mean I
personally don't think that's a good
idea because I think the aggregator
could be the orginal but in the document
it says you don't have knowledge at once
you don't have knowledge inator you
can't you can't so it is not found at
this point if there is no row that
matches the prefix so it but if there's
a row that matches the prefix and it
should be invalid well if you have a
bunch of aces in a set you can't
authoritive ly tell if it was originated
by the same guy no but then the prefix
is invalid
exactly yes or not found or not found
all right
so maybe you got maybe might at least my
suggestion is you document something and
say here are the rules and then I have a
follow-up a question on your last slide
yeah actually
in summary you say that if the RFC 1897
is enable you see multiple states yes
ideally you should see same state across
within and yes right no the point is
this what let me go here so slide number
11 so if I have r1 r2 and r3 they can
have different states if they point at
different times so now I have a prefix
in this prefix let's say for example I
see a rose left I got it okay hello cute
ellipse so my thank you for the report
my question is it made me anxious that
if we are losing connection with the
cache the state of
perceived roots maybe change from valid
to unknown and with this wonderful
extended community these roots will be
renounced all routes will be renounced
inside all routes that change the
validates of state yes yes do we need to
update these RFC about extended
communities and remove share information
about the wedded state because it's
quite enough to share information about
Internet and unknown but in at the
moment we achieved by changing the state
and we are getting so so if you drop
invalids and you never will send out
that's yes sure and if you now just take
the unknown out or the valid out then
you still have invalid unknown so I
don't believe in anything
no it's different because the number of
valid roots will be increasing and
finally we are hoping that it will be
nearly 100 percent of ballot roots the
number of invalids roots is not that
high it will not be you know and I I
would I would prefer instead of changing
the RFC and making it more complicated
if you have more than one cashier
connected to and if one goes then the
impact would be less maybe that would be
a better solution you suggestion to have
every government to have at least two
applications connected to each route do
you think it's reasonable or sensible I
don't think it's very expensive now I'm
not sure it will happen in real networks
and for I don't know I mean the thing
the thing is is too in our day and age
so if you take I don't wanna endorse any
product but if you take for example the
ripe NCC Valley data and you just power
up three virtual machines and different
physical machines and you connect to all
of them you have it anyway so from my
perspective that the situation when we
are losing in connection to a cache and
we are getting a ray announced of all
prefixes that have a valid state those
big
I'm strange to be to be also going one
step further the best thing would be you
don't even use this RFC 1897 and you
make local politician even on ibgp
because the thing is this the validation
is not expensive validation is not
expensive so if I also if the problem is
this if I have a system there I have
distributed caches this alone gives me
already an interesting thing that I can
have different validation states how do
I deal with that what do I want to do
about that so if I say I validate within
my router every particular update I mean
there are many many ways to roam I don't
think by saying oh we just don't signal
one state which solves a problem it may
be reduces by a factor X but if you took
a look at the implementation of bird
routing daemon and the way they
implemented application so it's it's
just a piece of software with no
separate cache just inside as far as I
know there is no at the moment there is
no way to connect into another one no
but if the cache is part of the router
itself so if you lose connection to this
and the only thing how it could be
that's the whole thing crashed so I mean
then you have a different problem you
still have a connection with your
transitive anchors I mean the thing is
the only thing what we want to do is
here think about it think about the
implication think what is the best for
your organization you always can have
policies of what you want to send out
what you don't want to send out I think
the more important thing is that
everybody is aware that there are some
things that can happen you might be able
to see something in your outing and I
just want to bring you a pointer to say
hey maybe it might be that it might be
even something completely different so
more of you look into
more we test the more interesting things
we see the more questions come up
sometimes you do something wrong
sometimes you say hey wait a moment that
is a that is just an attribute of rpki
and it's fine as long as they know about
it as long as they can do something I
could think about if if it flickers too
much that I just turn off my validation
care or I turn off the r Cena 1897 so I
only sent you if I make a change in my
in my selection process until I have a
stable connection so and there's so many
different ways and I don't want to tell
you what you have to do and I don't
think we would shouldn't stand here and
say what you have to do the important
thing is that you know there is
something and you have to make your own
decision what you want to do with this
information
okay so the AF set as far as I remember
was considered when we D actually
designed the whole thing as something
that should go away
and I'm not completely sure whoever we
were completely wrong about it and it's
not that design decision is now biting
us on the other hand one if one really
wants to look into it
one should recognize a assets'
essentially happen because some AAS is
creating an aggregate root and that
essentially means that well okay you you
probably are going to see the origin of
the aggregate root as the last AAS
before the a s set kind of kind of yes
things can be more screwed up but kind
of if we are talking about 1.0 0.0 one
percent of roots that we are seeing and
1% of those goods are the special cases
well okay yeah I mean if if you wanna
open this this box that is actually
something but I always like to open
because all the identification
identifies to identify an AI said
they're all optional I can make a cure
got a guess pass aggregation if we don't
put my asset in my path if we don't set
the aggregator you don't know it's
aggregated and all of a sudden my AS IS
the auger is the originator so why is it
not the originator if I put C is it in I
puts your asset in because I cannot
guarantee that I create a route group so
we can open this discussion I'm really
okay since years won't have that but
yeah well okay the my highest priority
comment actually is to your question
should we do a document and yes that
might be nice maybe more documents than
one but actually for getting started I
think we really ought to identify some
repository where we just dump the stuff
that we find then what we get along and
that may be later on be refined into a
document that actually has consensus and
while okay high quality and whatever as
far as I can tell so far we really have
not yet installed or recognized such a
repository that we agree to actually use
I may be wrong I may have forgotten
about it the only one I know if it's
email list and but but I mean that's a
good idea as well I mean the question is
just is there is there interest you know
if it is a document if it is a github
thing if it is I don't know what what
other people will come fresh into the
whole field can read and educate and get
some ideas if
not hey be my guest I'm fine with that
as well it is just an idea I throw in
the room yeah well okay I think actually
such a recognized repository is actually
very very much needed because pointing
people to a mailing list it's a little
hideous yeah but works as well job
Snider's entity too short remarks in
terms of SS the implementation on an
open Beach PD is that we ignore the
asset when doing the original edition
procedure so we just look at the last
sequence of the s path the
implementations I've done internet
exchanges for route surfers using birth
birth has an option to look at the last
not aggregated ASM in the SPF so we
could just shortcut this discussion ASL
does not exist I mean that maybe it
would be nice updated RFC 6811 to
basically the indication of my asset but
I think that's a different discussion I
think the thing is is if the only thing
what we identified is that not every
implementation Isis seems to validate a
asset there are some implementations
that actually allow you to configure the
heck out of your router and you can do
whatever you want with that you can even
roll the dice so I think if the vendor
provides enough document enough
configuration so that you as user can
decide what you want to do that's fine I
mean it's a little bit of problem if
other everybody uses its differently it
is just something that I say maybe you
should look into what does your out or
do with that and just know about how it
works and final comments when speaking
to operators about deploying origin
validation a question that often arises
is what will be the performance impacts
and then I sketch out well it's patricia
cheese we do the lookup in this table
the table only has this specific types
of tuples so we can do it in
microseconds having a document where the
title is
performance impacts of origin fala
Dacian or something more that just
focuses on that one question what is the
impact and that we can prove that
there's virtually no impact would be
very helpful in promoting original
validation so if you end up writing
documents one document specifying that
there is no performance impact would be
very useful yeah
if the document says use something
produced after 2014 sure
[Music]
thank you okay so we propose a
validation state unverified and I
propose that for two things for rpki
origin validation as well as for T to be
sick pass validation the I believe it is
important to distinguish between
validated and non-validated routes just
label non-validated routes as not found
waters down completely the validation
state of not found we have yeah so there
are situations where for example if I go
and be to be sick for a second if I
receive routes I might want to do lazy
evaluation so I just want to take them
in I want to do my route selection or
whatever and then maybe I want to do the
validation later on it would be
interesting to see there if this route
was validated or not
not just to sign some label in the same
I think is also true with Origin
validation the algorithms in RFC 68 11
and 8205 specify values that are the
result of a very defined algorithm not
validating something if I just assign
blindly the validation state I watered
on them all
as programmer for me personally if I've
write something and I have pointers I
initialize them I either set them to
nada or I have them to some objects I
don't know what they're just leaving
them hanging in the in the blue doesn't
help me and sometimes I need to know if
they are not and I think the same thing
we have here as well
the for me basically an unverified and
and a verified route are not the same
and unverified and what sound is not the
same if this is the same then what can I
say if I see a valid route my router was
it validated was it not validated there
are some routers as I said before that
on ibgp label everything is valid so
normally well it tells me that this raw
that gave me the result that this route
is valid now I just labeled it it we
found two word usages and I learned the
meantime there also a couple of more but
one for example juniper has the
unverified and I don't I don't want as
I'm not saying that I want to prefer
this vendor to any other I just say they
for example have that I liked it very
much
our implementation isn't undefined what
was a little bit more semantics but I'm
very fine with unverified as well going
to RC 68:11 so we we wanted to have
unverified specifies the state of a
route prefix which one which no which no
evolution has been performed and to
update this statement a validation is
not the fountain or au its
implementation should initially they
initialize the validation state of such
route to not found to the sentence if no
evaluation over out prefix is performed
in any form the implementation must
initialize the validation state of such
route to unverified if I would have that
then I could figure out if for example
the routers that returned on the a s set
they're not found in
they chose to not validated or if they
have a bug because if they chose to not
validated they should be unverified if
they validated I know you know invalid
if I have a covering raw to this also
RFC 1897 should should have the
unverified look up in there as well I
don't believe that the absence of the
community string tells me that my peer
validated the prefix or didn't maybe it
just does not sent me the extended
community string and the whole thing
becomes really important when you start
writing policies for not found once you
start writing policies for every
validation state you might be very
interested in the fact if this one was
validated or not
because then you might say hey if I
receive something VI BGP that was not
Murray dated maybe I start my local
validation or maybe a low prep it or
maybe whatever it could be a good I
didn't good good thing if you look into
your logs and you see okay why is this
unverified why did some validation start
not start for that particular thing
maybe I have impacted my configuration
same as RFC 8205 they be only have the
state valid and not valid and these one
are the outcomes of the body days an
algorithm if I don't validate it then
sure it's not valid but they're not
valid in this case means more okay it
didn't pass validation so if I did not
validate it if it didn't even attempt it
to evaluate it then I should say it's
unverified so and then we would just say
BGP routes feature music routes must be
initialized using the BGP SEC validation
state unverified until proper evaluation
of the BGP SEC route has been performed
how you evaluate is different this is
completely up to you but if you don't do
anything to the route it should be
unverified why should I set it to not
valid why should I said it - well it
okay last time I don't strongly object
to this but I think this is a little
confused
both the origin validation and BGP
second round and round and round on how
many output states are the from the
validation okay an origin validation as
the three states because they're very
simple but good and I can prove it it's
bad and I can prove it and everything
else what the flavor of everything else
is outside the scope of the validation I
I can understand an operational reason
why you might care what flavor of on of
not able to prove anything it is but
that's what you're talking about is
different you know the point is this you
made you made something very important
you said the outcome of the validation
algorithm if I don't even start the
validation algorithm then I need to
initialize it because otherwise I only
have three States I can attach to this
particular prefix RC 6811 says if you
choose to not validate something you
should have a case should set it to not
for sure but look at all the weight look
at all the different reasons why you
could have failed to run the validation
out for them you didn't want to you
weren't able to connect to something
you're having a bad day and you're
running really slowly there are a whole
bunch of different states there the
point was just to skip over all of that
in terms of the specification as I said
in your implementation if you want to
keep track of a whole bunch of different
we didn't quite get there States
whatever it's harmless but the algorithm
description is trying to distinguish
just the security state from the
security standpoint either you can prove
or you can't
similarly with DGP SEC it's but if you
say you can't then why don't you say
invalid
why did you say not found
that's my mind you know you go you know
you're going you take a perfectly valid
validation state no invalid is it's
wrong I can prove it yes and not found
is I didn't find any raw information no
no you just said what I had yes not not
found is mislabeled not found is
everything else that's really all I've
ever been but if you listen to the
algorithms there is basically says you
look up and if you do not find a
covering route prefix mmm that's one
reason why you might not be able to do
it doesn't say anything about anything
else
it just says this and then it is not
found if I if I don't even look into it
how should I know that it's not found
how should I know that I did not find a
security state when I was looking it up
that's all it is similarly with BGP sec
there's I can prove that it's good and
there's everything else that's the
algorithm description who UFO touch
Telecom
I think the BGP SEC argument is somewhat
different than the origin validation
thing in BGP SEC kind of yeah well
actually actually no I disagree with my
with the first statement no actually
actually marking that you have analyzed
analyzed the analyzed the state of stuff
or you have not really really is
significant information were not found
as it is labeled in original validation
by now by naive persons like myself is
interpreted like we know that with our
current set of rowers it is
not covered and so we cannot tell we
cannot tell with envy rpki whether it is
valid or invalid because the
authorization scheme of rpki doesn't say
anything about it having having not done
and started the test really is really is
a different thing and it makes a lot of
sense to have different policy decisions
based on that
and with the BGP SEC yes kind of the
Fate we have done for checks and we
found it is invalid kind of is a
different thing than in origin
validation were the unknown really
really is a distinct state from invalid
but anyway undecided in logic in logic
you sometimes run into the strange
situation that the chatsy unknown dot or
does not apply yes or no true or fails
in some cases really has to be amended
by we do not know we may not be able to
decide state then at the end it's all up
to the operator or to the user you can
say for me in found and undefined I
treat them both the same it's not that
we say you have to treat them different
[Music]
you can treat them the same you but they
also could say you know what I want to
hold back on them
maybe I'll oppress them or I don't know
whatever you like reading I said it is
it might be of interest and I think it
is of interest to determine if a route
was validated or not and just assigning
they're not found I think it's not the
right thing and not distinguishing
they're quite certainly creates the what
was your turn in the previous talk in
our conflicting conflicting state if you
have announcements coming in from a
Rooter that has for whatever reason lost
the capability of classifying and
another one that actually does the
classification you are getting a
conflict knowing knowing that the one
has lost its mind and cannot really tell
allows you to say well okay if I have a
better classification I can use that
I suppose are you proposing to write a
document it's discusses this problem no
I mean you're you're proposing to either
write to biz documents or write
something we can chat about in on list
at the next meeting or whatever about
should the states should there be
another state or you just bringing up a
problem saying this is interesting and
we should fix this but not sorry oh
sorry yeah actually two drafts uploaded
yep okay great thank you
I think Tim this is you I hope this is
the right one it says something
different in the the schedule says key
role anyway that's probably my fault
yeah okay but it is it just started life
as a but I'll get there so I talked
about this a few times already we
currently have no proper way of rolling
route keys in the RPI so goals of this
whole exercise are that well we want to
be able to do it in a reliable way you
want to learn from the in a sec what can
be learned there but we also want to
look at what we have in the RTI and make
sure that this has a soft landing into
the existing standards that we may be
able to leverage things that we have
here a another goal that I think we can
reach as well is that we can leave a
trail for clients for a relying party
software that is out of date that has an
old sauce hanger configured with it that
it may be able to find a new toilet
trust anchor so the changes in the o2
version I
there was not a lot of discussion at the
mic last time I presented this but I had
a long discussion with Austin afterwards
and actually Rob came on as co-author as
well we discussed well extensively and
basically the bottom line of it is that
we want to allow multiple keys in
parallel in theory you can have 20 but
the same thing is probably to only used
to at the same time it supports both
planned and unplanned rolls you don't
really know if you're going to need an
unplanned roll so there is at the moment
no indication of when you plan to do a
roll because that might be misleading
you might say I'm going to roll to this
next key and then it turns out you lost
some X key so we can discuss whether
that's actually useful to include
because you know this should not happen
all the time but for the moment it's not
in there then the next steps well okay
don't take it literally but I would say
we're going forward with this what we
want to do we want to actually make some
running code and anybody interested in
that I would say let's talk and work
together somehow an option might be to
do that at an ITF hackathon or get to
get our but you know there's other ways
as well
so if you're interested in doing work in
in this space please let me know this
was actually the executive summary let's
say so reminders all what we do is for
you know a cast but if this time I do
have more slides on how the process
actually works so is it time to go
through that then I might do that so
okay now the current situation we have
trust anchor locators that are either
shipped with a relying party software or
configured the software will then fetch
a certificate verify it and then that
certificate has a publication point we
manifest serial and other
stuff like a certificate or a child then
that has its own repository and so on um
so that's where we are today and if you
want to reconfigure the chancre you have
to put a new towel into your relying
party so far so to avoid confusion
between science tell and tell that was
actually in the previous document to
tell is a plain text file with a bunch
of your eyes and a a subject of the key
info fingerprint but this object that we
are now creating is a bit more than that
so I sneakily renamed it to sauce anchor
keys instead of tell to avoid that
confusion but I still have to get used
to that name myself so I might say sign
tell why excellent have you known them
so but in any case what you can do just
using one key like today one root key
you can opt into to having this you can
create a an object a tal tag object that
basically refers back to your one and
only current key associate this is a
current key so invalidation software
will be configured with the trust anchor
it will find the tag file there and
discover okay that the crossing car used
is still current so I'm good to go and
there's nothing else to look at
importantly but of course just doing
this won't get you very far or give you
many you know benefits so if you have
two keys well what you can do is lots of
drawings here in this state both keys
are current both are fine if you
configured with its anchor for the first
key what you do is you find a the blue
tea a tag object you validate it and it
refers to two crossed anchor
certificates
there are curls so you will then need to
look at both well one you already looked
at but you don't need to look at the
green on you'll discover there are a new
tack file that also lists these two keys
that's good so you don't there's nothing
else to look at as documented now the
relying party tool can then just
continue validation with the key that
they started with so they can just take
the thumb pointer here well the top see
Acer certificate right this one to
continue here right and I left that in
manifest in crl here or because it would
get very close as well um
so another approach might be that you
you would say you have to take the union
of everything that's good and undo
something like that but I figured that
you know this is the easiest seems the
easiest to me now to continue if you
roll to a new key and this is a plan
roll what you can do is you can well
first of all you introduce a new key
three it has the same content as s2 but
for number one you actually stop
publishing shell certificates on all
that you only population manifest in
this URL and a new long lift attack file
that says I am actually revoked and
these are currently the new keys yeah I
guess in theory that could also be a
pointer to ta three there at this point
to here but yeah it's not strictly
necessary actually
the this file this one still refers back
this one needs to be revoked letter out
here because essentially the relying
party only discovers this when you
already learned that this is going to be
revoked and if you would keep the list
of all
the old keys around all the time then
this list grows in road so I don't think
it's necessary and that's it really on
plants though I didn't make a slide of
that but I'm plan that essentially is
you have no ability to update this so it
will stay like this right so the
viewpoint from ta1 will will be ok 1 & 2
are current but then 2 will say one has
actually revoked
so you still learn about it and this is
also what I meant with there's no timing
indication in there you could include it
and if you know if you do a planned role
that might be useful but in theory
there's no way to be sure that you don't
you may have to do it on that role so
that's why I left it out I don't think
it's strictly necessary to have it there
but you know if other people feel it's
important we could include it and I
think that's it yeah so I've been even
more concerned cat here I would say was
hurt occur I say and I've looked a lot
lately into rolling top-level keys of
various things and well the short and
sweet the TLDR is it sucks it's it's not
easy to do right a couple of takeaways
from what and I there's a document I
need to actually publish at some point
that after looking at all of not just
you in a sec but looking at x.509 and
peak Hicks and the web and that kind of
stuff - there's a lot of takeaways that
that I've you know gotten out of it that
I can transcribe into a couple of
bullets of wisdom one you need to plan
on doing longer key roles lifetimes and
you were probably originally thinking
you'd come back to that in a second and
two you really ought to be prepared with
you know multiple keys in the future and
part of it becomes from that that need
for a long hero and and the reality
is that in all of these systems there
are really three places three ways that
Keys get distributed toward you know
running systems first off you have
software updates where keys or basically
you know encoded weather whether it's a
you know a flash rom in an in a router
or whether it's actually you know bird
being installed somewhere they often
come with pre distributed keys and that
update process especially in critical
infrastructure takes a very long time
so the other option is doing something
like fifty eleven and DNS SEC where you
know there's this automated update
mechanism not everybody turns that kind
of thing on so you can't assume that the
that is always going to be the case and
as you know warren found things running
docker don't really sort of have that
longevity of measurement and then three
is the manual configuration where you
know users wait until the very last
second before they finally update their
config you can't really you know worry
about them too much but but my takeaway
from all of this is that it has it takes
a lot longer to do those those key roles
and and therefore especially if you're
planning on accommodating the software
pushes the the you know the the pre
packaged software pushes that's on the
order of two or three years so it might
actually be a beneficial to have you
know two to three key staging in advance
not just one or two and being prepared
for that and so the good news is yeah
you've your happiest stateful yes and
that doesn't I can be in a second sada
but the document also says something
about that you you may actually wish
start shipping this and if this is your
intended new key what you might want to
do is update all the nine party software
then there's out there to get them to
include a new one instead
but it yeah you probably shouldn't do
this you know every week and and I'd
like to go less everybody supports it
fully automated etc but I think we're a
long way from that I like the fact that
you're you're considering using double
signatures which we can't we couldn't do
Indiana Secretary Pat concise
constraints and things like that which
you don't really suffer from so that's
the positive side but at some point you
still have to turn off the old key and
you're still going to break every
that failed to irrigate hi job Snyder's
just relaying a message from IRC beta
from Dec from Power dienes would like to
sit down with you to share the good
lessons and the bad lessons from DNS SEC
and sync up to see the some mistakes
made in DNS SEC can be avoided in this
rolling mechanism so that's astounding
offer will you I'd like to point
out that the rpki Act use actually has
some significant difference from our DNS
SEC in our PK in rpki we actually we
actually need to expect that relying
party implementation has some heuristics
that raise alarms if things start to
fail in big ways or while okay in
suspicious ways I'm not sure that all of
the existing relying party
implementations do this but one cannot
repeat that often enough until it is
this way and of course they also need
some heuristics how to deal with it and
that needs that needs to be documented
in some ways so now for DNS SEC one
would expect that yes operators of
resolvers get some feedback but kind of
the expectation in rpki deployment I
think is that relying parties really
need to need to have those expose alarms
and the workarounds and yes that's not
really
helping helping with this design at this
point right so you have a relying party
so far that doesn't support any of this
it's configured with this truss anchor
locator and it comes here and it finds
an object that doesn't understand and on
otherwise anti repository yeah and yeah
I don't know if all the validators alert
about that
I think the right-hand Susi validated
two series at some point raised a Luis
if there was a change larger than 10% of
the repository or something but yeah
that may need some veteran you know
that's that's that's really that's
really important that's hurt occur I say
again because I forgot my second bullet
point which is that the other thing that
was horribly broken with the you know
sec key role in particular and is also
broken in the x.509 world but nobody's
thought about it as much there is that
the signaling mechanism so the publisher
of a key can trust that all of the clock
all of the relying parties are actually
using the new key is basically
non-existent or broken or incomplete and
so I can had you know an absolutely
horrible heartburn up until you know a
month ago where they finally just had to
go we're gonna do it anyway without
knowing if things were gonna break and
you guys might have the opportunity to
kind of fix that but knowing how files
and think are synced I'd have to go it's
I'm two years out of having real
associations so they're not in my mind
at the moment so you need to do
revalidation top-down all the time
anyway so I see Russ is in Lima you
suggest that a document to me where
basically inside a certificate you can
signal this is going to be the next key
I looked at that but I figured that we
actually have a way here to to do this
as well within the up yeah because of
how its published you need to Bro
validate this whole repository anyway so
you can have an object there a signed
object that
[Music]
these things that we want to communicate
and that's essentially why I went for
that but I think in in terms of
semantics it's not that difference but
so to take away it's essentially saying
these keys our next public key
fingerprint essentially panel location
where you might find them and it's
communicated within let's say in banner
of the RPI repository so you can find
these things so as you're doing
validation all the time anyway I think
you're missing my point which is that
maybe maybe that I'm actually talking
about the relying party signaling to to
the people that it's pulling data from
looking at the routing objects saying
these are the keys I trust so that so
that the the publisher of the objects
can say oh it's now safe to switch to
using a new or revoking an old key
because all of the relying parties have
now you know gotten to like 99% of
accepting the new key and without that
signaling measurement you just burn
heartburn interred right well yeah okay
just shooting from the hip what you may
be able to do is monitor the access to
these things are published in different
places right so you can look at your
access logs and figure out if people
still try to fetch the the old
certificate for example keep in mind but
no yeah okay it needs so it needs some
more thought because you know you're
right that's incomplete so this is Russ
I think there's a big difference between
what Wes was just talking about in this
because our certificates have an
expiration date if we get to that point
it doesn't matter that is not the case
in the environment wes is just talking
about the other thing is I do think the
document I pointed you to creates a
situation where people get used to
building the next at the head of time
and so you're always in a situation
where in an emergency you have the key
which are let's go
Randy Bush IJ Marcus so unlike the
locally world of DNS SEC a failure to
validate within the rpki tree is a soft
failure it will only produce not founds
invalidation relax so Warren Kumari the
other other thing we learnt from the DNS
SEC key role is that yeah or something
or maybe the only thing we learn is that
emergency key rules are really really
really different to regular key roles
and actually the process that we have
for normal key roles in the DNS SEC
don't work at all for KS I mean for
emergency roles and I think that there's
some correlation here where you know I
just
my key is no longer trust able needs a
better signaling mechanism maybe okay
yeah just coming back actually currently
the document says these keys are
equivalent and we have no way of telling
you which is going to do the next role
so you can't really monitor what people
do right maybe it's better to change it
to really say this is the Intendant X
key regardless of that maybe you do need
to do an on plan thing because then you
can monitor whether people have moved
over
good afternoon my name is Alexander
Smurf from Goethe lips and today I'm
going to provide a short overview of
about all works that are related to
rotis so as far as I know there are
three active drafts in different working
groups first one is BGP open policy and
it is related to preventing networks
from leaking the sector one is the
oldest one and now it's about detection
of flicked prefixes using communities
and the last one is using your
application object here and is capable
to detect both mistake and malicious
activity so looking at this comparison
one might ask why do we need this thing
with communities because we already have
something more powerful more advanced
that is capable also to detect both
malicious and mistakes and the problem
is time and time does matter taking a
look at the raw deployment process it
will take years before we'll get a stay
a verification in the world and that's
why we decided to use communities to
detect root leaks we will not be able to
detect malicious activity but still it
will be helpful to detect accidental
leaks and so protects our networks and
from these kind of threats so this is
how see the strategic planning so at
first the first will be deleted
community based leak detection and I
hope it will be delivered during this
year or not this not until these at the
end of this year but using one year
period I hope to take less than this
the
we'll be a lick prevention this will
also automate the way leak detection is
working and the last one will will be a
a spay which together with raw records
will finally bring us through the
paradise but so you know there was a
update of a spade raft and authors work
worked really hard as a result we have a
new abstract and some small restructure
of the document but there was an
important clarification in the version
zero one ace be is not trying to provide
a full ice bath check instead of its
predecessors it's just provides a tool
to detect real operational problems
hijacks and root leaks that's all it's
not a general solution for the ice bath
it just a solution for real problems so
this is how I see it in a near future I
hope you will be able to see this
progress in half in half year so be open
policy seems to be ready nearly ready to
up to the last call we already have two
implementations and so after a clean up
I sure I hope there will be a logical
and it will be successful second root
leak detection is also near a radio so
after it's the growth session it seems
that we finally decided to go on with
large communities and specified format
for these large communities there should
be no location anymore and ASP is be a
verification it seems to that we are
ready for adoption code so I requested
option call now thank you any questions
please be sure to send your request
enlist sure
Julio Volk stupid question
what well ok you are saying for open
policy there is still cleanup necessary
cleanup in the text just there was life
it hopes that were included if it's some
it's some time ago and we just need to
make a cleanup be quick ok it was
because time matters
can that be done really quickly no I
hope so I need some input from my
co-authors and I hope I will have it
that you in this meeting after that
we're done
ok and as you are asking for adoption
yes the ASPA is fine yeah thank you
so it's good to this we have a consensus
I hope so and I hope that both working
groups of both all working groups that
are related to this topic grow idea
insider ops will soon see the progress
in all these threats thank you
that's totally not your side it's got
two rolls in it maybe three it's coming
[Music]
thank you
so we discussed this in back in London
and desert policy and here the idea is
to drop invalids if it is covered if
there is another prefix route in in the
router that is for the less specific
that is either valid or not found in
that case the most specific invalid can
be dropped so this is a joint work
between NIST
folks and job so just to recapitulate
what desert policy is basically it
desert stands for drop invalid if still
routable so the idea as I said is drop
invalid if a valid or not found less
specific route exists and why why do you
why do we want to do this or policy so
if a rover for a subsuming less specific
prefix exists but there is no Rover for
the prefix that you want you want you
announce then the desert policy working
elsewhere in other a SS it ensures that
the traffic for the more specific still
reaches you you are the
legitimate destination for it and but it
reaches you possibly in a suboptimal or
non traffic engineered path invalid
announcement of your proof of your more
specific by you or others are rejected
so that's the basic idea of the desert
policy we updated the draft to we got
pretty good feedback and discussion when
we presented it in London including
comments on the list so there are two or
three main discussion points questions
that came up that that we have addressed
and updated that the draft in the o2
version these are included so the s0
question s 0 Toa question came from Tim
and the wording in the draft which did
not exist before
it says the existence of an S 0 Rover
for a prefix means that the prefix or
any more specific prefix subsumed in it
are forbidden from routing except when
there exists a different Rover with a
normal ASN for the prefix or the more
specific so given that understanding of
a s0 rower
the desert policy must apply the
following exception if a route is
invalid due to na s 0 Rover then always
drop that out so hopefully that takes
care of Tim's question so normally you
would if if a route is invalid you would
look for a less specific that is either
valid or not found but if na s0 Rover is
the one that makes it invalid then don't
even look for it just drop it once
should we can take questions on the fly
if you know ok let's a couple of more
minutes and we can finish through this
and go to the questions and kay you
raised this other question about default
routes 0.0 v4 or v6 in the routing table
so those must be excluded from
consideration in the desert policy this
what I think I would wanted to see so
that that wording is also in the new
version of the draft
John Scudder pointed something about
multihoming so jeff has has had some
multihoming question so John took a cue
from that and he posed this other
question so in this scenario there are
2/20 force at the bottom those are
aggregated by as2 into a slash 23 the
and that slash 23 gets to a s4 and why
another path through a s3 the slash 24
on the right also goes to a s4 and there
may be also a hijack also happening from
a s5 so John's point was that the in the
case of multihoming the slash 24 on the
right it is really multi-home so that it
can it can have reach ability in the
event of a limit link failure so in this
example the link between the stash 24 on
the right and the s2 fails and now the
question is for some reason John third
thought that a s2 might still be
aggregating and forwarding a slash 23 to
AS four and John's concern was that a s4
now he drops all the invalids and routes
the traffic for the slash 24 on the
right to a s2 and s2 has no way to
deliver it so that was is concerned then
he's saying that sort of the purpose of
multihoming is lost but the point is
this is happening when you have a
combination of things there is
multihoming Noro as are being created by
this slash 24 and there is also a link
failure so apart from the from the
combination of all those things having
to happen if you look at a s2 one might
ask if the link is down
and it is no longer has announcement for
the slash 24 on the right why is it
still aggregating it should just D a
grenade and send only 1/24 up so that
itself probably answers the John's
question in in addition of course any
multi-home customer in in any scenario
should be all should be always crew fool
about rpki if they don't create ro as
for any of the multiple announcements
they make to their upstreams
that and not have I mean not having
rowers not a good thing so in terms of
conceptually implementation Jeff had
this was not in the original draft Jeff
before the London meeting
I spoke with Jeff Haas and he offered
some interesting insights into what is
feasible in implementation so so that
aspect is now captured in the updated
draft so the next two slides which talk
about conceptual implementation they are
now included in the in the draft yeah
yeah they are fully described I mean
they are described at the level of
conceptual implement a implementation so
Jeff's idea was that you don't do the
desire policy as part of the path
selection decision process you do the
path selection decision process
including origin validation and then you
put your valid invalid not found routes
in the local drip and after that you do
that is their policy and before you
you'd send the routes into the PHA but
the ad ribbons from the local rib that
is where they in between those two is
where you do that is their policy and
that we seem seem to make perfect sense
for many people that that looked at this
in London when we presented it so this
included in the new draft and another
point is that you can have these three
situations that arise a valid or not
found route that was used to route to
drop invalids
that when a new one can be can be added
or an order existing valid not invalid
route may be withdrawn or you may have a
PKI state changes and they're out there
is informed about it in all of these
three situations we need to we need to
do something that is a policy needs to
deep refresh and those are described as
well thank you questions and you would
also like to request adoption call on
this draft okay job Snyder's entity this
may come as a bit of a weird statement
given that my name is on this draft but
I I am not so sure at this point whether
pursuing this draft is worthwhile
because I feel we've been somewhat
overtaken by events if I look at origin
validation deployments and I've had some
handsome experience by now the mode of
operation simply is reject invalid and
deal with the fallout the DSD is our
mechanism we came up with that as a sort
of dampening mechanism to ease into
original validation give him that
there's between five and six thousand
envelop HP announcements in the default
free zone but I think attacking the five
six thousand invalid announcements
should perhaps not be done through a
router change where we you know upgrade
codes look at the deployment timeline of
three to four years and then have a
degree of tolerance for miss
configurations I think it will be easier
for everybody if we just reach out to
the people that have misconfigured their
robust and asked them to fix it or
delete it
new Sanu has shared some research on the
right routing working group mailing list
and on the nanak mailing list about who
the entities are that have done miss
configurations and it seems that the
majority of miss configurations
comes from only a handful of companies
so I think this is a I've come to
realize that this may be a
disproportionately big hammer for a
problem that can be attacked through
different means and conceptually I like
this but I'm really not looking forward
to getting to running code because that
will require me far more work than just
fighting the bullets and dropping in
ballots and calling it a day
so I'm not sure we I personally I'm not
sure if we should pursue this idea so
for the I experienced Eames like it
makes sense to drop the invalid even now
because like you explained yesterday or
in the apg you you I mean it will just
go through the transit provider rather
than go through the IXP right so like I
can lay in other cases that may not be
true so if you drop invalid there will
be so it's so the assumption that there
won't be any invalid after some time if
you are diligent and make calls I don't
know if that assumption would hold it
hold good in the long run so what I
didn't mention that's I apt I did
mention that I've space should drop
envelops right now but in the Dutch
networker community we are deploying
original edition in is piece where we do
the same philosophy and drop in fella
announcements and there's a significant
number of commercial internet providers
that are dropping in ballots and they
report that it's not harming their
business and that it's a viable model so
you are able to drop invalid without
affecting reach ability for the for this
situation so it affects reach ability
but it doesn't affect business another
number I can share from a it doesn't it
doesn't create user tickets well it
creates a few per week but it's
manageable that's the that's the message
the the the discovery of the networker
community is hey we can drop in ballots
and it's not her
too bad can it quickly since you both
are the co-authors in the document
I suggest at least to take this offline
and then once you have a consensus
amongst yourself make a request again if
you want to still adopt this as a
working group documents thank you I
guess so
so Warren Kumari I'm was a part of the
NOC team so on this network we have two
peers ebgp peers who are taking full
routes from both and we're dropping in
ballads on both so it's 6100 prefixes or
so or routes that we're dropping
nobody's noticed nobody's complained no
ticket no tickets I mean he noticed and
was like why are you still passing these
on and then I realized because the
filter wasn't actually applied but it
seems to just work presumably some of
them are following covering routes maybe
who do folk
I guess the timing argument is fairly
important but first thing is I hate it
when someone explains that a zero rowers
are anything special the only special in
the a s0 roars is that we know that
routes with origin a s0 cannot occur
hopefully the route of vendors actually
enforce that or VI ISPs in their routing
policy there is no doubt with s0 rower
there is only a door with a s0 there's
no doubt yeah well okay but explaining
anything special about a s0 rowers is
kind of misleading people if I if I if I
if I in create if I create a rua for an
a s that I own and I know will not show
up in the in
the wild it is effectively the same as
an AS zero raw yes well okay kind of
kind of creating special semantics for
it
are something that I would question very
seriously but K you're actually if you
found that also one has to protect
against using the default routes of
course that is something where you
figure out one okay you do not you do
not only want to protect against zero
colon colon slash zero you also want to
protect against zero colon colon slash
one and where does that end now consider
that as an invitation to people to
announce / eights again that they do not
own in the public v4 and all that stuff
I I just wanted to comment quick Tim
evangels quickly on the ASE or thing so
personally I'm not a fan of a s 0 robust
but I brought it up because people to
see these things as meaning block this
and if that is intended then you would
need to do something extra for that to
work that that's what my point is not
that I actually like them or want them
or anything I think that's a completely
separate discussion but people people
who think that there is actually special
semantics don't get the clue that when
they do their a as one two three Aurora
it essentially excludes everything below
regardless of what a s number and unless
unless like in VA s 0
as more specific roar is issued for
different yes okay I think probably any
more needs to go to the list George's oh
okay he's gonna so hopefully this is a
shorter version of what we've all seen
once before so the problem statement is
reasonably straightforward we have to
have a coordinated state between three
slightly different communities of actors
we need code to both sign and validate
and we need an agreement to move to
using that code by both relying parties
and signers and we have to decide how
we're going to move this of course is
predicated on the assumption we want to
move in any class of technology in this
space which is materially going to alter
the behavior of validation or demands
change in the existing software suite to
take respect to something like an OID
change or a structural change in the
certificate so these conditions are in
some senses a general statement would
apply when we make non-compatible
changes to the system but they are
specifically focused in this
conversation on validation reconsidered
so I did a review of what I felt with
the code changes we had conversation
last time there are some people who
would disagree with my summation of the
ease of doing this I left the slide in
for sheer cheek and outrage but
essentially there's a conversation about
how hard it's gonna be
we have not had a real conversation
about a timeline as RIR as the engine is
in the RIR community we feel a very
strong concern inside our own space
about our exposure to risk it and we
would wish to propose a future date
which has not been too
find in this document because that is
presumptuous but we think that we need
to define a future date to have a flag
day and give somewhere around a year of
notice the complete migration to a new
OID and a new model of validation and
our intent is to actually go into the
nog community and talk with operators to
get some sense of convergence and
consensus from that community of what
they want to do but when I presented
this idea last time I got very strong
pushback on an expectation that a draft
should exist that is a formalism that
can be talked to in that context and
having discussed this in the ECG we
agreed to submit a draft so there is now
a draft document which was lodged midway
through last month which I am
effectively seeking adoption on and it
discusses some technology questions
around what do we actually want to do it
we want to make a complete radical shift
in one hit to a new OID space or do we
want to have some mixed mode of
operation where the introduction of a
new ID provides signaling options of a
rigid validation model and a more lacks
validation model and the questions that
would arise from having provision of
both in the same information space I
feel very strongly personally that it is
simply not possible to move without some
sense of tripartite convergence on this
it's a mutual deadlock situation and
that does implicitly mean anybody in
that sense of community who says I will
not move has oppositional qualities that
really are a roadblock we can't move
without code we can't move without
consent and agreement by relying parties
and Cas to adopt this new technology we
can't deploy towels specifically in our
rir role without a sense the community
is ready for them because deployment of
something with a radical new OID
instantly breaks the validation model
for everybody I still believe that we
are in that golden moment my sense of
the number of active party
who are engaged in this is that it is
less than 500 now we can quibble about
what the exact numbers are I am involved
in a body of work with a collection of
people to try and explore the space and
understand how big is the field of
people who are using this system so we
already have a problem it's a
distributed problem but it's not
internet scale in the sense of tens or
hundreds or millions of people it's 500
engaged entities and it feels to me like
a Flag Day is logistically simple and
actually can be done we can do this so
I'm seeking working group adoption for a
zero state craft that has been authored
by myself and Tim Tim was in the RIR
system and wrote the initial state of
this draft in his previous state but he
has since moved to a different role he
now works in NL net labs developing rpki
software router Nader ha route inator
3000 sounds like something that should
be on sale on a TV shopping channel yeah
it's brilliant I mean I think I think
it's brilliant
yeah these apps perhaps later did this
for me so he's moved role and will
probably consider an author shift
because it's not fair he should have to
take the eggs and tomatoes because he's
not actually in the RIR space but
nonetheless he remains on this ground
state craft and will discuss what to do
next but this is assuming we get
adoption and clearly there are many
things in the conversation one of them
is that we probably have some flaws in
the model we might have put forward
timing constraints or behavior
constraints that are wrong so there are
conversations of merit around how does
it work but there is also the more
important conversation for me which is
what would be a to be defined date if we
were going to do this
what are we prepared to put in the
ground as a stake and say we're aiming
to move in 2019 in 2020 because to me
that's the more important quality what
we do when we move I understand in
technological sense is more relevant but
the decision to move and when and how
much notice in a process sense is what
actually motor
baits and drives me because that drives
the conversation in the community to an
emerging consensus that's it
Radhika
hi George my memory is leaking so I may
have well ok my ears are someone
sometimes dumped so I may have missed
something do we actually have a roadmap
were also into operability reports show
up having running code kind of yes kind
of having the kinks actually worked out
probably would be good to have have been
achieved and proven before of the flag
day comes that's that's probably a fair
point if we were going to actually do
this and make an assessment of
dependency and interdependence then
having an understanding of which
platforms do implement support for this
would or could implement support have
some interrupts that's reasonable um I
believe the right validator has code for
this model I'm not convinced that it's
live but I believe it was at one point
implemented in their codebase but
there's a reluctance to undertake a body
of work that doesn't have broad
consensus we're left with a problem and
we are very aware of our exposure of
risk in this problem and this is a path
out for our problem but we have the
other side of the balance book we have
budgets in time and in labor so if
there's no community intend to move then
asking people as validation software
developers or see a signing party to
implement is a burden they don't need we
need the signal but no it's a fair point
we would need a matrix we would have to
understand interoperability I can stand
here for another 15 minutes if you
really want 20 minutes of me but I don't
think you want the date what I think
help students just make a date say 18
months from when the RFC is published
okay yeah
although otherwise we put 2019 in the
original dog but X hey it feels a little
unrealistic I don't know Jeff Jeff
Houston um really his points really
quite valid if there's no code I like
setting a dates yeah you know
don't know it's fair right you need code
you need to actually have version and
write your code before you can figure
out when a dates valid that's all I'm
saying
so we probably fantasy horses so we
probably do have to lay the hole in the
ground and write the code and test it to
see if it's viable that would make an
awful lot of sense in an Operations area
George
the long-haired friend behind you has
comment at the mic well Rob last night
so it should not be news that my gut
reaction is two days after hell freezes
over however I completely agree with
verdigris comment if he wanted to
consider this seriously I would be more
comfortable with deciding whether or not
to do it after we know whether or not it
works so write the code first test if
you can prove that it's harmless we can
have the conversation about whether it's
a good idea okay this is actually very
good input because we have a
coordination meeting this week and we
can actually discuss investing the time
to do the code base to provide a basis
to make the move but Rob you are an
author of validation code and you have a
time budget for work in this space and
it's pretty small so are you saying you
will implement I don't recall having
said that very not okay I'm
thank you thank you very much um do I
actually have to formally stand on one
leg inside requesting adoption mommy as
with everyone else who's done this today
[Music]
[Applause]
because