I know well yeah it does everything
except load my presentations so I come
on this you know I'll go ahead and run
from here but this doesn't get me if I
go to the agenda and I say fine
you know I can this is my agenda this is
my Charter this is a map
okay except that powerful I'm going to
run that video actually okay
so I actually want to run it as all
importance oh you need I need you run it
as nobody's dinged me about submitting
my slides as PDFs PowerPoint is just
fine yeah well you have to do yeah I'll
do this okay thank you that doesn't work
on my computer
oh well yeah I'll get there but I'll
show my dentist okay so it's 903 okay so
it's 903 you're looking at the agenda
that we have posted today Ron and I have
a couple of questions we need to deal
with and then we'll move directly into
this thing but is there any bashing that
people want to do to the agenda do I
need to change the agenda in any way
seeing none
okay
so two questions one between I ATF's 101
and 102 and then I atf 102 and 103 we
put out a question every week or roughly
every every week saying let's take a
look at a draft and comment on it our
perception is that that work has worked
reasonably well that people have looked
at the drafts they've found the load
acceptable and we've gotten comments on
a variety of drafts and in at least one
case we discovered that their working
group wanted to adopt a draft and we
hadn't figured that out and so that
became clear and we adopted a draft but
I'd like your opinion because I I've
just gotten kind of a few comments here
and there as a working group what do you
think about that process is that working
for you is that helpful is that
something you want to do raise your hand
if yes okay I see a lot of yes raise
your hand if No okay we'll continue
doing it
okay second thing I'm gonna turn over
you okay and we have a draft PD Hosts
that has been kind of flailing looking
for working group and adoption or not I
have two questions about that draft
first raise your hand
if you are familiar with Fred temple ins
PD host draft okay of the people who are
familiar with it how many think that it
should be a working group item one how
many think it should not be a working
group item one two three four five
okay would you like to make your
consensus call Warren okay oh we're not
working walking to the mic are you
working to the night no okay okay so
what I think we have an answer yes there
was one person do you want to speak in
defense uh no okay
so we can move into the agenda okay cool
and with that we're gonna switch to the
other laptop Shelley shingly so good
morning this is about the China
educational research Network ipv6-only
practice including backhoe servers cries
and ipv4 as a service okay then that's
the outline of my plantation so actually
we have a tree or backbones China
education the research network
why is caught sir net it started in 1994
and I it's ipv4 currently we have 38
hops and about more than 2,000 the
universities and another project has
started in the year 204 which is called
Serna to actually the interests is
seeing is here it is ipv6 only studying
from to all four and the currently there
are 25 hops and about 1,000 the
university's connected so you can see
they're separate backbones
and the highway starts ernet to design
then actually there several questions we
asked ourselves the first should we
start using do stack our ipv6 only and
the decision is ipv6 only in 204 I will
give you reasons later and also we have
some kind of promotion strategy
basically it's high performance in there
free another another thing is the
security because ipv4 their nets and we
sought the ipv6 because there is no net
six six then properly we can restart the
end-to-end security and that's the thing
we caught salsa address validation
architecture and we work in IETF let her
into the savvy working groups that's for
the first hops and then we talked about
we sought the transition and actually
because that's the ipv6 only backbone so
we thought we can do things update so
ipv4 over ipv6 at that time also we
thought probably before in a v6 should
talk directly through some kind of
translator then that actually we working
I if behave software and this group we
six ops so the promotion strategy and
the plan is for performance for CERN at
its ipv4 and it is because there 2000
the universities connected in congested
however Serna to its ipv6 only and its
light loaded at least from the beginning
so high performance for ipv6 and other
things actually even we are academic
network but we do not have operation
fees from the government at the
university professors in the students
pay the connection fee so that's some
kind of sharing model so
ipv4 is not free Anderson I to ipv6
Tinley it is free so actually was the
promotion slogan we told to our members
is if you want use free and high
performance network then please use ipv6
so that's the way we promote from the
beginning and tell you the truth it's
quite a success for because about half
on ok the ipv6 to ipv4 traffic ratio is
50% is all like however in reality we
sought can we turn off sir net ipv4 for
a single day and the see if the users
still satisfied with our network and
service no so the users need to
communicate with the ipv4 internet even
the network is somehow congested and the
not free so that's why we move in this
direction and the solar sings that's a
summary for security as Sabah and the
Saudis asada
are cease related in in the savvy
working group mostly savvy working group
and ok for sir net some tempers networks
actually we actually deploy savvy
technology so make the sauce trace
possible and the most secure so that's C
and the for transition actually that's a
brief history starting from 1994 that's
ipv4 sir net and the in the year 1998
actually we start to connect to six pool
and uh that's ipv6 over ipv4 the reason
we realize we need to work on IP v6 is
in China email in China they are 320
million students definitely we cannot
get enough ipv4 just from a beanie
and they in the year 2000 we tried you
stack which is called Natural Science
Foundation Network and the later as I
mentioned earlier in 200 we start
ipv6-only
signature then we thought we can do
innovation
so as ipv4 over ipv6 because as ipv6
only backbone that's turning to the ITF
software working group and the later we
work in the behaved working group that's
translation
Staley's translation and we call avi
because in Roman replantation IV means 4
v i mean six so i by actually means four
and the six can talk and the later we
realize there is some application embed
ipv4 literals and some applications ipv4
only so we saw two probably can do
double translations so that's the boy
that we call that and because it's
something for 64 issues and by that time
actually behaved working group clothes
that he cleared of victory so we move
back to the software and then later we
realize actually double translation and
they in cabaret she is something quite
similar so that's into the outcome after
RFC SMAP t and map so that's the story
for our experience so those other
related RFC's and the for single
translation in the ipv4 as a service
actually color mark the blue are the
RFC's actually we deployed in the siRNA
to backbone so that's basically the same
so currently that's the situation we
have two backbones cern at ipv4 and the
siRNA to ipv6 actually we have multiple
stylus translators deployed between cern
at ipv4 and ipv6
the reason we can do multiple
because that's one-to-one translation
that stateless so no matter was
trafficking one direction can go back to
the other address family in another year
translator because it's tailless just
like in a BGP lo the balancing states
and then actually we have ipv6 only
servers distributed in different
universities who connected to Sena to
also their ipv6 only clients are ipv4 as
a service clients distributed in
different universities wire second
translators so the the first translator
or the core translator are the same
Staley's one-to-one mapping between
before and the v6 and the depending on
the the hosts are and the systems either
as a single translation or double
translation or even some kind of
encapsulation or not in this case no
interpretation just the translation so
there that's the same and okay again
talk a little bit of backbone because so
near to is a ipv6 only backbone so
certain Aitu has its own address blocks
lat / 32 and the some converts networks
have their own provider independent ipv6
address block so BGP connected to those
universities and if inside the / 32 sir
netted then that's static route and the
link speed is 2.5 g Kenji and 100 G IDPs
OSPF purchaser and the BGP that's IBT
PAE BGP whatever and then another thing
I'd like to mention is multicast
we run SSM in the sauna - backbone and
actually the restriction is the user
cannot use their own / 48 as the SSL
sauce but instead we assign a special
as the sausages of SSM that's a better
security control another thing is the
unicast actually the routing accepted
link change of those kinds of his static
however multicast it's depending on the
join the situation as install that route
are not install and that make security
and the scalability or whatever
performance is some kind of disaster
so actually because as SSM so it's
predefined so we have static join for
the groups so the whole sir net to back
boom ipv6 SS is static not a dynamic for
multicast so that's the same and further
actually there the truthful Serna to
ipv6 only backbone the routing and we
are thinking we should try SR v6 but not
yet we're looking for that and the
translation as I mentioned a stainless
translation and the encapsulation and
the SSL so that those kinda C and some
kind of sauce address validation beyond
the first half so that Sava and because
there are multiple prefix so we try to
define some kind of controller to
control the prefix so make some kind of
Sdn drive and for the first hub or for
the end users as DLC p ra and sorry so
that's basically the structure in the
backbone and the ipv6 only servers so
actually we deploy ipv6 only servers
with the ipv6 address is based on RFC 60
50 - so the ipv4 address directly
embedded into ipv6 address so if the the
user connected to this server using ipv6
that's connected directly if
that bitch so ipv4 actually that the
user sees the ipv4 address but actually
is translate to that ipv6 and because
it's stainless so actually we is more
people translators can be used to do
load balancing of those can see and so
currently we have four 10g translators
as all can cast it but the performance
still relatively ok ok and the ipv6 only
clients that's the interesting say ok
for the partial function ok that means
if your application is ipv6 and no ipv4
letters embedded into that then actually
support a lot of operating systems and
the last th CPV ok ok I repeat again for
the clients there are two kinds of
clients wine clients can support the
dhcpv6 stateful except Android most of
the operating system can do that another
is the cannot support IP dhcpv6 that's
mainly Android in Windows XP for example
so so those two things and we have two
SSIDs
or Wireless why is for is the pv6 state
for another is in C just are a switch
the rbass so that's the ipv6 on it
that's the one dear
he mentioned to look at the problem
another direction is ok if for example
the iOS and Android with 464xlat they're
actually even their ipv4 later O's
embedded our IP then still you can use
that so this we call the full function
support of the ipv6 and the partial
function
supporter is okay if the webpage which
yes no problem because the s-64 where
you can access those kind of information
however if ipv4 later horse embedded UI
are still you cannot be a fail they seem
either safe and by doing before you move
on okay I'm guessing the Jordy has this
question in his mind he's asked a number
of times when we talk about ipv6 only
what do we mean do you mean here that
you're only giving the client an ipv6
address it doesn't there is no idea
before there at all isn't that the
definition you know yes so Jordy do you
have more any question there my my point
is that is not that simple as that when
when you say a network is ipv6 only if
there is some ipv4 function even if he's
at the end of the upstreams let's say
you are translating so that network is
not ipv6 only my my my my belief is that
we need to start speaking about when we
say ipv6 only with specific part of the
network we are talking about
it's the lands it's the access is the
core it's the app streams I think that's
the only way to really have a clear
picture for everyone that that's that's
the thing I agree okay actually here I
mention I think v6 at least ipv6 only
subnet it says answer your question
right so ipv6 only subnet okay actually
a little bit more complicated
that's to the subnet side and the truth
application said actually there are two
cases for example iOS as single
translation so to the application socket
is still ipv6 only however for enjoyed
that the probably four six four X later
actually to the socket function that's
use that however the sub
thank you and analysis for legacy yes
one question Bob hinden so over in
six-man we're working on this ipv6 only
flag things though Ras can the
administrator can tell can use that to
tell all the hosts only use v6 is this
something that's useful to you have you
looked at this
so in six-man there's a draft about
having the administrator inform all the
hosts to only use v6 did not turn off
the four is this something that would be
useful to you yes yes okay well please
come to six-man and say that okay thank
you okay like okay four six four X
ladies deployed in the operating systems
if for the legacy applications are owed
OS which is ipv4 only then actually we
deploy a translator in the same second
translator so that subnet is use that
however the upper stream so that's
another se and friendly speaking
actually at our campus networks we have
two SSIDs why is IP V still only subnet
another is you stack subnet however the
upper stream Arkham's ipv6 only okay
another thing actually type II so
actually this is also ipv4 as a service
so the upper stream is ipv6 only but the
subnet is you stack and then the same
actually this friday is for high
performance computing ipv4 as a service
and actually you may know there are some
top super computers located being russia
city like jump supremacy in china middle
of China China however some university
for example my University
the bio research center use that
computational facility and that the data
is about like one tea per day or those
kind of see so actually we use double
translation to provide this kind of
service the reason for that is actually
in this case the ipv4 address is private
address not the public yes so that means
404 to build a VPN so that's situation
and the the consideration for this is
and the network can be fine-tuned using
ipv6 prefix so that those ipv4 the
physics prophets can be put into a
higher priority through traffic
engineering so more flexible in the
controllable than ipv4 PDP and the more
cost effective than MPLS and then and
there were network operation amendments
very simple and to end address
transparency no in calculation
decapitation is required a for example
if the network operator try to take the
traffic and reducing if it's in
calculation eternally then the first IP
address you'll see is the eternal
address not end-user yes however for
double translation the ipv6 address in
bad before
so you'll see different end user has
different addresses and the no need to
activate application at this stage so
the user still use
ipv4 as the application and one thing
quite interesting for us is the
different charging model can be applied
why are you friend i pv 6 previous so
because i mentioned earlier they you
professors sharing I mean paid the fees
for using the internet however for this
what actually they can have unlimited
usage and that also make the tempers
network administrator life is much
easier so there are some interesting
discussion since that's our observe
the filly for ipv4 as a service either
use inhabitable Asia double translation
and the way play we prefer the bow
translation because the turbo
translation can reduce to single
translation and eventually as ipv6 only
however in Kappa later you need to keep
two points and also the traffic
engineering as I mentioned I have a
thicker meter to show that and a second
the staleys are stateful because
stainless can restart entry and address
transparency and there's much more
easier for scalability as skill so if
possible try stainless and the RFC 1650
to address all other mapping abuse and
the way belief there the IDC map you
know those kind see we believe we should
make the the why the people take a look
at the wire know what's the IP before
literacy bed is so make it as
transparent as possible and the same
crate ipv6 prefix for the sauce in the
destination or befriend ipv6 address in
RFC 1652 actually it says you should use
you should use the same prefix and
however that can retail okay actually
same prefix can result in the optimal
route him however if you have two
administrative domains then probably the
only choice use different of prefix and
finally for the clients here CP v6r
snack actually we like dhcpv6
unfortunately enjoy the cannot support
us so we have not no choice we need to
support slack so there are some reasons
right because this is quite interesting
from I can
the ipv6 address protector and the GPD
and me you can see the high GDP our
demand countries
ipv6 is quite good however for the last
about put our developing countries there
is no ipv6 so probably the ipv4 exists
for details on many details and if we
want eventually get an ipv6 only then we
need to deploy translator in some place
of the Internet to keep a single engine
and well this is actually I said in the
wire the operator can take look at the
ipv6 address without a declaration to do
a CR or traffic control rate limiting
however if that's turning in technology
you can not do that directly using the
existing - so you have to do the
calculation and they make sure the
traffic otherwise you give me - all the
traffic in that provided by that Turner
point also the end window just transpose
I mentioned so on the wire we know
across the ipv4 address embedded that we
can do a better and that's the optimal
routing so if it's the same prefix then
no matter the ipv4 is used in ipv6 or I
translate it in ipv6 are in original no
problem
the longer is the prefix match to
automatically redirect your traffic into
the right place however if different
projects then you need to do whatever
here being all those kind of seeds and
though I could certainly support as I
mentioned the full function so for for
iOS 9.2 and above in the Mac OS 10 point
above in the 464xlat Android actually
that's quite quite good like originally
for six for explained
supported the LTE interface but
currently about 6.0 the W dentists
support soils very good and now I heard
the Windows 10 can support however the
Home Edition we try to have not but
eventually that you are supported that's
a very good news however one thing is if
you want sled you have to be very
careful because Windows 7 cannot support
our DSS that's the problem I don't know
Microsoft can have upgrades attack
attached that will be great so finally
because our theory is IP pics only with
single translation if you can ipv4 as a
service with double translation
information if you should and the do
step and if you must and the way to ipv6
only as for as a service ipv6 only with
single translation and they eventually
ipv6 only so thank you very much any
questions hi there my name is Natalie I
noticed you are using an interesting
prefix for your network its 2001 da8 i
think it's very close to the
documentation prefix which is 2001 DB 8
actually that's the real sir net to
prefix yes also surprise exactly did you
ever have any issues with that oh okay
okay fine maybe some mistake they
thought so now to actually we're using
document oh yes
okay now yes maybe lorenzo quiddity i
wanted to ask you what what mechanism
used to discover the nat64 prefix in the
host as you mentioned RFC 70 fixed fee
and also you mentioned this table in 60
52 which has got different
clanks and suffixes but I know that the
70/50 implementation in Android only
sports 96's yeah so in that case we so
used our size 26 do you see any reason
not to use slash 96
okay actually that's that's a very good
question we actually prefer some kind of
Spanish translation so if we want to use
just representation defined in like map
t then actually we can not use the slash
36 in that case actually the compromise
is the salsa yes that's the map t format
however it's the nature of gasses laughs
so okay so right now you can't do right
now you can only do 96 but you would
like to do something different
sure definitely funky that will be great
well actually the reason I ask is the
six men we're talking about deprecating
everything else so these are practice
then we use different route unless the
trade off I see I cannot see you why not
why not use other prefix lens rather
than 96 - because that says 1750 then
there's a draft in six-man later a
little later this week we're presenting
the reason for not supporting it is that
it would make the option 50% bigger in
the RA there's no space for prefix
length if you want it to fit in 16 bytes
and so maybe you want to might want to
comment on that because we're not aware
of any implementation that supports it
actually I think the iOS implementation
does support it did you did you did you
verify that I OS supports non / 96 yeah
it does no it does not
that's not what David told me he wrote
it but clearly
yes all right thank you well not
shingling let me comment on that when
you started building ivi which was 2008
something like that your argument for
the way you structured the address was
that you wanted to straddle the ipv4
address across bit 64 so that you could
use ipv6 routing to take traffic to
different places and have multiple hosts
in a given place but but basically it
became a routing game are you still
doing that in ivi yeah yes so you are
not using a 96 you are using a yeah 40
years 48 yeah basically the exam bar
gave me still using 40 not changed okay
those 46 the nice is slash 24 ipv4
subnetting equivalent to a / 60 for some
reason yeah yeah so an additional
comment there then Lorenzo is that they
are using it in a way that they use
routing within the siRNA to network
based on parts of the ipv4 address
action our pin is we at some stage into
ipv6 and a turn-off okay okay so thank
you very much
I don't see anybody else at the mic so
I'm assuming we're done okay
Jordi
hang on a second mortgage come so okay
so the the first document I am
presenting today is the nat64 4 6 4 X
lab deployment guidelines the the region
of this document was a discussion that
we had in the in the ATF mailing list
about setting up the network which not
64 only and then while I was saying
there are applications that
unfortunately still use literals or all
sockets and that means that that that
will not work for for everyone and then
I think it was Christine and Emma was
suggesting the mistake with it basically
was using dns64
and and then I started to work in a
document which deployment guidelines for
4 6 4x lat
explaining what are the consequences if
we don't use dns64
and then there was a suggestion from the
working group regarding that document to
instead of working in just the 4 6 4x
lat
working in a general deployment
guidelines for any
nat64 usage so that's that's what we
have at the document today across the
different versions of the document
I got sometimes questions like if the
document is just talking about NASA 64
as a preferred transition mechanism that
that's not the thing what I am NOT
suggesting in the document is
this is the way to go what I am saying
is if you already decided to go to not
64 then this is the way you can deploy
it not not just to discussion that's
another question I got frequently is not
just a discussion about God are the
things that dns64 breaks with the
intersect it's one of the important
things but it's not the only one
okay so the starting point for the
document is there are three main issues
which deploying necessity for one of one
of those is if you are using the
unassisted for it may break the
intersect the recent work from Jen that
was talking about 1.7% I believe that
was about two years ago I guess that
will increase if the penetration of the
deployment of Gianna SEC were gross
obviously the other thing is the using
just nat64
there are applications that use literals
or api's that of course they are not
going to work on that situation and of
course if you happen at work with just
not 64 and you have still all devices or
applications that use IP before only
they will not work so that's that's
meaning that in some scenarios
you cannot just survive with nat64 alone
right when the DNS system for document
was published there were a few scenarios
work it out in that document and from
the perspective of an operator today I
believe there are much more scenarios
and I have done a classification of
those scenarios in a scenarios that are
known to work and those that will work
only in a special circumstances which
are still valid but not the generic case
so for the scenarios not to work there
are
for possible scenarios or super
scenarios where you have an internal or
outsourced nat64 dns64 combination okay
so that's that's the first set of a
scenarios then there are three
additional scenarios where you are using
for six Forex lat and either you have an
internal or obtuseness sista for dns64
combination and then two more possible
super scenarios where you have four six
Forex lat but in this case without using
DNS 64 and again you have the necessity
for functionality inside the network or
outside the network known to work in a
special circumstances there is when a
scenario which is not 64 without dns64
another scenario which is dns64 in the
ipv6 host which is something that more
and more operating systems are already
including so it's it's something that
maybe today is not the optimal situation
but it may change in the future and then
service provider with the NAT 64 and the
dns64 is in the remote only network it
seems that this this scenario don't
makes too much sense because if you have
at the NS 64 in the remote network they
logic thing is to have actually those
remote that remote network is already a
pv6 right but it may happen I am trying
to do a very quick comparison about
these twelve scenarios at the end we
come to 12,000 areas and this
compression is based in four specific
questions the first one is are the hosts
in that network validating the intersect
the second one is are the hosts using
literal or api's the third one is there
are any ipv4 on the hosts and the last
one is any chance the user can change
the DNS I call this foreign dns because
that may break some
things that the operator is considering
so for example if the operator is
providing a dns64 but the user is
changing the DNS then of course the DNS
system for function is not working so I
am writing each of these items depending
if they are good or bad in each of the
possible scenarios and then I come to
this to this table right
I have additional sections looking at
them very quickly there is a section
regarding the DNS SEC considerations and
possible approaches discussing one of
the possibilities is not using a dns64
the other one is the dns evaluator aware
of dns64 estoppel editors silat with DNS
proxy and validator ACL of clients
mapping out ipv4 addresses and then
considerations regarding dns reverse
mapping then the usage of forces for X
let which or without the end of 64
explaining what are the differences of
one case and the other a manual
configuration of pouring the DNS again
is when the user is able to change the
DNS configuration so that means that the
DNS functionality is not under the
control of the operator anymore
DNS privacy because that's another thing
that get broken when you are using DNS
64 together with privacy you are not
controlling using the DNS system for
probably a split DNS it's another
possible case where the dns64 may be not
working comparison between using a
well-known prefix or a specific network
prefix considerations regarding the item
for literals and all api's ipv4 only
host and applications and considerations
regarding the salaat translation then I
am doing a summary of all the
considerations and explaining also that
the document is not just talking about
operator networks because in most of the
cases all the
the durations will be the same if you
are an enterprise headquarter you are
trying to use nat64 in that network so
basically it makes no difference and
then it was I think it was suggested by
my fret to include an example of
broadband deployment which forces Forex
lat and also seal at implementation and
I'm not really sure that that will be
possible but there was also suggesting a
suggestion to include some benchmarking
and I think that was that was it so
questions because one of the problems I
I am having is that since probably two
months or so I am NOT getting inputs for
the document so even if this document
was adopted as a working group item is
still useful is somebody interested in
contributing or saying something I don't
know Jenn Jenn :
I feel a bit guilty because I promised
you to read this when I was a monorail
and I actually finally did and I my
feeling is it's probably my simplify the
document slightly because I found that
it might add my impression that in many
cases you might actually just combine a
number of scenarios in one scenario for
example saying you have not six four you
have dinner six four and it really
doesn't matter where dns64 is located
because I think currently it's a few
different scenarios which makes the
document probably way too long because I
actually was struggling finish and
originate because I found too many
similar scenarios and you need to sit
down what's the difference between them
actually so it would be my suggestion to
scientific to see if you can slightly
simplified also margin from NICTA said
just recently did more measurements on
dns64 and ipv6 similar to what i did a
couple of years ago and percent they
look quite similar I can send you link
but it's not in
unfortunately the same I need to use
Google Translate sorry I said consumer
format again as I said my suggestion
would be to review how you make it more
readable at the beginning I was used I
was having lesser scenarios and actually
I got the input that I should describe
more more of them there the reality is
that I agree there are some scenarios
which are very similar but this is not
actually making the document longer
because if you look at the length of
that part is because the pictures so
it's not like you need to read a lot of
more things is because each picture they
have four page okay so I don't think
that's increasing the complexity of the
document but I thing is providing
clarity if you see a picture it's very
easy you don't need to read the text
because the text is basically not saying
anything different but you have been one
case for example four scenarios and
looking at the picture you get the idea
about all of them and then the text says
all these four are the same okay
probably yeah because I got an
impression that I'm reading a lot of
similar text saying it's exactly the
same scenario above and then another
couple of section of text so again it
might be just me being like I can't take
a look again and try to squeeze a little
bit the text but for clarity I think it
was that way and that goes the
suggestion I got before so so I agree
we'll have different views and some
people will say it's too long and some
others will say is too short please
terrify it and some people were
suggesting even additional scenarios
which I don't think we need we need them
right so general let me ask your
question you were on the hook to do a
review of the document are you still
gonna do that thank you thank you so
Warren Kumari summary my comment is only
slightly related to this but I didn't
think of it earlier so I wanted to
announce it now so Stuart Cheshire has a
document which adds the ipv4 only darpa
name to a registry
you know and you're talking about EMS
things florists I figured I should
mention it now yeah so the did the ipv4
only dot ARPA name was never actually
added to the special use domain names
registry and so this is more admin stuff
but anyway he's got a document that does
that it's kind of related to v6 ups I've
agreed to ad sponsor it because DNS up
said there looks like admin stuff not
interested so I will see see the list
when I actually start that if people can
review it by using no P no comments you
comment it I think I commented on that
and I have I believe I have I mention in
the in my document about that so in fact
in my IANA considerations in this
document I am saying if this is not done
we need to do an errata and and so on so
I have I have to split it text for that
thank you okay any other comments so it
sounds like we're really not ready to
close up on this documents until you get
Jen to review and you know whatever
comes out of that so what I'll do is in
in our list of documents going forward
then I'll ask for people to comment on
the document so it's again your review
will be very helpful and this fight that
there are some some of labor room so if
people believe it's interesting we sit
down together to speak about this
document I am happy to to try to set up
some time for that may be an option
right okay so now surely you're also yes
okay so what what happened here is this
document is started as two different
documents the older one is is the sunset
ipv6 document unfortunately there were
very very few comments on that document
and then sunset is sleeping so so there
is nothing to do that and
and Cameron from D Mobile was sending
another document and I think it was
somehow fretful that fred was suggesting
to merge Cameron document with the
previous document I have presented and
my comment was no it don't make sense I
mean those two documents don't work
together but then I realized that the
ideal thing will be to match these two
documents and I talked it to Cameron and
he agreed so we drafted a document which
basically saying hey dns64 is while you
deploy it for six for ex-lap is quite
the deploy yet we have also support for
dns64 in happy eyeballs we have also not
sixty-four widely deploy it especially
in cellular networks there are million
of costs using those mekinese and what
happens is that horse validating dns act
may fail the same command I I did before
it's true that most of the server
networks the the smartphones are not
validating I think they have functions
that can be call it by applications to
validate or that can happen in the
future but today is not used but what
happens when you are doing tethering and
there are horse behinds that may be
validating so it's still a problem so
the other thing the other consideration
is a big cost of the transition is on
the back of the espys okay because at
the end the ISPs are the ones that need
to deploy these transition features and
need to solve the problems if the NSTIC
is broken or whatever and at the end
that means the users are paying somehow
for it because of course the the ISPs
will carry the cost to the end-users so
why not try to find a way for content or
application providers to carry at least
part of the cost okay the thing is if
they have the technical of
to do the intersect they should have as
well the technical ability to do ipv6 so
that will solve the problem clearly if
we have ipv6 in every DNS SEC horse we
don't have dns64 breaking anymore that
functionality right so the thing we are
trying is to find a way to push the
application or service or content
providers to to deploy ipv6 if they are
deploying the intersect that's the first
thing and then indirectly to assume part
of the transition cost as well and find
a way to get them clear signals that
this should be provided they should
really make an effort on this that's
that's the thing so the goals of the
document is let's make sure that the NSF
infrastructure is ready which ABB six so
dns64 is not any longer a problem even
just for one point seven percent of the
cases one point seven percent of the
cases in a he'll desk of a nice piece is
still a lot obviously so so we need to
try to sort out that make sure there is
a plan for the rest of the DNS
infrastructure to be as well
ipv6 ready okay so one site is the NSA
but not only let's let's try to figure
out how to work that
so what we want to men which ipv6 ready
is that ipv6 is accessible that there
are quite a rare resource records that
pm-2 is not broken and so on so that
that's that's easy so we are trying to
define a time line to make this happen
and the time line is root until this and
we know that most of them are already
done roots are done already TLDs I think
99 per second of the CCT all these are
done but there are still some GT all
these that are not done
despite the I can contract man
days for that so that's interesting
there is a contact that says you should
do it be six but it's not being enforced
so we are asking them to be ready with
JP be six in six months
the same for DNS SEC infrastructure and
then they name servers in twelve months
another resource records in eighteen
months and then hub Ayana RIKEN or what
I'm doing at validation and forcing
somehow suspension to those registers
that are not doing that it's this an
auto P I don't know but clearly there is
a contract which I can that is not big
follow it and yes we are ITF we are
responsible of the numbers so somehow we
are indirectly responsible that this is
happening or not right and there is
clearly some kind of infrastructure or
liaison or whatever which icon that we
should work together so maybe the
document is not the last war on these
clearly and maybe is not the only way to
go for this but we should do something
and and that's I think that's the last
is life yeah that's that's that's the
thing so throw tomatoes so whatever I
know Jen so let me be clear on this
you're asking I can to essentially take
a regulatory position well if you have
something in a contract and you are not
enforcing it why are you happy doing a
gun front so Jordi its yep dan you work
I spent some time before when I was in
more of an ipv6 advocacy role and I was
very excited when that contract that
you're referring to it's the registry
agreement but the detail is that only
applied to the new gTLDs it did not
apply to any of the country code TLDs
etc so I think and most of all of the
new gTLDs are ipv6 because they had to
be in in order to be launched
the I can process so that was so
regarding that the contract point it is
affecting all the ones it can affect so
there's all the other domains the CC
heal these the other pieces that were
not part of that in various ways
although Warren may be able to correct
me if he has no okay alright looking at
him okay
I know I know in fact is not affecting
CPLDs but luckily cctlds there are only
three or four that are not still doing
so that's the mean of of of the problems
so yeah okay anyway I don't know that
chasing that's gonna do too much my my
larger question though was or two one
was have you brought this at all to the
DNS op working group I I think I
forwarded a copy or somebody copied and
I didn't copied because I saw somebody
already posted there okay I didn't get
any inputs I well I would encourage you
to do that
I will admit I haven't been following as
much here but I have been over there and
I think that would be useful to provide
that input to but the other part when
you ask about DNS SEC and saying that
you know so I agree with the goal right
yeah but I think from an implementation
point of view
I'm not going to necessarily sign any
quad-a records if I don't have them if
my web server is only accessible over v4
then which is what the dns64 needs right
to get to me so of course we are not
asking for that if you don't have
transit which you should not have
whatever records that's clear yeah but
then how do you put I mean in what
you're really saying in this is that
everybody should get their websites and
everything else to work over ipv6 which
yes I completely agree with that but I
don't know that necessarily we can I
don't know I don't see it necessarily
being something we can necessarily
create right there and Mark Andrews is
in the queue yeah yeah at the Tod level
I agree everything's pretty much right
the problem is the the assumption you're
making assumption here that if you can
do dns sick you can also do ipv6 and
once you
down a little beneath the tail days to
the actual enterprise that isn't true it
is not true to a large extent to do DNA
sick all you have to do is to deploy a
name server which supports it and
register your keys in the pair exam that
is something you can we've been able to
do for 20 years nearly now it doesn't
read there's no gating on ISPs doing
giving you delivering your ipv6 over
your over access network and anything
else like that so anything which
actually get which actually slows down
DNS SEC deployment by getting it on ipv6
being deployed is actually a bad idea
the DNS SEC which is why this craft this
as a recommendation you should do this
yeah it's it's all good motherhood stuff
but in practice it guess what happened
so mark so you are suggesting that we
just stick to a recommendation and
nothing else and don't work which I can
I wanna do try to fix it I don't see
there's a room I don't think I don't see
there actually is a problem of that
level because the only one the ones
which don't have ipv6 aren't
contractually required to have ipv6
either because there's there's a set of
T of these which have contracts and they
do actually do ipv6 does that make sense
yeah Paul Wilson here for maybe Nick
very recent discussions with ICANN
senior folks showed that though they are
very interested in this they are aware
that there's a lack of compliance in the
support that they're expecting for ipv6
functionality to be provided but one of
the things for instance that they're
after is that their registrar's should
simply provide
the interface that allows domain holders
who have ipv6 to to register that it
into the inter DNS so I think they're
they're looking at that functionality
that the question of the functionality
offered by the era they contracted
parties I'm not sure with the whether
there's consensus on whether the
contract is correct or not but they are
they're aware that they've got certain
contractual requirements that aren't
necessarily being them being met and
they're not maybe not monitoring as well
as they could and they were just they
are definitely interested in so it looks
like if ionized or icon is in this
direction we should work with the
liaison to try to define yeah so if we
think that the dimension of the maiden
Claes that the problem is a Dennis
operators do not really understand the
impact of having dinner check enabled
without the ability v6 then I agree we
need to educate them so probably so I
really like the first draft which was
just saying if you deploy it in a silk
you should think about the impact you
should be aware as that some people
might have issues accessing your record
so please consider an event ipv6 that's
the right thing to do however what your
draft is currently said is that your
suggestion to invent a magic wand which
will get ipv6 deployed global in 18
months and I just do not believe it's
feasible so basically what your
suggestion I could not see how it could
be implemented it's I just do not see
implementation details and I think you
basically suggested something which is
not feasible so I do not think we should
be enforcing this because there are
countries which do not have v6 at all
people who have sides there they just
could not have be six in that time frame
it just just totally unrealistic so I
suggest we stick with recommendations
and explanations of the impact and
that's it and as it's been said DNS ops
people need to be aware of this because
at last right meet Nvidia
working group had no idea about this
document whatsoever okay second Dan you
work it just one comment the mark led
onto it I think you are off on the idea
that somebody who has DNS expertise is
also if they have that technical
expertise then they could do ipv6
because to Mark's point you know
activating DNS SEC on a zone is really
just a matter of maybe uncommenting a
line in one of the config files or doing
something like that and so boom you do
that and it's on and now you're signing
all of your zones depending upon which
of the various different authoritative
service you're using so that's I mean a
very basic thing that you're done versus
trying to get ipv6 transit and ipv6
routing and everything else and
firewalls and all that configured so
it's a different technical set so I
would not make that assumption in there
too to Paul's plan I think there are
people within ICANN and in NSR C and
other folks who are out there working on
ipv6 issues who you would talk to I
don't know that Ayana has any role in
that type of thing with that but I can
would be the folks item yeah thank you
balint as far as hi anna goes there a
service function they do what they're
told
so that thought thought their job so
okay what I think I'm drawing out of
this and tell me if I've got this right
oh you're gonna need to change the draft
to make that beer recommendation as
opposed to the contractual thing we need
input from DNS ah either you need to
discuss it in DNS op review yeah I think
I think is trying to ask the Ennis ought
to read the document and provide inputs
probably after that it will be clear
that it should be just a recommendation
but I think we should still work with
the liaison which I can to see if they
have some suggestion about the document
about way to go and if they can do
something maybe I don't know I am just
thinking so
are there any other things that I should
be pulling out at this site those are
the two points that I'm pulling out at
them okay so I have one other question
during the discussion a few months ago
on Cameron's document there were several
people who said that they shot thought
his document should go to BC P so let me
ask the working group if those changes
are made in this document do you want to
take it to bc p question for the group
um if that's a direction you think it
should go would you please hum the one
he's just been talking about no um okay
thank you um so okay so now moving along
six one seven seven yeah
and I'm amazed you're an author on this
one as well yes okay so what we are
trying to do to address here is the
perception of many ISPs read the 677 as
something which is not very very clear
so I decided to speak with the outers of
that document and try to see they going
to get involved in this version and I
think we didn't get a response from
Thomas Martin and Jeff said I am NOT
interested at this stage and then leader
over said yes let's work on that because
she has the same perception okay so the
thing here is that we move it from RFC
three one seven seven two six one seven
seven and then we somehow tried to fix
the idea that as last 48 is good for for
everyone however when you read the
policies of different registries some of
them suggest to still use his last 48
some others suggest his last 56 in any
case it's clear in all of them that it's
an isp decision and we agree with that
but the people is still doing some
strange things and when we ask them
people I mean I speak when we ask them
they don't have a clear understanding
from from our point of view of what this
document is saying the actual 677 so
let's make make sure that we fix this
document especially to say a site needs
to help many subnets not just one and a
single as last 64 is never recommended
this is somehow already in the document
but we want to make it more clear okay
I was working for two years and is still
ongoing in a survey the last time I'd
look at the figures probably about six
months ago I had almost 1600 responses
from ISPs from all the wall 23% of the
ISPs mainly from more advanced countries
in terms of ipv6 deployment are using as
last 48 for residential customers 35%
are using as last 56 and and this is the
big problem there is 33 percent that are
using a single is last 64 for rental
customers okay and when we speak with
those they are somehow pointing to
energy 6 177 so that's that's the reason
we believe it's is broken you want to
say something now Barbara okay
so what we are trying to do in this
document is to update the
recommendations
stop them are exactly the same as we had
today in 677 the first one is a single
is last 128 is extremely discouraged it
there are not in ipv6 hard-coded
boundaries we use c IDR one-size-fit-all
is not necessary or appropriate but we
still need to ensure that insights get a
sufficiently big number of subnets a
single is last 64 is not a normal choice
there may be cases of course but is not
a normal choice neither should be a
small number of subnets and we don't go
to define what is a small ok we don't
want to enter into that discussion
because that will be endless inside
should always be able to take a
reasonable number of his last 60 force
for the rectal and planet usage and over
time range is specific in many years
probably decades ok so we are not
talking get the use of something for the
next four years get them something for
the next 20 years
ok there was we are following more or
less the existing structure for for the
for the 677 that we have today actually
our version is shorter because we
deleted some some of the sections but
there was one section that speak about
why is last 48 and what we are saying
here is per address cost considering the
charges from the resistors is not a
problem so that should not be a stop a
showstopper for an ISP to to to allocate
more addresses or more prefixes ComNet
control protocol needs super segment to
downstream routers so maybe as last 56
may be too short in those cases use of
ul is internally not matching the ISP
prefixes so they you
last 48 if you want to match that which
the preface that you get from the
upstreams is not going to work if
multiple links are present DNS is simple
with same traffic size from each link
instead of having different is business
different traffic sizes
business may need more than a single as
last 48 and the actual addressing
policies from the resistors already
allow it even in some cases they still
need to go for a justification but this
is something that Google need to fix at
the policy level and I am actually
considering submitting policy proposals
in all the resistors to fix that single
is last 64 per host interface is
something that was not considered when
this draft was was done this document
was done because it didn't existed so we
need to consider it now
and then as last 48 is not graceful in
many situations because one of the
reasons from moving from three one seven
seven two six one seven seven was people
saying is graceful and then I did those
numbers which spreadsheet to show that
is not wasteful if we have as last three
that contains that number of slash 48 if
we are really really really bad
deploying ipv6 and we have a fifty
percent utilization we have only the
half of course and then if we suppose we
are going to have 32 billion population
and that they average expectation for
every human is hundred years and let's
suppose that when everyone dies we don't
recover this last four days that get to
them we can give as last 40 is for the
next forty one thousand a hundred
thousand years if we go for four is less
48 we have only twelve thousand eight
hundred years and we still have eight
times that space so if we use all the
dressing space it means that we will
have at least for the next hundred
thousand years as last 48 okay you
to say something now yeah Julie that's a
curiously naive modeling of human
behavior and addresses are actually not
used by humans they're used by machines
so well I don't I it's hard to even
criticize the model on which the
assumptions in this slide are built on
because it's not well described but I
think it's I think it I think we can be
reasonably certain that that assumptions
that you have there are completely
meaningless we can use all this address
space in two three four decades maybe
without too much trouble so fifty
thousand years is maybe three four five
orders of magnitude off okay Ron Ron
Bonica speaking as an individual
contributor I think this slide may have
been more for humor than for actual
modeling even if he's off by four orders
of magnitude we're still okay he's still
okay that's the thing I mean I am NOT
trying to be accurate because of course
he's not just human so James you
expected us to chuckle obviously chief
Houston not chuckling part of the reason
why we had a problem with the 3177 or
whatever it was was that in looking at
the ratios we were using in deployment
and 50% utilization is a laughable joke
the whole idea of v6 was not to place
pressure on operators to achieve address
utilization densities which were
expensive the whole idea was to be
enough space that it really didn't
matter and the combination of using
enough dress space that it really
doesn't matter and projections of device
density meant that assigning a / 48 to
everything would give us less than a
decade if you happen to read the stuff
what I object to about this kind of
slide is joke mathematics it just
doesn't cut it and the case that they're
trying to make that slash 48 SAR fine
implicitly behind this
is completely and utterly false in my
mind I reject that as being
irresponsible if what we're trying to do
is to utilize the larger address space
in v6 not to repeat the phenomenal
pressures we placed on this industry to
strangle v4 beyond its reasonable
lifetime then what you're doing here
is oddly enough repeating that same
mistake and the least we can do is learn
from this so no it's not funny it's
actually misleading and wrong I'm sorry
it just doesn't cut it for me go ahead
Christian Itamar Jody I kind of agree
with what Jeff said and one thing you're
missing there is that the pressure is
not linked to the ratio that you are
using it's actually look a bit meek and
we explained that in RFC 4180 for and if
you do that you should actually go from
there
and if you go into the logarithmic
effect then it's very much closer to
just position than yours okay keep going
so the summary of our document is that
exact perfect choice it's still an
operation issue and we have a reference
to a very recent document from Wright
which has been quoted by operators from
all the regions which is riped 690 we
strongly discourage using a single as
last 48 we strongly suggest considering
as last 48 alternatively we reserve as
last 48 and assigned the first as last
56 that will avoid remembering the
remaining is last 48 can be a sign if
you need it later or use it for other
users if it is not needed encourage
alignment of cellular networks because
that's that's another thing we have in
silver networks we are providing just as
last 64 and we don't use the HCP and so
on and and the thing here is that the
the reason for that is because it's an
alternative to broadband networks right
cellular networks and more and more
alternative to to broadband and in some
cases there may be users that only have
cellular connectivity for their
broadband connectivity and today they
got only a single is less 64 so we we
want to make sure that that's also fixed
and that's it basically
so Barbara yeah
I disagree Geordi first of all I guess
on various levels
you mentioned the mobile networks which
are handing out the SAS 64 effectively
because there is no DHCP I a PD in those
networks and right now 64 is the best
they can do with the mechanisms they're
using yes it would be lovely if they
handed out more but I think that putting
out some strongly worded RFC that says
you know we really discourage slash 64
and sending it to them and it's like
tilting it will windmills you know there
are also operators who have our six Rd
deployments we're providing a slash 60
and telling us slash 56 by gully and
slash 48 again you're tilting at
windmills and it's kind of insulting I
mean we've got ipv6 you know if you
start putting more and more barriers
like this in front of ipv6 deployment
then you're actually going to in my
opinion decrease ipv6 deployments that
still need to happen in so much of the
world and I don't think you have made a
case for why this extent of address
space is really needed lorenzo clitty i
think i think this is a tussle and and
and the reason is that and the reason I
say that is that I disagree with
everything you said Barbara well pretty
much everything I agree that saying it's
like I agree that saying something super
wordid is not gonna help that much but i
think i think we have to say something
here i think we have to say here's what
you can't do when there's when you just
use a 64 and it's i think we have we
have guidance on this in in terms of our
ir policies but we also have to have
guidance to isp saying look our
protocols are designed for this and that
is a statement that the ITF is qualified
to make it has to make right I think we
wrote a bunch of stuff I don't know was
it 10 15 years ago these days and we
wrote a bunch of stuff about address
sizing and you know that was before ipv6
was deployed and now we have operational
experience and I think yes there are
operational reasons to assign a 60 to
assign a 64 but there are not good
things to follow in the future right
when those operational reasons disappear
like the fact that you can only do a 60
because if you're 6 Rd pools are given
size we should move towards 56 if you
have a native network there is no reason
why you can't do 56 and if you don't
know that as an isp you should now if
their operational reasons sure I mean
reality takes precedence over wish lists
but we have to say something here
because otherwise people might just
choose whatever everyone else is doing
and then we'll just fall into a minimum
common denominator trap and we shouldn't
do that thank you Eric lean I guess I
wanted to ask is it is it more
appropriate to have our er documents in
this context is this a night does this
need to be an IETF level document do we
need to have a re are in my opinion and
that's why we working on this we need to
have documents in in in in different
directions
do the are ers needed IETF document to
refer to yes it's good sometimes and I'd
like to let mark in to the queue
yeah two points a sticks ID there's
nothing stopping any 6id
operator from deploying slash 48 to
every one of their users it's only when
you start shoving the whole / 32 from
ipv4 into the address that you actually
become become size limited in the number
of prefixes and what we really need to
do is start trying to describe how to
not waste addresses be that the
instructions to enterprises on how to
actually allocate addresses so if your
enterprise and you actually just assign
a slash 64 on demand yep
you have 65,000 slash 60 forced to hand
out you don't need to have internal
structure when you heard her an
enterprise it might be nice that handing
out the dresses doesn't require doesn't
require internal structure it's that
sort of thing that ends up wasting
addresses we have routers they know how
to route things giving guidance the end
to the end sites on how to actually
deploy ipv6 in such a manner that you do
not waste addresses stop encoding things
into addresses which shouldn't be there
thank you Jeff Houston again look either
we're all commonly amnesiac and we just
simply forget everything or we endlessly
repeat these conversations so we can get
more and more expert at reciting our
positions
neither of these correspond to progress
there is nothing in 61 77 that said user
slash 60 for nothing it actually says
the opposite as you might recall what it
did say which is what you seem to be
contradicting here was that one size
fits all is wrong and the whole idea of
classful addressing as we learned in v4
was actually a hideous mistake and
deployments and operators have enough
nouse to figure out what they need to do
and trying to do one size fits all
create such gross an extraordinary
wastefulness of address space that even
the 128 s-- of these some bits of v6 get
wasted almost immediately we can hear
through this space in a year if we
really want to because we're endlessly
inventive I do not see anything in this
draft that justifies why we should be
doing abyss on 61 77 to me this seems
like a complete waste of time what we
said then is true now there is no
one-size-fits-all go pick what you need
to do by the way a slash 64 to insights
is kind of difficult for those insights
you really shouldn't go there or if you
do understand very clearly what you're
doing because it's not the best idea
beyond that go figure out what your
customers need and do the right thing by
them not as you're saying strongly
suggest going back to the exact same
problem that prompted 61 77 to come up
so you know I'll keep on saying this and
you'll keep on doing that throughout the
next five years and we'll all feel good
about it will we or can we get over this
stuff and actually move on to areas that
are productive because quite frankly
cycling around these conversations is
just a waste of everyone's time thank
you
learn zouk lady I do think we need
something that discourages a single / 64
because we have things like HomeNet that
say that you shouldn't do that and I
think we I think I think it's worth
writing a document that says look here's
what we learned and here's what we think
this should look like in the future I
don't you know maybe 61 77 says exactly
what we need to say for what it's worth
I mean Jeff is this just because you
don't you don't like 48 if that said 56
well you would you sort of be happier
because that's actually the de facto
size in our a our documents lorenzo
summer IRS uses less 56 some others keep
using his last 48 so it's not the
standard okay thank you Mike I'll try
and paraphrase my understanding of our
IR policy and I don't want to be
authoritative about it but the our IRS
heard very strongly in their policy fora
that one size didn't fit all and what
they allowed as far as I can see is v6
allocations based on what the operator
said they were doing and it's not a / 56
or a / 48 or anything else there is a
charging structure in a lot of the our
IRS we're forced some of them more space
means you pay more money but that's not
all
and quite frankly it's none of the ITX
business to intrude inside that area but
no one inside the our IRS as far as I
understand from policies perspective is
saying it's 56 57 58 or whatever that's
not the business anymore
we some of them kappa recommendations
this is not an RI armaiti the second
thing is sixty one seventy seven says
very clearly don't go down the / 64 path
and I really don't understand why we're
having a debate about that because as I
said you couldn't make it much clearer
if you actually read the taste so I
don't see where the problem is on that
side so you see this is basically
already stated in 61 77 people is not
reading that way - so just pushing back
on the last one and so going back to 33
14 from 2000
like we had this discussion and we
really recommended 3gpp to go its last
64 and it was like a big big battle to
get it pushed down there people say oh
that's like really wasteful and
everything I just don't want this to be
the open again at least for the cellular
I know like Lorenzo's gonna come back
here probably but everything that needs
to be said has been said in 79 34 okay
it says like what can you do it this
last 64 what you cannot do so I think
that work at least for the cellular side
is done like I don't want like anything
specific saying put in a bigger prefix
for a cellular network because this is
like really entrenched and we're really
happy that this happened that everybody
got us last 64 so you can do like
creative things like you know like four
six 4x lad or you can do things like you
know 64 share and things like that that
that came out because we did this at 64
so I just don't want to miss to be
revisited anytime soon from the jabber
room Brian Capron tur says RAC 61 77
says and this document still recommends
giving home signs significally more than
a singer slash 64 but does not recommend
that a vm site be given a slash 48
either hi Bob Hinton two points from the
discussion so certainly if we are not
prudent we will use up this address
space very quickly it's we know how to
do that so we do need to be you know
careful how what allocation policies are
and the other thing that I'd like to add
is that the intent behind this was not
to make the ISPs better it was to give
the N sites enough address space so they
could do whatever they needed to do so
there wouldn't be address scarcity like
we have with before and that's you know
thinking or at least my thinking was
that the ISPs have resources and can
manage it their space and they conduce
they can deal with complexity at that
level but the insides can't and if we
make it hard for the insights to get
enough
presses or having to renumber frequently
then we'll end up with that again
exactly Lorenza Khalil I you know I
think what if we said simply assigning a
single size 64 per site is not
recommended I mean I think pretty much
everyone agrees with that right and
that's clearly not being done everywhere
and the reasons are varied but I think
if we I think even ice bees would agree
with that aspirationally they would like
to assign that and I think it's
important to state that in a very simple
way as for cellular networks
I mean Suresh the that's actually a
great example of how what we said made a
difference and it's it's a shining
example I remember a major one of the
earliest adopters of ipv6 and the person
at that operator who was pushing my pv6
was I'm not gonna name any names here
was convinced that 64 per to the device
was super wasteful and was really stupid
and that operator discovered after
deployment that actually this thing that
they had assigned a 64 because the
stupid ITF had forced me to do that I
was like oh cool now I can do 4 6 4 X
lab and so so I think I think I think
there is value here and I to be honest I
do see I do see the point that we should
say if an LTE network is a an
alternative to to home networking then
it should assign a 56 or so or whatever
right that's the thing that's valuable
and and we shouldn't say like oh don't
assign is 64 right but and and you know
it's to the earlier point that date that
mobile networks don't support HPV 6 well
it's written in the standards right it's
not like it's not there in theory you
know maybe the gear doesn't support it
but it's there since release 10 so I
mean I think that that that's a good
statement to make you know if you want
to provide an alternative to to home
routing to to home if you're doing 5g
because like of you're like one
millisecond or air interface time woohoo
right then you should assign a 56 if
it's an alternative to home that ok I
think that's pretty reasonable thank you
kevin is a individual contributor I like
one of the things that Lorenzo said a
lot that we should have a recommendation
that says slash 64 or shorter is a
really bad idea there's also and yes it
may already be in the existing draft
yeah then there's a need to specify an
upper limit and an area where we give
operators free rein anything between the
upper and lower limit is just fine now
the question is what's that upper limit
the best thing we have to judge the
upper limit your analysis which was
clearly humorous but not serious and
I've also heard that if we use slash 48
we can run out in ten years that may be
true but supporting facts would be good
so maybe it would be a good idea for
like the two of you to sit in a room
together oh and do a serious analysis of
what number is too big yeah thank you so
Brian I don't know if you're ahead of me
or not but yield to you if you're before
me oh I'm sorry yes Brian Brian go ahead
Brian II there okay so just like going
back to what Lorenzo said so there is
some limitations in in cellular networks
okay so we've done quite a bit of study
on this on a fixed network if somebody
gets this last 64 and they decide they
need more at this pace they asked for
more address space and they can get a 48
or as 50 like 56 or 60 whatever they
want right but the way the cellular
networks are architected they get only
one prefix it can be a what Evelyn so if
ITF decides like hey everybody should
get a slash 30 do like fine right but
but once the session is established like
putting in a second prefix it's very
very difficult
so bunch of us worked on this thing
together I think like Ola worked on it
with me and youngy like few P
we worked on it so we figured out like
you know how to delegate a prefix with
the hole in it so that 6603 that came
out from like you know how do you take a
prefix take a whole lot of it so all I
get is 64 and then allocate the other
prefix on top of it so which is all
separate from saying like what length do
we want and but what I'm saying is like
this last 64 discussion back in like
2002 was like very painful okay already
people thought it was very wasteful back
at the time so whatever number we come
up with right now it's gonna be equally
painful to have that discussion so I'm
really happy that we have the 64 there
and we can try to push like further if
needed but I think 64 works well for
mobile networks like for mobiles and as
like Lorenzo said if it becomes like
more like a site that's behind a mobile
network then maybe we can come up with a
slightly more targeted recommendation
for other things in there but I don't
want this to be like a chain Drake idea
like tells 3gpp that every Mobile gets a
slash shorter than 64 okay so thanks
Geoff Huston I'm just going to remind
the IATA from this working group where
we are because 61 77 is a BCP now
underlying this is where does address
allocation policy happen in the internet
and a long time ago after a lot of
fights and some of you might remember PR
we kind of said to the our IRS will give
you architectural guidance but URI hours
of the address policy fighting room go
there and hash it out the ITF can
recommend that it can't enforce so 61 77
says very clearly the IETF recommends
that any policy on v6 address assignment
policy to end sites takes into
consideration the following points which
is an appropriate language for this
working group you can't say Oh URI eyes
have to do this or that it's beyond your
scope your arms aren't long enough you
can't reach that far point one it should
be easy for an insight to attain address
space to number multiple subnets ie a
block large
single / 64 and to support reasonable
growth projections over long-term
periods either a decade or more if that
doesn't say don't use 64 I don't know
what does
secondly the before yeah typically I'm
that's why I'm helping by reading it out
the default assignment size should take
into consideration the likelihood
insights we'll have need for multiple
subnets so my point is all of this is
stated already so I really don't
understand exactly why we're circling
around this again and again and the real
issue is the architectural guidance
might come from here but the feet on the
ground is actually inside a different
room a Bruin carpenter gain even if I
don't look like him it really says that
RAC 61 77 doesn't say that 60 says first
/et 42 small / 48 maybe too much
so poor so apart from making people read
6157 again what's you I think we we need
to bear in mind that 160 177 was written
v6 deployment at the Internet's to the
0.2% okay now it's two orders of
magnitude above that and I think we can
we can it's kind of like amazing to me
that 61 77 has a BCP cuz there's
basically no deployment right so it
wasn't a current practice it was a
future practice to CNBC piece you've
been like BFP or something so and to
your point Jeff I think that text is so
easily that people can read whatever
they want into it and I think while I
would agree with you that it says don't
do slash 64
I think there's benefit to saying don't
do slash 64 because if that's if that's
what everyone agrees it says then let's
write it in plain English right if we
already agree on it you don't do 64
unless you have some strong operational
reason then you know what's the problem
with that let's just write it in English
though let's not write it in sort of
weasel words a stronger warning is
needed not a stronger wording just a
clearer wording do you if you were that
strongly like yep 21 to 19 well I think
it I think it's
you should write yeah if you have a
legitimate operation reason right yeah
so if we said should not use a 64 right
how many people disagree with that I
didn't think this room would I don't
think the IRS would either because the
IRI has already say don't do this
so let's just write it and in plain
English and say look if we want to I I
think from my perspective having a clear
document as a win and I think if we want
to say look here's after like whatever
between 0.3 percent and 25 percent of v6
deployment here's what we learned and
here's what we want to recommend let's
do that thanks John linka I've been
listening to this that looks like we
just basically discussions that the few
section in the original RFC is not clear
enough should it just be a very short
document saying let's update this text
with zebb text and that section and we
are done
making it more clear and to wrong point
about providing upper limit I do not
think it's a problem we have now right
because I think practically most of the
real problem is that ISP is assigned
just slash 64 or even slash 128
I do not think we have problem with two
blocks assigned being too large so we
probably do not I am Not sure we need to
concentrate on discussion should it be
slash 48 or something else we need to
make sure we're not assigning too little
because it hurts if you assign too much
well you burn out your address space you
have to go to area our back and ask from
address space and pay more potentially
well it's your problem so my opinion
it's not real and at this point we have
to draw this conversation to a close and
bring it to a spirited discussion on the
mailing list yes please I will suggest
the people that that happen not read the
document make a deal between the
original six 177 and this one because
the difference are not that much so I
agree with Jen that it may be a shorter
document yes this document is shorter
than the original one so we actually
remove it parts of the original document
so okay let's take this to the list now
so we have one document left today and
find in the story you've been busy
I have six more okay so this this
document I think actually you suggested
doing a comparison of the transition
mechanism so GABA which is the main
author of the document said yes I take
it and ask it for volunteers so few of
us started contributing I know we have
short time so so I I did a very very
small presentation because the main goal
of this presentation is to to get input
from the working group okay so we need a
lot of work here and we don't expect
this document to be an easy one or
something that we are going to do in a
in a short time so basically what we're
trying to do with this document is there
are five basic transition mechanism that
we call like ipv4 as a service which are
four six four X Latvia's light like way
for over six months and mati there are a
few others like Lee's theory on ipv6 and
so on that we decided not to consider
because there is not that much
deployment as the previous ones so we
prefer to concentrate on de what we
believe are the five mine ones if
somebody disagreed please state hey
there are that many number of
deployments which other documents sorry
which other mechanism and maybe we will
consider that so the thing is if we try
to make a comparison between all of them
to make easier for an ISP to decide and
we already know from the beginning that
this this is not really an easy task and
at the end it will depend a lot on every
specific Network case so we have
different sections of the document again
the document is still work in progress
and we'll retire
of additional work but we have one
high-level architecture where we discuss
each of the transition mechanics
their trucks in the SP network and how
they are sharing that in four addresses
for for doing this mechanism okay so
summary of the document we have the
toilet analysis of their detector
architectural differences between the
different the five different IP for a
service mekinese based comparison of all
of them trade-offs among the efficiency
of poor numbers and stateless operation
support for servers operation support
and implementations including operating
systems cellular and broadband and
implementation Co sites we have also
typical deployment and traffic volume
there are some figures that that Cameron
from t-mobile provided to the mailing
list oh we compared it those stickers
which other similar makers and it looks
like like most of them are
coincidentally in that in that sharing
so we are basically describing the
deployment possibilities including the
server which for six Forex lat the load
sharing performance comparison this is
something that we want to do so this is
not still done but the idea is Gabbar
has some students that will be able to
do this performance comparison we still
need to define exactly how we are going
to do that because it's not an easy task
and that will be part of the document
and of course we'll have a security
considerations and and that's it they
thing here is asked to the working group
to contribute ask to the working group
what other aspects do you believe are
interesting to to be considered by the
document what do you think will be
useful Barbara yeah so something I think
would be useful is a number of these
technologies actually have
various options as to how they can be
set up you know maybe you have blocks of
ipv4 addresses associated with it maybe
you're using that you know there's all
these various things and so it would be
useful to understand what are the most
common configurations that are in use in
thumb yeah first of all thanks for
grasping the nettle and try a handle on
this stuff because it's a fairly
expensive task and it probably should
have been done some time ago I gotta
look through it and I've got a raft of
comments and the current version of
there which I'll post the list later on
but the main things I had some there's
been a spreadsheet that's been doing the
realms over the last few months and I
think Lee Howard and well based on your
work that does some kind of comparison
between these things based on kind of
yes/no is and you know are very easy to
look up and something is the plan to
kind of incorporate this stuff and you
know find some ASCII way of rendering
that that thing sorry is the plan is the
plan to incorporate that comparison
table so here's an easy and yeah yeah
okay good - the performance testing I I
mean we've talked about this one already
but I I've been kind of wracking my
brains about this as to whether it can
anything meaningful come out of this
that isn't just going to say this
implementation is faster than that
implementation you've got physical
versus virtuals you've got God knows how
many different variables on here to be
honest we still don't know we are still
thinking about how to do that and how to
put that in a document because we know
that there are person cons to every
possible option so yeah I am even myself
sure about how we be doing my gut feel
here is that unless you're comparing
different implementations a single
technology you know you can't come out
with anything meaningful right and
there's a you know the risk of well very
time consuming about inconclusive waste
of time there well the advantage is that
we have the students that are happy to
do that so yeah but I mean do they have
access to all of the different hardware
and software implementations that's
another month of ours
right unless they're very well resourced
I doubt it yeah thank you okay so now at
this point we have only a couple of
minutes left until the top of the hour
are there any further comments that
people want to make to jority on this
drought seeing none okay
the time is now 1054 I think by the time
we do anything it's gonna be 11 and 11
we're done so I'm gonna adjourn at this
point we're gonna come to thank you
[Music]