so good evening welcome thanks for
coming this is full of people I love it
please put your phones in silence
there are people with the phones on
really how unrespectful this respect
welcome to this talk the title is i/o
tea master chef cooking it run for
hockey my name is daya bilenda I am you
have my Twitter account there to make me
feel more important to feed my ego and
let me know that I have lots of
followers so that's me
this is chairman we still that's a name
and as I've said in the drone I propose
in the Robert Texas Ranger because
everything's great if it's called that
way and I am also the author of the book
hacking with runners in if you have you
brought it with you I am at the
delighted to sign them so I've been in
this event and a few more making look
important slide let's put something
strong if I say Isis and drones people
start going crazy really you have to
start strong the current event then you
concerned of the Pentagon the drones of
the Isis say and we see two guys these
are the drones not the ones that are
published in Huckabay but we see it
around here with tape full of and if you
were aiming for something to do
something bad it would be useful
actually another news item that I like
this was shot down great job you can say
that you go home and feel any of earn
your salary is that requiring a further
explanation
the Defense Ministry this came up
yesterday and the panel discussion a
large of the threats of drones in the
hands of foreign enemies and I'm ABC
drones a great threat made America wrong
look cute
the drone could have a midnight but
that's native kid I want to provide
context for this talk
the drones threat they are actually
flying computers IOT Internet of Things
on your above your head that's what we
used to call it but we're actually
talking about the small computers and
better system that's all specific
payment of hard our charges you can you
can put make it transport anything they
say a neutron has come up from the
research and development department of
the company superstar that it carries
something in the storage part
do I do perception development if I put
something in the back of my car mm
nobody had put in before I'm doing yeah
so this sector the industry goes crazy
droned how could we detect them chase
them control them and throw them away
humiliate them and dump them out and one
of the ways is detecting them through
cameras or thermal cameras or infrared
and that can give you a physical shape
of the machine based on the heat
produced by the engines the engines the
shape that they have inside of the
camera well for hot points in the shape
of a square that's probably not a bird
people also say well depending on how it
rings it could be one or the other the
audio of footprint but above all and
first of all the signals that it
compares to the pilot of the drone and
it they they control in telemetry ok
this drone of this brand has a certain
signature
the conveyors you can notice that behave
in a very specific way and there are
happy needin studies that focus on on an
external stimulus first as if I believe
that I'm being spied on with drones at
home or at the movies I switch on and
off the light of my home so that the
bright changes in the drone image that's
very weird but there's actually an
article published about this but above
all it's about the signature of the
radio signal in each one of the machines
this one I have a particularly funny hey
do not worry with my app I've designed a
knot and you can install that and if you
see a drunk you do that
and the app tells you which is the wrong
one summation X right because this is
becoming trendy here and it seems to be
heading for drones to be flying around
the city some of this application you'll
be able to check with each drone in in
real time whether it is legally legal
and what submission to force everybody
to install that this little program in
their own drone so that they voluntarily
provide this information about their
intentions
I mean that one was smart really smart
your own conclusions
so what actions what we have already
detected at wrong and we can we have it
sort of a payment screen and this we're
do you issue a greater power it's about
I'm stronger than you you that's all so
I speak louder than you and therefore
your drone cannot listen to you it's the
EMP the electromagnetic pulse and I
found out what that was playing
Starcraft and a while ago certainly and
it's about nineteen electromagnetic
pulse that sort of melts the electronic
but the more standard procedure is radio
Yemen and is appealing because they talk
about the gold fever and I have Joey and
I'm here with my wife I'm Jack her this
came up in the DEF CON this type of
device in our Sears
which is drones gone mad we go crazy
with their Santa drone system they can
go to 3,000 your are still 10,000 and
you need a guy to be holding that rifle
but this is really my favorite this is
from I think a British brand well it's
part of the same team the whole thing
and it's about Raider
thermography cameras yeah mirrors
protocol of hacks so the whole catalogue
for just 1 million yours
and you say to yourself it's gonna be
very bad if with a million euros you
cannot insert yeah stop today drones the
question is how many drones gonna buy my
stuff with a million euros so depending
on the model for port in thousand and
five hundred drones no can that this
machine it those 14,000 drone maybe
that's not how you should compute these
figures you just should throw in money
and that's it and because what the only
thing that matters is stopping them at
other options I love
and the issue is whether these drawn is
the appropriate size what if it's not
whether you get it from how do you hold
it and then matron is bigger than yours
we were saying my radio is bigger than
yours and now my tron is because any
yours it's all about size really only be
called counter countermeasures but these
are just palliative measures if
frequency starts being I'm not going to
talk a lot about my this life because my
bosses are here and they are there
people in telecommunications and they
might beat me up afterwards but the idea
is to use white and spectrum that is to
use a very wide range of wavelengths so
that if one fails you have a very ample
base the next one is obviously do you
use the frequency that the Yammer is not
prepared for this is like the cat and
the mice so if you have this if this is
your frequency range your summer
something else and your Yammer is no
good and then robust protocols I
remember I don't know if they are around
here if you're here one who did an
attack on an authentication attack
through the drone Wi-Fi and I thought
I'd do my own Wi-Fi protocol with
casinos
and casinos think that that kind of last
year and I'll show you what it is about
later on that's that with all this and
all this but let's do air drone that
goes through a 3G and 4G okay they
cannot do you having to me because it's
illegal I don't know what could go wrong
with that
yeah MERS do not die him
this was the site that I picked up from
the dead come and they were saying
that's what they were saying it is
illegal for G
so I know you jammy was having me draw
number one so to to get more specific
and more technical you know that con
2013 in fact it was my first talk I
presented the at report on which is it's
a drone it's still there I didn't kill
it off yet
it's a dropper strong Wi-Fi router
there's a Verity control he's through a
C program I'm sorry that runs on the
router and it reads the data of the same
source that were just the commands of
the we because at that time you couldn't
buy sensors that easily or they were
incredibly expensive so I was better to
use the command staff they if you want
to see just have to go to the web of
wrote that whose control through html5
and it was a radio Wi-Fi and I did a POC
on beacons that I will explain more
about
and what next
in the face of this I said to myself
well I have to do something and then I
remember this city in Star Wars when in
Star Wars were not about a reason to cry
and they commanded it I thought that
they are 30-30 shapes but they're so
small that they are laser I've named
this interceptor in just a few hours ago
I'm gonna call it our interceptor
depending on which vision which region I
made with Chinese rocks because they say
the cover of the Tron is are so cheap
you get one in nature in the Chinese
story that's yes but then nobody will
believe that I've done it but with this
Chinese and this is a book or plague
plague that exists it has four engines
no tri-phasic engines just standard and
and not super efficient now what's the
late motive of this project obviously
it's harder to detect without this a
thermographic cameras minimum weight
that means I can do more I can launch
the whole squadron against you depth of
hardware everything I wanted it to have
everything
you should also hack
this is what I come here to complain and
to tell you about my sorrowful story how
this project went because that's why
we're cooking it wrong the first thing
was to choose sensor data our sensors
not the type react so I expressed that's
always a possibility the first one that
struck me was MPU 9250 karasov
accelerometer magnetometer barometer so
great
and then ask for the smallest board with
until five minutes ago it was correct
but until just recently there's this
board which is just a bit bigger than a
euro coin and it has Wi-Fi in Linux and
has inspired himself in in the Wi-Fi
router the black is the system that has
Wi-Fi Linux and the system of course the
CPU and you have the memory in the flash
it's a signal a digital signal that is
sent in intervals up down up down it's
just a square signal and the longer it
stays up more wealthy engine turn so I
went the pain is up I can change that to
the time that the pain stays up to
change the speed
but then the party starts at the quarry
comes in and the first thing I see is
that the guy who has designed it another
Chinese guy so is that the link driver
because it is their own it is private it
doesn't meet the standard that I have a
perfect SDK to develop my stuff and I
say okay well pay me if you want me to
up in your great SDK an image of open
wrt but it's not in the official branch
you have to download it from somewhere
else there is a little program there to
change the pins and then there is a
device tree that I will explain in more
detail
so I couldn't believe that because it
was really still half coke that's still
more strange software I take a look at
the drivers of their centers because the
MBU 2.5 and the other ones this is cheap
maybe your mom has it just completely
standard but you go there and then first
of all for makers will have Intel that
says no problem I have a library that
I've done it on my own from scratch to
make your life easier
what's your library like then do you
have an ID son no do you have a
raspberry you know well get lost
well if you go to the source code and
you are this in that version from that
ivory I don't know how that is now but
in the version of the library you have
to touch the source code and to say I'm
a friend I'm just going to I'm just
going to use that but they say doesn't
say Edison here and also it came with
Brighton's Python but you have to
deactivate all of that because you don't
want to to have sixteen Megazine
something like that is actually normal
rotors have four and then because we
need this to be quite sort of in
real-time in an operating system which
is has not been designed for real-time I
do must get my own scheduling and I say
well I'm gonna forget about the library
because I don't have a driver do not
tell me that it doesn't have a driver
I'm going to do it properly like a pro
so I go to a hundred and yes drivers but
they've also done sort of on their own
as they saw fit and the cabinet was
monotone and the candle of course are I
don't know this is three year old so
easy let's not overdo it the
functionalities he turns out that their
garland is the most current one the most
current one didn't even have support for
that chip specifically so you have to
say no it's something it's another one
so you can see here in the well tree
when you're going to compile it open
when you do cattlemen coffee you get the
kernel controllers everything at the
normal current should have you activate
a driver of the controller of the i2c of
the specific hardware for your board for
your tip set and then you say there is
an inventions here and be using five but
it's not the same okay but that's be
nice to each other if you are a few
defiant then you can you can work
together so all happens afterwards you
you need to modify the device tree which
is a hardware description file
for example if you're looking for mobile
device trees every mobile house its
device tree so this one has this or that
sensor in that description it tells you
as you might see here within the i2c
section you have a sensor and we think I
to see you have address 6969 has
accessible use tablet that is compatible
with in that sense NP you now you need
to fight danger option pain code so
unlike okay look at the board so there's
nothing saying interruption here okay
I look at chip datafeed and they didn't
put it through a ping you need to weld
it on the actual leg of the sensor not
on the board
so despite that obstacle say ok no knows
how these in dropshipping so the driver
knows where you are
well you aren't oh no you have a
prepared reading you lift that thing and
you read it and you drive with us or not
so you need to recite all those things
in this file the other things like alkyl
like are with the orientation matrix if
you have set up this answer on the one
way or the other for it to fit well to
fit perfectly so that it turns like this
amount I doubt basically so like oh
great
he's good to go so he's a poet
I get drivers to compiler get them from
another corner and then you go to read
them to read all data and girls like
black and then he continues okay so not
black did wrong just black as well and
counter for the luxury of these going
bust all free of these working pretty
much always but not always say that I
acutely son to lower the CPU consumption
only the consume to between two and nine
percent of the CPU so that's quite a
intensive usage I just thought that was
weird
someone was saying if you have read the
slides well can you use I to see we
software there's like what are you with
on octopus when I didn't have a real eye
to see so you can get those two pins say
that it does not a high to see and dine
side there is an i2c emulated unlike
what what are you talking about
so here's a device tree and there are
full talks on the device tree just like
now JSON and the format is pre open but
you may have seen depending on the drive
is like the parameters you put on the
driver when he comes to his thoughts
that depends on the driver hey I need a
parameter called T so dart okay thank
you it's in the source code you can look
at it of course so after all of this you
get the vocal - you get support for
Leedy - now unify the open wrt device
tree is this n't so I know completely
the NP you and go to other solutions
that integrate the filter even so that
the new scope and the magnetometer and
another device works earn
so the pwf has four chance per hard word
but only two of them are active because
guy who worked from the board made a
dinner device tree and the person may
want these paints in this configuration
and the chip may use them differently
fair enough why not
good luck without but you need to
disable the you are a RT to some of them
much they you are too so need to disable
to a neighbor another too
in develop course among masks guy hey
you know I want you to disable the for
two rounds okay so you need to
to disable and enable of this he's like
what look at that face and these are the
last post of the thread so what do we
actually need to do here
we need to look at how the device tree
works device tree works by defining some
sort of groups or Assamese give them a
meaning so that's like a cross matrix so
these groups are groups of pins
associated with this functionality so
the pins of the you are to half you are
doing the function here - it looks
obvious doesn't it we have other pins
and PWM 0 which is at P W have 0 then
the 1 which is 1 and they all have the
name and the function but I do need to
disable the function
of uart and say that it's pedo um I need
to find a whole new set of pins in 2301
and the other two which are the you
aren't so the people who did this call
those pins you Artie - but they could be
PWM even now they're called you a year
t2 and you like what the
so what you need to do
and these goes through layers first of
all you have a chip and then you have
the board so need to find them
and then the code
this is managed by the kernel itself and
he is where you define the functions you
have a group PW everyone and this may
have all these functions and so on and
we're interesting in this one in
particular for the you you are to what I
want in PWM so I don't have that you are
but I have the to PW apps and we need to
go to the datasheet to see this and here
we have same thing as in the code
very states that the you are - they may
have gpo's pwm we see in this picture
kind of
looks that I'm doing something sensible
these are the accompany workshop we were
trying the power stage of the drone
which is a MOSFET works as a power stage
for the NGS it goes from the PWM egos
the MOSFET it has a roud compensator so
Jesus in crash or you just set yourself
on fire and we were doing debugging with
its butter also called Silas cope and
here you see the
it looks like
the heart rate or someone who sign and
when you stop giving power to the engine
the engine becomes out in writer
and as they return power so we need to
control those things so that it doesn't
work like crap
then we get to the last stage
the turning of a PID the pimping of the
PID
and this thing's silly but it's the most
reliable way of adapting it when you buy
it wrong it's already do you not but
they don't tell you how they did in
factory and you only need to do it once
so here you block the drawing all the
access except for them for one and you
trans that one I'm not gonna give you
too many details where PID virtual ease
control algorithm dust will well you
have a reading and you read your minus
one degrees of inflection won't be a
zero
so this algorithm applies the exam just
drunk to the ideas to get to zero
without going too far it's like the
cruise control of a car but times three
three chances like this like this like
this
okay so interceptor as a hacking tool
that are implemented in this room so
this is a controlling telemetry but
through Wi-Fi he has an extension of the
protocol I design for the other part is
a big console based protocol we because
frames
Wi-Fi announced in a network that
doesn't exist in the payload of beacon
and here I sent the control data so this
drone also gives you one data
and if you see the mobile this is
working I haven't looked at it but you
can see then you have the pilot in
scepter of
SSIDs and those networks do not exist
the exchanging data through the payload
become show you okay I want to do this
but just with a we fear doctor I want to
have more adapters they don't fit so
what do we do I go through all the
channels just in case I want to run a
tool such as boy for Wi-Fi out into a
river one of those things so I need to
my interface that are used for drone
control and as well as to launch those
tools safe
broadcasting our channel I'm blocked
there so I avail of the overlapping of
channels and say with a remote control
okay I want to change the channel and
they're wrong
dreads artists are okay so if I mean 13
ago to 12 and so on until I get to a
channel I want that is done with AES
coding encrypting to protect the
packages and well
I can review me a lot airport okay I
need to change the battery because I've
been charging for an hour
he may see
control that's the website
you can see it here
this is served by the PC PC has a Wi-Fi
network and the becomes go from this USB
trial even though it looks like an
expensive admit he say USB command I use
be more control it could be like a
Playstation trolley he works with the
joystick kernel mode it reads from down
and he converts something to become
frames the whole movement of the leaf
different levers and then on the way
back since the monitor is injecting a
fitting of a safe adapted the I truck
mode and also does it in mantra mode to
talk show packages from the drone that
is insane wrong he's giving back its
lavatory if I move it
and it gives me telemetry in the battery
voltage it's kind of working on pay
okay so this year works with the u.s.
sockets those from the PC server to
navigate to the browser you got to
become friends with the drum and they go
to the u.s. sockets that I are
representing JSON on the interface so if
they want to retain to switch a channel
that's so fast here okay plus client
mode I have an access point here which
is my home both a drum would you see
mode so I ask you to go to my normal
mode Juicy J channel otherwise unblocked
in the client mode channel so now I can
switch the channel
so here is beginning to launch the bully
to different very different SSIDs
okay
she liked all about the really
yeah Machado she knows lack of you CBN
is preguntas so if you have any
questions we may begin love ya it
no makeup on oh thank you you need to
give me another round of clothes later
when I finish properly so other other
any questions
hello first of all congratulations I
actually have to question it's two short
questions first of all have you thought
about selling it founding kickstarter or
whatever you wish please do please do
have it
secondly I found remarkable that you
trick the become frames
I guess it's quite easy to have that
wrong because if we find the SSID of the
to wife as you're using we could inject
packages very easily right well there
are two ways and I'm gonna say this
before the demo which is a bit dangerous
please this is an expensive screen
let's not damage it and we know that
Wi-Fi is unhackable
I'll never deny that but they're
different mitigation measures one of
them ciphering another one is a message
integrity I dunno you may ingest
packages my proposal has not been
developed the final proposal
it's something we're really doing is to
have a sequence control reject all
packages you know it's not that easy
please do not do it but that's the way
it is we need to check integrity as well
as an in sequence number and these can't
the others and he's also encrypted with
the payers and the code changes every
resort he's changed by the normal
network in each fight the the keyword
changes because he it I'm like traffic
you may get me my keyword so it goes on
those lines however the aim is to use
something different than Wi-Fi and I'll
leave it there for other talks because
this is to be continued
so I'm gonna do the demo are there any
other questions meanwhile do these are
good question by the way if you manage
to answer it if you get a better
question I'll give you a book for free
I'm gonna give a book for free to the
best question there's another person
over there please rise
raise your hand
hello hi so from the Harn world
perspective I think is like suicide to
use brush and you said of using brush
less easy just to make the drum cooler
what were you by the way I like to look
at you in the eye
well you know to wrong because the
brochure and Jesus o'clock for drones
but they're grateful tiny round the tree
fasiq and Jesus with their controller
how's it done have a tiny size and
they're all brushed well please look at
Bangor oh I'll Express because in that
size you have Brutus that are very thing
without with less interference another
cars oh these ones came in a truck he's
like three three years purging well
cheap clothes the ECC yeah you pay down
the you lock your area thank you however
if I crash a minimum cost it doesn't
really matter
ok thank you thank you
okay so let's check I just finished
pimping this this morning Arturia
okay let's check how this works
and this will be actually very short so
please pay attention she won't take a
picture please do it now otherwise might
be too late Oh
thank you very much let's try again if
you don't mind you know I'm kind of
liking it
oh I can't believe I'm so clumsy okay
one more and we're done
in fact this is him come up in the
slides you can come close and look it
but this sensor does not allow for
filter configuration so you need to do a
physical filter which is to get to
thermoelectric tile bounce and put a
little coin there and that was a filter
to cut the high frequencies of the
activities
otherwise this would never fly oh there
we go
Wow
okay he's been parked now
thank you very much and I don't know
whether we still have some time so one
last question
but you've all seen there were the Bruce
Willis anyway well thank you for watch
the vid well thank you oh by the way I
will have one very last slide
now we're all there not just numbers
there is beer free through nights until
10:00 so I would like to defend these
people who are actually bosses thank you
very much thank you
[Music]