try memos esta es erin de un grupo de
fabric antes para hablar de deception
e-discovery lo más rápidos con cada uno
de reportero dolor en en la solución
mirando desde fuera stood intro m-pesa
ramos cone meet under the foot on blue
leaf la posada MOS a lotta for mother
said she on the guess you a trap no trap
data discovery is within the company
with microphones malware and behavioral
analysis and patent search defense
inside with barracuda with email coming
in and finally with lead there will give
us the overall vision of everything we
have overlooked in our company's next
wave is continuously scouting for new
vendors
how does a my girlfriend relief well
tell us
thank you so much one good afternoon
everyone
I'll be very brief I'll tell you about
what we do blue live monitoring the
external side of companies so to say
this is where we start and blue live
there's a very wide range of threats out
there if we focus on that concept there
cybercrime there is a certain degree of
complexity in monitoring all these
threats we monitor different sources
which are related to these threats so
give you an example we're monitoring
passive in tour sites forum forums where
cyber criminals share or offer their
services they sell their credit card
details they've just stolen we also
monitor for mobile obligation threats
leakages in databases
the main complexity arises on the fact
that there are many formats here so we
normalize the information we enrich it
with our research and then we filter and
categorize it in our own internal
database at the end of the day companies
can configure the domains that IPS and
their email addresses within the system
and as soon as mentions are made in any
of the sources we would notify the
company that is complemented by malware
analysis that we carry out on a daily
basis we analyze a large amount of
variants of malware codes we analyze it
we detect connections
the type of encryption that is used at
botnets the very news we extract data
and we store it because this is data
discovery
apart from discovering the data itself
we want have intelligence and context
around the data we had a number of
services on top of that like credential
monitoring something that is closely
related to the round table which is
focusing on data discovery we tell our
clients whenever a credential appears in
any of those sites in private forums or
in tour sites where criminal cyber
criminals exchange the information and
also information coming from botnets
which is particularly interesting I
think that basically 100% of
organizations having affected computers
that can be malware installed as a pony
to steal data to still email credentials
for example those credentials are sent
to the Samba server antibodies will then
use those details for all those things
you know about so it's important to
detect a threat but it's also important
to say why it is important if you know
what I mean
what do threats mean what do they imply
for example when we say that this
credential is related to this botnet
that is this malware doing this it shows
a certain behavior within the sandbox
I'm not sure you're seeing this here you
see the
a flow charts for that malware it is
injecting code into another process it
is creating certain files within the
system it is connecting with a certain
domain with a certain IP address so that
would be what we call the intelligence
around the data and I will discover so
we can extrapolate based on this and say
this malware is connected to this domain
you've seen this URL but within our
system we have other malware that
connect with the same URL so we apply
monitoring or follow-up for that we can
analyze the full domain and say well
this domain is related to this IP we do
inverse resolution towards other domains
which allows us to detect additional
campaigns when you have detected more
than one campaign you can start
distinguishing different patterns within
those campaigns to try and find out who
is behind the scenes the person or
persons this would be the hashes
well we say that this group may be
behind this campaign the context would
tell us that this is a targeted or a
normal attack it is not just about
discovering it is about providing our
clients with intelligence around the
data that we have discovered what each
threat implies for each company we check
of this foolish
overall there now let me introduce you
to the crescendo en españa comemos
comedo pousada la la - al menos una vez
en la vida simply they say a very estado
and upon polygon Telugu cinema we run
destroy 100 years we are introduction
sorry Latino here the deception
what does conocen Latin lo que the
deception
the losers omnipotentis no veo bien well
so much better funda auras s the ambit
of deception que significa stop possibly
the report incidentes they only keep on
wheel and inertial open this fundamental
medium presence of hetero Takas porque
cuando alguien que entra en contra una
forma de entrar tech risk en todos vamos
elementos que son necesarios para detect
are a lotta came st-cyr como abort
emotion problema y como can be a Mosel
para Dilma del fevers herida being led
fever trap fever trap a.k.a Punta a
poontang a distintos alimentos es muy
importante de tech tar a que ya salmon
Arthas no conocida see despues también
los ataques dairy-free dos y como la
famous fever trap tiene the tenemos upon
Dolores
Clavis pro camp low contrast ennas
connector s Davis de datos
todo lo que puede ser interesante para
Britta desperate a partner manos de
quois los de cochon Como honey pots
Simona manera the aboard our esta
deception and then honeypot for the
scholar podcaster with you with this but
II at a local with my skin toner Dante I
sent or no SS here que el ataque ante
entra en la infrastructure ah otra vez
de estos a punted or AC nosotros
obtained a MOS información sobre lo que
pasa
después de la vulnera fiancée habla Mo's
del nose a punted horas de los loros
puede estar map a oddo
en el punto final de manera invicible y
despues poor otra parte tenemos las
contra Senna's k estado en masse nadas
en la memoria e alguien a stout Elizondo
algunos de estos ludus acaba aqui y
nosotros sabemos immediate Ament ay que
lo que esta pasando NS a-- machina ya
partir de y podemos profunda farinelli
Vento ISA burma Seema's se por que yo te
trabajado mucho el for essica quiero
saber que lo que pasa aqui eros a ver lo
rapido quiero tender respuesta rapid a
disaster hace que por ESO a mostest
Arenado esta Rami enta a ckr finance a
trata de datos de sobre las amenazas sse
información sobre pour quiero una de
rossi own Yaron dosto and eau de las
direcciones
IPE need a haciendo pay simplemente
estamos viendo a la parte más Alta delle
pyramid a para yo
Puia yellow-star lo con caso con ello en
la primera Appetit que nosotros detect a
Mo's consider trap for him ah c'est tres
años
muy orgulloso porque la première lo que
nosotros tuvimos companion who know the
estas internists
reception CBO Colorado yeah party da yo
Greta v un mensaje Seerat renacer de
connect Sione's te malware yaki be
mostró que me episode exactamente dentro
de ESA's máquinas yo estamos hablando de
un cliente que tenia
muchisimas alimentos t prevention
applica dose a los equipos para proteger
say TV hemos petitio Nez todo el tiempo
para Nisa Kiera ninguna solution Kudo
detector esta actividad de s Canyon yaki
vemos el fin de semana aqui vemos como
free Natividad no cynicism ana es SE r
que esto nos indica que estan trabajando
en todo esto para ganar dinero sassy
trabajando Nunez awareness he'll be
earnest said man if it is Malala is
canceled tambien BMO's que teníamos
estas Luis and total infrastructure ah
era la injection deck Cody hall la otra
um archivo grotto Tammy encontramos una
shell Chinna y tambien be Mosca be on
Corrado being injected o malware en la
macchina imaginary yo estaba I commend
Oh
follow me toss
yeah mayor west mensaje okay have you
address me Artie Vash yaki Ella Haku
table stuff your modicum of mcafee yum
yum accorded estás certificates Nestor
certificado Skiba mister mismo nombre
athena sannyas came a second Ramos be
more sunken traumas aramean tha's Evo's
que el mal wa cambia la fere ma pero la
Sarah Mientus tomatillo Santos well
INSERM as Mandela mismas si si si puede
Schoharie stasera Mientus e receiver is
a Korean format film productive in to
infrastructure ah estas mejor ando Oh
Don Dahler resilient via ah to
infrastructure ah they separate data
protection
I'll keep in most common I can t give up
a sandals in the machina otra when I
también se Kiboko puso una serie de
Rory's grammatical s en la kappahd a
deception teníamos datos tato's casein
documentos comarca stea wha
Estes it a lien is the momento que está
robando documentos podemos identificar
como se movin los documentos pour Lance
Russell - ah sí sí sí allí está robando
information de esta interested - yo can
be our toda la cadena the instrucciones
de commandos he demanded a peep identify
car king esta rallies and o el ataque e
por que llamo formación de que él está
robando
en esto estaba revenue loss cliente que
nosotros estamos en esta Centro de
seguridad de prasi own sa seguridad para
recibir porque si bear trap las Flores
knows per meter on detector a lotta
Conte de manera rápida en el momento que
alguien toca under el nosotros Casa de
Moura TV motioning for mafia
in marietta de este compromiso si si si
nosotros podemos identify career que
alguien que esta dentro de la res ya
partir de nosotros estamos Ojeda Ramos
in Chile in fear they I mean nothing so
breast Amina is just an okay to no post
comprehend mercado porque no por que les
fear master Santa spawn niblets para
este tipo de ataque esta serie Casey
comprado ribbit Evo's tienes applicati
ready Turkish own impossibly silk a
lentil a champion los datos k concern
Ramos at Rivest estas soluciones the
deception is significant which is
Molinaro al fin don t NS esta you form a
fee on kale upon a sin to
infrastructural upon us into frosted to
de e motivo pontine SS and form a seal
upon s la introduces interfaces to raya
parte de ella comparte yes es como
nosotros a ver damos este problema de
seguridad cuando estamos hablando de
estos atticus avanzada zkk a su fren la
Senne presses a Travis de nuestro severe
trapezius
next speaker is home arena he comes from
microfocus
he would tell us about data discovery
within the company
my name is hokule'a marina I am the
responsible for preventive for ing
solutions for micro surface like
Ferguson for South Europe so two weeks
ago when I was asked to come here to
give you the sensation for experts such
as yourselves and say well will I be
able to do that considering that
managers are not good into technical
things anyway happy to my best I don't
know whether you are aware of this topic
it is a very trendy topic and the first
thing that I'm going to do with you to
share three use cases three real
solutions so that you are aware of the
problems that we try to fix with that
and then we move on to a couple of a
slides well I will be sharing with you
the architecture that we use for that
the first use case is powder client from
the transportation industry he's called
a file repository that is growing a
large fuckup takes a long time there is
a long big tree of files with the small
files users upload that with files but
because of the trade unions I kind of
really go into these files to see what
is happening it is there this is growing
I am storing them I'm giving them a
storage space but I don't know what to
do I need a tool to connect that to
analyze scan all the file is just index
them and first of all for that you to
tell me what it's in there and so that
the tool is is smart enough that if I
change the extension of the file
continues to tell me look this is a
video this is a word file and what do I
want to do that well I want to do that
for many reasons first of all because I
don't know whether that intelligence
will compromise my company somehow
because that information is illegal or
because I just want to migrate data to
the cloud and I just want to clean up
data so use case number one first of all
we have to analyze those files and then
to attack the meta data of those files
this will tell me whether those files
have been have not been accessed in the
last two years whether there are 25
copies around
whether these fires from I don't know
Sadie files or but in the end actually
there are videos okay use case number
two manufacturing company of arrow
special engines so this client called us
because they wanted to have an
understanding of two repositories first
system and then another one in the set
point and then two for us to check that
they give us terabyte of intelligence
this is what IT people use to share
their files okay we'd run the analysis
and we found out two things first a
plain file with all the keys full of the
Wi-Fi or the whole company okay someone
has copied that well to move it from one
place to another
and it is sitting there okay but
secondly we found the drawings of
missile from anti-nato so what is
whatever comes from okay
please sent in the drawing suffice the
drawing files and then it is stayed
there so with this mean that we don't
know what we have third use case banking
sector clients concerned about the GDP
are the new data protection regulation
and he wants to protect data in his
environments so we have Oracle's my SQL
my mainframe and a wonderful database
and information that I want to look into
so I need a to connecting all these
environments connecting all these
databases and then from grammar that I
give to it I will tell him what to find
for me so the three use cases cases
we've worked on in two months okay so
since we started 2018 okay so this is
the architecture that we use so we'll
have two products connecting two
different repositories there is the
difference between talking to database
and to an open environment then we'll
have a central engine applying policies
through these two elements against these
overseas repositories so we will not be
only happy with finding information we
want to have possibility to act to take
action on those data and if necessary
when we find out what they are to delete
them if they are to be deleted it's a
mistake just to keep intelligence just
in case we just want to delete anything
that may potentially compromised us and
all in all manage that how do we do that
with our three through three different
products in our portfolio control points
we'd use it to access these open
repository fan systems will drive you
name it so the enterprise content
management we use it to access databases
and then we have this central engine
which is the that was the content
management it is very important while
managing data does not mean that you
have to move meta data it's about
managing that data wherever they are
okay so these are screenshots about our
tools there are highly visuals in all
the time we have the possibility to
create grammars will have a number of
standard grammars already in place
however we can create others and compile
the grammars that we need for our
purpose and the
a view of what we can do in szm which is
exactly the same that is to say using
grammars that defined by aspirins as a
grammar for the banking sector where we
have all the different ways of storing a
bank account so that by the time I tried
to find that information I know where to
find it okay and this is all for me
thank you very much now we move on to
adapt on defense round parrot from Panda
hello welcome hello
each and every one drawing on one hand
told us in terms of data control there
is a big why about that and especially
why is about the structure data
companies have files all around the
company in different across different
PCs files over which we have no control
whatsoever
problems about that are well known by
all of us lots of data leakage is so
clear cases of Yahoo and others big
problems
well these problems have demolished many
companies have hurted many other
companies significantly so some of these
companies the value drop in the stock
exchange negative advertising or so
unexpected costs interruption of
business etc so what we try to do is to
put order in all that because we have an
agent in each what place so what we do
is to find all the files in each
workplace and then we monitor their
information and we check whether it is
at risk of me exfiltrated so this is a
demo showing a lateral attack through a
file through a compiler so this is a
brief example as to how we detect this
type of threats
okay give me a sec so hon tell a
practical joke please
so the idea is to get a view from the
outside to the inside in the side of
deception that is the difference between
setting up your own honey pots in your
company or a sinkhole and then to look
from that from the outside based on
discoveries strategies versus a service
instead well compared to the handcraft
such that you made to yourself and then
the importance of looking inside no
platform so magics with DLP allowing you
to control everything it's about ongoing
search also the importance of looking
into each excel file when looking into
the behavior of it disassembling is or D
compiling it as I will just show you all
right so this is my example so approach
well what do we do with my work we not
only trigger and alerts okay let's take
a look at this specific malware we see
activity at all times and we monitor
what the malware does so we see all when
a full behavior since the beginning
since it has started it went into the
workplace and then we see a timeline we
see what it did I'll try to write
logging scripts connecting to processes
we see all the movements so we are
analyzing all that in big Tara and we
receive between 250 and 400 thousand
samples that are analyzed every single
day in depth our Patera is powerful
enough to analyze this high number of
samples the sample that I want to share
with you in terms of data protection is
this one here which is a file that
escaped all the network counter measures
so we have this file with no big issues
so we look at the activity so these file
access the compiler
when they did that it generated the talk
as our and went into the car PC and
copied all the Excel and Word files to
exfiltrate so this is methodology which
is usually used in this type of attacks
and we try not only for the man were not
to run itself but to have to monitor all
those files through our cm platform cm
platform receives all those events so we
can see all the operations all the
actions are done for those files whether
they have been opened copied on a USB
whether this being an attempt to
exfiltrate them so at all times we can
see what happens with that information
where it goes to what is done with it
we also control the risk of expectation
and what is what's been done with those
documents so the idea is to give global
visibility global view as to what is
happening to that information where is
that information going for us this is
vital most companies do not have this
type of information this type of control
which we believe is extremely important
alright so thank you very much to
everyone for your attention
okay we give the floor to Antonio Roma
no sorry to commit verily he will tell
us about him she'll tell us about
Barracuda
thank you very much fun good morning it
is not because we have for lunch okay so
it isn't an honor to be at VidCon
surrounded by security experts I don't
consider myself to be an expert but just
a person who has learned everything I
know from the internet and well the
problem with internet so the cool thing
about the Internet is that you
everything is in there the good things
and the bad things these allows us to
get lots of intelligence to share that
intelligence entities what have made us
experts on this topic so therefore we
believe that it is very important to
make use of that intelligence to protect
data businesses of companies so
intelligence against threats and for
data protection
obviously
one of the most important elements when
it comes to these intelligences is pier
fishing so well we all know them we may
have tried them and see what happens
when they are bland company and what are
the main risks that companies face when
it comes to applying advanced techniques
to human deception so we know that there
are more and more complex services on
the internet we have the resume where as
a service available so all these
technologies are becoming more and more
modular in nature so therefore we have
to work at the same level than several
primers and we also have to work and
improve these techniques and actually
they're also looking for customer
satisfaction looking for chat offering
chat box in cases of kidnapping or
ransomware so they do not only work from
9:00 to 5:00 but they have cooled Center
ready to take our requests so this is
one of the Barracuda systems this is
about the tension of advanced threats so
Barracuda has an advantage because it is
the manufacturer has the highest number
of security devices in place is very
same good position to apply security
measures so because we have data so as a
worldwide level we use a number of
parameters so we look for this security
so we have learned from the main risk
from society which is Panda Mia's and by
applying similar algorithms to those
detecting infections and Panda Mia's we
applied them to the Internet so
therefore Barracuda system Joe's number
you
number of advanced technologies to find
out what is happening in all these
security devices implemented in the
world to have detailed information as to
what happens obviously analysis of
signatures of behavior static analysis
and obviously last layer when the other
three filters having overcome sandboxing
and then from there well we may run or
not may not run the file and what with
the intelligence information that we are
getting what is information of all that
well considering all the devices
available to us we are in a position to
collect information all through the
process up until the data breaches the
company and this can be done anywhere in
the world
once the malware activity is detecting
any of the layer that layer informs the
rest of the layers so that that
information is blocked in an advanced
and in a fast manner so a threat
security threat detected in a place in
the world is transmitted fast to the
rest of the devices in the world some
specific example this is what we useful
email where we apply artificial
intelligence technology to detect less
per phishing cases and as well as domain
fraud technologies by using D mark and
also fraud simulation to have users
trains on that why do we do that
by applying artificial intelligence we
will be detecting the patterns of
communications in place in the company
so that we know whether the email is
legit or has been changed so we identify
abnormal sign else well in the beginning
was easier because it was about a bad
translation in the email but now we can
analyze writing patterns giving us the
Clou and telling us this is not widget
email and then we put all those systems
into quarantine so we used amok to
manage that the main domain that's the
best way to check that it has been sent
in a legit manner so therefore we have a
great capability to protect both senders
and recipients as well as a spoofed
emails and we also make fraud
simulations in the company will tell you
more about it later on because we
actually look for those people that we
really want to be trained on those
specific security buttons also that they
have good training and good awareness
about spearfishing
and the actual platform allows us to
generate internal phishing campaigns in
the company to increase training and
awareness of our people so that they
become firewalls and I'm ready for any
questions that you may have for me thank
you
now we give the floor to Antonio Ramos
all right so see what Antonio has for us
sir companies hire him to find out
whether that that will be launched chin
is feasible okay so thank you very much
one when I talked to fun about this and
I said what do you want me to go there
we are not technology providers I said
no no do you come over yeah you come up
there and to tell us exactly about what
I will be telling you so I will be
telling you about transparency guarantee
for those of you have the have attended
rooted editions before we were here
three years ago talking about lids which
is say security rating agency it
evaluates the strength of any security
measures that are put in place by
companies where the information is
stored but if things have been misplaced
but the time has come once you know what
the information is you have to protect
it
so for those of you in charge of
protecting you need to know how the
opacity or measures are and for those
who trust you they have a tool that
tells them really from the outside how
robust you are in your security systems
so far everything we had to do this was
perhaps convincing the senior management
that we needed a management system in
place you will get a twenty seven
thousand and one stamp OCU telling you
that you are hyper secure that is simply
rubbish no one has that
so that only tells you this you order
your security system is well-managed but
it can it doesn't say anything about its
strength a lot of people forget about
their providers you are looking inwards
you're looking at yourself without
realizing that you may have 300 500 or
2,000 providers connected to external
systems all over the place and handling
information that comes from you in their
own systems and you have no idea what
they're really doing with it yeah
sometimes you send them a form and you
tell them please say yes to all of these
and they always say yes to all of these
okay they check all the boxes you store
that form and then you say you said oh
yes these guys are rocking it anyway
that's the world around us okay the
optimistic view as one was saying how do
we do our appraisals our assessments we
have a simple test in place with some
1200 questions I mean no no shitty tests
in our case but joke society fee if you
want a serious test you really need to
have all the relevant questions in it
these are this is only for the brave for
12 main areas of security anything you
can think of by the way if you think of
something which is not on the slide tell
us we will include it in our system we
would need to know how secure your
organization is if you want us to take a
look of course and for that you need a
proper analysis people are doing that
looking at the IP addresses from the
outside based on the reputation for
those IP addresses I don't want to know
how you are doing internally well we we
focus on both sides outside on our
inside that's 1161 questions which are
mapped to some 30 something regulations
in effect throughout the world this is
the most comprehensive set of questions
about security that we know of it takes
a while to respond to everything and
obviously we
tell people whether the D a see an a a
be an A or an A+ A+ means invulnerable
no way that doesn't exist it means that
if you're working with someone that is
delivering an A+ service to you it is
less likely that you will have security
problems than if you are working with
someone that has a D as simple as that
okay it's like when you will when you
buy a washing machine when you say a
plus or a plus plus plus I have no idea
about energy efficiency but for certain
you know that an A plus washing machine
is better than a C washing machine well
as simple as that we want to be user
friendly and we want to help anyone to
put in place at all there is real a tool
that helps you realize where you stand
okay so you need to know whether details
but you need to establish a system which
will be proportional to the criticality
of the data that you have and you may
achieve at ESEA B whatever depending on
what you use that data for and then
there's another part which is repeating
this continuously on a regular basis but
I will not tell you about the details
otherwise we'll go straight into dinner
rather than lunch okay there was
everything from me it's always a
pleasure to come to rooted con thank you
continue our event a hey now just to
move on and briefly I have a set of
questions with me
one of those questions I ask why is it
better to use your platforms rather than
using your own honey pots and urine
things cyber trap technology instead of
typical sinkholes and honeypot strategy
well fundamental meant a loss honey pots
didn't interaxial millimetre say you
know manually trans cadent if akkad okay
so system a honeypot o algo para sido
una solución della the deception da a
lotta contain total opposite way in a
third of akhirin LT empathy in a
sorcerer una una una nakami machina
sino-soviet all infrastructure cases a
principal diferencia con la system as
honeypot los honey pots aaron bueno si
el pasado cuando la vía Tantawi dough in
turn em oh ye si podemos Ana machina no
party era en internet unicef ekta an
question de menos de minuto
aproximadamente
ock honeypot son buenos tardes
estadística oz para ver que esta pasando
Percy you know key Arab a message am
Bria Tandy acutally sir 1000 here the
tipo deception India
so we sink holes inside the companies
when you see coal is our deception is
sinkholes on the consider distintos
sinfulness and a possibility additional
cuando uno tiene que ready he'll
disappear melis users although mean
yours ooh no puedo Tilly certain Allah
here is at the reception que nos diga
que que no se lo mejor lots of parties
información sobre la infraestructura the
deception para ver donde esta todo o
corriendo Kip McKean estan compromise
Eva's acuerdo gracias another question
this goes to Jose Miguel how important
is it to to do a credential search as
early on as possible it is not what we
should be concerned with is that what
everyone is looking at
well talking about credentials it may
sound simple your credentials are for
email are stolen and you might say they
cannot do too many things that but the
real anything else has a different story
in recent years email credential theft
theft can be very critical it can become
a very strong vector for entry into any
type of organization if it is an email
if it's email credentials it targeted
attack may be set up to with someone in
the organization sent through someone
that knows that person
the target is attacked with spear
phishing if we're talking about
attacking systems
with a note from an oncological sister
attackers may compromise additional
machine additional boxes and end up
compromising most of the infrastructure
then monetizing the intrusion we have
seen huge gaps in different
organizations that started with a simple
theft of email trees empathy MIMO
credentials so detecting this as early
as possible is important if you find
credentials in paste VIN which may be
three four years old
for which spot the password has been
changed that is very different from
detecting a live infection within a
certain organization there can be part
of an attack happening right now okay
so the sooner we can do things
the sooner we can detect those threats
the sooner we can act rather thank you
so much for a meal another topic for
Holly on the type of patterns you're
looking for within the company do you
look for all sorts of patterns patterns
that you could look for with there's
many things that can be found credit
card details bank account details
let me give you an example of the real
case at a certain bank where they were
doing trading the trading operators have
telephone conversations there are tools
where everything is recorded and the
regulator's requests that information
for sentence transactions must be
submitted because there is a suspicion
you should be in a position to find all
that information and not just on those
files a structure or unstructured but
also the voice recordings for certain
transactions all of that can be done
thank you and last but not least to Raul
on threat hunting what are you doing
that makes a difference in your case
well 3 billion events new events every
year processed by a platform hunting a
detection platform and leveraging the
fact that we quite a few people working
on this we can see what the attackers
are doing lateral moves the movements
basically in real time we see how these
real times evolve we see how they key
how they the input goes through the
keyboard since we have this enormous
really near real-time with big date as
well we can have indicators of attacks
and indicators are compromised we go
beyond what most people do rather than
focusing on a erase or i/o sees that's
not hunting that's its detecting we do
the hunting part in a Noma in near real
time creating attack premises analyzing
movements this is the latest technology
that we have implemented and the truth
is that we have been able to extract
quite a lot of interesting information
we've been able to detect intrusions and
a lot of interesting details
when they're there that means that
they've gone through the proxy on the
firewall the last part the last mile is
a workstation and that is what we need
to focus efficiently Thank You prowl in
searching for those patterns do we have
that for email well a barracuda
our philosophy is rather simple since we
have protection through the firewall
through the email gateway including the
backup systems this is very
straightforward
talking about email we focus on
integrating and detecting what is
happening within the email system as
such we use the data who use the
algorithms we use their way people write
to ascertain the typical pattern of
communication how people use their
grammar how people use their syntax in
order to be able to detect spear
phishing so it's quite advanced on top
of that we want to be able to alert at
any stage for example with advanced
unboxing we know that there is malware
that detects that it might be in a
sandbox so he wouldn't get room executed
no problem sandbox in is a
next-generation system which avoids that
detection on the side of em of the
malware so we do our best to stay one
step beyond the bodies and we have a
presence in any stage so searching for
patterns and email which is only a
natural element of our approach so that
we can update our systems we can have
our systems with the latest technology
and procedures in place thank you so
much to all of you I know you must be
really hungry let me tell you that we
are looking for people to work for many
of these vendors typically in pre-sales
and research so go ahead and sent your
CV if you're thinking of applying for
any positions within any of these
companies
any questions from the floor
do you see a trend towards a net that
will become impossible to be open since
Google are launching protocols like HSTs
do you see a trend towards protecting
endpoints throughout the Internet well
if you ask me I'll say yes that's my
that's my job
what we have seen is that because of
this type of protocols and in perimeters
it's getting more and more complex
seeing what is happening is more and
more complex can you hear me
if we go to the endpoint we see
everything
so we are in the right place
but with this new protocol so cannot be
seen they are making things more complex
in terms of the perimeters but we are in
the end point and that makes life easier
for us if you take a look at companies
focusing on the perimeter they've
actually acquired companies that focus
on securing the work station or the
workplace so the trend is clear towards
the workplace rather than the perimeter
so nothing else thank you so much
[Applause]