[Music]
hola hello good morning thanks for
coming first of all this is a difficult
time right before lunch I'm glad that
this was interesting enough for you to
come our talk as the title says security
paradigm security
we look at the problem we face and our
approach I for we're part of the group
will be a will make the interaction the
first part of the talk can you hear me
okay first of all hello thanks for
coming it is a privilege to participate
in the return I hope I don't bore you
those of you who are dying to the
technical part I ask you to be patient
because I think it's interesting to have
the context so we're moving in will tell
you later on so where do we come from
in the context of our customers we come
from with somebody they went to the bank
to update their card and then we moved
on to the bank teller machine where we
did that through internet but now what
we have a situation we have is that
everybody can operate with a with mobile
phones with smartphones and I'm given
the case for my father or for my
grandfather and how does that change the
situation for us well we get a lot more
transactions and and you think well
that's great that that means more money
but if you look into what's happening
you've realized that not all
transactions generate
income most of them are actually just to
look at the balance or just it's about
information so that gives us a lot more
of a bigger burden without any profit
and that in dangers our computer
infrastructure we used to come to to
live in a world in which we are
competitors and in the current world we
are not we the FinTech have come around
and we find ourselves in a new situation
that we cannot control because this
FinTech companies can make daily
releases they have an incredible
productivity and that's not all they
have a time to market of any idea for a
week of just weeks and we are not ready
to compete with them why because we have
we work for a typical company that has
with IT for years we have a monolithic
application we have data all over the
place with processing cycles that are
incredibly slow that eat up most of the
day and we have little ability to use
advanced intelligence tools context we
find that different geographies have
different technologies and that entails
a lot of cost and link to the current
situation that I've described means that
the model is not viable and therefore
this is the current situation we are not
doing things because we have our CEO
talking with another CEO and that
they're saying I'm doing I'm computing
in the cloud and it's great but the
situation is that it's either we change
or the studies are saying that if
company will no longer be viable so what
should we do we have to change
and the good thing is that we know how I
have to change but not only from the
technological viewpoint everything
starts with the change in attitude or
mindset it's not about calling this
company for them to come into the job
for us but this is about talent and
in-house talent it's about changing the
way we think it's no longer an office
gripping past that I that I can move on
we have to have an end-to-end automation
and the architecture process have to
follow them ups paradigms where you
integrate the tests and so there's it's
a whole round approach and we have to
reuse code let's stop doing the same
thing over and over and all of that
through API we have to abstract the
complexity in the backend and be able to
provide information for our customers in
the best possible way and all of that
working in communities because the model
of I do the job and you use it doesn't
work we have to work together so the
change is also based on a technological
change we're building the other platform
that as we say here is a global banking
platform which allows developers to
easily build deploy and operate banking
devices of any kind of leverage in the
Virgin cloud so and there is a trough
platform because we used to do an
architecture in one of the countries and
then we would fit that architecture to
the next country and the best we called
it but that doesn't work what do we have
now we have a hybrid cloud to be able to
balance our workload based on public or
a private child according to cost and as
we've said it has to be automated as
well we do not want black boxes we want
use the open source a working model and
the customer is the developer and
finally we have to decouple the business
our architecture to build the business
logic from the architectures to be able
to change in a faster and more agile way
so from the viewpoint of security what
are we facing - I love this slide
because I think it conveys very
truthfully my day today we have very
metal the operating system we have the
infrastructure than the operating system
then a platformer saying hey I'm going
intervention front I am the security
layer it's crazy
our job is crazy but it's a lot of fun
that's my view of it because in all of
these layers we also have diversity
technologies and I believe that the
challenge is fascinating I don't know if
many of you find ourselves in this
situation but for me it's a it's a
beautiful challenge so how are we facing
this BBVA from the viewpoint of security
one of the main components that we have
its seekers last year it was mentioned
so I want is to have security and better
and offering it as a service but what do
we really have from the viewpoint of
secure development
working with an airstone I was saying
the big change what we need is for
people to be informed of what is it that
they have to do because people don't do
things wrong because they enjoy doing it
they don't think it don't make things
insecure because they enjoy doing that
their problem is that we do not give
them deleted information and when we
give it to them late because it's the
developers have to production and in the
last step they security tells them they
cannot they cannot use that so we have
to they need to have that information
earlier they will have a better life and
we will work better and this is not
about our technologies but it's about a
hurried value to the selected tools and
finally security also must be as a
service ok as javi was saying what we
want to do from sega's our goal was to
meet
all our goals to be automated and
easy-to-use and to focus on developers
and to facilitate the integration of
security in their job that's where we
start it's important to take something
else into account to develop good
software should allow us to be very fast
and have a lot of quality because it
allows us to change when the business
changes and develop new things first way
we need to do that as a bank because of
the context that hobby has described and
the quality the better they code in
terms of easier it will be to maintain
focus on the real context that we're
talking about 12-thousand developers in
vba working on a common a cloud age so
it's a huge challenge so we move at this
developers of speed we try to make
things fast so we and we stop things
that cannot be accepted or we pick up
their speed and move the way they do so
that's what we mean when we say shift
left as in intervening earlier in the
process if we're going to work with the
developers are going to be using cloud
platforms are doing fast releases so we
are not the first ones who face up to
this problem what's in the market
I saw the first thing with it was to
take a look at that and we came across
many interesting projects and terms we
particularly like this one they all was
which was an object upline important
that I will explain later on called
deficit cops which is about from
security people who have stumbled upon
the same block and they said we cannot
keep doing security in the same way but
it has to be security that delivered us
code we have to be the code and to make
sure that developers have security in
their day-to-day activities and as we
were working other initiatives came up
such as professor which is a Google
initiative which basically is an
metadata API because they said it
doesn't make sense that all products and
security solutions representatives the
way they want we have to standardize
this information beyond the existing
standards already and we are
participating with them in this
initiative because we believe it is
interesting to share that experience
we go quickly about what and they always
find what they propose to us they talk
about a security pipeline that means at
some point of your development cycle or
in the pileup stops you generate a new
security pipeline and the first phase of
the application and then we run a
battery of tests
static cold black box and with
information to generate from those tests
you generate actions remedial actions
risk actions risk management reporting
that sort of thing but if we go back to
our context we said okay that's all very
interesting this always proposal how do
we apply this and we have three options
once more as a security architecture we
gave them a catalogue of tools and tools
and lots of scripts etc but for 12,000
developers try and we try to manage that
or to help them do this we try to
develop simple easy to use product and I
like Apple in that way because they give
you a product that naive users and
expert users can use it really standard
is very easy to tries to solve the
situation and within to be able to solve
the points that we have given ourselves
there a security architecture liebherr
services that developers can use in a
simple way simple way possible simple
way for them usable by the security area
because he a code review that the
developer can do is the same code review
that is going to be done by the security
department what they act as as policeman
to make sure that something works so
that's the first goal really do have
those two from mines developers and
security the second goal they can they
always metaphor to have a number of
services of each one of the parts of the
DevOps cycle from the tree F the testing
delivery of security teams in the bank
and an automatic provision and for
security this in an automatic way we
wanted to be transparent for the
developer easy to use but that we do not
depend on having to crawl in terms of
people of staff because that's not so
what was the proposal in terms of
product we have three goals here
abstraction of security solution that
can be used many were developed for this
world and some not but even the ones
that were thought out for for this world
review of docker images Eclair we stock
in aqua some are open source and some
are from vendors that we do not want to
stick up to just one because in the
future if delivers more value that we
can change that and that is transpired
for the developers so so we use them
when they are useful we
game time and we test this functionality
and our intern our customers are
developers they only know I know that
there's an API where they can ask for
every view of the docker images and
chimera will phone always in the same
way and if I change Claire with by
twistlock
or aqua they won't even notice and I can
actually pick and choose from the three
it does add value many of the solutions
have very interesting solutions for
instance twist lock is very good for
containers but not so much for images a
lot of there's not so much focus on
images and there are some shortcomings
oh we improved what we look gave us we
standardized that and we added value
bringing information from different
layers that sort of thing and the best
thing is the orchestration part and in
that part for instance choosing between
these solution which is a branch of
feature you can use Claire I provide an
automatic feedback and there's a
functionality that will function with
the color function that I might do a
more thorough test or I add policies to
provide information to the developers as
to whether that part once it's gone
through audit is going to be deployable
in a platform so three points one
solution abstraction add value and
orchestration
to a large extent this new model of
chimera we've been working on for them
six eight months trying to deliver each
and every one of these services and in
the six months we've achieved what we
show here we have one abstraction layer
we have two available services to
further developers and we are finishing
up the third one we have these tools are
very integrated some are more mature
some are less mature some we're still
testing so you have to keep in mind that
we're talking about 12,000 developers
each time they call I realized that in
hash those collide well it has to run
well that beyond that because in BBN who
are working as a large team we even have
developers from lab that we are thinking
of integrated infinity mirror because
that was a software to analyze the
penalties yeah to look for
vulnerabilities in these things that was
quite interesting our aim isn't with the
same philosophy we deliver dr. Chimaera
and given the same architecture area
we've done in chimera so we not only yes
fine things we're also trying to avail
the time and talent we have by doing
additional things okay
so regarding explaining how we direct in
detail I like to explain how we do it
what were we doing for the image so we
have a API and from your pipeline
manually from the Chimaera front front
end or from from any method you call us
and you ask us to review a docker image
here is a detail so what do we do in
Chimaera we tell twist hop twist lock
hey give me the information but they
were abilities of these two she's loved
groups for that in the registry here the
registry he set up with artifactory and
i'm reviewing this information because
it's quite important and we have two
options either we apply this information
to develop and they can seep down the
pipeline or we may use it on the commute
coming so many other place when they
won't share information so we try to
make this easy for developers because we
have different maturity levels in the
bank among the 12,000 developers we have
will have different levels so they're
obviously beginners in some markets
people who are beginning to do 40
Jenkins you transfer the image
parameters and without they do all the
magic of Colin Chimaera
the return and the Valois library to
make developers lives easier and here
they're different libraries simple to
use is library equipment the team is
really functions they use ours so the
end using commercial be very easy
does my thinking well for for the other
feedback the Harvey was mentioning so
you know that if you're gonna use an
image as $226 abilities using barley and
you need to corrupt it and will command
as a developer you may choose not to do
it
what's the thing here when you deploy
our imaging search environment that's
gonna be rejected so what do we do here
to the value above twistlock we give
information how that image should be
assessed is gonna be flattened and you
may deploy it in one or other
environment and we say it simply and we
say we cannot deploy it because the
policy says you need
you have many more so mentally simple
info please advise you maybe charity
Chimaera in your pipeline because we put
everything on Jason we need this
information you may also see the heart
on the other console that's how he
mentioned earlier the Emma Vetter is for
vocalist use it as a thing they've gone
solo with all the information and this
is nice you can be choked there give
their hand we have security what do you
do here
we have a city guy checking every image
that he's is comment every so often well
we don't do that we try to have her to
make it a person sees we don't need to
hire so many security teams for that
with you automatically
even our hardest and pug images saying
has been reviewed he's got this
information and these are the
recommendations environment the platform
this is deployed automatically she'll
validate those properties and know we're
using a function of our country because
we can actually our properties of the
artifacts they call the properties and
that's a metadata associated to the
aunty family what are we doing here that
security seal we're using any token job
that's adjacent for my token design
eventually
okay okay okay well the good thing about
this is they came up with this
the team the rest of our colleagues not
something we fall off in tonight we'll
talk to project very well aligned how we
do transfer on the Google people how so
they called annotations in the goofiest
project to sign the metadata that is
been left in that stop it was very
interesting can you do that yes subject
in the job is associated deal image of
the doctor which is a shamless in charge
so we know the image we review that
chart is the one that is deployed and
the deployment platform services and
that's try to do a live demo I think we
have a bit of time
otherwise we'll just play the video be
plumb so
or get that long
Kodomo connects your own butter so I
think we're connected wait so I'm gonna
show
how the API launch would happen via
Chimaera
okay
so first of all camellias authenticated
first Fanta Kate to call the API
what do we send Chimaera we have the
concept of projects and we have projects
to reach team and functionality the
consul's does this need to be associated
something particular now when you
identify you know is something yours and
what do we do this force but whenever
you leave information you should be
authorized to check it and see different
things on the front end so first of all
create the project
great has been created and without which
in the case of veterans we were saying
the actual console could you it's saying
there's a new project in the bank this
is it fire we know which one it is it's
a summer and these are the users
developers the our main and once we get
that information we know lives is
the developers simply send honeymooner
abilities requests we see the image the
project that reviews r32 and without my
even answer
try to show the bit better and he was
come this image wish of the sages
sometimes if there's a big load you
can't just jump trying to show you
something else
you know
level lies how this way that's what
happens when you have life okay
so there's nothing there it's kind of
the Scotch must use be launched even a
refresh and now it's on the fire
I know you see well resume me so we have
some damage to interfere
and from the front we may even company
expiry date and so on but the most
important thing is to see the report we
see the abilities policies we sort them
out
I may see how I'm doing eh environment
which medium
is it working there which one it isn't
you in the Cosmo just like just like to
the front and I see the report here
and we have the Foundation's in detail
of how many there are the amount of
abilities and their details
why because you can depict this any way
you want to the fears you want use this
information when you call this pipeline
either you have a maturity you may say
well yes we just wanted to even get
feedback you fast I'm not your team you
feel comfortable locking your pipeline
you can avail of these information and
do that how we're doing timewise okay
right so another thing that we're trying
to do
is so trying to have it on the junkies
library
okay
right
just trying to work with his mouth
I think this is it
still having promised of the Marvel
assuming we see the library with the
parameters that we need we can see the
image name the ID and he may be where
everyone today young kids
and here it shows review this image
yeah hey my man the race Halloween whom
I also actually send semi image to be
reviewed that's right
well you know if the demo work well no
you just need to scan you'll be ready
and there's something important here
out of time it's not working pretty well
due to my house if you view this thumb
you can sit here on the Sun Visor
you see the nice results and eventually
policy says it's open job with an
inspiring with expiry date
you need to leave much amount and which
clashes are they responsible
functionality to vote these on under
Jenkins to validate these lumps of code
so let me check whether I can see it
and basically it is a mini library where
a validated is done the answer which
environment I send the information of
who is it for
so there it shows whether it's good
which is not something that a soap a
given this here if I change any value
change
the environment does not be in
development but you'd be production
just now we cannot deliver it
it says it both falls
yes they are saying well that's politics
okay
the environment is KL because in
interaction you cannot flow down it
which is white you will eat it this time
but and the issue that it is okay so it
gives you all the functionality that it
can so the developers and platforms
we're gonna use this functionality can
do so
important day for the secrets I
mentioned earlier there's nothing cool
secrets the guys hidden around here
we're trying to secrets
so that a lot is level we don't see
information that he's not repository so
we have to leave information in each
stage of the development cycle it is not
saying not come this is more necessary
to work on this even for developers so
no chance out of time this is everything
we want to tell you about and we have a
long way different things things are not
the marketing you have any question or
suggestion please let us know thank you
Howie thank you
[Applause]
are there any questions
a couple of questions here so let's be
here closer hi in the future are you
gonna release this are you planning to
release it as open source well we love
to yourself
in fact lapses open source and the
traces in the breviary repository for
Chimaera when you talk to the legal area
of the bank well we have an open source
philosophy we work for a month that is
something I'm gonna change so we need to
go through maturity stages but our right
is to do something though my beliefs
even doing advertisement the guys from
the team have availed of their knowledge
and we have number interests and things
even in BVI some personal people are
availing of the innocent we're trying to
create open source sewers we have this
good you know that there's some
interesting in this
hi
first of all congratulations the tool is
very interesting I really like it
I'd like to ask about the false
positives in my experience with these
tools they relieves those for false
positives and how do you manage this in
Chimaera well regarding from shorting
chimaera right now we have the
possibility salmi you haven't yet to
find the role that means to do it by the
governance we really have functionality
of marking that these are false positive
regarding the chlorophyll Chimaera
ideally in the first stage for feedback
and so on
the developer has a certainty of wool is
a false positive and then a bank level
we have the dog team which is a user of
the tool you as the security team will
define those rules and they'll be tabled
to work with the ethical hopping and the
Securities in this process this is
automated in fact that's the other big
sign of my security inclined my security
team is whenever they get these products
to validate it your way to review all
the false positives they do it with us
phew
it was as possible so they may focus on
reviewing one of things that maybe the
software even though I deliver to give
me around the reviews but having done a
project how it evolved and how the
amount of vulnerabilities of a certain
power decreased so they may focus on
those things so that we may have a
history of the product even analytics
because we have it as MVP one of the
things we like to do is that we know
these projects are certain statistics
because it's recurrent regarding the
amount of tons that we get library
we've used that lager has been taken out
so we just want to simplify the final
security teams work we have until you
feedback to the developers to make
things simpler and also to scale the
security teams it's just impossible Mary
speaking just like this you GT Jews okay
for 12,000 12,000 developers so Dom your
team should be able to be much more
productive in the process much more
focused any other question then you can
go for lunch I guess well thank you very
much everyone thank you thank you
Guillermo sobre la presa media
[Music]
holding back the years thinking of the
fear I've had so long