Yury Luzhkov is me please
bueno en vivo esta Charla soloist Oh yo
a kiss noise infinera una persona
yeah vosotros junto actresses de como
hacer so you know it's a una reflections
to sobre como estamos haciendo el
software
como esta tarde el sitio nvidia software
y que tiene primero en pasar por lo que
mas me proposed resulta conformity a day
he doshas algunos problemas de saguni
ecology dos mac fixes me parece natori
Oh porque estamos en dia Horan's over
where Thomas nothing near Mucha Logica
case my idea de da de las discrimination
is convicted a Neftali - estuvieron
Solomon Torre and others
conversions before we are different
versions we have six point zero six one
three five point two but right now we
have a trending programs it softer to
have a major or a minor revision
different versions and lots of
information and it seems that people are
just working without a real structure
another thing that we need to remember
is the security awareness racing is
growing a lot on the other hand we see
that a number of patches and updates is
also growing and this brought to mind a
series of questions this is really
positive people parching because they
found vulnerabilities and are they
applying the knowledge to detect them
quickly or is is because we're being
less careful in programming okay so
one of the things I thought would be
convenient was to look at the number of
vulnerabilities we have country so you
come to 2017 and you find an interesting
piece of information fourteen thousand
seven hundred and nine vulnerabilities
having different detective easier so far
what does that mean it means that in
it's been the year where most vulnerable
T's has being have been detected in
comparison to the inverse of the years
it gobbles up the figure of 2016 and
this could be some interesting food for
thought
so you may think that techniques have
improved the people are beginning to
apply the doggy's when it comes to tech
things and that's where we find many
those techniques are showing some small
flaws realized about earlier and people
are working on that now the Visia if we
look at how we're out in 2018 we're
gonna follow the same trend in two
months in a sex part of a year we have
found 2605 vulnerabilities as more than
five fifteen hundred six fifteen
thousand sixteen six hundred all
together here and
I'm a certain type of category within
programming of the area realize that is
quite well distributed we'll have a
faithful applications while the fail
operation systems mobile devices are not
lagging behind and what is important bit
here we need to think that
would you have uh software than you
developing you're gonna use an operating
system set of libraries that you can
apply in your software and you and will
probably also have vulnerabilities and
this is this yet another stage in
development of the technical abilities
so did you get to look at a set of
programs are you using and maybe up
Gracie I have a problem or am getting
the numbers wrong and achieving the
wrong conclusions but when I go into
them the far B's kind of headlines I
start researching and you see that
people are alarmed by these figures and
I think that piece should be concerning
for all of us so with this idea this
concern in mind let's do some analysis
I'm gonna focus is analysis first
on how developers and companies are
looking at security first of all who
realizes our axis of confidence even
though there is lots of training and
we're trying to raise a word ask on
security of years people are silly
spicing and so to say and rejecting the
problem for the wrong software
so you go and say well these problems
affect me these are all software such as
Skype or Windows but whose and look at
my software so what does this break this
brings about a lack of training there
are companies are not aware and they do
not give the developers the needed
skills to develop secure software so
what happens with it is they develop
proven they read an article there to
applaud they go to a website for more
secure development and a lot of
imitation they find that they need to
work a lot and that is difficult to
carry out that work most people laze
around they don't look at these concepts
and vision rays that you may have no
abilities in logging in the Access
database access in input validations
alone
and these questions is something we
should think about have you ever heard
them aha very often and I may have
committed leasing of thinking of them
sometimes not just these questions and
these way of thinking but whenever you
find someone who does pen testing and
not it and who works on all of this you
find that well I got the software of a
friend that they're developing his
company and since I know they will have
abilities I won't shackled up and
they're amazed so if we take as a basis
that the software may have run abilities
and the people not corrupting them maybe
you delete something wrong another way
you've seen this is on the actual
development so we have cycle when it
comes to develop a software we different
societies where security is extremely
important and you need to start
designing analysis
I do apologize I kind of lost my slide
okay
so as I was saying and I do apologize
for the interruption in each stage of
the development of the software you need
to apply a set of methodologies to use
secure and psychosocial you need to
apply these and we begin
and we cover you for implementation any
such analysis of the code and afterwards
in the tests the assess our product we
apply simple my nama Canales is
penetration testing used to look at how
that software is made and you actually
get a product so was a problem here the
problem is that these brings about the
highest real did costs when it comes to
general right in it in its invest a
bigger amount of resources that you
thought of and then you have for
development for the long time you cannot
tell a customer are you gonna integrate
it in a month or a week there need an
assessment tend to calibrate at those
times on the other hand what do we get
well we get a low error rate or low
frame rate a more simple code they're
reviewed and easy maintenance this will
be a model applied to security
so how do you companies receive it they
have the kickoff meeting they have the
product they want to offer at the end of
the project and everyone is happy and we
have eating a perfect soft recycle the
problem is our asset quality
contribution we're trying to reuse the
delivery time to the customer so they
have these good service and we make the
right money and here's a question you
have sitting gap so you need to cover
and you need to do full testing and when
you have the product you have an
uncontrolled estate the million right
many mistakes afterwards the one hand is
moving good for the company less costs
last time I turn around all this giving
us I was writing a sable curve that is
not all tested
and the question here is does this
really bring true benefits for the
company is this what the company wants
so the first come this benefit is how do
you happen suppose you have it you fix
him on the market to prefer to fix the
problem in maintenance eventually
generates a cost on the actual product
and the real benefit terms of product
you may see turns well if I program for
how they've months and I give a say
without to the product for a certain
period I'll run out of money so if I
exploited our paying for months if I
should conduct for months so we need to
look at whether that's beneficial
without in the civilization of the
actual product and the effort invested
in these terms
needs to be understood Eve actually the
main team is a stage
in that stage is harder to fix bones and
the early stages of the software they
see I did need to go back such as having
the resources invested in another
project and we need to move that again
and if that project s also loses trust
of the customer because if they fail
rate increases the Kozma would be
reluctant to use our product and let me
know now koala value and then the
pressure when you have a project and you
have other objectives project and right
so how can we approach these set of
things well we're not trying to explain
that in three concepts we all need to
account first of all is integration into
development is essential and I think
that people should make an effort in
applying those methodologies such as
threat modeling I've mentioned earlier
applying the design of threats to your
product and assess the risks of those
words and the concept of TD security
which is a concept that is being
developed by wasp which is very
interesting
well you're not just worked in
development the testing of that is more
important for me at least in our
assessments this also has a positive
point but when you are developer and you
know your product and you know both the
drama's are in fact you're doing a test
in an analysis of the problem that you
may have
towards you have all you have programmed
however if you give it to an external
company someone who doesn't know you
probably they test it comprehensively
maybe with this you can get a soft
shoulder and what's the concern it's
important to understand the risks and
this is connected to what we are above
it's not just design but also keeping in
mind all the risks that may be brought
about by having certain software
assuming with the whole set of
developers and project managers so they
show different abilities or problems or
mechanize and you very sorry which users
have a system but also the ones are not
going to use it product I'm gonna spoil
it to get a profit out of it
so you need to keep in mind
get a short of time you need to respect
the process and in the way of doing the
software developers
and we usually despise the work well we
should be applying much better the
awareness of how much our work is worth
and how some people keep in mind
and some people spice it usually in top
levels and last training it's important
that companies can give their employees
security training that's one more than
most important elements to comply with
everyone does a bit for secure software
development
and after all of this the conclusions
are I personally I'm very concerned with
a number of vulnerabilities and problems
are being found
the software in production constantly
and I'm not sure that's positive for our
software however we do have a massive
amount of resources that we can apply to
our software software that is not
suffering attacks from people who trying
to spoil it
so will we need to give these talk again
thank you very much
hello thank you for your talk
so I have a question on the usage of
semantic version do you think that most
development teams know about it about
semantic version do you think the
development teams know about it and
secondly they is your strategy feasible
in agile strong project sorts of
projects sort of methodology fits
brainstorming is one of the parts of our
j'l do you talk as a whole but he's just
not focused for what we're trying to
approach here you supply it and to make
people aware what the father Enterprise
about sometimes to think on the promises
of from my house not just for the
percentages of the product to bring get
ahead without in the first question
I see that Mouse Avella purrs I mean
other ones who come to these conferences
are not able to apply certain techniques
and I don't think I'm selling one of the
Flies I don't think we were able to give
the right value the software and the
final quality to apply that kind of
technique
any other questions
thank you for your speech regarding the
internals tool development which quality
would you suggest security techniques
well tools for testing all the wrong
tools that you wanna use afterwards well
tools developed in the company maybe for
people maybe that generate files you
know do things
these are usually small tools they have
their own requirements
well in fact responsibilities and
there's even a big buildup because our
problem is gonna be launched my public
is gonna be an internal tool so devoting
sources from the company to bring get
out there and do it may be very costly
and very beneficial maybe one person
will benefit from that if they know that
they have various in program
to manage to have access and resources
in the company what you not securitize
say communications channel because empty
may happen and so on me how hacking
techniques and yelling to that child
listen to your conversations because
eventually the company has not given
value to that to be honest I haven't
thought about it from the internal to
perspective might need to are to assess
whether at all comes in process is
necessary to account because in the
lifecycle of an application you use that
too may be done too it's giving you a
way of doing things so we might need to
look about
show different opinions these kinds of
these kind of ideas will be very
interesting thank you
okay we do have time for yet another
question hi
congratulations for your speeches be
very interesting
and I'll talk about some problem I see
very often people who work on
development are not usually interested
in security and people who do security
are not usually very interesting
development in fact occurs hardly know
how to velop in Java and other big
applications so I wanted to mention it's
do you think that we should go to the
model well we'll be there in two
thousand teams people who know how to
develop about security instead of
developing edges review they call
security
well losing the secures vermin process
and by the way thank you for the
question you need to have a team in
charge of security in that project that
is application is not just development
we want to develop it securely in my
face
jobs are worked as a developer and where
he transferred security to end a person
evaluated rather than we've been testing
the product now and I also have a
certain controversy controversy with
that problem because those two extremes
are kind of a so isolated from each
other some people might share it but
someone wants to do hacking is not
giving value-oriented unique team of
infrastructure get out so I think that
is necessary for companies to include
there are some people with security
knowledge also that developers don't
just have someone specialized but also
that they're given that training but
they're given sort of their mind yes you
are threshold
well then maybe I would to balance out
the two versions of how they're working
thank you very much for your question
thank you much everyone thank you I hope
you enjoyed it thank you