and tell stories on Fitz and mobile
networks you know we're in the city of
of the image in Madrid we have the CEOs
of 10 Madrid their Spanish TV and we
have overall satellite teleport and
whenever you see those antennas next
door see something I made that picture
that day and now the picture is here
again and talked about today it's
something to contribute on as you are
then I'll come back to the topic but I
want to publish the tools because I
think that these will really be useful
in your daily basis vulnerabilities for
manufacturers or certain models we never
you begin playing with that you see how
we say it is there are two attacks will
not focus on channel sequesteration
and channel hijacking and URL injection
as the are is the software right you'll
find and he goes by the hand of TV in
2010 some people started playing with
Tongass one these are TVs
started and the real chip that's what
whereas the are comes from and the real
answer that real tech chip even those
they synchronize and they tuning TV
frequency they can use it for other
frequencies so when they do that the
chip has a converter
converter so all the information that
came from the antenna is transferred to
the usb it's fully digital is like this
it's a software-defined radio as yob
because those zeros and ones are because
we're gonna treat them in a computer
when we scan something for example
everything we get to computer us and now
for the document house so he says a
whole bunch of zeros on once we need
allows yacht recognize something
something here how Dunkeld yas yas and
zeros and ones take off the TV I need my
own software and that's the ser okay I
don't know whether it sounds familiar
but whenever we go to buy a TV everyone
thinks about the inches and about
whether is curved or flat and that's it
of course the price but there is another
sandal which is the HPV TV coming from
Europe in 2009
and this has to do with what happens to
routers at home the router so being a
router now they have all sorts of things
USB files printing servers and what we
want to compute in the route are we
never have it same thing for the TV they
want to make it in truck if there are
millions of TVs globally and we
developed a lot of line to watching TV
but until recently the TV only just got
a signal and that was it so these people
get here and said ok don't worry we're
gonna give you some measure measure a
time see oh wow
and how am I going to give you this
advertising customized advertisement
because it's going to be interactive I'm
going to broadcast to the right forget
about the satellite it could be in area
whatever the image comes in and in that
signal you're going to have the standard
HPB TV and the TV will archer by a rotor
that's why it is hybrid broadcast
broadband so the broadband is the router
although we we call it smart TV because
it's connected but we connected with
those means this is a very schematic
diagram if you are familiar with this I
apologize because I have really
simplified just the focus this is an
operator just like I think mobiles are
better known but this is Intel
operator content is generated to the
left this is the reporter the reporter
with a van and an antenna that is lent
with the radio link with the production
center where they prepare the material
of course operators have several TV
stations that they have to multiplex and
they distribute it and then it's
broadcasted to get it to our homes okay
now we'll move on to TDT you all know
this is the rational digital television
but if you're going to look for
standards you will find nothing about
TDT because it's called digital video
broadcasting and this is also born in
Europe in 94 we had the first standard
satellite and in 1960 which is
terrestrial which is what Israelis were
called the television digital
terrestrial you have millions of
standards for
4pd air those of you who cannot sleep
well it's the best thing to help you go
to sleep I won't go into the modulation
details where's my pointer
do I have a point
so those are the parameters it country
implemented in its own way we haven't
played this part with and why does that
matter
because we'll use that later as I was
saying the TV comes with those dunkers
how many of you have played with one of
those dongles they were something that
always struck me this was a manufacturer
- for TV and we've said that the
bandwidth were eight make earth but when
you go play and you put it in your
sample rate analyzer there's a limit at
three more than three makers you will
never be able to capture but the channel
is eight did you have a clue as to why
because I used to ask myself and look it
up well it's about the famous drivers
when you install you have to delete the
original drivers and in the model say
this chip has three modes the one that's
originally used that were are you to
receive eight mega ads this is the
normal TV but when we change to that
secret secret mode or engineering mode
we are limited to those who make us so
if you ask yourselves because you're
sort of in the wavelength of the SDR
if you're not into Linux ignore it a GNU
radio is the program when you want to
play without it there's a we're lucky
that there's a gentleman called Bachmann
that generated this block diagram and he
used this a weird machine with which he
could watch TV at the end it says file
see but at the bottom right he got
divided TV so it's just a little program
to watch TV on your computer but of
course manual so here you can get your
hands into this is 2013 and he did it
only for the DVP and he gave it today
GNU radio and it was included this is
digital television right you not only
have the ability so and they decided to
create it for the baby the RF as well in
his webpage
he has three articles and he said that
he needed i7 processor the bandwidth of
one channel is very wide both for
broadcasting and for receiving so it's
one of the parameters of relativity in
Spain has been customized so in each one
of them applies in each one of the faces
as you can see that's just in case
you're interested to play with out in
the future frequencies
digital television what you can see here
in this table is that many channels are
in the same frequency
that's what happens when digital
television that's was not there in the
analog television in multiplexers itself
so in the same frequency we have a lot
of channels this is did't E and you see
that there are blocks and this is
completely regulated there are royal
decrees you know that the operators took
frequencies over from TV and and this is
going to continue this will continue the
ad was lost some part of their
frequencies and this will continue and
there's others the whole regulation and
operators and government and there are
eight of them and they call them
multiple digital I don't know what is
this but these are regions that
broadcast in the whole of our country
except for the fourth one where there
are local televisions that's the ninth
block and that's how we would be told
about this on school ok
the thanks to Michael Osman he brought
about a hacker research with a utility
where you can see 320 McGarrett so you
can see all channels you know I don't
know why in my TV I can't see this
channel the best tool for
troubleshooting is this one form from
400 to the left till 800 you can see
everything there's a trick to this
you're not taking the 401 you pick them
right by life time but with this utility
you can do a sweep but without that with
the
and this is the same you can see the
nine groups organized by frequency 482
till 778 another way of looking at the
same China this is just a comment but I
don't know if it happened to you I used
to have machines in within one TV I can
see one channel and in the next one I
got none when we buy a TV and nobody
tells us what centralizer is inside here
to the left 482 there is a channel and
then at rest areas and I have a TV in
which I cannot see it because of this is
the tower that they use and there are
other TVs all machines that could not
get to those channels if you have in
different interferences look at all the
channels at the same time and finally
they seeing see issues some quarterly
reports with important information if
you want to know about the what are the
share of the different channels and how
many people are watching what program
80% are still using T DT and if you're
going to do an attack to a China there
you want to know which is the one with
the greatest share to be more successful
and I'm not encouraging anybody to do
any attacks whatsoever but this is the
place where you can see what's the the
market share of every or the public
share of every channel
I came across an article from Magnum
Aryan marijuana from 2015 at the end he
mentioned the same cases in 86 capitan
midnight interferes satellite television
HBO and this guy he was caught it was a
satellite channel in the necessary
material to broadcast what other in the
hands of everybody there were three
people who could do that so he was found
but the one at the top he's very well
known hendren he was not found these
were two broadcasts he comes up with
this mask just laughing and later on in
an episode of Doctor Who it comes up
again if you want to look at the videos
they're quite weird they're in YouTube
they talked about creepy images or
something and the more recent ones in
the Lebanon Lebanon War the satellite
there is propaganda against Hezbollah
there are other cases but they do not
see Quester the channel the Playboy
channel also a guy came in and started
selling religion religious messages and
in 2013 in Montana somebody sent a
message about zombie threat in are still
Smarties what you're going to find last
year there was an interesting talk from
Rafael and he focused on Sampson he had
two television models and he exploded
two known vulnerabilities of the
navigators one of Flash and one of
JavaScript what I didn't like about his
talk he was using a Harvard to
broadcaster that was proprietary hard
work with a window program I was struck
by this I was talking it up in that
program in window and and that Harbor
cannot be
metal with but there was a background
open sirs
so if we want to learn that's what we
want to use so how do you lose tools to
replicate he's attacked and many other
attacks that rebel do so I focused
myself on we're going to attack the
network client we're going to leave
their network in peace member 2015 there
was a very well known attack to the TV
five month which is the fourth biggest
channel in the world and the Islamic
state these are the night of service and
14 in 18 hours they brought down 11
channels they have to be synchronized
and there are many transmissions through
satellite and if you do a German or you
connect to that transport network and
you bring down a piece of equipment it's
relatively easy to have a denial of
service than by injecting our content
although there been cases of that as
well but we're going to focus on if I
were to study Smart TV to find
vulnerabilities I'm going to focus on
the clients I have my TV and I focus on
that we're going to broadcast through
radio and we'll look at the server so we
replace the whole operation with our
poor mobile computer
so first we sequester that in China
we're going to use what I've mentioned
and all the tools that we've seen the
GNU radio you are the editors producers
you can choose any video the web
government and you can reject the video
of the channel itself and we're going to
add some metadata to the channel we are
attacking we is the art that we're going
to send again the parameters that you
see at the bottom original work Network
archers deities this is regulated there
are organs there are bodies that define
which are the identifiers and we have to
use the right ones because otherwise
they will find us out so we have to
replicate the information of the China
that we're going to generate the
information is like normal channel will
generate the transports the stream and
IDs file there is an Android application
it's called aerial TV and you connect
you it's and you can watch TV there's a
JSON file when you synchronize the
channel and you have the information
there and you can pick up the
identifiers from there in Linux we have
a the same way right hand side bottom
you can look at the properties it's not
very clear here but you can see network
identifier a transport flow etc these
are the parameters that we need to take
to our to our script we generate the
transport file and we
so this is the scream we are pick to
videos you can choose whatever you want
as we've seen earlier on
by using these we're going to change the
format we're going to adapt that this is
mpg too and at the end of everything the
metadata are generated and this is
really the most important part from the
Python script there are plenty of tables
I don't want to go into detail about the
physical stuff but the transport and
stream the TS files have a number of
tables who have the is very important
this is the application information
table here we can name our channel we
can configure our own channel always
making sure that the identifier czar
those of our victim that's going to be
broadcasted then
so we're watching TV when you broadcast
and then it stops this is the injected
video
and as soon as we cut normal TV comes on
so this is a proper and right channel
sequestration but this is not all we've
attacked one TV scripted tell you love
and that's it but your organization or
large buildings only have one area and
then there are a number of cables that
distribute the signal from that area to
every home and your understand why then
I said that if we in rejecting original
video it's better because nobody knows
that they are being attacked or we can
reject it no problem I have the honor of
having a great friend who sit in a year
that has invited me to his condominium
where we let's see
he knew the community of the neighbors
we ask for permission we see when we
could do this without affecting anybody
and so on so it's and here you see the
box where the area comes in and from
their head when it was distributed
upwards in green so it was through their
four homes to aerials and then to annex
face so if we do the attack at the
beginning we're going to eject our video
to the whole of the condominium if we
want to affect only a few homes
depending on where we inject the video
it will affect a number of people
Allah is a great human being but he's
also a great body he's very tall so he
could help me by getting on top of this
Tiny's - he would reach that box in the
picture I've recorded this so that you
can see that there is no trick I'm gonna
tell you how we did this there is a
mobile in the garage he which is where
he was recording he run up the stairs
there's another mobile phone recording
and finally with the last mobile phone
I'm going to record a second television
that's why it starts late because there
were only two of us what you're going to
see is that either with his hunt will
disconnect the cable because they a
community of neighbors asked us for that
to happen for just one minute so he will
remove the cable and the signal will be
lost then he will connect the blade the
RF which is what he has in his hand the
video would be injected and then he will
disconnect and reconnect the original
and when he connects the original
although they signal they're not going
one of the TVs will have seen earlier
but when the second one comes along
they're completely synchronized that is
the evidence that I wanted to have to
prove that there's no trick here
in the audio I gotta love the free hunt
and I'm talking we're talking with each
other on the phone that's the way we
synchronized and that's also evidence
that of what really happened okay
the name of the channel will change it
says hijackin channel
so he now lives the original one and it
comes up first on the first one and you
see in the second one that they're fully
synchronized so we've taken two TVs but
as I've said sorry this was on a loop
just to tell you that what we've seen
that can affect an isolated TV obviously
that can affect a lot of a lot more
people I just want to tell you a bit
more about the evolution of the as the
our boards which weren't really boards
but it started in 2011 and the first
ones were serious hockey - and the USRP
which are the ones that both um but you
see at the beginning they're very
expensive I have the price there and
chronologically how they have evolved we
but that's not going to all that this is
how is the arts were before when both
cam was playing with the end 2010
sorry 210 it was very difficult to have
the money and the means to acquire that
we're talking about some 3,000 euros and
that's now I'm sure it was more
expensive then and this used to be
plugged so you have to plug it so
another to do this Milan it was
incredibly complex so what happened in
2018 seems that picture we've a lot of
STRs have come along and these are not
all of the available ones this is the ex
TRX from faith we're the ones that you
had a previous model and look at the
size this is it means that it has a
multiple input and output so we can
broadcast two channels at the same times
and
and receive two channels and it's the
same price so we're not talking about
the previous prices and this is the lime
Str which I will have not to use but it
got to me late look at the size of the
key holder it doesn't have me go but it
has the same chipset that the previous
one and it's incredibly cheaper this is
like $100 hundred and some and why am i
interested in me me eternal citation
what do I want it small because if
you're thinking about attacking TV and
reaching as many people as possible I
thought how easy would it be to rent a
drone we're always talking about round
round wrong yes if you're going to do an
attacker I'm not going to take my nitro
proof of concept I found a web page
where you can read them in most places
when I wrote to them they said okay we
will rent the Tron we will let you rent
out wrong but with a pilot but I wanted
it without a pilot because I am the
pilot but this is a web page where there
is a discount if it's on a weekend so I
know where to rent this drone but how
much weight can the drone carry because
in the specifications of the
manufacturers you will not find anything
about weight there are plenty of videos
in YouTube of crazy people who lifts
buckets and
water bottles to see how many kilos can
be left I don't I do not recommend it
because most of them crash I only found
this webpage what they said that the
Phantom could live 300 grams so I had to
call 300 grams whatever it is that had
to broadcast be independent and crawl
they weighed 300 grams well there are
many hours of calculations the hacker
was 300 grams the battery was a hundred
grams and the 22 it was 62 grams and
with a cover it was 300 center of
gravity because if you're going to take
this and into the drum you cannot
destabilize the electron you cannot
these things offhandedly
you have to it has to be a physics solid
solid a rigid solid and the camera I am
finding the new center of gravity so as
not to destabilize Neutron so a lot of
work but let's look at it
[Music]
so the drone is testing
[Applause]
no matter a be a traitor i I didn't dare
bring in a troll here I wanted to make
it all over I demo but I didn't dare
bring in their drone here okay I was
helped by another great friend hallo
I don't know if you have noticed but
there's another trend he had a magic he
is a professional photographer and in
order to be able to see it and for you
to see that there was no trick I don't
know if there is a mobile camera that
that's the one that goes into the house
the other way and that's the one that
records a TV after seeing how the drone
takes off so you've seen the Phantom
take off and to record the it's wrong
approach in the area we use the tripod
and he's maybe I don't know if you
notice I don't have to show it again but
if you are interested we can I could
show it again and you'll see the Mavi
that was on top of the house and that's
the one who could record how I
approached the antenna which wasn't easy
actually okay I've told you at the
beginning I don't know if you remember
the scheme about the operator and a
network when I talked about distribution
and broadcast into their homes
I've actually lied to you because there
are two broadcasting has through Network
primary and secondary the primary takes
the signal from the transport network at
what we call them a primary centers
broadcasting centers but there are
secondary centers they receive the
signal the radio signal from those
primary centers and they repeat it so a
primary center if we want to do an
attack to a primary center that's not
going to work we have to broadcast like
a satellite broadcasts or the radio link
but a repetitive as we call secondary
centers with them this attack works if
that wrong rather than X approaching the
house area of course to repair
repetitive then you would be affecting
thousands or hundreds of homes okay this
is a Channel sequestration I wanted to
show you how easy it is to do so in
television nobody's authenticating the
signal of course and do not think that
you can just do it at home you can
actually reach a lot of people what for
to broadcast video yes you can advertise
in propaganda you can reject their
original signal because you'll remember
the server if you've done the capture of
the traffic of your TV you will see that
each time you're watching TV it's making
requests to servers that I guess it's a
good practice in the domain they write
the H B BT the dot and many people get
confused by this they say number one and
two have that not only the application
of channel one and two you can view it
and it takes it the other channels have
an application as well I guess is that
what they do is that they're saving this
the fixes that they used to have to call
they are going to know and you will see
that they are regular every certain time
the TV connects itself again
and here comes the best so far we've
seen how the video was broadcasted but
in that signal we're actually sending
our own you are all so URL so we can
send the video and there you are
the other thing that's gonna change is
that interpret that item besides having
to include the identifier that we
mentioned before we have an open field
which is the you were all happy named
rooted this is our application that
doesn't have too much the anyit
serve route the IP of our server and
path the file index.html or whatever we
want so when we broadcast this video we
make the CV if it's connected to access
that URL so so far we're talking about
Hatton having fun but perhaps I want to
inject the original video into the
attack here in that way the victim will
not know their pain at hack they're
still watching TV and the URL because if
ash Rafael told us you know availability
of the TV you can exploit it kilometres
away and thousands of victims you only
need to know what TP what vulnerability
and to broadcast wherever I want to have
an impact I want to tell you before I
continue because this is going to get
even more complicated there is a
navigator within a smart TV
there is one which is HPV TV which is
automatic and with the signal that comes
through radio it's going to access that
URL which is what you have just seen but
all Smart TVs also have another
navigator which is the user navigator
when as a user you access TV you always
have one navigator which because these
TVs are designed so that you can
navigate while you're sitting
comfortably at home being hacked in and
that browser is much easier doesn't make
sense for the user browser to attack it
via ser because valve is browsing a kink
in he can check the website he wants
so the techniques we have are the usual
RP poison NS I'm joking but need to know
the Wi-Fi of the guy I need to be
connected to do that okay
he should know these are two browsers
were two different types of towns long
his remote he's an example have access
to two TVs and a lot of the fortune of
calibrating the orange last year and we
were able to see uh something here are
the two user agents this Panasonic is
wrong here the work will easier on the
user agent they have the good practice
of showing the model to my father of the
TV which is right
because if I send out my signal in
housing government the first Renault
Aachen can do we say is marked if he is
coming on the apartheid laws
I can look TVs that are watching that
channel because I'm broadcasting one or
several channels I can give each other
an IEP or a different your high so now
which model and which TV is watching
each channel with the IP public to start
with and we can given assess the
audience
neck's obviously after years playing
with captive portals I don't know but
the first unknowable you were the first
thought the first thing I thought it was
hey something you know I could have my
own application okay so even better
maybe you're thinking about house but
many companies are the entrance other
places to look cool they have a video
wall or very cool 40 million in TV or
calcium some sort of corporate video so
that whenever there are visits
oh what a cool company it's a great film
or a great video but now they're not
watching TV so bro Carson TV that
doesn't make much sense here we have a
dryer that I'll put on the wrong these
cannot be done on the raspberry the CPU
doesn't the holidays it's got a small
bathroom here we have the hawk RF if you
want TV to be seen properly with a good
quality your fault radio you cannot get
directly with an antenna cable I've got
this cable because these TV has the plug
looking downwards otherwise is between
your top you leave that you plug in to
the antenna you go away
I think these costs about 200 euros
while the hawk RC is a bit more classy
might be 300 euros is a mountain that
aside you back anyway cannot be sue the
TV
I can't believe watcher this is the
normal TV is not connected I didn't know
we were gonna have the signal here but
we are closed to tell him into it okay
great so you're gonna ever see better I
didn't think you you'd be able to see
well he's my attacker that was supposed
to be blocking her leave disconnected he
has a self start hope do not take too
long
this and this would many companies half
my company's is playing its my video to
give it in many places and in many areas
there they won't realize and the real
attack this will they usually have on a
video wall so you can you already want
that really okay
what I meant it
oceanography Ladell exterminate up just
give me a second tell the TV that is
connected through the cable maybe will
complain because of lack of the Internet
okay have you seen that the application
just loaded on I told you he was
connected it was off earlier and it's
lovely navigator is the HP B TV is
rendered my HTML page this has been done
on the purpose and he's got the booted
Lago he's a usual captive portal if you
change that logo by the manufacturer and
you work on a nature like hey this has
been updated and use an outer form can
you please confirm your Wi-Fi name in
the world update it so you have a word T
Kibo you can move these buttons there
you go
when you accept it's a basic you can see
it here
you have that file
and here you have what the user replied
to the phone you see it well
Valley in SF Ichiro configuration
setting low Yama so-called these final
configuration settings I wanted I wanted
something in these forms on Europe ash a
browser you have the IP the TV and the
Wi-Fi in a very simple way is the usual
classic social engineering
a monkey lover
I thought a keylogger attack could be
bung-bung HPB TV the guys watching TV is
gonna not gonna keying anything I didn't
seat for the use of browsers if the guy
is browsing at home doing whatever
whatever he writes is a JavaScript you
can inject it and we'll see it later you
may inject it
here we have a keylogger so everything
they press our sword on that text file
they go to browser they're using a
newspapers website and the what the TV
reads the website uses if it wasn't a
smart or multimedia enough and if you
want to watch some of these Emma or
something silly there's no problem
there's not to change them so I'm
showing it to the video and on the X in
the taxi later you have all the keys on
the codes this is quite limited but here
you may see the proof of concept and see
that the keylogger is actually working
and it just needs to be adapted to the
standard okay so this is going in a loop
but you just need to send it to the HPV
TV Santa to use need to mark the keys
and it's super simple to use not need to
know the code and a text file you have
all the keys at the guy house breast and
what else well likely we see loads of
cryptocurrency mining and this also
loaded on websites and TVs read websites
that was a JavaScript looks like it
doesn't it
okay so you took quite a bit quite a
while I've use it echoing anyway this
guy he's a simple we the most basic one
and after all the attacks and all these
things but now the ultrasound is not
working there's a flood I'm JavaScript
through to my not much but it doesn't
work the first time the user needs to go
to start mining do you accept that
you're gonna mind recurrences and think
it's mines so I just wanted to check on
the city on the Panasonic these wouldn't
work it was a steam variations they'll
go the JavaScript from one of those
attacks where the code is really
modified to have ultrasound ourselves
it's not
ultrasonic maybe to do web sockets but
what I see the the source code there is
a first stage
Kinesis in the Attic so yes I'm the
wizard culture first of all he loves the
applet perfectly he establishes the HTTP
connection with your flyer next with
navigator when it comes to creating the
WebSocket on this DVD stays there
and these are service IP here are the
first HTTP negotiations there it is last
the last thing that I think made sense
was Matt exploit right if you want to
research vulnerabilities and look at
those now browsers seriously we have
beef with met exploit same thing does
make sense retrieve eh will be TV or the
user I think makes more time to talk
both or might be more interested in
checking out the results on the user's
browser I'm using better cop then Ong
better cop between Jack JavaScript one
day using injecting one of those in
website I hooked a navigator browser we
have a JavaScript code we have a better
cop who my computer and the TV the beef
with Matt exploit and he's just writing
we just want to be actually
and it actually hooks the browser knew
who browser there are the details and we
send an invisible e frame with the met
exploit sought easily the browser auto
Punk I have the URL of the medics bodies
working for and I put that on the frame
and copy it
we hook it command we create an
invisible frame we're seeing a deceit
does video and when we send a frame to
now to the browser much as blog begins
work him
okay so it's that conclusion a few years
ago when we all have fun we didn't care
about the approaching system in care
could be an Ericsson and okay are you
use had a phone mobile device right now
we don't really care about the operating
system of the phone we all the browser
it has because we know all the
vulnerabilities
I came to phone when they became as
marked and nothing the same thing is
happening to TVs but no one is talking
about that and that's when you go to my
TV maybe you don't care about inches
I've mentioned and there's no operating
systems are several and here are the two
TVs of my dear Anonymous
these are the two TVs I could check with
the results of those at ours which
operating system and each browser we
made how may have different results so
the attacks we've seen are local they
focused on the fact that you could audit
your Smart TV so instead of doing those
attacks on our TV if we do them on the
web server so that we seem for each
operator they're actually compromising
many TVs and those webs there will have
vulnerability so that no one can carry
out that type of dark
and just gives me a bit of time our part
on the github repository the only thing
you need is again your radio 3.7 one and
your ass your device as well as your
Smart TV and this is all from me thank
you
excuse me what you don't have time for
questions so you can ask him things
outside while you have a snack thank you
thank you
[Music]