I've routed dot-com by the way we are
delighted to be here this is a beautiful
event so will not open time for a debate
reservists against cyberattacks
patriotic collaboration to state costs
as you probably know a few months ago an
initiative was published in the press
at that time it was assumed that it was
the popular party in Spain came up with
the initiative to organize a group of
cyber reservists and that's how they
were called to be honest the details and
our initiative we don't know anything
about yet this is in a very early stage
okay in other countries they've been
doing they've been doing these things
for quite some time but anyway this has
hit the headlines several times
on whether they should there should be a
fee of whether these people should get
money in exchange for the services how
they should be organized
what sort of duties they should carry
out and so on and so forth so in order
to talk about this topic we have
organized this roundtable and we have a
number of exceptional guests in our
medical order Rahman has reminded me to
do so Adolfo Fernandez in the red jumper
co-founder of cybersecurity is a
think-tank is an extraordinary
professional course computer science
degree from the Autonomous University of
Madrid a very experienced professional
with very good criteria in his work we
also have another exceptional guest in
Medina he is a two-star general in the
Cyber Command of Spain what could we say
about him he is the first commander in
chief of the Spanish Cyber Command
together with his excellent team of
collaborators he is right there in the
middle of the storm and collaborating
with that project he will give us his
opinion we also have every cabbie
laughter director of the national
excellence center of the Autonomous
University in Madrid also a specialist
in this field I am NOT a civil guard
myself so miembro I'm a member of the IT
division in the Spanish government I'm
sorry but sorry about that but I know
you are a great supporter of this
initiative on cyber reservists we have
another guest good afternoon
he is his lieutenant colonel in the
Spanish army and in charge of the
National cryptology center of the
Spanish government and also an
exceptional cryptologist himself a
long-standing track record and then we
have mr. Jorge Davila good afternoon
Jorge Jorge Nabila is a senior lecturer
at the informatics faculty in the
Complutense University of Madrid he has
been working on cyber security for a
long time he leads he's in charge of
they keep ecology laboratory in that
University
he's also an instructor in this field
it carries out assessments for people
working in this field and last but not
least we have ROM and Ramirez he was
co-founder a member of the leading team
that Kahn a wise man someone that knows
a lot about these things
and let me introduce you to my colleague
miss Fernandez who is the editor of the
SiC magazine he will be moderating this
debate with me
we have agreed to have all of them
speaking very briefly for three or four
minutes to tell us about the initiative
what's hyper reservists and by the way
let me introduce a minor change I think
the first person that should speak is
Carlos the general I think you're the
most suitable panelists to tell us where
we are where we stand and based on your
comments define the scope this is a
first surprise good afternoon everyone
I hope you can hear me it is a pleasure
to be here with all of you I'll be using
my time we known as you give you some
context some references these are my
ideas by the way okay this is my opinion
and the most interesting thing here I'm
sure will be the debate itself
the concept of cypher yourself I like it
it's a good idea without its
difficulties no without its challenges
of course in order to ensure that it is
effective and useful we need to ensure
that it is properly organized the first
thing I'll do is to perhaps change the
title for this round table so that I can
convey the first message it's dead off
or first Simon reservists against
cyberattacks patriotic collaboration to
save costs I would suggest another title
which is similar reservists against
cyberattacks patriotic collaboration in
case of crisis that's how I would choose
my title three aspects I would like to
focus on first of all what do we need
that cyber reserved for secondly how we
could organize such a thing and finally
how we would pay the cyber reservists
I'll be very brief I'll just give you
the key elements in my opinion so why do
we need the same of reserve to start
with it is very important to be aware of
a fact this cyber reserve is not a
replacement for resources that must be
there on a permanent basis there are
resources I'm not going to tell you
about the size there is a set of
resources that must be there all the
time
cyber the cyber retire from my point of
view is a complement to those resources
in case of a crisis
so this is not for daily duties or daily
operations this is to account for
extraordinary events those events for
which existing resources are not enough
or are not suitable no need to say that
in order to ensure that the cyber
reserve is effective especially in cases
a crisis hits when almost nothing works
it is essential it is essential to be
trained during so-called normal periods
so that's the answer to the question why
do we need decided reserve how can we
organize this allow me to say from my
point of view a hybrid approach is the
best approach part of the cyber reserved
would be comprised of professional
military personnel and part of the cyber
reserve would be civilians some ideas
from me in a few minutes you know for
well the cyberspace is all about
operations ok it's the fifth domain in
operations what do we do we plan we lead
and we execute operations in cyberspace
when talking about executing operations
I would use cyber reservists who are
military personnel for the rest it
doesn't really matter whether the
military personnel or civilians for
everything else there is a huge area
when we talk about military and civilian
reservists we need to ensure that all of
them have the corresponding security
accreditation at different levels
depending on their profiles and then
talking about military and civilian
personnel we need several things we need
to meet several requirements we need a
recruitment process in place we need a
training period we need an activation
whenever a corresponds and a regular
updating of the training they receive
for those of you who know about the
voluntary cyber reservists in the Armed
Forces the differences are and must
indeed be very big wines because
the physical abilities are not very
important not very sensual the services
to be delivered by other reservists
could be delivered online they don't
necessarily have to be there physically
the training period will extend for a
shorter duration and the activation
procedure would be much quicker just to
give you a hint on the basic differences
how would we organize a cyber reserve I
know it may sound obvious but we need to
do this in a progressive manner
step-by-step we would define an initial
call of specialists we would define a
basic set of procedures will then
validate those procedures and that would
allow us to grow in an orderly manner
and last but not least how we pay how
was the compensate deciphers reservists
I'm not contemplating really either we
would pay them a salary and obviously we
cannot expect that we can compete with
private companies head-on some food for
thought for me what could we do for the
compensations were obviously covering
their expenses and covering many other
things and I think there are many
potential things where we're good that
we could use to compensate them for
example through trainings what I want to
make really clear is that from my point
of view it doesn't make any sense to
include cyber reservists in our armed
forces as personnel thank you so much
thank you Carlos
so we now go back to the initial order
so first of all I would like to thank
the organizers for letting us share this
space I'll be very brief and the things
I will mention will relate to what I was
mentioned two years ago along the lines
of the comments made better general we
from from cyber don't want to take full
credit for opening a debate on this but
back then in 2014 in April 2014 we
started talking about the initiatives
and cyber reserves in other country
especially within NATO we came up with
our own model for Simon Fuller cyber
reserve we believed that there was
necessary
I have to say we have stuck to the same
idea we came up with back then in 2014
he had to be a non military or a pillow
or not a purely military cyber reserve
we have analyzed where they've done in
estonia bestonia is a very peculiar
country a very small country
sometimes success in other countries can
not be extrapolated directly to our
reality we have analyzed the situation
in France and the UK in Israel in the
u.s. these are very different cases and
you cannot expect to extrapolate them
directly those initiatives in those
countries are in the early stages so we
don't know yet we don't have any
indicators to know whether they've been
successful France is one of our major
neighbours the French have a different
degree of maturity so we don't know yet
but we have seen failures keys to
failing in those approaches and we've
seen that a fully military approach to
cyber reserves it's a mistake so we are
not talking about technical profiles we
are talking about different profiles
across operating this approach so
therefore what we propose we propose to
each and every one of you is to create
something of our own
based on Spanish reality based on the
model of morality that we have in this
country considering the level of
confrontation in the public
administrations so therefore now that
this has gained some momentum and this
has been widely I was strongly catalyzed
because of that's here because of wanna
cry and it has also gained some
political momentum which is different to
the taking our time and deciding what to
do I'd like to launch a question to all
of you are we in the right time - yeah
we believe we strongly believe that we
need a cyber reserve but not at any cost
not at any expense because this is a one
bullet game and then if we can waste our
game because at the end of the day these
reserves it's a voluntary
from all of us so we just don't want you
to make a mistake and to get it wrong so
with this I mean that everyone should be
in line political forces the
administration and the cyber reservists
we should all be aligned in this project
and brick' please good afternoon
everyone
thank you for giving us the opportunity
to share part of this story with you
story there has been in the media and
because of that has created confusion
and especially to those of us who carry
out our activities in the cyberspace so
it is known as resurface strategy of
talents in cyber defense and cyber
security this is not a minor idea that
four people came to us about drinking
beer so highly qualified people have
been working on this idea for many years
and they have operational and tactical
and strategic experience in this matter
why did we decide to present this
regulatory aspects well I'll give you
good news our democracy sometimes works
so we thought that it was the right time
and the right place to do it we say we
either do it now or never
at any cost no of course not not at any
cost but at a cost we are ready to pay
for and then assuming that in the
cyberspace domain we you have to make
mistakes you have to make mistakes and
you have to put tools in place to make
progress as fun as possible this is the
same as businesses if I create a
wonderful poster and this is being sold
on Amazon the main research on the US
then local government
the success of my poster Oh front page
and they are copying it and doing the
same thing okay they are being
prosecuted investigated for tasks so
this is what we believe why we believe
that this is the right time and place
for us to do it I'm going to learn to
this question two questions so the
states as long as we want to keep that
up and as long as there is no
alternative cannot compete in a global
market of talents so we cannot access
not even by law so that market of
talents and we have talent resources but
they are also in the market
my professional salary is published in
the Official Gazette and does not match
up with the salary that is being paid to
colleague working in the private
industry so my question is how can we
attract first level specialized talent
because we are talking about multiple
discipline talent multidisciplinary
talents
so this cyberspace is multi-dimensional
and we have to assume it as such and the
same as our national defense strategy
security strategy says we have to defend
it and we'll have to defend it with all
the weapons available to us as long as
we want to defend it so that's my first
question and the second question is
about the need that we as a civil
society participate in the defense of
our nation
as our Constitution reads our
Constitution is there for us to use it
and to collaborate with it and it is
also a good
traction allowing civil society to
participate in the defense through
preservation and through the strategic
reserves reserve of talents so these are
the two conditions that we took into
account when we developed regulatory
text and we selected the Seavey's of how
well that we thought that were feeling
and put it forward to the political
groups that were willing to sit down
with us so as I say they told us they
directed us to the party in government
if you really want to have success when
you launch a standard a regulation you
have to address the political party in
government so this is not a party
oriented initiative but we just thought
that it was the right time the right
place to do it the people who
participated in the project and great
experts in this matter and I'd like to
clarify on the following point so we
have asked for the necessary resources
to bring it forward because in this
country we tend to make policies okay
with clause that says with no cost
increase or with no expense increase
because all the public policies have
associate cost associated to them and
expense associated to it and it is true
and we are aware of it and hopefully it
will come out in the following debate
that I hope they will be very lively so
these processes of problems of
coordination and
problems because we are embarking or
going into an export territory we didn't
do that before we are going to make
mistakes and we're going to learn from
our mistakes not making mistakes in the
cyberspace it's a risk and as well as a
threat so thank you very much
hello good afternoon drawing on what all
these speakers I mentioned I also would
like to change the title of this
proposal as general said reservists what
I would have changed would have liked to
change the name and to say volunteers
not a silver cost per volunteers who get
money and reward whenever they fulfill
their mission but they accomplish their
mission if we do not comply there if we
do not fulfill that promise we will not
get anywhere we will not reach our
destination the second point that I
would like to mention is that I disagree
with has been said that this is not a
one bullet shot we have to grow
exponentially or vertically we have to
start off with a core we have to gain
experience and we have to take it from
there and to keep growing as general
mentioned the objective of cyber reserve
is to identify silent if people people
with expertise in some capabilities but
it is cyberattacks have defense forensic
analysis reverse engineering to hire
them and to hire them whenever we need
them and to hire them on a flexible
basis because these people will have to
feed themselves and they will have to
press family and we will want to not to
forget about that so I see some lack of
maturity nowadays
in terms of the horizontal services that
are being provided by the government so
to absorb these cyber reserves and to
use it properly I think we need places
for these people to sit down and
profiles that we can apply most of these
cyber security services are based in
departments by this and we will have
horizontal services of cyber security
not only Madrid but also in the bridges
of his pain surely will be of will be
more widely implemented so haha now you
have the floor good afternoon everyone
I will try to change the discourse
slightly I would like to start off by
separating cyber defence from cyber
decide so we have organized groups
shooting everything walking dead model
and some white supremacists from Ohio
then the second mode George Bush and
Cheney and colleagues am going to set up
a war I'm going to outsource it and to
make money out of the Iraq war the
Americans put the money and the attack
is put their life and then the third
mode which is more European Swiss model
more civilized world is they admit that
at some occasions sometimes may need
citizens to defend the equity the
structures the values that are shared by
all and then these people are mobilized
well the out of the three movements the
most civilized one is the third one
that is to say if needed people will be
mobilized externalizing defense that is
to say to pay the free prices of the
market will lead to black border to
Cheney set up and then the first model
of shooting everything around you will
demolish will end up with everything in
few more minutes so therefore there is
not much choice and then there comes a
time that we've we have to well if there
is need to use the reserve perhaps that
reserve will not be this will not be
something that voluntary so I don't
really see the temporarily given to this
if this is necessary especially this
time of crisis so reservists produce
whenever Katrina took a toll on so many
people where we need reservists to come
back to normality as soon as possible
but in cyberspace to turn to things like
that I just don't need thousand men
unless but to stop any attack so defense
is proactive it's not reactive what is
reactive attack is reactive and now let
us move on to the second part that I
announced cyberattack so in a democratic
system cyberattack has been transferred
to a very specific characters without
the Armed Forces
and then in this case is civilians do
not really make sense services man wants
to push the red button it is his
responsibility
none of us and not allowed by the
Constitution to think about that second
characteristics and I said well they
cannot has manufactured this attack no
no no no deaths are known as weapon
manufacturers if you want to set up a
place such as haka team and then to put
in the market digital weapons you will
be treated as an individual who is
manufacturing missiles they are closely
monitored they paid enough lots of money
and then that's it so if we do that we
have not invented absolutely anything
so actually reserved ISM does not really
fit in to me in the digital world in the
digital world I just don't understand I
don't understand reservists
okay so the debate was not started yet
so number one
when I was more hostile than I am now
actually I very much like Carlos
arguments because I understood since
that perhaps was not understanding
before I'm going to ask you a question
are you aware of Westphalia peace do you
know how the modern democratic order
works so you will know who has the
capacity to access power outside the
borders of the countries and within the
borders of the country DARPA scientists
European countries were tired of killing
each other
they decided to set up rules to build a
modern state I would like to launch an
open question if you are in the street
and then proper as actually with the
knife so who do you think do you think
that the law enforcement agencies are to
defend you when that happens to you if
you are do your staircase and you are
drunk and then someone tries to steal
your water from you who do you think
should be responsible to defend you
press your hands up sue think that law
enforcement ideally should do that if
there is a wall and people are to be
sent to Afghanistan who should go to
Afghanistan raise your hands or to think
that these are the military okay
and now why in the case of Salva we
companies and citizens have to do that
why law enforcement agencies are not
defending me against cyber attacks made
by individual profits individual wine no
the military are not defending me in the
case of cyber war and why private
companies or private individuals will
have to do that and the question what
the hell civilians doing in military or
no enforcement of policy environment so
creating this figure has a dangerous
consequence that is to say to open up
the door to the abuse of the capacities
and the talent that you have for on the
part of people who have a very specific
function and
respect them you know what who a comrade
is do you know how can you address a
person as a comrade you can only say
comrade to a person who has been
shooting in war on your behalf
has been there like in a battle with you
so to me the military and the forces of
the state are my comrades because they
are fighting in the cyber domain and
actually but I very much respect this
function so we have to spoil the
military function the police function by
having in turn doing black ops dual
agencies will have free service for
black operations for intelligence
operations we will have reservists in
the legal side military lawyers will be
supported by a private law firm this is
very complex and I absolutely share what
El busto said this is a one-shot game
how many of you will go happily to
Afghanistan to be charged now for Spain
raise your hand so you are facing a
cultural issue of this country so I
don't believe in the concept of flag and
of Patras so I want to defend my
neighborhood I want my children to have
good jobs and if that entails taking a
project from US companies I will do it
that has nothing to do with me patriot
but it has to do with defending your
community because as we are here to die
defending a community the reservists
collaboration first of all you have to
convince these people like a thousand
people to collaborate in many other
things under the concept of
community instead of the country and how
are we going to compensate companies how
are you going to compensate companies
for for instance if you've had I belong
in SIA is it's also good idea to
volunteer for 3 months ok to go away for
3 months how are you going to compensate
and reward companies for that
okay so do you have hurt everyone so I
don't know whether you are sitting on
the right bench no no this is not a
clash so this is something which is very
important which is known as generating
collective intelligence so all the ideas
that can be put on the table already
valuable supper actually the only thing
that is not valid is to put on the table
destructive ideas without providing an
alternative solution are you telling
that on me none of them is saying that
are you so on and saying if actually if
everyone assumes that there is a threat
so we will have to put on the table
solutions possible solutions or
solutions we can think of but but to
open up this debate this dialogue what
is the threat we don't have enough
talent to support the military cyber
defense is there a shortage of talents
so what we have reserved so in the open
question that I asked in the beginning
is includes part of the problem that
being do we have enough talent there is
never enough talent is it necessary or
could we understood that this could be
the backbone of the cyber defense of our
nation not at all no one has said that
actually general was very clear about
that this would only work in crisis
situations crisis situations in the
cyber space are of different nature may
be of different nature they may unfold
over time and moreover if we assume that
we will find lots of black stones
because it is a black about black swans
so only if a given point in time you
know what their talent is you will be in
a position to give a response this is my
view
this may be their this may be will
develop some we have most likely to make
to get it wrong but it is best to get it
wrong to learn from this and to reassess
what we did and that perhaps with a
llamas to give the right response in the
face of a crisis situation general would
you like to say something
well I'd like to say two things starting
off by what we mentioned last I have to
make mistake of course we have to make
mistakes undoubtedly but we have to make
mistakes in a controlled manner we
cannot make mistakes in a irreversible
manner
this is a process for having an
initiative checking that that initiative
whether the initiative works or not if
it works we move ahead we move on and if
not we corrected but I insist in a
controlled manner
so I'd like someone from the public to
clarify for me these exceptional
situations that would require bring it
together all the silence in this country
I'm against it oh actually I don't feel
that this is a battle of some black
swans this is take out silent contest
this is not about who's got the biggest
hacker that if I have something which is
not working please do not use it so
defense is a different thing attack is
about who's got biggest muscle defense
is should be proactive we have to make
our systems being defensible and you
don't achieve that overnight this is the
result of long-standing and sustained
activity so there could be exceptions in
the attacks so for instance if we are
talking about taking out our attack
talents to launch the other attack
talents okay I just withdraw because I
don't like tv5 the Spanish TV 5 channel
when we were putting together as we
approach of this session
the rider responds so what was desired I
just want to focus on the second part
patriotic elaboration to save costs I'd
like to ask question to Carlos in
representation of the ministry for
defence Navi Araz representative of the
public administration which is the
following Spain
has enough resources and capabilities to
face up to the challenges of the 21st
century or perhaps Spain doesn't have
those resources and perhaps may have to
use additional arguments to kind of
offset that lack of resources that was
shown the fact that now says well we
don't have a cybersecurity Center for
the general administration of the state
of resisted the bread distribution or
reallocation of the Ministry of Defense
in all the its demand in the 21st
century your competence
it is infra served or underserved do we
have enough resources if we have enough
resources perhaps with the near
volunteers where we really have it we
see the subterfuge or not
I'd like to answer
well there is never enough okay we never
have enough it is true but we can say if
we cannot just really go to a maximum
policy could have faced up to any thing
that may happen but we cannot just stay
or keep a minimum policy that would not
allow us to respond to anything so the
way I see it is like to have some
resources on stuff resolving a high
percentage high number of situations and
then if we go to extreme situations to
face up to touch the screen situations
it is anti-economic that's when I are
ringing with the title it is not it goes
against economy to have all those
resources on our stuff ok so this is my
idea
so I don't think it is a question of
resources I stayed has budget and we
depend on that budget and then what we
have to do is just to see what do we
want to invest the third party around so
when everyone says that cyber threat is
very important but perhaps the budget is
being spent somewhere else
I tell would like to talk about so I'd
like to say something so I don't see
that situation for crisis situation what
happens with wanna cry we all call
people over Friday and then on Sunday
things are over so I have to work with
whatever it's available to me so cyber
reserves is a procedure to detect
silence and where the administration can
select these people and invite them to
say and I'm going to go I will go
against Roman and I will tell him that
there are many people that do many
things for the nation do many things for
in Spain and France they are ready to
spend to devote two or three months of
their life so that we can assess the
capability their skills and to listen to
the offer that we make to them it's not
a question of resources state has those
resources but it is true that we have to
be able to what those who have to ask me
those newly priority people we just want
to detect him best profiles for that
general gave an example I agree if
another one so regarding stretched
vulnerability
so we had many trouble in many entities
and we would have needed people experts
with in Linux Apache service helping the
public service to go back to operation
so this is an example if we had those
profiles identified we could have used
them we are not we were not humming a
company's because that took place in the
weekends but anyway we had to reward
them for having given us those
additional hours of work ok I answer and
certain of with the strats it's truth so
some people here detected vulnerable
sites to the administration they
reported it through routed and through
other well through civil cards and that
works and it is already up and running
do we need that to be regulated for any
politician to have a place in the Senate
oh sorry I said that out loud and I just
had it on my mind so you are talking
about reporting vulnerabilities we have
that already okay we have whenever it is
reported through very many different
channels yes but the problem is going
there and fixing that vulnerability but
don't you think the administration
should have qualified people supported
the system paying them a bright salary
decent salary perman happens when the
crisis comes in and then the problem
arrives and then you need you have a
shortage of hands and as I say if you
don't have those hands available as
confessor we just recruit them on a
voluntary basis and we will pay them
good money well we just would like to
clarify what you want a reservist for
for defense if caucus that are before if
that will have to do lots of
preventative security you have to train
them beforehand but if you are talking
about identifying talent talent in work
in
King into fire firewall rules were
exploiting us Danny another we talk
about ROP that is not offensive that is
offensive and though they saw a trend on
a party committees and if we talk about
that I find that really are setting in
terms of the relationship between the
military and the private world the world
of private companies which is
mercenaries reservists will not spend
four months investigating exploits
that's impossible and you know that
perfectly well at the end of the day
we'll have to find companies of that
type because the military I respect and
I admire them because they have a
commitment or with my country when the
mercenaries my feelings are not the same
so be aware of that mercenaries
time goes by and I would like to take
the opportunity to ask for examples on
how the cyber reserve us it has been
posed in Spain it is actually it is
currently a draft the draft law how that
could be articulated with you but the
companies and with the government of
Spain this is just an exercise that we
are on the same page and we understand
exactly what this all means there is
this misleading interpretation the main
goal for this act as a reserve is not
hiring it's not recruiting people to
launch cyber attacks the cyber reserve
will be active at times of war under
times of peace at times of peace they
will be operational support basically
so if you're expecting to join the cyber
reserve to launch a DDoS attack on North
Korea forget about it can you give us
examples those things that of cases
you've seen in recent months about how
this hard Cyber Reserve should be
activated could be activated have you
heard about an events that could we
could use as lessons learned
oh man by the way let me tell the
audience please go ahead with your
questions okay okay with panic cry a lot
for do you remember the involvement in
the Spanish government the set up record
and they set up a coordination team and
I don't mean the CCN that was working
hard from 9:00 in the morning on that
day but remember who is pushing for that
Rapid Response Team there was no one
there was no one there we had to call
upon primary individuals so that they
could form a group the only contacts the
only call I got from the public
administration was a phone call to ask
me were they happy to get happy about
whatever had been impacted this was
through a telegram group believe it or
not it was it's a bit sad we have some
questions already
I'm the mercenary Roman is afraid of I
descend from several people that have
been working on weapon development at
Santa Barbara the National weapon
company have seen all sorts of things
there's two things you mentioned talent
retention and cost savings one of the
worst things I always saw in my military
career is that you reward a nice time
better than Talent why are you not doing
anything to change that and on
cost-savings the army works with many
different private companies with tallies
with intra military with a pass defense
and space GFI and many others and I see
the in many of these companies some
people come from the ministry and are
appointed in very high positions we also
have a miss miss hospitals husband
working as a CEO at amber so instead of
rewarding nice ties how about talent
retention and cost savings so that we
have enough budget for the side reserve
thank you
was that a question or was that a
declaration of intention or a statement
I didn't understand the question since
I'm also in public office I don't hold a
high position and no one in government
I'm very proud of what I do but I don't
I don't hold high positions I work for
you amongst others with a nice tie I
didn't understand the question if this
is a political forum I would agree with
that but I don't think we were talking
about that because if we manipulate if
we mislead people when talking about
these subjects we'll get into something
which is very special very unique in
Spain
which is that attitude let us attack any
ideas without offering alternatives
because some things are not working if
you and I go for a beer in a while you
will see that not only I agree with what
you said but probably I have more
radical than you are but we were not
talking about that we were not talking
about that we were talking about
professional careers I work for the
Civil Guard professional careers the
civil guard are not suitable for the
21st century we're working on it yes
talent detection programs within the
civil guard that was never done in the
past we've been forced by circumstances
to do those detect talent inside there
are certain people in the civil guard
that are not holding the positions they
should be in because of their talent and
their abilities this is their dynamic
thing and we are adapting ourselves to
them and we are moving into a new domain
we are exploring we're exploring a new
domain which has nothing to do with
territories which is very dynamic in by
nature the subtlety in decision-making
processes this is technical not
political Roman politicians serve the
state some serve the state unless you
don't want to state unless you don't
want to form of democracy in that case
forget about it but politicians in
general do serve their country if this
is a political forum let's talk about
politics but we're not talking about
politics here we're talking about
whether there is a need to have public
policies in place which will give us
access to certain talent profile so and
by the way let us look beyond that
because maybe just maybe we could use
source certain tools for what we call
the positive externalities I see very
few women in this forum how about
setting up groups
multidisciplinary talented groups to
favor STEM abilities or STEM skills that
could be generated by something like
cyber defense or perhaps setting of
cyber multidisciplinary teams which
would produce a positive impact on our
economy
wiebe says Martha we have been training
the best cohorts of university students
in the last 50 years in Spain and
allowed them to leave because you were
champions among champions after
investing a huge amount of resources in
training the past generations ever in
the history of Spain we've allowed them
to go abroad to work for other people to
work for other countries sorry
general do you want to say something
well what I would ask is that we stick
to the subject and I think this is some
it is worth that we focus on the topic
we could talk about difficulties in any
area in the world but we've come here to
talk about the title let me tell you
from my point of view from my
responsibilities I'm buying away I think
the opportunity to respond to a question
that was posed before how do we make
that talent toil how do we attract that
talent and make it loyal towards our
mission ambition how about forgetting
those rewards for nice ties going back
to the question you posed well my
experience my personal experience which
can be a great tool I think tells me
that this has to make sense people must
understand that this makes sense we must
reach that reach their hearts secondly
they need to feel that whatever they do
with us is attractive that whatever they
do with us
convinces them that they're using their
time in a wife manner
the third element would be creating a
wonderful environment for them to work
in money is not the most important thing
as I said before if we have the ability
to put that into practice and this is
something I'll I experienced myself all
the time
our potential for success will be very
reasonable I agree completely with you
and I can assure you that they don't
move because of money that is not the
main driver for what they do I'm talking
about respect towards our profession if
you don't allocate the necessary
resources and you expect them to
compensate for a number of limitations
I'm not saying you have limitations I
don't know how you are like allocating
your budgets internally it is not that
they want to have a higher salary if you
give them eighteen thousand a year
you're insulting them I'm not working
for you for eighteen thousand a year
because there is a lack of respect I
have a friend of mine who is a waitress
that makes three thousand five hundred a
month and these guys were always reading
and updating their knowledge our
guessing offers at that level respect
first of all and Rika said it's very
expensive to train talent to let them go
away after the trained well perhaps
because setting up the cyber reserve all
of us here should push our government
and not democracy you mentioned so that
the government does its best to ensure
that they pay reasonable salaries to
those they employ and that would be step
zero before you turn your story about
whether I should be a cyber reservist or
not treat me with respect I think that
is a summary of what most people feel
we have a question good evening my
question relates to costs for companies
and the availability of potential
reservists for example I can go through
the website I can check the alert level
which is very high in terms of terrorism
for example and I'm sure there's a
strategy behind the scenes will you
consider the cyber reservists that are
already available
how much availability are you thinking
about because there is a clear cost here
for companies and for people do they
need to be available at any point in
time
because they have their lives have you
thought about that in detail thank you
so much
please yes
now we have a question over there
another one I was there and then the
third one
thank you
but first of all I would like to
congratulate the panelists and the
organizers I'll mention you my my two
cents based on my own experience I met
someone some time ago that works for one
of these modern armies that has the
cyber reserve he had a position in the
army and he was working for a private
company at the same time at the same
time so two situations we talked about
that will become my questions one which
is purely operational this person would
disappear for three weeks without
explaining anything and projects would
become impossible with him it's not just
the money what what sort of rules must
be defined for that game when people can
be caused by government at any point in
time and then in the depending on the
nature of the company they may have
access to data which may be very
sensitive data which may be very
attractive for intelligence services
from other countries from other
companies
do you want to wait until the end of
those questions or right okay the next
one at the top
just bear with us for a second
hello my name is Jose Manuel
my opinion this is not the best point in
time to set up a cyber reserve so I have
two questions this has nothing to do
with cost savings why can't a state in
Spain attract talent and then another
question for the general why are we
working on a cyber reserve before
setting up a proper cyber defense unit
within the army
well some things are taking for granted
anyway if you allow me I'll respond to
the last question that is not true that
is not true as always we are focusing on
achieving certain levels in everything
we do as we see as we see it we believe
that having an additional resource the
same reserve is a good idea what I
wouldn't support I would never support
is that that cyber reserve could act as
a replacement for some of the resources
we already have in place I think I made
that point very clear
so then examples for many of you so
answering to two questions I am exactly
the same questions our colleague had ok
same questions same questions exactly as
far as I know okay don't take this for
granted the fact that you belong to a
cyber reserve in a certain country could
prevent other countries from hiring you
or certain companies from hiring you for
example in the UK the British are very
clear they want technical profiles there
were technical profiles with knowledge
on databases that sucessful days their
eligibility criteria in the French model
was the same thing they don't go so much
into the technical things you have to be
a French citizen free of a criminal
record and then this issue of security
accreditation which is a sensitive issue
as you can imagine okay let me give you
an example which is right is a
relatively recent perhaps we are
thinking we are assuming that the cyber
reserve because it is part of the
military approach as a reservist by the
way I want to support my government and
not just the army on the military I want
to support government in general and I
wonder if that is a suitable approach
there is a national layout for the
security of the country I think that it
is a mistake that this is led by one of
the stakeholders in that scheme because
this has failed in other countries
that is my opinion so as someone working
for a private company let me tell you
what other countries are doing they have
details for employees for employers well
as a company I hire a guy who is going
to be trained by the state with public
money and to be honest I'm not sure that
person will be trained in something
relevant for what we do in our company
and the second thing is the question
posed by a colleague I know that they
have 22 days of holidays every year
class between 17 and 29 days of training
every year just like the British have
let me go back to the issue of wanna cry
I mean straights our global sometimes
they target the Ministry of Defence and
sometimes to target the entire public
system I remember those days in Lyon
remember that
Rahmon we didn't have enough people
there
and
we need to have people to do all sorts
of things and we didn't have in our
hands suddenly eight of the people that
were working with me
Simon reservists were called remember
the situation I do believe in cyber
reserve but have doubts in how to apply
that concept practically this is not
about being patriotic we're a very
special country in other countries I've
seen beautiful examples here I have
danced I'd love to have ideas from any
of you I have danced and I have to apply
all of these concepts practically how
thoughtful you're an expert do they have
for the tears in China today in China
have something beautiful which is called
democracy and CNN you cannot even find
that in any browsing engine in the
search engine
thank you so much first of all there's a
question from me how do we retain that
talent I've heard several people today
saying that we learn talent escape
it seems that talent is going away
someone else said that money is not the
most important driver it isn't the most
important driver when you have a salary
of a general let me give you an example
which goes along the lines of what Ramon
said I love my country I love Spain I
don't love their flag I don't feel that
flag but I love my country someone
working for the cryptology center with
my were reports learning 28,000 or
35,000 euros goes away is forced to go
away because their salary is not good
enough I don't understand that why do
politicians in this country never pay
attention to compensating talent
reasonably why is that and not retained
by paying them cut salaries
since I am the visible face for this
project and we more or less average
answers to all of these or many of these
questions let me let me attempt and so
respond
let me start talking about company how
people are compensated one thing is the
salary and another thing is the reward
okay these are different concepts let's
reward people let's reward companies
we're not proposing to have a
compensation package as such in place
for companies or people and by the way
you are absolutely right in everything
you said I am a strong supporter
of this idea and not just with
government there in this country we are
paying people peanuts and we are not
monkeys we have a lot of talented people
on board and company policies must not
focus exclusively on getting higher
deals at the expense of salaries because
I said that centers in the long run but
let me go back to the main topic our
proposal
rewards to companies well we can take a
look at alternative models that we see
in neighboring countries in terms of
rewards reward programs if you
contribute with cyber reservists to a
certain project with government why
shouldn't that be valued why shouldn't
that be acknowledged because it is
public administration that is training
those cyber reservists son and him
projects carried out for public
administration you should take that into
account
that would probably make companies
understand the cyber reservists might be
interesting people to get on board
thereby retaining talent within for any
projects that he could develop with the
state let us think big not just the
state Europe the state can't still has
the power to compensate the state and
this is the answer to a question from
that side of the room I seem to remember
of course the state have the ability to
recruit talent this is public
examinations anyone can go to public
examine exams some become a civil
servant I for example I'm a member of
the information technology level in
public office are we enough but for the
time being it seems we are
are we ready to compete in a global
market for talent no way they would even
be legal we cannot pay the best talent
in this room because there's no more
limits the salaries that I can pay I
cannot I cannot pay cellular salaries
that are higher than mine so
a potential approach here could be
voluntary voluntary status awarded we
have made a proposal for certification
in this world if a certification issued
by the state saying that someone is an
expert should be a good argument to get
a good salary in a private company when
you are submitting an application when
you are participating in a public call
to become a civil servant
how about acknowledging that you are an
expert what if you're earning a legal
expert in public in international public
law and you are specialized in IT when
you judges and prosecutors we need lots
of people everywhere so comentario
rapido
esto quiere decir que cieaura tengo tres
mil euros my mum too nice le y me dijo a
kaptara todo esto voluntarios okay we're
talking about recruiting and retaining
are you saying what you said that's your
interpretation of what I said
companies go out of their way to pay
really low salaries
their opus is also very tricky very
dodgy situations well there is an
institution in this country where you
have a group of inspectors if we had
enough inspectors we could allow them to
inspect what needs to be inspected
please
yes I wanted to focus on buyers
questions addressed to you Xavier is
there a way to find out that the
recruiter is in the right side
well we have personal security
accreditations in place and also all the
elements that have been included in a
draft bill but anyway security
accreditations are already there these
security accreditations give you access
to confidential information for security
is it possible you know that but with
accreditations we can ensure that we
have people we can trust on board all
countries have their own security
accreditations
I've heard that question before if I
miss I'm a reservist and I'm called by
my company what happens I think if a
crisis comes along we will see who would
use whatever resources we have it's very
difficult than we can count on
additional resources and I keep telling
the room the audience the cyber reserve
will be useful to capture or detect
Talent
on many occasions we tend to believe
that we have more talent that we have
and my expectations salary-wise might be
a hundred thousand and then the football
club comes along and says thirty
thousand dollars more than enough having
said that we need to play by the rules
of the game if someone joins the cyber
reserves the recital reserve gets
training they should earn points if they
want to become a civil servant then I
find a character with a correct approach
but any cyber reservists should have a
professional career plan they should be
clear about that time that they're
expected to work for the cyber during
which they are expected to work for the
same reserve
there's many things that came up
this is about bashing software at
telefónica because I wanna try this is
not national security this is not about
talent I was thinking about something
much more serious
point number two talent is leaving if
they have to go abroad it means that
this country doesn't need talent because
they're not acknowledging talent
ransomware
there's always there it's not an
exceptional situation who is who is
training talent in that field I think
you as hackers tend to say well I'm a
hacker I'm stunning
I'm also do you have surgeons born
surgeons or do you trust them because
they have operated on 500 patients who
trains those surgeons that we need
individual scenario when are they why
don't we have permanent stable positions
that training is not 15 days or 20 days
every year this is about professional
continues professional development what
we can expect is to find that talent
there where we have done nothing to
foster the existence of talent I don't
want to offend anyone but I think this
is useless this is an empty these goals
okay another 1.44 what is that abyss
hello
the question is what I've shared many of
the things that have been said here but
the question is why instead of having a
patriotic defense to save costs so Red
Cross volunteers they actually saving
costs is are they getting money from
somewhere and we're talking about
specific wanna cry crisis why the
Estonians have cyber a voluntary cyber
reserve I know that general Medina has
reservists they're paid and we're
talking about a different thing
why don't we identifies national defense
with something else with another thing
certainty synthesis problem or an issue
of our culture of Defense
perhaps in Spain we don't have our
culture of defense and that's my
question I'll leave it there well
several points how about that
undoubtedly a situation which is well
known by every one of an ongoing threat
makes everyone mobilize themselves in
same direction that is the case of
Estonia or Israel so we should not be
this is rob ourselves here okay so not
having a culture of national defense yes
it is true the recent one but now the
point is let us start this cyber reserve
if you think about the multiple
difficulties that we will find we will
even take a single de step let us go
back to the exercise that we said before
let us try let us try and use the most
appropriate mechanism we will make
mistakes we will control mistakes and
let us fix that that can be fixed
but let us not be petrified paralyzed
due to the multiple difficulties that we
will be facing because they have very
many difficulties and we are nearly
finishing okay so ten minutes away from
finishing this run table and before you
say you must was in the current state of
the art how many of you would be happy
to be volunteers can you please raise
your hands is that 50% of the room well
a bit less than fifty thirty or forty
percent okay you'll raise your hands
rise okay
serpentine is a question okay
first of all congratulations you are
wonderful very brave for coming over
here and to share your points so a very
simple question imagine let us assume
that I will have the talent to do that
so I don't mind the money that I will be
getting so because I'm hearing about
real world certifications so that the
private companies pay you but public
companies cannot pay you how much can
you pay can't you give me a bracket well
and I will just leave this room okay
very happy to know how much you will be
willing to pay because I pay the things
that I buy with money but not with
homeland spirits I answer to you okay
they said that they will pay nothing
because they cannot afford it okay if
they pay nothing they will get nothing
we have the last question
okay I'm going to recap something that
was said before it was said that there
were only few women and that you could
take advantage of the cyber brief prim
serve to give more visibility to women
but if there is no real economic
financial supports we are talking about
a volunteering program what is the exact
plan to engage women in that what is the
actual weight and importance that will
be given to women who are interested in
these projects when I mentioned that has
a positive externality that could come
out from any project that puts into
communication multiple talents okay and
without any gender segregation so we
have more and more binary societies
Millennials against premillennial so our
democracy is characterized by that we've
seen that in practice we've seen like
specific segments of populations that is
has the specific vote so therefore they
managed to prevail their common
cognitive bias over a small population
group so I am one of the baby boomers as
you can easily seen well I don't know
how I will end up my days with no
patient because you are not enough to
pay for my pension so well I hope to
have a decent ending end of life
Oh careful with what you say that
doesn't sound very good
well euthanasia is started to be
regulated when this is what is waiting
for us okay we are in a difficult
situation okay having said that they are
suffering young people are suffering
from us getting hold to our job position
okay for years and years because of
retirement so we are undergoing a
process of binarization for instance in
gender ratio let us think about stem
issue
so not only stem issue I'm going to show
you the counter example of that so that
I understand it very likely we will have
to make an inequality public policies to
hire male judges and prosecutors because
gradually women are embracing or working
into the legal world and they have bias
so to my viewpoints we will have to
create multidisciplinary groups to
attract the stem talent that has been a
serie typed from our in our society
where by women are rejected or feel
rejected or do not feel sufficiently
appealed by science and technology so if
the and enough women developing
artificial intelligence the cognitive
bias of the algorithms that are being
developed as it was recently proved with
Microsoft will make more men oriented
more chauvinist society and algorithms
will make many of the decisions in the
years ahead of us so by putting in
contact talents of different
background so different origins result
in the distribution of talents that is
to say people learning from each other
and it is very likely that if public
policies establish - most likely one of
the effects from that or impact for that
will be eliminating the stem bias at
least in this group and I wish that will
happen all right we move on to the last
round so very brief brief words from you
okay let us start off with Ramon Ramon
do you are you willing to embrace this
initiative yes I would be happy to be
reservists I just don't want any
politician to win a medal because of
that and I just don't want someone to
politically capitalize that and to get
money out of it
I defend my culture but I just don't
want anyone to make any brats to make
any profit out of me so me I would not
be a cyber reservists I would be a
volunteer I would do it for my community
I would did for those who need it but I
would not play this game of disguising
myself to pay for a consultancy so it
doesn't really make sense that someone
who has not invested any money on the
training expect something in return for
free but any other thing if I were the
head of an NGO or any other charity
well no not uniform no no no you don't
pay well no no no uniform for me in that
case well yes okay I will be ready ready
to sit down and to discuss it okay it
will charity organization all right I
insist
only need to have volunteers
it looks like if we were going to come
to us and we were going to tap you on
the shoulder so this is a task of years
of months we have to get to know each
other we have to trust you but in the
case of CNN when we called people we pay
and when we pay people are always happy
with those with that money
so my question my answer is one known by
all of you here yes of course I would be
a cyber reservists knowing that there
are many problems to be resolved but it
is a public policy that if well oriented
including highlight specific projects
with good resources could generate very
many externalities which are not for
this at different from those of the
cyber reserve system okay yes I will be
a summary service but not at any cost
and any expense would you like to add
anything else well my specific case
understands that we have to support the
estate okay not the ministries and I
don't want this to be a tool and I know
it is a true I work in the private
sector that would be double-edged sword
so I just don't want the private
companies ending up competing with the
administration for talents okay and that
could easily be the case okay so
positive I am an optimistic and person
by nature to summarize it I think it is
worthwhile to try it difficulties have
very many of course and the last message
Oh several references have been made to
the Ministry of Defense the Ministry of
Defense's at the service of Spain and of
the Spaniards and not at all in favor of
no one at the service of Spain and the
Spaniards and that's our only purpose
and I would like everything everyone to
be very clear about that thank you very
much general so this is the end of our
from table so pick a greater applause
please for them
this is rooted something it's a pleasure
it's being a pleasure being with you
this is the end of the round table