okay so now let's talk a few minutes
about how high accuracy parts so the
part even after finish machining looks
beautiful but it's actually not accurate
and and I was saying of it if you have
some moving parts sliding against each
other if you build them just from
machined parts you know say machined on
a milling machine overlays you'll find
out that pretty soon they'll wear out
and there will be some play and to
understand wise it is all that you have
to do is take apart and mill it as
finely as you can on a milling machine
so this was done at a very slow feed and
a very shallow cut finishing cut and it
looks very beautiful but actually when
this maids another part it's only
touching a few high spots and the way
you can demonstrate it quite simply is
you can take one of those dry erase
markers so you can color the whole
surface and the special fluids for this
purpose are special paints used for
detecting flatness but just for a quick
test it can mark the whole surface and
then you can slide it against the
granite plate which is very accurate and
tea to your surprise actually it's not
touching anywhere it's only touching at
this corner and at this corner and one
spot at this corner because it's only
touching where the ink will off the
market well off now what this means that
if you made an assembly from this part
which has to move as soon as these few
high spots will wear off the path will
be loose and that's a problem is all
assemblies that if you are not if they
are not done properly they may seem
accurate but they lose accuracy very
quickly now if you can make it touch on
the whole surface it will not wear for
two reasons the first reason there's
just a lot more surface area its resting
on so there's a lot more material to
wear away but that's not the main reason
the main reason is that if something is
a perfect flat surface and you lubricate
it
it will act hydrodynamically there will
be an oil film and the metal will
actually not touch the other metal and
there will be zero wear so if the
surface becomes perfectly flat and it's
lubricated the wear doesn't go down a
bit it goes three to zero and that's
very important to understand okay so
first how do we make it a really flat
surface so the answer is very simple on
small parts like this you have two
choices you can either lap it or scrape
it on big party or give one choice you
can lap you have to scrape because if
you have a big base it's too big and too
heavy to lift and lap you have to scrape
now there is an intermediate step which
improves the accuracy of the machining
and that self is grinding if I put it on
a surface grinder
I can grind it will be much better now
the reason why surface grinding produces
a better accuracy not just a nicer
looking surface but a better accuracy is
because there is a lot less forces
between the cutting tool and the
workpiece and a lot less forces in
clamping so reason why this is not
accurate is a is a milling machine is
not so accurate but when I claim to it I
distort it and once I take it out of
clamping it swings back
now since surface grinding uses much
smaller forces I don't need to clamp it
as hard and also the cutting tool
doesn't distort it so basically there
are three steps you can machine it which
is this you can go to an intermediate
step which is grind it on the surface
grinding off the cylinder on a
cylindrical grinder but it's still not
accurate enough if I do the same test on
the surface grind there it will still
only touch it a few spots it's not going
to touch it the whole area the only way
to get you touch of the whole area is by
lapping of scraping so the only way to
make a machine which is not only
accurate but stays accurate forever on
moving parts is by lapping or scraping
okay so in order to bring the surface to
a full bearing area surface
as we said you can either lap it up
scrape it so the small parts are easiest
fastest to lap and what lapping means is
moving it in a randomized motion on an
abrasive surface so first you have to
clean a granite surface plate okay
because any kind of dirt behind it which
will change the flatness is to stick a
sheet of emery clothes or emery paper
now it usually it helps to put a drop of
water if you just pull down and stick so
if you just put the drop of water and
squeeze out the water and make it stick
okay now this is 220 grit that's kind of
a typical grit you would use if you want
to remove a lot of material you can
start with a 180 grit if you want to
remove a little material you can go
straight away to 400 grit but somewhere
in that range is good you can do a try
and well you can see it
it's a rough grit so it takes off a lot
of the red but it still only laps a few
spots now the trick is is your lap in a
figure 8 motion and you don't lean on
one corner unless you want to correct it
you can correct lap parallelism by
leaning on the corner what if you don't
want to do any you don't want to collect
anything just lap you try to uniformly
press it go in a figure 8 maybe turn it
over turn it over again until the whole
surface looks dull and if you want it
really accurate you have to remove all
machining marks here I can still see
machining marks so a little bit more
lapping because it wasn't so accurate
now the danger in lapping is rounding it
because if you walk it around so if it's
very critical you sometimes attach to
dummy pieces just to give you a wider
bearing and you lap it together
another thing you do if you make parts
which have to be mated by lapping you
can relieve the middle so there's less
material to lap but the parts don't have
to slide we just have to fit perfectly
it's enough to have some four spots or
just two ribs so you remove all the
extra material let's tie clip okay so
now now it's left okay now we can repeat
the same test right here clean the plate
and do the test with a Marquis oh okay
just it's not paint perfectly but we can
see already gravity bit now you see the
result okay so basically it removed all
the marking now as I said them if you
want higher accuracy you can't rely on
this marker it's too cold you have to
use a better method and there are
special marking inks marking paste to
see exactly what's going on now another
way to know what's going on if you rub
it the high spots will become shiny so
actually all you have to do it don't
need any market at all you just need to
hold it and tilt it and look for the
shiny area so it's a mango I'll just
tilt it until you see shiny area okay
and now you can see the shiny area is
about half of the surface area because
he'll still have machining America still
low so if I continue letting the Chinese
I will spread until it's all shiny and
at this point it has full area bearing
and full area bearing means not only
that it's precise that it will never
wear out as I demonstrate later okay now
so this is lapping if you wanted to lap
a hole say like this you'll make
yourself a split lip
you can put the paper around this and
let it there's different sized split
left to let holes if you wanted to let
the outside of something you'll make
yourself a split external lap and again
you'll put say Emery clothes in it if I
wanted to do that I would take semi
clothes like this I would run it so the
split lip just to hold it a slot is just
to hold it then I would run the piece I
want two laps which put it in the lathe
let it turn and go back and forth now
the interview seeing is going in two
directions because going to directions
is what randomize is it so if I want to
lap a seal in there it's not enough to
leave it in one spot it just make
grooves you have to keep going in two
directions and and this is the reason
why some shapes are how to lap if you
have a co taper you cannot lap it easily
because you can't go in two directions
you can send it a bit cosmetically but
it wouldn't become of accurate because
you can't let it only only shapes which
can be moved in two directions can be
left so say a sphere can be left because
you can walk in two directions the
cylinder can be left the flat can be
left other things can be left if you go
in one direction but it's less effective
like a thread or a taper it's problem
slapping it say taper you can have a
little segment and slide it along the
table but it's harder to let okay and
this is tightly related to term called
honing hole a hole is like a single
exist which is has a stone only the
grinding stone and acting as a lecture
but especially the same technology
honing and lapping just laughing usually
uses a paste or alleging field okay
something very important about letting
if you leper soft materials a luminal or
brass you can have particles embedded in
the soft material and then the soft
material itself will act as a lap so if
you had a bronze part and
stealing part and you left both to make
a bearing and if these particles get
embedded in the soft material like bonds
the bonds material itself will become a
permanent left and keep letting the
steel so it's very very important to
make sure particles don't get embedded
so if you have a blunt part don't push
too hard and the safest way to do is to
use a software lapping material which
cannot embed in bonds so there are so
this regular Emily in regular lapping
compounds are really good for steel okay
so this is a regular lapping compound
that's already a powder mixed in grease
that you can smear on the shaft and lap
a steel shaft a 400 grit which is like
the common lapping now this is a special
epic compound it says yellow label for
soft materials only and this is a softer
grit which doesn't embed in the soft
materials so if you do have to lap soft
materials with regular compound make
sure we don't rest too hard that they
don't embed in the soft material okay
the other way to achieve high accuracy
besides lapping is called scraping and
the advantage of scrapings that you
don't have to move the part and move it
around and that's suitable for big
structures so scraping is based on
touching the surface with a plate with a
reference surface and looking at the
high spot and in this case I can just
see the high spot by the reflection and
then removing the high spots with a tool
and the tool is very simple it's
basically a bit like this chisel I
showed you before I can use the scraper
its ground either 90 degrees or
sometimes just a bit less than 90 but
most of time it's gone flat at 90
degrees and what you do is you look at
the high spots and you simply remove
them exist it just peels off a very very
thin layer of metal and you go in one
direction
and then you go in the other direction
typically okay and then you test the lit
after you have done that you rub it
again look at it again and the high
spots move somewhere else because he
removed them so you repeat it and you do
that for many many times until the high
spots are spread everywhere okay
now this sounds very tedious actually
these what helps is there is a power
scrape where an electric scraper which
can do it okay so if you have to scrape
large areas like a base of a machine
it's too slow to do it by hand so if you
use a power scraper like this one
now you check it again okay so this is a
new high spot and Yuri scrape it 90
degrees to the original direction so I
see the original scraping marks and I
see some high spots here so just to get
a better surface
okay
yeah and now the high spots start
spreading everywhere this is obviously
done too quickly to be accurate but you
can see where I scraped now with random
high spots where I didn't scrape there's
two big high spots so I would have to
continue scraping until the whole
surface is covered with the univille
density of high spots if you look at a
high precision machine tools as they all
have this surface if you look at regular
machine tools they have a fake scraped
surface what they do they grind the
surface and then they do a surface which
is sometimes added on top of scraping to
retain oil so if you look at this I see
so you look at less precise tools they
have like a fake surface but you can see
the grinding marks below it that it's
not really scraped because people
traditionally are looking for this
appearance on high quality machine tools
okay so now that we fix the surface to
achieve full bearing I mentioned before
the significance of full bearing is
double first it's more accurate of
course it doesn't walk it sits
accurately secondly it's more it's
stiffer because if I put a load on it
it's not resting on one point which can
squeeze it can bear a heavy load is much
higher stiffness and the third thing is
that it will not wear if it's lubricated
now the reason why it will not wear
because two perfect planes with
lubricant will become hydrodynamic very
very quickly so if it was lubricated and
I moved it it will actually not touch
each other there'll be a soil film which
will separate them and then will be zero
wear and you can demonstrate it very
nicely when you look at any one of the
new hard drive spindles the old hard
drive spindles use ball bearings and you
have Drive spindles all you sleeve
bearings but are very accurate and they
are designed to operate hydro
dynamically so if you look at the light
bulb the light bulb is on and I have one
wire connected to the case of the hard
drive and another wire connected to a
finger which is touching the spindle so
right now it shows electrical contact
between the case in the spindle but as
soon as I spin it it loses all
electrical contact okay and and the fact
it loses electrical contact means it
will never wear that's a significance of
it because if there's no electrical
contact there's no metal to metal
contact if there is no metal metal
contact how can it wail so indeed a
properly designed spindle like this will
run forever without wear and today's are
also using this idea in the computer
fans too that there aren't quieter more
accurately in everywhere another demo
that you achieve I
the dynamic lubrication very quickly
you say this is a granite square which
is very flat and a granite table which
is very flat so usually tends to stick
to each other but as soon as you move it
a bit it can become hydrodynamic very
quickly just float frictionlessly okay
and the reason it floats frictionlessly
because he also air has very very low
viscosity if the surfaces are perfect it
doesn't take much of a velocity to
become hydrodynamic because the load is
distributed over the whole area if the
whole area is perfect the load is
distributed on every point so at no
point is a high pressure if the surface
is not perfect the load is resting on a
few points at those points as high
pressure it means it will need a much
higher velocity to get hydrodynamic
conditions because they to achieve
either dynamic lift it's a function as
you see on the equation it's a function
of the viscosity and the force and this
and the speed okay so for a given force
in a given viscosity you need a certain
speed to become a dynamic and air has
very low viscosity but since the area
here is very very large the force per
unit area of the pressure is very very
small so in spite of the low viscosity
of air this becomes hydrodynamic at very
low speed and the same poses another
subject when you talk about building
precision equipment is how do you
determine that it's precise like it's
very easy for a flap I just showed you
can rub it against the grain it look at
it you know it's flat but what about if
this had to be right angles perfect
right angles so again if you have a
granny square like this it's easy
because that surface is already known
flat now you can have it against the
granite and now you can look at the
contact of this surface now the question
is how do you get it Square and first
place so if you have a very very
accurate square vise on a milling
chin you can clamp it on a grinder you
can rely on device and make it square if
you are not sure you have a very
accurate square vise the best thing is
clamp it to something known very square
for example if I wanted to get this very
square to that very square meaning to
one micron or better what I would do is
I would take something that I know is
square like this bow which is square to
submicron okay I would clamp it to this
bar and put this whole thing down on the
surface grinder or a milling machine and
then I will take this cut and then I
know it's square and then I'll just let
it to get it flat so now I have two
areas now to get it parallel it's very
easy okay because now you have one sides
you can just turn it over and drying it
on the surface going there and then lap
it now when you want to get it parallel
you can fix small levels by lepak by
hand lapping say if you put it under a
dial gauge and you discover there is an
error with parallelism one side is a
micron higher than the other side all
you have to do is lean on it a bit when
you lap it on the higher side so instead
of pushing in the middle you push it
here you develop this feel very quickly
that as you move the load point you move
the tilt so very quickly you can change
the pressure and let it parallel to a
mic on so now it's square and parallel
to a micron now other things that you
want to check if you want to check
around nests typically you have to
separate of course run out from
roundness whether if you make a perfect
spindle the spindle may have run out
because you things are not mounted well
but it's still tunis of rotation is
there so so far our spindle is two specs
that is run out and the stone is of
audacious around this and you can
separate them for example one way to
separate them is you can take a ball or
a perfect cylinder mounted on the
spindle and take two probes at right
angles and now you have two signals and
and because you have two independent
signals and you have two unknowns
because one man was running out
as wellness if you can have two
equations two inputs and then you can
find both separately so this actually
leads to a more generic principle which
is known as reversal methods and the
reversal methods it's a interesting
principle because you can expand this
concept to many many measurements in
precision and it's actually very hard to
find it in any textbook so I'll just
explain in general reversal methods and
then we can show some examples how it's
used so the basic question in metrology
is let's say you want to measure how
straightest is or how round something is
or how square something is but you don't
have a reference if you had a perfect
reference like this you could see how
straight this is just by touching it to
the reference but how do you measure
this if you don't have a perfect
reference okay so it turns out it's very
easy it turns out you can measure the
straightness of this or the flatness of
this or the roundness without having a
reference and the way you do that you
use something called a reversal method
so let's say you have one straight edge
which is unknown and another straight
edge you want to measure need neither of
them you know anything about okay so
what you do is you you measure actually
this this could be the other safe let
the table could be the other edge
although you don't know anything about
it you don't know if it's flat or not
okay so what you do is you take a dial
gauge and you set it up to scan here and
you move it we put something here to fix
a trajectory so let's say you move it
and you write down the reading every
centimeter okay so you have a function f
of X which is this is X you have the ydv
ation for any X but you don't know
whether the Y deviation
came from this or from this or both
because you don't know anything a lot
either okay however what you can do is
you can take this part flip it over flip
it over and now measure it from
underneath flip over the gauge and you
set it up here that the gauge will go
underneath will fit which it doesn't
know and you scan it again but
underneath and same thing this has to
move on the same trajectory you you line
up and you make it move the same
trajectory as before okay so if if this
surface was an unknown and this was an
unknown and let's call it f of X Y is f
of X and let's call this G of X let's
say okay so when you measured it when
when the original surface was up okay so
the total measurement you got let's say
that it is the sum its al-bakr you can
call it sum or difference so now when
you measured it you got f of X plus of G
of X as a function of X now when you
invert it you now have G of X minus f of
X because you inverted this so now you
have two independent equations for each
point so basically for each point here
you have a EV of X plus G of X and f of
X minus G of X now if you have two
unknowns F and G in two equations you
can solve it so now you end up with a
function your end up with two functions
by taking the sum and the difference of
the functions you can separate f of X
and G of X so although this is unknown
and this is unknown but you have two
separate equations you can resolve
separately f of X and G of X what the
interesting that these two don't have to
be the same height exactly because
that's another unknown if these are not
on the same height you'll just introduce
a tilt arrow so when you look at the two
functions
so you will see that one function came
out that it has a tilt arrow but you can
always remove the fixed term the team
table because when you talk about
straightness the till doesn't mean
anything all it means is one point
relative to the other
so actually you don't even have to match
those the arrow between those we just
will show up that is a function the
graph will have a tilt which you remove
okay so this whole idea is called the
reversal method that you have two
unknowns or many unknowns but you have
enough independent equations to resolve
it and this is one of the more powerful
concept in precision instruments and
metrology and basically this is how you
separate roundness from one out when you
measure a spindle this is how you
measure straightness and this this is
how a circle is divided accurately
because you know in a circle is divided
accurately the division has to close
right because if you have all the angles
have to add up to 360 so if it doesn't
close you know you have an arrow and
then you can do multiple measurements
and find out where they are all is okay
so this whole concept of reversal
methods can be expanded to many many
tests in metrology to determine how
accurate things are