okay so now we are going to try vacuum
forming you can do it by putting a
plastic or you can heat the plastic in
an oven and quickly move it over we are
trying to do it with lexan which is
actually very difficult material for
vacant forming because it doesn't soften
easily but that's all I have on hand so
RapidArc
as I said lexan doesn't really soften
and as soon as it cools down a little
bit it becomes hard so it wouldn't pull
down all the way but any other plastic
like PVC a BAS polyethylene the old form
beautiful is all pull down all the way
so for the Vulcan forming all that you
need is a little bit hot but for the
very conforming or what you need it
looks terrible but anyway shows the
principle so you need a bottom mode okay
and the vacuum will actually spread
around so you don't need to make roofs
or anything so they can spread around
the corners you need a top frame to
clamp the plastic okay otherwise you can
just pull in the ends will pull in it
wouldn't and then you need a heated
sheet of plastic and that's it it takes
one second let it cool down the
advantage of lexan of course it's strong
shatterproof so and you have to leave it
for normal plastics you have to leave it
completely to cool down because you know
it still can distort if you take it off
the mold the lexan how it's very hot
still but it's already hard but normal
plastic stays soft a long time so it
will form beautifully but you have to
leave it to cool down
okay another
which is sometimes useful is replication
of parts in plastic now today a lot of
the plastic parts of special shape can
be made by desktop printers by 3d
printers 3d printers but sometimes you
still need a part with a very good
finish always very good properties of
plastic like a filled plastic which
cannot be used in a 3d printers so the
way you make it is you make a mold of
silicone rubber and then you pull any
plastic you want including some molten
metal too if you want another mold so
let's say we have this knob just as an
example and we want to make a copy of it
so what we do is we put the knob in a
little box and cover it with silicone
rubber this is not the silicone rubber
adhesive I showed you in the caulking
gun this is silicone rubber mold making
material which actually it doesn't stick
to anything that's its uniqueness it has
a stick to anything so you don't have to
put any kind of mold release or anything
so you just put it at the bottom of a
little cup mix the two components mold
making silicone rubber and over it and
cure it and when you get a part like
this so basically this came out from
this okay this is how it came out from
the mold and he pulled out because it's
so flexible under the cuts are okay for
example you can see two pins sticking
inside and these two pins are actually
the two holes or the set scores so it's
no problem at all to mold it including
the holes because it'll pull out and
release themselves so you can even see
there this has Alan Schools
you can even see the hex inside the
school copied here but really the
ability of this process to copy goes
down to a molecular level like if you
trace the surface here with a probe with
molecular resolution and you trace the
surface of the copy they follow within
molecular resolution
the reason I know that for sure because
think of replication of records like a
normal LP record of the old days
had they something like a 50 micron gold
EPS but near a hundred DB dynamic range
which means that the modulation was at
the nanometer level at the bottom for
100 DB below 50 micron so anyway so it's
a perfect process it is not so good
dimensionally because this can distort
it's flexible so if you want to
dimensionally more accurate you have to
put some metal screen inside before you
pull the rubber to just make it a bit
stronger but it's very very good for
surface texture and every little detail
now one other things when you mix
viscous materials like some epoxies or
silicon there's a lot of air bubbles
trapped in it so what you have to do you
have to mix it pair instructions put it
in a vacuum chamber like this and the
gas it the guess it means you start up
the vacuum say and you leave it up for
half an hour until all air bubbles
exploded and and you have to put a
country you put in a container much
taller than this is because you'll form
up please see four times taller so let's
say ID guess that I bear put this in a
plate pull the rubber overweight heated
it up awaited today took it out and now
have a mold so now I want to cast a copy
of this so the best way to cast a very
high-quality copy without air bubbles or
defects is casted in vacuum again by
sucking in the epoxy so the way you do
it you put the mold here inside put the
mold inside the vacuum chamber you mix
up the resin you want to cast is a
polyester or epoxy or polyurethane or
any typically any component to component
residues to polymerize if you want the
best result you have to do guess this
first as well so you only put in less
than a third of the height put it in the
vacuum chamber and first
first you have to dig ass resin itself
shall be no trapped air bubbler
so you put it under vacuum you can see
the vacuum going up
you wait for full vacuum bubbles will
start forming okay so you leave it there
for half an hour until the bubbles
collapsed take it out now you have the
guest resin and the same thing as you
did before would be guest silicone
rubber now you put a feet.you bin and
rather plug one end of the fee tube goes
in the resin I don't know if you can see
it here this is a resin with a fee tube
okay at the end of the feet u'b goes
into the mold now it's a good idea
because sometimes you can overflow or
suck in a bit too much it's a good idea
to put this a guard around the mold so
if it overflows it doesn't mess up the
oven just put in a guard like this
put the other end of the tube in the
mold and now we can be a bit higher
because of the SAG out there like this
okay now as you start a vacuum there it
will suck out the material fill the mold
you do that okay the mold is already
full you can see it sucked out the
liquid from here okay now you pinch off
the tube because you don't want any more
resin inside now you release a vacuum I
can see some bubbling zero and you'll
release a vacuum okay okay here I'll
spread out now once you release a vacuum
two good things happen okay if even if
the material is the gas there is some
miniature air bubbles were introduced by
sucking it in and putting it in now
these air bubbles may have been trapped
still inside but once you release a
vacuum these bubbles collapse because
it's vacancies bubbles inside have very
little air because it was done all
undone on the vacuum so even if the real
bubbles it would used and what you saw
the end the foam which was formed is
real collapse and disappear so now what
you do is you can take out the feed tube
turn on the heater and depending on the
resin you use you cure it anywhere from
50 degrees to 80 degrees if it was
silicone poured in I was cured at 100
degrees but some of in this range it'll
cure the now well that'll be cured so
silicon take a bit longer now once you
take it out once you take it out and of
course you can dye the resin to have any
color you want so in this case I added
black pigment to the resin so I made a
replica of this knob the surface finish
on the replica is the gloss isn't as
high as the original but a lot of it has
to do with this resin because it was
coldly mixed and filled just just show
the principle okay so this is a simple
process of a replication you can also
make two powered molds if there were
features on the back of this that I also
wanted to copy what I would do I would
pour another layer of silicone to make
the second part of the mold and I would
put in some registration pins so when I
pull it apart I have two halves of a
mold when pins to align them so I can
put it in a
put a feed hole in an air escape hole of
an air inlet hole and I would fill the
hole mold which would being closed and
open it up take out the part now this
process walks from tiny parts to huge
parts but of course gets expensive
because the material is expensive you
can if you have you can put metal
inserts in the mold if you want threads
you can put filler in the mold the
carbon fiber you can mix the failure if
it's chopped finely into the resin or
you can lay carbon fiber inside the mold
and impregnate it this way this is also
the process you impregnate the
electrical coils or other things which
have to be waterproof and very durable
because usually air will be trapped
everywhere so the only way to impregnate
something with resin is for a vacuum
process like this now a very interesting
property of silicon that short term it
can take very high temperature so if you
made this mold especially if you made it
from a red silicone which is higher
temperature you can easily melt zinc
alloy parts and pull the molten metal
into that you can some even some
aluminum alloys can be poured into it
once or twice but it wins the mold if
you use it for plastic you can make
hundreds of parts with one mold if you
use it for metal maybe you can make ten
parts but there is a common zinc
aluminum alloy used for die casting and
you can cast parts in the silicone from
the cellar and they look perfect just
like a bike as part