okay so we'll go over all the machines
you need to make the prototype as I
mentioned the key machine is a water jet
cutter this is an all Mack's 26:54 water
jet cutter now this is the only
expensive piece of equipment you
actually need the poor man's version of
this would be a plasma cutter a CNC
plasma cutter like the ones made by
torch mate a plasma cutter is about
one-tenth of the cost and one tenth of
the operating cost and a water jet but
it's much less versatile because it
course doesn't cut as well and can only
cut metals and doesn't cut all metals
equally well a water jet can cut
practically anything up to two inch
thickness or more and cuts beautifully
so the ideal machine is a water jet but
sometimes because of budget reasons for
home use or whatever there you can do a
lot of the things I'm talking about
today you can also do the CNC plasma
cutter
okay so the first thing is the
modifications you need to do to improve
a productivity the most important
modification is to add a sliding basket
because when you cut out small parts
they drop into the tank
sometimes even big parts have surprising
ways to tip over the sleds and drop into
the tanks and once it drops into the
tank which is full of discarded garnet
it's basically lost the chances of
retrieving it if you ever tried are very
low so the first thing you have to do is
you have to make a moving basket and
I'll show it here and the basket is
resting on the bottom part of the you
beam which is holding the sleds now the
reason it sank below to be far enough on
the jet not to be cut by the jet has to
be about eight inches of twenty
centimeters below the top of the sled in
order not to be cut now you can move the
basket by pulley and you can pick it up
take it out and find all the little part
you lost and also recovered a lot of
parts you can be reused for other things
like slag metal slugs it just
now the basket just sits on the cradle
and just sits on the cradle you drop it
in and you're moving back to position
now for sheet metal if you don't have a
basket you can leave sinks hanging of a
tap and break them off but unfortunately
anything sicker than say an eighth of an
inch this method doesn't walk because if
you have a half-inch steel plate and you
leave things hanging on a tab you can't
break them off so basically you have to
have this basket to save time the second
modification which is very desirable is
to have some way to know where the beam
will hit and the best way I found is a
laser pointer which shines through the
beam passes a jet and shows where the
beam will hit and I understand this will
be available from the omics Corporation
but right now this is a homemade one so
it's just like a normal laser pointer
accepted right angles it's precisely
made
it's precisely made so it fits exactly
where the fee tube you pull out the fee
tube you plug in exactly where the feed
tube goes and to keep the nozzle clean
from water you plug it into an air
supply okay I'll just hold up a piece of
paper so you can see this part of the
video much better so you can see the
laser point of spot coming out the
places spot will hit the metal is where
the jet will hit the metal because it's
going to st. V tube that's a second
benefit the shape of the spot also
measures the way around the mixing tube
so just by looking at the shape of the
spot you know if you have to replace the
mixing tube or not so
this is especially important if you had
to stop a job for any reason and then
start cutting for where you left off
before it's very important to align the
beam second place it's important when
you have to mix some precision holes
with waterjet holes and so you have to
register the cutting to pre-existing
features like big holes so you use this
now this chap here to go from splashes I
found out that the best cap is actually
half of a tennis ball and that's what
this is which is much better than any of
the caps supplied to the machine the
reason why it's better it takes very
little space so you can come very close
to the edge and you can flip it over
very easily to see what's going on so
one good modification is to add clamps
like this for example that you can just
tighten down these clamps obviously are
cut on the water jet so takes no time to
make them and they go from zero to one
inch and bigger stuff in one inch is
heavy enough that you don't really need
clamping it will sit from its own weight
okay so a quick demo of something very
inexpensive and useful called a plasma
cutter over air plasma cutter
get it out this is a top unit it's very
light all that it needs is compressed
air and regular power household power if
you have a water jet cutter alone most
of the time you never use it
but you still need it sometimes if you
want to cut a hole in a box or an
enclosure which is too big to fit into
the water jet let's say you're working
on a car you're working on a cabinet you
can't drag it into a water jet but you
still need to cut out a well-defined
hole so what you do is you cut out on
the water jet a template allowing for
the oversize allowing for the fact that
there is a diameter here of the nozzle
so you cut an oversized template clamps
the template is a cabinet order you want
to cut and use it just you follow it
with this now if your template is steel
sometimes a good idea to insulate this
tip so it doesn't electrically touch the
template and also keep some distance
from the material you cut because you're
supposed to keep a very small distance
or the material you cut so it's the best
thing to do is machine a ceramic tip to
go on it I know if I don't have one I'm
just wrapping up some tape around it and
that will be good enough just to cut one
part sit like this good enough so what
is does it transfer the arc from an
internal arc to the work piece so if I
ground the work piece okay first you see
a butane bottle here which is not a good
idea to have what we are going to make
sparks so and again for a it's the you
have to have goggles not only because of
sparks okay but also because of intense
UV this emits a lot of UV now these
glasses are actually UV filter so it's
okay
so such precisely the cut is not nice
because my hand isn't steady but if you
set the same torch on a CNC table the
cut it's quite nice not as nice as water
jet but completely acceptable for sheet
metal work so if I wanted to cut a hole
here and I couldn't take it to the water
jet I would make a template let's say
this is a template and I would clip it
heel to ground it of the template but
I'll use one of these strange shapes
this is a template you have to somehow
clip it so you can still reach it with a
gun see I can hold it with another piece
of sleeve from the other side because
yeah if you have to be able to go around
the template and
okay so
and knocks it out so it didn't do the
greatest job because I didn't go steady
but but you can see I copy that shape so
that's quite a useful thing for quick
and dirty walk especially considering is
that the whole machine is about a
thousand bucks or less so very
inexpensive we will cut out two
quarter-inch steel the bigger ones will
cut up to 3/4 inch steel it will cut
stainless aluminum but of course will
not cut non metallics will not cut well
cocktail of materials which conducts the
heat away very fast and so on