it's been about an hour since the 43rd
public meeting of ICANN closed here in
San Jose Costa Rica I think it's safe to
say that new generic top-level domains
again dominated many of the
conversations here at this meeting rod
how many registrants do you have right
now in the new generic top-level domain
registration system we have 290
registrations registered users in the
system as of mark 16th so that's parties
that have gone in and registered
themselves and been verified as users to
then submit applications for strings
subsequently rod you said that even
organizations not applying for new
generic top-level domains should pay
close attention during this process
during the application process why
should even non applicants pay attention
sure because there's a lot of
protections that have been built into
the program for rights holders such as
their right to object to any string
that's applied for for any reason
whatsoever at no cost in the original
objections period in window so it's
important that that parties watch if
they're concerned that someone else
might use their name or their brand or
and not have a right to do so bottom
line organizations have to be vigilant
sure they should just be watching when
we announce the strings on may first of
this year to review those strings and
see if they have any concerns and if
they do then they can express those
online Steve let me ask you about the
applicant support program first of all
can you tell us what that program is
secondly what sort of interest are you
getting at this stage as we put the
applicant guidebook together and neared
the opening of the window there was
giving a question about whether it be
possible for us to provide assistance
for applicants principally from
developing countries but not necessarily
but who may not have had the financial
resources of large companies the board
allocated two million dollars to help
alleviate a portion of the application
fee it's that that goes some distance
but it has to be taken in the
that in order for anyone to operate a
new registry the application fee of 185
thousand dollars is only one portion of
a significant budget that one has to
have and so our contribution to reduce
the 185 thousand to if I recall
correctly about 47,000 is helpful but
not I don't think it's going to
stimulate a lot of people who are
otherwise unable to get into the
business there's been quite a bit of
interest and part of what we've had to
do is to find people who can evaluate
and judge the appropriateness of the
application worthiness and we've not
wanted to do that ourselves we wanted to
have independent people do that that's
all very much in progress how is the
search for volunteers for that panel
coming we're in the process of
finalizing that at this time and so that
will be ready and available to to go and
to support and to analyze the
applications that are received I also
just want to note we're very encouraged
there's a something called in-kind
contributions as well where any group in
the world can offer products or services
to support needy applicants and we have
more than a dozen parties that have
already gone online and made offers to
help whether it's with DNS SEC
consulting ipv6 with preparing their
technical plans are various things and
we're very encouraged to see that and we
hope that more companies and
organizations will offer to do so as
well and they can offer that online at I
can you're looking for some fairly high
level qualified people for this panel is
it going to be tough to get those sorts
of candidates for the panel when you're
not paying them when they're volunteers
you know I think that we're very
fortunate that I can draws upon a global
community of people interested in the
internet and I think there's a large
subset of those who care a lot about
needy applicants in this cause so I
would actually anticipate quite some
number of excellent candidates coming
forward although I haven't looked at the
the application list yet what's the
status right now of the registrar
accreditation agreement it's still under
negotiation and a document was published
in early March before this meeting there
were numerous
sessions at this meeting talking about
it and where there were opinions in view
shared a different constituency and
stakeholder meetings and other
discussions so i would say that those
discussions are have gained for more
information here and hopefully will be
advancing with concrete results soon
we'll see let me ask you a question I
asked you gentlemen in the car when we
did this interview and that has to do
with batching first of all describe what
batching is secondly tell me how far
we've come in that process since the car
as you as you're aware we have this
application window that opened in
January and will close April twelfth we
don't know how many applications will
come in route is described the number of
registered users but each one can submit
don't have been any that could be zero
or they could submit up to 50 so there's
a very very wide range of potential
applications and we're in the window
even for registering isn't done so we
don't know the numbers we have very very
carefully sized the evaluation process
and the management and the quality
control to be able to handle 500 at a
time if we get more than 500 then we
have two segments them into what we call
batches and when the first batch is
through that process then we can start
the second batch and so forth so the
this window is open for what we call
around and when we get all of them in
that round is broken up into batches of
500 is the is the what's on the table
the plan and will will do that if you've
already said very definitively that
there will be a second round of
applications following this first one
yes and you've also not specified when
it would be when might you be able to
announce wind that second round
the excellent question so I think we've
tried to be clear that there are
fundamentally two variables to two
factors that will influence when the
second round starts one is how many how
big the first round is if the first
round has a large number of applications
we have to get through that before we
can get to the second round quite
obviously the second factor is that
we've also committed to take a pause and
examine how well the system has worked
in every way Systems wise and in terms
of the evaluation process and all of
that so we can't pin down a date certain
but we can make rough estimates and the
first part of the rough estimate will
depend as i said on how big the round
this when we know how many applications
are and that will be within a relatively
short period of time after the
application window closes then that
factor will be relatively pinned down
whichever and then we can make you know
a rough estimate of the amount of time
necessary between rounds not a hard
commitment but we can you know sort of
give a window and contingencies what
does all that mean it's it's it's time
measured from here in years but not a
large number of years you know it's
probably a small number of years the
night and I can't pin it down greater
than that because we're running the
experiment this meeting occurred in the
wake of an announcement by the
Department of Commerce that it was
rewriting the request for proposals for
the iono function what does that mean
for I can it means that next week we'll
be sitting down and having a
conversation with NTIA to understand how
they got to this point and what's the
roadmap that they see going forward and
we're also pleased last week that we did
sign a modification to the agreement
that extends the period for next another
six months while we have those
discussions Stephen December there's
going to be a meeting of the ITU and
Dubai which some have characterized as a
potential threat to I can what is this
meeting mean
for I can certainly it's it's a concern
that has been expressed I don't want to
comment on what might happen or what
might not happen but it's certainly in
the air and getting a lot of discussion
the ITU is a venerable institution been
around for 100 200 years and has played
a very important role and one of the
challenges that the Internet has posed
in many many spheres including the
regulatory sphere is what how do you
adjust the institutions that have were
created before to operate in this new
world and so it's quite understandable
that the ITU is quite interested in this
and it's quite understandable that where
the in the internet community quite
interested in how the ITU thinks about
things in discussing the issues of
conflict of interests and ethics you
mentioned that i can was hiring three
new consultants what do you hope to
achieve with these new hires sure well
the board approved a plan for working on
conflict of interest issues and one part
of that plan was to hire external
experts so we scanned the world to try
try to find some of the best experts in
the world and we're very fortunate to
connect with German Brooks and his group
they'll be reviewing the code of conduct
and bylaws and other aspects of I can
and in our performance and living up to
those two to help us get I think an
objective benchmarking of how we're
doing and where we need to focus going
forward Steve where are you at in terms
of finding a successor for rod as CEO
search process is well underway we had a
report today from George sadowsky who is
chairing that committee rod very
graciously announced in mid August that
he would continue his through his tenure
to the two July first and gave us a very
good amount of time
to do an orderly search process we
advertised we communicated with the
community we laid out what criteria we
thought was appropriate we took feedback
on that way engaged a very high quality
search firm and we formed a committee
within the board to oversee that process
we have received a large number of
applications and we have narrowed that
and narrow that and wearing that process
we are keeping extremely close control
over the specifics out of concern for
the privacy of the individuals who
applied so I'm not going to give numbers
or names but it's moving on schedule and
it's in it's moving along quite well
bottom line when will you make the
announcement well there's always a
certain amount of uncertainty about how
the details yet but hopefully you know
on the somewhere in the May time frame
probably give or take let me ask both of
you gentlemen this question looking back
at the past week in this meeting here in
San Jose Costa Rica what stands out in
your mind a couple of highlights first I
thought that sunyata President does
speech Laura Chinchilla was just
exceptional and we were honored to have
the president of Costa Rica speaking to
us and was such a hard-hitting clear
visionary view of the Internet where
it's common where it needs to go so it
was really just just amazing to see such
a powerful and elegant leader really
engaging in global internet governance
issues and I think that inspired
everyone that was here and I even had
attendees telling me they wish that they
had a president like that in their
country so that was very positive for me
the second highlight was probably the
signing of some letters of exchange with
lek nique to add more root server
capacity in Latin America helping us
with the l root system where they're
going to support multiple instances
across the region and that signals are
really warm and welcome a partnership
with a very important international body
like nick the regional registry here so
those are the two highlights many
challenging question because there
highlights across the board but I
certainly have to agree that President
shakyas speech was moving for those of
us who have heard many speeches and been
around a lot that speech stands out i
would rate it not just as an excellent
speech but a historic one that one that
will be referenced and serve as a high
water mark for some time to come in
addition the the points that rod is made
are right a couple of things that stand
out in my mind this was there was a
regional summit of the Latin American
Caribbean regional at large organization
lack Rallo and there was a comparable
meeting of African gac members and
at-large members here in in San Jose
following up on a similar summit that
they had into car so both of those are
tremendously important organizational
cohesion type events and really signal a
maturation in the growth within the
regions of awareness and cooperation and
from an i can point of view are just
tremendous that's not the end of it
there there was more quite a lot of
progress on the things you talked about
on the ra a conflict of interest of
hard-hitting very specific kinds of
things a lot of focus on who is which
has been a problem for a long time and a
really quite superior panel showing a
lot of the details and bringing people
together than and i'm sure i'm
forgetting several there's a lot yeah
there was a lot of what one of the most
impressive things is that it's hard to
pick things because everywhere you go
there's an extraordinary amount of
action it's it's a rich community with
an enormous number of things going on
also when i say i think it was a lot of
healthy discussion and debate on the
conflict of interest issues this week
following on some of my remarks and a
lot of reaction to that and and I saw
that come in a lot of the sessions
people talking about balance and what's
the right way to do things
and I certainly hope and I feel that
that does help to move the conversation
forward so it's very encouraging to see
gentlemen thank you very much thank you
you