today I'm going to talk about how to
abuse Azure ad
post authentication vulnerabilities we
found earlier this year
so I'm going to do a lot of demos so a
couple of slides then to the demos and
they are live demo so let's see how it
goes as always
nice to you know try to tease demo cards
okay so I got already introduced so
it's me nestory hi I'm from Finland I
work for CQ works and you can you know
follow me on Twitter and also in
masterton because that's what we do
nowadays
uh I'm a Microsoft MVP
and I'm also Microsoft MBR which stands
for Microsoft's most valuable researcher
so every year in dacat US Microsoft
security Response Center is publishing a
list of 100 most valuable researchers
and I was secondly on that list and this
time I was on on 70th Place
so it's nice to be there
okay so most of the people around the
world know me from my toolkit A8
internals anybody use that here
okay a couple of yes okay well I have
some stickers here so I can you can uh
you know
just pick me from my leave later on and
I will give you a sticker If you want to
so it's an open source tool and I'm
gonna use that today also
uh it's been listed by my attacks since
February this year as a soft s677 and it
has been used by groups like apt-29
also known as nobelium and as we as we
track that in City work it's called Ira
ritual but the same organization
but they haven't paid me anything any
ransomware they got from this so
yeah
and today's talk it's based on three
let's say documents if we also two blog
post of me and then secure Works threat
analysis we published on I think that
was in September yes
so
today I'm going to cover three things
not necessarily in this order
but anyways I'm going to tell you what
is possible indication
how we can abuse that and also how to
detect the abuse and how to mitigate if
possible
and let's start with talking about Cloud
security
so quite I have got this question quite
many times that is cloud secure and I
would say that yes cloud is secure as
thoughts
so it's easy for users they just need to
you know provide some form of proof of
identity and they are able to you know
use their services
it is bad for attackers or threat actors
because they can't use their old you
know methods to penetrate on-prem they
can't do that anymore
so yeah if you are using only Cloud it's
okay
but most of the organizations are not
Cloud only they are so-called hybrid
which means that they are using same
identities in your on-prem and then also
in Cloud
and that's good for admins because it's
easier to manage you have only one set
of management tools
and it's good for users because you can
use same credentials in on-prem and in
Cloud
and it's extremely good for attackers or
threat actors
because why because when you are doing
this hybrid you're actually connecting
your on-prem to cloud and you are poking
holes to that safe Cloud environment
and guess what
attackers can now attack your on-prem
and Via on-prem they can get into your
cloud
so that's what happened during the solar
arcade attacks for instance
and there are plenty of options you can
choose that reads like authentication
option you are using and today we are
going to talk about the
where is here the ptas
and talking about PTA let's go to the
high level architecture to how it works
so here it is
so basically what happens is that when
users are trying to log in in an
organization that is using PTA it is
like typing the credentials using my
password in Cloud okay
and then after already is sending those
credentials to eight cents that are
installed in your on-prem environment so
they need to be installed on server
domain joint
it's right here as we can see
and those credentials are like encrypted
and the 18 is decrypting them and then
technically the Third
part here is it is sending those
credentials to system 32 function called
logon user W so basically it's trying to
log in as that user
and that's when the agent is actually
connecting to on-prem ad
and then it will will return the results
so that's the high level architecture
but now let's go into details
so this is what happens when the PTA
agent is starting up
and as you can see
here on the top left there's a
certificate which means that
PDA agents are using certificates as an
authentication method so they are using
certificate based on application or CBA
and it is connecting to
the Azure ID and the first thing it
wants to get is a configuration and that
is called bootstrap
and that what happens with the steps one
two four
so basically it start by connecting to
Azure ready and it's telling us already
that hey give me the configuration and
when it gets the configuration
it is establishing websocket connections
to Azure service bus
so it usually has like eight different
connection points it is oh sorry input
is connecting to so this happens what
you start updated
and now the 18th is ready to you know uh
for receiving the authentication request
and now what happens Technically when
you authenticate it is like this so
everything starts with a service bus
we're actually already sending you the
credentials to use a type when he or she
logged in right
and then it says that actually first
that hey connect to this relay and then
18 connects to relay and then by a relay
you will get the authentication request
and then on step four
you will the agent is sending those
allocation response to a proxy so
there's a lot of components here so it's
very messy but it's a white robust
actually it's working all right
now what is inside that authentication
request then so that's an important
so actually I think I forgot to mention
that Microsoft says that you should have
at least three agents for high
availability and a maximum number is
like 40.
so technically you can't add more than
40 agents
and in order to get some request you
have the users username and password and
the password is like encrypted
and it has entry for all agents here so
every agent usually get the list of
sorry the authentication request and it
has entries for each of those agents and
usually there's only one
certificate per agent but there can be
more than one usually if you are
compromised but there are certain
situations where that's normal for a
short period of time but anyways based
on this information like a key
identifier so that's the agent ID and
then the thumbprint of the certificate
so those help the AIDS and recognize
weeds like encrypt that block I should
be decrypting
so yeah
we will get back to this later and now
how to abuse PDA now that we know some
technical backgrounds and I only have
like 30 minutes so I need to move
forward quite fast
so
to abusing
so I've been doing this PTA app using
since 2019 at least so that was when I
published a thing called PDS pie
and to use that it requires that you
will get the local admin level access to
that server that is running PDA agent so
you don't need to be like domain admin
or anything like that local admin is
just fine
and what you do there is that you
actually inject the dll
to the PTA agent process
and what it what that technically does
is that it replaces the local user W
system function
in that process not in the whole
computer but in that process
and it accepts all the password so it
doesn't communicate with ad anymore it's
just accepting every password you keep
them
and it also saves all the credentials to
the local CSV file
and I heard that apt-29 has been using
this actual PDS pie for you know
Gathering credentials but also like as a
backdoor because it accepts every
password you are able to login as any
user you want to right
but this is a bit noisy
you know when you are injecting
something in processes in Windows it's
uh well every EDR solution nowadays will
you know
notice that and block that or whatever
they are doing
so we invited another way so this is
based on our research this year
so we can now steal the identity of the
pdas and so so we don't have to be on
the server anymore we can be the server
and this also requires only local admin
permissions on the target server so what
we do here we just you know get the
certificate with the PTA agent is using
for CBA and also for decrypting those
credentials
and we put it on the threat actor
control computer and now we can
impersonate that agent
without any connection to the on-prem
anymore
and you want to see some demos
okay so let's let's do that and I'm
going to test a Meek now Mike now
okay yes
nice
so let's see how this works
okay
I found my mouse great
um and I'm pretty much in time so
it might be a bit funny because I
I don't know how this actually works
because I don't know let me try
something
it's a bit far away to see there
so let's try something totally different
now that's better
okay
so what do we have here so we have two
let's say Target organization servers so
we have a domain controller that has pth
and running
it's a bit small here but it's this
to right there
and then we have the server that only
has PTA and it also has the agent
running right there
okay
and then we have the attacker machine
and let's start by
running the pts boy
but first i'm gonna shut down the oh no
I'm not going to do that yet sorry about
that I was going ahead of my time
so
let's open up
admin portal
of the organization
so
what an admin can see about those ptas
and so we are now running two of them
and here's the admin portal which shows
us that okay we have two agents
we know their names and the IP addresses
and that they are active
and that's the only information you can
get as a as an admin from the portal
however there are some API
endpoints that you can use to request
the same information and I'm also
implementing this in Aid internal so I'm
going to say get a 80 in what is that
called proxy Athens
and form a table
and here we can see
in a second okay so now we can see the
same information here but we can also
see what is the ID of the agent and that
is important
because that kind of will it identifies
the
agent so now we're part of director
stuff so again when I go back to Paul
here and I'm gonna go to signing logs
like right here okay
okay two fat fingers
let's go back and sign in locks
so we can see signing events here
and I'm going to try to find out the
correct one I would like you to see
there's too many of these okay so
failure failure stocks is that try
that one
and when we go to authentication details
we see that well it's very small
so when I you know hover my mouse there
it says that this was possible
indication and the agent ID here is 3E
something so you can see actually that
which states and perform this the login
so if they are like a
some weird behavior that okay these
certain agent is like accepting
everything or blocking everything you
know that okay maybe that's compromised
but anyways
uh
I'm actually going to start a script
here that is showing this same status
here every three seconds okay and now I
go to DC and I'm going to shut down this
particular 18th row that we can be sure
that the PTA server is going to get all
the requests
and I'm gonna
start the publisher here and as we can
see I created a new version def cam
Edison for just for this conference
and what I'm going to do now is that I'm
going to install AED in PDS by
are you sure about that yes
and it's completed and I'm going to open
the process hacker I'm gonna search for
azure
I'm going to tune in so not yet so it's
this one
and
I'm gonna tube in a bit so I can see
that the PTA spy is actually injected in
that process okay so now it's accepting
all the passwords and and saving
everything to
to a file and now I'm going to try to
sign in as this user
and what password should be
try okay
hello if
camp
and it doesn't actually matter what I
type here because it accepts everything
and I'm just gonna no that one I need to
log out
I don't want to say my password okay
sign out
and when I go back to this computer now
I can say
get a ad
int okay can type
PDA spy lock
and provide decrypt Optical passwords
and now it shows the password so hello
devcamp here and it shows when it
happens as well but anyways as I told
you this is a bit like noisy it's easy
to be get caught
so let's um
let's do the stealing the identity stuff
now
it's going to close this one
and
I have another
session here it's red because that I
recognize that because when I run this
command to export or certificates this
system gets elevated to local system
which means that you can't use that to
anything after that so I'm just going to
say export in
proxy AIDS and
certificates
and it's exporting everything
and as we can see there's two different
certificates
and I happen to know that the one that
starts with 308 is the correct one okay
now what I'm going to do is that I'm
going to shut down the agent also here
like this and then I go to attacker
machine where I have already copied that
certificate
and when we were researching this we
actually implemented our own
let's say
proof of concept of agent
and I'm going to show you how that works
so I'm going to run PTA agent it's on
very small sorry about that
and I'm going to provide the certificate
which we have
which we have here it's the dev camp
so it's that one and also I need to
provide the name for the machine
and I say okay hacked
and let's see what happens
it should work but we we don't know
because that's a proof of concept so so
it is so it was actually now connecting
to those endpoints I was mentioning
earlier so these are in the
configuration file and now when you are
looking at the bottom of the screen the
name and the IP address should now
change
and why that happens is that we we
discovered that that IP address is
changed whenever the agent is getting
the configuration
and when it's getting the configuration
it's also sending the machine name
so it should like change here in okay
now we can see so it's hacked and the IP
address changed so you all get caught
okay this obviously works so if I go
here and try to sign in
well hopefully it works
I just type something here
and we should see some traffic here
let's see
again because it's a proof of concept
it's not that stable so it didn't work
this time
so we're just gonna
start again
and let's try again
and it should show us the password it's
a couple of seconds but again it depends
so
this is nice to have this you know live
demos but I'm gonna do that one more
time we have a time for that
also so also the network connection
might be one of the reasons but
let's just try a
but we said we see the yeah but there's
like a no it doesn't want to work now
let's see if it works after a couple of
seconds
or minutes maybe maybe not but anyway
what's the point it was here that
that
you will get caught because the name and
IP address changes right
but we discovered that if you like
provide the configuration to the agent
so that it doesn't need to get that so
it is connecting to directly those
endpoints
the IP address and the name doesn't
change
so
so now I go back to
the
PTA server I'm going to start the agent
so it will get the
configuration and change the IP
ax is original and I think
I think it's done already so I can stop
that
so it should change back
but now I'm going to run the same pth in
here but now this time I'm going to
provide the bootstrap
and now you can see the name James back
to original
and now when I provide the bootstrap
it is connecting there now but
because it's not getting the
configuration from the server those
stays the same
so let's try to log in now if if that
helped anything
because now I'm running this from the
local computer and it's connected to
internet via my phone so it might be not
fast enough so that might be the reason
that it you know doesn't allow us to log
in but anyways as we can see that the
name didn't change even though we
connected there so this is a way that if
you eyeball as an as an uh threat actor
you're able to get that
certificate it gives you like undetected
access to the organization
and also what I would like to you to see
is that if I provide a parameter called
failure and into any Windows like error
code like here
it will it will work as a denial of
service attack because now you anybody
can log in it says that your account is
disabled so I'm just trying to run this
one more time
and if it doesn't work it doesn't work
so but I can then demonstrate it later
on
so let's try once again
no it doesn't want to do that but
anyways what it what the agent is doing
now here it would show the password of
the user and then saying that you are
your account is locked so you can log in
to every user and you don't know what
the hell is happening
and and um
what you can do actually is now you can
go to see the signing logs that if
there's a there is an agent ID that is
like you know
uh having like blocking other users or
accessing every user and then you can do
something about that but what you can do
as an admin
so now when I go back to the portal and
I see that okay this particular agent
here is now compromised
so what can I do as an admin
there's no delete button here that I
want to you know delete this I8 and so
you can't do anything well actually you
can
so
when you don't use that agent for 10
days so it's inactive it goes away
automatically
but so you can install your uninstall
your server and wait for 10 days but
that doesn't help why not
because the threat actor is using your
you know certificate
so it it remains active until well
forever well it may it remains active as
long as the certificate is valid
but guess what
you can renew that certificate using the
old old certificate and you can do that
again and again and again
so
that means that now and it also this
system allows that the one agent has
more than one certificate so we tried
and it was something like 10 118 can
have 10 certificates but you can see it
here you can only see that okay there
are agents active but you don't know how
many of those are are compromised or are
they
so for that purpose we in Secure works
we actually created a tool
that is called PTA agents and dump and
we're gonna that's a free tool we're
gonna publish it later this week
hopefully
which allows you uh to see that whether
you are compromised or not
so I'm going to show how that works
so now I'm running this command on the
PTA server which you can to do also just
shut down the original agent
then I'm going to run the tool here so
PDA agent
dump
oh sorry wrong place
and then I'm going to provide the
certificate
which is under demo and
it's not that one it's this one and
that's it and now it also connects to if
we can see the connections here
we can't
that's nice
let's try again
okay now we can see that that is
connecting
and then you just need to sign in
using any user or and also any password
it doesn't matter
okay well
it already did that okay so what it does
is that it actually if you remember the
audience gets a request so it can see
that all the agent and the certificate
pairs so here we can see that it says
that this particular agent has two
active certifications so now we know
that tractor has
you know export your certificate and
they have renewed that so somewhere
there is a threat actor that is you know
doing this stuff and you can see that
anywhere
we accept using our tool which allows
you to list those at least
but after that you know the agent ID you
need to report to micro tap that hey
remove this so they can do that but you
can do it by yourself
okay
so I think that was all the demos I was
gonna show you
and
takeaways from my talk
so first one my personal opinion don't
use PTA
that's a piece of fine technology but
two fine in currently because you can't
you can't detect that and you can't you
know do any medications
except for you know connecting Microsoft
and to protect yourself against these
kind of attacks is the first thing is
that you need to create any of those
servers that are involved in hybrid
identity as a tr0 servers which means
that you need to protect them as well as
you protect your domain controllers and
that's the first step so this wouldn't
happen at all
and then you can use MFA
which prevents using PTA as a backdoor
because that doesn't you know allow you
to bypass back door it only accepts all
the passwords and as we probably know
MFA is post on vacation like protection
mechanism so if you are using PTA you
are blocking that using as a backdoor
but you can still Harvest credentials as
a direct actor you can't log in but you
can Harvest credentials and maybe use
them in other services
and then you should monitor those items
in a regular bases like are the other IP
addresses changing and you can do that
with A8 internals or by calling
Microsoft apis and you should monitor
those certificates using the ptas and
dump
when we publish that obviously and then
to follow any such business activity in
signing logs
and finally if you see that there's
something
suspices going on with some PDA agent
you need to contact Microsoft to remove
that
and with that and 22nd
left in my schedule thank you
[Applause]
thank you so much
um technically we can take some
questions but we're gonna eat out of
your break so if you want to ask
questions just
you know
choose between that and go into the
bathroom so we can take one or two
questions here
hello uh thanks thanks for the
presentation uh I have a question
um there was a recently an attack well
it's not necessarily recently but
um a Microsoft researcher who presented
a Nico X relay attack Nico X being the
protocol that Azure ad uses that is
similar to to Kerberos or it's based on
the same API uh and it's active on any
any machine that's joined to an Azure to
Azure ID and he demonstrated an attack
that's similar to ntlm relay but but
done on on this new protocol Nico X do
you know if that still is that related
to this does that still work if PTA is
disabled or does does PTA need to be
enabled for that attack to work I have
to say that that doesn't ring a bell so
I think that it's not related to PDA
assets yes okay but we can discuss about
that offline okay sure thank you thank
you
are there any more questions we can take
maybe another question
if not then thank you so much for your
presentation and uh in about two minutes
we'll start the next one
[Applause]