so if you if you probably you know
walked with the
understand you probably saw a lot of
people soldering opening some devices
doing some wacky things on them I was
like when I was passing I was like oh
this is interesting this is the smart
people over here you know so we think
that it was interesting enough I'm not
going to go into the knitting written
boring details but I will welcome and I
don't know what the prizes are by the
way maybe you can tell tell me what the
prices are so first price we apparently
the handed over only two spots I don't
know why is that but so first spot is
Adeline totaro I presume let's give him
a round of applause
okay so uh congratulations
you've got a medal man
you've got a medal come on act happy act
surprised
and I and I can see here that apparently
they saw they sell this only in the us
because we include an adapter as well
which is good thank you so what do you
want to see a few words or
drink all the Bulls hack all the things
patience
okay
and places number two Gabriel
he is not around here
okay you also got a medal and you also
get a diploma
I want to play as well in this
competition they give out Xboxes for
Uncle Plus for this guy
so you want to say a few things
yeah so never trust your router again
okay yeah or build your own if you're
dead
thanks a lot friend of applause
I told you there are only two places so
this goes
back to you whenever you're ready so
four is yours thank you thank you very
much
uh the next on the stage should be hack
the hackers
[Applause]
okay so hi I'm Alex I'm here from
appendix tools our contest was to
basically about Bounty find
vulnerabilities in paint stools uh
congrats to you guys you know yourself
we talked a lot these days so number one
alexandrian
[Applause]
want to ask
we'll do a row so we can stay here
number two Mars next show
[Applause]
and number three George wagos
thank you
directory two people
everyone around the road Plus for them
please
thank you very much and congratulations
give me one second
next in line
it is my pleasure to invite for
ariadness thread 5.0
[Applause]
so old so old so very old
yeah
hey little guy
remember from three years ago
so
um Ariana's thread fifth edition
um third prize Stefano prishan please
come to the stage
with the medal or with the medal
whatever
congrats hope you enjoyed it
apologies for the technical difficulties
that may or may not have been but yeah
congrats
um
second place Andrea vasiloyo
[Applause]
was that a surprise
foreign
I think you actually have switched so
yeah congrats
thank you and last but certainly not
least
first prize you're not slalo
[Applause]
congrats this one and this one and uh
so
to quote from a previous winner snort
all the tobacco
and
do your things congrats folks always a
pleasure
next
um it is my pleasure to invite somebody
who will represent a network forensics
Adventure
[Applause]
everyone my name is I'm here to deal
with my colleague christieone and we
work at Seaside and it's our pleasure to
announce the winners for
Adventures so for first place uh Dominic
Eduardo doroka
[Applause]
what are you doing there
have some patience
congratulations
for second place uh Francois de Ville
hope I pronounced it correct
congrats
and your prize
right yeah yeah
thank you cheers and for the third place
uh dragons
[Applause]
there you go
congrats thank you and your prize
thank you
thank you very much
I hope you guys had fun and I really
hope to see you again next year for
another round of
hacking
cheers
next in line we should have a Target
Zone
you as well
me again okay so this is going to build
with more of an analog challenge
so um
this was a bit of a more humid ocean
type of thing so basically if you
thought things get couldn't get any
weirder you had to play Target John but
I know for a fact that three lucky
people got at least two or three Tinder
matches and they are in the order yes
it's you know getting a Tinder match was
one of the challenges of this um
things so without further Ado let me
actually let's do it the other way
around let's present place number three
which I think it reads
uh hold on because I also have it
written in digital format as well
because uh I'd like to invite Antonio
budnaryuk here come on
so let let's see what face gets you
third prize for Tinder he's the guy he's
the guy pretty good pretty good
congrats man congrats congrats
here we go you don't get a medal but you
also got a Tinder Tinder match so you
know do you want to say a few words
Bluetooth device on wacky Place each
place doesn't know uh you are right but
you're not supposed to turn it on or at
least do it in the in the intimacy of
your own home but thanks a lot thanks
Mom and congratulations Round of
Applause
okay so number two foreign
come on come on come on
this
okay I will have a chat with the guy
that wrote this but congrats man
thank you nice ring so do you want to
say a few words
I would like to thank you my team
pentastools.com you are a great one go
Panthers
thanks a lot man and congrats
and place number one for Tinder match
I'd like to invite let me double check
the name again because I've already made
a fool of myself once
don't you
it's a girl right it's a girl come on
come on Applause
come on kindly mind that Applause
okay so congrats do you want to see a
few words you don't want to say anything
right
um at the Target John rule number one
was to be anti-social I think it you had
to be very social to win this
okay I'm sure to pass down to the
organizers so round of applause
thank you this will be my last
intervention for the evening see you
thank you Sebastian so congratulations
to all the winners and next we will have
lock picking Village
hello
so thanks to crowdstrike for this
awesome Workshop uh we've got a bunch of
prizes that will secure you'll have very
nice cozy place when the apocalypse hits
so whenever
you know hits the fan
somebody's got the skills to pay the
bills so without further Ado we've got a
a bunch of Lucky winners I'd like to
invite on the stage please hold your
approaches until we invite everybody uh
all right so Gabrielle chubota
dragosh juancha Florin Catalin bugario
bunch of floating again and darzoches
are Marius
and we've got another set of winners
hang on we have
uh the ban Alex
we've got Roca Dominic
Nitza horia
and for the grand prize for the guy that
actually knows the skills please welcome
us Claudio per shoyu
we can actually make a gang now so don't
get crowdstrike for the physical get
outs for the cyber thank you
[Applause]
congratulations
and meanwhile I guess we can continue
with uh
spider's net
some applies
[Applause]
who is announcing the winners
hello I'm Livio I'm the proud organized
main helper for the spider Darkness CTF
and I would like to announce the our
best warriors like our best cyber
Warriors for uh today and yesterday
I'm going to start with the team that
got the third place uh I would like to
invite on the scene nacy Warriors
wait a second I I totally agreement I'm
sorry okay it was in a zaiwan sorry
[Applause]
okay
I've already made a fool of myself once
uh I would also like to invite the Timon
uh place number two brusselsville
[Applause]
and for the the big winners of today
I would like to invite the team
PlayStation on the scene which
iconically won their third Xbox in this
competition
[Applause]
okay
thank you everyone it was a great
competition and we're gonna handle the
prizes right there because it's gonna
take a while
[Applause]
congratulations
and we will move to the next one which
is passport to prizes
[Music]
[Applause]
we need a box with some names inside yes
in the middle
all right you take the mic
thank you hi everyone congratulations to
everyone that caught all the stamps here
so I guess we need to open it up
aha
lots of you did this all right that's
kind of cool uh Christina if you can
help me a little bit to hold or actually
so the first prize
would be
the VR Oculus
all right
I'm not looking
send your best energy here for Christina
and we have a winner which is
anas dachma
are you around here
all right fair enough
tough luck for her him or her the second
one Xbox series C console so whoever
wants an Xbox send the good energy
I guess there are a couple that don't
want one anymore
and the second one would be
alexandru miklos
all right
[Applause]
hey Alex
or this way
there's your prize
yeah congratulations
who would have thought
and the last one which is JBL box
to listen quietly to music in your own
house or in nature and the winner is
Alex Alex
it's a nice it's a nice one
here you go
on his behalf
that's called social engineering
all right thank you everyone for
participating for uh in this uh
Challenge and for filling up every time
everything hope you had a good time and
see you next year
thank you and congratulations to the
winners
next on the stage we will have
the secure open vote election
thank you
okay so a few years ago at Defcon not to
be confused with deaf Camp the one in
Las Vegas I hacked a mock election
reporting system when I was 11 years old
and I'm like I can build a better system
than this so I created my election
reporting system for my voting system
secure open vote I brought it to Defcon
about two years ago no one was able to
change the vote count so I brought it
this time to Europe thinking maybe
someone can hack it here and no one was
able to change the vote count so I can't
give out any prizes because no one could
hack my system thank you there we go
and now
last but not least last but not least we
will have on the stage in Europe houses
these City fee
dcdf
oh
[Applause]
thank you
did you enjoy this Edition
right
okay
so it gives me a lot of pressure to
announce the winners of this editions of
devcom CTF so the Edition number 12. and
in order to do this I also invited one
of our old friends we can we can see
before we can see it from from the
audience so this is our friend esku it's
escu it's not eska
and
we will start with the
third place and I will
I will ask esku to give us the name of
the team which was positioned on the
third place in the death camp CTF 2022
time to announce the winners for 2022
the third place goes to the few chosen
so the future is on
uh
so will give us some
some thoughts about the experience Korea
it was an amazing experience uh we were
so grateful to be a part of this
beautiful competition alongside uh our
uh like uh enemies let's say even though
they're not enemies
um
we think we did a really good job and
we're really proud of ourselves and uh
we're really proud of cyber edu for uh
coasting such a beautiful competition
thank you
so thank you again and congratulations
[Applause]
okay
so don't leave just stay here no don't
leave from the audience thing
so what
is
so second place they've come CTF 2022 I
will ask again Esco
the second place goes to Lucky Lucian
lucky Lucian
also from Romania
[Applause]
okay lucky Lucian Lucian
[Music]
who will tell us some words
just pick one of you
who is the who is the leader of the team
so please congratulations
it was a very tough competition
especially this was attack defense so
the the opponents make half of the
competition it's like one thing is
challenges but the hard hard opponents
are actually making it even harder and I
mean we we use all our tips and tricks
of our sleeves and there was still a
better team so you know
we wait for for the yeah maybe next year
thank you again and congratulations for
your work
now before to
ask the first place I would also like to
join me and congratulate the def Camp
team and all the volunteers and the
partners that are help us to organize
and to deliver this event so please
Round of Applause
okay so in school who is the winning
team for this edition of death camp CTF
and the first place goes to wreck the
line
oh wreck the line please join me here
and congratulations
also dragash I will uh ask you to tell
us some
finesse okay Venus
all right uh what can I say uh I guess
it was 2018 when we are we first played
these finals and we got a fourth place
then uh the following year 2019 we got a
third place in the finals uh followed by
2020 second place uh 2021 we got the
first place at the online edition of
devcam CTF and now here we are uh 2022
first place at a def cam finals on site
obviously uh thank you
uh probably one final thing to add
we got this new cool merch we dragged
the line obviously uh and we left a
bunch of uh spots on this on the back if
anyone any company would like to sponsor
egg design in order to find this
so congratulations again guys excellent
job
and now also we have uh the best team
from Romania Awards
so Esco please give us the name of the
best Romanian team at this edition of
def cam CTF 2022
the best team from Romania is the few
chosen so again the futurism please
and congratulations guys
dude
so again the last few words from the
winning Romanian team
proud to be a Romanian excellent work
thank you guys and congratulations again
[Applause]
so a big round of applause for all the
teams not only the winning one all the
other teams
thank you
see you next year
congratulations to everyone and I guess
the ceremony
is close to the end this was uh the 12th
edition of death camp thank you very
much for uh for being here thank you
very much for your presence and for um
for your energy
thank you very much for the organizers
and at last but not least again my
glasses and then let me read
the list of sponsors without
this event couldn't couldn't happen
without them so first orange business
services for being our main support for
many years now thank you for secure
Works bit Sentinel keysight Technologies
pen test tools booking crowdstrike
Siemens infoblox expressvpn KPMG Tera
Huawei happening ztec and cyberado
[Applause]
so hope you had a great fun and see you
next week next week next year
have a nice evening bye
[Applause]
[Music]