thank you very much for the introduction
this this presentation concerns
the the description of a system which
allows for the arithmetic computations
to be performed directly over encrypted
data
the real world use case involves that
the medical data is collected from the
enrolled patients
um they are transported to the back-end
components where they are processed so
the arithmetic computations are
conducted directly over the encrypted
data and they are also stored in a
secure fashion and the decryption occurs
only at the client side when the patient
requests
some medical information
so just a few words about myself I am an
associate professor at the Transylvania
University of brushov
uh in this capacity I conduct various
didactic and research oriented
activities
and I am also a researcher with the
Siemens Industry software in in Bradshaw
in the department of research and
technology and I also conduct a research
projects with business
oriented value
just a little bit of
mathematical background before jumping
into the presentation of the use case
we should be able to
make computations directly over the
encrypted data and in this respect we
use two logical Gates
it's a and and
exclusive or as you see here
so the exclusive war is the gate which
is being used for the sum and at the end
is being used for the product
and the reason behind this is clearly
visible here
and uh we we can say that this system
that is made up of the end and exclusive
or Gates is during Complete because we
can perform any kind of uh arithmetic
operation using only these two gates
the the whole idea is based on the
concept of fully homomorphic encryption
historically the concept has been
introduced in the scientific literature
uh by a researcher that is named Gentry
in 2008
where he presented it in his PhD thesis
and a fully homomorphic encryption
system is capable of conducting any
number of additions and multiplication
okay so I'll jump over some of the
slides that may not be interesting
uh for uh for this
uh particular stage of the presentation
and uh I'll uh I'll start by talking
about
the mechanism which is behind the
symmetric encryption
so in order to define the symmetric
encryption model uh let us consider our
secret key as a very large odd number
that is uh designated by PE
then in order to encrypt a certain bit B
we choose a preferably random large
multiple of P so we get the Q times p
then we choose a preferably small number
which is called the noise in the context
of our discussion which is uh 2 times R
plus b
and this noise is very
relevant in our discussion because it is
important to keep it at a proper level
as otherwise it would be impossible to
decrypt the beats and therefore the
fully homomorphic encryption
computations would output an incorrect
bit and would not work at all
so uh
one of the main tasks in implementing a
system like the one that is described in
this presentation is to keep the level
of the noise under control
and there are several techniques in this
respect
one of the most used techniques
is uh referred as the bootstrapping
method
so why why is this important because in
a kind of an exclusive or operation
which which implement the uh the
addition operation
you you see that the noise is relatively
small from a quantitative perspective
but
if we apply an end operation so if we
perform a multiplication
the size of the noise
which is
okay
does not work
you have to hold it
okay so this is the noise
and we we see that is it is sensibly
larger than what the the addition
operation would produce
I am
so in order to keep the noise under
control several Solutions have been uh
proposed and the the most well-known one
is called as the bootstrapping method
uh what does the bootstrapping method
says
we establish a predefined threshold
and if
the size of the noise goes beyond that
threshold we should apply certain
arithmetic methods in order to decrease
the respective value
and we'll see in a moment how we
implemented this in our real world use
case scenario
and usually the threshold
is
set as a half of the value of the
ciphertext but of course in real world
settings this can take other values as
well
and I'll jump over to the presentation
of of the use case so that you can
understand better
what this is all about
okay so the use case is uh reported
mainly into to papers the first one
which describes the initial version of
the system has been published in 2019
and the second one which describes an
updated version of the system has been
published this year
as you as you see here
it considers the following use case
there are
750 patients that are citizens of of
Bradshaw City in Romania
and each of the enrolled patients is
fitted with the polar h10 wearable
device which is essentially measures
their cardiac Rhythm data
and the data is being transmitted using
a Bluetooth connection to their mobile
phones and the mobile phone sends it
over to the
backend components for further
processing and the data processing
occurs directly over the encrypted data
which uh
practically overt any attempt to
tamper with the data or to to read it
even if a hacker got access to the
system he would not be able to use it in
any useful way
okay so uh in order to transfer the data
we use uh virtualize the 5G data
channels and the 5G data channels are
defined
using uh the virtual Network function
model as it is known in the literature
uh in essence this means that instead of
using Hardware components for every
level of the 5G Network we simply use a
certain virtualization model and most of
these Hardware components are defined by
your software
routines
okay so um in order to specify and
implement the 5G virtual channels we
have used the Ericsson Network function
virtualization infrastructure
and as you can see uh here the
uh
the first stage pertains to the data
acquisition as I told you using uh the
acquisition method that I described then
the second stage refer to the data
transmission to the backend components
uh the back-end components for our use
case are being deployed into the IBM
Cloud infrastructure but of course it
can be deployed to any other Cloud
modern Cloud infrastructure
okay uh the third stage it's uh the the
actual storage of the collected data and
of course we also have data processing
uh we'll see in a moment how data is
being processed in a homomorphic
encryption manner
we see here a general schema of the
system you see that there are basically
two data pads when we deal with the
transmission of system State data we use
a standard standardly encrypted data
Channel
and when we should deal with the
personal uh data we use the fully
homomorphic encryption routines why is
this because
um the fully homomorphic encryption
routines are very time expensive
okay
uh uh so what what word are the basic
operation that the system supports
the first operation is the homomorphic
addition
we've already understood how this is
implemented
then we deal with homomorphic
multiplications
and the implementation is done using an
end gate
then we have the homomorphic rotate as
the name implies
it rotates the data bits at some moment
during the data processing stages
and then is the homomorphic
cell mask operation
which has the role to correct the bits
that may become altered during the
computation
then
very important is this level
because this level is how the threshold
is being defined
um
one multiplication operation basically
increments with the one the value of
this level
and
we established a certain threshold for
the value of the level
and this threshold was determined
through successive experimental
assessments
and uh
we have made sure that any homorphic
operation is being conducted correctly
okay
and then we have another important
parameter which is the number of the
cipher texts which is this n city that
you can see here
and uh
let's see what what follows
here is a general uh
architectural model of the system which
suggests how the operations are being
performed
uh computationally wise
and um we have used our system and the
collected data in order to detect and
assess three medical parameters and
conditions
uh just as a an additional remark which
is not particularly important for the
fully homomorphic encryption is that we
have also included some and true
homomorphic
mechanisms apart from the standard fully
homomorphic encryption ones
uh This was done in order to speed up
the computation as much as as possible
okay
so the the slides that I jumped over uh
have always have already been presented
uh so uh there's no need to insist on
them
so what are the three medical parameters
and conditions which this system
considers uh
first is the average heart rate
which is uh determined out of the data
that is uh collected by the polar h10
sensors
then there is the delayed repolarization
of the heart
this is a hard medical condition which
is uh generated by a an abnormal
influx of the electrical signals that
flow through the heart
and this abnormal condition May
determine for the oxygenated blood to
mix up with the non-oxygenated blood
and the last one are the minimum and the
maximum Hertz heart rates
yes some brief remarks about each of
these conditions and how they were they
were implemented the
the computation of the average Verge
rate is based on the storage of the
encrypted values using those and CT
ciphertexts that have been mentioned
and in in essence we
perform a homomorphic addition
and then we divide it by the number of
the values that have been collected
during a certain period of time
uh client-wise the client is being
represented by an Android application
and when the user requests
the average herd value
he specifies a certain time interval and
in a certain time interval there is a
number of Cipher texts that have been
collected
okay so uh
the the detection of the delayed
repolarization of the heart syndrome
uh considers a certain time interval in
this example we speak about
475 milliseconds
the the parameters that you see here
mainly tqt and trr are standard medical
parameters or physiological parameters
that are generated by any
electrocardiogram test
[Music]
and the value of
475 milliseconds has been
ticked up and fine-tuned through
successive experimental evaluations
so that the detection rate became uh
had a high enough level of the accuracy
and uh foreign the last medical
condition we speak about the
minimum and the maximum heart rates
the the principle here
is to convert the data in a binary
format this data in a binary format is
being compared
bitwise in a homomorphic manner
and if the first number is greater than
the other number then the result will
include a single bit of one
if the the number is not greater then
[Music]
it we will have the opposite situation
and this is how we Implement a
comparison directly over the encrypted
data
and we are able to determine the minimum
heart rate and the maximum heart rates
okay
so uh the system currently supports
android-based client devices but
it can certainly be extended to any type
of mobile oriented client device
and the study population as I've already
mentioned is composed of
enrolled let's call them patients
although they are not like proper
patients
and the the data collection device is a
polar h10 h10 device
I I described how the data stream is
being
configured while the data collected by
the polars are being sent to the mobile
phones which in turn send them to the
background components which perform all
the computations
uh
the encryption occurs directly on the
client device so it's being sent over
over the 5G data channels in an
encrypted form
the computations and data storage is
also done in an encrypted format and
when the client so the patient requests
some medical information
the encrypted the data is sent back
the and the client devices uses the keys
that are stored for any data requests in
part and this is able to decrypt the
data only on the client device
the performance evaluation has
considered several parameters
the first ones refer to the data
transfer as you see here is a data
transfer in and the data transfer out
the direction of the transfer is
relative to the backend component so
transfer in means the data that enters
into the backend components and transfer
out is the data that gets out of the
backend component when the client
requests it
then is the storage ratio
we should know that uh
one bit of plain Text data is multiplied
by a number of times when it's being
processed in a homomorphic encryption
fashion
so if this storage ratio is for example
500 it means that one bit of plain Text
data is being
multiplied by five times in order to
store it in an encrypted format
then is the processing speed which is
defined as you see here the number of
the cipher texts and the very important
level L which which you understood
uh and
this this level L is essential as if we
don't manage it properly our whole
homomorphic encryption process will not
work properly
and the these are the performance Matrix
values that were obtained
um as you see here we have considered
the several
data collection intervals they range
from one minute and go all the way up to
24 hours
and the
on the First Column you see the load
that is placed on the 5G
data Channel
which
suggests that the 5G data channel is
used in a scalable fashion
or the most
load that has been registered is uh 0.81
which is very good considering the
amount of data
then we have the number of Cipher texts
that are being
processed and the values of the level l
and the amount of of data that has been
transferred
we have more data that's been sent out
of the back-end components
the the more frequent the data
collection intervals are so that will be
the explanation for this value
and finally the storage ratio and the
processing speed on the last two columns
these uh the values of this performance
metrics suggest that the system is
scalable
and as we determined in practice
it was capable to
[Music]
um
correctly determine and assess all the
implemented medical condition with the
accuracy with good accuracy
and also with the very good speeds from
a client perspective this means that
the greatest time that
the process took from the client
perspective or was at most three or four
seconds
which is a very good time considering
the complexity of the homomorphic
encryption operations that are performed
in the background
and uh
one uh let's call it anecdotal remark
considering the importance of the level
L that I've discussed about
uh during the the early stages of the
system's implementation the value of
this level was not properly calibrated
and we had the situation when a patient
that
has been wearing the polar h10
arrived in the uh Intensive Care Unit
due to some medical medical condition
and the the data that was being uh
reported at that time suggested that he
suffers he was suffering from uh that
delayed repolarization syndrome
which was not actually the case
so the incorrect calibration of the
level
produces uh very unexpected results
especially when we speak about personal
medical data
and this is as well the performance
metrics values for the detection of a
delayed repolarization syndrome
so
um as far as as we know
this system is one of the few
that collects the medical data in this
way and it also
encrypted end-to-end so from the client
devices to the server components and
backwards
uh which ensures Absolute Data privacy
in almost any condition
the downside of the approach is uh
represented by the fact that
the homomorphic encryption operations
are very time consuming
and
in the absence of a proper algorithmic
optimization we need increasingly more
powerful Hardware
components in order to be able to
sustain the the implementation of such
routines
therefore there is a lot to do
uh in the coming years concerning the
time efficiency and computational
efficiency of the homomorphic encryption
routines
in essence this is what I wanted to to
present
and I'm waiting for your questions
so do we have questions in the audience
yes
thank you for your presentation very
interesting I have several questions
so in the end
what exactly
is the encryption scheme
so uh the the encryption scheme uh is uh
for the
processing of the personal medical data
is that homorphic encryption scheme
which is based on the operations that I
enumerated so it's homomorphic and
addition homomorphic multiplication as
the two basic operations
that are sustained by you the end and
exclusive or Gates
and uh
this is the scheme and for the
transmission of data synchronization
or state data through the system we use
a standard AES
encryption scheme but for the processing
of the personal data is the homomorphic
encryption
okay yes we have another question
so I was curious can you speak a little
bit about why you had to use those 5G
virtual Network functions uh instead of
uh
um uh just a normal let's say https
based data transfer to get the data into
the secure
storage
uh so uh the the 5G is uh represents
only the physical layer which allows us
to implement the data channels for the
transmission of the data mainly in order
to contact the server backend components
uh of course we use secured data
channels
and the the choice for uh the 5G
virtualize the channels was made because
we wanted to see how such a system would
couple with the transmission of the data
through a virtualized 5G infrastructure
and how
such an infrastructure would would
simply scale up with the amount of data
the initial version of the system uh
consider the standard data connections
such as wireless connections uh 3G 4G
connections
but this represents a
another iteration of the research
great uh any other questions
yes yes we have a question
good day
thank you for the presentation and you
mentioned neutral system and and what
word do you use it do you think about
making pizza encryption post Quantum
safe
we haven't
relevant uh research assessments
concerning the level of safety against
the quantum computers attacks
so we I cannot express with a sufficient
degree of relevance on how safe the
model is for Quantum computer-based
attacks
but
at least for uh poorly implemented
attacks it should be
pretty safe yeah
okay uh I have seen another hand raised
over here someplace and my
yeah there
oh okay
so we've all you've already managed to
answer two questions in one so I think
that's a great performance uh thank you
so much uh for your presentation