uh hello so I'm Monica bojano I'm the
startup programs manager for orange
Romania I know I have the odd talk in
the in the whole conference I guess it's
a bit of a different subject but uh I'm
hoping that you cyber security uh
passionates uh will consider Building
Products this is what my talk is about
we're going to go into a bit of Basics
around this and I hope you get inspired
and you make the step towards this thing
first of all why am I here and why am I
representing orange Romania and
discussing about entrepreneurship and
building startups
um
for orange Romania we are running an
acceleration program for startups we've
been running it in Romania for the past
five years since 2017. we've worked with
eight cyber security startups from
Romania in this program already and I
hope there will be many many more coming
in the further years uh this is why I'm
here
um what we did so just to show that we
put our money where our words are we
have bought and we have resold products
from startups we have paid to Romanian
startups in the past five years 2.2
million euros and out of these
808 actually have 808 thousand uh went
to towards the security startups in
Romania in our program
so we are involved in this if anyone is
thinking about making the step I assure
you that there's a lot of support in the
in the community from Orange and from
all directors as well
a bit about myself and thank you for the
nice introduction I graduated computer
science a while ago I worked in
different environments I worked in the
I.T Department of University of the
university in sibio I've worked in
startups both in Romanian startups and
in an international one I've worked in
spin-offs Espino from which is kind of a
startup but it comes from a bigger
company and has a bit of extra resources
and now I work in a corporation I also
worked in various other medium sized
companies to say
what I did I worked as a software tester
I worked as a technical support I
managed a lot of startup programs and
I've worked as a product manager this is
why I'm here then this is what kind of
brings me close to the subject who are
you
is anyone in the audience willing to
share why they are here to listen to
this talk
otherwise I'm going to tell you my
assumptions but they might not prove
true right
why are you here
okay so I'm guessing and this is why I
did this talk like this that you are
passionate about cyber security most
probably you are technical persons uh
you either work for companies in the
security field or you're maybe doing
consultancy and you're offering your
services to other people maybe your
students and you're passionate about
this subject and I congratulate you for
being here
so when it comes to building products
they say that products are kind of an
intersection of these things right of
technology which you have to really
understand in order to be able to bring
new products to Market of customers of
users and of the problems that they face
and usually when people start building
products they start with one of these
areas in mind either they are very good
at the technology and they're doing some
research in that area and they discover
some algorithms that can be used to
automate some things that they currently
do manual I don't know you you have
something here and you think you can
build a product around that technology
right your Maybe
have have some potential users in mind
either I don't know you're a security
guy you have some pains and you think of
a product that might help you uh uh
solve those problems right so you either
start maybe you want to build stuff to
enable security people to do their job
better so you you kind of start with one
of these three aspects right usually the
technical people start with the
technology in mind right you you do you
build some algorithms and then you say
now I really wanna I wanna sell these
and why do you want to sell these
in Romania usually it's kind of a it's
not good to make money right it's weird
to want to make money out of what I'm
doing or I'm used to being paid for my
services for my time but when I kind of
try to aim higher it's it's not
comfortable but what I want to encourage
you is to view the fact that you are
doing something that can be solved on a
salt on a large scale as having a bigger
impact
because if you do Services there's only
so much time in a day that you can offer
those Security Services for your clients
right if you manage to automate some
something of this and that can be solved
later on and used by a lot of people
that builds way bigger impact than you
can have by yourself
and the money that you make out of this
is a great way to measure this impact
that you're having right
so
people start with the technology and I
uh this is my assumption that this is
the audience so what I saw that
technical people uh make as a first
mistake is building those algorithms and
thinking that they've sold the the that
they've created the product and they try
to sell it to other people right
that is true what do you think
nope
so what what does it mean to actually
create a product around the technology
right
[Music]
um
you have to clearly identify the problem
or the need that you are addressing and
without this it's a research paper
without this is invention right
Innovation is invention times
commercialization so if you don't sell
that if you don't manage to put a price
on it and to see people that are buying
it you don't have a product you have
research you have invention you have
something interesting but there's a lot
more to think about when it comes to
really identifying the important problem
that it can solve and with it's it's
normal to do this there's a process that
you can take to towards you know
brainstorming and then choosing what
your algorithms can solve right and how
do you do this you talk to people so
this problem that you're solving has to
to address some type of customers
now customers or users and they're not
always the same
um you need to understand them and they
can be very differently served to say
and I noticed this yesterday when I came
to see the room and I'm very happy about
the fact that we have this Gap here
because I want to tell you about user
experience
this Gap here if I wouldn't have this
mic if I'd have a handheld mic and I'm a
nervous Walker and I like to walk around
the stage okay this
that's a problem for me right
but if I'm here
to do a live coding session and I need
to have my laptop here that I don't even
notice it so not only that it's not a
problem I don't see it
for the organizer who maybe wants to
take photos of me for you the audience
who maybe will be
won't see the presentation as well if I
walk around there it's actually a useful
constru constraint the fact that I
cannot walk around there right so this
is one thing but for different types of
people it represents something else
maybe if the organizer is really
interested in me not going there because
if I had the head and health mic
they told me to speak into the mic so I
wouldn't do that I promise last time so
if I go and I walk lower that's a path
that me as a user I might take right and
you maybe would discover this when you
do some user testing if you do that
right and you stand over the shoulder of
your users before releasing the product
and you notice that they take that
pattern you say I don't want them to do
that if you're the conference organizer
maybe you build a fence here and you say
no way you're going to go there right so
this is something that I put it here you
see customer you say you think about the
customers and it seems easy but in fact
if you really want to do this right and
that's how you build worldwide products
by doing each little aspect of your
product right is something that you need
to really think about and you need to
experiment so you will try stuff you'll
see how people interact with your
product and then you'll decide to change
things or to keep things as you've
thought of them
as I was saying you have to sell this
product and again this is not easy you
can sell your product in different
channels and you can put different
prices on your products and if you do
this again to do it right you think you
have to really think about strategy here
so you can put a price on your time
that's what you do when you are offering
cyber security services probably right
there's it takes me some time I will
come into your company I will help you
with this it's going to take me two or
three days and it's going to cost you
this
you can look at it the other way on the
benefit that you are bringing to your
customer and you say what is the risk
that they have if they don't employ my
product how much money can they lose and
what percentage of that does it make
sense for them to pay me to avoid losing
that right
now again it's really different if you
serve uh large Enterprises you can put
higher prices on that because there's a
lot of other stuff
for the product that you need to build
or uh if you're doing a b2c so the end
customers a consumer product you're
probably going to price that lower but
you're going to count on larger amounts
right if you build it you give it to
millions of customers ideally
sales channels again uh you can I don't
know do you remember the times when we
used to buy anti-virus licenses on CDs
yeah so you you went to the store and
you picked up your antivirus license
that was the sales Channel that's that's
what you did it back then it was kind of
retail now you don't do that now you uh
either I think we went to buying that
online right but it still usually was a
lifetime license and then we started
going into the model of paying it
monthly if you want to stop paying it
last next month maybe you find a newer
more efficient antivirus you stop paying
me and then you you take a
you make what what what's best for you
so again all this think about it uh and
it's not easy now let's say you did all
that right
um You have to offer technical support
and that again if you if you have a good
product that should not take you too
much if you have a bad product you're
gonna have to put more people into
technical support and they're gonna come
back with bugs and problems from the
users and then you need to keep
improving the product
so in time maybe you so again this these
are aspects that you need to take into
consideration and without these you do
not have a product without these again
you have a technology you have high
potential and when it comes to invest
investors uh giving money to startups
Sometimes They Bet On Your Potential
right but once you have at least a
decent amount of all these things
figured out and you have some paying
customers and it looks like you're
growing and you might go that's when you
have a product and that's when you're
scaling up until then you're building
minimum viable products right
um
and and that's how it goes
I said that that's not easy to do and
for sure it's not for one person to do
it but there's a lot of Frameworks that
you can use to figure out those things
I'll just show you two of them because I
can teach you to how to build a product
in 30 minutes uh but you can read books
and I I have a slide on that so this uh
this is a framework that was developed
by uh Bill olet who's the director of
the Martin trust for entrepreneurship
Center at MIT so it's built for
technical people so I encourage you to
to look into this it's a thorough book
and it's a completed by a workbook
and this takes you to some steps not few
into figuring out how how you can build
this company and how it can go well you
won't do this in a in a day or in a
month you will do it iteratively by
building stuff testing it seeing how the
market responds to it and then adjusting
this is why it's putting uh Snakes and
Ladders type of game because it's not
linear so you make assumptions like I
did maybe in the middle of this talk I
stop and I insist on you answering my
question of why are you here and I
discovered that the talk is not well
thought out and then I have to iterate
right so this is what you're going to do
here you try to figure out who is your
customer then what you can do for your
customer and
along the way you will kind of
brainstorm into potential people who
might use your product you'll make
choices you'll go down One path then
you'll test if your assumptions were
right and you might be proven right
which is great and then you move on but
you can find a letter that brings you
back and it says no that assumption did
not work those people aren't willing to
buy your product like it is you have to
go back some steps and rethink what
you've already built okay again we won't
go into detail so let's just read the
steps so it's about who is your customer
and understanding those types of people
what you can do for your customer
how does your customer acquire the
product that's the sales channels that I
was saying how do you make money off
your product and that's uh pricing and
everything the business model
um how do you design and build your
product right and that's a lot of the
MVP that I was saying there and how do
you scale your business so you you may
figure out how to sell to Romanian
people and when you try to go to
different markets that doesn't work
right and that's that's about scaling
and figuring out how to grow
um it's this solves part of the problem
but it's more uh known maybe to answer
maybe to entrepreneurs and a bit easier
to go to to figuring out your business
model so
why does this work oh yeah okay so this
takes you into the value propositions
which is what the product is and what it
does for the customers right the
customer segments again who are the
people the customer relationships that
you have to address these segments and
the channels you have to reach them who
are the partners maybe you partner with
some retailers or I don't know other
people who have
similar products to yours that can take
you to some customers the Key activities
and resources that you need in order to
actually build a product the cost
structure and the revenue streams again
how you take money from these people
this is these are Frameworks and this is
also described in a big book that you
can use and you can talk to your team uh
on on what the assumptions are how you
are thinking of developing your product
and
starting to do it iteratively
now do you read books
who here is still reading books
okay great
um
wonderful audience for me if you I'm
sure that you can go to Corsair and
udemy and find some courses on each of
these topics uh maybe some of them even
helped by by the guys that wrote the
books but I I love reading books and I
think that it's great that you can
always come back to them and these I I
suggest you take in in physical hard
copies right
so disciplined entrepreneurship is the
book by Bill olet who did the snakes and
letters steps uh wonderful book and then
you can let me check on I have time good
business model generation is the
business model that I uh showed you the
framework value proposition design is
strictly for
for this part
so this it looks
a small thing right this and how you
actually think of the value proposition
is developed in one book again it
depends on how much you do your homework
and how well you want to think each
aspect of your business so it's about
thinking if for example if your product
is nice to have for the customers like
Facebook is for example Instagram we can
live without it or if it's a painkiller
right if you cannot live without
something we cannot live maybe without
our mobile phones right now
or maybe we can but that's a question
that you want to have and that's going
to influence how you think of things how
you put the pricing on if you're
building a painkiller for somebody but
maybe you can price it higher than if
you if you build a vitamin
for example then there's a startup
owner's manual which was written by
Steve blank it's startup Owner's Manual
of 600 pages
another framework so these are kind of
Alternatives of thinking of things the
Design of Everyday Things talks about
physical products mostly but IT
addresses a lot into uh online and
software products it's gonna help you to
think of this when when you I don't know
there's there's this car did you take
the bolt that has the handle here
I I've noticed this so it's some people
who have designed this card
have thought that it's really
interesting to put the handle here
instead of here where we're all used to
it right and what is going on people
don't find the handle I I've noticed
both cars that have stickers like press
here so why would you do that that's
nice for design Maisie baby you want to
do something different but is it really
useful because you have to take into
account that the people are really
accustomed to opening a door somewhere
okay so maybe some wheels are best not
reinvented
great book uh the mom test will teach
you how to do customer surveys so the
idea is that usually if you ask your mom
that about what you're building if she
likes it she'll try to encourage you but
if you ask the questions rightly she
might she will not have the opportunity
to do so so you have to when you're
doing customer service and you're trying
to understand about your customers you
have to ask about their experience not
about what would they do
so you it's a book on creating surveys
and on having these types of interviews
a networking book by Paul Renault is for
anyone who's coming to this type of
conferences to do some business so it's
uh general for for the business
environment I think zero to one by Peter
Thiel
he was in bran you know the so that's
the guy uh he's uh Elon Musk didn't come
but Peter Thiel was here and he's quite
a big deal he wrote this book on reading
on on really inventing things that go
from zero from something that is not uh
it does not exist in the world to one
which is something a lot of the people a
lot of the products are solving uh
problems iteratively so you do something
better than the tools that they are that
are out there but maybe you can go from
zero to one with a security product that
pinpoints something and maybe automate
it automates it like it's never been
done before
and there's this is a talk about also
how investors evaluate these types of
disruptive startups again interested
inspired for product managers the hard
thing about the hard things is uh really
the story of uh Ben Horowitz building
different types of companies uh and shoe
dog I really like it and it's
autobiography from the founder of Nike
so it's it's just nice to read but it's
really inspiring when it comes to the
entrepreneurial mindset
and you can be entrepreneurial don't
mistake me by being an employee in a
company yeah companies
are building new products every day and
a lot of the times these products start
as ideas from some employees who raise
their hands and say I think we can do
this more productively I think we can do
this and they managed to to get
resources from that company and they can
start an entrepreneurial team that's
entrepreneurial right so you can do that
don't be constrained by where you are
and maybe the fact that you wanna
make sure you have a monthly salary to
keep your family safe right but you can
also have the entrepreneurial mindset
and really go after it on your own
and that on your own
is incorrect you will never be able to
really build a valuable product by
yourself
few people have managed to do one solo
founder companies
and even these people
rely on strong teams
so you have to have strong teams I told
you about all these different aspects of
the company that you need to take into
consideration and you can tell that
there's a lot of work to be put in there
some people who are very analytical are
good at one part some people who are
nice to talk to people are very good at
other parts some have to be creative
some have to be very organized and we
didn't talk about financials and stuff
and we're legal right you know legal is
is a big thing to take into
consideration information security so
build strong teams if you want to create
products there's no way other than that
and lastly share the journey which means
talk to other people who are working a
similar path
and these are some examples of the
startups that we're working with in the
orange Fab acceleration program these
are startups that are around here Arcana
AI Core anti-virus the Guinness in stage
one you can meet them in the Expo area
at our orange booth
pen test tools they have their own boots
there's their sponsors for this
conference they have grown wonderfully
during the past years and they're great
people and I'm really happy to see them
kind of giving back to the community
yeah they're I know ADI Fortuna is also
a speaker for many conferences so these
people and cyboredo the guys in the
hacking Village use this platform too
for for the capture the flag contest
again these are people who are good at
cyber security like most of you are I
guess
and they are building stuff they figured
out some parts they're probably most
probably still figuring out some other
stuff some are trying to raise
investment rounds some are trying to
scale their business worldwide
but I'm sure and this is my advice to
you to go to talk to them if you have an
idea people are usually too busy
building their own ideas to steal yours
I hope the days of having that fear are
gone
and even if you have that idea execution
is what really makes it or breaks it
so talk to these people uh get inspired
share your struggles learn from their
mistakes so you don't have to repeat
them
um and good luck building a product
that's
that's me and I'm right on time thank
you if you have any questions three
minutes right
thank you I wanted to ask you in your
experience uh what is the best way to
tell technical people that their the
features that might suggest even though
they are revolutionary aren't the best
fit for the market to Target right now
so my advice would be not to tell them
but to show them uh what we did when I
worked in the in one of the companies uh
everyone learned to do user tests so you
can build a prototype like the most
basic prototype of what your idea is and
that can be even a napkin sketch right
and show it to some people so these are
the potential customers these are the
people we want to address go out and
speak to one two five ten and when you
get that experience of discussing about
the feature that you have in mind with
the end people you will get the feedback
yourself so this way the way you show
them otherwise it depends on the
personality types that you have and I
said build strong teams you have to also
manage those from strong teams right
you either create really clearly thought
out paths and if you're Technical and
you're super good technically if you
want to be part of this team and you
don't want to do the user tests for
example uh you have to stick to your
part but you have to listen to the
people who do that so you either learn
to do it a bit about yourself and see
for yourself what I'm telling you about
or you need to trust the people around
you and that's important so teams are
built around Trust
thank you I'm a middleman between the PM
and the technical team so this is very
helpful thank you thank you
hi awesome talk thank you I wanted to
ask you what are some of the most common
mistakes that you have seen startups do
maybe in the process of defining that
users or even in the technical process
so it's General uh answer but it's not
testing their assumptions so you you
know mindfulness and things like this
you need to be aware of where you are
assuming stuff and where you really know
stuff that you tested yeah and that you
validate it and you you tend to go on
those Snakes and Ladders
when you're doing the snakes and letters
you tend to move a lot of bases in front
and you don't realize that one
assumption is wrong and then you've
wasted a lot of time and a lot of
resources into building something that
you should have realized way earlier
that was wrong
General otherwise a lot
yes
okay what was the idea behind Panthers
tools
oh you have to just go into
go and talk to the guys I don't want to
be their advocate so they started
building pen testing automating pen
testing
uh was there any
initial problem that needed to be solved
specifically yeah I don't know that
team so you find them in the Expo area
they have a booth and I'm sure you can
find ADI Fortuna who is the founder of
that and ask him how how he started the
company
okay thank you thank you
I think that's it right we have more no
thank you
that's it thank you very much thank you