everyone
have you ever wondered why malicious
actors use different techniques while
developing their modeler or how they
think
well today I'm gonna present you the
techniques of a prevalent Banker over
the years
to an offensive perspective and I hope
I'm gonna answer to the previous
questions
well my name is Mariano and I'm a
specialist threat researcher at Northern
LifeLock currently we have changed our
name and now we are gen digital
and my main responsibilities are threat
and vulnerability research
well let's get into it today's topic I'm
gonna start with a brief introduction to
Black Moon and the terminology the
technical analysis of a mother family
how would the malware arrives the
delivery methods and the expected
results the techniques that were used in
the latest version of Black Moon
the offensive perspective over those
techniques and some comparison with
other variants of this model
okay so a short introduction
black moon it's also known as bambra or
KR Banker because it was originally in
Korea in 2014
and its smaller category it's a Trojan a
banker exactly
and it's copied to steal credentials
from banking institutions client in
order to access their their accounts and
Gain
gain access to to their financial
information
other variants also delivered malicious
payloads
to the targeted users okay a short
disclaimer
we are not covering all the black moon
variants due to various reasons one of
them is the fact that the time is
limited for this talk
and some changes were small so
we didn't want him to to mention them
because the flow was somehow the same
but the changes were really small and
also the research was done based on our
Telemetry so there might be some cases
that we have probably missed but let's
focus on on the one that
that are are part of this presentation
okay here are some some numbers
regarding the samples that were
identified in the Years
the idea is that even the
the malware started in 2014 we are still
we still
uh received a lot of samples in 2022
here is a
photo from our Telemetry and between
June and September 2022 we received
around 7 000 samples so the the numbers
are still increasing
okay a short recap about malware
analysis
portable executable looks on on disk
uh PE file is actually uh it's actually
the executable files on Windows systems
so we see here the architecture in the
header the sections some the compile
time and other informations that are
available
about static analysis
we refer to static analysis as
everything that we can obtain from a
sample without executing it so
everything that we can see like strings
linked libraries Imports function
exports and others and
when we are talking about Dynamic
analysis we will run the sample and see
everything that the sample is doing on
the the system like registry
modifications if there are any process
activity or network activity and then we
can go to the debugging state
to Kernel debugging user mode debugging
and dump some memory and see what we can
extract from that point
okay now the delivery methods for Black
Moon
well it was
social engineering and also by other
malware
by social engineering we meant that the
user restricted to allow malware onto
their machines and this is actually made
by a psychological manipulation and I
have a statement here a good scam is
targeting people's reaction on specific
emotions so
these These are the one that that have
the most impact
because they are somehow playing with
with our emotions
okay how this is done via spam emails
attachments other campaigns or as
mentioned before through other modelers
droppers downloaders backdoors what what
are those exactly well a dropper drops
the malicious file on disk a downloader
interact with the internet and make
requests and try to download the
malicious payload into the the system
and the back door means that the
attacker already gained the access to
the targeted machine and
just download the the malware and
execute it okay now the infection chain
of the latest version identified in our
telemetry
we have here the initial sample that is
going to drop a file into program files
then it's going to create some
persistence in services
after that it's going to
the service is going to start and a new
process is going to to be run and the
payload is executed it's injected
actually in memory and then it's
executed okay uh
at step six uh I see that here is a
little problem with with the
presentation but at step six we we have
a VBS file a script that is going to to
just delete the initial file from disk
okay
now
um
we can see the the first thing that we
observed is that the the file was packed
uh was packed with a common Packer what
packing means well actually we can think
like the executable is compressed and we
don't have access to the initial
information like we cannot access all
the strings all the import files and and
everything that was mentioned before at
the static analysis
so um I'm gonna focus on something more
visual now
we can see here that a new process is
created the FD launcher sr.exe
this is really important because as
mentioned before the persistence
persistence was done via services
and we can see at sample.exe that we
don't have the new process under its
initial process tree
why this is made why why this was done
actually
well because
some
defensive mechanism are watching over
the processary of
of the initial sample and in order to
evade such detections it's actually
starting from the services that EMC the
the service manager on Windows
so this is actually an evasion technique
okay
now what we can see here is that the the
process if the the sample FD launcher Sr
was dropped on the program files uh
under named Microsoft SQL Server compact
Edition
do anyone know why this was done can we
think about
an interpretation why why this was made
why in that
directory why in that way under that
name
well you can think about it and maybe
maybe you will answer later
um
I really I really want to to hear your
opinion about that
and also we can see here that we have
persistence as a service the name and
description is also related to Microsoft
services and the start type it's two so
the service is gonna start automatically
so again uh to run offensive perspective
this is done to various reasons one of
them let's see like okay the user
understand that okay I'm compromised I
see new files on disk or something like
that let's just shut the computer down
and put it again well when we have
persistence over this kind of samples it
doesn't matter because the the sample is
gonna start again again at each boot so
this is this is done for for persistence
okay here a little cleanup stage
where the the script it's uh it's going
to delete the initial file from disk
and um
here we can see the process injection
phase and the network communication that
is going to gather the
the information from the user
system okay after we
analyzed the after we dumped the memory
and received retrieved the
the the process injection we analyzed it
and we see here some strings that are
related with everything that I already
mentioned before so the SQL
Microsoft SQL service
um the location of the file and
also some some of the URLs that are used
okay
another technique it's um
the the fact that some strings were
hidden and this was done by moving a
single character at a time this is
actually made because when we try to
retrieve all the strings from a sample
we don't always
to recognize such such strings because
they are placed one character at a time
and usually someone is looking on
strings that are longer as
as analyzing the sample okay
so here is the the meter techniques the
all the techniques that that were
identified for for this sample they are
presented in this table and they are a
sum up of what I have already presented
and now I would like to to go to the
techniques comparison with other
variants of this model because as
mentioned before it started in 2014 and
we are still receiving samples today
in 2014 a little background it was used
the farming attack so um
the traffic is redirected from a website
to another and that another website it's
usually owned by a malicious actor and
it's made in a way to masquerade the
legitimate one
so the user want to so the user will be
tricked and put his credential in there
okay when we are performing a web
request using DNS
it's important to know that IP
information is retrieved from the local
system in this order first the DNS cache
memory is going to be checked then the
host.ics file which
lays under C Windows system 32 drivers
EDC and then the hosts file without an
extension which stays in the same
directory okay this is really important
because it's going to be used by the the
attackers
in in 2014
the the setup was done like this first
we have the initial sample it's going to
make a web request get request
and something interesting is that we
have
here at that page
a zip file but the zip file it's not
actually a zip file it's just containing
the zip header and if we if we try to
download that zip file and open it as a
zip we won't be able to do that because
it only has the header of the zip file
and all the content it's encrypted
so what is actually happening the
the sample it's decrypting the data and
this host that is ICS file which will
contain multiple banking internet Pages
which are
going to be moved under the the
specified folder with name host.exe so
okay
why this is done I think you you can
guess it but the fact is that next stage
is to disable the DNS cache memory
uh using the the registry
and we are going to see that the the
model where it's creating some more
persistence
and um
again
we we can expect
uh that the the file is going to run
when the
the system is going to boot again okay
how the data is collected this is really
simple because now the user is is
compromised when he is going to make a
request
it's going to use the IP that is
specified in the host.hc so this is
going to be freshly
um
a new list of of ips each time the the
system boots
okay
now in 2016 a little background we have
a proxy that enters it's an intermediary
for our requests
and a pack file which is actually a
JavaScript that
it's going to decide what is going to
happen with our request
okay
in the same configuration the initial
sample is going to start a proxy which
is going to be host on the uh which is
going to host the the encrypted
encrypted JavaScript
which is going to decide what is going
to happen with our request
the decrypted JavaScript contains
multiple
um internet banking pages and when the
data is going to be collected the user
is going to make a request
and the back file it's actually going to
check what type of request is there so
if the request is something related with
a banking institution is going to
redirect it to the malicious website
otherwise it's going to resolve it as a
normal request
okay
now in 2017
we have a downloader
which is going to perform a get request
to a web page
and it's going to download the malicious
file on disk okay
the file is going to be executed and we
can see here that something new
has changed in the way of operation of
this model
so auxor operation is going to be made
on some of its bytes in order to decode
an URL
and it's going to make a get request to
that URL which is going to download a
gpg file on disk
okay
now that file is actually not a gpg file
uh and uh it's going to make another
store to decode the bytes of that gpg
file and obtain a new portable
executable one
that portable executable it's going to
be executed and it's going to check the
device language
this is a really really interesting step
because
if the language doesn't correspond with
the targeted
the targeted country it's just going to
stop
otherwise it's going to interact with
the command and control server and it's
going to download the black moon and
then it's going to execute it but this
step it doesn't matter what kind of
Black Moon it is if it's a 2014 2016 20
whatever stage
uh the the important the important thing
is that
all those steps were done
with with what reason
can can someone guess it
okay someone said like to to not
download the binary the right directly
on the virtual machine and analyze it
yes other yes
trigger any defenses
if all those steps go
I would say that all those steps are
designed to try and Trigger any defenses
possibly
and if if it so happens that all of this
execution passes successfully then it's
more likely that black moon will also be
executed successfully yes somehow it's
it's done to to actually evade the
detection for the for the in the the
actually the the payload the black mold
so to somehow not detect in the first
stage the the model directly so just go
to the Drone downloaders over and over
again and see where it can get okay
in 2021 or the
the stages were a little
a little different so the initial sample
made a copy of itself then it drops the
VBS file
that downloaded the payload
which it's actually going to to perform
a get request and obtain that to that
malicious file and then it's going to
run the malware
for that the persistence is going to be
created in the Run registry
for the copy so if the initial sample is
going to be deleted the copy is going to
be still there and the persistence is
made on the the copy of
of the modeler okay
now as a conclusion
it is actually better when you know what
you are fighting against so what I
wanted to point is that both offensive
perspectives and defensive perspectives
are linked together
uh through an offensive perspective
when we we want to to see things through
an offensive perspective
adversaries are have to evaluate need to
evaluate all the mechanisms that uh
Solutions defensive Solutions provide in
order to bypass them
and when we are creating defensive
powerful defensive Solutions we have to
take in considerations how adversaries
thinks and to try to
identify and
mitigate such actions
and this is what what we work on at gen
digital we try to build
to build powerful defensive Solutions
well thank you if you have any questions
please and also I I want to to check the
the answers for the the previous
question
sorry uh can we help with the microphone
thank you for the presentation uh
one question here is this avoidable by
using a secure
security or will it be overwritten
anyway
uh Excuse excuse me could you please
repeat the question is this avoidable by
using a secure DNS server or will it be
overwritten anyway
if it is if you can avoid downloading
them
um
malicious
well
yes this can be avoided through through
different mechanisms and this can also
be detected also
okay but if you like change your DNS
server does it help in any way like
or it's uh well the idea is that the you
are referring to the DNS cache memory
stage at the 2017 when it was disabled
and
it was used the host.ics file
figure out if you can like avoid this by
like without
um antivirus or anything like that
oh here's a proxy depends yeah I use a
proxy or different uh different
techniques yes
okay thanks
okay
so to the first question the answer is
to make it seem legit that it belongs to
Microsoft at least that's why I think
there is no compact Edition anyway so it
wouldn't uh overwrite anything it would
seem like an artifact because Microsoft
does live artifacts in setups okay yes
maybe one way to avoid that I think is
by being a low privileged user because
you can write in program files
and that's why they avoided everything
in uh
later versions regarding program files
and downloading a JPEG is
let's say an innocent at first glance
uh
can you please repeat the other
questions
well this was the question the why the
name is used and why in that specific
folder why end program files and to the
other the other question for obfuscation
with all the actor and everything else
to not make it seem so easy to detect
because it's one thing to see a VBS and
even someone not
I.T servicing a link that they don't
recognize and might seem suspicious but
some garbage code that is obfuscated
might not seem that dangerous maybe yes
not just to avoid detection for uh
anti-viruses but I mean even to the user
because some users might Panic if they
see a new file yes if it's innocent it's
innocent somehow yeah this is this is
really a really good question thank you
um
the the idea is that obviously to to
masquerade Itself by as a Microsoft
legitimate software and under that that
specific directory in program files
because what do we have in program files
we we have the installed software that
is in our devices so a normal user when
it's going to just check there it's
going to see something from Microsoft
and it's going to say oh okay this is
legitimate I'm not gonna delete anything
from here so this is one of the reasons
and also somehow to bypass the
detections because
maybe the user it's going to make some
exclusion lists and is going to include
that that directory on the exclusion
list and somehow to to evade detection I
think the temp folder is better for that
because nobody clears it and it's
usually excluded
uh yes temp folder it's somehow of a
directory that it's commonly targeted by
malware indeed I I was surprised to not
see stuck on a stagnography used in the
jpeg I thought that's what it will use
to do another get request uh actually no
stenography it wasn't used but um
the the payload was each time obfuscated
and encoded so we had to check the
the decoded mechanism and retrieve
somehow the payload
thank you
uh so how does this string get installed
is it installed through initial access
Brokers or do like the the
initialize that do they have their email
campaigns directly the malware operators
or do they go through initial access
Brokers or something and link to these
questions is how do they get persistence
well uh first the first question
um
usually the the mother arrives through
as mentioned through other campaigns to
email campaigns to to phishing campaigns
and um
uh it's
once it's on the the victim machine it's
executed and from from that stage the
the user is compromised
uh if it requires administrator
privileges yes some of them it requires
administrative beverages
how do they ask for them
well
because they are targeting users devices
because they are not targeting somehow
the banking institution itself they're
targeting the clients of the banking
institutions to gain access to them they
doesn't really uh
they just hope that the the user has
that many Privileges and they allow it
to run as administrator okay
and there was the second question sorry
I could you please repeat it
oh okay
like do they use uh some other service
like to ask for administrator privileges
or does the binary itself downloaded
from the internet ask for administrator
privileges that was the question okay
thank you thank you
yeah so I have a question about the
defenses uh I can think of a scenario
where you can poison the DNS at one
stage and at another stage maybe after a
reboot of numerous reboots you can
actually download the file from
another website with the poison DNS do
you actually take into the
considerations via about your defenses
in your socials do you take into
considerations these scenarios like when
dynamically analyzing and running those
binaries and trying to detect the
malware to actually take the
conversations the cases where it
requires multiple reboots or just one
reboot well
we take in consideration multiple
scenarios when we are developing our
Solutions but
I
am not going to to get into details of
everything of How It's implemented and
how it's done thank you for the question
okay well if there are any questions you
can find me in the lobby in our break
and I'm happy to to respond to them
thank you guys