foreign
spot in the second day or in the last
day after lunch but let's see how it
goes
uh so hi everybody my name is Radu I'm
uh yes Graciela said a network architect
and I'll try to speak a little bit about
well networks and network architecture
in um
in the new world because we haven't
heard so much about this in the past two
days
so first of all to set the stage a lot
of things have happened in the in the
past years
especially in the network space so a
couple of years back we will all of a
sudden went home to work from home
all of us at the same time and it was
quite a challenge for a network
throughout the world to keep up
and I guess we did a quite a good job as
an industry as an IT industry in these
past two years so now working from home
is The New Normal everybody is doing
that
more or less than some who would want
but it's working one other thing that
started happening a while back is that a
lot of things
that weren't previously connected to a
network now are
and
this is still happening and it's one of
the reasons why we have all of these
security problems right everything is
getting connected to everything at the
same time wherever they are where we are
now uh working from Siemens which is not
necessarily the youngest and uh
it's not quite a startup right it has
quite a while existing
uh we are still trying to adapt as a as
a company and to lead this change to the
new world uh and this is a little bit
what I wanted to talk to you about
so first of all uh in these days
a lot of things are happening some of
them are pretty hilarious so uh this is
actually a real thing and everybody now
has light bulbs all of you have like
smart light bulbs at home or other smart
things at home
which are not really usually hardened
enough or are not state of the art when
it comes to drivers and uh network
interfaces and how they handle things
and these kind of things well are funny
when they happen in a lab or at home
but when they happen in a big company or
in a public institution or God forbidson
and I don't know power plant or
something like that it's stopped being
funny
sometimes it's even a privacy problem
and this is actually a real thing that
can happen these days
well
this is a definition I am not into this
so much into these dense things but I
find this definition of what Zen is on
the well on Google and it kind of
applies to how how whatever we're
heading to the networks these days
because now everything is connected and
everything changes and we need to pay
attention and to learn from what's
Happening and to adapt the architectures
of the networks and of these security
systems in order to cope with with all
of these changes
so what's going on with regards to
network security
traditionally the way not only
traditionally I think that to a certain
extent is the status quo even today
we are defending our networks or our
locations or our data centers or power
assets with uh something that was
thought of uh quite a while ago we built
a big wall around it
we Define walking path that people can
or devices or packets can take through
this through this Castle
and at the entry gate we check everybody
that comes in see if it's a good guy
he's allowed to get in right so this is
a traditional way of also doing network
security you build a big perimeter you
put in a gate where your control who's
coming in you define some policies there
if that somebody got in there they're
good they're fine they have access to
everything as long as they walk the the
paths that were defined
but actually the new world looks more
like this so there is no really a wall
anymore and you don't really know where
everything is going
and where the bad guys are or who is
inside those much each one of these
we call it attack surface today
so in this new world
one of the approaches that is widely
popular and it's called zero trust it's
what I want to talk about it's a very
good thing that actually this is
happening
I wanted to to look at this totally
different and say forget all this
network security let's we cannot do it
anymore let's change a little bit how we
do things and just Define some
principles and we started from they
started and defined the standard
actually from simple things like uh
you should always assume that something
has been breached when you design
networks and architecture you should
never allow a user a device or something
or somebody to have more access than
they actually need in order to get the
role or their job
you all you can you also need to do
smaller segments in the network and in
the security space
and things normal things like
multi-factor that now I won't talk about
because everybody this is these days
and this somehow translated into well a
standard whoops
I think I'm missing a slide
bear with me
[Applause]
okay I'll talk through it so basically
the idea of zero trust is that
um
a standard has been defined by an well
well-known uh institution in the United
States that's called zero trust
architecture what that said is that
in order to make everything safe you
should forget all of these controls that
are placed everywhere
and follow some simple rules and an
architecture should be defined with some
elements and I'll let you read through
that because as any standards it's quite
cumbersome
but there are some basic things that
were defined which are quite important
these days one is that you should never
Grant somebody access to anything based
on where they come from so the tradition
of doing things is that in many
locations or companies if you're inside
the network you get attached maybe you
get authenticated maybe not depending if
you're on wired or Wireless it doesn't
matter even if you are authenticated the
de facto standard is that you get access
to the network you get you get a link
you can get access to to anything that's
there's gun that's
we are moving away from from that model
some other pretty important things are
related to zero trust like you should
always authenticate everything and after
you authenticate something you need to
authorize if they are in entitled to
access that application
uh one other thing is that everything
should be encrypted and The Good Old Log
everything and look at the logs and
monitor everything
the motto of the zero trust architecture
is Never Trust always verify
which is all good and fine and it's an
approach that has been widely adopted at
least as a strategy by many companies in
this world
and uh
what does this mean now now talking on
behalf or as a representative of a
company that does industrial things uh
there's another side to it and that site
is driven by the fact that ASU most of
you know the life cycle of an industrial
thing whatever it is and I don't know an
automation line a power plant and
MRN scanner whatever it is a train
the life cycle of such a such a thing
it's much bigger than your usual I.T
life cycle so it's something that you
invest a lot in as a customer you live
with it and you take advantage of it for
I don't know 10 20 years in which time
you don't
usually get the chance to do any patches
and the guys that have been developing
it at the beginning are not really
keeping things up to date
and that's that's normal and the way
this has been approached additionally
was physical security nobody reaches the
uh the control part of our power plant
it's physically there separated nobody
gets in there only the technician that
knows what they are doing
but now also with the pandemics and with
the changes things are also happening in
that space so now many vendors of such
industrial devices
and maybe subcontractors that of that
vendors are asking for remote access
and that doesn't exist because it's
physically separated and we end up
number one
with very
not so funny situation in which somebody
operating that the device is really
getting a DSL line from somebody from a
service provided and connected to that
in the public internet to that whatever
it is control part of an uh of our plant
and it it gets its vendor access there
which is not funny at all and I guess
many of us have seen this kind of things
happening
on the other hand all of these smart
devices are also triggering the
industrial world where everything needs
to be connected to the cloud these days
so this is scary the fact that
industrial devices are getting connected
to the cloud of the internet and access
from from from outside it's scary
and uh
this zero trust pillar is one of the key
things that we are looking in the emails
for the future to be the de facto
standard so basically uh what this means
is that and by the way this doesn't
apply just to Siemens products or to our
internal Network or to the way we
approach our customers or to our data
centers and so on it's supposed to be an
overarching strategy that applies the
same rules everywhere
and the couple
how do how do we do this because it's
it's hard to
if we have separate entities separate
rules for internal Network separables
for data centers rules for workers from
home for products towards our customers
it becomes complicated so the idea was
let's do things simpler simplify them
apply that never trust always verify
everywhere and uh
an interesting part
internet everywhere what does that mean
we we are turning a little bit around
how things are working so since
everybody started working from home you
know that initially three years ago that
existed that always existed working from
home was always a thing but it was for
that Lone Wolf account manager that was
out there somewhere in the middle of
nowhere and it was okay because it was
limited exposure these days everybody
works from home what they triggered in
many companies in many public
institutions was that the end devices
went hardened enough and this same zero
trust principles of uh of of
authenticating and authorizing are being
to an extent applied
so then what we are trying to do and we
are rolling out in our locations is that
we turn things around and instead of
trying to over complicate our intranet
or internal Network we said that look
all the managed devices the laptops that
we are using or demons employees are
using they can be used from home it's
the last two years for a proof of that
so let's then turn it around and offer
those employees and those devices the
same major experience that they get at
home at the office which means that for
our employees and for the managed
devices basically when they come into an
office they get
the Starbucks hotspot experience of
course is everything that Enterprise
should have on top of that
secure internet access Cloud
optimization and so on and so forth but
at the end of the day it's the same the
same experience
but now the somehow we know this
the expectation from many uh the
expectation from
the majority of stakeholders was that
after you introduce this new thing with
zero trust which kind of defined rules
around how you how you write
applications how you expose them how you
enforce clients to access the
application and so on so when you do
this somehow there was the expectation
that the network would not necessarily
become obsolete because everything is
connected to everything but it will
become flat right everything will be
connected to the same wide internet
you'll get access to everything
everything will be hardened from
application Level because it's zero
trust compliant and everything is is
simple so
in all our experience I guess we learned
that one single tool or one single
architecture one single set of rules is
usually not the one that can solve
everything like in that movie
um so then what about the network which
I have been doing for uh the majority of
my life Network architectures and it's
still my hobby so the question
somehow is uh is haunting is is the
network stereo level because
all these zero transmeasures are
covering now everything and uh looking
at how traditionally network security
was defined we don't have a place to put
controls anymore not in the same way
that we were doing before
but there's a but here as long as people
write code well it will have bugs so
then all these zero trust principles if
you just rely on application Level
security then
things will happen
and at the same time not only that the
bad guys are everywhere but they have
connectivity towards multiple
destinations from multiple points and if
the network is flat then
foreign
server application uh hardening enough
I guess not so uh
I think that the network is still
relevant it will explore that a little
bit
there's another side of it uh so he's uh
as I touched on earlier these devices
that have a long life cycle usually
don't get updated very often so even if
you define a strategy you'll end up
with maybe a long development cycle
until you launch the next industrial
thing that has the capability to be zero
transcompliant and the written following
these rules
there's the other side of it there are
many vendors that are competing on
pricing you see those smart light bulbs
or maybe security cameras or stuff like
that those type of vendors will never
have the development power but indeed q
and day testing and all of that to make
sure that everything is hardened enough
so bottom line is that we will I guess
for the foreseeable future still have
clients and applications which are not
zero trust compliant so
how do we close all this circle so
Network to the rescue right
I really think that modern network
security uh adapted to these principles
and to this landscape is
is critical in this in this new world so
first of all
we should we should remember and keep in
place everything that exists so the
changes in the network security
architecture driven by this new zero
trust principles it's not about removing
controls we should not get rid of
everything that we have and make a
revolution it's about evolving what we
have
and there are I guess three pillars
three main pillars that uh I'll bring up
a little bit that I think are the keys
about the evolution of the of the
network
in this context in the zero trust world
so first one of it is Sassy I don't know
how much you have heard about it quilt
it back in the next slide
the second pillar is around how we
segment our networks and how we reduce
the attack Surface by
enforcing policies on this segmentation
and the key here is that if we do things
traditionally and I'll get back to that
we won't get very far
and the last and not least is software
defined
many of us have heard of soft defined
networks I will get back to that in a
bit
it this is actually the most important
part the most important change because
what it brings with it is the capability
to use the networks as we have them
today just as an underlay meaning just
for transporting packets and Define
overlays on top of that that are much
more Dynamic and can be better
controlled
so one by one
so cessie stands for secure access
Services Edge
somehow this is also a
I don't know if I should call it a hype
but it's a buzzword these days and all
the security vendors I think you have
heard of some name this killer Cisco
umbrella and so on Prisma access from
Palo Alto they are offering these
Solutions and they are somehow marketing
those as being the one thing that the
Enterprises or companies or public
sector entities need to implement
internet work in order to change
everything and become zero trust
compliant well it's not quite that but
it's a very important pillar
so
what this is what it it was sort of
being this new architecture it's
actually a new architecture for remote
access but it's different from what you
have used so far from what we we have
all used so far so how does remote
access look traditionally you have
somewhere an um VPN Gateway if you want
to call it concentrator
you would build from your client the
tunnel up to that and then it's like in
the traditional
connecting with the wire in the internet
you get access to everything else
afterwards inside so that's a
traditional Network approach
this new approach is about using
somehow a cloud driven front-end towards
your customers and you will bid an
application layer an application overlay
on top of that so you can look at this
as being an um if you want a smart
and encrypted application Level proxy in
which the end customers maybe employees
working from home or working from the
office and just getting internet access
as I as I explained earlier
they would have a client that is
application aware and can route
applications
with using this overlay towards
applications that are hosted inside of
the of the gates of the Enterprise
now
the
one of the most important new things
getting back to the initial picture of
how the New Castle looks like is
building those small red bubbles around
each one of the elements of the New
Castle
and how do we do that because
traditionally
how do we do Network segmentation
traditionally we we take the layer the
the lens inside locations or data center
you we split them in layer two domains
vlans we put a subnet on each one of
these villain and maybe we apply an
access list on each one of these
villains defining who can come in and
who can go out maybe we even place a
firewall there
and the new world is very very different
because the way it works now in the
networks is that whenever a device is
attaching to the network it first goes
through and so it connects to the over
to the underlay so exactly to the first
layer so before getting network access
that device is being authenticated maybe
the user using it is getting
authenticated there are a number of ways
to to to identify who is that device is
maybe with an agent
after that is being done that device is
being mapped to a so-called micro
segment so some vendors call it Security
Group some other call it roles
the idea is that
this is
a multi-site cross segments cross
traditional segments across subnets
cross vlans uh thing so one of these
micro segments can spread across all of
your sites
across all of your buildings in a campus
or across all of your floors you know
building and so on and so forth
and all of those devices in that micro
segment can be uniquely identified with
the tag with an ID it doesn't matter
this new ID is actually something that's
being transported on the overlay created
with software defined methods
and this is a very big thing it's a huge
thing actually because imagine that
you have four locations and some data
centers here you have HR users
and you have some HR applications
traditionally you know how it goes you
define the the HR users in each location
go to a circular subnet then you take
the firewall in front of the HR
applications you define an access list
there and you maintain all of that
what's the problem with that if you look
at those firewalls three four years down
the road you'll end up with a list of I
don't know 20 000 entries in an access
list and never nobody knows what those
are doing and nobody can remove them and
it's extremely hard to maintain on the
other hand when you add a new building
or even when you extend your
applications everything is complicated
and getting back to this micro
segmentation why is it such a big deal
because now it's called business intent
you can now actually Define in the
network platform in the policy
definition point
just one rule to allow for this
communication that says
HR users or HR user micro segment can
access HR applications micro segment
that's it one line
not only that it's extremely easy to
maintain it's easy to understand what it
does
and it's
you decouple somehow the policy
definition from what are the sources and
the destinations
which is actually getting us back the
control that we had initially with the
with the wall against the castle but in
an extremely dynamic dynamic and easy to
maintain way
now in
this new world what actually makes all
of this possible is the software-defined
networking which has been somehow an
academic thing initially so originally
it was thought to be something else
today it's the tool that allows us to
create overlays to make things Dynamic
and not to need to Define anymore those
static and IP based rules in the network
and because not everything is simple
there are multiple uh software defined
platforms different ones for different
for for different scopes
so you can have one for your campuses so
for where users are for what will your
locations are one for the data center I
think many of us heard of sd1 which is
uh standard one thing in Enterprises
today
and
the area is that fully for each one of
these domains
there are some rules and some things
that will apply so for example for the
campus part and production area and
devices iot areas as I said initially
we'll need to identify everything before
connecting to the network put them in
segments in micro segments and applying
the authorization part
for the uh branch and when and sd-1 part
it's important to do a couple of things
in in order to not have the users
complain that the water the network is
not working well so number one is to be
smarter in the way we Route traffic in
the network so the sd1 somehow includes
doing application recognition which
means that as a simple example when I
have users in my locations wanted to
access I don't know Office 365 I don't
need to put them all the way back to
Data Center apply their policies and
break them out there I can do it locally
directly why because I know fix 365 is a
software is a zero trust complaint
application that is already integrated
with my backend and I can trust that the
traffic can go over the Internet
directly it will be encrypted everything
will be applied the rules that I Define
the other thing which is important in um
in in the new one is that I will be able
to apply a different type of qas if you
want it won't be packet based so
initially the traditional Qs works
uh works by prioritizing something some
type of traffic over another in in
moments of congestion now with the new
tools that I have at my disposal with
sd1 I can do some some different type of
queries for example I have this big
cheap internet pipe that I only use for
scavenger applications like I don't know
employees watching YouTube
uh
commercials
and I have this more expensive maybe an
mpls pipe where I wrote my my critical
applications and the nice part is that
using Central orchestration I can do
things like
if all of a sudden YouTube it becomes a
business critical application because
maybe I have the trainings on it I will
be able to just
with a couple of clicks Define look the
YouTube traffic now it's not scavenger
move it to the more important link so
everybody is happier including the one
that wanted to do training on YouTube
so since we I only had two more minutes
I'll end with a
whoops
on button with a thank you
and if any questions please thank you
very much we have a question
hi so uh first of all I just want to say
that your passion really comes through
thank you a really great talk
as you mentioned the the landscape is
fundamentally changing and with that the
role of a network engineer is
definitely changing right we're moving
from one model to another what would you
say are
[Music]
individual contributor level skills that
people should focus on as we move from
the the way we used to do things to the
new way that we're apparently going to
do things thank you thank you very good
question because actually it's even more
complicated than that it's not gender
internal users at the same time there's
this big move to where it's Outsourcing
of all i t and of all networking so
things happen in parallel and usually
the service provider is taking it over
are not really much more equipped than
the users inside but just to answer your
questions I think that the
main new point that the network engineer
should take in is to understand the new
technologies that are around software
defined things and the reason for that
is that it's fundamentally different so
you would say an entry-level Junior
engineer initially if you go and tell
them look you need to change this 1000
side QRS mapping they all said it will
take half a year I'll do it Hand by hand
on which one of them plan the changes
and so on maybe a more senior one would
think about scripting and doing some
sort of a hand
little application but with this in
these days if you get it right from an
architecture perspective
and you couple all these
software-defined walls together you can
actually do changes in just a in just
with just couple of clicks
you know I'm I'm not praising the GUI
and get lit of CLI because
we should also have employees and know
how how things are going but when it
comes to how to apply changes and also
how to apply security from that
perspective things are much easier and
much more Dynamic and much simpler with
the software defined platforms and some
of them are more mature than others so
for example I think that software
defined when is at
about there with the maturity
Data Center Software defined networking
is in its Bloom somehow while with the
campus part we are still at the
beginning but in terms of fundamental
shifting in in how Network Engineers
think
understanding these new things is key
and how to use them because it
there's another challenge to it usually
Network Engineers are very afraid at
least the I would say the more
experienced one are very afraid of these
platforms when you do three clicks and
it changes everything in your network
and they should learn to live with that
because it's how we need to do things in
the future
but thank you nice question
thank you very much I I can see another
question
point of view of security not commercial
do you think that is better well that
the network equipment producer to make
updates on firmware software many years
not only five years three years
yeah I think things
a lot of configuration a lot of you know
yes so just to play it back to make sure
that's correctly you're asking about the
level of support and the updates that
the network vendors are keeping for
their equipment correct
so basically it it depends because uh
some equipments have a longer life cycle
than others however I think what's
extremely important there apart from
what the network vendors are doing
because we we have limited leverages
with them I think it's very important to
maintain healthy processes and healthy
rules and way of approaching things
inside companies inside public sector
inside Enterprises and things like
making sure you don't have equipment
that's end of support and nobody does
patches for it anymore it's very
important so I would say yes of course
the network vendor should do much more
for us because we are paying them
large amounts of money everybody knows
that but there's also I I firmly believe
that we should also look at ourselves
and see what we can do better and what's
easier to do
and keeping healthy rules about how we
maintain software how many team pages
How We Do patching how we keep equipment
in support is
even more important
I
we are not good so good and make a
worse configuration and for important of
your security is not good
no it's not and uh these things will
always happen I think that at a certain
extent this new software-defined world
will help because as long as you
decouple this Sunderland overlay
you should be safe because the overlay
part the security part that is actually
user facing or application facing is now
moved to something that's automated and
orchestrated and usually the engineers
are just creating the underlay which
exposes
less from a security perspective
but you're right so things can be
improved there
thank you very much for the questions
I guess I have we have time only for one
more question one more short if possible
how do you mitigate the identities on
something
sorry how do you mitigate if a user
password is leaked
if a user password is stolen that's the
question right okay uh I won't go to MFA
because that's the obvious uh answer to
that so the the key there is to define
the policies and the way to map
endpoints to micro segments not just
user based so usually there's a
combination you need to authenticate the
device via certificate somehow then you
authenticate the user there is way of
doing that to the ways of doing that
today with yep chaining and so on and on
top of that you also look at the posture
of that device meaning it has the right
level of patches and the virus and so on
you're just decreasing the risk
obviously everybody will be able to
store passwords as we have heard earlier
today
and apart from mitigating how you
authenticate that device there's also
the key factor that is these new micro
segments new segmentation way is really
decreasing the a lot of the attack
surface so even if a credential the
principle is even assumed Bridge you
know from my second slide assuming
having bristles then you have
such a small attack surface that usually
you'll just get devices of the same
security sensitivity exposed after you
get such a breach
but as with security you can never be
100 safe
will still be available in the lobby yes
additional questions and now we can move
for the thank you very much
[Applause]