hi I all right welcome to be sized
Detroit the six year
so you guys are there's something
special today on sessions run from 10 to
five today if you have a paper wrote
like our program thing that things out
of date and so are the signs so check
your fault you know
go on the web for that or there is a TV
over there with the schedule on it so
you can go on check it out
box lunches will be provided by us today
because it is a little bit of a walk for
a lot of places so enjoy enjoy free
lunch arm yesterday was converging a
great turnout some of we see some faces
from last couple days out there thank
you for coming back today
we also like to thank our sponsors
cuales who's been besides Detroit
sponsor for all six years arm back for
kids who are downstairs which is awesome
ah taking walk-in still also we have
several other sponsors consumers energy
Kirk on CBI sentire trusted sec check
marks and security vital to give around
and like i said the schedule all be up
to date online so on
we do have one open spot so if anyone is
out there that wants to speak at one
o'clock we will take your take your
graciousness to come talk
so we won't throw you at all these days
hangs out of my second Nobel Prize
speaking of my second we also like to
thank my second the volunteers are we
wouldn't be able to do this without the
volunteers so give her a round of
applause
and with that we'll get ready for our
keynote our keynote is atlas of doom