hi my name is Edward I'm from
- 360 enterprise security group where
in China focused
security and I'm switching in lieu of my
colleague who is going to speak on
crowdsourcing and people I'm gonna speak
on wanna cry on people so just to give
you a preview today's chat will really
be more on people and process so a lot
of the other talks that you had today
are more about technology deep
technology and you know the code and how
to hack this one's more about a company
and hopefully it's interesting you and
and so yeah we'll get started so there's
two ways to deal with security threats
the first that is the first way in case
of emergency just pull the cables
dealing with threats getting offline
which doesn't work and the second is
actually getting hands-on getting people
involved in the process people analyzing
data analyzing the specific attack
finding where the attack came from
figuring out remediation and pushing it
to two people so today I'm actually what
I'm going to talk about are a couple of
these things
three days of Red Bull which is 360 and
the team at 360 stopping run and cry in
China in 72 hours and how we did it it's
mostly gonna be about talking about
which teams were involved I'll introduce
what kinds of teams are involved in a
national level incidence response I want
to talk a little bit about the types of
technology and products that we also
used behind the scenes okay so a little
bit more about 360 we we are spin a 360
enterprise security group is a spin-out
from 360 group so there's two sides all
together if we combine the consumer side
which is 360 group 7,000 people and us
about two thousand we're about nine
thousand ten thousand person shop my my
team or my group focuses on serving
enterprises and and government and our
mothership if you will
focuses on serving consumers but in a
moment you'll see why
both of us working together has been
very helpful and specifically in in data
coverage and and network coverage hey
I'm sure everyone here is familiar with
one I cry but just in case someone isn't
wanted quiet what was you've probably
heard around somewhere which is when
something gets on your computer and they
tell you to pay some Bitcoin somewhere
to unlock your files was unique about
wanna cry is it combined ransomware and
NSA's eternal blue hack and that tool
was a tool which enabled the ex
exploited Windows SMB protocol and
allowed for this around somewhere to
spread very quickly it started this
attack started in May earlier this year
and in one day infected over 200,000
computers so got to a lot of different
places that you might have even heard
places like hospitals in in Europe got
those machines couldn't work ok so
here's a here's sort of the the battle
replay eternal blue actually was leaked
out sometime in mid 2013 and it was
patched earlier this year in April or
May and marched by by Microsoft but as
you know a lot of people don't use their
patches in in April of April 14th shadow
brokers released this code so everybody
was able to start using an NSA level
exploit tool and and so then we 360 we
already we started really Microsoft
released some patches we released the
patches and then in May of May May 12
360 started seeing the breakout the
breakout of wanna cry and that's because
we have over 500 million pcs in China at
user software and we have about coverage
at about 10 to 20% of the DNS lookups in
China and so we're able to see when that
actually started and very quickly it
will see over the next three days we
started patching the older os's
we released a foul at repair tool so
even if your father unlocked we're able
to repair it that was on the 14th and
then and then and then we released a hot
fix on that on the 15th now store on the
team this is how we structure or
security team at 360 we called the
security innovation center and
underneath the security and innovation
center there's three security institutes
one focuses on national security so we
call it state and China I guess we call
state nation state it's the same the
second is enterprise security in the
third is personal security and
underneath each of these teams we we
have 15 teams that do what they want to
do basically 15 research teams want each
focus on different areas focused on some
focused on virtualized machines some
focused on mobile hacking some focused
on hacking the Tesla and also PC and
Windows and whatnot we've invested a lot
in these teams they've already covered
408 as CBE's multiple championships
whatnot lots of patents also found a lot
of vulnerabilities in this case it's
Android I'm finding it sorry I'm
battling two flutes from the last two
two weeks so bear with me you know
multiple multiple vulnerabilities found
by our team doubled out of Google but
today I want to mention about five or
six of those teams that were involved in
in one a crime and the first is the
threat intelligence center our sky eye
team sky wall team or cert which is a
security incident response center and
then two of our the two of our hacking
teams the first three teams I wanted to
mention is sky eye and that team
specializes in looking at DNS data so
for our company one thing is important
is we need to be able to provide a map a
situation map of national security so
having a threat intelligence team that
looks at network traffic dns traffic was
very important for us to figure out that
in our case at 3:00 p.m. or
we am in on me I think it's made at 12
we found out that trying to start be
compromised by want to cry the second
team is an end point team or Skyler team
and they're the one that makes their end
point product in a short time but
they're also the ones that are providing
this the system hotfix as well as
patches to eternal blue the third team
that was involved is our firewall team
they provided the product patching to
monitor in and out traffic so that any
company that was had endpoints already
infected I was connecting to the wanna
cry systems the firewall team would to
be able to block that block that in and
out traffic one point team that maybe
doesn't get enough attention is the the
cert team instance response so 360 cert
provided the security response and
coordination across multiple lines the
product sales even PR delivery and
threat intelligence to deal with wanna
cry the second the other team two other
team that are involved was the Vulcan
team which prior won pwned to own and
found a lot of vulnerabilities in
Microsoft there were the one to do the
file repair tools so that even if you
were compromised and your files were
locked they are able to unlock it the
third team sometimes people forget but
product delivery and the system
engineers the sales teams are also very
important in an enterprise operation a
lot of our companies also a lot of our
customers also include the companies
that had what we call computers not
connected to the internet so in I don't
know if in some of your companies or
maybe if you're a security engineer you
might serve some customers that security
needs are so high that they there cuz
their computers don't really even
connect to the internet and so we had to
manage 1,000 people over the weekend to
take USB disks and go to each of the
customer
to provide the patches immediately
provide patches because the water crime
is not going to wait until Monday for to
start the talk was always on the weekend
and so that was very important for us
these are three of the people some of
the stars some of like the people in
this room people were involved in the
security the first guy mr. Zhao is the
head of the emergency response team and
so he led all the coordination in the
whine and cry incidence response now to
touch upon the process in in the next
few slides
second team which create all the tools
to remediate and also protect mr. Jang
he he's established a security
capability threat intention threat
intelligence and DevOps
and a third is our my colleague mr.
Zhang who is a leader of the solution
delivery team so he's the guy who was
able to work with a thousand front line
experts security engineers whatnot to do
all the patching repairing and all the
communication so processing
collaboration so for each of our
customers or for violent crimes
specifically we created an ad-hoc
response command center so this is
almost like a emergency you can liken it
as emergency if there was an earthquake
or a fire in a region you might set up a
ad hoc command center in that local
region so we set up an ad hoc response
there specifically for one a crime so
that any incident that's broke out would
first that would be communicated to us
we would have expert team across
multiple disciplines and product lines
and research centers to figure out what
was the main reason for that attack we
then Ford those principles behind the
incident to the solution team and then
the solution team would create a
solution and guidance document and how
to deal with that incident and then the
third would be we would deliver that
product for our PR team our product team
and our traceability analysis team to
communicate and deploy the solution
so this is sort of a different way to
look at sorry well it's not changing
sorry okay
this is another way to look at how we
how we clustered the response team
emergency response team had a expert
team we had someone from solution
development and then the support in
addition to that then we had scheduling
customer feedback as well as the
contract contractors to collaborate us
to deploy the solution
okay so technology so what was the kind
technologies that we used in in sort of
figuring out these things and and
finding out wanna cry well one is
customer coverage so because we have
about 90 percent plus the PC users and
mobile phone users in China as was much
many customers and government enterprise
they were actually the ones that were
able to give us the wanna cry file
samples so when we got the file samples
from them be from them we can actually
have things to work with and also we can
observe when our customers their
internal networks are setting forth
wanna cry traffic so a high customer
coverage or a lot of customer coverage
is in the field knowledge and that was
very important for us here's a more
example a broader example of some of the
the file the file coverage the file
behavior coverage website database etc
that we have and all this was very
helpful for for awhile decry deployment
one specific tool that we it was very
important was our DNS record system so
we have around coverage about 10 to 20
percent of all DNS traffic in China and
so when you have coverage of DNS traffic
in China and across different industries
in
in this left hand side you can see that
when they're when wanna cry started
breaking out so you can even track to
the exact exact time when that would
break out in China by oh man one
question there's anyone anyone here
works in the government or state
security national security if you okay
maybe you don't want to tell okay no
worries but but I'm happy to if you're
interested some more the details I'm
happy to connect you to people in our
team that to share more about this but
the right hand side is also on specific
an even pinpoint specific places where
the computers that were compromised in
is in this case so some that the four
the four main tools or the four main
outcomes that we want I want to cover is
when we created the NSA exploit immunity
toolkit so this is to deal with eternal
blue so if you have this or if you patch
through Microsoft you wouldn't be
affected by the SMB exploit and so
that's one way to stop sales wouldn't
stop tool the second tool if you got
infected already was there file
decryption tool so we developed a tool
that was able to fetch the secret key
out memory so that even if your files
were encrypted you're able to to
unencrypt them and use them so you don't
have to pay Bitcoin
the third and fourth tool are more
enterprise level tools that for network
and forensic so in order to support one
and cry incidents breakout and traffic
comparison we gave a tool called magic
mirror and that was very much used in
government and enterprises for self
inspection to make sure that your you
aren't compromised or if you are
compromised what's the situation
the fourth is our basic endpoint
solution and that provided that the
intelligent patching for system okay so
as sort of wrapping up you know I think
this was a just a very very brief and
quick introduction of some of those
things that we've done for for
national security in China back in
earlier at the Woodsen conference mr. xi
jinping
who's the president of china visit our
booth and he told our president that you
must cybersecurity is important you must
do a great job and then serve as a final
shameless plug we also have a security
conference where we meet with a lot of
the government and security experts in
the field and and we have that also
going on this year in September 11th and
13th if you're interested please let me
know maybe I can try gonna coupon for
the conference and so forth from my key
takeaways security is a 24/7 mindset
it's not just creating a product and
deploying sending out a product it's
actually what we call in China it's
China's is there's this term called 996
it means working from 9 a.m. to 9 p.m.
six days a week in this case security is
really 24/7 and we had to start working
on this right on the weekend over a
Friday Saturday Sunday and an investment
second key takeaways investment in
people building world-class teams across
multiple disciplines a lot of our teams
especially these hacking teams we just
sort of let them do what they want to do
I've seen a you could probably find you
know coffee making machines or like toy
guns or like drones or even washing
machines in or hacking a hardware
hacking team and that's because they
just like to explore and so for our
company is very important to less than
people who had a passion for security
and in this case the people had a
passion for security and windows
technology was very helpful maybe a year
later or maybe some other time maybe
it's a hat it will be a hack on IOT
citizens or it's a hack on SCADA systems
and in that time you really need a team
that's very capable in that specific
discipline to deal with that specific
issue third national level instance
response requires coordination across
multiple teams so having an instance
that having the product teams not
enough you need incidence response
product you need your security research
and a file you need customer deployment
even if you have a solution just like
what we've seen in Microsoft Microsoft
has patches that people don't use them
or not everyone uses them so you really
need a full range of teams to deploy the
solution and finally in technology and
data a part of these attacks were
utilizing a prior known technology so
technology like eternal blue we are a
developed technology to prevent the
spread of the virus using external
external blue so we already had some its
expertise and prior data and our and our
prior infrastructure that we created on
DNS lookups let us able to pinpoint the
customers more quickly to know who had
one in Christ so technology and data
were very important foundation of what
we did ok so that's it thank you we put
questions or okay if you have any
questions I'll be free alpha Nori's you
can find me and then love to chat and
meet you thank you