good morning everyone um my name is
Kemal
in cyber network operations just a
little bit of introduction about me I
work with the company named dark matter
we are based in Abu Dhabi I have been
doing digital forensics and Incident
Response for seven eight years I've been
I have been part of doing a lot of
threat intense activity as well and
everything that I'm talking about here
is based on my own experience in my
current company in my previous work
experience as well anything being
presented here does not reflect the
position of my company it's all my own
thoughts and also I'm not here to talk
about any classified information since
we are talking about intelligence and
counterintelligence so if that is
something that you are expecting that
you'll be disappointed because I didn't
have I don't have any classified
information to share for intelligence
activities so to start with why why we
are talking about intelligence and
counterintelligence we are we are here
for a cybersecurity gathering in my role
of doing threat hunting and red teaming
and blue teaming as well there there
have been instances where you play a
different kind of roles one of them is
the terrorist not the terrorist that we
know of but it's some more more closer
to the right team members because they
are the kind of the people who give you
the tools and technologies and they give
you those inputs which you can apply for
making your cyber operations of more
intelligent so the intelligence gathered
from from your rate team is it works
like the opposite force which is a
well-known well-known term in US
military then we have the hacker or
ethical hacker as we call in the
community
the usual penetration tester role
software developer breakers makers a
consultant most of most of us in the
cyber security industry we do it on a
daily basis while we are trying to while
we are trying to cover up the usual
technical stuff and at the same time
trying to make the people who are
non-technical and not not into
cyberspace make them understand that
what exactly we we are into and spy this
is something that will cover up in
upcoming slides and the most important
thing is yes we are here to talk about
cyber security so cyber network
operations
it started as military thing as computer
network operations
it can majorly be seen as three
different domains cyber network defense
cyber network exploitation and cyber
network attack I'll be mostly talking
about cyber network defense and cyber
network exploitation attack is something
that we are not covering here defenses
is of a networker system from your
adversity attack and how we gather the
intelligence from that phase and feed
into the other team and utilize it
exploitation is the data obtained from
the intelligence apparatus to support
the defense activity so both of these
are both of these team C and D and C any
support each other with the
intelligence gathered I wanted to talk
about intelligence and
counterintelligence because these these
are the traditional intelligence method
methodologies which have been refined
over the time and nowadays into into the
cybersecurity we use a lot of a lot of
feeds there are a lot of buzzwords when
we when we talk about cyber intelligence
every day we come across people doing
new research and trying to provide us a
kind of a new framework or new thought
process about it but but there are
well-established framework from the good
old days which we can apply and utilized
in our in our current scenario with
respect to your commercial organization
seeing your commercial organization as
similar to a nation-state so I'm not
here to I'm not here to trying to stop
the the current the current process but
rather rather take a backseat just look
at the well-established old processes
and apply the same thing in the current
scenario so this is the agenda for today
intelligence and its applications in
cyber network operations and also about
the counterintelligence so we will we
will deep dive into cyber network
defense and cyber network exploitation
both from intelligence and
counterintelligence perspective and how
we are going to utilize that in our day
to day work life as we work as a cyber
security consultants so
what is a national city what is national
security what exactly nation try to
protect when we talk about national
security why they use why they why they
emphasize a lot on applying intelligence
and counterintelligence so if if you if
you think of if you think of a nation
they try to protect their technology
their finances their economy their
infrastructure and of course every state
every company and every person has their
secrets so that's what a nation try to
predict if we look at our organizations
in the same perspective what we are
trying to protect so we try to protect
the assets in our company which which
helped us to grow and hood has put us in
a profitable position as compared to our
competitors whether we know or not we
contribute somehow that integral society
through our organizations and so our
operational capabilities our financials
our client secrets are in research and
development so all these things if you
try to relate it relate it with the
secrets that a nation try to protect we
can actually apply the same methodology
we can Apple we can apply the same
thought process the nation applies to
protect themselves from other
adversaries and your enemies so because
we we as a company we as person have
quite a few secrets that we want to
protect so that we can put ourself in in
the competition and get ahead in the
market so we'll try to apply the same
techniques I will see what are those
techniques what are what are those
methodologies and how we can actually
apply in our cyber network operations
so when we talk about intelligence it's
essentially collecting analyzing and
exploiting the information that supports
a specific cause that gives you some
power that gives you some knowledge so
and when we talk about cyber
intelligence or cybersecurity there is a
lot of hype these days that we need to
avoid a general notion these days is
whenever we talk about threat
intelligence or cyber intelligence
people are very much attracted to
different kind of feeds so just getting
a feed is not an inter it's not
intelligence it is just an additional
source of collection that you are
getting in maybe from a third party
maybe from another source but that is
not essentially intelligence that that
you are acquiring it is just another
form of information that you need to
apply in the intelligence lifecycle that
we will look into the upcoming slides
and how you can utilize it in your cyber
network operations on on daily basis so
one of the objectives of intelligence is
to support support yourself support your
company in such a way that it gives you
the power and knowledge and competencies
to get ahead in the market specifically
talking about specifically giving you
insight into a lot of things that you
can that you can deduce from the fields
that you are getting in so a really
brief history about intelligence if you
if you think of the intelligence
activities you can get kind of
references as as old as in a lot of
religious methodological books as well
be it Bible or any other religious book
there has been not direct but a lot of
indirect references so also the early
the early days of cryptography where
they use they use a lot of the they use
a lot of cryptographic methodologies to
pass on information to protect it from
their adversaries and in the modern days
title 10 in the US military function and
title 50 in national security and for
foreign intelligence so it's like every
country has although they they have
their military operations they surely
have dedicated work force dedicated
personnel and dedicated wing for
handling intelligence and
counterintelligence in early 20th
century when we started getting more
into the cybersecurity world there ooh
we started seeing a lot of private
intelligence services both on the
personal side as well as the cyber side
and today we see a lot of overlap
between both of these what are those
techniques which were being used in
those old days for intelligence and how
we can correlate that to cyber network
operations so with respect to cyber
network operations it's a multiple
source intelligence product and it
includes a lot of counterintelligence as
well you can think of a lot of different
sort of intelligence functions like
signal intelligence open source
intelligence human intelligence and
those and a lot of these were being used
in the usual intelligence and
counterintelligence activities by the
state nations in almost every country
these these these sort of intelligence
activities are widely used in in cyber
network operations as well whether you
are working as a red team member a blue
team member you are an investigator for
instigator Mallory analyst you somewhere
you apply those techniques I you just
need to be maybe a little aware about
that how we are how we are correlating
that with the existing framework of
intelligence and not getting lost into
trying to discover something new just
because this is related to cyber there
are a lot of other disciplines as well
when we talk about intelligence apart
from open source intelligence human
intelligence and signal intelligence so
starting with the signals intelligence
this is a lot of folks among us have
already been doing this which can
further be seen as two different
activities communication intelligence
and electronic intelligence so
communication intelligence is the
day-to-day network operations that that
we do which is related to the network
traffic ssl/tls in inspection network
based DLP a lot of a lot of other
network based fields and network based
information that you ingest on daily
basis and you try to feed in to whatever
solutions you are using or whatever
solution you are trying to develop when
communication intelligence is probably
one of the most recognized form of
intelligence collection today and
electronic electronic intelligence is
something which is which is based on the
non communication very close to the
signals data be it your GPS signals
missile operations anything that does
not contain the usual network
communication signals can be can be seen
as the electronic intelligence and there
are there there there is a whole lot of
application both in cyber network
defense and cyber network exploitation
so from the I because I'm working in the
defense side I can very much relate to
all these all these activities for
network traffic monitoring SSL and TLS
inspection network based DLP DLP lot of
other host based data that you that you
collect anything which is coming from
the computers this is surely being used
by a lot of seeing the guys and when you
talk about cyber network exploitation
performing man-in-the-middle attack you
are looking into all this communication
trying to trying to pick it up in in
between so what what essentially are you
doing you are essentially applying the
interior applying the intelligence
technique over there something which is
passing through you are just picking it
picking it up and you are trying to do
exactly the same thing that a usual
intelligence and counter intelligence
operations guys do open-source
intelligence is in in cybersecurity well
lot of guys will argue there probably
this is this is probably the only form
of intelligence today which is somewhat
kind of true because when we when we
talk about applying intelligence in
doing exploitation or doing even even
for on the defense side on investigation
side we use a lot of open source
intelligence which covers a lot of data
coming from open source feeds it could
be DNA as IP
geolocation any information leakages
that we that we come across every day so
some people also argue that there is
something like close source intelligence
as well that could be payment
information policies applied in the
company a lot of these things that that
you don't come across in the open world
so open source intelligence is something
which is widely used as well the human
intelligence but this is this is very
interesting and very very close to
applying intelligence techniques I have
been using a lot of human intelligence
in my previous experience doing a lot of
Investigation interrogation as well a
lot of a lot of these a lot of stuff
related to human intelligence is very
common to your other operations which
are not into sight but for example your
human resource so when they are
recruiting are they able to find out the
guy that you are talking to is not any
spy what is the history of that guy
whether are you applying the proper
human intelligence techniques over there
not just looking into the to the
technical capability of the person but
also but also the human human factor
behind that so what is the objective
what is the objective of human
intelligence it is a widely recognizable
form of intelligence and it this is
typically where the human espionage
system comes into the play and you have
to keep in mind what are the sources
where you can get from where you can get
the human intelligence information a lot
of these have been applied in the past
and today as well in crisis related
sources like refugees humanitarian
crises detainees leadership related
sources diplomatic embassies local
leadership all these functions apply
lot of human intelligence and again when
we try to relate relate the our
organization capabilities with the
nation-state capabilities we can we can
apply the same techniques when do when
we are doing a kind of recruiting or
when when you are when you are an
investigator or even if you are a
forensic guy how do you relate the human
intelligence factor with their with
technical evidences that you gather so
this is a typical intelligence cycle
please excuse my prolly drawn diagram
but this is a typical intelligence I
cycle where if you start with the
tasking collection go to the processing
analysis and dissemination
this is a typical intelligence cycle
that all intelligence groups usually
apply and we can apply the same
techniques while we work in the cyber
operations and there are high chances
that most of us are already doing it at
different we have already been doing it
at different stages in our life in
different stages of our work experience
whether we are aware or not and in and
in daily basis as well it helps it helps
you to in decision-making how you can
quickly gather the information and how
quickly you can process it and apply it
in your cyber operations so let's take
an example of of cyber network
exploitation where a red team can
leverage the intelligence cycle and
gather some intelligence feed in that
intelligence to the other team and how
the how that can be applied so let's
take an example that there is a team who
is doing some sort of in offensive
cyber offensive operation and they got
their target they know that whom they
they know that whom they are targeting
they tried to gather gather some
information using open source
intelligence they achieve some
information using a person's open source
intelligence they start doing the
collection acquiring information
regarding the employees infrastructure
management and lot of other open source
intelligence process and analyze that
this collected information and deliver
it to the upper management whether this
is something that which which you are
looking for but they come to know that
okay this is this is not enough
information we need to go a little more
deeper and they want to launch a
campaign directly targeting the other
organization that's why everything like
social engineering web application
attacks network penetration target try
to gather human intelligence of the
families of the employees so even even
if even if these guys were not able to
gather the information they wanted to
they still got some information this
will got some information which can be
feeding to the top level that helps
again to take your decision that what do
you want to then to do next
exactly applying the intelligence cycle
so based on the intelligence that was
gathered in this phase decision is made
to probably up the risk level let's go
to let's let's go to a little closer to
to the company which we are trying to
target and physically go to that host
country if if that organization is in a
different country so they try to go a
little more offensive they go on site
they go on side they start probably
using raw ApS try to try to catch Wi-Fi
signals
got to break a few passwords and with
that information you are able to be able
to get into a few user accounts so so at
the end of this activity what exactly
they got they got access they got access
the Wi-Fi provided them more enough to
start a additional additional collection
getting into employee information
getting into more passwords and all and
this information once collected feeds
back into to the additional objective
again into the decision-making and the
phase the whole cycle again starts with
with the tasking so they started with
the collection the process stayed
provided it - provided it into the
decision-makers based on that the
decision is made and again the whole
life cycle starts until until and unless
you get was what exactly we are looking
for if you apply the same cycle in the
defensive side for example three hunting
so if so if you take an example that you
are the company who were targeted in the
previous example how do you and you have
no idea you have no idea that you have
been penetrated one day one day one of
your you know your IT team applies some
updates and they got to see some maybe
signatures which looks which which looks
like a little dirty and your internal
thread hunting team decided to get into
a little more deep thread hunting
activity so what they what they do they
invited a third body three hunting team
to to get a little more information that
what exactly has happened so there is a
there is a insulin response and
threatening team there they come fully
armed with the shock in a box
leveraging customizes full network full
network packet captures EDR SSL
inspection neutralization everything and
they try to go all over the organization
trying to collect as much as information
they can connect they can collect so
they start collecting they're capturing
all the event logs processes
applications firewall everything that
they can think of everything that they
can get access of now they start
processing this information they start
reducing the noise trying to reduce the
signal-to-noise ratio they isolated some
traffic cross-references the traffic
with the initial detection from the AV
or whatever solution that you were using
and analytics of the data gathered was
done and it is started to build a
picture and a picture to start to emerge
and you got to know that you were
compromised
what exactly was that but that is
probably not evident as of now but you
get to see that there was a compromise
probably six months back so this
information is passed on to the
management who decide based on the based
on the information that we have that
what exactly you want to do next
probably would want to involve another
team to utilize this intelligence
gathered and probably go a little more
deeper so the intelligence collected
from the previous phase in the in thread
hunting you involved forensic guys
marvelous reverse engineers to come in
and work with the tree enters via tasks
so how do how do they work from there
from where do they start they cannot
simply go blind
you know just picking up anything and
start reversing or picking up random
computers and taking a disk images Ram
images and start doing forensics so
obviously you need to give in some feeds
some intelligence and that is how you
can probably minimize the time to
respond so they their work is based on
the intelligence
gather on the previous phase the dear
tasking is based on the whatever threat
hunting guys have provided them this are
the this are the process of collecting
the information for the purpose which
would be RAM images disk images pcaps
may be mobile phones as well they
conduct interviews they apply some sort
of human intelligence interrogations
questions like which all guys you
connected in the past ten days
what are websites that you can remember
or what what all pop ups that you could
see on your system based on the traffic
that you have seen and again the
information that is collected from the
analysis forensic analysis as well as
malware analysis in Virgina reverse
engineering is fed back to the threat
hunting cycle and it starts again with
this information with a more targeted
information and the threat hunting cycle
starts again
the whole process whole process of
collecting the information starts and
the information is fed back again to the
next civil team so this is this is a
typical example of applying intelligence
in in cyber network defense operations
based on this whole exercise a picture
is drawn up for the management to the
organization to make a decision and that
is that is how a lot of nations take the
decisions based on these activities when
there are specific teams when there are
specific operations team provide them
the information so possibly what could
what could be the best thing that we can
do after all this activity is done I can
probably think of the best possible
thing that we can do is information
sharing when you share this information
with others they can they can utilize
the same intelligence that you have
already gather I mean rather than rather
than
depending on some feeds that you are not
aware of
you can probably whatever whatever
intelligence that you have gathered in
your threat hunting cycle you can share
this information with other other
parties other people in the community so
that they don't have to get into the
same cycle again because you are
utilizing the well-established framework
to to gather that information so at the
end of the day after all this activity
regardless of whether you are part of
the red team or the blue team where you
were attacker or the defender the
objectives are made their objectives are
to Intel to leverage the intelligence
that was gathered and apply it in your
cyber security space and whatever
results have you obtained pass it on in
to the community who can utilized the
same intelligence techniques and if you
notice one of the things that we did was
especially on the defensive side was
threat hunting and based on the
information that we collected from three
hunting was the other teamwork you can
do you cannot do threat hunting unless
you know your assets and this is a
well-known quote that many of us might
have heard from the chief of NSA spoke
at besides that you have you have to go
to know your systems devices and
vulnerability is better than your enemy
because information is power I mean you
cannot defend that you don't know and
also they are putting in a lot of time
and if we get busy putting in time every
time doing the same thing we we we might
be in behind behind them always so once
we apply those techniques once we need
to make sure that we have the
information about the assets our systems
our device
says and everything else better than our
enemies and well in time and keep
feeding that information into some sort
of intelligence cycle so that that
information is always available for your
offensive team as well as the defensive
team
so again application to applications of
intelligence into sub network operations
is there have been example that that we
see in that that we have seen in cyber
network operations remember in the in
the first slide is in the second slide
we talked about different rules one of
them was a spy
and this is what exactly we try to do in
our in our daily activities cyber
security analyst you have to be like a
spy in your own job where you know what
they do they they try to gather as much
as information from the human side from
the open source from cyber from any
other source that you can think of so be
the spies of your own network try to get
as much as information try to get
insight of every nook and cranny in your
in your company
become the collectors become the analyst
become more educated into taking
decisions and helping your your decision
makers will will will get into
understanding counterintelligence and
its applications into usual cyber
network operations so country
intelligence is essentially a subset of
intelligence itself and it supports the
protection of an intelligence collection
apparatus it's just it just the other
side of doing intelligence activity we
will see how and it is it is definitely
not always related to espionage
activities it's it is more on it is more
to on
it is more being proactive for for
everything everything that you might get
attacked off so the usual
counterintelligence
is focused on these four things
deterrence which is a defensive
counterintelligence detection which is
again defensive as well as offensive
we'll see how deception and disruption
which is again offensive
counterintelligence so there are
multiple ways to look at it we'll see
we'll see how we can look at all these
ways of applying counterintelligence so
this is an ideal situation that we can
think of or any company can think of it
it is intended to be relatable most
sometimes it it doesn't happen but we
can think of this is an ideal situation
that we have mature processes policies
procedures and operational operationally
effective in the company technologies in
place have been properly configured one
team is and one team is aware of the
other activities that this is what a
typical case that you have a blue team
you have a red team and most of times
they are not aware of what the other
team is is exactly doing you don't you
don't have any intelligence coming from
the your counter power of the team so we
we we only know that okay there is a
team who is more into attack and how how
they are trying to attack how they are
trying to be on the offensive side what
kind of information that they have which
we don't have so we start with the the
defensive side that we have a blue team
they get into the data center they
they're not aware that the red team is
targeting them and they have been
noticing an increase in the network
traffic some sort of malicious
activities poor scanning application
firewalls they get into the data center
they got an alert from a few devices
some sort of rock devices entering into
your environment via some a DHCP Network
and this'll be monitoring on a switch so
they they detect some initial
enumeration of systems using some
deception Network and behavioral and
analysis they observe some money network
traffic some sort of attack attack
scenarios and they think that okay there
is some sort of bad activities going on
they inform the incident response team a
kill chain operation is executed and
they neutralize it right there well
everything is good recovery of the
devices they obtain those devices which
appeared malicious to find out more
information and probably do some
forensics malware analysis and try to
find out the attack activity so this is
a typical situation when they get into
the data center looking at the attack
activities there they were not aware
that it was a legitimate activity what
happened that a red team is also working
they're a team exercise package or
organization a data center they perform
reconnaissance penetrate the facility
probably using the back entrance get it
physically get into the data center your
security guy your the physical security
guy probably didn't notice it so they
decided so the red team decided to go
covered just somehow somehow dodging the
CCTV camera penetrating the facility and
they get into a data center and they did
whatever implants they wanted to do in
the data center and they were able to
successfully exit probably from the
front door with all their badges and
probably the security guy didn't notice
because every time you get into the data
center you are making some entry and
when we were coming out the security guy
thinks that okay
I he this guy had probably already sign
registers or probably is already
authorized but you enter from the back
side they were coming from the from the
front entrance and you know the security
guy doesn't know and he cannot provide
any information to any other team so
what happened at the end of the scenario
both these teams got something so the
red team was successfully successfully
executed a covered operation although
the outcome was not ideal probably all
the objectives were not achieved because
while they were doing the red team
activity it was detected by the blue
team they were there they neutralized it
so a feedback loop begins a feedback
loop begins the rate team provide the
inputs to the blue team that we were
able to do all these activities this is
something that you need to look in this
is something that you need to fill in
feed into your intelligence cycle at the
same time your blue team need to provide
the intelligence to the red team that
how how easily they were able to detect
the the red team operations or those
offensive activities and this continues
so it's a win-win situation for both the
team how do you so how do how do we
apply the counterintelligence
methodologies in the cyber network
operations starting with the defensive
defensive counterintelligence it starts
with the usual risk assessment
methodology we don't whether we know or
not this is this is where we are
actually applying the defensive content
intelligence
physical security personal security
information security community
communication security it's all part of
the deterrence and detection which which
we need to think of when we are looking
at cyber network operations this is a
this is a typical
consequence and likelihood that you can
think of when you are applying risk
assessment methodologies you can
leverage sort of similar framework or
maybe a different framework to identify
the likelihood of the risk which
essentially helps you to feed in that
information to the other teams that what
can be done or what has been done
already and what is missing
this is a typical risk metrics that you
can think of which can provide some
inputs to to your rate team as well as
the blue team based on which what kind
of actions you need to take deterrence
and Direction a lot of activities it's
it's an capaz everything everything that
it can cover starting from physical
security to scenario is like a red team
is if if the red team is not able to get
after a certain level because of because
of the kind of a security posture in
your company that's a kind of good
deterrence and that is something that
that needs to be there so the same thing
for the defense the defense side the
cybernated defense side their own
security controls forced them for the
right team into entering into a
high-risk penetration because if if you
didn't have proper security controls if
there were not proper blue team if there
was not a strong blue team over there
the red team probably would have easily
got into whatever they wanted to take
away from from the data center this is a
very basic and generic deterrence
deterrence option this is a primary
component of protection of information
of physical assets and infrastructure
and in the example that we saw if
somehow
our red team was able to get into into
their data center and come out as well
with whatever information they wanted so
here we are talking about a lot of
things doors locks windows access
control CCTV lightining than everything
so containment this these systems should
serve not only as a deterrent but as a
detection and prevention mechanism as
well
if if you don't have all these proper
mechanism again a red team or an
offensive team will be able to do the
sort of activity they are interested in
personal security again deterrence and
detection detection apply is here as
well
everything everything falls into this
category remember we talked about human
intelligence so a lot of things about
background checks and screening role
based access control this is a typical
this is a typical example of doing in
this is a typical example where you can
actually apply counter intelligence in
general are all sort of gatherings that
we are all aware of so well when you
come across people are you able to are
you able to do some sort of background
check before before you sharing your
information
you know anybody just coming up to you
and asking that can I scan the code
behind your badge whether do you know
whether the person is a part of the crew
whether he is authorized to take that
information or not so a lot of
background checks and scanning role
based access control policies and
inspections of social media accounts a
few basic things like personal so
personal security is designed with the
idea of preventing unwanted employees
from acquiring positions as well as
preventing insider threats so this this
makes a major part of
a person's deterrents and detection
information security are a whole lot
about document safeguarding document
transfer document prediction handling
data classification mobile phones bring
your own devices video audio recording
in the workplace pot all these policies
needs to be in place to to help you to
be in a position to save your secrets
and information that you try to correct
communication security is a preventive
measure to ensure that interception and
manipulation of communication traffic is
computationally infeasible you need to
have proper encryption in emails and
instant messaging it should not it's
like if you are sending sensitive
documents without proper encryption your
phone communication radio systems
whether you know or not there are people
listening to your conversations so
properly implemented communication
security is not only a deterrent once a
breach has occurred it also helps you to
detect detect things so applying
applying deterrence and all these all
this part of counterintelligence in
cybernetic operations so deterrence and
detection are the primary drivers of the
defensive counterintelligence so but it
is it is widely used as when IT
departments network networking
departments and they're already doing it
on every single day whether they know no
or not your recruitment HR has a role in
defense whether they were able to spot a
spy when they were doing the recruitment
or not does the HR have a system in
place which engages the employee - for
bitter happiness that's a that's a part
of the defensive counterintelligence but
even on a more centric level every time
you stand up a new firewall
every time I sign new access right at
the access controls user account all the
excess rights in Active Directory how
does the intelligence of your
organization collects about itself being
leveraged to deter and detect a lot of
host based intelligence all these
activities are a part of defensive
counterintelligence offensive content
intelligence is like red teaming
exercise it and adversary simulations
against your organization all these
activities are applied by the right team
whether they they try they try to find
out whether they are being detected or
not what kind of tools and what kind of
tools and techniques they should be
applying that it is not detected when
you are doing when you are doing the
offensive operation not as saying not
not for not for enemies but you have to
be you have to be the spies or you have
to apply the counterintelligence for
your your own organization so so one
little thing that you need to do is you
need to switch it up every now and then
ask your red team to work as a blue team
and ask your blue team to work as a red
team to understand what kind of stuff
the other time other team is able to to
to get into make it so there is no value
there is Nova and that is how that is
how you I think that's the best way to
feed in the intelligence when your red
team works as a blue team they are
essentially using the intelligence that
they have from their red team activities
and the same thing applies on the blue
team or whatever techniques they apply
for the detection and all when they when
they go on the other side how they are
applying the intelligence that they have
as counterintelligence when they act as
a blue team detection rights it's a it
should not be the case that something
has happened somewhere and I have seen
something it should it should always be
very specific that what happened who is
involved identifying the person people
systems anything so and you cannot do it
unless you have a proper intelligence
feed detection is deception so now when
you're trying to where you might not be
involved in this directly when you are
doing detection but however depending on
your position in the company depending
on the kind of role that you are that
you are in to you you might be doing
detection at different level during
interviews interrogations while you are
a part of if you are a part of security
operations monitoring the electronic
communications physical security all
that all that all that thing is related
to the detection activities deceptions
deception is a kind of there are two
types of deceptions active and passive
active is like purposefully misleading
an individual or group and passive is
this is without withholding the
information from n so sometimes you need
to sometimes you your organization or
the team is aware that what kind of
deception technology are we using
internally and sometimes you have to you
have to use the technologies that the
other guys are not aware in your company
so that you can actually detect the bad
guys if they they are within within the
company so but call it whatever or
whatever you will this concept of active
this this is this is active defense the
concept of active defense is based on an
age-old tradition of deception this is
this is a kind of techniques which have
been used well well in the past and this
is this is not something new
if we are not doing it now both active
and passive deception
within our organizations we need to do
it now the offensive counterintelligence
principle of neutralization z' primarily
responsibility is what typically is
known as counter espionage we we have to
be always prepared there for the spin OS
activities not essentially as as a
nation because at the very beginning we
try to understand that we have to look
our company our assets our information
as a nation-state and we need to apply
the same methodology we need to apply
the same mindset of counter counter
espionage as the nation-state so so so
detection deception and neutralization
can and should always be leveraged in
your organization after all it's our
it's our organization it's our
information it's our secrets so give a
shot at looking at these concepts in the
terms of technologies you have in place
and with the existing technologies we
already have in the company we need to
reinvent we need to just reinvent we
probably need to reframe whatever we
have rather than trying to try to get
into something new approach just running
around with new vendors it's just just
looking for new fields you can actually
utilize whatever you have already have
in your in your organization and you can
actually use that so but the the idea
behind I mean all this discussion that
we had is that modern cyber network
operations were the defensive or
offensive suffer a lot of unique
predicament because as professionals in
the field of cyber security we come
across a lot of overload of information
defining return on investments metrics
politics a lot of things and all the
while we try to seek the same goals as a
age-old physical world related
intelligence and counterintelligence we
need to we can apply the same the same
techniques of intelligence as well as
counted intelligence that we saw in in
our day to day activity so by just
reframing the context of our daily cyber
security duties into an intelligence and
counterintelligence perspective
regardless of the offensive or defensive
nature of the work we can better protect
our organization by leveraging the
age-old well-established framework the
fundamentals and the practices that we
have been applying in the physical world
as a person as and as nations as well so
that's about it if any questions if you
have any questions or even up you can
catch me up after the lunch maybe it was
long talk any questions you can catch me
up at our booth good thank you
[Applause]