hi everyone thank you for coming thank
you for the opportunity day everything
else today I'd like to share some of the
techniques to bypass 2fa with the focus
on the private keys so how to bypass to
a very well in short you must obtain
something user has generally this could
be either OTP or properties unless you
find a way to disable it where pay so
you probably know DB every day such as
when you're doing internet banking or
when you log in to the online accounts
especially the website that applied very
strict security measurements you can
also find out to be in a text message
your voice and your software token
thanks on yourself smartphone but the
point is how do you get somebody is OTP
basically you need to hack their voice
accounts the SMS accounts or you have to
compromise the software tokens such as
Google Authenticator or you hit up on
social engineering so this is the real
life is able to get over TV by social
engineering attacks I believe most of it
a gmail account if you have a gmail
account you probably have received
something similar and if you are reply
to this SMS I suggest you change your
account password now how do you feel how
this how is this work attacker first
they know your Gmail account they know
your email address they know a mobile
number they will try to reset your gmail
password and have the OTP billable to
your mobile phone
then there were SMS you something
similar to the test above and ask for
OTP once you do private OTP they could
proceed to reset your password and then
compromise your mailbox
so once the attacker inside your mail
mail accounts they can proceed to the
security setting and disable the to a
pin support another way to get OTP is
using malware so ben qazi is Trojan
horse
the infects android device once it's
malware installed on the Android device
you will intercept the codes that form
the two-factor authentication you then
do two things communicate with the CFC
C&C server
secretly sending the sensitive info to
sending to attacker then you also call
forward but won't call for because in
some country there is a loophole in the
telephone carrier service they allow you
to doubt a specific number to enable
call forwarding so that means even the
OTP is sent across by voicemail
it is defenseless for this malware
another way to get OTP is if you can
sneak the wireless signal to capture the
test messages there are devices
available I mean I saw some of them in
Def Con so if you want to check that out
on internet if you can predict lottery
number you probably can apply the same
techniques to predict OTP usually there
are three incorrect OTP attempts allow
after that you either have to you either
get banned temporary or you have to be
start the whole process again
so cloning a sync up you can receive the
OTP as well or you use IMSI catcher this
is this device can allow you to set up
fake mobile tower tower you can hijack
and intercept form signals including
boys and test messages usually targeting
phones on the older to G system because
they cannot tell the difference whether
it's real or fake tower it also block
the 3G and 4G signals forcing the mobile
phones hereby to switch to our secure 2g
service and is frequently used in rural
Africa 2g service is more common okay
private keys to get a private keys and
to bypass that were you must first
locate the target their support
key-based authentication most private
keys are protected by pathways so after
you've got a private key the next thing
to do is to crack it before you can use
it or you can extract it from the memory
such as from the SSH agent certificates
can contain both public and private keys
so did you get that container private
keys are also stored in the physical
device such as the USB token the smart
cards and other physical forms again the
certificates are normally stored
encrypted in physical device you have to
crack it even though you got it
sometimes by mistake the users can
connect the USB token to computer and
allow them to be shared as a
Network drugs therefore when you found
them
your monitor these network drives you
might find the certificates or key files
by surprise if you cannot get the past
phrase you can still try to get useful
file information from it let's say for
Peter of certificate it is was trying to
extract the following for using open SSL
or key tool sometimes a simple keyword
can get you a bigger picture of the
target external environment so if the
OTP or private key were compromised what
we the impacts who will suffer the most
for the web they use Google
Authenticator such as Gmail WordPress
Outlook or Google Play if the OTP will
compromise so does the user account so
for the application that use single
sign-on with two-factor authentication
enable compromised a client certificate
to allow access to many different
accounts belonging to their affected
user so because single sign only require
user to authenticate once software
bandar they lost the private keys we
ended up being accused for distributing
malware malware to users because the
store have a key can be used to sign
malicious software for a website or if
the server's private key is compromised
the attacker can put the user by
creating a phishing site the server is
most likely the Linux place servers that
use public key authentication to major
issue with the pka are the passwords
authentications and authorized abuse so
if you can find the settings in your ssh
configuration file you need to rectify
immediately because the password
authentication is set to no so there is
no password the screenshot on the right
shows many entries the authorized keys
file although of having too many public
key entries in the author has key file
does not directly causing the problem
however in the case in the future if one
of the public key were arbitrarily
either added to the file or one of the
private key has been compromised and it
would ask to remove the effect that he
is immunity from all the infected user
accounts wouldn't there be a haptic to
you so are you a let's say if there are
200 entries and of how are you able to
detect the anomaly and respond to it
therefore it is always recommended
to keep the authorized Wow neat and
small so the tool it is best to
understand it comes out how to walk
around with the two-factor
authentication it's the two is only
there to help you if you need assistance
if you know how things work you can
always buy how to have a security
manually how Wikileaks were commonly
associated with issue that causes the
cost by the older version of the best
shell critter graphic libraries and open
ssl so for the product that implement
this effective software no doubt they
also suffer the same fate
you can also use the tool to check
across this issue without having to do
it manually there are many ways to steal
private keys even without using a
seasoned gas boy if the server is not
hardened you open up many loopholes for
attacker to access the system and
download away the private keys if the
secure password policy was not enforced
the account never looked down on
possible guessing attempts it's only a
matter of time for attacker to force in
an extract away the private keys malware
and spyware activities were often fun
together with social engineering attack
us to steal properties so let's start
the demonstration soon I will
demonstrate the process of stealing the
private keys from network then using the
root the key is to assess more accounts
on the network at this point we don't
even talk here so we must first start to
enumerate the network okay let's talking
about the enumeration you will never
know what's on the network you can
choose a few scanning most run depending
on the network environment Advanced Mode
is more like firewall evasion scan the
web skin is is required for haply
she'll shake shell-shocked sorry on
ability in order to find the potential
URL and the hidden network required
error be scared you can choose super
scan they will do all but it would take
more times
although mode is the simplest way to
check everything this process will start
by network and Liberation's because we
need to build up the target database
first to get a list of what holds up all
services are running which posts are
open once here the host information you
will launch each module against the
targets in the database with the primary
focus on getting the keys finally it
will use the root the keys to perform
key-based authentication
besides ameliorate ameliorating for life
host on the network we also need to find
out which hosted setting he based
authentication if a horse does not
supposed PKA there is no way we can
authenticate using stolen private key so
how do you know if the whole support PKA
you can just establish SSA connection
using debug mode then look for the key
what next authentication method public
key if you didn't see likely one means
the remote doesn't support public key or
the engaging at all
or you can just use the to these tool to
check it out for you the command is
there so let's long the SSH attack to
get a key I started the mo okay so we
just run a quick enumerations for
demonstration purpose okay after that
just launch the SSH attacks using the
tools it was not with a brute force in
this case the hosts have been set using
easy password so we managed to get in
there the system's the tool download way
some important info and then the most
important thing is you will download
both public keys and the properties of
each host after that it will start the
authentication process the key pairs of
indications
okay we see one of the PK authentication
success the tool also outputs some
important information which is valuable
for later manual verification usage it's
like here which machine can be accessed
by what users can stuff like that
okay client certificate authentication
the current certificate is the type of
digital certificate that is used by
client system to make authenticated
request or remote server now they more
and more SSL websites require client
system to a quite digital certificate
before visiting the site so the
traditional method for website to
authenticate user is using a username
and password and check in the user
source IP like by watters before
allowing user to hit the protector site
this matter is ineffective and not
recommended for you so they always need
to move around different regions let's
say we found a p12 file during the test
we first start by analyzing the foul
while we analyze it because we want to
determine the best method to extract the
private keys then we proceed with the
dictionary attacks and then Rufus
attacks always use do to launch this new
attack first before the proposal head
because the boo force will try all kinds
of augmentation and it will take a long
time the PDF file is in binary format
inside a certificate you can find both
public and private key and some other
information just like a regular
compressed file is passphrase protected
and also susceptible to hospital
cracking so let's dissect into the
certificate okay this is the whole
process the entire process we already
done analyzed difficut and we have done
cracking the passphrase now we do a demo
okay you remove the passphrase
after that you were strikes the private
key and then the public key okay let's
halt let's see the common name to FA
assassin did you notice it doesn't show
the top-level domain we don't know where
it is calm dog so this is a better man
named the tool proceeded to find out for
you
it will try to enumerate against a list
of top-level domain name and it's found
that is using calm after that you will
contact to FASS and calm try to get the
public file try to match the key
fingerprint compare the fingerprints of
the public key and the private key if
they match then you can confirm this is
indeed the true domain name for the
target for the target URL so now you
found it SSL website you have to prepare
a Windows clients because Peter Peter
means that is used by Windows mostly so
we need to prepare a Windows machine and
install the crime certificate in order
to authenticate to the SSL server right
we setup the SSL website and then this
is the Windows client machine
okay this is the domain name we just
assume it is one A two and then now the
certificate the kind certificate is not
installed when you go to the site it
will give you this error message
forbidden error error number is four
zero three
well just to show you that the
certificate is no install and nothing
helping transfer over so you go to the
attacker machines you just put in one
line command and you will set up the
whole things for you you transfer the
client certificate and the instructions
creat to the Windows system and it will
execute it
or sometimes you have to run it yourself
because you have the reader Peter
doesn't work all the time
the browser will pop up automatically
and it will go to the SSL website and
now the certificate have been installed
you can see the difference
all right if you see the pop-up that
means the client certificate
authentication has successful this is
the remote this is the server
certificates
just to check the cars that have been
installed okay
before once you access to any machines
maybe you can add up a system backdoor
before you leave so next time when you
come back you can come back to the same
system again there are two ways to do
these you can either drop the reverse
shell that can survive the system reboot
or you can add public key to every
account that have been SS but first you
need to create a new user to ever
assessing and generate a new assigned
keeper and then at the public key to
every accounts of every targets in the
database let's do a demo you creating
the user at the background then you
start adding the public key to every
user account
okay let's verify let's switch to 2fa
assessing which is the new user which
how to do a PK authentication to the
remote server or let's try the next one
it doesn't ask there's a doesn't palm
for password that means the pka event as
a success
okay you can disable 2fa on ssh
sometimes some system had bad file
permissions if you found ssh
configuration which is writable you can
always disable cubans authentication by
modifying server configurations
impersonating as a sale website what if
all the previous method failed but you
still need to hack the networks okay
let's bring in the social engineering
let's say you manage to steal a server
certificate you create a server key and
now with the certificates with the
passphrase you can actually create a
phishing site to your clients to visit
and download them our way
the fish the phishing site will appear
identical to the original site because
they are actually having the same so
that we can enter main name your browser
will never check for the IP address if
it's different because your browser only
check the domain name and and a
certificate validity so since the three
teams are mostly current systems so this
is essentially a client-side attacks so
this is the whole process this is our
plan from the previous demonstrations we
know that the windows clients we
establish client certificate
authentication to SSL websites since we
had a server key we can create a fish
inside we then perform the DNS spoofing
to modify the a record of the DNS and
then force the domain and to be
arbitrary we redirected to a fish site
the crime we then visit the phishing
site and download and run the key ended
up in getting the reverse key share a
secured on the client system without
doing dns spoofing there is no way to
civilly redirect the client system to
our phishing website by the way this is
only one line command it will set up the
whole fishing scenario like what we are
playing so let's see the demo
so this is the attacker machines and
this is the window system this is our
DNS which we are going to poison later
this is the SSL website back to our
current system okay now which before the
DNS spoofing is happen we try to see
where is the SSL website this is the
original as always like the IP is 1 a 2
so at the attacker machines where 2 FA
assassins running you just have to put
in one line command and it will set up
the fishing side for you
okay you have been set up the sub key
have been exported the moment you see it
from the reader Peter three windows will
open up each running different processes
the first process to run is the multi
handler that will listen to the reverse
shell by the one in the right and then
there's a DNS spoofing which run in
which using the little cap and also is
dropping so when you go to the Windows
system now you try to paint a 12 8
thousand-dot-com
you notice they appear just change but
to use a they rarely detect anything
different so when the user go to to FASS
and.com they do realize anything because
the certificate is the same
the site content is slightly different
but normally the user will not detect ok
the user run a software and immediately
the attacker get a meter Peter sessions
this is the DNS poofed record we do not
eat anything at East drop windows
because we haven't seen anything
important to the Windows client
so often people ask me these three
questions whether having those
activities can keep them to private keys
the answer is straight no because
private key never left the machine only
the public key will be sent across
network if you if it doesn't then that
means there's a design flaw in the
network protocols so SSH tunnel you can
actually create SSH tunnel using the
route of private key let's say if you
have stay inside a big teams network for
sometimes and I believe by then you
already a compromise many machines they
attend some very important files but how
do you how do you make sure you can walk
out of the girl house without people
busting you the Big Brother make maybe
you can stop you and taking a take away
your USB Drive or maybe just a matter of
time they get a kick hole order to
decrease the USB Drive so the short
answer is you will need to send those
files out from the network the victim
that was security or inside of it means
that was so it can walk past the guard
house without worrying about anything
else if you agree with me then you may
want to create a tunnel to send out the
files so for demonstration purposes we
just created a single chain SSH tunnel
the greater the chain value the longer
the SSH tunnel let's say you can access
the user one and then the user one can
access to another user account by
key-based authentication they just
imagine user tools on the internet and
there's no firewall low Cobra firewall
blocking the connections
again one buying command really the
tunnels created so we need to verify we
login to the user 1 and see if he's if
the tunnel successfully created indeed
he had so let's go to user to a see if
user 1 appear in the process just to
make sure that the tunnel is there
before you send anything else yes
so for recommendations how do you
protect your keys
don't use the post as well as key-based
authentication don't store the
passphrase on computer and try not to
use the same key or same password on
multiple machines don't share your keys
or password or anyone and always encrypt
your keys or DNS server considering
using DNS sack you works by assigning
each DNS request with a certified see
nature to ensure authenticity preventing
fake requests you might try to shorten
TTL which is stands for time to life and
regularly clearly in the DNS catch of
the local machines as well as those
network systems it is good if you can
remember the IP address or some of the
important systems because the browser
will not check the IP it just changes
for you you only validate the domain
name and the certificates so maybe you
can consider using hosts file hard-coded
IP address so you know the first host
power is always checklist before the DNS
if you suspect your key your certificate
in stolen call your CA to revoke the
certificate and also check your SSH
server configurations well time flies
that's all I can share for the short 30
minutes I wish can ensure the future
with you I regret this all the time I
have any questions
so any questions from before yes we have
one about the signalling life other ways
like meet you
well cause I like I hope that it's not
poor you should get a call from like
some unknown quorum call and you any and
the code as it like figure out it you
can clone anything or something if you
receive a call like this and try not to
deploy sorry what was your question I
might have actually you know we apply it
right like all night tap card and I
handle it there's nothing wrong I just
end a call like Willie or my cat be
close something I think my hair I'm not
sure about that maybe we can discuss
tonight offline later yeah okay yeah
okay
Thank You Alexa thank you thank you
[Applause]