thank you all very much for coming today
at our table
I hope you you all had a pleasant
journey to intelligence Ewald here today
let me introduce myself my name is Minh
trivia team of and I am chief technical
officer at embody company my primary
interest is security of embedded smart
devices I'm into code analysis robust
engineering optimization vista's karate
mostly in Python I also maintain Python
arsenal for reverse engineering project
my name is Alex I'm a security
researcher at empathy and also we should
have here maximum illusion but his
absence he is founder one of the
vulnerabilities we found for this talk
yeah so on this slide you can see today
agenda we will start with basic of Intel
MP and into AMT technologies then we
will share our more interesting findings
with you so I will start off today by
taking a look at the Intel 64 system
architecture this is the type of desktop
laptop system architecture you can see
that Intel CPU is definitely the main
execution environment here however it is
not the only one there is also a chipset
with integrated subsystems and
controllers to support peripheral
devices and other system critical
functions one of these subsystems is in
tone management and gene or until M II
it is an isolated stealthy and most
powerful execution environment here the
system field is stored on spi flash
memory it is divided into a few regions
the main region is the flash descriptor
containing the sizes offsets and
in missions to other regions so that the
users of the flash could find its the
region and won't have access to to to
other regions that for security purposes
so the next few regions each every
region is belongs to the specific user
of the flesh the Gigabit Ethernet region
stores the configuration for the network
adapter the ME region is designed for
Intel a new phenomena storage
it holds internally human binary they
are CPI embedded controller region has
peers in skylake architecture however we
never have never seen it so this funeral
blob is included into EFI bias the last
region of the flesh every every code any
program code that is running on the
system is executed in one of these
CPU protection rings we have the ring 3
with user applications having the least
amount of privileges and the most
privileged mode for the CPU is rink -
system management mode such code is
executed from hidden space in Durham
occult SM ROM it it is not seen at any
other level before it so however we were
able to gain access to ring minus 3 the
most powerful execution environment here
it is an Intel it has even more access
capabilities and memory isolation
techniques so now we are going to go
more in depth with its architecture it
is based on MCU with raw memory and
as from memory it consists of a mock
level controller host embedded
controller interface or manager
potential interface here my memory in
Durham a member a funeral which is
stored alongside with the bias on a
spare flash this subsystem is generally
thought as the most privileged execution
and hidden execution environment and
there are a few reasons for that one the
human memory is hidden from the CPU it
is not seen for it in any in any
protection ring additionally it has full
access to drum and outer band access to
the network interface so and the funny
thing that management engine still works
even if your device if your computer is
turned off but plugged into an outlet
this subsystem is integrated in any info
based chips Intel chipset in toad based
system since 2010 it's named variety
pending on the platform type here by
year the interests of researching this
subsystem
into management engine has increased the
main problems with reverse engineering
this technology is false Intel me
ephemeral quote models use its Sisley
functions implemented in the boot code
which is stored in the ROM memory
it isn't accessible for the CPU of
course but and it's sometimes it is
difficult to understand the function
behavior in any genre which is calling
these sleep functions and but
fortunately ROM images can be found in
the back versions of a meteor another
problem is that the code Portela
compressed with help on algorithms with
unknown
with a known compression dictionary
however the dictionaries are had been
already reconstructed
there is also an undocumented m GC or
host embedded control and face
communication protocol we and it is an
undocumented interface what good beer
but the protocol could be Ravens and
reverse-engineered the Emmy you my
memory is still inaccessible for us and
an open society has created a heading to
disables this hidden and stealth
environments but there are no stable
method to do this our systems so if you
really interested to revise in
iterations engineering the insulin if
you know you will need to disassemble
and if you script presented here keep in
mind at this presentation will be
available on our website so don't worry
about copying everything down right now
also there are a few useful links if you
are interested to understanding this
broad team so to understand the
following segments of this presentation
we would like to provide the basics of
Intel in EVE universe so its code is
divided into models and depending on the
system we called model list rice so
however there are basic models such as
bring up the loader and kernel some
drivers and services which is present in
every favor there are also the
application called models that
implements different Intel technologies
basically there are three three funeral
types the ignition field which is
actually only available for NBA version
6 and
with the minimum number size of contacts
then we have 1.5 megabyte funeral which
has incomplete model contents and Leslie
the 5 megabyte finger which is it the
fool if you ever contents so intel amt
active management technology is
implemented as a cold model site in
Germany humor the technology itself is
meant to remote control and
administration of computer systems it
allows remote powering on and the system
resetting the system accessing the by
setup through serial serial Overland
feature also it allows getting the
environment the information about the
system hardware installed through the
web interface and it allows booting the
system from the custom boot image file
through ID here our feature and it
allows quiring the full control of the
monitor keyboard and mouse of the system
through the TVM feature or remote
desktop it is called any of these
features required the deep bra brand to
have for the system usually it is it
means that which set with the plant
should be present on the system the
there are several ways to access into
Lamptey features remote or remote access
is available through the wire to
wireless network interfaces
starting from certain versions messages
received on a wired LAN are instances
and address to certain ports are
intercepted by management and gene prior
to reaching the operating system NAT
stack
messages received on the wireless
interface go to the host wireless driver
and which detects the destination port
and sends message to intel amt whatever
local applications are available to
access interline two features the same
way network applications do for example
the SWS management or swap or HTTP when
a local application sends message
addressed the local internet the local
Intel AMT hostname the LMS local
manageability servers
listen to the traffic direct to the
hostname and intercepted messages route
them to into management and ginger face
or host embedded controllers face here
well-known net for ports that are used
by the remote administrator to access
into empty system thank you Alex I don't
take the floor at this point moving to
come to the next section of our
presentation let's have a look at the
possibility of unauthorized remote
access to into a empty system the first
things to do is to look from users point
of view and how the things are arranged
when user success the intel amt web
server why as a one six nine nine to
network port they are referred to the
logon page and the change challenge with
a standard application required quest so
let's use medicine proxy now with the
help of a proxy server let's analyze
what is actually happening in more
details FC 4 as for our c 26:17 digest
authentication the first request
I guess responds with authorize code for
o0 401 so then we are given a correct
username and password the so accept one
as a legitimate user when give an
incorrect username or password this
doesn't accept one this kind of we have
not surprising at all on this slide you
can see network traffic of successful
attempt so nothing extraordinary has
happened during the authentication
process but the toilet look at sniffing
packets give us a clue what to look for
in the am/fm where it is authorization
header field names we can use with
drinks for searching through that
firmware and pinpoint the very code that
is responsible for the digest
authentication for purpose of reverse
engineer we will be used the ID abroad
disassembly and special order scripts
this plugin was written in Python and
it's a support any format in either the
assembler it should be work for all film
variations prior to them it's called
available our github page some and after
the lotto completes a parsing and
otherwise process in the firmware we
will have a nice and clean in look onto
the present code and data on this light
you can see other windows after analysis
a quick search for the strings like
username real main on signals response
provide us with the exact strings within
an end stack model as we can see they
all cross our effort from the one
particular function this function is
responsible for authentication like
header fields processing and the overall
digest authentication
after a careful examination of function
code we have found an interesting bug
the exit place object path is in the
final comparison of the provided add
computed response the two bailiffs were
tested
against each other to see if they match
but the actual number of wise to be
tested was taken from the user provided
response not from computed one this if
one provides an empty response string
string compare function return zero as a
number of bytes to become part is zero
you it's mean successful of translation
is but it's easy buddy
so let's repeat our previous experiment
but with a local proxy in order to
exploit the newly found probability one
can use a metered proxy to with a simple
script that blanks the response field in
the authorization hidden or gone request
it is very simple script which has a
small size about 10 lines of Python code
so the web browser is configured to
access a network through the local proxy
at hh8 a network for the password so we
have just typing is obvious in incorrect
because the interim C doesn't allow the
password shorten them 8 characters but
we will give it a try the first week
request gives us the same response like
in previous experiment it's okay
but then voila please take a note on the
way of their spawns field is empty and
to him several response wishes to 0 0
it's ok it's successful stir ization
some the attack is now is anticipated as
a legitimate system admin and has full
access to words of the Intel AMT
controls he can do absolutely every
scene without knowledge of password we
check it whistle ability on other Intel
empty Russians from well all
two new ones to check them we simply use
proxy without any realest engineering
after that we reported to be so ability
to into and then the vendor offered to
participate effort to us to participate
they are private by bounty program on
hacker one and we were given a ten
thousand dollars of work as must have
understood it is antiphon bypass
vulnerability which was later to be
known as CV 2017 5689 at least one
ability was originally discovered in a
fiber abyss
yeah for successful attack only need
system based on Intel CPU in chipset
where only need is accidental AMT so
services for successful attack we'd not
depend on software we can successful
attack Windows system Linnaean system
only Mac system not affected because
this code is cut from from where the
general idea is attacker possibilities
and Intel anti capabilities as the same
thing especially they can use the Intel
AMT functionality to achieve their
malicious purposes so what what about in
part according to the Shoreham to my
second there 6378 available IP with
interim team it should be taken into
consideration that shodhan data covers
only the internet while a good deal of
Intel AMT use it incorporate network
this corporate empty can easily be used
by attacker who has connected to a
network some the most affected
industries
providers and universities it turned out
that we saw mobility cadet ACS for
instance assimil central computer based
on the Intel chipset we're sensitive to
each in other words not only enterprise
and the public organization but also
critical infrastructure may be affected
by the vulnerability exploitation so now
a demo time
swing
configure web browser forum access to
the network
through proxy start meeting proxy to log
in the sister
then start me to proxy tool with our
script that just blanks response field
try again I mean in obvious incorrect
password successful stories ation on the
system that's all
so about integrations excuse me
after a blog post went public enable a
network security company was able to
rediscover our vulnerability despite not
having any access to the technical
details of the vulnerability it sir it
is a really impressive work and then
after we released technical details so
the security community developed many
useful tools and streets especially for
visual mobility one of the most
interesting tool been honey pots the
existence of these honey pots make it
impossible to now how many RL into an T
system accessible from Internet now
mitigation well into created patch for
bisphenol Billiton and then provided it
all affected I am vendors follow these
all affected iron vendors created new
firmware which is now available for
users for to download because there's no
ability exist at the front where level
you personally need to update it
it won't happen automatically so how
many people really install it with patch
for example is this whole how many
people yeah no painting of course after
patch releasing we check down great
attack but interim it from where could
be easily downgrade if the s van was
increased as well number wasn't list in
that case the flash right access is
needed so the system which with unlocked
SPI flash regions in most cases the
access permissions probe appropriately
configured so sending cost message flash
protection override to Intel em in using
the hard drive is by flash programmer
should do the trick
Thank You Dmitry of course
it's all good and well but is but this
is possible if Intel AMT is officially
supported on the system F if this
technology has been already activated we
wonder if it's possible for attackers to
spread out the coverage of this one our
ability and the Intel empty itself for
their own goals so as you know it'll
empty is already it is a part of Intel
vPro brand first of all we wanted to
understand how exactly as if we pro
system differs from the normal program
well the vibra the non vPro system is
cheap we check that not a pro system
every pro system may have absolutely
similar in telomere fever images so that
intel amt implementation is often
present on an only pro system
first there is Intel empty code in all
five megabytes funeral versions it turns
out that the main difference is the
presence of the Intel metics m m eb x
model in the UEFI bias and some options
in bias top it's this model that uses
host and better control interface or
management and G interface to configure
Intel AMT however maybe there are
Hardware restrictions or can or how can
we interact with it and make it work the
host embedded control interface seems to
be useful communication channel with
into a mere could be used in the
debugging purposes to gain the status of
Intel Andy and the system itself or to
retrieve some data unfortunately it's a
pity the commons system is not public so
this interface is a bunch of registers
in PCI configuration space and memory
maps input/output it represents a
circular buffer which should be used to
send or receive messages in a special
format this message the messenger should
contain common
after the message is sent to into any
the unknown acknowledged message with
the common status should be responded
there is an Intel driver designed for
these purposes in the system you can see
it in the device manager the driver
maintains the communication listen to me
the message protocol itself is based on
DC my h-i protocol to send a message you
need to know the ID of the specific
client you want to communicate with also
there are some known clients we with a
certain set of capabilities in our case
to configure MT we should use the am thi
client at the format of these messages
arise depending on the history client is
used so for the am thi crying the portal
format should be used as you can see the
messages to have the group ID field
meaning the common group identifier each
group has a specific set of comments so
we should specify the group ID common
code the idea of the clients and send
these messages one by one to configure
until empty after sending this message
don't f each after sending each message
don't forget to receive their knowledge
and a very important moment until my big
model is absent on beer on inside the
you fi bias unmount across system so
there is no user interface for enabling
and disabling empty so user can disable
empty after activation after we have
activated it for david also for the
activation you need to send another
comment and reboot the system and the
funny thing is that the knowledge of the
passport password is not needed so it
occurs that there aren't any hardware
restrictions or at least for some system
we have checked
maybe this areum's fault as a book
proof of concept we have created a tool
to activate the intel amt technology and
assistance both we brought normally Pro
the activated course is consist of the
following program components it should
be used should be run with administrator
privileges then you can remotely use any
feature of Intel AMT so we should have
prepared the demonstration movie for you
so now we on the system one trying to
connect to the another non-liberal
system it the attempt was unsuccessful
we go to the system - which is not vPro
deleting I'm uninstalling the management
interface driver to show that we don't
need it then we use interline t
activator these enable arguments of the
sometime it enables into empty and
assigns this IP address to this system
so we are trying to establish connection
to it to the Intel AMT network port and
as you can see the recent was successful
as you can see we are connected to
gigabyte motherboard with h97
chipset which is not a pro
okay thank you so a current version of
mt activated
has experiment we gained some
limitations for usage so only six to
nine in total desktop chipset series are
supported now a successful empty
activation on 100 and 200 series chips
not yet achieved until empty configures
to standard manageability mode this
means that you won't be able to use the
KVM feature if your CPU is non-literal
the CPU of other chips the mt activation
is possible on the systems with Intel a
mere five megabytes finger versions as I
have already said 1.5 megabyte funeral
doesn't have such functionality
implemented this tool is currently
windows only but it can be ported on
chillings
it uses our kernel drivers for its
operation but it can be implemented to
work with the already installed Intel
management engine driver as well so
maybe you guys are thinking about the
possibility of intel amt technology
being used in the modern so for a
malicious code using calamity is worth
noting that first Olympic or researchers
have already come up with yes with with
this idea in the research second quite
recently platinum a malicious program
has been detected in the world
platinum uses the Intel AMT serial
Overland feature to secretly communicate
with the command center in both K in
both cases the mobile doesn t use a
vulnerability in Intel empty so as
Microsoft says start stated this channel
works independent way of the operating
system ring rendering any communication
over it is over it invisible to firewall
and network monitoring applications
running on the host device so how can we
mitigate this problem well the community
is just
few several medals however none of these
techniques are perfect in some cases the
attacker has a countermeasure for that
if you're a company that uses interim
chief frequently organ infrequently in
your corporate network you simply can't
block this port in the network firewall
and because it is needed and then you
can always use any cleaner script to
remove this functionality however this
is dangerous and can break your system
we didn't stop here and went on we had
the question to be answered what can a
potential attracted to the system has
one point 5 mega byte fever without
until empty implementation this funeral
image could be swapped to fight in
backing over to add the absent until
empty implementation to the system this
part of our research is the progress now
however and but however we have the
following results the obvious way to
swap the 1.55 in word image to 5
megabyte funeral image on this system is
to use an SPI flash program and hardware
program this will allow to bypass the
flash regions blocks but some system
have a spare flash regions unlocked so
this opens way to do the same from the
software the administrator privileges
are required to do this to do that you
can use
kernel driver or exploit local privilege
escalation voice from our abilities in
system management code thank you Alex so
what can a tracker do by using Intel NT
we stable demonstrate what is possible
which chipset serious as you can see
there's still some question marks to the
wrist because there are many system with
many different configurations for us we
still work in progress but it would be
great if you could help us with vendor
we slide to demonstrate at
how attacker would maneuver through your
system for the title we'll check to see
if your system has empty enabled and if
you do and it's not passive then the
attacker can just go ahead with exploit
to use your Intel AMT however if it is
Patchett the attacker can attempt to
activate mg or increase the size of the
firmware and then activate NC to use
your into NT functionality the sync is
because the Intel Emil is right Rinka -
free it of course as the lowest level
people themselves have to patch their
this firmware which is likely going to
be a rare this means that with some
ability will exist very long time so
takeaways we have established today how
easy is it is for an attacker to exploit
a vulnerability in intel amt web server
we also showed you how attacker can
activate in the activate into MC on we
probe in nonverbal system through
undocumented features and finally we
demonstrate how it possible to swap from
where image from 1.5 megabytes to 5
megabytes for the goal of for aiding
into MT system we hope that our search
has supplied and brought awareness to
the security issues in the Rinka - free
faces so thank you for your attention
thank you very much any questions from
the floor no all right well great thank
you very much again