so I confess to knowing absolutely
nothing about smart cities so that's my
confession so the first questions you
anyone is can you just describe to us
what a smart city is so Matteo you're
closest to me and and I've got a beer so
your first okay so the first point I'd
like to make is that in my opinion
actually the opinion of the people who
build Mercy is that the first priority
for a smart city is to improve the
citizens life so to do that they try to
create new services that will help the
people of the city in order to better
manage the time the resources etc so at
the moment the main problem that I see
in a in a smart city beside a security
point of view is that all different
sectors inside a smart city works mostly
on their own so for example to create to
make an example mark you are from UK
unfortunately so you don't know
unfortunately oh my god this is an
Italian making a joke about a bridge
this is not gonna work well Matteo but
even if you are from UK I read in your
in your biography that you spend some
time in France
yep so you may have learned something
about wines I learned a lot about wine
so I lived in France purgatory so like
you in winemaking when you have to make
a wine there are different actors in the
process like in a smart city but all
these actors usually when you when
you're speaking from a single vineyard
or a single continue they all try to
create the same product so they all are
agree on some specific things on their
product and they are all trying to
follow this guideline so that's what I
think is going to happen for a smart
city and another thing that I'd like to
highlight in my opinion is going to
happen very soon is that we have we are
going to have intercommunication between
three main actors the first one is the
physical layer so the sensor
all the stuff that are placed inside the
city so we can control traffic we can
control whether we can control energy
consumed consuming and all this kind of
stuff and the second let the second act
or a second layer is the logic layer
that is something that usually in my
opinion is built by some vendor and
implemented by the city itself so there
should be one actor that control the
different system or at least try to make
the system communicate with each other
properly and then we had a third actor
that my previous research I never
considered man now I'm seeing that is
more more important and is the what I
call the cloud layer or the service
layer that is the integration of no
service that the users already are using
like for example Google services or
Apple services and we can see that is
happening already maybe in a smaller
size like for example IOT
so Apple has for example a home kit or
whatever is the name that you can allow
you to interface with sensor and system
inside the room and for example other
example I'd like to to point is I don't
know how many of you know about the
what's name written down because I'm
very bad with names is Google Flu Trends
so basically Google made an experiment
that with starting reading the research
of the users try to understand when
there is are a flu epidemic when the few
epidemic starts like every year there is
a flu epidemic and they did this
experiment in the UK and they were able
to understand that makes five days
before the National planetary system in
the UK so I thinking that government and
cities will try to use the power and the
knowledge or third-party services or
third-party corporation in order to
implement this third communication layer
within the sensor and the rapture
operators and stuff inside the sea okay
so let me mean a whole because again I
know nothing about smart cities so I try
to try to understand that might be
useful so if I understand what you're
saying it's a combination of sensors
that can tell about where people go
within the cities yes there where people
want okay
connected services and connected data
between all those things yeah and that
is both public data and private data it
sort of is it a partnership between the
both public companies and private or the
public sector and the private sector
that's what my opinion is going to be
okay okay and and then what but before
we go to Eddie because I want to ask the
question of like what's the you know
what you think is the biggest problem in
that what's the model smart city in the
world right now
like Wesley if you if someone says like
that is the best that's the most
advanced smart city at the moment yeah I
can tell you it's not San Francisco
where I live it's like the most backward
class moment they see the most advancing
probably to buy and Singapore as well in
Europe I don't know much Barcelona okay
Italian oh yeah San Francisco definitely
okay right okay great this is a lot Oh
also of marketing behind the Smart City
concept because many many cities are
saying okay we are the smartest city in
the world but when you go there
technology body's not like so what makes
blue makes Dubai and Barcelona are so
advanced then what what's the technology
taking the lead
thinking about okay I mean part of part
of it is that you have to think of a
smart city as a as an ecosystem where
you think of it as like a body where if
you were to design a body and say now I
want to connect all these pieces so
there's a living breathing organism
that's what you're essentially building
with a smart city so you know imagine
where you know again I know this is
simplistic but the roads are arteries
and so on and now you want to create a
better flow you know today the roads are
terrible in a lot of cities traffic you
know clogs up and Dubai and I live in Oh
and Dubai there's a lot of traffic at
different times day you know with
self-driving vehicles and with the
sensor grid and so on
you know the idea would be that it's a
self-healing environment over time I
mean this is going to take time but it's
the orchestration of the sensors and the
signaling and then the vehicles that
ultimately lead to better outcome and
there's a lot of modeling done around it
and so on and then it's obviously
orchestration of greater systems that
you know then into relate to one another
so you know where the power system and
the you know law enforcement system for
example and healthcare systems and so on
or all have interrelationships and as
you can imagine as you start creating
more and more of those ecosystem based
relationships the idea of a total system
failure you know can be really
problematic as any of you have seen die
hard for or any of these kinds of movies
you know these kinds of problems exist
particularly where the underpinnings are
hardware and software IOT based
environments that you know have 1990
zero vulnerabilities and so on so I was
going to say so I'm assuming this is
like the city of the future I'm
imagining in my head right the Jetsons
like riding on this thing I imagine this
is built on the latest and greatest
right correct assumption well you know
it may very well be the technology that
came out yesterday but as many of you
know that you know do research it's the
technology that came out yesterday that
has the 1990 zerah web server built into
it with you know the same
vulnerabilities that we patched 20 years
ago that are unpatched or on updatable
hardware you know unobtainable software
you know lots of these types of problems
and so part of the things that many of
us are working on is you know how do we
create systems and systems how do we
create ultimate owners so we're the way
Tesla has create you know taking
ownership of the systems in the vehicle
and so there's lots to discuss this area
ok so if you had to so you're sitting
with a newbie like me what is the single
most
saying about security and a small city
today I think one of the main problems
is that the attack surface is growing
every day and why is that because
governments are purchasing new
technology and deploying it without any
security testing they are blindly
trusting develop a vendor say we
implement encryption we have
authentication bla bla bla government
basically then they trust them acquire
technology deploy me deploy it start to
using it there is no security testing on
any stage they do a lot of testing for
functionality they compare providers
vendor solutions to see what it fit
better but there is no security testing
what I hear is that sometime they use
questionary where they ask the vendors
if they have enough security vendor will
have to take yes or no but it doesn't
matter what the windows say because no
one will test that before that after
that then I hear that some cities are
partners have partnership with
universities show the system the devices
but that doesn't scale and also the work
is being done by students or PhD
candidate whatever and they don't have
any real life experience cut sometimes
it doesn't it's a way because we have a
lot of new technology coming out every
every weekend it's difficult to keep up
with everything so that's I think that's
the main problem - how to find a way
every time a government is going to
acquire new technology to make sure that
the technology is secure and ready to be
deployed and won't be hard next there
okay material encryption one of the
problem that in my experience is very
important at least in Italy is that
since the government is not replacing
existing technology and since X the
existing technology maybe be like 40
years old or 50 years old for example we
used as a as an example a train station
or the railway or the three three
traffic
so they buy new technology and one of
the requirement for these technologies
that the technology must be retro
compatible with the existing sense or
the existing system in place so that
means that you have to be in somehow
some way vulnerable to problems that we
may have solved like he said like 20
years ago 30 years ago because they have
to take in account sensor that is still
vulnerable to the same problems but
until now those sensor doors actuators
law system we're offline were not
connected the cloud system of the city
were not interconnected to other
ecosystem of the city for example the
traffic sensor was on his own now the
traffic sensor are connected to the
police station or the traffic sensor are
connecting to the medical station so
their ambulance can find a better way to
go to the hospital so since now all the
sensor must be connecting one another
they also have problems that are
available to exploit from other systems
so maybe an attacker can act the medical
system and therefore access to the
traffic system and therefore access to
the police system and so on and so on
and so on and as Cesar said these things
is growing up everyday so it's very
difficult now to understand if I act
from one of the system where I can reach
where I where there is something that
can stop me so that's another problem
that we face in it so so you raised a
really good point I mean you know
there's a number of dimensions to this
let's just take for example the just
understanding the potential resilience
of a smart city you know you've got a
first of all look at the entities that
are involved in this if you look at it
at any city right there their intent is
good right I mean they want to low in
lower carbon emissions lower the the
cost lower the tax burden you know these
are all good initiatives right but but
you know there's a lot of entities that
have never really worked together in
terms of orchestrating you know the
different you know inter dependency so
you have to profile the entities you
have to profile where they are from a
technology perspective you have to
profile the services
that each entity is bringing to the
table and where those services are from
a contributory perspective what data are
they contributing what networking
they're contributing and so on then you
have to model that you know and just in
that work there's a lot of complexity
that many of us in cyber really have
never dealt with you know you know just
in terms of understanding that and then
if you think about it in terms of impact
let's just take the power grid as an
example so suppose the power grid had a
reduced capacity because of some cyber
event so you know suppose half of the
power generating capacity went out now
you think of all these interdependencies
where you have the ability normally to
supply power to a hospital to the
financial services organizations to
those that do you know cleaning water
for you know place like the UAE and so
on how do you apportion power in that
situation well you might say oh well you
know we'll give it to the hospital first
well the hospital might have a generator
that would run for two weeks so you
don't have to give it to them and so
there's a lot of thinking that has to go
into this it's not a one-to-one
relationship it's a many-to-many
relationship and each entity in each
service has a many-to-many into
dependency that's complex and then when
you start adding threat modeling to that
and attack scenarios where you don't
really have 100 year data you have to do
a lot of math that is you know how that
has randomness in it you know Monte
Carlo simulation stochastic approaches
so there's a lot in that we as security
people have never really looked at and
that's just that on the side of just
trying to figure out what this could
look at it we haven't even talked about
some of the stuff that that is done on
well you know what you do for example it
says so on the side of testing for
vulnerabilities at all so you you kind
of maybe think about privacy right so
imagine this huge privacy implications
of this so I'm thinking about the the
horrible attacks that happened in
Barcelona last week I was in Barcelona
we're walking down that Street three
weeks ago and it took several days to
figure out where that van had gone after
the event now if that had been in London
there
cameras absolutely everywhere and within
30 minutes they would have figured out
exactly where that van went there's
clear privacy implications between those
two things and who has access to that
data in the right way but if I'm
understanding correctly in a smart city
you know exactly where someone's gone
you know exactly where they are there's
a whole set of privacy things how do
people think about that in the context
of a smart city yeah I think it's always
like cost-benefit equation people have
to to give some privacy away to be more
secure right because you have cameras on
the street that help to for you know for
traffic help to prevent crime
but okay people will know that you will
walk in at soma Street at some time I
cannot set that so I think it would take
some time to people to understand and
and also not be extremist about privacy
because there is some movement around
okay I need a hundred percent privacy
but that's not even possible
understand that they have to to give
away a little bit privacy to have a
better life to be more secure in general
and that's our discussion that had to be
that should take place sometimes and
have to be some regulation and so law
relating without because also there is
the possibility to abuse by the ones
that are in charge of technology because
you could have an operation so yeah an
operator the hobbitses to the system can
see the cameras can read the sensors can
see a lot of information that that
information should be protected but it
should be only used for the intended use
for something else and I think right now
there is little contra about what
governments or cities are allowed to do
or not with that information right right
but if you if an individual participates
in a smart city the choice of whether
they use or whether they give up their
privacy if they get to choose that the
whole the whole concept fails right
doesn't it so like it's an on a
non-issue isn't it in a sense like like
like like once that data
they're like if I'm if I'm trapped on
the metro and someone knows where I am
someone is who sold me the card at that
point like you can't have a optional
optional opt into that thing what you
can cut up online right you can decide
to opt in the tracking and all of these
things but that system kind of fails
doesn't well I think that that's one of
the main issue and why that means that
security must take in account because I
can I don't obtain for this privacy
regulation I mean I live in the city I
automatically obtain so that means that
I in exchange I want to be sure that
information that I'm giving away or
somehow protected and I feel like we
must to speak to to InfoSec people so
they are by default by definition
susceptible to privacy issue but when
you speak to normal people anyway when
you speak with the people outside the
InfoSec community we give away our
privacy every day I mean I use Gmail for
for emailing and it automatically adds
me like my travel information in a
proper manner so it's very easy for me
to to get this information that means
that gmail is reading my mail parsing it
and adding in some database with my
travel information the same happens with
appointment or the automatic reply
function of gmail opt you made the
example of the security for for
Barcelona right but there are much more
common example in terms of usability and
making the life of the people easier or
more more yeah I think it's just one
comment on this I mean I think that you
know if privacy any thinking about
privacy today is just an illusion and a
lack of understanding of technology I
mean we in security because of our
knowledge have the ability to create a
certain measure of privacy because of
what we understand how to do but in
general it's it's it's an illusory thing
to think that we even have any as
general people living in the world
just based on what's out there I mean
there's all of this fictitious viewpoint
of you know it's it's sort of created
for us by opt in or out but I mean to
your point there's that say if you want
to read a book that is still relevant
today is written in the 1990s it's a
book called the transparent society I
know if any of you have ever read it
it's by a guy named David brand can
actually download it on PDF off of one
of the Harvard websites I think and he
wrote this idea that you know this is
trade-off between you know would you
like to live in a world where there's a
hundred percent surveillance but there's
you know everything is a perfect
electronic society and you have all of
the benefits of zero crime and
everything but you're basically exposed
and you're naked you know from a
surveillance perspective or would you
like a complete opt-in type of world
where you you you choose every point at
which your privacy is given away but
then you don't have all of the benefits
of modern technology and of course there
is no you know binary decision in this
as you all know but it's an interesting
read and it was written in the 90s and
it's as applicable today it was my
observation is I think the people that
are growing up today have no expectation
of privacy and it's fundamentally
different so I used to work on Microsoft
and we used to have a set of MIT grants
that would come in every year and I was
a good a product unit manager so I kind
of ran up as this function and these
these folks would come in and these MIT
grads and you get to ask them questions
and a lot of the older people would ask
them questions around like you know what
can we do and one the the kind of
stunning response from all of these
people was you should use all of our
code to do as much and make my life as
best as possible and although these
people are like shuffling like free me
really uncomfortable we can't do that we
can't do that I would tell you I want to
use your information and I think there's
this fundamental like difference between
the the notion of like growing up and
having an expectation of privacy and
accepting all of these services that
aren't but it feels like if you want to
participate in the smart city stuff you
have to give that up and it's not an
option interesting oh yeah I should I
should call out as a guy down here in
the audience who works for me who has an
interesting thing about
obviously he's gonna get really
embarrassed now but it's quite funny so
he he is the most privacy aware person
that I've ever met here he is like he's
like he's sticking his hand up so he
when I foot when we first they were
working together we got on a business
trip and he goes through the scanning
and he won't get scanned I'm like dude
like come on we started talking about
this and it turns out his house is
completely wired but every night he
pulls the USB connectors out he pulls
everything out of the house and then one
day I go into work and I find that he's
gonna lexer and it's like and it's but
it's this trade-off between like
functionality and once you get that
stuff everything else gets thrown out
the window right I mean that the Alexa
was it connected to the Internet so
every time he said Alexa what time is it
Alexa said I don't know yeah no his was
because I asked the question right yeah
yeah all right so so fundamentally
technology pieces that are involved in
this so it sounds like driverless cars
like autonomous vehicles is a is a big
thing right now it imagine autonomous
logistics in general right like all the
stuff that we're we're hearing about
that's happening whether it's Hyperloop
stuff and like you know city to city
transportation or things who are the
players that are int that are in the
space I'm imagining like uber Tesla like
all of these are the big electric for
example should I record a let's shader
electric okay you know for example they
make traffic lights and control system
signaling devices so you know their goal
is to tie all the signals together and
make systems of systems out of that and
link them to systems that turn off all
of the street lights you know when no
cars are going through all the street
lights go out for a while you know
saving power for you know or talk to us
to vehicles and and traffic patterns and
redirect traffic things like that okay
so any geopolitical kind of concerns
around this I know you tell me that's an
interesting question because related
with what I say before because when if
you're a government acquired technology
um you don't really know what's inside
the hardware for it so you don't know
what's the embedded software is doing
you know
that we will capture the data and send
it to some place in Russia China or the
u.s. so that's a very interesting point
when you think about geopolitics and see
ok these technology I'm using which is
from a country which is maybe not very
friendly or is well-known for spying or
whatever then you need a Sakura in
protecting your citizen sheep and the
country you need to know what software
are you running in your cities and
that's something that no one knows right
now it's like you practically buy black
boxes you connect them and you use it
and that's one of the problem that I I
spoke before that there is no actual
that controls all the different elements
in a smart city like like Eddie made
example of the body so at the moment our
Smurfs et have no brain and as well as a
lot of little grains one for each
elements but there is no central brain
that can control everything and can put
in for for putting in our computer
engineering perspective we should have
like a proxy or something let know how
this system works and how they
communicate to each other and and can
put them in communication at the moment
we have like a dozen of vendors a
doesn't know who I am that try to sell
their product smart city buy the
products deploy them and forgot about
that so and then next year they buy the
new product again and that's over over
over so yeah and I think to the to the
point that says I was making a Mateo as
well you know the models that that exist
today for testing and validation in
general you know for example Common
Criteria other models like that really
are not helping us because you know
they're based on the idea that somehow
you know for example for smart cities
there's going to be a protection profile
that is somehow applicable to you know
the kind of vulnerabilities that we're
gonna find in some box that you know
we've never seen before that's out there
and
you know we're magically two years from
now I'm going to have a report that says
this is okay you know so it really does
require our community you know security
researchers you know like those of us up
here like yourselves to take these
things cut them down to bare metal you
know pull the chips out of them you know
look at the code and really say how do
we find the vulnerabilities in these
things that really haven't been seen so
you know intentional unintentional
backdoors bugs bad implementation of
crypto I mean you know to your point
earlier you know somebody does an RFP
they say you know do you have a es
encryption in the box yes you know the
real question is is it done at all in
any semblance of correct implementation
you know do you have authentication yes
well you know is it a four character
password yes okay well you know so I
mean there's a lot of things that really
through you know more aggressive testing
and validation that can be brought out
and obviously that's not a perfect
process either but it's a lot better
than sort of these these things that
we've seen that are generally accepted
in our industry unfortunately yeah and
speaking about that well last year we
spoke about I was talked about in ug SEC
about the transportation system asking
that that we did in the past so one of
the thing that we want to brought in the
thought was how our methodology to
assess the system for the exact same
reason but during the last year what
we've found that is that this
methodology is very good if you want to
test a single system but the point in a
smart city is that you are not assessing
a single system usually so we also need
a methodology to understand not only e
thread on that system but the thread on
the other systems so even if I take
apart is smart traffic sensor that can
turn off or on the traffic light and the
base of the vehicle that passing under
it I still don't understand how the rest
of the system works because the rest of
it
system first of all maybe located
somewhere else their back end can be
Germany can mean Russia can be wherever
the lava Center is cheaper and secondly
I'm assessing one of the system that is
connecting to three or four other system
and I know nothing about them so even if
I act this there may be repercussion on
the other system as well so I think that
as technical guy I'm not on high level I
won't take decision about the government
stuff and all this I am more a technical
guy so as a technical guy what we need
to do is try to understand what is the
best methodology try to assess the
system efficiently because we cannot
span like one bomb for each device and
try to a can expect that the industry
will follow our time they will publish
new devices they will ship new sensor
they will ship new products without the
security in the industry in mind so we
need a more efficient way to do that and
we need to have a proper communication
with the Schism maker so we go to the so
anyone is anyone in the audience got a
got a question there's no many people
drinking beer which is my question is
like why is that the case
but anyway anyone got any questions
because if not I'm going to ask anyone
no one's got any questions at this point
okay so Eddie imagine you and now evil
Eddie all right that's a hash tag right
there someone's put that on Twitter hey
Eddie has just become evil Eddie what is
the worst thing that you would do to a
city so evil Eddie sudden he says great
I'm gonna I'm gonna do something bad to
Singapore what does it look like what
would you what would you do and what
would the outcome be well you know again
I think the the issue really is about
the interdependence you know even though
we've called out certain cities as
leading relative to the smart
environment I don't think that they're
so leading that there's this
catastrophic interdependence yet that
you know that could be in the future but
you know having said that you know I
think Matteo brings up both a good and a
bad sort of specter you know in the
Specter is that that ultimately in some
areas you do need a system of systems to
manage you know certain aspects of a
smart environment and just like a lot of
these you know command and control
environments the concentration of you
know that level of control is a very
attractive environment for someone to go
after because obviously you know that
level of control if it's not done
properly could give you the keys to the
kingdom so if you know if I were to look
at something like that you know I would
look at as you said you know the the
little brains that control these
different environments or if there was a
big brain you know I and I had a lot of
time on my hands you know to to
basically own it and to just keep that
ownership and keep it quietly until I
was ready to use it I mean that would be
you know an interesting objective
alright so in practical terms what would
you do go after transportation first go
after utilities go after healthcare go
well it depends on your objective
I mean adversaries have different
objectives you know I mean you know
whether you want to create mass panic
and riots and you know just chaos and
pandemonium or whether you want to you
know for example create you know
financial turmoil in some way so it
really depends you know because cyber
terrorists and activists and criminals
and others are going to have different
objectives so I think it really just
depends on and who's pulling the strings
all right say so I can't think of assisi
at the moment but I'll think of one in a
minute malware Matteo we could have but
but I can't think of a C but anyway all
right good what would you do well I I
can't think of city as making an analogy
with a human body yes you have you know
the system so we try to to to hug those
places like for instance for the for the
vision you can attack camera city
cameras you can attack sensors then from
the blood stream from the nervous system
you cannot attack the traffic control
system the street lighting system
curry you can go for the power grid and
you can hit a lot of more different
things but usually that's something more
more protected more with more safe words
but thinking about in that way you can
just try to have different impact on the
city depending on the attack he said if
you can cause a riot panic maybe you
will just shoot down electricity on
other robberies of the city so there
would be a lot of fryer probably people
without beer and drink well in San
Francisco every couple of years the the
pathway we get so much air-conditioning
gets turned on the power grids go out
sweeping anyway and there's no riots but
yeah I understand they think if you have
a lot of different possibilities like he
said there is a lot of different
interaction a lot of dependences on the
system so you can create chain reaction
by maybe hot in a small city it end up
being a big impact because ordering the
relation between the system so even for
for a tap here is interesting to see how
the system what will happen if you have
one system how that will influence
another one so it's a he says very
complex and different a scenario that we
have that we see usually on corporations
or or regular organizations right ok
great so Matteo healthcare
so imagine hospitals and pandemics we've
seen bird flu in the in the u.s. so
spread across the world and we saw
people track it what is if that happened
how would we in a smart city world what
are the security implications of
something like that if a pandemic kicks
in how could it how could either a smart
city be great or how could it be abused
by someone who wants to see something
like chemical warfare or pathogens
spread in a particular way like what
would they do is there a particular you
know are we now storing more data like
Microsoft have health fault right which
is basically sort of potentially storing
all sorts of interesting information
about people in Beijing we have the
Beijing genomics Institute 90% of the
world
DNA right these are these are very
significant data stores of human
healthcare stuff but how it has that
related to smart cities yeah at the
moment I don't know okay but in the
future probably this data will be
available to hospitals or for example to
these services that I spoke before like
Google or whatever and so they imagine a
Google that can tell you okay you are
searching for these symptoms you
probably have these disease or something
like that this is something that we
couldn't do in the past because we
didn't have the computational power but
now we do now we also starting to
getting more and more data as you made
an example insist I think like another
another system all of this stock will be
automated in the future so I'm going
back to the question of you before so
what system I would attack in the case
of I want to be the evil actor on Mercy
deaq so since i had time to think about
the question my answer is media probably
because i don't know some years ago i
think i don't remember the exact year
someone act some online journal and
spread the false notice about some
political issue in in less than 15
minutes the stock market's drop by like
ii like 50 percent because all the
system that are actually taking care of
these are algorithms algorithm read the
journal information and acts accordingly
so that means that probably acting on
the media or the
data sources that spread most of the
information so also social networks and
stuff like this if i can spread the kind
of information that I want on this on
this media I can probably trigger the
most of the system in a future of in the
smart city of the future so most of the
system will take care of this also let's
see the example of before we D let's
take another example let's take Google
Google Maps use information from Android
phones
people using Google Maps to track
traffic right so if I can fake this kind
of data sources I can affect how people
use Google Maps like from normal people
to drivers to yubi drivers anyone
probably also like we did some research
in the past against the smart carriage
system so that basically they are sensor
that detects if a garbage bin is full
and they are automatically cause the the
truck to take and all of these use
Google Maps API and that's another
example of what I said before so that
our smart city will integrate third
party system so yeah probably source of
information for the for the whole
ecosystem ok good so we must now now
surely the audience a third of a great
question if not alex is gonna have a
great question because he's been put on
the spot come on
someone must have a great question yeah
just throw that throw the microphone in
his face and he has no choice right well
done instead yeah naturally I yeah want
to think of cities I think about it's
more than a big organic distributed
system and I question if it's even
possible to secure it because if the
nature of the organic distributed
systems were multiple devices just join
the network or D join the network and
it's almost impossible to control of
these right so instead of controlling
the you know trans control the actual
devices like is it better to have active
system that can monitor and police in
take actions so active controls for
example so I don't know what you guys
think about that but that's that's kind
of how I think about it so to restate
the question there's a there's two
models one is you can figure out how to
try and secure it internally or the
other one is you can trust but verify
Martin or monitor but verify is that
correct
isn't that the same thing I don't know I
mean look you know we pretty much fail
at everything you know from
perspectives so I mean I think there has
to be a measure of both right I think
you have to set up some objectives from
a security perspective and then monitor
the shit out of it you know so yes both
a German person privacy come on yes
[Applause]
[Music]
Turkey she's gonna get political very
quickly so if you don't follow the world
stage
Derwin recently accused Angela Merkel of
being evil all right come on let's get
the question hey I live in America I
have to do a Donald Trump your problems
your problems are nothing compared to
mine trust me
and you're from UK okay I know I don't
live where we have a clown for a
president what can I say anyway oh I
guess it's being live-streamed I'm sorry
the problem is when the clone goes on a
witch hunt Wow yes anyway yes okay so
what's the question
what is it yeah doing a witch hunt and
smart city or a smart nation easy target
because so much about you he wants to
take that I have no idea how I would
possibly answer that personal question
quick yes so let me I'll try and
summarize it and say so
Germans obviously a very privacy aware
and very privacy conscious and how would
you say well how would you talk to a
German citizen when you have potential
rogue nations such as Turkey for
instance and now got a beef against
Germany and there's there now you know
potential a lot of data and a lot of
things that could be attacked against
the German German people so
my first answer is a question I mean
what do you mean with going wrong
I mean look row row yeah sorry what do
you mean yeah I mean half of citizens
investigation yeah most of the press is
getting what to be fair and it would be
fair and impartial
I don't think half of the Turkish
population around the terroristic issues
fit just so no well I think that well I
don't live in Turkey so I don't know
about the turkey situation but from a
perspective of a Italian guy that has
not this big issue I say that at the
moment most of the modern country are
not looking to harm citizen I mean they
probably want to control them but the
final aim of a liberal country is to
provide welfare to the to the people so
actually I I don't know what once your
question because I don't see a scenario
in the modern countries in which the
government should use this information
to go against the normal people against
the the people that go to office every
day and beside controlling them to
provide them more welfare I mean so
there is not so I think this area was
it's not necessary the German government
are gonna use that data against them but
it may be Pyongyang are gonna suddenly
decide that the journey that there's a
huge population a huge Bank of
information that's war that's very
naughty so the question is not how did
the government no but it's nasty right
but once you have a data bank of
information conferring governments then
use that in a geopolitical situation I
think that's I think I think we're a bit
off-track but just just to be clear I
mean if any of you are on the internet
and you see advertising Google Facebook
etc have a lot more information than
anyone else has I mean the government's
wish they had the information that the
walled gardens have so
and that's why the government gonna use
those providers for information they
want it but I'm just saying I mean so
that's really where the data is I sure
wish I has this as a cyber Intel analyst
sometimes had access to that information
good boy there's some great stuff there
is that it strategically is that why
Google are playing in the autonomous
vehicle space like they're investing I
don't know I don't work at Google but
yeah okay so so yeah you're smirking
into your be right and I like they must
be they must have that they must have
some like oh like logistics is clearly
very important right and logistics of
vehicles is one thing but logistics of
things like shipping and all of these
other things is also very important
right so how do they play in that world
like Google have a huge amount of data
other companies have a huge amount of
data like what's their what's their role
in this smart city future I don't want
to speak about Google because I again I
don't work for Google but no I mean you
know that's a you can speak about them
if you want to talk about them one way
or another I mean the but you mentioned
machine-to-machine communications and
that is a big part of smart city I mean
certainly the idea that you know we can
track chain of custody of goods and we
can track it moving through the city and
have a better idea of what's moving
through the city and when and so on
based on integration of different
technologies some of them have been
around for a long time some of them are
emerging it becomes particularly
interesting when you start putting it on
the blockchain because as you know as we
see blockchain emerging as the fifth
wave of technology and we see the
integration of logistics systems into
the blockchain and integration of
blockchain into this I do see benefits
relative to non-repudiation of supply
chain events obviously we have to solve
the the PKI issue that currently exists
there you know in a post quantum world
but having said that you know there are
some interesting applications so explain
that to me cuz I'm the dumb the dumb guy
the blockchain how does that affect will
adjust
you know the idea of a non reputable
ledger for supply chain management and
as you're moving Goods through you know
from port or from you know origin
manufacturer of origin to final
destination let's say in the city the
idea that you can have a non-repudiation
of custody is very very interesting from
the the moment that it that something is
created in a factory to the moment it's
received by somebody and you know think
of that on a much larger scale you know
and and that same registry could could
serve a lot of different purposes in a
smart city environment but you know
there's a lot of cryptographic
principals and other problems that need
to be resolved in blockchain before we
can you know think of that you know that
level of application deployment on top
of the various the systems that we have
today and that gave me a privacy sure
alright I have another question yep I so
where are you from where am i from
yeah from the US ok good I hope you
didn't vote for Donald Trump but apart
from that good you did vote for Donald
Trump you didn't deny it did you shame
on you
anyway ok carry on I am taking this
vacation as an opportunity to step away
from political realm
well I'm deeply immersed in it well god
yeah thank you for helping save the
world so thank you for trying to drag me
back home just there
so I was hoping you could maybe provide
some context and insight around how much
municipal groups and the people who
would be purchasing to develop smart
cities are aware of security issues and
how much the security of these systems
enters the equation when they're
selecting vendors selecting products
that they're gonna bring it to their
environment is this something that it
gets discussed is is there awareness
from from the municipal purchasing side
and I guess to wrap up are there any
like it's positive examples that you've
seen you could you could highlight yeah
that's a great question I was actually I
was I changed in that when it's almost
when you when you guys are talking
earlier I was thinking about when you
sell to the US government
FIPS 140 you have to make sure that your
devices are compliant and there's a
whole set of things is there any kind of
like the follow-on question to that is
there any work around defining what
those standards are and making sure
people you know it here to them vendors
it hit yeah so so in working with with
municipal groups and smart city city
organizations is their awareness of
security to the point where it enters
the conversation when they're selecting
vendors and making purchasing decisions
is is it almond saying actually no I
don't think so usually because
government don't understand security I
mean the people in charge of security
are not the one picking decision or
selecting the vendors so it's basically
sometimes a lot related with politics
with a pro-bender so who is they want to
purchase for because of what you know it
depends on the country on my country
there is a lot of corruption so you buy
the one which money back to you as a
politician but in other places is
basically they have a list of vendors
and they do functionality testing they
say okay this work better is cheaper
less buy this and that's it that is I
haven't seen
anyone worried about security of if they
worry about security they will never say
yeah yeah we are we are secure and
that's it there is no no way to enforce
the vendor for for being compliance with
some security basic I haven't seen that
yet I think that rise another question
that may be more important is who is the
who is liable if some accident happens I
mean if the government buy some
equipment it is insecure and some
attacks happens and we see are addictive
people who die who is liable for for
this disease action I mean there should
be some regulation that can prevent or
at least identify the liable actor in in
this situation and I at the moment I
think there is no so that's one of the I
have no answer about this but that's one
of the question that when we realize
that we can speak with people that make
the seizure we usually ask them and they
don't know so to your question in Dubai
for example the smart divided government
actually is thinking about the
underpinnings relative to security so
the you know they they understand that
there's some building blocks needed to
you know as enablers for that you know
like I mentioned blockchain there's an
initiative to blockchain certain
government services by 2020 there's a
initiatives around PKI post quantum
crypto so and that's been publicly
announced and and so on and there's
public tenders in these areas so you
have to have these building blocks in
place if you want to then build you know
the ecosystem that we're talking about
in the US there are smart city councils
that are starting to get groups of
municipalities together to talk about
how to do different aspects of Smart
City and there is a security dimension
in the smart city councils in the US
because I was on the board of aisaka and
we got involved in that now
how mature is that today it's not that
mature but at least they're talking to
each other and at least there's the
notion that okay there's all these
vendors that want to participate and
there's municipalities that are not very
mature in terms of their procurement
process but they want to do it and
hopefully you know they'll come together
and they'll get the right advisors and
something that'll come out the other end
of it but you know as as usual the first
the first people to the table are
probably going to learn the lessons the
hard way so something interesting to
consider is that you know for a smart
city there is government behind there is
many things related specifically to
government you don't see own companies
and what I known also with politics one
thing it's important to high mind is
that security is invisible for politics
that doesn't add much value because you
can say okay I will spend a hundred
million dollars securing or the city in
practice or people won't see that they
won't get more votes for the politicians
it's different I say okay we are
spending a hundred million dollars
building a new bridge so you will get
back from work to come very quickly we
will take more time with your family you
will be happier people say oh yes that's
not this bulb for this guy the next
round so that's something concrete and
visible but Security's invisible so I
think that until there aren't we'll say
regular attacks on cities related with
the technology they use mostly there
won't be much investment on the security
area unless there are some places like
Dubai procedure politics doesn't work
that way because they are ruled in
different way but in general when you
think about politics and how invisible
securities until we don't see much
attacks think about change I think
Hillary Clinton and her email server may
disagree with you about politics yeah
observe observation I guess and maybe
just trying to summarize it feels like
these purchasing decisions around smart
cities are made by regional government
and I think you know my experience of
that has been central government
generally has a sophisticated approach
to security and regional government and
non sophisticated approaches that a is
that an oversimplification of things so
we are we basically kind of the the
smart city is put into our regional
context and that's part of the problem
or not no response or area like like if
my experience of government has been
around the world in general and an
overgeneralization is that central
governments are very sophisticated
around security in general right they're
all running intelligence agencies
they're running very large pieces of
data but generally regional governments
are less sophisticated and that's just
the nature of thought what they'd what
they're doing it sounds like the
distributed nature of smart city to
security decisions are being made on a
regional basis is that part of the
problem so if this thing was started to
become centralized and started to become
regulated the we may see an increased
security or not I don't know that that's
true
actually I mean I look at large cities
would that have a large tax base like
London or New York and so on they
certainly have the muscle to do this if
they want to say there's a point you
know does it doesn't give you outs and
you know it doesn't Mayor may not create
jobs that are visible so you know it
doesn't keep the trains on the tracks so
you know I think I think there are a lot
of factors that come into these
decisions and it's also possible for a
medium-sized city that is very very
well-run that has a decent tax base to
do a good job with this
with the right advisory so I don't think
there's that correlation that you're
stating okay good we got a few minutes
left we got another question she
answered with what I'm trying to do is
like make a suggestion because I'm
coming from the country where the first
world is always our role
though so what you guys doing in Germany
and USA UK is like what we're looking
right now is the good model that we can
employ man copy or whatever like
choosing the right vendor or whether
like security past it we can do to to
have everything properly and stuff like
that and I don't know probably is like
mark you personally done great with all
odds negative days then probably you can
do the same thing with the smart city
and making some new standard now how the
security testing for the smart city
solution and stop at it I don't know 80c
SAR what about so I think you discuss I
think Jim Maggiore where Jim is saying
is is someone gonna take the charge and
expose or or a champion what the problem
is and figure out how to create
standards around this so who's who's
leading who's leading that charge and
who should you attached we are doing
some effort with cities initiative we're
after identifying all these issues and
problems I thought okay we I should do
something about this not only
complaining and pointing out the
problems that try to find solutions and
right enough or something so I talked to
people friends and companies and there
was a lot of interested people and we
started to work on that so we have
created the guidelines we are publishing
papers because something to you know
about is that there are much resources
related specifically to cyber security
in smart cities the resin you can find
cybersecurity about any topic but for a
small cities amount of information so
one thing we are doing is creating that
information making easy to understand
for chanel public not only for technical
people only for decision-makers for
government people that can take you know
a five page paper and understand the
problem and trying to do something about
that we are a few people we are trying
to do something we haven't done much but
we are working on that I said where
would people go to find out that
information security
Maur cities are and there are a lot of
useful papers there we have companies
and researchers collaborating and once
in a while we release a paper some
research that is very interesting
because like I said we try to focus on
practical and simple things that can be
understood by anyone I don't know if I
can say that but we are also working on
a training right right now there is a
project incited initiative for training
like high-level people on these issues I
mean the training may be divided but
there is also part for eye level people
to understand better the issue and
actually the initiative last year in Def
Con we also got some some response from
government people that were present some
people from the government that like ask
question and try to take I don't know if
they try to say in constant later but at
least they participate during the talk
over last year yeah right also having
this panel you know helps to yeah to to
Sherry there's two IDs and to to bring
the the problems to the table trying to
find solutions I mean we are at every
stage but we should doing something
right now because when in a few years
when there will be really smart cities
you know a lot of Technology in deploy
everything integrated any cyber attack
if the technology is not secure there
will be a huge impact on how we live and
how it will affect our lives great so we
are at the end any other burning
questions from the audience I don't see
anyone oh we have one more here great
where where are you from and what's your
question I'm from Singapore excellent
you didn't vote for Donald Trump I did
well what did this
well done here as you asked so I'm just
curious
smart nation smash city all talks about
government I see four guys up there not
from government so maybe we'll miss
important element in the discussion
certain drop we asked about having
government people from Singapore and I
don't know what was the reaction I think
the along we'll know but we asked couple
months ago to participate it is in his
room table to Singapore government
usually people from government don't
want to to talk on the record well I
think I heard you just now that you say
that deployed don't know much that's why
they don't have any much to say but they
have the power to put on regulations to
enforce putting money on this
so maybe I'm just wondering what is the
top three things on your list that you
want the government to do yeah so just
to be clear I certainly didn't say that
government people don't know much the
government people I work with no alive
another one and I've been I've had 20
plus years involved with the government
and my current job involves a lot of
government people so you know I've
worked for a long long time as a
government contractor so I think the way
I would I would think about it is that
you know while you know and I know my
colleagues have as well you know well
certainly we're not government
executives having worked so closely with
the government for so many years of my
career I certainly have a perspective on
the way the government thinks now you
know having a government rep up here to
tell you what you know what regulations
are thinking about and how they view
procurements and how they view the
vendor landscape I agree is a lot of
different perspective than hearing
vendors speak about it but I'll tell you
that you know my life is daily
interaction with city officials federal
officials and so on
listening them talk about their vision
listening to them talk about how they
view this space the things that keep
them up at night the dreams they have
about making you know people's lives
better so you know I don't think you're
getting a skewed perspective because
we're not here selling you anything as
much as trying to tell you that that you
know we're reflecting the viewpoints of
the people that we we talked to in our
daily lives you know so it's not it's
not that far off you know you're gonna
hear a different version if we were the
actual government
yes I will be government to it and they
actually know so maybe it's so maybe
it's a great way to kind of and Oishi
so the question was three things but
we're not gonna get three things from
everyone but if you get one wish that
you could ask every government around
the world whether it's testing
regulation driving standards into
benders whatever whatever that thing is
you each get one wish what is it and
we'll start with you at the end Eddie
and we'll work backwards you know I
think that my one wish would be you know
what I'm seeing a lot of in Dubai you
know I see that across a lot of
municipalities which you know which
would be to think about the the plumbing
first you know we a lot of times you
know and this is not a bad thing it's
just what's happened and it's fine but
you know we rushed to all the cool stuff
first and it's like oh you security guys
come in you security men and women come
in and fix all this stuff for us and you
know I think what we're seeing with a
lot of this is the healthy fear of what
could happen if it's not done right and
a lot of it involves good plumbing and
I'd like to see the plumbing done right
that would be my wish okay great say
that from me I think first thing to do
is education because people know need to
understand they need to know first what
is security about what it's important to
to have security because if they don't
know about it they won't do anything so
I think education is the main thing
people should be educated officials at
the government different level from
technical to high level people they need
to understand that now we depend a lot
of Technology and we need to protect
because if we don't protect it and we
won't be able to have a regular life
like we have today and these technology
dependence keep growing every day so
every day security protecting this
technology become it's also most more
important so they need to learn that the
need to understand that I'm from there I
think they will understand that they
have to do something about it great
so plumbing education and awareness yeah
you can summarize all of this with the
interaction and involvement with the
security community community and and
security researcher I think that's you
teammate answer to let them understand
the problem and try to anticipate bad
things great
so fantastic it sounds like your
resource is a brilliant resource for
people to start with so can you just
repeat that so I know this is being
streamed so what is the URL of that
securing a smaller cities or there is a
lot of information there papers
guidelines and there is a email there
you can use to contact us if you want to
join and collaborate you're welcome
great we may put a link in the YouTube
video description there's something
possible down there down there I think
is what you say with YouTube right
though down there if you need to call it
great gentlemen thank you very much
indeed it was a great inauguration for
the pub right
all right thank you thank you very much
[Applause]