okay next up we have Matthew lucky from
kada hi this is what I've done well what
has been going on for the round about
eight or ten years now educator and what
I'm talking about has been going on the
work that I've done over the past sort
of year this work that I've done with
bread and mogan Casey okay no okay so
what this talk is is about a project
called is Frank which is available on
the internet or no results through I've
everyone into ice rink catered at all
and what this project is is at first we
infer is relationships going down the
same road that number of other
researchers have gone down over the
years of using publicly available bgp
paths so what we what we do is we
download rubs from reviews and resin
there's approximately 400 aess providing
views to wrap use and resin about a
theater than were providing full views
and with the is relationship inferences
we make custom provider peer-to-peer we
then try and fear the influence of
individual is is based on the size of
their customer comb and the way to think
about the customer cone as an operator
is that a traffic that arise from a
customer and then is transmitted to our
customer so essentially the fraction of
traffic that makes you the most money
because you've been paid twice for it on
net traffic so an overview of this talk
I'm briefly going to talk about some
objectives of of the work and then most
of this talk is a methodology about how
we go about it in order to gauge
feedback for you about the validity of
our assumptions so
we're going to spend a lot of time
talking about the assumptions about how
they algorithm works and then illustrate
the algorithm with a sample path and I'm
going to show you some results and grass
and I've got to sway at the end about
how you can help so I think we can all
agree that s relationships determine how
traffic flows through the internet and
having a set of accurate is
relationships enables us what supports
some measurement of of the
infrastructure security and stability
what happens f say one of the larger AES
is with a large customer cone is
disrupted what is going to happen in the
Internet in terms of reckon versions how
many parts are going to be disrupted so
on analysis of Miss collegiate we miss
configuration for example that helps to
download case where if we're dodo starts
announced with provider routes to
another provider we shouldn't see this
in the internet so having a set of
accurate relationships might enable us
to detect this automatically and what
we're using it for is an analysis of the
influence of a s is based on the size of
the customer comb and again that's
roughly what is the absolute number of a
s is that a provider could charge
traffic for so and this talk we focus on
28 relationships these are the canonical
ones that I've always hold but they come
pretty close customer provider where the
customer pays a provider to have access
to its providers appears and customers
and peers where the agreed to
exchange traffic between their customers
with these set of relationships we
assume that the cash flow follows from
the customer to the provider and terms
of BGP relationships we can't tell if
peers the settlement free or paid
peering I'd like to have feedback on
that was the end but essentially money
is flowing from the customer to the
provider so the customer cone is
governor governor set of
chips for a ace customers direct
customers are BNC but I provided that
traffic reaches it from C will receive
settlement not from D but will be paid
to transit traffic from for example data
if assuming it doesn't go across the
peering link so ace customer cone
contains B C D and E and F but not G
which is across appearing link so the
customer code contains customers as well
as indirect customers so we have a set
of btb powers on the left and a set of
relationships we've and food on the
right I'm going to present three
different ways of constructing a
customer cone and solicit your feedback
on on each of them the first one is
what's called a recursive customer comb
so because we infer a to be a customer
of be it might be natural to infer that
a as an indirect customer of a except
the bgp pads don't suggest that that is
that be so that a has a path to be
because we never see one so the
recursive cone contains all of the aces
in the graph five of them but if we look
at what is observed in b2b pads we don't
see a path from E to a so that follows
custom provider relations are links so
we infer that its customer cone sizes
for and does not contain E but the
computation is a little bit more
complicated than that so a SS may have
and a piece of feedback we've had
repeatedly is that asus may have a
customer provider relationship in one
region but be peering elsewhere but when
we assign relationships we choose a
single relationship between two aces so
when we infer a customer by relationship
that overrides everything on the graph
so even if appearing nearly nearly
everywhere else we infer a single
relationship customer to provider but
using observed BBB+ limits the amount of
damage that can occur
so in this example we have x and y with
region based relationships customer
provider and type C and B have region
based relationships a customer provider
and and in the min America and
peer-to-peer in Europe sobeys cone will
contain F G and H using the observed
cone become us are using observed b2b
pars if we see that the pars across the
peering link because we infer custom
provider for between C and B overall but
a scone will not a scone will only
contain from see DNA because those are
what we observe to see followed on a
series of customer provider links so our
third approach to defining customer cone
might be to define it based on what we
see announced to an peers and
providers what we believe what's rate
certainly to be the customers the actual
customers so in this case because we see
a path to a from B that contains D and E
but not if G and H then we will infer
B's customer comb to contain just D and
E and C so with those with the customer
code in mind there's a bunch of caveats
again I've talked about region based
relationships and we can't be on that we
can't differentiate between paid peers
and settlement free peers so a paid pier
we do not include in the customer kind
of an AS even though they are paying
settlements to their peer even though
one of the aces paying settlements but
the PB that we've had in discussions
with operators is that there's no
routing difference that a paid peer is
treated identically to a settlement free
pier we don't know about traffic so if
you're a large access provider and you
have tens of millions of residential
customers you're
customer code is going to be small
because your customer code is countered
by iess so we don't hear traffic we
don't have a lot of visibility and
appearing to see all the pairing
relationships in the graph we need a
esas below the peering link and we don't
have a lot of again 400 a SS that's
that's about one percent of of all the
aces and internet so we don't see a lot
of pairing relationships the paths that
the public data source that we use is
messy again because of poison so weak
minded for your relationships that don't
exist because of poisoning and
potentially also leaking and the size of
a customer cone is not a metric of
market power we need a lot more data
than then customer khon2 and ferb market
power but with these caveats in mind or
maybe to keep you interested i'm going
to present a few graphs so this graph is
the observed customer cone time series
from 2002 to 2002 october 2012 on the
y-axis is the size of the customer conan
a SS in absolute numbers that were
observed over time and we see in this
graph a number of cases that have
increased in size I've labeled a few
majors you can see on the bottom left
where level 3 acquires Genuity and
merges with them and up on the top right
just recently we level 3 merged with
global crossing so those are using
observed pars and this doesn't cleanly
deal with region based relationships
particularly you might notice that there
are spikes in the graph that aren't well
explainable that these could be due to a
single relationship being Miss and third
or it might be that we don't have we
have visibility sometimes but not others
but perhaps that could also be due to us
seeing periodically evidence of region
based relationships
so this graph is the customer code as
defined by an providers and peers
so this cone is likely to underestimate
the size of ivan is because we are
presumably missing some customers and
pick me know we're missing customers but
as treats all ace's equally in fact if
you provide a view to route views then
we have a good view of your is and that
is reflected in the observed cone but in
the provider and Pierre cone that view
itself does not influence the size of
the customer cone but what matters is
what your peers and providers relate to
us I'll relay publicly so in this level
three the largest is has a customer cone
that in absolute terms and two in late
two thousand twelve is forty percent
four percent of the internet and the
observed cone the previous graph that's
fifty nine percent so that's customer
cone I'm going to talk about the
relationship algorithms that we the
algorithm that we developed we went back
to the drawing board with this because
and the ground truth that we'd collected
over a number of years our relationship
the algorithm we that we provided that
are publicly for and a number of other
ones did not match the ground truth very
well so with that in mind we tried to
develop a new one so I'm going to begin
with a few definitions a transit degree
so we use the governor set of BGP powers
and a SS transit degree there's a number
of a SS for which it provides transit
for and we can't tell if the ISS but
that they are providing that they are
transmitting traffic between our
providers customers or peers but what it
allows us to do is to differentiate
between large transit a SS and large
edge I users that might peer extensively
so this is instead of a node degree so
and B's case B's transfer degree is for
because it provides transit between a
see sorry a C D and E but not if Angie
and this is a
of using bgp paths we have an assumption
that there is a collective asses at the
top of the hierarchy you may think of
these as tier 1 a SS but these include
more than just the t1i uses these
include other transit providers that are
paying that may be paying settlements to
these other members of the click and a
full peering mesh so we expect to when
we earn our rhythm what we are looking
for is for a link between and a s and
all other members of the current members
of the click and that there is no
evidence that there is transit taking
place that the transit is not being
provided to a na s across the cliq some
have a relationship with all of the
of the tier 1 i'll throw all of the
click but they receive transit from some
of them so they we don't include those
in the cloak our assumptions behind our
algorithm is are as follows that we have
that click at the top otherwise and then
the reason this has to exist is that
otherwise the internet topologies
petitioned or a SS need to have
relationships of all members of the
cloak we assume that a provider
announces customer routes to its
providers this is the main point of
paying provider to obtain connectivity
to the rest of the internet we assume
that the transfer degree of a provider
is larger than n of its customer and
this is a porter by our ground truth 99%
of providers are larger than their
customers in terms of the links that we
see and that the topology graph in terms
of providing customer relationships as
they circulate that means we never see a
as a customer of be be is a customer of
si si is a customer of a existing
relationship algorithms produce these
things called strongly connected
components and Alice does not and this
is supported in our ground truth we see
no a ptc cycle and our ground truth so a
high level algorithm is that we infer
the clock and and them Pierre appearing
mesh at the top
then we do some filtering of our btb
passed an example of the function week
we do is remove cards reserved a SS and
we remove pars with is evidence of
poisoning for example if we to see if we
see to click a SS with a non click is in
the middle of them that suggests that
that the two classes are using another
AST as transit but we know that they do
not quite this they can exchange traffic
between themselves so infer that the due
to poisoning then we break our paths
into triplets and this algorithm we are
not seeking to maximize valid paths as
previous relationship algorithms have
done but we used the the basic unit of
information in these and the
construction and the paths then we visit
a SS by then top down and order of
largest transit agree and we infer a
neighbor if a neighbor's write a
customer to provide a relationship if a
neighbor passes a router provider or if
the neighbor is a member of the clock
and it passes the route to another
member of the clock and this gets us
fifty six percent of all the all the
graph observed graph relationships and
food for their customer customer
provider relationships and these are
ninety nine point eight percent correct
according to our ground truth there are
additional steps in algorithm but
essentially everything that we don't
infer to be a custom provider is in food
to be up here and that's thirty-seven
percent of the graph and 90 x into those
relationship inferences are correct so
given a set of btv pars we have millions
and millions and millions of these but
given just this one we have a path
involving 50 years I've labeled to them
because you recognize these as AT&T and
level 3 but to begin with so there's a
directionality to the to a b2b path the
information there outflows from the
origin to the vantage point the vantage
point is providing its view to wrap use
and res
we don't know anything about the
relationships at this point but we infer
in a previous step that AT&T and level 3
are members of the cloak and have a
pairing relationship in them we label
sorry then we break up the path into
triplets and then we label each node
with its transit degree what we observed
to be its treasure degree so a in terms
of the transfer degree apart from the
clock a esas a as then followed by C and
then as followed by B and then followed
by C by transit degree then we visit
them an order of transit degree so we
visit a first now it might be natural to
interfere that a is a customer of AT&T
in this case because there is appearing
relationship upstream from them but we
don't make an inference based on this
information unless we can this we have
other things pointing us in that
direction because it could be the case
that AT&T is leaking routes p routes to
a we would expect fa is a customer of of
AT&T that they appear on the right hand
side of AT&T and a BGP path because then
that means that AT&T is announcing paths
from a two other pairs and customers
that's right other peers and customers
and the net decision to do so has been
validated multiple times and if we don't
enforce this rule than our validation
results go down so that's essentially
why we do it we inferred thee as a
customer of of 18 that's right level
three because we see level three
announce across the click so again if a
it appeared on the other side where the
appears now than we would have inferred
a customer relationship but and thus we
don't and we still might be inferring
leap blinking but we can't do much about
that when for cust see is a customer of
B because we see see the CB announced to
its provider routes from
see so and we proceed so we had seven
percent of special cases in our in our
algorithm vantage points with no
provider outs so like I said roughly
two-thirds of a SS provide not a
complete view FNA s provides less than
five percent routes to listen typist end
of a SS and we in fear that it's
providing peers and customer routes and
not provider routes and so we have a
special case to deal with customer of
right of relationships below them we
have a case of course to deal with
providers that have a smaller transit
degree than their customer we have a
case term for customers for a SS with no
providers again our algorithm focuses on
inferring providers and not customers
but we have to do it for a essence that
have no providers because otherwise we
would infer no customers for them and a
good example of that is transit rail and
finally when all else fails then we are
left with triplets where we have
inferred no relationship and if we infer
no relationship then we will fear both
links to be peers and this may or may
not be case the case so we try and
collapse one of the two AES is down we
tend to bias collapsing zeid down to a
customer to provide relationship with
why so in terms of our ground truth our
efforts develop eight this we have
assembled a set of 47,000 relationships
we acquired two thousand of them
directly through is ranked from 2010 22
2012 and what these relationships what
these were submitted we're mostly
pairing relationships our previous
algorithm and third many more providers
then existed and when an operator or
someone with knowledge would visit the
page but correct our false provider
inferences to peers and essentially
leave everything else so there's some
motivation to do so we used the routing
our psl database from ripe to to extract
a set of customer of writer
relationships because there might be
some out-of-date relationships recorded
what we
quiet is that they have been updated
within the last two years and that for
each link we have a and B we expect to
see a expressed that be as a provider
and the rpi silence would be being
expressed that a is its customers so we
have high confidence in these in this
set of ground truth and finally we have
a set of relationships extracted from
bgp data using community values there's
we assemble a while pusillus assembled a
collection of roughly 40,000
relationships that are expressed and bgb
communities as defined by operators so
these are published and web pages and in
whois for approximately 230 a esas and
so roughly two-thirds is provided
customer and a branch with overall to
theses provided customer and a third
peer and validates approximately
thirty-eight percent of the graph in
terms of how we do and how other
inference algorithms do we're very
accurate and fearing both provider
customer and peering relationships
ninety nine point six percent of
provider customer relationships that we
classify as provided customer
relationships are what we say they are
so point four percent of those appears
you might notice down the bottom girl
has a very high positive predictive
value for peering relationships but like
our previous algorithm may include many
more providers they need then in reality
so they have a very small set of peer to
peer relationships and the small set
validate well but the provided customers
don't do so well so this is the clock
that we've been feared to exist over
time what we're looking for because we
don't have a good set of ground truth
for who is in the click on who is not
what we have is what we're looking for
is as some semblance of stability so
mine of the a SS have always been in the
clicks for the past 11 years we've seen
some that have been merged for example
down the bottom level of ice one
WorldCom went away and more recently
there have been a esas particularly in
Europe that have appeared to be in the
clique because we don't see any transit
relationships for them but this might be
a limitation of our bgb data we're not
sure and what we've plotted here is a
graph of the three largest a esas as
they stood by customer code in 2002
january 2002 and the three largest now
so i potted for the third line cogent
but cogent looks roughly the same as in
teluk went and what were the other ones
are we have to see it sorry they look
roughly the same as in teluk want and
there's others TeliaSonera so we have
seen from 2002 the birth of three very
large guesses in fact maybe five or six
and the ones that were the largest 10
years ago are not so large based on the
size of their customer comb and level 3
has a proximally forty-four percent of
all ace's in its customer cone and
that's been relatively static for the
past eight years again this is our
provider and peer to find customer cone
this is what the previous graph is based
off except now we're showing absolute
numbers and again you'll see to the
right cogent and telechron intelius
aneri roughly the same size and their
lines for a roughly the same pattern if
you can pick them out I'm happy to show
you this graph afterwards so in terms of
what we'd like help for from men are
like to know what it is that we have not
thought of like to know we'd like to
have some information about how
prevalent paid peering is we've received
some amount of indications of paid
pairing but not enough for us to be able
to come up with any methodology about
how we might distinguish a paid pair
from a settlement free Pierre
and in fact we're not even sure that we
can do so the bgp data relate with us
and what's one of our assumptions is
that a customer is announced to a
provider's providers and what situations
might this not a cure we'd like to know
something about how prevalent complex
relationships are so if you can provide
us with ground truth information about
relationships you have with a esas where
they are provider and one relate and
rent one region that peering and another
we'd like to hear about that I would
like to know what the granularity of
complex relationships are as a
region-based thing we've hit Express
mostly in region and our feedback but it
may be it's at prefix as well in ideally
more vantage points of rappers and res
and additional ground truth and with
that questions we do have time for
questions or comments
trib used in a panic in this study your
kind of treating every a s as an AS
right but I notice in the allocation
statistics the in the asia-pacific
region there are only five thousand one
hundred a esas that are allocated yet in
North America 15,000 and in Europe in
the Middle East 18,000 so it seems that
an AS isn't an AS and that while in some
parts of the world nodal notably in
Europe AS has actually expressed a
relatively fine grained degree of
routing policy whereas in other parts of
the world a SS encompass much much
larger sets of users and policies how
does your study relate to this
difference that we see in the use of a
esas across the world it treats them all
as equals and that's a limitation again
we don't have traffic which is
essentially what we want whether or not
this can be used to as an as a proxy I
don't know as a simple observation
somewhere in that massive ranking of
huge providers you would expect to see
something like China Telecom but they're
phenomenally notable by their very
absence in any such ranking and it kind
of wonder how you would integrate
different regions uses of a esas into
this I guess we would need additional
information in some way to express that
as a rule so we need more ground truth I
better go more of my can you go to the
questions Lee so you're asking questions
here that you know how prevalent are
complex relationships how prevalent
hearing and things like that there's
what 40,000 ish AAS is available in the
global table for 30-something thousand
35-39 thousand of them the answer is
zero to all of the above so if you limit
yourself to a much smaller set than the
questions become nearly one hundred
percent the complex relationships have
even the people the networks that you
had in that slide the very large
providers are massively complex I mean
look at just what level three announces
through press releases in the fact that
you know cogent sorry Comcast got them
to somebody here works for coaching is
going to piss to me now so the fact that
level three puts out a press release
saying that Comcast force them into
peering as well as having a transit
relationship and things like that so
these are all you know well known as
ground truths as you say but the problem
is that you're treating everyone the
same when in reality the very very top
ones have complex multilateral
relationships and like Jeff pointed out
you know bgp works on a prefix asses are
convenient grouping but clearly it
doesn't work that way if you just strip
out the bottom 90 something percent of
them and concentrate on the complex ones
you might have a better shot but then
you have to be your algorithm your
procedures have to be far more flexible
and complex if you want to do just the
bottom ever however many there are then
these things become much easier and
everything you say holds easily does
that make sense yeah okay what's the
chances of you doing that on a per
prefix basis for level three that's what
I thought
thank you let's thank the speaker