and announce the next talk it's y'all
gouging or a yell King whoo i don't know
if i pronounced it right a young king
where did you go there you are and he's
going to talk about fast incremental fib
abrogation aggregation and i think this
is really interesting from a standpoint
of route table blood and things like
that are there ways we can reduce the
FIB sighs so so hello aroma my name is
joe giglio a 50-year pd student from the
University and University of Memphis my
advisor is dr. lam well we collaborate
with the total bitch went down from the
University of Arizona and today my
presentation topic is fast incremental
feeble irrigation also called the FIFA
notice this is not the international
football association name but our album
name so in this talk I'm we're going to
cover a motivation the FIBA education
overview the update handling and the
evaluation the operational impact and
finally the concluding so first
motivation so the left picture shows the
main components inside the rotor so as
we know the rotor the rib is mainly
responsible for collecting all the
passwords and download download them
into the FIP look at the underlying card
and also it handles all the updates and
downloads the fifth 20s or the rib
rotating changes to the line heart so
but right now adays in the right picture
as you can see the rid of Carruth of the
rib has been overall in your rate since
2004 so things we know the fib is the
from the rib so that that makes the FIP
very big and the large fib then may not
fit the FIB memory anymore but to do to
the first look up and the forwarding
requirement the FIB memory is very
expensive and it will cost is P or
customers a lot to do the upgrade for
the hardware or the line card or for the
rotor so we proposed a fib irrigation
which is a local glucose and the
software solution to reduce the FIB
sighs so why local low cost is important
because ice PS are reluctant to deploy
solutions with the high cost and with a
lot of parties involved in and also this
protocol not protocol at least elddim
doesn't need to change any routing
protocol currently deployed in the
network so this is adjusted local
decision and the motivation to actually
that there are some existing works
including our process work fukers arm
reducing the fee beside the rib size
alpha besides by as much as seventy
percent however in this the guineas work
we also focus on reducing the overall
overhead for the aggregation so the most
challenging job in this incremental free
valuation is not the one time education
itself but the update handling because
we have to apply all those updates to
the Aqua defib but meanwhile maintained
a very good complaint ratio so the
opportunity was in our work first of
course is extended line hard our
objective is five years at least and
also we want to reduce the overall
updated handling time and
the total number 15 g's also the food
burst so what is the valuation I provide
send his explanation is to mod a merge
multiple fib entries into one so for
example we can aggregate five entries in
the original phpbb into three as through
in a a great fit so we proved and
verified they have one hundred percent
forwarding the same for me behaviors
before and after the aggregation so so
we propose the FIFA model first let's
see the normal operation the operation
in a in a rotor so as you can see if
there are any road changes we will be
downloaded into the fever located on a
la carte directly and we designed this
album we plugged by module between rip
and a fib and in the control plane so if
there any world change right now the
first will be handled by the FIFA module
and then the fever module does to
download the effective ones into the
line card so we propose three fast fast
incremental fib every album piece down
improved or HTC or HTC also called
optimal rotating table constructor the
original or RTC words first proposed in
1999 using a binary tree and it needs
three passes over the binary tree to get
the one-time aggregation optima
aggregation results and there is no
update handling for this album so we
made to country many contributions in
our work first if we improve that ortc
using patria chart which is a space
optimized try and we only use two passes
to finish the same task
as the original of our RTC does and
right now is 2.5 come faster and it's
only takes forty four percent of the
original memory and the keep the strong
for link Ronnie's the second
contribution is we propose three fast
incremental of update han areum the
first one is we call pas this album is
the optimal size of the entire album for
each update its maintain a global
optimally optimality for example for
each update it always keep the smallest
websites and an old reallocation and for
the Tea Party is the mean more time
added a deal Henry algorithm so this
emblem is the fattest one but things
more and more of these are coming in the
fifth sides may not maintain the optimal
one so we have to set a threshold for
this one so this one need a reallocation
and similarly for FP aah this is a
hybrid hybrid abid handling album so in
this album we pick the two features from
SNT and there's no reallocation and it
has small small fee besides 3po changes
so first let me roughly go through the
or RTC implementation just give you a
big future how we did the application
first as you can see in our left table
we have the original fib entries so we
load those entries into a binary tree or
try and since I mentioned or at least in
use three passes so the first pass is a
top-down process to normalize all the
other leaf nodes and so each normalized
node will get the sim desktop as the
same as is the nearest ancestors so like
this
and the second pass is a bottom-up post
order process too much nest hops so for
so ever that means you each each know
that we have to maintain a set of
finesse hops so as you can see that with
us and the third pass for what you see
is to select the nest hub from the root
of the tree it is a top-down process so
finally after the three passes we only
pick the effective knows that is true in
the corrinos so they will be loaded onto
the equifit and actually it has the same
forwarding behavior as the original one
so I roughly good went through the
application and let me introduce the
update hun dream so first the update
hunting without any aggregation for
example I will have a new purpose
announcement coming in 141 dog to the
file / 18 with ness top three and if you
in a in a pile in a tree actually one
node will be generated and this the
prefix will be downloaded into the fib
so as you can see the relationship
between one rib update and the one the
fifth change is one to one relationship
so one rib update 1 15 or 1 a fan
keynote but if we apply the same update
to the every drip it has a different
story so that means one rib update may
trigger multiple 15 days or a lot
multiple nodes will be get affected I
will use the f is FIFA s
update honey as an example so the left
the lab toiletry is the aggregate of
people as shown in previous slides and
so right now we are update we apply the
art Steve update to this try and this
this album will keep the global
optimality so multiple nodes will be
getting pelted in this example for level
three nodes will get a felted fh energy
but only the effective 1g actually
finally will be downloaded into the fit
everything so it has the same forwarding
behavior as the original update update
one so 40 and the age they have the
similar properties so i just give it but
i won't give you a straightforward
example to show the differences between
the three of them so finally i got one
that is a ir spring example so for
example i have i have a fever Adam and I
have already knows spring so the
original spirit represents the
alternative size so for the first step
we apply the improved or RTC to the
original fib and we go to the optimal or
smallest tip size and for each update
each atom after the other words are the
updates the results for each update and
as you can see for you to update the
favor always keep the smallest websites
so let's see FIFA Chi so at the very
beginning we have the same original fib
size and things more and more this is
this album will keep a look of the
melody so we're more and more of these
are coming in we the free besides will
be go back will be going back to
original fib sighs so we have to set a
threshold to control the fifth size but
the first step is the same we need to
apply the same algorithm improve RTC and
so when more and more updates are coming
in and create the flip side will get
loose and until a threshold is reached
so what's the threshold reached the
threshold can be can be a I mean a
memory a memory limit you have a your
memory image and you can state that were
held for that and what's the threshold
reached the algorithm will push the egg
with this this web sites back to the
optimal using reallocation notice that
each relegation only requires a point
two seconds and so on and so forth this
the reaction will down periodically so
for fifa h before the threshold is
reached it has the same operations as
FIFA t but you know in order to avoid
the rear vision instead helpful pushing
the fifth sides back to the optimal the
smallest tip size we we just the album
just push it under the threshold and
when more and more updates are coming in
the album the fifth sides will go back
about about the third hole so we hope to
the push again so on and so forth but no
radiation so so right now you may get a
big picture of the differences of the
three evidence so I'm going to talk talk
about our evolution evaluation
methodology and the evaluation results
so first our data were from the road
view project rip debo and updates from
january first 2011 to December 31st 2011
and
use this pure because this fear has the
most es hops so generally the more s the
Martin s hops number the more difficult
to do the aggregation so that's also
indicates that we are estimating the
worst case so we did Stan Mikita
pre-processing we filter after all the
wicked update messages and into that in
the end of 11 other year they are about
50 for immediate updates and we use the
nest es hub as in the nest hall so we
did the experiment our normal desktop we
use for metrics to do the evaluation the
most important and student for line is
the fifth size the total number of
entries in the aggregate fib the second
one is the time cost the tutor now the
top of the total update handling time
and the third one is the total number of
50s as I mentioned before well Reba
updates may not admit cost multiple 15
days so we need the total number of 15
days and also reversed so we want to get
a distribution of for example how many
rip up this cost zero this value can be
zero since some people of this may be a
duplicate or covered so how many
relationship is 120 how many is 121 how
many s went to 10 some level so I'll go
through them one by one first the fifth
sighs so the top red line represents the
original fifth sides without any
irrigation you can see in the end of
2011 they are about 300 8005 entries and
the the red line at the bottom is the
results for FIFA s so you can see in n.o
to tell evan is
it's about 150,000 so about more than
sixty percent people any treat have been
aggregated and so for the fib FIFA T and
H we have to set a threshold we set a
threshold as 180,000 so the blue line
represents the results for FIFA Chi as
you can see it will periodically to the
that's the reallocation and there were
93 allegations in 2011 and the each
irrigation is about point two seconds
and that the black line is the FIFA H
does so as you can see before the
thresholded reached it has simply it has
the same fifth size as the FIFA chi but
once the threshold is reached so it will
the flip side will still around the
threshold and then no recognition so
overall the aggregation can engage more
than fifty percent of the people entries
so that the second Matrix is the time so
the bottom black line represents the
normal updates without irrigation the
update is part 1 point 1 micron second
probe date so the blue line represents
the tea party results is a part 1 point2
macro micro second probe date and for
the fifa h is by the 1.9 second probe
date even for the optimal one as the
smallest value of size 1 is about to the
microsecond profit formula grass as you
can see the affordable so the third
metric favorite indie is the total
number 15 days and for the the bottom
black line is the updates for normal
number updates without any obligation so
it's one to one relationship right so
one change product
so for the tea party with us is about
1.1 change / update and the FIFA H is by
the one point to 10 days / update so
even for the optimum one is about 1.8
second provident so from the last you
can see they are all accessible so the
last one is the free burst so first from
the category of less than or equal to
one category you can see most rib
updates a great cost 0 or 1 15 days and
about 99% of the rib updates cost less
than 10 15 g's in the category less than
or equal to 10 category we also observe
that in FIFA s and H the heavies the
worst is about 500 and the 1115 TS
respectively and the FIFA Chi with the
fever's your early very small but it
could be very large because that
reallocation so you can pick the one
feel for you so summary from fee besides
you can see FIFA s is the best from the
time costs fifa cheese best from the FIB
10 days fifa cheese best and from the
feeblest a fever ass is best and from
the revolution prospective FIFA s and H
are the best so there's no silver bullet
right so what's the benefit our
conclusion is that we can stand around
her life or the Lionheart left
more than five years up to seven years
so we use the history data to get this
conclusion for example remember in the
end total 11 the optimal fifth size is
about 150 so if we map this results to
the history Trent of the fifth size we
are back to 2005 so even we are using
the third hole one tnh actually we are
back to two thousand six so that that
means if we if one rotor or like Harlan
were supposed to be replaced in two
thousand five or six can be used till
now so what is the operational impact so
of course you need to maintain the
aggregate fit in main memory I mean in a
control plane and for you to edit them
you have to pay the corresponding time
and clip changes and reversed as I my
analysis before so the conclusion from
benefits actually we can extend the
rotors lifetime for more than five years
and they have smaller head from the time
15 days and the cost is that I mean the
cost is 440 updates I mean the feedback
which Adam is not only hours you need
attention additional memory in the
control plane and you need to hand out a
few bursts so these some references
including some our previous work and
this work was supported by s current and
we also thank want to thank professor
this charger from UCLA for her in style
for comments and all right so um if you
are interested in my research or
you think I may be one of you all I mean
the right person of Y openings please
let me know since i'm going to go at
this with my contact email address why
are you six at memphis told you thank
you i'm happy to take your questions
jeff has juniper networks for your
aggregation statistics are your next
stops taking into account bgp eco cars
multipath we have within a kc that I
need multiple costs so right now we only
consider one single es hop so I would
suggest that your statistics are a
little optimistic given that okay thank
you another question microphones are so
up and we have some minutes for
questions come every Latino fog touch
telecom looking at your evaluation of
your gain I'm missing a little bit
caveats about well okay how the
estimated gains may be off from what's
going to be experienced first of all
voila cage the question is quite
obviously you are assuming there are no
ibgp rules in a forwarding table actree
when prefix corresponding one that's hot
so if it doesn't matter I mean all right
BTW peeled well I have I have I have a
significant percentage of my roots that
I'm that that I have to feed into the
FIB that are actually internal ibgp and
never will show up in route views and
very likely are not being aggregate able
in good ways that's that's
that's probably that's probably taking
away from the estimate of how much how
much you can gain the other thing of
course is at least the caveat should be
in place that well okay well you did you
did an estimation well okay you
evaluated your gain from a signal from a
single hopes I think I desktop yeah no
no no no no a snapshot of the routing
table I mean for example well maybe did
the evaluation first we pick up pick the
rotten people in at the very beginning
of 2011 and then we get the other
updates of the whole year and then we
apply all these updates to the people so
it's not a square shot you saw that show
you so you ran the aggregation from on
the table of 2005 and of this of today
for us no I mean I picked the table for
example january first 2011 and that is
the ok people and we apply all these
updates afterwards and because the
results of the whole year yes so kind of
kind of the assumption that the
aggregation well ok the ability to
aggregate you are projecting from today
into the next five or seven years yeah
that probably should be should be worth
a caveat because well ok the way how
addresses are split and being aggregate
about today is not really sure to be the
same in five years time
okay yeah that's going point actually
yeah another work with either the
evaluation from 2000 Wi-Fi I'm a right
to 2010 with we found that actually that
application ratio is better and better I
mean we can add with more and more I
think due to learn more and more more
specific perfect in a table thank you
any other questions actually I have a
quick question um d you Michael Sinatra
ESN I have a quick question do you um
have you actually implemented this in
any kind of router like a like some sort
of open flow routes herb or anything
like that are you planning to the
Creator is no and that's why I
motivation we come up here to ask your
support about these Pro to this
algorithm so if you are interesting in
this research yeah please continue thank
you okay thanks very much