yeah I'm just so just as the quick
introduction into frame things I'm
palabras man I work at Infoblox in our
ipv6 group and a lot of what I do is I
go out and talk to people and sort of
collect their experiences of what
they've had in a way of good and bad
things rolling things out I'm also one
of people that goes actually I am the
person that goes to the IETF for
infoblox to participate in see what's
coming down the pike so basically what
i'm doing here is sort of sharing what
are the things that we have probably all
gotten used to doing and have stopped
questioning as assumptions because we've
been doing it so long and before some of
the new things in b6 and what that might
do to change how we're sort of tearing
apart in building up our new networks so
there's a lot of material here I'm going
to be going through some of it a little
fast but it is on the slides my email is
also on the slides and I am also going
through so I can have five or ten
minutes at the end for some question and
answer so basically like I said that the
assumption here is that you don't want
to have you know a 70s Leisure Suit
mentality about your network we have
been doing the same thing with me for
four years because we have been out of
before addresses functionally for years
and we have done things with NAT in 1918
and clever pool sizes and all sorts of
other crap to try and keep things glued
together and we've gotten so used to the
pain that we now design our networks
that way is if that is correct and the
reality is is that no that is the best
way to deal with what we have and a lot
of that is different v6 so there are a
huge number of changes the IETF loves
changes because they don't actually have
to make things operationally ready myth
is that change is good well not
necessarily but we are all going to be
dealing with it v6 is pretty much
inevitable at this point the only
question is when you're going to be
putting it into which places in your
network and how are you're going to be
migrating gradually to have your v4
probably move further and further to the
edges there are a lot of things that we
have sort of gotten used to it this is
what we don't have particularly address
space and subnetting space that are no
longer issues
and the other thing I I tend to
emphasize is this is probably as big a
paradigm shift as when we all went from
class full addresses to cider in how we
think about everything in our backbone
and how we do our dress usage is at
least as educationally challenging or
disruptive to our lives if not more some
of the good news um there are a bunch of
things that we did learn about and there
are there in v6 that it's going to allow
a six on routers to be much more
efficient at the point at which we have
v6 only backbones and you don't have to
switch before packets it's a fixed
header size so you know exactly how many
bits to snap off the front instead of
having variable length and all of the
options built into this amorphous blob
there's now an extension header chain
one of the other efficiencies is that
the router specific extensions are all
at the front of the chain so any
intermediate device between the sender
and the destination as soon as they hit
a non relevance header they can stop
parsing flow labels are better placed in
the headers and potentially may be
useful for that wonderful mythical
unicorn we call quality of service
another good thing in some ways there is
no intermediate fragmentation anymore
there's path MTU discovery only the
sender is allowed to fragment packets
now so you don't have middle layer boxes
screwing up fragmentation and reassembly
which has been one of the many things
that those middle layer boxes do to make
our lives more interesting another one
was there are no check sums because
their check sums in the layer below and
above it there is really no need so all
of these things together mean that
router code will be at the point where
if it's in a sick and it's v6 native
only will be able to shovel
significantly more bits potentially and
have more control over things like flow
based routing there are some things on
the local wire too I will call it the
broadcast domain that there is no actual
broadcast in vb6 but it's the same thing
one single virtual wire first of all
there is no broadcast it's all multicast
which is one single sender to multiple
recipients who have subscribe
two messages of that type and they're
well-known type so if you want to reach
all the routers on the subnet there's a
specific reserved address if you want to
get to the DHCP servers or relays or a
recursive DNS server or all the hosts
they're all there and you can send in
only those entities that care about
being that type of box will need to
listen and neighbor solicitation and
solicited node is these replacement for
our how you take a mac address in turn
into a v6 address on the local wire it's
hashed on the last 24 bits so again even
that which in theory is a broadcast only
the people whose last 24 bits of their
host address need to even listen and
icmpv6 has become much more granular and
specific in all of its type so you can
be much more particular about what you
filter and do and don't allow all of
those together mean that there is less
overhead on a local wire now this
doesn't mean that we'll be able to go up
from 256 for a thousand host to 18
quintillion but it does mean that will
probably get twenty or thirty percent
more hosts on a single broadcast domain
than we used to once we're v6 only and
not dual stack so one of the things I
love about v6 is we have been calling
ourselves network architects for years
but we're really more like plumbers and
possibly even handyman we are taking
duct tape and baling wire to our
networks we aren't architecting anything
these tix we actually have a chance
again to do what our job titles says
actually design the network that we are
going to be using and one of the big
things is we can actually subnet again
and subnetting is not how can I fit as
many hosts as possible into the address
space I have right now you can actually
design it you can make it map to however
you divide up your networks so that your
subnetting plan actually immediately
falls over into how you do your ackles
in your security and i'll have a sample
example of how you could do this based
on geography to give you some ideas one
of the things I stressed very very
heavily when you're figuring out your
address space and what you need count
everything all your 1918 space
everything you use and then
Global unicast space enough for all of
it public routable space there is a 1918
equivalent called unique local UL ace in
v6 but it has the same disadvantages in
1918 does it's not guaranteed unique
it's more likely to be unique but it's
not guaranteed it's not routable on the
internet if you get global unicast space
enough for everything now you have
choices you don't have to not if it
needs to get to the internet for some
reason you can filter it if you don't
want it to be out on the internet you
may even use ula in places in your
network but get enough address space so
that you have the choice of using
non-routable space not getting stuck
using non-routable because you can't get
enough routable space and again do a
scheme that aggregates well so that your
announcements are clean you know let's
help with the dfz and the routing tables
actually make it better some basic rules
of thumb pretty much the longest prefix
that anybody buddy considers routable
right now is this 48 so if you have two
separate or sites that you both need to
have on the internet you will need to
have a 48 for each of them even if they
don't need that much subnetting spacing
that is the equivalent of the 22 or the
24 in ipv4 current recommendation is
also anything that is not a
point-to-point link anything that has
any form of n toast whatsoever give it a
/ 64 as the subnet size don't go longer
than that there are already boxes that
hard code that the rightmost 64 bits is
the host yes that violates the specs yes
that is broken congratulations we have
broken boxes on our network never
happened before 4.2 points the
recommendation is for security reasons
using 127 don't allow anything other
than two endpoints there are proponents
that say you should use a 64 for
everything including point2 points
ignoring the it wastes lots of address
space which I think should it still at
least be thought of it's not a huge
point but there are security reasons
read that RFC that will explain it if
you want to truly have every subnet
everywhere is always 64 no matter what
the current compromises you allocate a
64 for that point-to-point link that you
only configure a / 120
that way you get the allocation ease of
a single subnet size but you have the
security problem dealt with any place
you use the / 31 in your current network
you'd use a 127 any place that you would
use the / 32 usually loop backs that you
pass around in your I GP you use 128 my
recommendation is if you are not doing
the 64 for everything everywhere take
160 for that is all of your
point-to-point links 164 that is all of
your loop backs and that is per routing
area obviously if you have discontinuous
areas you will need to give 64 stewie
inch one of the reasons that that's good
is you then have a 64 that is the
loopback for every router and every
networking device in your network and
it's really easy to put in an apple that
says ssh to and from those works to your
not just another example of how you can
actually make your ackles make sense
easily here's a sample plan basically
envy 48 that boundaries are easy anytime
that you do a subnet that is or a prefix
length that is it a multiple of eight
it's easy because you are not dividing
the number between the dots in the ipv4
address we have done that with cider but
it's not as easy the equivalent is that
they're 128 bits in a v6 address 32
hexadecimal characters that's four bits
or a nibble for each one of those hex
characters so again to make your life
easy if all of your prefix Lancer are
divisible evenly by four you are never
dividing in the middle of one of those
letters for right now that's a whole lot
more readable and there's enough space
to do that and even the rirs and li RS
are doing that allocation info box has
eight sites that have no backbone
between them we didn't need more than 48
in terms of subnetting for our entire
company but we had eight sites so when
we went to Aaron and said we have eight
sites they are physically distant from
each other they said okay you need a 48
for each of them 16 of them would be
plenty for you therefore we will give
you a 44 and that was our whole
justification wasn't how many hosts it
wasn't anything else it was we have
eight separate sites
we need a 44 done in this case this is
one where I'm a data center and I am in
multiple cities and within the city I
may have multiple buildings that I have
equipment and what I usually do is I
break it down all the way down to VLAN
and I usually have a customer for VLAN
in this case I just go through how many
of each do I need well in my example I
assume I have 12 cities so 16 possible
is enough so 4 bits is enough if I had
needed 24 cities I would have had to
jump up to the next chunk which would
have been eight bits and it would have
been 256 yes I'm wasting space but it
made my scheme work and we have enough
space to do that so what this means is
by the time I get to a 64 for a VLAN I
not only know the customer I know
exactly which city i'm in I know which
switch I'm in I'm know which VLAN it's
all completely self documenting I don't
even need to do reverse pointers to know
exactly where that customer is and it's
all about subnets we are no longer
counting hosts like we do in v4 it is
not I have 256 hosts therefore I need us
a / 22 or flash 19 whatever it is how
many subnets and even when you get your
allocation if I getting / 36 from right
what they're actually going to do is
they're going to take a 32 they're going
to give me the first half of that 32 and
they're going to block the other half
and reserve it in case I need it later
that way if it turns out my allocation
scheme didn't work I go back to them and
they say okay here just change your
prefix length use the other half you
don't have to remember it just works so
again get everything you need get it now
get it while the rars are being generous
and yeah there are some limitations
there 18 quintillion possible addresses
in 64 but again I've talked about this
layer to stuff Trump's you will still
get a couple thousand entities on an end
its of ice and last point at some point
we may not be able to do nibbles we may
be doing cider on v6 I predict we will
because we have a history of way
seeing any amount of anything we've ever
been given but at least while we can
make it sane for ourselves let's enjoy
it and use the whole 64 particular to
things like pool sizes you know one of
the things that has always been touted
as v6 is more secure as they can't do
brute force scans well that's true but
if what I do is I say that I'm on dot
one dot whatever you know when I you 168
1 for a subnet and my host has got 100 I
can certainly say 2000 cold and DBA
colon 1 is my prefix I can go colon
colon 100 and that's the same host very
easy very self documenting and for my
service machines I do that but I've also
now just reduced the scannable space
that I need to worry about from 18
quintillion to 256 which is brute force
cannibal so if you want that protection
use the whole pool you may have figured
out that I have certain opinions about
19 18 in that they are probably one of
the worst things we ever did to each to
ourselves fact when we were running out
of address space in the 90s in the 80s
that we need to go to ipv6 all everyone
said look G isn't there something we can
do just you know munch addresses around
and we said no no you can't do that it
won't scale it performance is lousy
there's security problems they and they
said no no we really need something
right now okay and we gave them that and
the problem was not actually worked
didn't work well but it did work better
than in non-existent v6 and it put off
v6 implementation by a dozen years
easily did it ever make sense well yes
we were running out of space we we were
they were still debating too but and all
sorts of other alternatives to what
became ipv6 back when we were almost out
and they just couldn't get it together
so it wasn't widely available there was
no dhcpv6 for another seven years people
were desperate they would take anything
I personally think there were
hallucinogenic substances being filtered
around and somehow we thought this might
be an accept
the way to get past this for now and
what we have been left with is 12 years
of hell well why is it still around if
it sucks that badly well because there
isn't still right now enough before
space and v6 is not ready for enough
people and there is the it's more secure
let me shoot on that one what we did was
we we were stuck with NAT and we were
trying to make ourselves feel better so
we were rationalizing that maybe there
was something actually good about this
whole thing where you have this one
public address in this whole slew of
private addresses behind well is there
anything good both it obscures my users
you can't get to my users they have to
initiate the connection ok so a that's
not Matt that's the stateful firewall
that happens to be implemented by most
Nats and be that assumes that the
attackers are coming in from the outside
reality has shown is that users are lazy
and stupid and that it's much easier to
trick them into coming out and doing an
established session so it's no security
anyway because most of the exploits are
being done from the inside by our little
users other things that it is done is we
have wanted for the whole series of
protocols that are rather twisted in a
key and design skype in particular could
have been a vastly cleaner architecture
if we had had enough public address
space everywhere and not had to punch
through NAT in most homes so the Emperor
is naked there are no clothes how naked
well that is not security as I said it
is a stateful firewall conflated with
the address translation if you want to
have that protection there is no reason
you can't have a public address on one
side and multiple public addresses on
the other and get the same obscuring and
it will have the same painful debugging
it will have the same congestion issues
that will have the same denial of
service vulnerabilities all of the
breaking of end
and all of the other things we know in
love with nap so if you really feel that
experience is positive for you you can
create recreate all of that pain with a
stateful firewall without ever
implementing that but of course we we do
like to suffer I have a whole series of
things I call beer bets I bet a beer
that because there are people to have
security audit checklist that say do you
use nap and it's a box that says yes or
no and if you say no you fail your audit
there will be people particularly the US
government in DoD who will mandate nap
therefore even though the IETF has said
NAT 66 will not happen we will never do
it well if they don't what will happen
is the US government will wave a large
check and some vendor will go you betcha
like Cisco and they will write a gnat 6
its equivalent and juniper will write
one and everybody will write one and
they won't interoperate and they will
still suck but there will be not 66
whether we like it or not and there will
be people using stateful firewalls
because they do feel the need for that
protection and if you really feel the
need of having all of the rubs with non
unique addresses and address collision
potentially and not routable and having
to renumber if you need to get to the
internet all the stuff that happens with
19 18 spaces you can recreate all of
those particular problems by using ula
so the next marvelous thing the ITF
talked about mac addresses they felt
that mac addresses were fundamentally
evil because they were not pure they are
not always unique you can buy hardware
and you there are some scummy vendors
and we've all had them who will clone
the mac address across multiple boxes
and you're stuck you can change it and
software if you're not a nice person and
pretty much all of the OSS will do that
and if you have multiple interfaces on
the same box and you try and dhcp to the
same dhcp server whichever interface
gets there first wins so i can't get
multiple addresses on the same box
that's true what the IETF
didn't consider was that yes all of
those are flaws that are indeed part of
mac addresses but ninety-nine point nine
nine percent of the entire universe gets
on to the internet via either a service
provider or a company that uses DHCP and
uses mac address and the internet hasn't
stopped working as a matter of fact it
it keeps on going so obviously while it
is not perfect it seems like a pretty
workable solution for the vast majority
of the universe ah but the IETF knows
better than ninety-nine point nine nine
percent of the world so they came up
with the dhcp unique identifier and it
does have some things that are
definitely significantly better there is
one identifier / host either server or
client every network interface has an
identity association or IA that
identifies that particular network
interface that pairing therefore is
unique so i can do dhcp with the DUI pd
and an IA and get addresses and a
different interface on the same box will
have a different I a so the dhcp server
knows so we have solved the multiple
interface box problem and you can get
privacy addresses you can get regular
addresses ula dua you can even get
prefixes and entire subnet ranges the
problem of course is that an awful lot
of people don't just use that as the key
in the lease file they actually use it
for filtering of set-top boxes all sorts
of other things a lot of companies want
to be able to tell that Joe's laptop has
these like TV for ipv6 addresses in
their IP address management system if
you don't have the mac address anywhere
visible in the v6 address there's no way
of correlating those on the server side
at the moment though they are working on
that and persistent storage the way it
works is anything that is ISC based in
dhcp stores the duid the first time that
either you as a client asked for an
address or as a server come up and it
stores that in the leases file on the
disk
on the machine all of the windows
variants store it in registry where all
things are stored the nice thing is that
if i change hardware and i restore and
that's in persistent storage i come up
is the new machine it doesn't actually
use my mac address that's actually a
feature but I mighty I just got a new
laptop for my engineering department I
take the first one I install all the
software they're supposed to get I test
the hcp at st and s I do everything else
and I now know I have a working machine
now I now clone that across 11 other
machines and I didn't think to go should
I wipe the registry of the lease file
first I now have 12 machines with the
same duid and storage so going back to
why Mac is evil well multiple interfaces
has been solved but the other two
problems are not guaranteed unique can
be altered in software persistent
storage duid not guaranteed unique can
be altered in software so they have only
solved one third of the problems for a
fairly major paradigm shift and you
should know how people generated again
this is in the slides and they are
working on ways to correlate currently
there is a draft on the ITF that is
looking promising that will allow
hardware address to be put back into the
relay message if you go through DHCP
relay which realistically most large
organizations would do so that would
allow you to at least store that
information on the server the good sites
is that basically as long as Cisco
juniper and one or two other relay folks
update their really code which can be
done fairly quickly and ISC and
Microsoft put it in their servers it's
much faster than getting client OS
updates which is why they decided not to
fix it in the client the other thing is
if you are using the option 82 envy for
their options 17 and 30 something in v6
but circuit ID and remote ID and you're
using data your identification currently
through before that does work in v6 so
one of course one of the other questions
dhcp or not in it before there's pretty
much two ways of doing things you
statically configure or you enable dhcp
he in a configuration and it
automatically DHCP s the ITF wheel of
choices so in v6 well yes you can still
do static and I personally recommend
that for routers networking devices and
large servers that they be statically
configured things that don't change much
you need to be found easily there is the
big change stateless auto config slack
this is where the box comes up on the
wire and it actually figures out from
information on the network from the
local router how to configure itself and
i'll talk more about what's good and bad
about that stateless dhcp says i get my
address from the network via slack but i
will get certain information usually a
dns server via DHCP and then there's
state full HTTP which is the full dhcpv6
experience so slack uses ras router
advertisement messages what this means
that instead of having a centralized
solution where your DHCP servers for the
entire enterprise or a company are
usually a fairly finite number in a
fairly central location every single
router port on every VLAN and network
everywhere in your network that has any
end host now needs to be checked and
configured so we have pushed the network
policy which is effectively the security
policy because for most of us are IP
address is a poor but only security
token we have so now suddenly our
network in our security policy has been
pushed to every device everywhere in our
network and audits have gone from a few
dozen DHCP servers at a fairly large
company to possibly thousands or tens of
thousands of interface configuration
lines it does mean it's much more
resilient if there are fractures in your
network good and bad you know it's the
whole decentralized versus centralized
model things that are not in DNS or in
our a messages for quite a while you
couldn't get a recursive DNS server so
you can get up if you get a default
router you can get an address but you
didn't have dns well people pointed out
that was not exactly functional so
there's an RFC and most of the RAS now
do support this unfortunately there is
inconsistent client support
getting client OS is updated how many of
you still have 32-bit XP users running
around loose somewhere in your network
yeah so the idea that we can update our
clients so for robustness and
operational safety we pretty much must
use DHCP to give DNS even though this
options now they're now dhcp does some
cool stuff you can get public and
private address with privacy addresses
you can get all the things you normally
got you know remote DNS tftp vendor
options all the stuff that make those
hideous things like our phones and our
printers work you can even have the dhcp
server update for forward and reverse
pointers but big change here there is no
default route in the dhcp server you
must get the default route via our a
messages so what we're reduced to is you
know everybody used to classify this as
the slack folks versus the dhcp folks
there's no such thing slack won't work
without DHCP at least for DNS servers
and you don't even use DHCP until you're
told to by bits that are set in the RA
message so you will be running both
everywhere the way you're going to be
choosing in most cases if you are doing
some kind of access control or filtering
logging in any way updating an IP
address management system ipam any of
those things you're probably going to
need to use DHCP because you don't want
people just randomly doing their own
addresses because then you're the one
that's gotten bit by the brute force
scanning or you're logging into every
router and looking into its equivalent
of it's a fart cash all the time and
missing people so you probably don't
want anybody doing slack if you are
doing one of those if you are currently
updating on DNS from the dhcp server and
you find that more conveniently letting
the clients scribble in dynamic zones
themselves which most people don't do
other than absolutely pure microsoft
shops again that will be something
you'll probably consider and if you like
a more centralized method you are
running out of a central authority or
you have lots of different devices it's
not mostly laptops tablets smartphones
you
things like printers phones other things
that use thinner options all of those
are pretty much going to push you to
dhcp slack does have some distinct
advantages in certain areas we're not
utilizing it as much yet but in areas
where you truly don't care that's one of
them is but it's local and it's very
fast it doesn't require getting to a
DHCP server anywhere else it's also very
lightweight which means that people who
are writing embedded device stacks and
aren't going to use existing code
because they want it to be really small
to fit in a very small amount of flash
right code dhcp clients are really
hard dhcpv6 clients are really hard
slack is pretty straightforward so
things like remote devices or embedded
devices that are going to be popping up
and going away on our network
manufacturing line smart power sockets
and our kitchens things in our car that
tell the dealer that we need an oil
change all those kinds of things are far
more likely to use slack and also
because it is completely decentralized
as long as you can get to the local
router you're up and if you can't get to
the local router then it doesn't really
matter if you have an address or not and
again if you don't need any of the other
stuff with logging a ripe Famer or DNS
over work just great so look through
your priorities figure out which one is
more important to you one of the other
one wants this technical support staff
you know if you have a certain level of
technical expertise to maintain DHCP
that's fine if the staff is the local
barista at your coffee shop for the
wireless hotspot they can probably power
cycle the right box most of the time
slack is going to be a much more sane
configuration and then again are you
dealing with a lot of different gear and
a couple of examples this again it's in
the slides but there are bits the
address auto-configuration flag says
should i configure my own address or not
if it's zero it says don't configure
your own address o and M bit r OS other
configuration ms manage address that
means get all of my other configuration
via dhcp get an IP address from dhcp so
in this example what I'm saying is a is
0 don't auto configure anything yourself
oh NM get both your address and all of
your other configuration via dhcp that's
going to be as close as possible to the
current dhcp before the only thing
you'll be getting VRA would be default
route and then at the other end of the
spectrum if a is one that says do your
own address Oh other configuration get
something probably DNS via DHCP but
don't get an address everything comes in
the RA messages another interesting idea
that will be useful at some point in
time prefix delegation I can actually
instead of giving you a dress I can
actually give you a whole prefix and
then you can carve out chunks of that to
subordinate routers below you so you can
dynamically create a hierarchical
network topology the most common example
given of this is a home where you give
the home router of 56 and then you might
have a router that is in front of all of
your audio video gear you might have one
in front of your kitchen you might want
to have one in front of your home office
we're getting to that point where many
of us are actually doing things like qls
so there are kids streaming or playing
World of Warcraft does not ruin our
video conference we're not quite to the
point where that we're not flat space
but we'll get there potentially this is
very cool there are routers vendors and
service providers that are working
feverishly particularly comcast and
CableLabs to try and get workable
implementations of this there's an ietf
group home net but there are a lot of
technical challenges it is not yet there
I don't expect to see this in enterprise
or large network environments for a
while yet there's a lot of things to
shake out icmp in v4 if i filtered
everything my debugging is more
difficult but my network still mostly
works and we do have the security Nazis
who sit there and they say icmp oh it's
a security hole we're going to disable
it everywhere well you can do that in
ipv6 too however
unlike before if you do that one of the
things is you can't do duplicate address
detection so you have no way of dealing
with two hosts trying to use the same
address you have no way of finding
routers you have no way of getting
router advertisement messages you have
no way of finding servers for DHCP you
can't do path MTU discovery so you have
no way of knowing if the packets that
you sent out were discarded by someone
else because the size was bigger than
they could pass on and there are certain
other carers so if you don't care about
having a usable unique address don't
care about getting a default router
don't care about DNS and all the rest of
it and that's usable network to you
filter away if on the other hand you
might consider that to be kind of broken
even worse than a pipa kind of network
you're going to need to do things more
surgically RFC 4890 is an actual
operational recommendation best
practices RFC it is very well written
and it breaks things down into here's
the stuff that you better not filter
here's the stuff that you may want to
filter depending on what you're doing
here are some things that unless you
have a really good reason you probably
want to filter one of the other things
that has changed reverse pointers so a
little bit of history back in the dark
ages in the early 90s I was working at
then a small company called you net and
we were running a fairly large ftp
archive so was Washington University of
st. Louis so is deck and a few other
people and we allowed anonymous FTP and
we pretty regularly got pieces of email
or occasionally faxes explaining that
they had trouble getting to our
anonymous FTP server and that wasn't
working right and we got tired of
dealing with the stupidity so we decided
that we were going to have an
intelligence test and the intelligence
test was that if you could use VI and
edit a IP sick or you know inadar DARPA
file and get a delegation correctly and
get anything at all into
the bar data portion of one of those PTR
records you are obviously clued enough
that we were willing to respond to your
email let you get our software and if
you could not do that obviously you were
a walking you should just go away until
you learned um unfortunately then what
happened was we started going well gee
that did cut down some of our crap and
we got kind of tired of people with Q
mail particularly because usually they
couldn't get send mail working not being
able to exchange mail with us so he said
well let's give them the intelligence
test and this time around we're going to
say that the a and the PTR records have
to actually match each other and if they
don't match me to tell you go away
unfortunately it escaped the lab and has
been used on security and VPN collectors
and they're even certain websites these
days that actually look at it for things
like I think the New York Times is one
of them and so the answer is that
breaks if you don't have PTR records for
your users and since most of us can't
afford to staff for stupid calls we try
and be proactive and so we pre populate
and so how do we do it well occasionally
we did by hand but you know well 256
addresses wasn't that bad you know most
of us knew how do you do clever things
in VI and emacs some of us wrote shell
script perl scripts find of course came
up with dollar generate some people were
even using their own homegrown IP
address management systems what we did
was we pre populate everything we owned
and so everything had a point of record
whether it was used or not and then the
problem or away well for v6 so I've got
one subnet 64 18 quintillion possible
addresses so a PTR record is 34 labels
long and even if I'm generously assuming
that it's about 60 bytes in wire format
for the whole record and our data per
record 60 bytes x 18 quintillion which
is 4 billion times 4 billion anybody
here got a computer that has either that
much disk space or even less likely that
much ram to hold that particular zone
file
yeah yeah exactly this is the it defies
speed of light is is pretty much where
it gets too and that's 164 and you get
64,000 of those with a 48 so what do we
do well my personal vote is admit it was
a bad idea and like I said I was around
we were stupid and lazy we have lived
with it forever I apologize personally
that we just tried to get out of some
stupid emails because we have been
paying for it ever since unfortunately
the reality is that our users probably
won't let us because there are enough
things that are useful and of course
prix population well if we can exceed
speed of light we might figure out how
to do that but it's not likely what is
more likely is just like I recommend
static routing for things like your
router's your networking gear and your
large servers also by whatever means you
have your eye Pam system scripts
whatever pre-populate the reverse
pointers for all of those boxes so
things like trace route work so things
like your mail MTA is not blocked by
people all of those good things then
odds are for most people most of us are
using DHCP for most of our an toast and
transient hosts good Microsoft and ISC
will happily do zone updates or you can
let the client do it if you don't have
issues with that the last possibility is
that and when I was at ISC we had people
who requested this can I just say here's
the our data anytime somebody asks and
I'll just make it up give that lie on
the fly which works until you want to do
DNS SEC at which point you either break
because DNS SEC shows your line or you
have the choice of putting your secret
key out onto your public off server and
signing on the fly which is
computationally expensive and which is
an interesting self denial of service
vector um I suspect that vendors will be
doing lie on the fly and ignoring DNS
SEC for a long time pick your poison
right and as some people have also
pointed out in all of these there's
certainly ways of wild carding it if you
understand how DNS sex signing of wild
cards if I do all sorts of gobbledygook
dot mydomain.com I can actually sign it
so only mydomain.com is signed and I say
specifically only the last two labels
are actually signed and validated all
this other stuff may be there but i have
not certified that it's okay and my
guess is that very few people are doing
vini a sec validation and checking
anything other than they got the ad bit
set so you could probably get away with
that too but so standards we love them
we love them so much that we just can't
stop making them there are currently
over 200 active and current RFC's
relating to ipv6 and dhcpv6 there are
closer to 250 active drafts in the ITF
that are not yet rfcs that are being
worked on there are at least a half
dozen to a dozen new ones added every
single ITF and they meet three times a
year simple stupid math says gee okay
that means we're less than half done not
quite that bad but there are an awful
lot of operational issues things like
the fact that most of us need a mac
address not as the database key and dhcp
but to correlate before in v6 addresses
another interesting thing for which
there is a draft right now and nobody
has a good answer I am a dual stack
toast and I am a multiple interface
house I'm a pretty typical laptop so I
dhcp be 4i get v4 addresses and maybe my
dhcp server gives me dns servers I DHCP
for two of my interfaces in v6 and I get
addresses maybe I get two more sets of
DNS servers I is the client OS what do i
do first one wins last one wins combine
them all if I combine them all how do I
sort them OS vendors come to the ITF and
say what should we do and
the IHS says that's an operational issue
well yes it is um but most of us I think
would realize having seen what happened
with happy eyeballs and all of the
different versions that all the
different browsers did that it would be
so much better if all vos vendors had a
single way that they could all agree
that they would take all of the stuff
and stick it in so that you knew what
your etsy resolv.conf would be and not
have to know what every single version
of every operating system did
differently so um yeah I know it's I
have carried a pager for an actual 15
real years of time in my life which
means that I don't like problems like
this because they mean I get paid your
calls so that's usually mine one of the
things that I do push on is because of
that and the fact that there are a whole
series of other operational issues the
IETF when you first show up if you're a
vendor they will really beat you
senseless because obviously vendors are
all evil but even if you're not a vendor
but you were an operational guy that
will sit there and go oh well you know
you operational guys you know if you
were really clever you'd be writing
protocols you have to sort of get past
that one and just keep working with them
because they do eventually start
listening and if we all go away and let
them do whatever they think with no
connection to the reality we all live in
we will be living with their decisions
and if we don't say it it's like voting
if you don't vote you don't get to whine
well you do get to wine but it's not
legit and so we need to vote we need to
actually send folks there and if you
can't convince your boss to go you
should definitely be making sure that
all the vendors you buy gear from send
people and that should be one of your
questions do you participate in the IETF
actively do you send people to every
meeting do you work on the standards do
you keep track do you know what's coming
down the pike because with v6 we have
another couple of years of these drafts
coming through and changing
and the last thing is that because of
the fact that a lot of this the ITF
somewhat legitimately is now reacting
when someone comes in and says gee this
doesn't work with my network it doesn't
work my provisioning system we need this
new thing the ITF says well gee you know
we've been working on this for the last
seven or eight years where were you why
should we listen to you why don't you do
things the way we figured them out okay
to some degree that's legit because they
have already gone through stuff like no
default route in dhcp it's probably dead
it has been beaten so bloody at this
point that no one is going to stick
their head up and say what do we do but
the reality is is that some people have
worked around it John brofsky at comcast
went to the ITF the IETF said that's
stupid dhcp sucks this is all stupid mac
addresses are broken get over it and so
john said well i have customers i need
to get this working so he went to docsis
because he said the ITF hey can you put
this mender options they said oh yeah
you could put any you want vendor
options that's what they're for you know
have a field they have your vendor get a
number of we don't care what you put in
there so he said great he went to the
doc says folks and he got standards done
and they are now rolling out things that
use the bender options and use docsis
three and it works and it works for
comcast and all the vendors they work
with well there are now other folks
other ISPs and broadband ISPs who have
been coming in and saying well we don't
do it that way that breaks our whole
provisioning model we needed a change
and John quite legitimately says well
you know I've been beating myself
senseless for years now where were you
show up and pick what's important
because you can't fix everything so
that's a quick blast through yes
yessum it yes yes and yes for the folks
that didn't hear um yes you don't have
to go to the meeting showing up on the
working group mailing lists is showing
up and much of the work is done there
and they have video casts and you can
mail stuff to the working group chairs
and let them know your vote on things
that are being discussed you can be a
full and useful participant without ever
physically showing up yeah they're there
they are very good at at all of the
normal they have chat they have jabbered
they have video cast they have email so
there are a lot of ways to participate
because yeah they it's all over the
world it's expensive this is the first
job I've ever had where I have been sent
every ITF and not work for someone like
a mega left like Cisco so I went through
it quickly because I figure they're
probably a lot of questions on things
that you have dealt with or wandering on
holes and you know gee we do it this way
is that going to work and b6 so if you
want to go ahead and step the microphone
and ask away yeah this will be a fun one
high lifes lawyer from Alaska and pretty
much it displays everything so I i work
for a telecommunications company up
there a three-letter one and i'm in a
proponent of ipv6 for probably the last
12 years there and in trying to get the
the company to start looking at ipv6
internally you know work with the IT
system architect and we have to follow
pci guidelines so they want net mm-hm
and so when I said well give me a
proposal for what your plans for ipv6
rollout would include and so their site
local addresses and locate yeah and I
look at it and I'm wondering why are
we allowing that kind of thing to
propagate because it just breaks so many
different things within a large business
and I'm looking I guess for for help and
how I can combat that Matt right so
there are several pieces all right right
so one of them site local has been
deprecated if you want to use 1918 now
use unique local that was another one of
the unique local was supposed to be
within one area site local was supposed
to be across an entire enterprise but
they can never define what site meant so
they gave up as far as the nap yes that
is the reality that's like I said wine
at 66 or some equivalent will happen but
the reality is is the security peace
that they are looking for actually is
the stateful firewall so my reaction is
normally use gusa for everything and go
through and then use stateful firewall
there are however NAT solutions out
there including quote unquote
carrier-grade nap that are certainly
functional if you want to spend that
kind of money there are things that will
function for those and ula isn't
horrible I I look at things like 19 18
addresses and views in DNS and certain
other things as it's your absolute last
choice after you've exhausted all other
possible more sane and more scalable and
more supportable technical solutions if
what is left is that then implement it
but you should have exhausted all other
Possible's first unfortunately when you
get into blind compliance rules where
it's a check box where you say yes or no
if you say no you fail we have a lot
less flexibility and so I suspect that
you will be one of those lucky people
rolling out a nap 66 yeah which which
makes me cringe but unfortunately and I
suspect that PCI and hip and a few other
people that blindly go through but
what's your take so first of all pc i
actually does provide for you you don't
have to use that if you can show that
you've got equivalent
security right which are the stateful
firewall is and the stateful firewall
qualifies for that and about forty
percent of the PCI auditors have now
been large to the point of being clue
fool enough to understand that better
than what I used to do it okay that's
good to hear the other the other sixty
percent still need large large supplied
please do so repeatedly if you want help
with ammunition Scott hogue and I
recently wrote a blog post that's up on
the Infoblox ipv6 center of excellence
discussing why you know you can get an
ad in ipv6 if you really determined to
do bad things to your network but you
probably don't actually want to yeah
naps are not good Nats are not helpful
Nats are just damaged yes well as let's
not add them to v6 please thank you very
much yeah London if you were here for
that section with the slides that nat
die die die was my intro slide so it
sort of gives my opinion on what we
should be doing with it but there are
certain realities there a whole series
of education things including also how
do I justify you know so it makes my
network more expensive it makes my
network more brittle X but I expend all
this more money and it doesn't get me
anything better that's another one of
those how to yeah right exactly and so
how do I justify spending for ipv6 um
it's another one of the common questions
but go ahead my name is Andrew Sullivan
and I am a protocol weenie and I just
want to say in line with this NAT 66
stuff and the other vendor thing you are
mentioning a minute ago be careful what
you wish for here there are lots of
vendors who want to sell this crap and
so part of a call for participation is
both you know towards the auditing types
and towards the standards people we need
real operators who are really there
saying no this is a stupid idea the
first time we're certainly not going to
do it now when we got all this address
space it's it's super critical on this
issue we got to get real operators in
the room yes and and along those lines
where I was talking about carrier-grade
NAT one of the things that a lot of
those folks are now pushing is well you
get v6 native and you let that go out
and all of your v4 stuff will get
carrier-grade matted and they say well
hey it works for LTE and cellular and
and i have several responses one of them
is yes it works for a certain valor
value if you want to keep giving someone
like Huawei or Cisco insane numbers of
dollars forever because they are
certainly happy to keep selling you
hardware forever the other thing is that
yes currently forty percent of all
Verizon traffic is v6 native and
twenty-five percent of AT&T is v6 native
and they are hoping that continues
because they are using carrier-grade NAT
for the other piece of it so far there
are several reasons why they have not
gotten caught one of them is that the
handsets are not yet using enough
data-intensive applications to make it
immediately noticeable most users are
not sophisticated enough to know that
it's a v4 site that I'm going to this
slow and a v6 site that's fast our
expectation is if something sucks its
cellular because cellular performance is
uneven in sucks so they have not yet
gotten caught the fact that there are
worthy six things out there means they
may actually win the battle because
essentially what they are betting is
that they will offload enough of it
tuned v6 native before their see GM's
run out of steam but there are a few
interesting twists the user population
that is sophisticated enough to notice
this and will blast it everywhere in the
world our world of warcraft guys and
when we get to the point where there's a
decent iPad app that actually works and
they don't get killed using it and they
start using it and they notice v6 is
snappy and before sucks on their
cellular plan they have all sorts of
network tools and they they are honored
how many viewer actually backbone
operators here yeah is it not true that
the most effective jitter measurement
that you have in the world are online
gamers yeah they notice anything in your
network way faster than any other knock
tool you've ever had right so those will
guys will start noticing so we will
start cashing up on those debts and
carrier-grade NAT is indeed a myth it is
not carrier-grade it is massively over
engineered to mostly survive in many
cases and there are other little things
that I don't think they've thought out
the fact that they still have to do
every
thing with address and port and that
means for everyone public address on
there you can get 64,000 simultaneous
connections well the reality is is
that's not a person anymore even a
household these days most browsers will
have 10 concurrent sessions to parallel
download if I'm at a house it's pretty
common to have three smartphones in two
iPads in an awful lot of houses right
now all of which are acting like
browsers so my guess is we're going to
get to the point where realistically you
could probably have one to two thousand
homes for public address and v4 space is
getting ugly right just ran out
September 17th ap Nick is already out so
getting more space is going to be
punitive Lee expensive as well so
getting enough address space on the
public side to actually not a big enough
pool if you want to be a new business
it's becoming more and more of a dummies
debt so all of these are pushing through
the good news if is that the fact that
there is forty percent of Verizon and
twenty-five percent of ATT and that was
as of jun is probably increased again
means that there is actually more usable
useful interesting content than ever
available on d6 and more providers are
putting on real backbones and unreal
hardware and gear parody has been equal
for a long while backbone latency
performance has not been equal for many
of us for a long time that is evening
out and the real growth pcs and
traditional computers are going up but
they're going up at a fairly predictable
rate where you're seeing the truly
logarithmic increases in number of
handsets are smartphones and tablets all
of which are going Wireless all of which
are going v6 native so more and more of
the users are going to get a better
experience with v6 and that's part of
that business case also why should I
well because your users will have a
better experience faster because more
and more of your users are going to be
using this mobile devices
yes yes and in latnok and AfriNIC where
it's cheaper to do wireless and cellular
because there is no existing
infrastructure to upgrade or that they
have to amortize over ten years to pay
off so more and more of that is
happening over these new technologies so
v6 is not becoming more prevalent so
much as the growing technologies are
outstripping the address space faster
than v4 can be cobbled and duct-taped
together other questions ok if you have
anything else slides are up my emails on
the slides or find me here at nanog be
happy to talk more with you and thank
you very much
oh yeah exactly yes they are well there
are a lot of things where the lawyers
and the accountants do the it's easier
to be in non-compliance or to be
non-compliance than to do the right
thing which I hate but is indeed
economic reality so forty percent of
bandwidth if you look bad yet good
friend of wireless yes good yeah God
yeah Bryson's landline don't have you
get it started um if you go to the idea
they have a role that since its launch
and their slides with presentation yeah
I'm seeing that a lot of places where
you're getting too yeah