all right so I know that the focus of
this conference is on the the junior
leaders but we were super fortunate also
to get General vile and general Stanton
to come in for this
um two of the most passionate General
officers I know in cyber
um so General vile is the um the Cyber
commandant uh the fifth cyber commandant
and uh he is
right right here okay so
um he'll be coming up to give us a
speech and a talk and a motivating
speech to to get us ready for for this
conference so with that we'll bring him
up
[Applause]
all right check in all right outstanding
hey good morning hey so there's one one
group in here that actually hasn't been
applauded for and so that's all the
cadets that have successfully branched
Library one of the most selective
branches in the United States Army so
give it up for yourselves and give it up
for all the future cyber lieutenants
now I I do want to be 100 clear so I
went infantry uh so I know the guy that
was last he was number 173 out of 173
that got infantry my year he is now a
general officer so there's hope for all
of you uh don't worry about it if you
were at the bottom of that list uh so
I'm proof and number 173 is proof as
well
so really what I want to talk to you
today
next slide
we're trying to get the technology work
all right here we go okay what is the
Cyber Corps what is it that we do why is
it important and then for you well who
are we what do we want to be when we
grow up now the way for me to do this
what I'm going to have to talk about is
I'm going to go through the entire
history of warfare now to be fair Brian
vile got a C in military history so some
of the facts in here might be a little
bit shaky but that's okay you know
nobody's going to question me today it's
a beautiful thing
so in a in a place far far away and in
time long long ago
next slide there we go
in infantryman name Kane took his
bayonet inserted it between the second
and third rib of a man named Mabel
twisted and in PB came
the first infantryman and so began the
beginning of warfare and way back then
in the beginning of warfare you know it
was just one-on-one well what ended up
happening was we very rapidly decided
the upscale operations and so now
instead of man on man instead of
individual combat which you had was
armies you had large groups of people
and the challenge that quickly arose for
the commanders on the battlefield was
how do you command and control this how
do you give guidance and direction to
the soldiers on the field
and if you think about it we didn't have
cell phones what did they use they used
horns they used bugle calls they use
guidance they use colors they use
standards
and why did they do this because the
commander visually had the look and he
had to see what was going on on the
battlefield you had to wear colorful
uniform so you could understand who was
yours who was the adversary and even
with your own formations where were the
officers where were the Infantry where
were the dragoons because they all
served different purposes and the only
way to effectively command and control
was visually
and you needed these guidance you needed
these standards and you needed something
called a runner in order to go out and
deliver messages on the battlefield you
know we wanted the questions last night
you know who here's run a marathon what
was the guy that ran the marathon why
did he run the marathon it was a
military messenger and so always from
the beginning the military has had this
challenge of command and control on the
battlefield
now time went on and on and then
eventually we hit the Civil War
and during the Civil War and this gets
back to the importance of academics
within our branch in particular Dr major
Albert Meyer he stood up the signal
Corps and for the Union forces on the
battlefield they did have telegraphs you
know but you had to physically spool the
wire the wire would break the batteries
were unreliable so generally you were
mostly using these four strategic and
operational level messaging you know
because this is infrastructure this is
difficult to run particularly in combat
particularly on a fluid Battlefield and
so what he developed was the wig wags so
if you've ever seen or you know somebody
from The Signal Court those aren't
semaphores that they're wearing they're
actually called wig wags and it was
developed by a union officer and the
ability to communicate on the
battlefield was one of the things that
gave the Union Army The Edge over the
Confederates during the Civil War
was it ideal no did it work in in during
that time absolutely it was the best
thing that we had
so history goes on and we hit this thing
called The Second Industrial Revolution
the first Industrial Revolution was the
steam engine Second Industrial
revolutions really what led us into
modern warfare it brought us the
internal combustion engine which allowed
for tanks it brought us machine guns it
brought us Mass manufacture of Munitions
it bought us smokeless powder
it's what brought us Aviation 1903 with
the Wright brothers the first casualty
in an aircraft was actually an army
officer an army signal officer at that
and it was advances in field or
artillery the Chinese may have invented
gunpowder but it was the French that
designed a recoilless Canon that you
could fire on the battlefield and didn't
have to fully reset every time
and so all the trappings of what we now
know as Modern Warfare really most of
them came immediately out of that Second
Industrial Revolution it was a huge
watershed moment
but what about Communications
so the challenge was
modern Communications words and in its
infancy
had we figured out radio had Marconi
figured out radio yeah he had figured it
out but the original radios when they
put them on an aircraft in 1913 had a
range of 2 000 yards two clicks
not particularly effective on the
battlefield
so what did we end up using on the
battlefield and you'll see some of the
pictures up there up in the top left
that's guys just carrying big spools of
wire now the important thing to
understand about this wire is it was
wrapped in natural rubber called
gutta-percha and it just it was made by
the lowest bidder it would break all the
time and artillery foot traffic Soldier
Falls he grabs it it wouldn't break the
telegraphs would work when the wires
were there but what's the challenge
batteries there's no two 110 220 volt up
on the front lines batteries were
unreliable stuff didn't work and oh by
the way the trenches were covered in mud
and muck and everything else so all the
Technical Solutions generally didn't
work very well particularly going into
the first World War
so what did they use for Reliable
Communications
they use carrier pigeons that literally
is a carrier pigeon being released from
the inside of a tank in order to tell
the commander where they're at they use
dogs
they would put a message in a little box
around the around its neck and send it
back and hopefully it didn't run away
hopefully it didn't kill it get killed
and hopefully it would bring the message
back
and they also used Runners Runners were
an incredibly dangerous profession
because what they had to do was
negotiate the trench line from the rear
areas all the way to the front in order
to carry a message
so as we roll into World War One all the
trappings of Modern Warfare are there
with the exception of communications it
just hadn't matured to that point
so World War One kicks off the British
get involved next slide
and the British decide they need the
relief pressure on the French at the
Battle of Verdun so in 1916 the British
decide they're going to launch a massive
offensive and it was called the battle
of the song
and what they decided to do was
something slightly different
they wanted to innovate
and so they saw the problem they saw the
problem with command and control so once
you went into No Man's Land once you
crossed the barbed wire in between the
trench lines you had no Communications
who here wants to be laying in mud
writing a small message to tie to a
carrier pigeon's leg to send back and
who wants to be the runner that has to
stand up and literally run back under
machine gun fire with a message
so the British knew this they had seen
the French failures of Communications on
the front line and so what the french
this or what the British decided to do
was they were going to do something
called a creeping barrage
so what's a creeping barrage so all
creeping barrages you drop artillery on
the enemy and then what happens is it
shifts back the Infantry moves forward
takes the terrain once they hold the
terrain the artillery shifts again
infantry moves forward so you're
basically slowly moving the artillery in
front of your forces in order to
maintain cover
now what was the challenge with the
creeping barrage you still had command
and control difficulties
how do you know that the Infantry
actually secured the first line of
trenches
and if you shifted the artillery too far
behind the Infantry what would happen is
they would lose all of their support and
then the Germans and the reserve
trenches would be able to come forward
counter-attack and seize the terrain
the British knew this so they put lots
of time and lots of effort into trying
to develop a finely synchronized battle
plan for the battle of the psalm where
they would be able to seize the German
trenches
so before this what the British did is
they hammered the Germans it was
originally planned for six days there
was a day of rain so they ended up Seven
Days Seven Days the king of battle
hammered the German front lines some of
the British commanders were told the
Germans will be dead you'll be able to
walk across that sling arms at no man's
land what they didn't plan for was the
fact that the German were actually in
concrete bunkers that artillery actually
is not particularly effective against
Duggan troops and that all of that rain
and all the artillery had turned No
Man's Land into a swamp it was flooded
concertina wire was everywhere barbed
wire was everywhere and again the German
were still alive in their dugouts
so what happened what were the command
and control tools that they used it's
actually very simple
the British officers had a watch that
was synchronized and Lieutenant vile did
the same thing we would synchronize our
watches to make sure we were all on the
same time
and then at the anointed hour Zero 7 30
on July 1st the British officers blew
their whistles
the British infantry got up out of the
trenches and charged towards across no
man land towards the German front lines
for the first round at zero seven thirty
the artillery shifted rearward to the
German rear trenches
what happened
well what happened was when the British
left the trenches the Germans heard that
the artillery had shifted behind them
they got their machine guns got up into
their fighting positions what was left
of them and they started hosing down the
British
so literally on the first set of trench
lines this beautifully well-crafted plan
based on assumptions of forward progress
got thrown into the Four Winds
and what did the artillery continue to
do according to the timetable because of
lack of communications it continued to
shift behind and relax the pressure on
the Germans who were able to reinforce
the front line and roll back most of the
successes
so for lack of command and control for
lack of communications
what was the reason
this is day one of the battle of the
song
the British lost more killed in one day
than we have lost in 20 years in Iraq
and Afghanistan
process that and then remember how small
of a country Great Britain is and then
how much smaller it was back then
compared to today
17 19
000 killed
most in the first few minutes of the
attack and for what very limited gains
so why it was an inability of the
commanders to leverage the information
that was on the battlefield they didn't
know where they were successful they
didn't know where they were failing they
lacked the communication they lacked the
information
in order to be successful
it wasn't their fault they did the best
they could but the communications
technology just wasn't there
so after World War one we roll in the
World War II believe it or not a
standard issue for Signal Corps in World
War II two still included wigwag flags
and carrier pigeons okay go to the next
slide
uh but somewhere in the middle of there
in 1947 bonus points who can identify
what that is
that is the first transistor developed
by Bell labs in 1947.
things started to change technology
started to change
and what ended up happening was the
military started integrating it into
every system
so now what we had going through the 50s
going through the 60s going through the
70s what we had for the first time is we
had weapons that were no longer
traditionally fused we had weapons where
we could program them where we could
guide them where we could Target them
where we could use the EMS the
electromagnetic spectrum in order to
deliver effects on the target
and then what happened
the internet the world wide web and yes
that is actually the original symbol for
the world wide web and oh by the way
this is the year I started at this fine
institution of learning
okay and so what did this launch in 1990
it launched the internet it launched
what you all grew up with it launched
what I had to learn the hard way as an
old person okay Facebook Amazon the
cloud all of that was launched in 1990
with the beginning of the World Wide Web
phenomenal and what this really did is
it allowed anyone anywhere in the world
to access information
you guys have no idea how good it is to
not have to go to the library and try to
check out a book that it turns out
somebody else checked out never returned
two months ago because you can Google it
you can find it
huge massive you know uh just the
ability to get that information
and as we're going through and in the
middle of this something happens 9 11.
and in 2001 we began the war in
Afghanistan and in 2003 we began the war
in Iraq
so one parallel pass you had a military
that was already using the
electromagnetic spectrum that now sees
the capabilities that cyberspace can
provide in the ability to move
information and we're fighting two Wars
for over 20 years
so what did we learn in fighting in Iraq
and Afghanistan
first
the EMS the electromagnetic spectrum
this is how you connect devices this is
how you communicate your cell phones
how is that communicating there's no
wires it's using the electromagnetic
spectrum in order to communicate
and then what's it doing what on that
physical layer for those that know the
OSI model layer one physical that's the
EMS
what's it doing it's passing information
and so when the wars in Iraq and
Afghanistan what we were able to do was
take National level assets things that
company commanders Battalion commanders
Brigade commanders division commanders
never would have imagined having seen
when Brian vile was a lieutenant you
were able to push information down to
the lowest level you knew where they
were you knew what they were saying and
you knew how to go after them
the EMS and cyberspace absolutely
drove any of the successes in Iraq and
Afghanistan
but there's one caveat to it
it was an uncontested environment
believe it or not I am not aware of any
Taliban hackers that delivered a cyber
effect
I don't remember them ever attempting
any jamming activities other than
blowing up cell phone towers
this was uncontested we were able to
fight in the electromagnetic spectrum
and in cyberspace
without a threat without an adversary
and what was happening while we were in
Iraq and Afghanistan was our adversaries
were paying attention
they were watching us learn those
lessons and what they ended up doing is
they integrated it into their own
militaries
the Chinese have significant em uh ew
electromagnetic Warfare capabilities the
Russians have significant mostly had now
uh had significant electromagnetic
Warfare capabilities and they both have
incredible cyber actors you know
malicious cyber actors that are able to
go out and through cyberspace deliver
effects
they know it and they've been planning
for it go back up one
and
they're ready for and I will tell you
that win or lose the next large-scale
contingency operation
it's going to be determined by who
fights and wins in cyberspace in the
electromagnetic spectrum
who can fight and win in those domains
okay go next slide so I'm going to hit
polls on the history lesson and then
what we're going to do is we're going to
talk about the role of the Cyber Corps
I'm going to go into something called
fm3o you all get a little bit of this
and talk a little bit about multi-domain
operations
so what you see on the slide aligned
across the top is what we call you know
the Continuum of conflict on the far
left of the chart this is peace this is
zolinsky and Putin hugging their
differences out over a cold one you know
we don't need militaries so on the far
right that's thermonuclear conflict you
know the worst conflict that you could
imagine and then somewhere in the middle
is what we call crisis this is where a
soldier rotates their selector switch
from safe to semi and squeezes the
trigger and now we are in Conflict
flicked now lives are at risk people are
dying whether there are or whether
they're somebody else's
it's a gray area in there when that
begins when that ends
but competition is where we spend most
of our time in the whole goal of
competition is to avoid going into
conflict
now off on the left for those that know
the Snowman model strategic operational
tactical the new doctrine it actually
has strategic National level which is
POTUS and then it has strategic theater
level which are your Geographic combat
commands southcom northcom ucom
Indo Paycom
and so this is really the chart that FM
30s built so why do I bring this up go
ahead and go first bill
so what does our branch do within this
construct
so our 17 alphas and our 17 Charlies and
our 170 Alphas
they fight to win in cyberspace in
competition to prevent us for ever
having to go to conflict if you think
about what almost all of your peers are
going to do when they get commissioned
it's fairly useless until we roll into
conflict
what can you do with a tank to deter the
Russians you can do live fire exercises
with the poles on the border we've
called it saber rattling is it a fix is
it effective
that's Up For Debate
but what we do is we are able to go and
reach out through cyberspace and deliver
effects against our adversaries in order
to keep us in competition
so our offensive forces at the Strategic
National level are fighting every day
everywhere and always in the fight
to fight and win
are dco forces are defensive cyberspace
Operation Forces are protecting our
cyberspace capabilities making sure that
the adversary doesn't think he can gain
the upper hand by bringing down our
computers by bringing down our networks
by bringing down our weapon systems
this is the fight that's going on today
this is the fight that many of you will
be given the opportunity to join
now the reality is can cyber keep us in
competition the answer is no Putin was
going to role in the Ukraine regardless
of what had happened and sometimes
conflict isn't inevitable
and when they bring it to us the reality
is you'll see dco and Oco Peak right
around that crisis line and then it's
going to taper off most of the easy
targets will be taken down most of the
accesses will be burned most of the
effects will be delivered
and then we roll into conflict
so what does our branch do for conflict
so with the operational and the Tactical
levels what we do is three different
things this is all generally the three
divisions of electromagnetic Warfare
first early on in competition
what are cyber branches doing through
our 17 Bravos or 170 Bravos and our 17
Echoes is they are ensuring that the
commander knows what his signature is in
the electromagnetic spectrum
for those of us that fault well deployed
I will tell you I never saw a radio on
anything other than high power
I can also tell you that in some
theaters of conflict that cueing the mic
on a military handset will get you to
receive artillery within five to eight
minutes
so telling commanders what their
signature is making sure they know how
they stick out
in the electromagnetic spectrum make
sure they train that way is a huge part
of what our Branch does
now as we inch closer the conflict we'll
start doing electromagnetic support
simply put this is targeting this isn't
intelligence work this is targeting what
we do is we get a couple of lobs lines
of bearings and once you have three of
them you have what's called a fix and so
that is a target that you can shoot and
the really cool thing about modern
electromagnetic support is that based on
the signals you are seeing you can
identify what system it is
so you can make sure that when you fire
your high dollar high cost weapons or
you commit U.S lives to the battlefield
that they're going after something
that's worth it
and then as we roll into conflict
what our 17 Bravos and our 17 Echoes do
is we do electromagnetic attack
this can be Brute Force jamming just
crank it up to 11 tape down the mic or
it can be a delivery of special purpose
electromagnetic attacks special purpose
EA we call it
this is finally crafted signals that's
grew with the threat systems at the
protocol level
these are the capabilities that are 17
DS our capability developers build
and they are delivered by our soldiers
so to wrap this all together you know
and to give you guys the elevator speech
regardless of where you end up with or
where you end up at in the cyber force
you need to know what the branch does so
my ask is when somebody asks you what
cyber does
answer for the branch first and then
tell them what you do
and what does the branch do
in competition we fight and win in
cyberspace to prevent us from having to
go to conflict
failing that when we roll in to conflict
we force the adversary to fight
like it's World War one we push them
back to carrier pigeons runner on foot
and dogs we shut down all their modern
Communications we shut down their
equipment this is what our Branch does
this is what you all are tasked to do
and if you think about it we are what is
different from combat a hundred years
ago to combat today
it's the EMS and cyberspace that knitted
all together that give the commander the
information to make smart decisions
at every Echelon and it's our job to
protect that capability and to deny our
adversaries from ever being able to use
it against U.S citizens
so what does this mean for you this is
the third question and the last question
so who are we
who's in this room
and I think it's better to talk from who
are our soldiers go go the next slide
so this is relatively new data six
months ago the numbers were actually
different
these are the soldiers you're going to
be tasked to lead
your average soldier in AIT
is 25 years old
one out of four already has a bachelor's
degree not some college not an associate
history one out of four enlisted cyber
soldiers newly enlisted already has a
bachelor's degree average GT score 119.
and anecdotally I will tell you that we
have the feedback we get from cctc it's
our common cyber core you all get to go
through it
the enlisted consistently complain that
it's too easy
the officers I am standing up a tutoring
session
because many of them are challenged and
they say it's too hard
these are the soldiers you're being
given the opportunity to lead
this is I I cannot State I cannot
emphasize enough how jealous I am of you
all in this room I'm closer to the end
of my career than the beginning you guys
are just getting started and I will tell
you that the Cyber soldiers of today
are a far cry from the Cyber soldiers
that I was given the opportunity to lead
they were great Americans these guys are
top-notch and so what you're going to
have to do is you're going to have to
lead these soldiers and it's going to
require you for you to have the same
technical understanding that they have
in order to give them appropriate
guidance and direction
you will be solving some of the most
technically demanding tasks that are out
there there are no easy problems in
cyber we've already solved all those
we need your generation to grab the
reins and to solve the hard problems and
to lead our soldiers in that fight
and they are incredible
guys truly the future is bright
I look out at you guys you know it
really does bring a little tear to my
eye
you know wishing I was in your seat
instead of where I'm at I'm at the
Tailwind
so ladies and gentlemen congratulations
welcome to cyber branch
[Applause]
all right thank you General vile sir if
you could come up real quick
we really appreciate your talk and just
want to give you a token of our
appreciation as well thanks
[Applause]