all right good evening everyone
all right so you can continue to eat
your cheesecake as delicious cheesecake
as many of you have already noticed but
we're going to go ahead and go move on
to the next uh part of this evening the
last speaker for today
and um
I'd like to introduce them so
[Music]
um
Major General Paul Stanton assumed
duties as a Commanding General of the
U.S army cyber center of excellence in
Fort Gordon on 30 June 2021 after
serving as a deputy Commanding General
U.S army cyber command at Fort Gordon
Georgia he graduated from this
institution West Point in 1995 and was
commissioned into the Infantry he
transitioned into the Cyber branch in
2015.
um
he's earned three degrees in computer
science a bachelor's degree from the
United States Military Academy at West
Point a master's degree for the United
University of Illinois and a doctorate
from the Johns Hopkins University
now I'd like to just give a personal
note here about
General Stanton when I was at
Fort Meade uh I I knew of of major Paul
Stanton at the time because I think he
was he taught here in eeks as one of his
assignments and uh and I go over there
and um there's one one day I went to his
office I think I was actually walking
with him up there and I I normally take
the elevators but I learned quickly that
uh
uh Joe Stanton does not like elevators
very much so um we quickly double timed
it up to the fourth floor in Ops 2B I
think and uh he looked at me and said
something like um wow we just got like a
free workout and I was like I've never
thought of it that way but that is one
way to think of it so next time you go
up the stairs you're getting a free
workout
um so we we had a discussion at one
point about
um you know what we're going to be doing
in the Army I think he was a lieutenant
colonel at the time and then uh he uh he
and I discussed I said well I'm thinking
about going back to teach at West Point
but I haven't found a graduate school
he's like oh he's like what are you
think you're doing I was like I don't
know like data stuff visual
um stuff he's like oh you got to meet
this guy Randall and I was like I don't
know who Randall is so we um uh went and
had Vietnamese food I think down in DC
and and I met Randall Burns Dr Randall
Burns who was a Johns Hopkins computer
scientist and uh and sure enough that's
how I met my PhD advisor now what I I
remember going home thinking you know I
could do this I told my wife this is
going to suck I mean there's no doubt in
my mind that following in in Colonel
Stanton's shoes of trying to do a
computer science PhD on an army timeline
is probably uh is probably going to be
rough so um fast forward a few years
later I'm sitting in a hackerman hall
and there was the computer science
chair came out and said you know we've
got a problem it takes about six and 6.7
years to graduate a computer science PhD
at Johns Hopkins and that's just too
long
and so I'm looking there and I'm sitting
next to Randall burns my advisor
and as as we looked at this chart it has
all the people that were at the six year
mark But as we go to the left there's
this one dot
and it it was three years and he's like
that's Paul Stanton
and I was like holy crap
so
um with that
I'll I'll pass it over to General
Stanton who is the first as far as I can
tell Johns Hopkins graduate of computer
science and the Whiting School of
Engineering that could pull it off in
three years so
thanks sir I appreciate it
[Applause]
thanks Steven okay yes I am definitely
miked up because my voice is not that
loud I'm not going to get on the stage
because I'm told that I have to stay
within the bounds of the speakers but
I'm gonna just float around a little bit
um I did not know that story I
appreciate you embarrassing me if I
don't know if my my face is red or not
um but uh
Colonel Hamilton and I are we do have
some history and when he sent me a note
a couple months ago and said we're
looking for a keynote speaker at our at
our conference here's what the audience
is here's what the class of 1970 has set
up
um do you think you have time
no but I'll make it
because it's that important to have an
opportunity to to talk to this amazing
group of current and Future Leaders
so let me first say thank you to the
class of 1970 to Mr John Collins uh and
and uh Mr Frank Monaco uh Colonel
retired Frank Monaco his son and I went
to high school together and you know
there's like six degrees of separation
for all you data scientists out there
right
um that uh that we we've had an
enjoyable dinner catching up but thank
you to the class of 1974
the concept
of putting an entire cohort
of our cyber leaders in one room
and yes we can include our midshipmen
yeah because they are valuable members
of the team you heard about five times
today that cyber is the ultimate team
sport you're going to hear me say it
probably about five or six more times
during the course of the next half hour
or so
let me say thank you to the Army cyber
Institute for putting this together
a lot of thought time and energy goes
into the coordination
things like doing an icebreaker last
night
and then when I walked up and did a
quick discussion with many of you
through the course of the day you were
talking to people that you had just met
that's huge part of the point
because this absolutely
is a team sport
because what we do is so challenging
there's absolutely no way that you can
be the expert in all of it
you have to be good
but you can't be the expert in
everything that we need our cyber forces
to understand and know how to execute
the folks that are in this room
your cohort
will be your friends and your colleagues
for the rest of your lives
whether you stay in uniform or not
because the bonds that you make
through the challenges that you'll face
you'll learn how to depend on each other
in very powerful ways
and God forbid
we need you to do it in combat
that bond is Unbreakable
so you're in a powerful setting that is
setting the conditions
for your future
in uniform and out
quick thank you to the officers that are
in the room with us tonight
you start to really date yourself when
you see your former students being being
off the in the speakers in a panel
but I also have to say that I'm pretty
proud of the fact that that folks that I
had had the opportunity to work with
whether they were in my class or not I
recognize many from my time when I was
on the faculty here at West Point and
let me tell you that we picked the right
folks to come up here and provide
operational expertise and a step closer
to what you're going to be doing in the
near term I mean it's great you get the
generals to walk around we're old right
and we're more than a step removed from
company grade leadership that you'll be
executing in the near terms so I
appreciate the the officers the ncos the
warrant officers that are dedicating
their time to come up and offer their
their perspective
it's not lost on the yellow let's be
clear no one remembers the guest speaker
these things
like literally no one does a benefit is
that you've already had Chow
um you know it was it was good food all
day again thank you to the class of 1970
uh for putting on uh a great spread but
you never remember the guest speaker
you can know me as like answer number 10
on your uh on the the survey from last
night the scavenger hunt right
um but like whether or not you you know
who I am
um I might run into you on Barton field
when you're down at Fort Gordon next
year so watch that I mean a notable
exception uh to the the guest speaker is
Burger General vile who
masquerades as the Cyber commandant he's
really a Mill Art P
um at West Point
um but but think back to the message
that he delivered
what has changed in the past 100 years
in the execute of the fight is what you
are responsible for
that's huge
and what a poignant exclamation point on
his talk
with the idea of taking our enemies back
to 1919.
based off what you are going to be able
to do
when you join the force
next year
that's right around the corner
hey so you won't remember me
you won't remember much about my message
but I'm going to keep it simple as a
result
be a leader
what do I need from you what do I want
from you what do I expect of you
be
a leader
there'll be a test at the end of this
see if you can
keep pace
one of the most critical aspects
of leadership in specifically leadership
in the military in even more
specifically leadership in the United
States Army I like to refer to it as the
trust continuum
you must demonstrate competence
you heard some of our leaders talk about
it earlier today
you must demonstrate competence if you
don't
your soldiers
the civilians that work with you will
sniff you out in a heartbeat
you demonstrate competence to earn their
respect
we're a disciplined Army
we're a disciplined Joint Force
you will get respect
from your subordinates based off the
rank that you have on your chest or your
shoulders wherever you're wearing it on
what uniform you have on
they will offer you that respect but you
have to earn their respect as a human
being and as a leader that's earned
and it's earned through your
demonstrated competence
when your soldiers see that you know
what you're talking about
they will follow you
when they Trust
that you will one know what you're
talking about in two deliver guidance
and orders in an ethical and moral
manner
you will earn their trust
if likewise your subordinates
demonstrate their competence
and they live ethically and morally that
trust becomes bi-directional and that is
what makes our army the best army in the
world we can execute through commander's
intent and execute Mission command I can
let you execute to discipline initiative
because there's Mutual trust between you
and your subordinates
are no other army in the world
can operate like the United States Army
in that regard
disciplined initiative through Mission
command
but you have to be a leader
to get to that point
competence
you heard major I can't get over saying
that Keith I'm going to keep doing it
you heard major earlier today talk about
technical competence
and you heard Jason the course you talk
about what it means to be a tool
developer and how you have to have
skills
absolutely the case
you are a special group
for every one of you
it's in the room tonight there were 10
more that wanted the seat that you're in
we don't have a problem
recruiting officers that want to become
cyber officers in our army
you earned the seat that you're in
how many stripes are on the shoulders on
the uniforms in this room
how many stars are on the collar
I know what that means
I can read the room I know who's in here
I also know that General vile and his
team recruited you and have been talking
to you for a couple years because we
need the best and brightest
you passed that test congratulations
now wrap yourself in a warm blanket of
confidence and get ready to get to work
because you must be a self-directed
learner
in order to be technically competent in
the cyberspace warfighting domain
you must be a self-directed learner
the rate of change of technology and the
rate of change of our enemies in our
adversaries is too great what you know
today will not be what you need for
tomorrow
we must continue to learn you must
continue to learn
it'll change
by the time you finish Bullock
it'll change by the time you get to your
first unit of assignment
you've got to stay on top of your game
however back to my first point about
who's in this room your cohort
you cannot be an expert in everything
you have to understand as an officer
the entire warfighting domain
but you can't be an expert in networking
in forensic analysis
in big data analytics
and the list goes on
you have to know who's in this room with
you that who has that expertise
so that when you need to phone a friend
you know where to find her or him
and then you have to bring your game
collectively we have to work together
you may be an expert in
routing and you may have studied the
Cisco command line and you've got it
down and and you're you're hot on how to
configure a router do you know how to
configure a Huawei router
do you know what the firmware inside the
Huawei router looks like
do you know what happens when you issue
a command how it operates on the inside
I'm not asking Jason he probably does
you have to be
a self-directed learner
you have to be humble
to recognize that you won't know
everything
and you must lean on each other
to develop that
technical competence and expertise
but that's not good enough either
forgive me for the midshipmen in the
room
but when you graduate next year it says
U.S Army on your chest
so you must be a technical professional
and you must demonstrate your competence
but don't ever forget that you're an
army professional
and with that comes expectations
I expect you to know your troop leading
procedures
as discussed earlier this afternoon I
expect you to understand the military
decision making process I expect you to
understand the vernacular of our
warfighting forces
if you are a technical expert and you
can't effectively communicate to a
warfighting maneuver Commander you're no
good to me
you've got to be able to communicate it
a great idea that you can't communicate
is not a great idea
and we have a community
inside of our profession that expects
you to communicate using the terms of
our profession
we cannot have
a three-star General
sit on a conference panel and talk about
dolphin speak
that's not okay
it's on us
to be able to take a highly technical
topic incredibly complex
and put it into
words and Concepts and visualizations
that
our community can understand
that's when we become effective think
about the inverse what happens the first
time
the Battalion Commander asks the 17
Alpha in the formation something about
cyber
and that 17 Alpha doesn't have the
slightest idea
you're instantly marginalized
and how many 17 Alphas remember the
charts from earlier today how many 17
Alphas are in the formation out there
with the Infantry and armor and field
artillery Battalion Commanders
you're it
you're alone and unafraid
as the representative of understanding
our war fighting domain
to the rest of the army
if you're marginalized guess what
happens in that Leader's eyes
cyber is shut down
I asked the Cyber question of the Cyber
expert that expert couldn't answer it I
don't have time for this I'm going back
to the mat board and I'm getting ready
to go shoot move and communicate sleuth
turret and engage targets
and that is not okay
because our maneuver forces will die in
combat and large-scale combat operations
without your support remember what
happened over the last hundred years
what's changed is what you're
responsible for the enemy can see you on
the battlefield
Indio FM 3.0 says You must operate under
constant observation it is not okay for
the maneuverists to ignore what you have
to say
so be able to express it in terms that
resonate with the maneuver Commander
and don't be timid and shy about it be a
leader
walk into the command post with your
chest up like you know what you're
talking about because you do and then
effectively communicate it to that
Commander In terms that he or she
understands
that's being professionally competent
put those two pieces together you got to
be technically competent you have to be
an army professional
be a leader
you have to figure out how to put the
pieces together
such that you as company grade officers
can build the teams of the future
you will show up to a formation
and you will have ncos and warrant
officers and civilians
that have been on those teams
for years
25 percent of the formation as general
vile told you this morning already have
degrees
they're past you already
and they've got operational experience
you have to step in and leave that
formation
but wait a minute
if you're going into an infantry platoon
hasn't that NCO also been there for
years with tons of experience
yeah it's not that different
it's not that different with a notable
exception of the technical expertise
that no one individual
can master all of it
so when you walk in to lead your small
unit
you need to understand who your people
are what their skills are what they
bring to the team and then you have to
be the leader to build the team
someone on that team is going to be a
network expert someone is going to be a
host analyst expert someone is going to
be a data analyst your job as an officer
is to be able to understand how to build
a team effectively to achieve Mission
outcomes
and to take care of your people
understand who they are
on a personal level
as was explained to you earlier this
afternoon such that you can Inspire them
to their life's best performances
that's what being a leader in this space
is about
giving them the opportunity to
demonstrate their expertise
but harnessing it into
an organized unit to achieve an effect
recognizing that you're not going to be
able to do it
on yourself recognizing that you're
going to have those dependencies
recognizing and having humility in that
you're going to have dependencies
but as several folks have said earlier
today
your future is bright
congratulations on having earned a seat
in this room
congratulations on what you've
demonstrated to date
now harness that
turn it into
effective leadership
be a leader
thanks
all right so last night we had this uh
challenge that
everybody participated in which was
awesome
and we have some winners for it so
the winning team
is blueberry grunt
which is Seth Benson from usma and
Brendan Ward from the University of
Akron come on up
[Applause]
yeah so you know Six Degrees of
Separation
It's a Small World
so Cadet Seth Benson's dad Colonel Jason
Benson
was Lieutenant Jason Benson next to
Lieutenant Paul Stanton back in 126
infantry in Schweinfurt Germany back in
the day so it's truly a small world but
it's my distinct pleasure to offer you
both coins
from the Cyber Center of Excellence on
behalf of myself my command Warren
officer and the command sergeant major
now based on your ability to solve
problems dynamically in the middle of
the fight congratulations
[Applause]
all right I'd like to present a gift to
General Stanton for as great words
tonight inspirational motivational as
always thank you so much sir appreciate
it Stephen thank you all right thanks
Steve
okay I do have one last
um
uh I have an ACI coin to give to uh to
someone here so there was one more
Challenge on there and um we didn't have
a we didn't have somebody who finished
first on that one we had one person that
finished that one so
um to those of you who don't know base64
or
um
encrypted elf files and how to run them
go figure that one out
um to the one who does is
um teddus
Sikorski come on up
[Applause]
Scott thanks
and I did forget to mention he's
actually from Johns Hopkins again so
talk about the separation he's there we
go
okay so um that's all for tonight I have
um just some admin notes for tomorrow
first of all you need to be checked out
at the Thayer before tomorrow's session
so if you're going to be here at
breakfast you need to be checked out
when you when you get up in the morning
check out get all that done there will
be a place for you to store your luggage
there
um
and same time as today 7 30 that there
will have the luggage room and then
after the sessions
um
buses will go back to the Thayer Hotel
there will have you will have about 15
minutes to change so good dressing
drills going on when you get back there
because the buses are going to depart at
1300 there will be some room set aside
so you can change there before you get
off so just keep that in mind that
you're going to have a short amount of
time once you get back with that have a
great evening we'll see you tomorrow
morning