all right welcome welcome back
I've got 1300 on my watch so that's what
that's what we're going with
all right so uh this afternoon we're
gonna have another breakout session but
uh we also as part of the Cyber leader
conference we've brought in some
additional guest speakers uh and these
these folks the first one we're going to
introduce here momentarily are kind of
going to give you a perspective on as a
team lead as kind of the first uh field
grade officer in your chain of command
what is expected of you what they're
anticipating and what they think you
should understand to be ready for on
those uh at that Team level from from
the field grades so the first one that
we have here as a guest speaker is Major
Keith major he's a 2008 graduate from a
West Point majored in Information
Technology while he was here and he has
a master's degree in computer science
from Stanford University
uh he completed a company command in
2015 and transferred over to the Cyber
Branch he then taught in the East
department and then he is held a number
of cyber jobs he is currently the 91 CPT
Liam CPT lead uh down at Fort Gordon and
I will turn it over to you teeth
well good afternoon cyber leaders
there we go so I've been given the best
challenge opportunity to speak just
after you had a good meal and during
your normally scheduled Dean's hour nap
so uh thanks Colonel Arnold for this
opportunity
so as a former 2008 Cadet as was just
stated I know that some of you are here
because you want to get out of law or
Mill Arts I might just be projecting on
those two or you're here because you
want to be as a former instructor I know
I have your attention for five minutes
or because you're here to learn you
might listen to me a little longer my
talk is focused on that second group
both cases
um so I'll say it's a little weird to
give a speech about my expectations of
company grades because I normally do
this in initial counseling and that is
more of a conversation
so I'll give you a little bit of my
background in dco or defensive cyber
operations so you have a background of
why I expect what I do I'll talk about
my leadership philosophy as well as my
leadership values and then I'll open the
door for questions so we can have that
conversation
so I've had the privilege of being a
team lead on two cyber protection teams
503 CPT and currently 91 cyber
Protection Team I've been in support of
Joint Force Headquarters cyber Navy as
well as Joint Force Headquarters doden
so I guess I don't work for the Army on
both of those so I've traveled a little
bit with the Cyber protection Brigade
I've gone to Korea I've gone to Hawaii
I've gone to the Pentagon and we've done
missions as well on the Defense Finance
terrain as well as transcom so really
good experiences on both of my cyber
protection teams
so
cyber protection teams your job
is in the dodin to discover the
adversary and to protect the doad in
from the adversary's attacks
General vile told you about why that's
important is to ensure that our
commanders continue to make decisions at
the opportune time
you're you will be in a constant
operational and training cycle
preparing for Mission and executing them
you could work with brief and report to
General officers senior executive
service civilians joints staff officers
and numerous Colonels in the Army Air
Force Marines and
to our midshipman Navy as well
for your operation missions to be
successful you will need to integrate
and get support from cyber security
service providers those Network local
Defenders and network technicians not
developing buy-in from each party
will impact your analysts ability to do
their job
you will take operations orders from
myself and people like me and develop
clear tasks and purpose for your
subordinates and Report daily to a joint
staff potentially while on Mission
and when your mission is over you will
write an operational report for what you
discovered that can be consumed and read
at the Joint Force Headquarters level as
well as the combat and command level
now these are large tasks to ask any new
company grade officer
but cyber is a team sport
and you will not be alone and I will
prepare you to execute your assigned
duties
so let me give you my definition of
leadership as part of our initial
counseling
enable the success of others
my job is to enable your success by
giving you feedback opportunities to
learn to challenge you and to coach you
Your Role is to be coachable
I don't prefer Hot Heads on my team
they're usually out for themselves and
don't care about enabling the success of
their subordinates
I expect you as Leaders to enable the
success of your ncos your warrants your
department of army civilians and your
soldiers under your care
I expect my leaders to give me input
into my operational plans to ask for
clarity and to be honest in after Action
reviews so we can all improve together
as I said cyber is a team sport we need
to ensure everyone feels part of our
team
and then can positively contribute to
our mission
I'm going to challenge you to lead with
focus on four leadership values that I
personally believe are great or critical
in creating great teams those leadership
values are a character care competence
and team learning
now let me talk about each in detail for
a moment
your character
is foundational for your arming career
as an officer
now there are different definitions of
that out there and I utilize the Army
values
because it's common
Foundation to everyone in the army
so let me discuss two of those
integrity and personal courage
integrity
I trust everyone when I start a new
assignment and I encourage you to do the
same
that trust is only broken based off of
issues with integrity
this trust is not broken when we plan on
getting something done and don't plans
change
it's when we report on something and
will willingly deceive
do not give away your integrity
this branch is small your reputation
will go a long way and will precede you
in your future jobs
the second character trait is personal
courage
now is the 17 Alpha
it is very rarely are you going to be
putting your life in danger you're more
likely to see as we do in every branch
in this service times when someone is
not doing the right thing
and people ignore it and thus encourage
it by not saying something
well you do if you hear a joke about
someone's sex culture race or religion
will you approach them and say hey we
don't do that here or where you ignore
it and allow members of your team to
feel less than and ostracized
I expect my leaders to have the personal
courage to not walk past an infraction
as silly as laces sticking out of
someone's boots
to a security infraction
not every report you give will be
positive and reflect positively on you
but you need the personal courage to
still do the right thing
as I've said multiple times and I will
continue to say cyber is a team sport it
requires cohesive teams where everyone
feels valued and everyone is accountable
ensure your people feel valued
and that brings me to the second
leadership value that I expect you to
have and that's care
you need to treat everyone with dignity
and respect
period
people will not be successful if they
don't feel like they are part of our
team
everyone brings value to our team
you must learn your people as
individuals what's their goals
their weaknesses what's important to
them
get to know them help them Reach their
goals and be their best advocate
to demonstrate care for your people
you'll need to train them
to do anything you ask of them
a briefing
an acft and yes we still do that
a mission on a new type of terrain that
you've never been on before a promotion
board
you need to spend the time to care for
your people by preparing them to do the
missions you ask of them
and then you need to ensure you give
them feedback on their performance so
they have every opportunity to improve
and to grow
and then you unsure a timely and
accurate evaluations and awards to care
for their careers
the final part of care is care for self
you need to find ways to balance your
life and your work to relax and do what
is important to you
just like you should care about your
soldiers and civilians taking care of
themselves you need to be deliberate in
how you do this for you
you cannot care for others if you don't
care for yourself
so I've talked about leadership it's
about enabling the success of others and
we talk through two of my four
leadership values which is character and
care
so at this halfway point I know what
you're all thinking
I wonder if major major is right in
catch-22
do you think he'll change his name if he
gets promoted
well to alleviate all of your bargaining
concerns you may have about me the
answer to both is no
well I guess I'll keep my day job
all right let's talk about competence
what I mean by competence is you should
strive for excellence
in being an army leader
some of that
some of you may think that is just being
technically competent and being
technically competent is part of being a
cyber leader
but it's more than that
you should strive to be competent in
your planning
your interpersonal skills your briefing
skills
and dare I say you're writing
and I know the English Department could
talk about my writing
you should know your cyber warfare
Publications and your army regulations
now this competency is built over time
you will not get it when you first show
up to my team
but you will continue learning
throughout your time in Bullock and
whenever you show up to your next job
do not pass up on opportunities to learn
you should always be learning
so why should you strive for some
technical understanding
you'll be translators between the
technical and the less technical
when translating up you are expected to
translate our technical cyber language
to language your mission partner
understands
joint terms operational terms army terms
when translating down to your analysts
you will need to translate those
operational terms in a technical way for
your analysts to execute
now you will not be perfect and you are
not expected to be
you have your weaknesses and because my
job is to enable your success I will
help you with opportunities to overcome
them
as I said before you need to be willing
to be coached to be successful learn and
continue learning read and ask questions
then take what you have learned and
ensure those in your severe of influence
know them too
cyber is a team sport we need everyone
to be
doing the mission to be sick for us to
be successful
and they need their opportunity to learn
to grow
for us all to be successful
so that brings me to my last leadership
value of Team learning
I know it doesn't start with a c and
I've already talked about my English
skills so I hope you understand
so team learning is important because we
all need to grow and improve together
everyone should be given an opportunity
to learn and grow
not all will seize the opportunities you
provide them but it's your part to
provide each one under your care that
opportunity for growth
you should strive for shared
understanding with everyone around you
be comfortable with learning from
mistakes
your successes and mere accidents none
of us including me
are immune to mistakes successes and
accidents
you should be deliberate and learning
from them and have the humility to
ensure everyone else has the opportunity
to learn from them as well
now on my team we conduct aars we
capture Lessons Learned and these
lessons are lost if they're not
Revisited or incorporated into our daily
work
we may find ourselves as we often do in
91 cyber Protection Team doing something
new for the first time
regardless of the outcome it is an
opportunity to learn from it and ensure
we do it better
the next time
we are doing team learning correctly on
91 CPT
if we execute the routine things
routinely
and by making success repeatable
let me repeat that
for you as Mission element leads on 91
CPT
we need to execute the routine things
routinely and make success repeatable
one person's success can translate into
team success if everyone learns from it
and improves too
cyber is a team sport
maybe even by the fourth time I say it
maybe you'll believe me
we need everyone to be part of the
solution so we can grow and learn
together
so that brings me to the end
of our initial counseling before we
start our conversation I've given you my
definition of leadership that I expect
you all to lead with enable the success
of others
I ask you to lean with the fourth
leadership values
of your character you care for the
people under you
to strive for competence and to ensure
we have Team learning
doing this well will enable the success
of others
and they not you they will make you
successful
now to prepare yourself for the next
steps of your career
take every opportunity to learn
be coachable
be humble
and ensure those in your sphere of
influence are all learning together
I encourage you whoever the army takes
you enable the success of others by
demonstrating care character competence
and a focus on team learning
now for the second half of our initial
counseling open the floor and I welcome
any questions
[Applause]
in the back
hold on a second we'll grab a microphone
for you
good afternoon sir good my favorite
question is
how do you best make use of the many
backgrounds and educational and cultural
and other types that you find from
working with both officers ncos and also
Department of the army civilians how are
you best making use of that yeah great
question
so whenever we get our orders and go
into the operational process
that invitation to develop our plan for
the team
is
everyone on the team is given
opportunity to give input and
we may find people with expertise on a
specific type of terrain
that's an E4
and I sure want them in planning for a
mission because our success could be
dependent
on the input that they provide
so the first step is getting to know
your people
right you need to know what their
strengths what their weaknesses are and
as a mission element lean on a cyber
Protection Team you will be that
Advocate on behalf of all of your
soldiers and civilians to the
operational process and then bringing
them with you when we do planning
so how do you leverage it
when you do a service time training or
Hip Pocket training it doesn't matter
who's giving it doesn't have to be a
sergeant doesn't have to be a warrant
officer it could be a civilian
it could be like I said a PFC
you will be shocked by the expertise
within your formation and the drive that
they have to succeed and so what I
challenge you to do is just to harness
it and to include them into the the
planning process
and then ensure you get feedback from
them too because their voice matters
other questions
it's a great question
um and it probably has to do what I feel
is a place that I did not succeed as
well and I was in company command I
wasn't a good coach
and so coming here to teach in the eats
Department
seeing two of my students In This Crowd
hi Skye hi Brian
um
that I think has changed my leadership
philosophy the most in that when we
coach each other when I coach when you
coach down that everyone grows at the
same time and then we can do a whole lot
more than what we could have done
previously so
these probably most of these leadership
values were kind of part of my personal
belief probably after company command in
a whole lot of reflection and then
opportunities for growth
our previous Brigade Commander from the
Cyber protection Brigade and Anna
current Brigade Commander they focus a
lot on care and care for people General
I think it was General McConnell said
that the Army is in a business of people
and that
if we're not leading well people are
getting out for leading well and they're
brought into the mission they're going
to stay in and we need them to do that
it's a good question
[Applause]