which button this button yeah yeah well
time okay should I start
[Music]
good morning can all take our seats if
we can all take our seats please
Tom we're starting
welcome to six-man I'm Bob Hinton's is
Olli thrown
we have a session this morning and also
well let's see so here's the note well
you should all have this memorized and
tattooed on your arm we Barbara is
taking notes we still need a jabber
scribe Oh
second note-taker good but we still need
a jabber scrab does jabber still work
Eric thank you so we have two sessions
we did our usual thing of giving
priority to working group graphs and
then active graphs and so we did this
generally the working group graphs
getting discussed today and starting to
do active drafts on Friday morning
oops
and as you can see so we have a lot of
short talks in the end of Friday we also
have a follow-on session for the segment
routing discussion the plan is that the
authors are going to be working with
people during this week and then bring
hopefully getting the document so we can
do another working group last call on
Friday I think that that would we would
hope we would like to see this document
be completed and move forward and we
also received a number of the general
requests that we didn't have time to
schedule and so we're listing them here
and in the online agenda you know it
encouraged the authors to raise their
talk about the grass on the list but you
can also see them here and you know feel
free to read and comment and alternately
okay so what have we done on documents
since the last idea we got to published
RFC's that's the IP six no requirements
85 over four and it got the historical
original simple IP protocol
specification published as well as RFC
eighty 507 I encourage everyone to read
that one to see what the initial plan
was for this project call we have
nothing in the RFC editor cube we have
two documents in working group last call
they've been there for a while the
segment routing documents since March
2018 is that what's the date today also
by the end of this week that will be in
working group last call for a year
that's probably a record and then the
reader advertisement v6 only flag since
September 2018 both of those are on the
agenda today hopefully we can close
these documents out and get them advance
we have three working group documents
it's the ICMP limits document spoke to
Tom and he's going to refresh that one
this week I believe there was just
expired we have the privacy extensions
document the base document for that
that's on the agenda to talk on that one
and then we have the prof sixty-four
document that was just adopted that's
also on the agenda alright so that was
all for document status any comments on
that so there is an ongoing effort in
the ITF to look at tooling and how to do
document production more efficiently or
differently there's one ongoing
experiment and some working groups using
github for documents and and we would
like to look at that in six-man as well
or at least initiate that discussion on
doing that here in six man it is clearly
some great things about you know doing a
a source control management system for
documents you get sort of the same
benefits that you do for source code
right you get much better revision
control you get you know at least we
think you might get much more focus on
editing the documents and changes in
their documents they would you know
repairs pull requests if you ended up
doing missing each tab as opposed to
sort of the meta discussions we have
there are lots of discussions on a
mailing list lots of responsibility for
the author to try to distill that into
an actual document change well if we
were doing this we think it would be
easier at least to do a much more
collaborative process of course some of
the downsides would be that you know
perhaps the discussions wouldn't you
know be on the open on a mailing list
anymore they would end up as as are the
comments on pull requests on github
which is you know - we don't control and
might not be visible for for everyone
but it's in write and github is
currently not accessible with ipv6
yeah so so yes let's discuss this so
Eric here the comment comment from
Suresh which is as you know remove this
we is supportive absolutely of this
approach as long as participants are not
blocked by using YouTube right right yes
I think we have to
I suggest we do this as an experiment
obviously authors will get to choose
this themselves so I put one of my
drafts up there and we started using it
Eric has posted a few pull requests that
which I think worked well I if you did
anyone attend yesterday's session on
github tools there was one tutorial
there on Sunday there's also a Thursday
working group is it a working group at
least there is a session yeah Andy I
have integration and tooling
there's a couple of drafts here worth
reading as well and the quick working
group I think has done taking this the
furthest and they have you know CI tools
and they verify the XML and everything
sort of builds automatically if you if
you push and you draft and you could
sort of imagine that you could also push
drafts in the future directly to the IDF
or submit the draft to the idea website
if you if you wanted to so it becomes a
you know a new tool chain but at least
for what I've seen
just getting a different way of dealing
with document edits is an interesting
interesting try any more comments on
doing it up ELISA Cooper just a note
that the tutorial materials are all
available and I'm it was recorded as
well so if people missed it you can
still catch up that way yeah cool thank
you so so we certainly encourage people
to try this out and you know we might
gently nudge authors to put things in
github as well thank you so it is you
go in the pink box and take your clicker
good morning so I'm going to talk about
the ipv6-only are a flag I think it it's
holy said it's in working group last
call so the changes since the last
meeting or in the new draft is and these
were to address comments received during
the last call these the author's view of
this so we added a host configuration
option that controls whether the host
should process this flag and the notion
is that if it unless this you know
configure it unless it's enabled the
host will ignore even if it's dual sac
you know ignore this the notion is the
concern raised was that if you're in an
ipv4 only network there's no ipv6
services this could be used to turn off
IP ipv4 maliciously so this gives the
site the ability to have it set so it
will be ignored so this attack potential
malicious attack can't happen but and
then you know in environments where they
want to use this the configuration flag
can be enabled to allow this and so we
think this will help with the concern of
using this to turn off before and a
before only environment we also in this
line we changed text that the host can
ignore this flag if it has active ipv4
configurations they have obtained from
DHC and so it's basically if if you have
working v4 then don't turn off before it
seems very sensible to do it this way
and if there's no if you don't have any
active communications then then you
should listen to the flag
some text clarification - to improve you
know what the administrators intent was
we had Jorn as an author he's made a lot
of contributions and done the FreeBSD
implementation we updated the
information on the contribute the
FreeBSD implementation and there are a
number of editorial changes yeah so so
at this point we have freebsd
implementation there was some tests done
with scrappy to make sure if you send
this it doesn't break anything and
there's now someone working on Linux and
TCP dump Wireshark implementations so so
as they said I think the the main issues
raised were you know will be used by a
bad actor to turn off before on an act
at the four-link and so we think that
the host configuration is one way of
protecting and that as I said you you
don't act on the flag if you have active
ipv4 you know if you just have v4 that's
using self configured addresses and
there's no active connections then you
should be listening to this and and I
guess the other comment is that the rest
of the security issues are really the
same as you have with all other control
protocols that run on on the link they
can all be used by bad actors to do the
wrong thing you know you can turn off
before you can break before with the
four just as well as with this so we
think this is what's in the document is
a reasonable compromise we think the
issues are discussed in the securityq
indirect consideration section and so we
think we've addressed these issues so
the authors think it's ready to advance
you know we have implementations that
show that you know it works and doesn't
seem to disrupt the legacy
v6 implementations we think there's
reasonable protections for security
issue for the security issues that have
been raised and so we we think this is
ready to be advanced so comments
questions yes I think the document is
really nice and ready for publication I
have one comment a question because I
just realized I have a crazy idea of
using Z's on dual stack network so
because currently the document says
administrator must only enable it on v6
only which I read as I cannot enable it
on dual stack however there is a use
case for this on dual stack when I'm
trying to move most of the devices which
are capable of working on v6 only two v6
only mode and still allow legacy devices
to get addresses via DHCP before so I
kind of she's a use case for this to be
in able to dual stack so do you think we
can relax it to shoot in section 3 I'm
not sure to be honest with you I mean we
try to make this be very focused on one
one thing you're erasing a different
environment I'm not sure you have to
think about that Tim shine I would
assume those legacy devices wouldn't
understand the flag anyway so it's
really just a matter of wordsmithing the
text isn't it yeah that's a good point
yeah I mean this this only applies to
dual stack host obviously if you had you
ever be for only toast it's not going to
understand this yeah so that the whole
idea
all you devices will be instructed to
move to v6 only and all devices will
stay dual stack as expected right so
basically I see it as a way to suggest
so as a suggestion to host to move to v6
on
SiC em right yet yeah and that's clearly
not the way we were thinking about this
but I think think about it more but I
think you could be used for that yeah so
conceivably we could add some text but
you know I want the focus to remain you
know it is an ipv6 only link and just we
want to turn off the background before
traffic okay any other comments just
thinking quietly in my head here I could
hum to myself yes I'm not sure that's
quite the process we want to follow here
do we want to do a call on this further
to determine the level of support to get
his advanced yes okay let's let's do a
home on that so the people in favor of
closing this working group last call
bouncing the document to the is G please
hum now and the people who are against
which would effectively drop this
document and never talk about it again
please hum now okay thank you so
fernando gomes can you please come up
okay I'm Fernando go on I'll be
presenting the RSC 49:41 this document
and the idea for this presentation is to
try to converge or or or close some of
the you know issues that we have to
agree on regarding this document let's
start with the first one in the current
version of the document we essentially
specify two alternative algorithms for
generating temporary addresses one is
essentially calling several random
number generator okay and the other one
is essentially modification to the
algorithm in 72 seventeen obviously some
of the arguments to the hash function
are are change so that you know the
algorithm doesn't generate stable
addresses by but temporary addresses so
the first question regarding this issue
is whether for example we just recommend
the simple randomization algorithm
whether we reduce whether we remove the
72 17 algorithm all together whether we
just include the description of all both
algorithms without recommending any of
the tools or any of these two or some
other option yes
found this is a question we tomorrow
there is a problem with using time for
randomization as is this thing working
I mean it is but at the bottom in order
to speak directly into the microphone
Christian yes like that
excellent okay fine yeah there is a
problem with having a concept of time in
the generation of addresses because in
practice you want your advance to remain
stable for some duration and that's
something we saw in MAC address
randomization that is good too it's
stable so that there are two notion of
stability is that if you come back to
some network that you visited two hours
ago
it's often nice to keep the same address
for various reasons and at the same time
if you come back on the same network in
a week then it's not nice uh-huh so so
you you have to work on this concept of
what's the stable time that you want is
a just I mean a Wi-Fi session is that a
day is that mean it has to be part of
what you what you are trying to do there
well in one of the next few slides we
actually well we are rising that you
know question too because there was the
comment regarding of adding the you know
the value of time or not for example
let's say that we are just using you're
just using a simple seldom a cell the
random number generator without a you
know the any time parameter if the
algorithm is that you know whatever you
want to generate the new others you just
select a new random number then the
question is for example what happens if
you briefly disconnect your link and
then you reattach again what do you do
you do you use the same address you
generate a different one which is a what
I'm saying is that it's a more broader
issue than just including the timer I
mean the timer makes it evident I'm not
advocating a timer I'm I'm advocating
having a discussion of this issue and
balancing different solutions
okay for example this one potential
solution to say that we don't use time
at all we assume the MAC address will be
randomized according to some management
I'll go with them and then we use that
that's one possibility
okay but I think that you know even if
you know we remove the the time
parameter from you know the 72 17 I
guess there's still the question whether
you know we want more than one algorithm
in the document have more than one and
recommend one of them have multiple
don't recommend any just keep a single
one and you know remove the rest
I'm fine with either option but I just
want to know what's what the working
group wants to do about this is a please
don't get up on the microphone line
everyone at once any hosts implementers
of 49:41 who cares either way are you
just going to stick with thanks mr. Eric
Cline coming up on the mine yes Eric
line I think I have a slight preference
for at least keeping a reference to
basically if you just use pure
randomness to journey and generate one
each time as a possible option
also I think the issue of what to do
when you come back to a network is just
some simple text about whether it's up
to the operating system whether they
think they're trying to resume a session
or whether trying to establish a new
attachment to it to a network so you
mean - kind of like the limit
unspecified in a way like you know it's
up to the implementation where to do it
when to do it
know when it's not you're referring to
if I understood correctly like you were
you were referring to the comment that
Christian made and you were saying that
it would be up to the implementation you
know you know for how long the same
address will be generated because I
couldn't understand properly right so
the it's up to the host if it's doing if
it's doing DNA for example right uh-huh
yeah so if it's doing if it decides I'm
doing DNA I've been in this I've been in
there's never before within parameters
that are operating system specific it's
okay to just attempt to reuse the
address as you would with DNA or not
it's up to the operating system right I
would just add some some text around
management is separate from address
generation right agree the question is
regarding the algorithms
I leave leave a leave early just make it
okay to be purely random
you can have you can have as many
algorithms as you want huh just let one
of them be pure randomness okay so no
but not me you know you can have as many
mix this with that and you know turn it
seven times and do whatever those
algorithms are all fine just leave you
know
so we instantiate you Mersenne twister
we keep the two of things I'm don't
break them in any specific one of them
that sounds fine to me okay thanks hi
Fernando Dave Wonka I guess I want to
also vote or my preference is the single
randomization I'm sorry can you hear me
so I was saying I'm also in favor of the
the simpler option of the randomization
a one thing I want to mention and I
think you know this and I'm not sure
everyone does but in in mapper G in the
last couple years we we explored the
possibility of we noticed with privacy
addresses that you can count you can use
the privacy address to create an
estimate of how many hosts have a
privacy address configured you know in a
network and there's some really nice
advantages to that and the randomization
one enables that the thing that you can
do is try to guarantee anonymity to a
certain size anonymity set if I can
count them so I I'm not gonna go into
the details now there's a we have a
draft about it and you can come to me
afterwards about it if you haven't heard
of this but basically if you use this
the straight-up randomization with some
fairly short live time like the day
that's in the RFC recommendation now we
can produce a high quality estimate of
how many hosts are there and do an it
hit aides anonymization for privacy so
that particular mode of operation has
some advantages we got and you'd keep
the two algorithms - I really prefer the
first there was the one that the the
recommendation that you know it changes
every day and that's a random number or
could be any other time range that
that's the version that has this
property not the one that when you lose
you lose the property when you choose a
pseudo random and you come back to a
network and use the same pseudo random
again if you know if you believe that
the next time you come back to a network
that you will choose a different pseudo
random that's the one that has this nice
counting behavior that lets us guarantee
a size of anonymity
set so I'm just saying that's one of the
considerations if you think you're fond
of the ladder I would like to hear what
it is it worth losing this counting
feature yeah the thing is that so
there are two separate questions one is
whether we want to you know remove the
description of one of the algorithms the
other one is whether we want to
recommend a particular one so for
example if I understood an area
correctly he wants to keep off and leave
the option to the implementation like
you know pick whatever you want okay I
mean I'm finally the way I'm just trying
to figure out you know what's the you
know what working group refers yeah and
and yeah I mean I guess I'm in favor of
even recommend strongly recommending the
former specifically for this in an
anonymous Asian counting feature if
that's some compelling to the community
I think it's a it's a nice feature of
the simple randomization mode that you
can do this so I suppose we you know we
could certainly do a hum for each of
these options if we think people you
know are well I guess we could ask the
people if they think they're ready to
make that choice or if if we have to
take it to the mailing lists I don't
know any views on that are people ready
to make this choice now or do we want to
take that to the main list well we would
confirm it anyway but how many people
have read this document recently okay so
we are going to take it to the mailing
list good but but yes let's so let's
talk about that phenomena and then we'll
post these questions and get this close
okay thank you and we would also like to
have some reviewers on this document any
volunteers Ron fantastic Christian would
you like to to review this as well since
you've been involved in this for a long
time
super thank you right sure continue
sorry yeah all the questions for the
working group
we had in a different ID a set of
requirements for the temporary addresses
so far they are not in 49:41 base so
there was the question whether to
include them on the on this document or
not essentially rather than specifying I
mean this is like something similar to
what we did for stable addresses on one
hand we had the algorithm but on the
other hand we had like a set of
requirements that the algorithm should
fulfill like you know the addresses
shouldn't should not be predictable they
shouldn't follow patterns etc etc etc so
some some have suggested to include
these requirements in the body of the
document obviously we would keep the
algorithms themselves others have
suggested to include these requirements
in an appendix so that you know if for
some reason people wanted to use a
different algorithm other than the ones
that we are describing in the document
they know what are they you know the the
properties that these algorithms should
follow I don't think there have been
arguments against not including that but
still I mean I don't mind either way the
question is what the working group wants
to do about it any views on that come on
guys
speed read the document and jump to the
mic okay
so we'll put that on the list yeah well
we start a mail thread on that then
there is another one which is this is a
change with respect to 49 41 which is
the current version of the document
makes temporary addresses on by default
now what we think is that you know in
the light of 75 28 you know that's a
sensible thing to do but you know that's
a change that is already in the document
from 49 41 but it's up for the working
group to to discuss whether you know
somebody's against that
what is 75 20 a pervasive monitoring
7258 Braille could be yes I got the
number rounding Eric Cline I mean I vote
in favor for on by default sorry I vote
in favor found by default we turn
privacy addresses on and Android time
ago okay I get this goes this could go
as a question to the mainland list the
last topic which is I mean some of the
folks have made comments about this as
part of the other question that I asked
is whether to add additional references
regarding you know when systems might
want to generate the new address or not
one might be to point to you know DNA
for you know folks that try to detect
when they have attached to a different
link or not but based on the comments
that we have seen so far it seems that
you know some reference to this might be
of help
yeah so I guess that's it okay any
general comments views item time when
you say requirements are you talking
about requirements from the host and
users point of view or from the network
management point of view is it
exclusively one or the other or both
you mean requirements when I said
they're requirements for the algorithms
just in general in the document so there
will be no doubt requirements about when
you think you should change IDs
interface identifier or recommendations
if you want like you know one of the
things that one of the issues with 49:41
is that there were for example
implementation that they would change to
a different link and they you'd keep the
same interface identifier so they might
they might keep the same interface ID so
the question is or the thing here is to
recommend at least like you know you to
generate a new address at least you know
when these things happen
yeah so part of that is about not doing
it predictably every 24 hours exactly
for example part of it also if you're
managing the network is ideally you
don't want hosts generating more
addresses than they need to to establish
reasonable privacy yeah in a sense well
this is kind of like up to the
implementation I guess and there are
like a number of things that you know
will bury from one implementation to
another when they want to generate like
a new one there could even be situations
in which you know some operating system
I want to generate a new temporary
address for you know some subset of
applications for example generate the
new temporary addresses for you know web
browser could be and I guess the
question is are you just trying to do
everything to maximize Percy of the user
and then push the impact of that on to
the people managing the network or
people like Eric who are trying to
figure out whether that's a session
that's we continuing or genuinely a new
attachment I guess that's the question
but you have any views on that whether
we should try and capture that in the
document I think it should my personal
view is that it should be mostly up to
the implementation of up to the house of
course there is a it's a trade-off right
on one hand your house might generate my
one but there's we have the BCP about
you know they availability of addresses
so in a way you know if hosts were to
generate multiple addresses it's within
that PCP I'm not saying that it's
perfect but it's it's a recommendation
that we have right now yeah I mean if
yeah if if the outcome is yeah the host
can generate as many addresses like deal
with it that's that's fine I just think
maybe we can put some wording in there
about that maybe it's not maybe you
think we shouldn't just leave it
completely neutral it's that's rewriting
it it's an opportunity or updating it
it's an opportunity to move that
trade-off slider one way or the other or
leave it i I think that you raise an
interesting point I would say that
probably
if we let's say try to impose any kind
of like constraints on that which you
know my benefit the network on the other
hand we already have a PCP regarding the
availability of addresses so folks would
say well we already have a BCP for that
and you know notes are free to generate
you know how many others is they want
okay thanks
okay super thanks Fernanda would you
mind moving this document to github you
think or is that right so now we have a
you know six man or an ITF six man group
on on yes so that would be cool I can
work with you later on that one
super thank you Jen okay
morning my name is Jenna and this ten or
fifteen minutes talk is about how you
can discover not six for prefix in
arrays so I just resubmitted the
document I said working group draft
because it's been adopted so I first
let's go through the concerns which were
raised during the adoption call I hope I
didn't miss anything so let me know if
any of concerns on a note on this slide
so first of all first concern was we
already have three different solutions
to inform host about the prefix but if
you look at them first one solution is
using the HCP which is not suitable for
slack only networks because basically
the goal is if I have the network which
using slack to configure hosts how can I
provide host with not six four prefix
insecure away so DHCP is not an option
here by definition PC
be basically the same right especially
if the host uncontrolled I have no
guarantees that supports PCP and if the
only think I used for configuring hosted
slack I have actually no desire to turn
on additional services especially if I
don't know if clients are going to
support it so this left us with RFC
70/50
using DNS to discover not six for prefix
those problem use it is its has some
security implications because you kind
of need have you have to trust it in a
sensor which can be easily spoofed so
obviously it still could be used by
legacy hosts but what we trying to do is
to provide host in with not six for
prefix in more secure away and also in
single packet host could get all
configuration information instead of
waiting for Dena's exchanges so well
other concern was the proposer do you
wanna take some question in between just
if we your name please might look at
that orange yes so let's assume it is
true so if we want me to occur there so
let's so sure you need to get closer to
the mic so I will try I will try my best
so sorry for that okay so if we assume
that the information which is in slide
is true that me that for every service
we will have to apply and to give us
arguments as as an argument to define a
service option in array so it's a secure
so I need to define some process for my
media slide cgn name there so I have to
be able to define an array option
because of this argument that you are
providing here these slides so thank you
for that a bit way and then I need to
define for us a sip proxy server then I
have nothing I am only Ryan slack only
Network and then I have to go to the
same arguments and then we we are I
would say repeating the same arguments
and again so I don't think personally
this is a good argument to justify
why we have to define this new option in
rice so it's if we give it as a fact
then we have to open the door to any
service name to be defined in the array
option itself so that's only yeah this
one let me answer this
slark is designed to provide hosts with
configuration information which is which
is needed for basic network connectivity
right I am not aware of any operators
who think that all the hosts need to be
provided with sip proxy to get basic
network connectivity while dns64 in and
not six flow and v6 only network is
basically required for hosts to have
internet connectivity so it's kind of
special case if in future we see any
other use cases for something else which
is required for the host to operate we
might consider I believe as array
options but I think we're doing it on
case-by-case basis I haven't used case
when my hosts need to be provided with
not six four prefix otherwise they
couldn't access the internet reliably so
that's why I'm such a suggestion using
array option I don't need to configure
SCIM proxies as an operator it can but
the other operators can decide that the
you want to have for instance to be able
to provide some specific services to
their ipv6 a host using using slack and
you can not one date to the other
operator how you can do it just because
for you you don't think this is a basic
service I think this is where it which
is really I would say and agree
area which is we are starting either we
all know it for every service or either
we are really careful about that anyway
maybe my comment is not is it really
about this this kind of legend here so I
I really don't care if we just start and
define a new option for rail and for not
64 and so on but my main concern is that
there is already there an ATF consensus
document which we have went all all of
this all these options and this is a
deserve you solution that we discussed
the eruption and so on I was not against
it at that at the time but the ATF
decided to go one way and
if we have to revise that the consensus
document we have to obsolete the
existence RFC which defined all and made
a recommendation for the ATF as a whole
and we cannot do that separately for
this specific case but by the way the
discovery ordinal 64 may be important
for some cases but for there are some
networks in which they don't need to
discover the net 64 because the nesic c4
is only a service providing the ipv4
service connectivity is not a mandatory
requirement for every ipv6 ipv6 ipv6
Network you can require for some network
but this is not something which is
mandatory for every ipv6 network that's
only open for this one sorry may I ask
you two questions so first of all I know
suggestions that we need to update some
of the other RFC's resists because I
assume what a variety of decides could
be reconsidered in the lights of new
operation requirements so that's why we
are coming to this solution and a second
question is we have other options like
most Pacific routes and DNS and so what
shall we also stop using them because we
will have other ways to provide the host
visit information yeah I think the point
has to be is to be fair for the people
who made the effort in the past and with
that recommendation and to have a
consensus just by the way for
information for the DVP for instance it
was not recommended a solution and we
have the opportunity in the past in the
issue working from the software working
groups defined a dedicated option for
not 64 but me as a relator at the time I
said no we cannot split the option
because it will have a side effect that
will be a way to configure the gnostics
the option and this will be against the
existing ITF recommendation so if we
will start to do this work just start to
do it in the right way that the right
way for me is to go and try top 3 the
RFC 77050 and then to just do it with
the new motivate with the new
information we have today and to explain
to the IETF why we have to observe that
recommendation and why new solution need
to be defined at the point and so our ad
Suresh he is unfortunately in India he's
in the microphone queue so I'll let him
enjoy
she don't mind okay Hey
I'm sitting at a chair so just to
secession can you move a little bit
further away from the microphone because
the volume in the room here was very
loud how about laughs full control okay
like I'm really like holding my mic like
as far as much front of me as possible
so there's something in the room but the
thing I want to say is whatever phase
share so the router should send stuff in
our ace and the DNS and nat64 our bono
cases so me dwelling next what is next
like a sip server but that's obviously
not gonna happen okay so this is like
somewhere in the middle that we can
consider discussing it but I'm not sure
either to be very frank mate right like
you know where this falls but so the as
far as like absolute in 1750 I don't
think it's necessary i we do have some
examples there like stuff so I have been
getting quite a bit of feedback myself
okay I think I'll just type and let
somebody really so Airy giving speaking
for Suresh and basically from a jabber
room so okay we get the good average I
guess at some point of sign so it
basically says view that if the
configuration information is fed sharing
with the router it needs to be into the
route advertisement if not it can be in
the HCP and then dns64 and 96 for a
border case that can be argue
whether they're our basic connectivity
primitives and I don't think this will
extend to sip server state favor
speaking of the mic so on the topic of
70/50 I think that it does not need to
be obsolete or whatever I think they're
actually for different use cases I think
the use case that you're targeting is
the one where you're configuring the
router and you want security and you
have secure Ras deployed right okay I
don't know how many people actually have
secure Ras deployed but 70 50 is for the
case where the organization that deploys
the net six foreign dns64 maybe under a
different administrator from the one
that's configuring the actual first hop
router so if they think about like a
tethering case or something like that
where you know you're the local router
on your phone or whatever and so 7050
works regardless of whether the last hop
router has any knowledge of it right
because you're getting it from entities
that are where the Nets net and and dns
server are and so I think that therefore
somewhat different deployment cases one
where you specifically have security
turned on which is a case where you're
using in your Ras and where you want
administrative control at the edge
router the other ones for a case where
you're controlling stuff or you're the
entity that only control stuff at the
dns64 and net6 for which may be farther
away than just the last hop and so my
point is that since neither one is a
superset of the other it doesn't make
sense to do an a obsolete they're
actually for somewhat different use
cases that they're both valuable we are
fair enough by securing our a I'm not
necessary mean send I mean I can
guarantee that my host receiving arrays
only from my router to some degree right
so I can prevent rogue host to send
array so I can say yeah my arrays are
reasonably secure and if I have someone
sending malicious re I have bigger
problems and not six for
if you don't have send then how is it
any more secure than 7050 as I think
right now he's 70 50 you're saying see
secure right because it's not secure in
that sense well meteors are raised
unless you have said I cannot guarantee
is that no the malicious host is not
saying spoof DNS response from outside
while forays if I isolate host to host
and traffic is only allow it from host
or router I can guarantee due to some
level of confidence that RSI secure if
you can prevent host a host then I clean
you can prevent spoofing of DNS from
other close on that link from outside
it's not necessary from inside the
network right okay I understand your
answer my point remains that I don't
think either one is a superset of either
scenario and so it doesn't make sense do
and obsolete Erik line yeah yeah in the
sense the RA option allows each and to
not have to have dns64 at all that's the
point so if you have lots and lots of
DNS over TLS or DNS or HTTP or some
other things and you can actually have
the host do DNS these for synthesis on
device and not have to have not have to
talk to a dns64 like dns64 completely of
course I about to deal with not with the
prefix themselves I do not even need to
run gayness x1 and in fact that is part
of how it was sort of discovered turning
on private eNOS so yeah another concern
raised was that it should be configured
on the router which is a creational
nightmare and I kind of disagree because
we already have to configure prefixes
for slack DNS services preferred
lifetimes and other things
and normally automation take care of
this so it's not a bug it's a feature so
we can allow all those information to
share fate with routers because it's
directly related to origin queries it's
not six for prefixes going so obvious
I do believe it makes sense to share
afraid I was around information so it
was some concerns raised about let's
unify dhcpv6 and our options to be
honest I did not really get it and
anyway I believe it's kind of out of
scope of this draft and if you start
doing this we can have another
conversation about this but to be honest
I just like to let my hosts in v6 only
network to get prefix and see
implementation as soon as possible so we
received a number of suggestions for the
document I first mark I didn't exclude
set for the four ranges honestly I kind
of think we should be doing this but
probably not in this option because
again this option is mostly useful on v6
only network exclude set would not be
really useful on v6 unless scenario it
would be used as well in dual stack with
DNS not six for network so probably we
just can't have another array option and
I'm kind of volunteering can write a
draft if you think it should be we need
this option so nan / 96 perfect support
we've heard about one use case have not
heard about others so first question
shall we be doing this and if yes how
because the current proposed option
format is trying to kind of minimize the
size of the option so we're not
inflating inflating array too much so we
came up with two ideas of how you can
support nan / 96 prefixes first of all
obviously is just add prefix length in
the top which unfortunately means you
significantly increase the size of sorry
always so even if you use slash 96 which
I suspect will be the most common use
case you still have a large array option
another slightly more crazy approach is
to have graphically prefix length and
the end and if the option lengths is 2
then you know that it / 96 and if
option lenses threes and you get the
perfect length and the bottom of the
option the benefit of this is that you
basically do not need to have large
option if you use slash 96 so you can
save some space and I think we have
presidents with route information option
which is also variable length so it's
not something so uncommon I actually
don't have any preference so I would
like to us the shipper can grow opinion
on this uh and another option is yeah
let's do / 96 now and if we have come up
with a personal use case for non / 96 we
can do that or use always a universal re
option for this so we just dress
admitted the document as a working group
draft
Mayon changes we clarify the y host
might need to get Danis not 6 for prefix
for it's a local DNS SEC validation for
6 for X lot use 19 for literals using
trusted untrusted external DNS servers
and also as we just mentioned
eliminating dns64 whatsoever because
eventually if I know that all hosts
support this option I don't even need to
run dns64 as a separate service and it
was it was some confusion apparently in
the text about why we saying that we
using only one option one prefix for all
destinations and at the same time the
option might appear more than once in
the array so we clarified the text a bit
hopefully it's more readable now and so
now I would like to hear some
suggestions options we need kosher
[Music]
mark Andrews the excluded addresses if
we go down the variable array length
path adding exclusion of adding the
exclusion information it could be
optional and I could we could do is
exactly the same thing as you're doing
with lengths you have a prefix length
and then after that you have a DNS
address where you where you pick up the
information from for the exclusion
information you don't have to include
including code exclusion information in
that were in that in the option itself
you just need to have a pointer to where
you can find it well and basically you'd
have prefix length and then a DNS
address included and encoded in the DNS
for encoding with the route saying there
is no address there is no information so
you get prefix length and one more bite
if you've got no information or if
there's no information and no prefix
length you do the short alright
yeah actually yes it does make sense
here so basically suggestions that we
using approach number two and we expand
this to have some other additional
information which will be optional if
you know yeah yeah fair enough yeah I I
would like to ask one thing is the
option able to transfer through for
example CPE because I do have a similar
draft which solves the issue differently
and I have been getting this question if
the option is able to transfer through
for example rotor because if you do have
a provider which support which gives you
this option of the prefix as first
Explorer
not if such device after the CPE would
also receive it so yeah so I I guess I
guess your suggestions that the CPE
should if they receive it for arms three
upstreams they should include that in
the race and down strips yeah I think
that you yeah well we can add the text
cloud of ions is here yeah okay thank
you
and do you wanted to say something no I
didn't really have anything to add after
you parties responded okay thank you
well so this has just been adopted I
guess we'll enjoy some more working
group yes thank you too okay Darren are
you here floor is yours
and I think you have 30 minutes right
see if we can get the mic the right
height here everyone hear that
we're good there we go how is that okay
alright so the SR header revision 17 was
attempted to publish and it's just
finally published now you guys can see
if there's been some updates done to it
so we're gonna cover what's in revision
17 in in this talk once again thanks to
all the collaborators and partnerships
we've had the the vendors the service
riders the members of this working group
for commenting and contributing to this
draft
so the today we're gonna cover four
major parts we're gonna cover running
code and deployments
that's our
kind of main objective of this working
group is to get closure in in drafts and
get get running code and get rough
consensus within the working group so
hopefully we were well on the way to
getting that and with the changes in
revision 1617 as well as the issues that
we need to close this week to complete
the last call and we'll cover how we
plan on doing that this week all right
so on the SR v6 collaboration adoption
we've had quite a number of years and
all this they mentioned it's been in
last call now for 12 months we've been
six years since this was first presented
at the IETF there's been like I said
lots of industry sport and vendors and
academic research there's been 24
revisions of the drafts there's been a
thousand emails approximately on six-man
mailing lists from a basic search like
that's one email per line of text or
very close to it there's been a large
number of ITF presentations and 35
versions of the draft have been
submitted since it was a individual
submission there are a lot of
implementations so I'll go through them
relatively quickly
these ones I think everyone's well aware
of I've talked about them before and
2017 and then ongoing updates to Linux
as a 410 Linux SR extensions and FDI o
VPP with SR v6 support in all three of
these including what's in the SR header
and beyond cisco has shipping code with
the SR header on the ASR 9000 5500 a
bunch of iOS XR platforms and that is
shipping today and shipping now Huawei
has a large number of shipping products
with SR v6 support as well on their VRP
v vr p v8 platforms barefoot has
shipping code since it leaves May of
2017 and I believe there's actually an
open source reference I can post a list
after this talk for the p4 code
on Tofino aspire onyxia have released sr
v6 support on their hardware
implementations on the application side
we have Wireshark tcp dump IP tables etc
snort and of tables all with sr v6
support release for them we have an eye
chart of research publications on SR v6
everything from some very cool load
balancers to some Sdn architecture for
for networks some enterprise use cases
basically lots of stuff there you can
you can take a look at the presentation
offline and and browse these as much as
you want there have been interrupt bind
2017 for l3 VPN with traffic engineering
and service programming between FDI OH
barefoot Tofino implementation Cisco's
NCS 5500 which is using commercially
available NTU so other platforms other
than just Cisco's can be building s r v6
solutions based on that and the ASR 1000
family using a custom Cisco ASIC again
at an Tech 2018 there was LT l3 VPN with
traffic engineering and TI LFA that was
interrupted between the NCS 5500 and
Strada comics the Inspiron release wise
and deployment wise softbank's of course
announced their nationwide SR v6 core
network utilizing the content of the SR
header draft a bunch of services that
are in that work programming beyond what
we're working on here
extensions nice a.s and BGP along with
ping and traceroute support from the OEM
draft that's going to be presented maybe
later today or Friday China Telecom has
deployed a nationwide network on SR v6
as I said nationwide but and
v6 network on China Telecom
utilizing this draft again some of the
functions out of SR network programming
and again s-sir v6 extensions in BGP and
ping and traceroute support alright so
that's the end of implementations all
right
I suppose if we're for going on on
what's been developed what's been
deployed what's been released there's a
lot of investment on this draft from
vendors from service providers and it's
been I think fairly well well deployed
so far even though it's still perhaps
early in its life so let's take a look
at changes in 16 and 17 and the
deployment model in revision 16 was
updated really to concentrate on how we
secure the SR domains from external
attempts to use it's it's we looked at
the SR domain as a single routing system
with delegation between components that
includes some description of how H Mac
can be used in in that system and we
described how back in handling happens
within the SR domain for ICMP airs for
MTU for a H ESB so it's pretty well
described now in the deployment model as
a revision 16 revision 17 we've removed
the reference to network programming
that was asked for by some one of the
open issues or actually two of the open
issues were on that TLV processing
limits were added this was again to
start to address another TLV related
issue that that we have in the issue
tracker there may be more work to do
there but we'll see this week we'll see
from comments that people have we've had
some updates to pad TLV some minor
descriptions made sure hm a discovery
covering the destination address of the
packet and it matches the first segment
the extension header processing rules
were updated to make it clear that
extension headers are in fact processed
in order and we're not skipping any of
them that wasn't apparently wasn't clear
in the previous revision I think there
was some confusion on that and flow
labels are required in this draft for
intra SR domain communication as well so
previously we had flow labels required
for inter domain this draft adds some
for intradomain there's a section that
like Adrian somewhere here it pointed
out a while ago that we needed which was
more description around what a
designated expert is supposed to do when
assigning making assignments out of the
Ayana portions of this draft are
specified the flags and TLV the
description in that section now follows
the best practices in 8126 so requires a
working group draft and requires
notification this six-man and describes
what what sort of time frame is required
and how the expert reviewer should
respond alright
issues to close on this draft we still
have some where around I think 10 or 12
issues that remaining open some are
duplicates some are partially closed and
some of those are actually fully closed
so we just need to do the housekeeping
to clean them up however on the tag
processing I'd sent an email look to the
list this past week on this tag
processing as it's defined in the draft
is well the processing is defined at
least saying that a was how a source end
point no it should be handling it when
we don't have a use case defined we
don't have a use case to find in the
draft and looking at how to actually
document in this draft what those use
cases might be and and and how the tag
field might be used was going to be a
fairly large amount of information to
put in here we think that it's still
better to leave that to
a separate draft to define various
various use cases and and and and how
that tag would be used to identify a
group of packets at the source for
processing at some segment end point on
the TLV side the let's see the the tlvs
are really that fundamental part of the
SR architecture where we want to get
that integrated underlay and overlay and
service chaining solution implemented
and we need to be carrying metadata
along with with some of those segments
the TLB provide a space for that
metadata and it's important that we
include that space within the SR header
if we if we have it preceding the SR
header we run the risk of expanding the
number of bytes that need to be
processed on some of the topological
segments to the point where we're you
know we reduce the amount of topological
segments that we can process or we
increase the processing requirements on
those topological segments that have to
parse those tlvs so I keeping them
included within the SR header after the
segment list allows us to basically not
process them or not skip over them until
they actually need to be need to be used
on the management section this was
something back at ITF 103 I noted that
we want to take a look at I think at the
point where we're at now we don't have a
management section defined in this draft
yet and we don't have any example text
on what that might be it's probably a
good idea at this point to leave that
for another document to describe any
additional management requirements
around us every six and oh there's
various gaming models that are coming
out for SR policies so so you know we
can we can talk about that folks can
give their opinion but I think it's
probably best at this point we'll leave
the management section for other graph
okay then the plan on how we're going to
close last call so we've been asked this
week to get to get this document closed
I've requested meetings with folks on
Tuesday and Wednesday the the folks with
open issues in issue tracker
there's a couple that I haven't heard
from yet so hopefully I'll hear from
those folks today and we can get on with
those meetings have a meeting set up
with Bob on Thursday to go over the
state of those issues from Tuesday and
Wednesday
so we can make any updates to issue
tracker and then be ready for Friday's
report of where we are with open issues
on the SR header okay and that is our
current status of the SR header in the
working group so go ahead let's open it
up to discussion and comments Eric not
my question on your implementation list
so do you know which subset of these
ones actually do encapsulation as
opposed to the old non encapsulating in
inserting on the SR a turkey so all of
these all of the implementations are VPN
implementations they all encapsulate
okay there's got to be more than that go
it's time left yeah yeah plaintiffs on
it
Tom Herbert so with respect to the TLV
there's actually two questions I think
so one is why are TLV is required in the
segment routing header as opposed to
using say a destination options before
the second outing header the other
question is if you do have tlvs in the
segment rounding header why would the
definition and the up and the
requirements be different than hop I hop
options or destination options so for
instance one of the big differences is
that there's a modifiable bit
however in the segment routing tlvs the
type and the length are not covered in a
modifiable bit by the off header
there's your doubt that's very different
from RFC 8200 so I think the implication
there is and this is probably something
that has to be closed I think at one
point there was the idea that segment
routing tlvs could be inserted or
deleted and it's unclear from the
current discussion is that something
that is intended or if it's eliminated
if we're never going to do that then I
don't see any reason why the segment
routing TLV should be any different than
hop-by-hop or destination options yeah
okay so I see the first one of those
first one of those questions which was
why have tlvs within the routing header
versus destination option so it so that
the there's two answers to that
the first answer the technical one is
tlvs that precede the segment routing
header push it back further in the
packet if we as we add more tlvs to the
to the basically preceding that segment
routing header those nodes that are
there simply let's say topological
processing notes for the most part have
to look further into that header to to
process the segment routing header and
have to do additional work as they
process that segment routing header they
have to walk each one of those
destination option tlvs with it with the
tlvs within the segment routing header
that's not a requirement on every
segment just listed in the segment list
okay so so that's that that's the two of
them alright that's the first one the
the second one that's the technical
reason the they I think more the design
reason is that is it about when you're
when you're defining a segment list and
you're defining a I guess the source
routing as a solution keeping the
segment's and the and the options
associated those segments in a single
extension header is I guess
yes attractive in that regard but
combined with the combined with the
additional processing overhead I think
that's a significant reason to keep them
where where they are in the Sigma
roadheader
Julie you've got a follow up child
halpern with Erickson the question on
your most recent comment I don't see
where the current document draws a
distinction in kinds of segments much
less says this kind of segment must look
at tlvs and this kind of segment must
ignore TLV is you may have implemented
it knowing what was safe but that's not
an interoperable implementation saying
there was a shortcut you could take
doesn't help us so this document only
defines the header structure and it
defines a single type of segment an end
segment but the processing rules for
tlvs have to be defined here they can't
be added later you're justifying putting
the tlvs here technically on the basis
of processing rules which are not here I
can't see how that can be a
justification for including the tlvs
technically it's not here
you're not spelling it out how can it be
a behavior that drives the redesign ok
so again this this draft is is designing
the base that other things are going to
be built on obviously it's not obviously
every conceivable use case is not
spelled out in this draft no but a
question of things must process tlvs and
must not process to yell these does seem
to be a base behavioral requirement yeah
implicit concrete is everything must
look at them not everything must do HVAC
processing but it has to notice it no
actually the current text document says
dependent on local policy which is open
to further clarification and in
subsequent documents as to what that
would be it does it would look it up to
you the user site would look at the HVAC
it doesn't lead to the optimization
you're citing is the excuse for doing it
the
it's okay okay I think I described the
technical reasons why fairly clearly so
such person do you have a also to be
seen yes in the other I see do so closer
to the mic please much fun others do
consider the acceleration only user
praying specification so that it will be
defined in Deseret it's very useful
because the the entity of the the user
praying of warding desire defined in the
other sto because a CBP consider a study
to to to put the year some parameter in
the other metadata in the servitor so
the city our principle to to study the
the other candidate of the user plan but
also yeah the processing theory is could
be defined in the entity of the dot user
pram so um to confine the all of the
metadata assert its the absolutely how
about you thank you okay so the right
honorable chair prescribed yes you
Java's try be speaking for my caliber
AMISOM he asked you Darrin can you
elaborate on the MTU discovery you just
mentioned and where to find information
in the draft MTU discovery yeah I don't
think I mentioned MTU designed to you
handling I don't recall saying anything
about MTU did I did okay I'm just
repeating the question okay yeah I
understand yeah
Chumlee from Hawaii and I have two
comments and the first one there's TLB
until the stranger option header has the
same functionality which the TV in SH
but actually for me I think that if we
put the cherries inside the SI h which
is it means the segment list would be
better for how we're processing right
and the second one is actually we have
several implementation already and our
customers require
as obvious except estava sex and we hope
those authors to address the issues as
soon as possible because it's a long
tongue yep thank you like this is the
for the forelli so coming back to kill
me I have a draft which is agenda
hopefully today but just to add what
Aaron said when to process TLV is a
property of the state if this is the
notion of programmability of the network
so let's say for instance see in van onm
use case that is there in the draft it
allows more flexible implementation that
all nodes along the path doesn't have to
look for the TLV based on the local said
the node knows whether look for TLV or
not which is which is the true notion of
programmability so it goes back so if if
we go with destination option or hopper
how option you lose the entire basis of
a services the programmability as second
efficiency aspect so in addition to the
hardware efficiency there are Network
wide efficiency and there are many use
cases and and in when onm is one of them
where we can take advantage of it
because not all nodes in the network is
capable of processing TLV so when you
send an environment in packet only node
that are capable of doing so needs to
look for it and needs to modify it
thanks so on the subject of local policy
this is used several times in the draft
and in some cases it's very open-ended
like it's up to local policy how to
process tlvs in certain cases and the
thing is that's so broad that it's
almost like an implementation could
decide to process these things however
they want
it's an unlimited open-ended thing which
makes me wonder how you derive
interoperability and conformance from
that so I think in the draft I
personally would prefer to
configuration as opposed to local policy
where you have maybe two choices you can
configure it this way or this way but
the open-ended local policy and the
comment that we're building this on the
assumption that there's going to be
things later that that further define or
clarify that I think you know going back
to the previous points we have to have
in in the draft it has to in a sense be
complete such that I can implement this
without having to make assumptions or
guesses about what the right local
policy is yeah so I'd say we're at this
point we're not making guesses there's
that there's a number of drafts already
that are defining tlvs and and how or
when they get processed
so so that's that's you know that's
beginning to happen and the involvement
of of this working group in the spring
working group in those drafts will will
shape all right it means defining tlvs
in the framework of what tlvs are and my
claim is the definition of tlvs
themselves is still open-ended so
somebody could come up with some
alternatives that no one else would ever
implement but it still claimed
conformance that's the issue
Roby inferno javi I think I know that's
their the what is caution regarding that
here is in the Asajj in fact that we
already proposed these some user cases
you know either dropped
that's the SRA PR we use the useful for
such a u-lock uses so I am a suggestion
you that because of these use cases
depend on the SR actual draft and
instead the SRO draft that depend on
these the possible use cases of the
theory is the draft so my suggestion
since this is the usual case is the
justified the theory usage in the SRH
header so my suggestion you that the
this draft user just use the prop hold
is the definition of the theory in the
SRH but for the problem is offered our
way for such that the user cases should
be in
tuh or the hubbub I hope I hope how
their or the SRA should carry I think
that can be addressed that you the user
keys offered is that you are we used to
craft that's my commerce okay hi Darren
Ron Bonica juniper this discussion about
tlvs and destination options could go on
for a very long time and the reason why
is we're making design decisions based
on poorly understood requirements right
now we know about exactly one TL v the H
Mac and we're not quite sure we
understand that completely may be a good
thing to do would be to leave the door
open to doing it either way later when
we understand more tlvs and more
requirements leave the door open for now
move them out of the document so we can
progress the document and get it as an
RFC and reintroduce it when we know what
tlvs were actually going to use does the
SFC TLV belong in there we don't know
yet we're six men guys when we
understand it then we bring it back and
we put it in the right place okay yeah I
I would think we I would certainly think
that defining it now and and defining
the base now and allowing for allowing
allowing for that innovation those those
options to be brought out is certainly
more valuable than then saying nothing
on it all of us have an interest in
getting this document published quickly
because we really do want
implementations coming out to get it
published quickly the best thing we can
do is put off the controversial
decisions and publish what we all agree
on no I like again I don't understand
this I mean logic this is like
everything is spelled out in this draft
and there are so many use cases drafts
that are there then claiming that we
don't know what is the usage when their
application their implementation that
exists for using those tlvs makes no
sense to me
and and and and with all due respect Ron
I mean there's a point where we have to
differentiate between political
interests and the actual reality of the
world I mean this is this is this work
has been going on for six years and and
and this discussion had been going on
for more than a year about this tlvs and
and and and you seems to be stuck with
this and he seems to be always cleaning
remove remove remove chop chop chop
where everything is properly defined I
mean I I think you have to be reasonable
I was coming ETL visa to find today
sorry I'll ask how many till these are
defined today
yeah they'll be defined for Ioana in
been O&M they're in list I'll kill fine
no in a complementary document which
references this doc and so so fine
HBU fine okay let me finish and this is
placeholder for TLV this is not okay and
then there TL will define for service
chaining performance management Robin
was this work opposed okay so if you
were to use the same logic then
destination options would have never
been published in 2460 because they're
exactly two TLV their pad and and pad
one rightly there was no TLV there fine
defined either so we define these things
so that we can we can build on them we
can build product on them that is this
useful to the network and it's useful to
it's useful in deployments and and you
know let's we define the vape the base
and we we allow the innovation to happen
on top of that I think that's what safar
was calling it is that that there is
there is definitions that are they're
being built and in different drafts in
coming out now you're asking to do the
design process backwards let's design
the packet formats now and we'll agree
on the use cases later you don't know
all the use cases before you start you
know some of them you've got a you've
got a good view as to where things are
going and you make the best engineering
decision you can with the information
that you have you know you
you take one step forward and you keep
taking another step forward and another
step forward until you get close to that
right solution and that's where we are
we're taking one step forward yo javi
okay I already mentioned I think the
issue not as a task officer drafter to
defend all the possible theories of SRH
I think that's the user I already
mentioned this is the design of this the
purpose of that er we are saying Edessa
the first is the integral in tikrit head
of the solution for the SRH so there's
the the segment and also this is the
segmental East and that here we can be
incorporated here in the one part this
is the first one I said in the one less
you the they are already that you
Decatur to draft a proposal to justify
that you are we that can be used in the
SRH maybe not a user th or the
hop-by-hop
this is the opener header so the one I
think that's the I think the purpose of
the SRH is adjusted who proposed this
the more capability of the network a
program I mean I think based on this one
I think we proposed this so the I think
a DC the Charter at the pace of the use
of the that your week
the theory either the in the pace draft
I think II I think the other that here
we may be in the future draft
we can't you find them all just to add
like when NPA the plane was defined not
all youth kisses for label would define
we are still defining you schedule for
labels so okay empty microphone lies I
guess that's that's some progress so I'm
not quite sure how to I think from up
here it sounded like the TLV she was the
sort of the biggest discussion topic
here and it's been discussed for quite
some time
personally I don't quite see the
difference but
between in all of these are containers
right that carry tlvs that are not yet
defined like the Hopis up options or the
destination options I'm not quite sure I
see sort of the significant difference
between this option and the other ones
we have and if I recall correctly and
I'm not sure I do but I think we did
discussion we had unlimited domains the
working group did ask you to add the H
Mac as you know an answer to the
security concerns of crossing limited
domain so I'm uncomfortable of you know
suggestions or going back on that but if
there are in clear interoperability
issues with the Till's we tell these
that are there you know please propose
text and and clarifications are famed
and clearly you know TVs that don't
exist
we can't specify but I think that's fine
but I don't think I don't think we have
any you know further ways of closing
this now I think as a part you know
letting the discussion continued yeah
what do you think public go during the
week
yes so we have asked the author's you
know with a strong encouragement to work
through all these issues during this
week we have a Friday session to
summarize this and you know please any
issues you have let's work through them
this week we have ample time between
Monday and you know today and Friday so
yeah
super thank you and just want to make a
note to those people with open issue so
I've reached out to get back to me and
we'll start let's start getting to work
thanks super thank you and Fernando
please come up
[Music]
oops
okay so this is for another gun
presenting document we go out or with a
young horse the title of the document is
slacks reaction to remembering events
there are a number of scenarios that you
know can lead to the problem that we are
discussing in our ID we're going to
focus just on one specific of those
scenarios so here we have a typical ipv6
deployment scenario in which you have a
CPA router that does DHCP prefix
delegation with the ISP and it
advertises a sub prefix we are slack on
the local network okay so the question
is for example what happens when these
cpu router crashes and reboots for
example what happens in many of these
scenarios is that when the CPE router
come back to life it does DHCP prefix
delegation again
the ISP it might get leased a different
prefix and it will advertise one of the
sub prefixes of the newly leased a
prefix on the local network obviously
the hosts on the local network will
configure addresses for you know their
newly advertised prefix but they will
normally also keep the addresses and the
roads corresponding to their now stale
prefix obviously the outcome of this is
that since the no previously configured
addresses have become invalid or stale
any communication employing those
addresses will fail obviously depending
on the scenario if it's a
six only scenario communication might
completely fail if there is before
connectivity and the application
employees happy eyeballs that might mean
that you know the resultant traffic is
ipv4 etc there are a couple of
deployments that you know might avoid
this problem there's the right document
I don't remember the 690 okay then write
690 document about the discusses the you
know the the assignment of prefixes and
they actually describe a little bit this
problem and what they do in that
document is recommend that ISPs lease
stable prefixes what persistent okay
persistent stable prefixes the idea is
obviously that you know if you always
list the same prefix to the CPE router
even if the CPU rotor crashes and
reboots it gets the same prefix so
nothing changes there there are a number
of reasons for which that might not be
the case but some of them you might
agree or not but I would say that at the
end of the day the thing is that you
have deployments that employ dynamic
prefixes for different reasons among
others there are ISPs that simply want
to cherish more for stable prefixes
against DC says deployment reality then
you might say well this is right I you
do things differently this is what we
have there's another thing that could be
done you know to avoid this problem to
some extent is to have the CPU routers
record the prefixes that have been
leased on stable storage so the idea is
that when the CPE router crashes and
reboots it remembers where was the
prefix that had been leased before and
the CP robber could somehow try to
invalidate the prefix that can be tricky
for a number of reasons
first of all if they're reboots are
frequent the CPU rudder might have to
record many prefixes not a single one of
course assuming multiple reboots and
reboots and dynamic prefixes they might
also need to advertise these prefixes
for quite a while the you know the
lifetime of the prefixes another thing
is that even if you try to invalidate
these prefixes according to RFC 48 61
but is lifetimes smaller than two hours
should not be honored so you can reduce
or you know they prefer lifetime as much
as you want but not the valid lifetime
meaning that you would keep these
prefixes or the address configured for
these prefixes for at least two hours
another thing related with this is that
there are implementations that enforce
limits on the number of addresses that
they will configure so since the CPS
cannot completely remove the addresses
configured for these prefixes well
you might by unprofor the addresses but
you will keep the old addresses so if
the reboots are frequent then you might
end up hitting the system specific
limits for you know the maximum number
of addresses that can be configured so
how we think this should be solved our
document discusses a number of things
that might be useful essentially and try
to put it simply the the main mitigation
for this problem that we proposed in the
document is to try to infer that when
you receive erase from the same router
that you were receiving erase before
these arrays include prefix information
options for other prefixes and not for
the
yeah for the previous one then you infer
that these prefixes have become stale
since we publish the talk this recommend
there was a lot of discussion actually
if you follow the 6-month discussion it
was over like 300 messages and while we
were discussing this topic yesterday
doing
and after the IEP team meeting there
were suggestions for example not to
let's say completely act in response of
these arrays again arrays from the same
router
they include prefix information options
but they don't advertise the previous
prefix but there have been suggestions
for example such as in this particular
situation try to perform some kind of
check before removing the addresses or
the prefixes to check if these prefixes
are valid or not
edek klein suggested for example to send
a packet to your same address but direct
the packet to the next hop router so if
the if that packet bounces back then
that's an indication that you know the
cpu rather still has you know still
considers the prefix to be there in a
sense
open open received of arrays with other
PA OS we might want to do something
about this what currently in the IDE is
to first of all UNPROFOR the the
addresses and then to remove them but
there are other things that are possible
such as for example check with a router
if the prefix is still there or not all
the things that might be of help
for example RFC 48 61 says that you
shouldn't honor
pios or the lifetime in particular not
the PIO as a whole
you shouldn't honor valid lifetimes
smaller than two hours the reasoning in
48 60
is to you know prevent the exploitation
of these pockets for performing
denial-of-service attacks our view is
that if you're going to trust the RS
there are so many different you know
attacks that could be performed that
just mitigating this particular one
doesn't seem to be that doesn't seem to
be you know much much sense to us if we
were to change this in 48 61 then for
example the CPI routers could actually
you know send erase on the local network
to actually disable completely disable
the prefix that has become stale another
thing that we discuss in the document
has to do with the lifetime of the
prefix information options for example
if you look up the default lifetimes
they are normally in the order of one
month okay and in the context of RFC a
t28 if I remember correctly for multi
prefix networks
the idea is normally that you'd somehow
tie each prefix to the router that
advertised it why because if you have
many routers and you're using many
prefixes on the same network if you just
send packets from a prefix to some
random router they are likely to be a
grace filter so one of the things we
discuss in the document is to cut the
lifetime of the pls to the router
lifetime and the current version of the
idea also suggests sending more freaking
arrays which based on discussion among a
number of folks it's a no-go but since
it's in D ID I mention it I'm mentioning
this in this slide comments Tim Berners
UNH Iowa so well my one question about
this forty eight sixty one allows for
invalidating lifetimes that are less
than
two hours so everything we tests you
know we give it a lifetime it's less
than two hours if you send it 0 it will
invalidate it right it's only when you
send at lifetimes greater than two hours
that it won't let you drop it to
directly to zero right so some people
for flashier a numbering basically drop
their prefix lifetimes the less than two
hours and then they can invalidate all
of the all of those rules that have to
do with lifetime are all based around
the two hour if it's longer than two
hours if it's shorter than two hours you
can just invalidate it using slack only
preferred lifetimes I think it's both
I'd have to go back and look but my
memory of this is that it's both
lifetimes that if they're less than two
hours you can wipe it out right so this
is to prevent the deal here is for
denial of service attack you just have
to set it higher than two like two hours
and then you won't run into this problem
excuse me you say that they don't if you
send the RAS with life's ten small
contours they just no no what happens
with the if you set it for more than two
hours and then you give it a value of
let's say five seconds it'll drop it to
two hours so if you had it set to twelve
hours and then you decided to drop it
you send it five seconds it will drop it
to two hours in some cases some of the
implementations will do that okay well
yeah the thing is that either way you
know if the RAS with lifetimes smaller
than two hours were honored then that
would allow for example the CPU rotors
that have recorded the least prefix on
stable storage to actually disable this
thing prefix on the local rate and
that's what you're gonna have to put in
there some sort of text around that
because in the case of less than two
hours you don't really have this problem
in the case of over two hours you have
to do something yes that that's gonna be
the problem sorry Richard Patterson on
that note it's so we already have
preferred lifetime so I think that's
what the document says around less than
two hours so fell a lifetime cannot be
reduced below two hours but the
preferred lifetime can so with with
sending preferred lifetime of 0 we can
deprecated the addresses
and that mostly solves this problem what
I think the suggestion to adapt 48.61 to
allow valid lifetime zero the only
problem that that solves is the one you
mentioned about having too many
hairdressers in the deprecated State
bound to the interface so for hosts that
have too many the valid lifetime would
solve that but that's the only thing it
was that was the only thing that will
solve them can't already solved with
preferred lifetime
yeah there's two things so on one hand
if you cannot let's say completely
remove the addresses yeah you can hit
the you know system limit on the maximum
number of configure a dresses then the
other thing is that if you cannot
completely remove the addresses if you
for some reason you might say it's
unlikely but you wouldn't be able to
communicate with a new owner of the
prefix yeah is that such a big problem
that we need to update 48 61 I'm not
saying it's a big problem yeah Andrew
McGregor on the reduce pio lifetimes
I don't recall whether there is anywhere
in the air see in any RFC that it says
that if you are redistributing a prefix
that you have learned through either
slack or DHCP that you should set its
lifetime to somewhat less than half of
the lifetime of the lease you have on it
but it really should sorry I don't
remember if we read distributing
prefixes there is something that says
that you should set the lifetime to less
than half of the lifetime of the lease
you have on it I think that the only
payment that is out there is that the
lifetime of the pios
should never be longer than the lease
lifetime that's it they should really be
listen half because of the semantics of
DHCP and there isn't a similar thing
with you know the previous point about
invalidating prefixes with slack it's it
has the same issue
mmm-hmm Jim Joan yeah just to echo what
Richard said at the mic just now also we
idea remember many many years ago when
we had the common problem of hosts
forming a six to four address from
Microsoft address sharing the people
turning that on and not realizing the
impact on the v6 network we had a little
demon that sat on the network basically
sent out Ras with zero preferred life
times essentially deprecated those
things I mean principle you could use
that kind of thing here but it'd be a
bit of a hat can be you never know where
there's another router that's issuing
these things you could do something
where if you saw a packet with a certain
source address to say oh that's no
longer a valid source and try and
deprecated it but I think the problem
here is there's lots of things you could
do that would be pretty hacky that's
there's some heuristics you can apply
and there's a one end this heuristics at
the other end there's hacky and I'm just
a little bit nervous that there's going
to be some very more hacky things
proposed here that are gonna cause
problems beyond their the worse than
what were actually trying to fix well in
I would say that you know in a situation
in which you don't have the CPA router
you know telling you that the perfect
has become stale you are in your somehow
trying to infer that that's the case you
know based on the conversations that we
had like you know yesterday and today so
for example in the IDE what we do is
open percept of a few arrays with a pios
other than the previous prefix first we
unprofor the address so it's not that we
remove it completely from scratch and
then when we receive a few more what we
do is we remove the addresses but there
have been other proposals such as
instead of reacting in that way try to
check the prefix try to check whether
that prefix is still valid for example
by sending a packet to yourself but
forwarding it to the nesco brother so if
it looks back that's an indication that
the prefix is still valid so it would be
like if you want like a more
conservative reaction than they want
that you know we have an idea and it's
that's that's directed perfectly fine so
conservative certainly sounds good I
think we'll be good to document for any
of these heuristics or whatever you want
to call them you know the constraints
that apply to them whether it's for a
single root situation multiple rooters
whether you're multihomed or not yeah
the other thing is what we do even in
what we have in dedi is we only let's
say I'm prefer or or remove the address
if it's being advertised by that single
router so we are considering the case in
which multiple routers are advertising
the same prefix in that case what we do
is we kind of like disassociate the
prefix with that specific router but
that doesn't mean that we are removing
the address so we try to accommodate the
case where the same prefix is being
advertised by multiple routers
journaling Cova so yeah I'm also been
concerned that we apply and kind of hike
a workaround to deal with broken routers
or administrative miss configuration so
I think it's a bit to have a solution
especially taking into account that
completely changes logic of processing
erase when you when you do not receive
some information it does not mean it's
active anymore
so you basically suggesting totally
changing the logic so I think that
changing the defaults of record anyway
at lifetimes totally does make sense
I believe we actually should have done
it long time ago because seven days and
one months it's like doesn't make any
sense from operational perspective I
believe it should be something similar
so preferred lifetime by default should
be similar to router lifetime avoided
lifetime should be I don't know twice
preferred lifetime or something like
that so it's definitely shouldn't be a
month
and this I believe would solve most of
the problems we should not actually
introduce any upper limit because you
say in copter outer lifetime in data
center environment I might have one week
preferred lifetime because even with my
router disappears I still might want to
have online communication so I think we
definitely need to change defaults it
would help regarding the problem of not
being able to talk to unlink prefix
after in ambient I'm not surely not sure
how big is the problem for home networks
you'll most likely do not talk to your
old prefix anyway much right so I don't
think we really need to tweak the
protocol to work around that issue and
another thing shall we think about
something like hey Bibles for source
addresses and if you have two other
addresses from different prefixes you
might need you might try to do kind of
head payables and see which one works
and use that one it's actually also
might help thinking caps to microphone
lines with the people standing there now
all right Eric not Marc so so one thing
that isn't clear to me and this is not
about what goes into our C's it's about
which devices do we think make sounds
tweaking all right
is it fixing these routers so that they
behave better and and is that something
that we should write down sort of rules
and if we do will they actually be
updated as opposed to saying oh let's
figure out some workaround hacky or not
where the host can actually be more
resilient towards those or are we gonna
end up doing both of them to deal with
this stuff it's not clear how much sort
of energy to put into this stuff and
where people are likely to fix their
implementations well if we had a good
feel for that you know then it sort of
would be more fruitful to explore what
are the best approaches for doing that
stuff that that move us forward and sort
of short term you know things we can do
short term as opposed to longer term I
need to make this better
Jimmy data regarding the default
lifetimes of the prefix I think there's
some probably confusion I agree that the
current protocol default is probably
wrong but in this particular model I
suspect it doesn't have much because
it's more likely that the router simply
copies or what advertised from the
prefix delegation so I think if we want
to change something that should be the
default setting of the prefix delegation
lifetime rather than a selfie
default prefix laughter so Tim do you
want the last comments just just one
thing that Fernando and I spoke with
each other about before this session was
that since there's been so much interest
in his draft we could use the Wednesday
time for the people interested in
meeting the smaller room and talk this
out as well I think you know phenomenal
you could send an invite for that I
think that's thirteen twenty on
Wednesday I don't know if there are any
free rooms but we can you know find a
bar if if nothing else but Tim do you
want to pay attention I was just gonna
say maybe we can tease out what could be
done here into at least three categories
one of just best practices and
recommendations for operators one is
sort of what implementers might do and
the third one is are there actual
changes to existing specifications that
are needed so maybe trying to think of
the different categories of things that
can be done name yeah yep super we had
close to my alberni but yeah super and
let's see free we do that Wednesday
session as well and we can bring these
things up super thanks a lot Fernando
and we'll squeeze in one more session
today because safar has to leave for
family reasons on on Friday so we'll do
that five minutes now thank you so far
yeah so I'll go quickly so this is a
work that is done with different vendors
and
Lee Dobbs and as long as with Mia this
is this work it started about one and a
half years ago so this I have presented
it earlier at six men at this cup of
times and also a couple of times as
spraying so I believe the body is very
very aware of the work and at the moment
we there are deployment that exists and
there is also a draft that was published
by Satoru this morning and that was
regarding former update to these
deployments so this draft has been
deployed at least in multiple networks
and additional deployments are coming so
from implementation point of view there
is a large number of platforms where we
have shipping code for the for the draft
as well as there was the Interop
activity that was done multi-vendor
Interop activity and that activity
result for that would be showcased in in
place for Congress next month in terms
of summary of the draft at the moment is
it basically just reuses the existing
ICMP mechanism for use cases of onn in a
service six network it also defines the
service flags obeyed the opiate was
initially defined in the SRS Draft but
as part of the comments during last call
this got moved out of resides us and
this draft actually define it exit at
the exact same location because there
are Hardware implementation that is
using the act it today and it also
defined 200 nm said and the purpose of
that set is to punt the packet either
without time is frame or with time stamp
and it also defined use case for in been
you am using a Suresh TV form assembly
of use cases it has ping for both the
end to end and segment by segment
traceroute end to end a segment a
segment and or actually hopper hopper
segment by segment in when UNM and pot
monitoring for the discussion on when
one in packets of a piggyback in the
actual data traffic distrust the excuse
of SR htlv and it is very important to
note that nodes not all nodes that would
be along the route for in when when M
will be capable of processing tell
wheeze or onm TL B's so for that matter
it is really up decision on the local
said the definition of the locus said
would know whether the locus said is
able to or should process the own n TLV
and in if the local set is such that the
node supports it and it is defined that
way to look at will be then the look up
to the TLD will happen so this is as
opposed to any other option that exists
through either destination option on hop
hop and this is why it's very important
to keep that TLV and the use case for
the tail v is properly defined here
there was a discussion to that effect
earlier from next step because of the
multiple deployment and probably a
status like the six men to adopt this
job there has been some discussion
whether this block belong to six men or
spring but I think is very clear that
this is really in its expand because of
the OPA designation because the TL we
use case so we really believe that this
is in six men I don't know if years had
chance to talk about that but I mean I
think that's I think pretty clear so I
really like the working of chair to a
start at option for poll and asked asked
the room in terms of the interests in in
taking on this particular taking on this
world and then once the working would
take on this word then we start working
on it in a collaborative fashion more
cooperative fashion and address address
your comments okay
as we have discussed
that a little bit and I think we'll hold
off with any other draft and we'd
finished the bass segment routing
document and then we can do another
option call on the mailing list when
when that's that's done so thank you
thank you so far and traditionally we
would have said see you in Montreal but
since we now have two sessions we'll see
you on Friday and the blue sheets please
can you pass those forward please well
you haven't gotten the blue sheets oh my
god that's a procedural failure we'll
see if we can fix that where are the
blue sheets the back can you bring them
up front here please
one very quick additional comment one of
the scheduled and not scheduled agenda
things around PVD stuff is being
presented in interior later so that's
potentially of interest to folks in this
room so if you're interested in some of
that work yeah head over there later so
you send an email there's an email on
the six man list on that fact as well
right yeah super thank you
[Music]