so Joel might be cheering this how about
good morning destination check this is
the six-man Working Group sure you're
all on the right place so this is our
second session for Prague we have some
well here's the note well should ask you
to recite it Minister trivia and Thank
You Michelle for Jabbar scribing this is
the agenda well I can see it here so the
first section is follow up on SRH we
hope to get the closure on the open
issues there's been a lot of work during
the week and then think well we'll see
how the discussion goes but I think
we're close
well I guess we have another slide on
that then there's two active drafts
Universal RA and the hop by hop into you
draft and then there's a set of
new drafts and we also have things that
we didn't have time in the agenda for
but I also want to call your attention
to the OEM the last two drafts I hope we
will have time but it there's some
chairs of the IP PBM group would like to
make sure we get a chance to look and
comment on these so the plan for the
segment routing is was to get the
closure during the week there's been a
lot of there's been discussion on the
email there's been side meetings we met
with Darren guests yesterday good
morning to go through the issue tracker
and several things got closed I think
there's still a open things that were
hopefully going to get closed today and
then our intention is to close the
current working group last call and
since what so that it will need to be a
new revision of the document posted and
when that's assuming we get agreement
today we will then do a new working
two-week working group last call on the
new document you know there's been a lot
of changes and it's been a long time
since we started and people should
review the whole document but at least
speaking for Olli and myself we would
really like to get this done in six map
so then it can go to the iesg and they
can have lots of fun discussions too so
any comments or questions on the agenda
okay good okay Darren so Bob's all about
sharing the joy today good
all right oh there's the screen so sr
header revision 17 like like bob had
said we've gone through a lot of work a
lot of late nights a lot of discussions
a lot of
very significant effort by a good number
of people so thanks everyone for your
input it's been really fantastic I want
to remind you of the quickly the
collaboration this isn't the I can only
collaboration this half in this drafts
been out for several years now five
years since first implementation I think
now our emails are at 105 1500 so maybe
more than one line protects our land
attack so one email per line attacks so
thanks this week for that we're now at
17 presentations this one included
alright so the collaboration started for
this this particular revision of the
draft on Tuesday morning I met a good
number of folks and really listen to
what the underlying issues were besides
just what was kind of in the ticket text
because that's not necessarily what
people are most concerned with we got a
clear definition of what closure looked
like for most of them and then followed
up with some prompt resolution on the
list and that continued as we started to
kind of work through the items all week
and learn more and and and get the text
out and then on Thursday we did add
tracking update with the chairs thanks
guys that was much appreciated where we
were able to go through and close a
whole bunch of more items and the items
that we closed during the week were some
tag related stuff where we sent out some
gifts those were accepted the SR HT all
these we sent out some deferred owes on
issue 38 those were good H Mac was
verified covers the destination or
revision 17 was acknowledged we had a
minor one for moving up our programming
was acknowledged some security related
items around edge filtering got
acknowledged as well when those were
closed by Thursday now where we stand
today this is a numerical order so that
the chairs can go through numerically
and and keep track
the first item number 54 is around TLB
limits and alignment of tlvs in the
segment routing at
the concern there was that while there
are limits in the in the text saying
don't exceed they'd like to the
extension header there was requests for
four more limits basically based on what
an implant implementation could
configure to limit the number of tlvs
that are processed and we added text or
diffs and sent them out to lists
indicating that an implementation can
limit the number of tlvs as they
processed on the alignment side of
things there was alignment text in the
draft but there's a feeling from some of
the working group members that that
alignment text should be in line with
what's done in RFC 8200 and that's the
NX plus y or x n+ y definition of
alignment so we reverted to or modified
the draft and sent out gifts to use the
xn plus y type of alignment definition
or alignment requirements and then allow
the source node to to align the tlvs as
necessary in order to meet that
requirement of each TLD type and that
was sent out that was sent out yesterday
the C padding one by Maya this was
closed a long time ago issue number 55
that's actually an old one we need that
well we don't need to do anything for
that it was close quite a while ago we
added the pad single byte pad there was
some muffs language and should must an
SH appear ones that were also closed
long ago so I consider those ones closed
now we had various minor issues from
Adrienne don't know if he's here we
confirmed the ones that were previously
existing are closed but then there's a
whole bunch of new nets that that were
brought up these are all primarily
editorial in nature and discs were
provided with them so we don't see
anything more that needs to be done
there follow the diffs 67 on padding and
h mac and flags this is a question of is
the support or is is the m is an
implementation required to support tlvs
and hvac and the answer from the working
group
has consistently been no and
implementation is not required to
support TL vh Mac that I responded to in
association with this question as well
so that one I think the working groups
responded to pretty well saying it's
closed 469 adding in the leading tlvs no
there's no text in here that talks about
adding and deleting tlvs so that ideas
closed the next one was for the SR
header should have some discussion
around aah
and discs were sent out for that saying
that the SR header for the purpose of
computing and a HIC v is mutable which
means the SR header can change so what H
does is it will zero out the the
portions of the SR header for the
computation of the age ICB where their
disk for that yes the district sent out
two lists on that as well number seven a
local policy is not defined oh yes okay
local policy is not fine so the term
local policy some folks have had an
issue as saying well we don't really
know what this local policy is described
and in discussion that actually came
down to well what you're really saying
is local configuration we'd be happy to
say local configuration may we be happy
to see local configuration we'd be happy
to see local configuration limits or
limits but local configuration I can
specify the things that local policy was
previously set up for in the draft so
we've changed the word from local policy
to local configuration and expect that
is gonna close this item now with that
that's the remainder of the items closed
the discs are on the list now the
question is do we close the last call
anything from the chairs perspective
will certainly say you know thanks a lot
to the authors and the reviewers for
having spent a lot of time this week to
getting everything resolved well feel
free not to come up on the mic what you
know as we've started with our plan is
to with all these issues closed consider
the working group last call of this
revision of it done we'll reissue a
working group last call that with a time
limit just to ensure that people get a
chance to review all of these changes
and well that's dependent on on revision
18 do you think you will have that out
so yeah very soon yeah I'm gonna I'm
gonna sleep on it before I release it so
so I'm thinking early next week Monday
Tuesday yeah yeah as if anyone has a
burning issue about this draft please
come up now or forever keep your silence
except of course on the mailing list
[Laughter]
yeah we need to pump up that number on
the mailing list well cool I think we're
done then for now that's that's for now
yeah way to go all right thank you
everybody thanks Cheers
so I'm next
oh right so for a completely different
topic the universal RA option which does
require a bit of suspense of disbelief
just like when you read a science
fiction book to accept the reality is
behind it so this is draft I posted a
few months ago in response to some
issues that we've seen which is to
follow I'll go more into that but it's
basically this view that which is a
reflection of of the idea failing
getting successfully deployed service
discovery in my view so it ends up with
we need these general carriers DHCP
being one RA being another from
signaling information or carrying any
information from the network to hosts
and so the idea was can we make this
more generic can we make it in a way
where you don't need to change the route
or implementations to add new
information objects and likewise you
don't need to change the sort of core RA
processing engine on the hosts and you
don't need to disturb the working group
every time you want to add a new object
so the proposal is is make a universal
array format will request number 42 from
the ini we'll see if you can get that
it's a CD DL concise state the
description language described objects
encoded in in seaboard and the point is
essentially to do this so you can on the
network side you describe your objects
as JSON object we can argue about the
exact formatting of this or you know
currently everything is text string so
they can be represented in Jason you
could make it more efficient with you
know binary encoding the
it's harder to represent in Jason and
likewise on the host side a user
application interested in one of these
object would just subscribe to a key and
you know that's x4 for example and I
will get notification from the RA
processing engine when it receives
objects for that key so I would you know
not require implementation changes in in
you know III Reuters then you had new
ones have been one of the problems we
had and likewise in you know if you did
the RA processing in the kernel or even
in separate process here's a typical CD
DL representation so this is an
experiment it's twofold one of them is
to you know how far can we get away with
not requiring an IDF specification for
these you know so the idea is to put
most of the description and most of what
you need into an eye on a registry so
you know it would just be the CD DL with
you know either reference to a external
document as a stable reference or we
would just have the description in the
ion or registry itself so as you see
this is a fairly neat way of describing
RA options so the problem I you know
with or I'm trying to solve and it says
you know remember that first slide
though is we're spending an inordinate
amount of time arguing about you know
these configuration objects if they
should be allowed to go into Ras you
know half the people say as well I don't
need it's uh not going to support
standardizing it and it takes an awful
long time to get it standardizing it
takes an awful long time to get it in
implementations and it's you know
questionable how much value we as a
working group add to this process so the
suggestion is you know new Ayano
registry CDL described objects which is
you know again self-contained into the
INR registry or a stable
friends and just expert review you know
so you needed the prep sixty-four option
for example you will just fill out the
form get that into Ayana or get through
expert review and they will get it to
the iron ore registry and you could
implement it if you wanted it or not
without any discussion in the working
group and so the experiment is along two
axes you know it's a technical one what
is the advantages of doing a self
describing describing format you know on
the implementations and the cost of
doing implementations and the time it
takes to deploy things and it's the
process part what's the consequences of
the working group stepping back and
letting go and not involving you know
these you know quality checks that
hopefully the working group applies to
these which means that you know take the
example of the RA only flagged for
example which you discuss for it for a
long time right lots of emails in this
case someone would just say well I
define one you city auntie you could of
course still discuss it but it would
still be there and available right so
there are there certainly interesting
consequences it has been you know I
think the third the email not to point
point out anyone but I think the third
email was say it was you know eg I could
use this mechanism if I love live
another you know in are s messages as
well I could build new protocols this
way right yes you can
but that's hopefully not that something
that would pass expert review so for the
experiment the proposed time is two
years your finger in the air would take
us about that much time to gather
information we would get a official code
point so it doesn't conflict with other
experiments and what are the success
parameters and I don't know I mean
absolutely no use of it would possibly
be a success massive use of it for it
well I don't know if it would be a
success but it certainly would be very
hard to shut down the experiment at that
point
so you know so so that is you know but
you could close the registry of course
but if lots of people use it it's very
hard to put that cash back in into the
bag so yes so you know this is an
individual draft the discussion I was
looking forward to especially around
that you know the process track it seems
like we can quite quickly agree on on
sort of the technical you know modeling
language encoding all of this thing has
been discussed that has mostly been
discussed at least not so much you know
the sort of working group implications
and the process implications of this so
yes please go oh no Jenny hygienic oh I
definitely like the idea of speeding up
deploying of new options right because
it means I can get the support much
faster on the router side side but I'm a
bit concerned so this would simplify
describing the option right so it will
be much faster however how do you think
we are going to define the host behavior
in this case because I don't I do not
think that are we spending too much time
discussing bits and bytes and the
options I think the most discussions are
normally happening around what hosts are
supposed to do and in this case it's
basically unspecified right so I would
be very concerned about how can i deploy
something if I don't know what hosts are
supposed to do so there is nothing here
that prohibits you from writing an IETF
document that describes that right and
there might be another one that you
could reference already that has uses
this object or very similar one right I
mean the DNS you know the our idea let
me see if I good example
so basically ipv6 only flag right right
I don't know maybe I was missing
sumption but I think the most discussion
was around host behavior so one flag
what few bits in the option is not
really a subject
Cashin so I do not think will be it will
would have helped much right on my damn
wrong here well for that particular one
I'm not sure the working group document
helps right oh right because you
basically ended up saying well it's
really up to the implementation what did
the implementer think makes sense for
that so I would be happy for that one
with a single line of text which says
you know signal system of e6 only link
but you know that's my very pragmatic
view so right Jen Eric Cline
the text in the document says if you
don't understand an option you ignore it
so there's there's that bit of host
behavior but if you define an option
then yeah and you want people to use it
then you should definitely have a
document to say what to do with the
option though the otherwise it'll be
ignored no so basically what I'm saying
I fully support the idea of introducing
new options in this format but I think
it should not be like implement that
until we describe what host is expected
to do because I'm not talking about
hosts do not understand Young's option
I'm talking about hos doing completely
different unpredictable stuff when they
receive that option hi Tony Polly so
speaking as one of the PVD authors
because you'd mentioned on the list hey
use this for PVD so in general I think
there's actually a really really good
mechanism I would like to see this used
for like a lot of basic option passed
through especially if all you really
need is the host just like passes up to
some other layers so they contribute it
seems really good I think in the case of
PVD specifically I think that is a
little bit more complex of case because
it's specifically meant to be containers
other options it has a large impact on
the host behavior when they have to
manage multiple different Ras that
they're getting and how there's interact
with advice however I imagine one of the
things that we'll want to do in the
future with pvd's is have because they
have containerized options have more
options to extend behavior there and
those should all be this definitely so I
think they complement each other well I
don't think switching PVD to one of
these is
the right thing to do but I think this
is very important work settlement and I
certainly wouldn't you know expect pvd's
do not have a stable reference to this
crap out there used right right I just
wanted to add Michael Abramson to what
Thomas said one of the use cases for PV
DS is four-legged sales to not
understand something so this would mean
we would have to have standards for all
the normal things let's go into an RA to
be in here as well if we you want to
apply this to the PVD case right so the
current sort of so if I want to send a
Pio to a PVD aware host that legacy are
not going to use I need to have Pio here
in the new format yeah that's already
here that's like raises lots of texture
is we're taking everything that we
already have all the options and putting
it here as well that's the experiment
right there's no you can put whatever
you like I mean as long as it would in
two thousand bytes Eric Clint I realize
now we also need an our flag I think
it's like 60 to 75 or something you know
guys take another flight video yeah but
all of it isn't that owner is right now
I I support
I liked the extensibility of this right
adding the MTU to the RI o was a nice
and easy thing to do so I do think that
if this is popular and successful
certain things we may net neck now is
the time to take care to minimize the
size of things right text strings for
prefixes they can be shorter than their
binary representations but they also
definitely cannot be I mean the reason
that I'd is it's very neat to have an
API on the rear side where the only
thing you need 13 is a JSON object and
if we are far binary encoding at least
you already have something that takes
the in theory can take something from a
radius server diameter
server and put it into a DHCP option
right so it'd be similar to that you
need a little bit more parsing right so
at least you need it would be nice to
not require implementation changes but
yeah sure we can say you know with the
v6 working group at least we can do the
v6 addresses in binary encoding and
requires support for that on the routes
but yeah yeah yeah now the
implementation on the regicide is 15
lines of code right it would be a little
bit more thank you dr. JOHN CARTER so
I'm very much in favor of this and I
think we should keep in the back of our
heads that having something in here
doesn't preclude us from noticing that
it's getting widely adopted and
hopefully reacting quickly and actually
moving it out of this so even so I don't
think we would necessarily be nailed
down to keeping something in this
Universal option and I think it's it's
the ideal environment to figure out if
something is actually getting adopted
and if that happens then decide whether
we want to keep it in here or create a
new option code after all and then have
some period of time where we have both
at the same time or something like that
Eric green idiot of I just said to David
really mad man I like the idea of course
pretty much like to meet a thing DVD is
mm coder there and your option is pretty
much a token are so it's not one or the
other and the last one and we preserve
buddies experimental status because you
are really looking for something which
may stands forever or you will get no
implementation in host for instance I
understand why you say experimental yeah
no and I think you know looking for
monitor status in the directive with an
experimental please use the mic for your
discussion 3 in the draft as far as I
know it's snark state whose experimental
yes
ah yeah Jenica took more comments so I'm
trying to think about a deployment
scenario so it means now I have to
duplicate information in both experiment
like universal array and existing array
options because I cannot be sure or
support this right no I mean well so
these examples are just you know you
could represent the current information
like this I would expect this to be used
for new objects which only exists in the
universal RA right so if people want and
part of the experiment is getting
experience with what the hell is people
going to put in there are there pitching
their beach be a routing table there
perhaps that wasn't a good idea we
should shut down the experiment right so
in the second comment like I am in a
favour for experiment but I just think
two gears my baby shot because I wonder
if it just me or getting something
supported on the Audion platforms and
getting it deployed after all this
qualification might take slightly longer
provide and I probably would not have
great devices just to get this right so
it need to fit into the standard
lifecycle management we have two
implementations already Tomek did one on
the hackathon for kia and and there's
one only poppy but of course that's not
the platform's you run presume air
cleaning it one of the things I forgot
to say earlier was I think there's some
you know doctrinal conflict about the
kind of things that belong in Ras and
the blowing elsewhere and I could try to
send some send a full request with some
text about what sort of qualifiers but
you know in general my perspective had
been that the things that you need to
use the network belong in in the RAS and
everything else belongs behind some
servers discovery mechanism of which we
have thousands so and the to take the
example from earlier in the week of the
SIP proxy the SIP proxy is not required
to use the network I must of course you
having a network whose sole purpose is
to serve a bunch of SIP only devices in
which case that is the purpose
and that seems like a reasonable thing
to put in here maybe yeah
well we have an infinite namespace here
right it's better but not an infinite
him to you yeah sure but you wouldn't I
mean yeah never cooperate it would only
put options that made sense for the
network so so I'd like to close to my
client to keep going but Alex Petrescu
generally I support the way it is
presented problem seems to be true the
way to address it seems to be
appropriate I would like to ask
clarification is it intended to be only
a router to host or all could it be also
a router to router well they are a
mechanism is by definition routed a host
right there is one open issue of you
know should it be allowed to go also in
host to router to signal what you want
it back as it sort of a DHCP like option
request option if you like or you know
but but but I mean Richard ureter
protocols are aiso not well the CP case
is special but then we say behaves in
host well right so it depends on what
you mean by router to router thing okay
I will take this question to the email
is to explain what is router to router
allow me a second question which is with
respect to judging success sometimes
success comes from the availability of
software tools to implement various
things now we talk about a new format
here we see Jason we hear C Bar C DDL I
think I've seen also sn1 I'm not sure
the syntax if you've seen that please go
and wash your eyes okay well I do like a
sn1 so the question was whether the
discussion on the format to be used is
still open or the decision is made
because C bar I'm afraid there is not
really many implementations so I'd like
to have as not discussed the format but
we should be discussing today whether we
want to do this
if we agree to do this then we can
discuss formats but right that's not the
main issue for us to decide so hold that
for later okay thank you
Timmy I support this I mean the the
protection here is that we we state that
any unrecognized options must be
silently ignored so the hosts were just
ignore it
my concern might be then this kind of an
implication of the document you might
generate or need extra Ras to convey
information so you're going to increase
the number of Ras at the scene on a
network with the obvious consequences of
that a little NIT in the document
there's a there's a bit where it says
the second purpose of the dot of the
experiment is to and then it ends there
so all right of a cliffhanger in the
document that you've left unfinished so
this is the key type of experiment the
URL is there pull requests welcome okay
okay yeah I was I can say yeah the other
thing it might be interesting to put in
a little appendix for the time being
maybe not to put in the final
publication is a list of proposed RA
options that have not made it through to
get an idea of the type of things that
people have proposed so picked up the
ones that are on our sort of schedule
now is never boot option it was proposed
didn't get the no gender lock but that's
a URL for beauty information it's well
it's you know the only one we're talking
about you know they pivot ease the
pressure 64 is there yeah I think that
the point is if this is something that
removes the barrier to people getting
things out there then having a look at
in the last few years as if we can do it
easily I sound like I'm volunteering
here so just to see what sort of things
people were putting forward you sort of
can wave at start people all these
options it might be nice to have a list
of what has been put forward is a right
draft I mean it's the ones we have
discussed a lot right there are so you
know good examples of if we have had
this at least viewed saved all the
working group time discussing them but
you know what yeah and we don't really
know what else is could be out there
right the transfer box original question
yes support definitely David I'm pablor
speaking as someone who
person FRR I'm happy to implement this
if I can find the appropriate libraries
and I'm happy to ship it so just as a
statement and Michael Abram suggested I
support this I would just like us to
look into the implications when it comes
to the MTU I'm worried about this and
some of this actually is multicast which
it has implications on discussions on
Wi-Fi and multicast so and if we think
that this is going to grow which means
that we're going to send more
unsolicited arrays I would like us to
think about that and conceivably come up
with something that means that this is
from the rocket to the host is sent as a
unicast only is it and it's never a
broadcaster - Romana cast it and I think
that's also one reason I proposed this
as an experiment so we gave a song room
for for learning along the way as
opposed to sorting out all these issues
right because if we think that this
might have for a while turn out to be
several kilobytes of information it
might be better to just keep it out of
the orient and invent something more
like I don't know yeah but whatever we
come up with so a new DNS SD would be
mentioned here so we probably need to
figure out like what should go in there
and what you're going so I'm Anita says
home sorry I have a a picture of my
family
you can send that over sending that on
the link so everyone knows right so this
is what it what happened with you snip
right let's just want to I'm not doing
anything with our ear in it now but this
looks it looks like a lot of fun yes so
did Suresh get the last word oh yes so
one thing I didn't see cover in the
draft that I like to see is like how do
you handle conflicts right so from let's
say you have some information that came
in from DHCP that could also be given by
this I'd like you know how do we resolve
who goes first and things like that
that's something I would like to have
some information so I'm I'm supportive
of the experiment but I would like to
see a little bit more text about like
you know sending configuration
information through different means and
how do you the solve the complex yeah
pull requests welcome like you know I
asked you to do this re all right good
I mean I have some concerns to you know
I'm worried that this is we this is
gonna become very popular there's gonna
be a lot of new stuff they'll be very
little barrier so we need to be careful
about how what we require to be
specified but it's gonna hit yeah so I
don't know how we do that and I'm not
sure how to thinking about it there's a
lot to learn here but once we get this
going with a type I think we won't be
able to stop it so in any case lots
let's this discuss but I think there was
a lot at least what I heard in the room
was a lot of support for this so good
thank you
okay it's a it's a bit strange
presenting something you think might be
a bad idea and also support you know oh
well let me go for another 30 year old
idea my co-chair Gauri is here as well I
think you're two in a box
well it's yes or it's no box
yeah they got rid of the pink box now
it's just an X on the floor so this this
is the ipv6 minimum path MTU hi-hop
option I guess we should have considered
putting it in an RA instead way doesn't
work that's my other graph do a double
act here so we all thought path MTU
discovery kind of work because it's very
widely implemented and it does work but
it's not really useful it's not working
well so we need something better and
there's two bits to this
there's maybe an important piece of the
transport layer and actually checking
what works and verifying it but here
there's a hop option and the hop by hop
option is basically something new that
we came up with which was something old
that we discovered afterwards but and
it's maybe a good idea now because these
two things come together and it can help
it doesn't help everywhere that we
ascertain that it helps in some places
so they're the new draft that was
published this month we changed this to
experimental from standards track where
I'm at least gary has convinced me
there's a lot we need to learn before we
try to do this permanently or something
the original draft just had it before
particular domains but you know this is
there's a lot we need some real data
here before we can decide what to do add
a new motivation and problem solved
section to better describe the purpose
and started describing experiments that
we wanted to do and some editorial
changes the motivation you know as Barry
said you know a MTU discovery as in a
toe 201 doesn't work well in all places
in the Internet I mean it does work but
it's not reliable enough for what we
want to do nodes in the middle may not
send a nice compact it to a big message
you know for various reasons it may not
get back to the source nodes are mostly
relying on MSS for TCP and we see a lot
of defaults to 1280 you know and
protocols that tunnel or encapsulate end
up reducing MTU and you know these
mechanisms don't work there and you know
we also sort of observing that you know
as links are getting faster 10 100
Gigabit Ethernet you know
if we're limited to 1280 octets the
packets per second rate starts to go way
up and you know the difference between
1280 and 9000 at 10 say a 10 gig is
significant and so if we want notes to
be able to do this if we can get to
bigger packets it's actually a big win
and these are the 10 gig numbers and you
know ya add multiple ooh I tend to get a
hundred gig and we're not gonna stop
there so if we could get ipv6 to work
better with bigger empty use I think it
would be a real win so turns out it's
possible just to send a message through
the network in the forward direction
asking what MTU is supported and then we
can figure out what actually is deployed
and then we can start using this but the
point is that such as the sender who
needs the message so how do you get this
information back to the source of the
ipv6 packet well we could send a path to
packet to big message an ICMP message
from there involved right back to the
source and this isn't perhaps as stupid
as it seems because we do get other ICMP
messages back from the remote all the
way back to the source because they're
not cherished on path maybe the state in
middleboxes let you forward these so
this could be a cool thing to do and
we're interesting people opinion on that
and particularly measurements on where
that works because that could be helpful
and we could also put the value that we
find out for the forward path in the
same pot by hop option using the return
path and return that value back to the
sender so the source knows this from
extension header option that's got
different failure modes pretty salsa
possible and we could also of course
perhaps easiest of all when the
transport does it we could simply put
the value in a transport parameter or
return it back over the top of the
transport possibly encrypted if you have
something like quick you just simply
return this is a message size value back
to the source
so now we have
three ways of getting feedback which
complicates it makes it more of an
experiment but I think there's good
possibilities here that one or perhaps
more and might succeed if we can make
this a lot more robust all three might
not be a bad thing but this is what we
want to find out all right okay so and
this we think it's useful thing to keep
this document going and and standardize
it as an experiment because there are
experiments to do and in fact there are
many expands to do but some of them are
listed here and the first one is the one
I've just identified how likely is it
that the hop by hop option will be
forwarded to the remote node remember
this is not necessarily a data packet or
it may be a duplicate packet of a
transport protocol so we don't require
it to get there we just want to know
what its fate is is does the packet it
tick with the hop by hop option get
discarded and does it traverse the link
and get ignored and just something else
happen maybe he actually gets updated
how likely is it the ICMP message is
returned to the source way as originated
from the endpoint but its rigidity from
the nor to rather than from a box on the
path because then you don't have routing
issues etc so it works with load
balancers how easy is this to implement
aha we've already started that we've
been doing stuff at the hackathon and we
had quite a lot of fun that and quite a
lot of success in making little things
work so this might be a really good
place to drill and how much support is
there for jump or friends anyway one of
the motivations here is to fix tunnels
where you get less and less m to you but
one of them is to send bigger and bigger
packets now we know Ethernet MTU in its
in homes and with with smaller NICs is
limited but how much support is that
really for jumper friends out there
can we actually start moving up to that
and I think there are more questions I
have a lot more but I thought these were
the ones we could actually drill into
initially
Janene Cova I was just realized so you
don't necessarily have to get make it
too big back you can get destination
unreachable and if enough of the your
head there will be included you can
actually get that information even if
you know doesn't support this right if
we know doesn't recognize that option
yeah I think that's quite cool yeah and
I am still going to give you some data
on the probability of getting that was
an old yeah yeah please join give data
right Eric Cline I think if you're
interested in Gemma Graham's technically
they can be of the empty you can be a
32-bit number right I think it was
Ethernet Jumbo's who were talking about
enough to be six Jumbo's just a minute
I'm I'm not that ambitious um a 2k 4k 9k
16 um you know these are sorting numbers
I'm thinking of not-not-not UDP packets
that are enormous because the MTU option
in the are a and in the jumbo all that
stuff is 4 bytes so cool if you think
that believes well no no I mean I'm fine
with them too and we can change the spec
to say if it's if the option length is 4
that our is 6 then you know then you
know why also I was gonna suggest some
text about is it the the socket API 35
42 if you have received path MTU options
set it would be good to get this bubbled
up to the app I think it's probably a
very simple mention to suggest that in
such behavior Thanks yeah agree with Al
Michaels I just wanted to comment on the
MTU Ethernet CRC calculation start to
break down if you go way above 9 K I
think it's around 10 11 12 that's where
you start to risk getting bit errors
that are not detected by the C or C
algorithm in news so with and since
Ethernet is eating the world this is
like a practical thing we would need
other link layers to
larger packets yeah for a template from
Boeing so I know this was close came up
on the list and you guys responded to it
but in 1990 RFC 1063 tried to do exactly
the same thing and a lot of people put a
lot of hard work into it at that time
frankly I think they were on the right
track which I think you are too I think
what happened back then is they were
under a time pressure they needed to get
something out and that's where a lot of
91 came from so I think we're back to
maybe getting on the right track again
but it's good to look at that history
lesson I think it's it's important to
see that a lot of people put a lot of
time into it the next version of in
draft will probably cite that okay
artwork are RFC 1063 and if people who
were involved in that one to help us
write the text around that that would be
great I like history to know why we did
things differently in the past we may
want to do them again I think this case
we probably do that don't they applies
to people born before 1988 I think I
qualify so I did a quick check of the
Linux kernel and as far as I can see it
does pass hph options along but it
doesn't look at them while forwarding
and I believe that this is the result
you will get from most if not even all
routers and I think that is something to
keep in mind for this because this is
going to be hard to change well so I you
are correct that's the status code today
I would at least like to think that if
we can show that this would be
compelling and provides better overall
service on the internet that that will
encourage people to do it I don't think
we have to assume that implementations
will never do anything they don't do
today right but let me also make the
argument that this is something where we
need to consider making it as easy as
possible for routers to actually
implemented it and I'm not sure that the
nigth option is the best way to do that
maybe maybe it's possible to find some
way to transportus that is easier to
pick out from the general traffic flow
by by the raw by the rotor itself so
another
during the hackathon I actually wanted
to do that performance tests difference
between you know what's the cost of
processing an exception packet for path
MTU T today versus stamping it with the
help I help option so I'll try to get
that work done and publish that
Charita one other question to tackle as
part of this experiment would be the
forwarding behavior changes when hopper
hop option is present if the path is
taken written without the hop-by-hop
option would would change that would be
important even for any other hop-by-hop
functions yes and we want to do stuff in
this space to figure this out however we
also or at least I do as a transport
person assert this is only a hint so we
would have to have a transport layer
mechanism to verify the bigger packet
worked or not
so the hint would be completely wrong if
they took a different path and we want
to know about that
but it would have probably derailed the
transport it got a little bit of wood
what do you think about I mean you said
that transport return path is obviously
the most reliable one and so you
mentioned quick and clearly quit the
patient on the table so we can do a lot
of things to it now there is another
transport that is commonly used in the
Internet TCP and what do you think about
opening up that thing in and maybe
adding ability to set MSS after
handshake could be used very useful for
your purposes could probably be useful
for others too so you want to
renegotiate MSS when you discover
something bigger this kind of a weird
thing with MSS yeah if you tell it yeah
well you you tell how much office space
you have and we just not change but yeah
I see what you're saying that and
interesting and let's think about this
we also need to think about how MSS
clamping would it would interact if you
didn't send it on a sin but yeah right I
mean MSS clamping is Pandu for
really values for symmetric pass anyway
so this thing would be for a symmetric
path would work for a symmetric basis as
well let's talk I think I'll look close
the line by Magna Steyr go ahead Tom
Jones and so just an American Davis
questions on implementation so the saga
API exposes the hop-by-hop data it comes
through and this is how we did the Linux
implementation of the hackathon and in
the forwarding paths the hop-by-hop
option processing is not great like this
is where the spiders live in the network
stack we've never done anything with
this and but it's not gonna be horrific
to add support so we could do this
Micron's and so in my twenty years I've
seen ICMP the TTL expired I could just
go from being handled by the cpu to be
done on the line card I guess then fuses
all have you talked to the silicon guys
but doing the hop-by-hop option in
silicon and have the MP you been up to
they they say it never needs to get
punted to anything intelligent not yeah
okay because I think that was a good
question it'll be very valuable to make
it sure it's silicon friendly and I know
I've talked to them and some they can
look like 128 bits into the 128 bytes
into the packet and I don't know what
they then can do but if you can do this
I mean we're going you're going to have
to handle like 10k 100k paid PPS of
these as we progress up in line speeding
you're going to have four hundred eight
hundred ten one terabits per second line
cards it's going to be a lot of ppso or
not buy up options that the line card is
going to have to process right and then
there's another question about you only
put these in the syn packets and then
occasionally or do you put them in all
pack right but we definitely want to
make this silicon friendly sorry
I I definitely agree with this because
commentary about making this line I'm
very worried about in general that we
losing the possibility to have the
network communicate and hosts and using
the
the the IP layer so the network layer to
do this communication otherwise you're
gonna have to do this processing in
hacks in transport stacks level and
that's really worrying for me so I had
closed the mic liner but if you're very
quick please okay yeah I'll just repeat
something that I told David Lampeter I
think it could very well be that devices
that already knew to CPMs s clamping can
easily handle this and devices that
don't won't and that's probably plenty
okay and there's another way to use this
in conjunction with your ongoing with an
ongoing protocol session and that would
be to just basically in parallel send
send this option from the source to the
desk with no next protocol there's like
49 or something C 559 thank you to the
next to the host so you basically could
keep your application trapping the same
I just how to probe this in parallel
this is probably easy to thank you so
just do this quickly so as Tom mentioned
we played with this at the hackathon
last weekend was the Linux host
implementation a BSD post implementation
VPP router implementation before a
router implementation and I did a
Wireshark did the sector I got to learn
bunch of stuff overall work pretty well
but we decided to change it of course it
is an experiment so we did a version
that this is not in the draft so this
has a return value and a return flag or
turn bid I guess I called it here
so if the source wants the destination
to send back the MTU it received in a
hop-by-hop option it sets the flag and
then and then the host with the
destination would put it in the return
value and in order to keep this to still
be eight bytes to not have it grow into
sixteen if you notice we take you can
only send even size
empty used back so you divide you know
so it's shortened essentially divided by
two but you know I think if we lose one
one bite of NTU it's not really a big
deal and keeping this short seemed like
a good thing so that's why we
experimented with and this is what it
looks like in Wireshark and I've almost
got this completed except for it notice
it doesn't show what the next protocol
is Wireshark is a little challenging
when you're not doing the end protocol
so one yeah I'll keep at this
so yes continue to talk to us you know
there's gonna be some experimenting with
this going forward and we hope to have
some data by the next IDF so I think
we're almost out of time if they're
going for a lasts so I was going to say
if you have questions or comments this
is a thing we intend to increase our
work upon as we go in the towards the
next IETF and hopefully report more next
IDF so please talk to us not just now
but as we continue to do this yeah
absolutely
I think there's a lot of work you know
interest in this work it doesn't
necessarily have to be that this is a
solution but I mean this collaboration
that we now have with the transport area
is so you know I encourage everyone to
accommodate up come a new suggestions
for that marker this is kind of empty
Yuri take Rome don't sit there like
you're not going to run up here and do
your twenty minutes if you can do it in
20 minutes our bio beer in for a
six-pack
okay run Bonica and there are four
drafts I'll pause for questions after
the second one the first one is about
the VPN contact no it's not first one's
about okay I want this one yes yes sorry
VPN compressed center yeah we got a bit
um keep in mind the segment routing
header that we just approved because
this isn't the same same line of thought
if you take a look at network
programming you'll find that there are
two classes of SIDS Trant a transport
Sid that steers a packet to a terminal
segment of an ipv6 tunnel it's processed
by the non terminal segments segments
left greater than 0 and examples of
these in the SRA char end and end X
there are a little relatively few of
these in fact two and an index and their
semantics is very simple very little
information is carried in a transport
set by contrast we have service SIDS
they determine the behavior at a
terminal segment they're processed only
when segments left equals zero at the
terminal segment and examples of these
are end d x4 and d x6 by the way this
this is all familiar to folks who've
read the network programming draft and
they're relatively many of these they
have a very rich semantics and because
of that it takes very many bytes to
carry them in any event in ipv6 we have
two ways to deliver instructions to
downstream nodes we have routing
extension headers that steer packets
from an ingress to an egress they're
processed at non terminal segments when
segments left is greater than 0 and they
are well positioned to carry transport
sets and by contrast we have destination
options that determine behavior at the
egress they're processed only at the
terminal segment that's the same when
segments left is great equal to 0 or
when there's no routing extension header
at all and they're well positioned to
carry service heads now there's one more
observation we need to make and that's
the problem with routing headers they're
too long
typically they take 8 bytes of overhead
4 bytes are mandatory mandated by 8200
most routing headers have 4 more bytes
typically they represent each CID in 16
so a routing header with three SIDS is
56 bytes long when it gets much longer
than three sets let's say six or eight
its impractically long
these aren't ASIC friendly processing
long extension headers is
computationally expensive that's one of
the reasons you don't see very many
extent routing headers on the Internet
today
also they impose unreasonable bandwidth
overhead short packets less than 500
bytes are very common on the Internet
routing headers with three SIDS may
become common and a routing header with
three SIDS would impose a 10% bandwidth
overhead so where are we going with this
we're proposing two things first to
encode transports heads in a new
compressed routing header and we talked
about that in graph Bonica compressed
routing header it's a topic of this talk
and we're also talking about encoding
service SIDS in a new ipv6 destination
option actually a set of new ipv6
destination options one of which is
draft Bonica 6-man BPM desktop it's the
topic of the next talk now what does
this new routing header look like well
the first four bytes are incredibly
familiar they're mandated by RFC 8200
the fifth byte should look familiar it's
exactly the same as the segment routing
header it's the next two bits that are
new they tell you how much we've
compressed each cid a cid can be
represented by 8 16 or 32 bits and let's
say we've talked about all this stuff
ready um comm tells you whether the SIDS
are 8 16 or 32 bits each sid maps to an
ipv6 address through either a table out
rhythm or look up and the ipv6 address
is copied to the destination address of
the ipv6 header just like any other
routing header the interesting thing
about this ipv6 address it's a real ipv6
address it identifies an interface
not a said it carries no semantics
beyond what RFC 42 91 gives it so for
those of you who were in love with
packet formats this is what the
compressed routing header looks like
when the CID is encoded in eight bits
you can see you can get eight SIDS and a
16 byte header if you need a little more
to encode your transport SIDS here it is
encoded in 16 bits and here it is
encoded in 32 bits we have some
compliance extras here an ipv6 address
semantics remains unchanged once we
translate us into an ipv6 address and
copy it to the destination address it
has no semantics beyond what 4291 gives
you there's no need for transit routers
ever to insert or delete if extension
headers there's no need to have two
instances of the CRH in the same packet
extension headers a process for Cle in
the order that they appear in the packet
no need to backtrack or anything like
that the status we have multiple
operators who've expressed interest in
this
we have prototypes under development in
juniper both on the forwarding plane and
Isis extensions to supports it
advertisement they'll also be in the
next few days
BGP well BGP advertisements to support
the VPN destination option and what
we're asking for is wide review in
spring and six-man and after some review
a call for adoption in six-man working
group anyhow stop for questions here so
we actually don't have time for
discussion so again and we expect you to
catch up on the next three okay okay oh
you can't be way behind okay if you can
get me to argue over that you can give
me the hook after the next one okay BPM
destination option here is the anatomy
of a VPN you have pease that learn
routes from CES a PE advert
associates the egress PE associates
information VPN context information with
a router that's learned from a seee
advertises it to an ingress PE when the
ingress PE gets a packet for that route
it prepends VPN context information it
to the payload it puts that in a tunnel
and sends it off to the egress the
egress pops it off now what does the
staff look like when it's sent across
that tunnel you have payload you have
VPN destination options with VPN context
information a compressed routing header
which is optional if you're taking any
path other than the least cost path and
an ipv6 header you see the new thing
that we're introducing here is the VPN
context informations it's where we put
VPN services do you have a need for
security with this no problem just put
an authentication header or an ESP
between them what does this new option
look like well it's got an option type
act bits or would not recognize this
guard whoa no change bit a zero you have
variable length data and so you can
encode as much information or as little
as you need in your VPN context
information and you have data to go with
it again the status we have operators
expressing interest we're building
prototypes inside juniper looking for
comment on the mailing list next steps
same thing wide review call for adoption
next ok this sorry thank you ok next
nope that's not next a.m. is next
not this one yeah no not that one no
yeah
[Music]
okay I'll do it without slides not a
problem no how yeah well go ahead and
this one right okay that one thank you
okay we have a new option if you want to
elicit OAM from a packet you put this
that option and either a hop-by-hop
a destination a destination header that
precedes a routing a header or in the
ultimate destination depending on
whether you want away M information from
every hop along a path from segment end
points only or from the ultimate
destination the OAM option has some
flags in it
the flags elicit of behavior from the
processing node the behavior is log a
packet count a packet send an ICMP
message to the packet source obviously
rate limited or send telemetry to your
NMS now when you say log a packet what
information goes in that log message as
much as the processing node can put in
it it might have a very accurate
timestamp but if it can do it it might
have what port it came on and on if it
can do it whatever it can do the same
for counters what counter does it go
into whichever one the processing node
is configured to put these B's in the
policy can be as complex or as simple as
you need what does the packet look like
well like this the interesting thing is
the act bits are 0 0 skip it if you
don't understand it the change bit is 0
what does that look like what does the
ICM we define a new ICMP message to send
in response to that what does it look
like it looks like this it has a
timestamp it has the original Datagram
next steps review call for adoption that
one am i close to getting the beer you
are very close to get you to ok this one
is just for completeness we don't expect
it to be used very often at all what
happens remember the first message where
we had the CRH that had these very
narrow bandwidth SIDS along the way well
what happens if you
want to use a CRH and you have a
high-bandwidth sit in the middle well we
have this thing called the segment end
point option it's to convey information
to selected end points in a service
cheat so let's say you have a service
chain with five elements in it you want
to get information to element 3 and
element 4 you put a destination option
header in front of the routing header
it's processed by every segment end
point you put this new option in the
destination option header it has a
segments left field
it gets decremented just like the
segments segments left field in the
routing header it also has a list of
containers in it each container has a
segment identifier and an option when
segments left equals the segment
identifier then you execute the option
it's a way to have a high bandwidth
segment identifier in the middle of a
CRH now do we expect this to be used
often no in fact you might choose if you
have a path that has a high bandwidth
said in the middle of it to use an SRH
so for some paths you might use an S RH
because you need that you need that for
others you might use a CR H but if you
just have maybe one segment in the
middle of it that has a high bandwidth
you might use a CR H with this again
call for adoption wide review and I
think I have beer coming you absolutely
have beer coming alright so we're
thinking at the end of the set of
lightning talks we have two more
lightning talks
we could take questions and all of them
if we have any time left then without
your ring there you will still get there
so Frank can you please come up let's
see if I can this is a session about
getting beer do you just apply for
lightning talks to get beer okay that's
the method to go
wine beer out of you cool all right so
this is a quick ask to IP from IP p.m.
to six men working group to go and give
us some guidance on how to proceed with
IOM in ipv6 so hopefully everybody's
seen I am in a nutshell so what we're
doing is we're adding operational
metadata into the packets very much like
what ron was proposing and we had a
discussion with ron to go and see
whether or what he's doing can be kind
of synchronized with the work that
happens in IP PM because there is a
shitload of overlap and so we're adding
metadata and we need to find a place in
v6 to carry the metadata so the ass
two-six man from IP PM is really we want
to go and carry the metadata in
extension headers and we need option
type Co points both for hop-by-hop
as well as destination options depending
on how we carry these things and well we
need this thumbs up yeah it goes the
same way as what was done for TBM PDM
earlier on that ended up in in an IP PM
shepherd at our of c so i do 250 so that
we can go and progress that work in IBM
so what do we want to go and do we have
right now in iom we have four types of
data that we're encapsulating two types
are tracing data which is pre-allocated
tracing or incremental tracing that
would go into an hop by option we have
proof of transit data ie proving that
your program progressing through a
predefined set of nodes and that we have
a edge to edge option which is just
encapsulated at one point not book that
throughout the network and then D
capsulated the other node which is what
we need a destination option code point
for so the ask is readier well we have a
set of metadata defined that is already
defined in a draft and a working group
draft in AI ppm and we want to go and
drop that into extension matters
that isn't without problems right so
after we we started the working group
discussion prior to the ITF meeting in
Bangkok at that spurred a bunch of
additional questions and so we thought
like ah yes just asking for coat points
is one thing but in addition to that you
want to go and have deployment
considerations that go on top of that so
we explained how the option would be
used because that's super useful for
operators to consider right and because
there is problems with that we don't
want to go and half the packet
forwarding behavior really changed due
to IOM being present the IOM shouldn't
we're adding things it shouldn't go and
exceed the power time to you is because
that earlier if somebody adds IOM
information well you need to make sure
that anything ICMP goes back to the guy
who added that information as opposed to
somebody else and we should go and find
information Co and come up with
mechanisms that allow us to understand
if there is misbehavior in the network
without too much of a pain right so if
that information would go or the
extension header would go somewhere
where it shouldn't go then well someone
should be able to go and detect and then
obviously ward on are gonna go to ear to
what is it said in 8200 ie
not inserting instead extension headers
on the fly and what the deployment
option drafts what they what the
Department RAF then talks about is a
couple of individual use cases on how
you can skin that cat with one or the
other trying trade off if you're
sourcing and terminating packets right
at the host then you don't need double n
cap you can insert the header there you
could terminate the header at the
destination in transit networks if you
just want to go and do it on one
particular individual domain then well
there's multiple source of what I would
call double n cap you can do ipv6 and
ipv6 and there is options whether you
use a dedicated EULA address in the
overlay so that well even if packets
leak they can never have a leak because
I can't be forward if there is no
seeing an eroding up for them we could
also choose for a different option where
we would use the same destination
address which makes it easier to make
the path of congruent and then obviously
you could use other parent protocols to
go and carry that information so you
don't need necessarily need v6 and v6
but if you're going to go and carry the
information in genève well you can go
and carry it somewhere else I want to go
and come back to the main ass right we
we really asked you to go and help us so
that we can unlock the work and progress
it in I ppm and I don't know well know
whether Tommy who by believers here the
chair of I ppm can add additional color
to that particular ask maybe you can go
and give us a little bit of background
off the discussion that we had on on
Monday on that very tough topic and
that's it for me thank you sure thank
you Frank yes I think the question and
the feedback we'd like to get from both
the chairs and the group in any any
basic comments are welcome is what's the
most appropriate place to do this work
in the past we have done work outside of
six men we wanna see is that appropriate
to do here how much do we want to do
here what type of relationship do we
want to do on the work as far as the
review I think from our perspective we
are fine doing this particular part of
the work in IPM the IOM work in general
has a lot of different encapsulation
possibilities this is one of the
protocols that uses it some of those
will make potentially more sense to
belong in the working group that owned
the protocols that they're encapsulating
with something like this I think is a
bit more well understood and I think we
could feel confident doing that in IPM
if that is what the ring group believes
is the right thing to do but if Britain
group believes that this should all be
specified in six men and be done here we
would like to know that as well um so
we'd like to essentially just get an
answer of what is the right place to
pursue this work in if it needs changes
in review that can happen in the future
but I think the main thing we want to
know right now swear thank you shooting
from flowey I think here we all agree
that we should be carefully
later the ipv6 encapsulation of the IOM
and but here the proposal is we are
proposing here is like to put the hem
data into the hopper how about that's
Tunisian option but if we look at the
ipv6 extension header order that is
before the RH so in the tracing mode the
the IOM data along the path is going to
become very large so we are going to
push the RH out of the parsing deaths
and so that will damage the performance
the forwarding performance in the data
plane and and we also have them the same
thought on this topic and we that was in
the agenda but we didn't get the slot
but fortunately we are going to present
in the next session in the RTG so
probably that we could contribute and
provide some more thoughts on this topic
so we had ten minutes left of this
session so you can ask questions both
for Frank and for for Iran I guess yes
please
Michael Abram okay you go back to the
consideration slide that had like six
points when I read this the first thing
that came to mind is none of this is
true with the proposed approach
Hoppa Hall Petters inserting stuff
that's gonna affect the ecmp does it
doing what I thought you were do I am
read the the draft I just saw the
presentation now you just violates all
these things I understand somebody will
read the draft right how about that so
we better straight up so all of that
right but we're trying to go and
mitigate these concerns as much as we
can if there is other deployment options
that can be considered let's go and
consider them there was no free lunch
right so that's something you changed
some
and if we were to go and deal with that
change in the most modest and and
operationally friendly way okay so are
you going to continue to do this and v6
ops as well or what where is this going
to be discussed like the operational so
I think that was the overall question on
guidance on where we should go to the
work right now well they're the core of
the work is really an IP PM this is
where the data draft happens this is
where export considerations happen this
is where the yang models are being done
there is a load of documents against how
do you encapsulate that into multiple
protocols also presented in IP p.m. at
that one well in particular and this is
again had jumping between these two
deployment considerations could go to v6
ops I think it helps if we have a way
that we think help keep some consistency
and the energy of the people that really
care about that in a relatively concise
forum right now but I feel it a little
bit like I'm on a dating tour and I have
to go and kiss every single bride and
figure that one out not that I don't
like that right but enjoy it because you
are yeah at some point right you want to
go and take a decision and and and
making everybody do the dating tour not
sure right so we need to move this long
sure Ash's racist hand so I'm gonna on
him yeah sure thanks Bob so the idea is
like Michael I'd personally for me like
this should go and I am the work should
be done in IP p.m. and the way is six -
shot at us like six man gets like final
say over whether this gonna work so I
think it's better that he's like you
know talk about this in six-man and see
if there's like some showstoppers before
starting the work rather instead of like
coming back during like the end of
the IETF call right so that's really the
idea like you know that like kind of
talk to Frank to like you know bring
this up here because it's it's if if we
figure out there's no way forward with
this it's like we rather do it early
than later right and
and that's really the goal of this draft
okay so if you want the operational
feedback on fresh can we mute thrush I'm
getting feedback or get headphones on
sorry again I think the people who might
be able to give feedback I say if you do
this to the packet this will happen in
the network that those people would be
basic selves would be a good place or
here um
I don't think those people will go to I
ppm and give you good answers there I'm
sorry sue me I could have in the
responsible transport 85 BPM yes we want
this feedback please give it to us now
but like we all say like I mean we take
the feedback we try to address it and
then we need to move and it's on at some
point right so either you make a
decision here that this is like
something that's really important for
you you want to work on in this working
group then you can have it or you
provide us some feedback now and we can
move on in I ppm but we need this this
decision at some point and of course
that also would mean that we will
interloop with this working group in
this community in from a Cheers
perspective I think we would happy to
have this in AI ppm I think we would be
also happy to review the format and you
know help you if you need an early
allocation request for a cold point for
example that we would be involved in
that but I don't know Bob I don't mind
this being owned by our ppm for sure
can we maybe as a starting point and you
find somebody who does like an in-depth
review and provides like detail feedback
that we can work on an IP PN we have a
waiver behind ROM thank you thank you
cool thanks oka mine that this is a
comment for all the I am Drive drafts I
own no I
please don't include anything that has a
ability to send back a packet elsewhere
and then forward and asks and ask up to
the same so any sort of loopback or
anything else because that's basically
an awesome director for reflectively
in attacks so deployability wise you put
it in it will not get activated that's a
good point and I gained feedback from my
ppm there's two things that are mixed up
right now one is take things and record
it and the other thing is an instruction
to do something in most of these cases
the instruction to do something is take
a copy of the packet or take a portion
of the copy or something from the packet
and send it somewhere well maybe to
local author maybe - oh yeah look a lot
of fine if the device can manage it but
maybe to some node in the network but I
think that is there that is where I
think the intersection between the Wigan
our ppm and Ron's draft is and we
already had a discussion that we want to
go on find a way to go and consolidate
that and also take these active things
out into different draft and separate
them out from just the recording
portions so I think that's been surfaced
and it's gonna be addressed thank you
for that yeah internet is a dangerous
place so keep it in Moorea Guardian is
fading it's dangerous as well by the way
Gouri first tell us going back to the
internet rather than dating there we go
some of the basic problems you've got
someone here the basic questions you
have are the same as Bob and I had um so
there's that there is a two part problem
one is doing the OEM stuff and
measurements and the other one is kind
of what's works in the Internet and I'm
not sure how we get the clue for both of
them in the same place because the two
different communities and so happy to
coordinate in some way or go to mahadji
and present some data and mix all I'm
saying is please don't lose the fact
that other people might be doing
something similar and we can all learn
from the same experience yeah and I
think next time we share your things
that might be used if IP piano and six
men are not really scheduled for the
same time so that we can go and be there
right so point well-taken
thank you well super thank you very much
and we'll put that on the conflict
minutes back we have your running
but that's all thanks to wrong lights
Thank You wrong for going going fast and
I'll also go go go buy your beer maybe
right after this session I'll buy that
one actually so the reason we're ahead
of schedule dispose of Darren at the
beginning because we had a lot more time
we expected that to go longer so well
good I think we are done so this
concludes today's six-man meeting please
continue these discussions on the
mailing list and we will see you all in
Montreal thank you
oh and we need the blue sheets back
please currently this drop is owned by a
PBM right and this is not you