we are going to start in about 30
seconds
so sort yourselves out so we can get
through the agenda quickly microphones
are not loud speakers allowed we are
going to start in about twenty four
seconds so get yourself sorted out
please
right why are you here because and I'm
here all week
and that's quite annoying right
so this is a buff but all of them note
well stuff still applies you are
contributing to the ietf if you speak
breathe twitch or anything else there if
you're unsure what this means please go
and read about it or ask someone and
take advice from your company's agenda
so the agendas online and was circulated
we haven't made any changes we'll come
to that in a minute please
feel free to contribute to the minutes
as they're being taken in the ether pad
and thanks to the couple of people
who've said they'll do it
Jabar is live and seems to have a number
of people in the room already and the
mailing list is up and running as
expected so remember this is not a
working group this is a above and we
will cover what the purpose of the prof
is in a minute
and our ad will talk to us our blue
sheets are circulating because the room
is very full when the blue sheets reach
the back could you pass them back
forwards and keep them circulating
because people have come in and filled
gaps when you speak at the microphone
and remember that other people do not
know who you are and you need to say
your name slowly and clearly on which I
am Adriene and Mrs Barbara we are easily
confused no no I mean we are easily
confused not you are confused as to who
we are
right it's a fairly hot topic people
have strong views please listen to
yourself and be civil please listen to
other people and be civil someone may
not understand what you're saying that's
your fault not their fault please help
them understand speakers please stick to
your time limits I think we're not going
to have a problem with that and we have
discussion time at the end of the agenda
so maybe when the presenters are
speaking your questions need to be to
clarify what they're saying rather than
to open up the white debate this is our
agenda does anybody want to bash that
agenda or shall we just run the meeting
have the minute takers found the
etherpad yet because okay just don't
want to be alone I mean I'm going to try
and help also on the minutes of it but I
need my minute takers to be there for me
thank you
right
not time would you not say a few words
yes I'll start by saying that you
misspelled my name and so I have written
a few words because otherwise I di say
silly things on the mic so thank you for
being here and thank you for being so
many here I'll try to be short so the
main purpose of the buff is that those
that come on the mic those that
we'll present please have the room the
channels and me understand your needs
because that's on that basis that we
will try to uncover work if any that the
ietf would do and when I say work I
really mean meaningful work for the
industry we're not here to discuss how
we could lose the time of the iesg the
FCA detail and so on so second point is
a plea to all of you oh yeah I've it
here focus on the requirements that is
in my view essential and focus on them
independently of the solution that might
or might not fit or satisfy these
requirements and don't use requirements
to defend in the background your
solution we won't have any discussion on
chapter because that's too soon and that
could end up being messy we are not
alone what do I mean by that is that
this topic has a Harma fication in
values as deals and more important one
being PBF it is a very important context
to integrate and I have been very clear
about that
in the first email I've sent on the on
the on the because list providing you
with the reason J zones will have a five
minute talk or ten minute talks from
David to give you more information on
that but it is important that whenever
you express your opinions you intake
like that in that context I'll say word
on Barbara's email so I for putting you
on the spot but I guess you did yourself
so I told Barbara that I was surprised
by it by your email not because of the
content because I'm not here to judge
the opinion of one individual or several
individuals but because of the tone and
because she's
jail and because it happened before the
buff we exchanged a couple of emails and
I consider these sorted out what Barbara
as expressed guy is no more wait but no
less weight than any of the opinions you
will be expressing today I want to be
very clear on that both no more and no
less I think that's pretty much it
yeah the chance will present you some
questions to guide you through the boss
please try to answer them as precisely
as possible to make it a successful or a
productive path thank you very much
everyone okay with that don't need any
more clarification from the ad good so
this slide is just to remind you this is
a buff and there is an RFC about buffs
you it raises a number of questions that
you might want to have in your mind
we will not dwell on these questions you
can go and look at the RFC but these are
questions we will dwell on a little bit
so on the agenda after our three
speakers we're going to come back to use
this slide for open discussion and we
don't need to go through the questions
one by one if one of the questions is
something that sticks in your mind then
come to the microphone and and talk
about that question otherwise we'll find
that everybody wanted to talk about the
last question but we won't get to it in
time so this is a trigger to discussion
and the answers to these questions will
help the ad understand what to do and
what the feeling of the room is
too many for us to read in the time and
I think we would be better spend that
time better now getting on with the
presentations as I say we'll come back
to this slide
afterwards young if you'd like to wander
up all right good morning everyone I'm
now from China mobile today I'm going to
talk about a requirement of the
disaggregate BMG in in terms of China
mobile view so just to give you a
background if you don't know what a BMG
is is basically the exits router for
residential users and it's basically the
first hop for residential broadband
subscribers in China most network what
we call it internal mobile the Internet
network in China Mobile and China Mobile
was a cellular network centric Channel
Mobile versus seller now it's eccentric
operator but we have 150 million
residential subscribers that has that
figure has grown up from about 15
million and in 2013 to the end of last
year the figure has grown to 150 million
so that's a huge rolls in terms of a
subscriber use case a subscriber base
and personally I actually joined China
Mobile in 2013 in this home a broadband
service service I'm team so
what we see has China Mobile has
actually distributed the be it be ng or
beer us equipment to the district level
or central office level in a very
rapidly growth rate and we have more
than 10,000 deployed BMG devices and
most of our subscribers are based on G
pong technology 95% of them and the
other 5% is not a DSL or anything copper
it's a pump so mostly 100% our fiber
optics so the challenges for the legacy
BMG we see there are four aspects the
first one is management plain we see the
distributed manner distributed manner
discipline the manner of BMG has called
many maintenance difficulties also we
see and the address management has
caused a lot of time-consuming
maintenance work for our professional
companies its ipv4 Bay so we have
inadequate address and normally what we
do is to give advanced planning for the
address pool that who will be configured
to the distributed be ng devices but we
have really poor predictions as we see
and the growth rate is really high of
the roasting user base so a lot of we
can't actually restore the the IP
address back to the EMS or BMG
management plane so is there as is and a
lot of them are wasted there and the
second one is the bucket effect between
the session management and the traffic
so for example VoIP service is very
sensitive session gritty where your IP
TVR is on traffic reading but the b ng
equipment will saturate either with the
session management or the traffic for
was e and we see a unbalanced threshold
there and it's really hard for us to
have us unified model for different
cases different BMG
deployment scenario because in China you
have very fluctuated a population
density in different areas and the third
one is the complicated interface between
the BMG and the neighboring system
including pppoe server including DHCP
server a triple-a British survey and
last one is when you want to deploy some
new services to upgrade your bng device
you need to configure separately for the
distributed D&B ng where if you have a
centralized control playing most of the
configuration or optic can be done
purely on control playing a software so
you have a much much better chance to
have a a easier deployment of your
upgrades so to tackle with these
challenges that the idea is really
simple if you have been involved with
the because mailing this discussion you
will be very familiar with the
architecture basically separate the what
we call controlling out PNG but it's
more or less at manage play so we
visually separate the control plane and
the data plane we're in the in the
centralized control playing you deal
with the session management you deal
with address management and the policies
wherein the user playing the distributed
user playing device either it is a
virtualized function or it is a physical
function deal with the forwarding plane
and deal with the pppoe forwarding and
etc etc and in Beijing we deployed more
than 200 you user plane bng function
managed spend only one control play but
this is for redundancy we deploy to so
China Mobile has been doing this since
2017 and some standardized work has been
carried on here in ITF in RT gwg so in
the trial we carried out last year we
deployed V&F for C that's of course um
four four four
control playing and for you circling we
have two versions one is for the session
greedy one because it's computing greedy
we use common hardware and we use
software based solution for that
controller sorry user play but for
traffic greedy services where you have
more distributed deployment of your pn g
/u p we use physical dedicated devices
the result shown in the trial we see a
40% better performance of IP address
utilization and of course if you have a
centralized control plane where you can
manage hundreds of your user plan bng
you will see a session capacity with a
huge growth and also we see the
SUBSCRIBE activation rate has has been
improved by 10 times and of course the
provisioning of new services are much
easier and one thing to mention that is
if you have a centralized control
playing with software solution you have
even you have a better chance to have a
simpler basically you have a simpler
exposure capability to deploy even more
novo broadband services so we have
supporting partners including huawei
exactly h3c centrist net and nokia and
the vendor listed here and has also all
of them has participates in either or
pork or a trial so next step we're going
to deploy these distributed or
desegregated BMG device in this year and
at this deployment is commercial
deployment and we will upgrade or legacy
BMG devices in the coming years we would
expect fifty percent to be upgraded in
few years so when we talk about mass
commercialized deployment where we talk
about inter cooperation interoperation
between
vendors so that's why we are here in 9cf
to discuss the possibility of bringing
the standardized work to this interface
between the use of user play and control
playing of the a BMG and the progress
that's being ongoing discussion on the
mailing list and also in our t TW g and
we have consensus on requirement and use
case and a consensus of proposing a
working group that's why we are here to
working on these architecture and their
interface details thank you very much
good thank you
that's clear to me but then I've been
discussing these slides with you a
little bit is that clear to the room to
people here what what that message from
one operator was well nobody wants to
get up and say it wasn't clear so good
thank you
okay thank you for the slides so I am
presenting this on behalf of Tom and his
colleagues from AT&T I am representing
another operator Deutsche Telekom
Germany and we are interested in the
split and control panel use a plane
functions also on the bng but what we
prefer is that but watch nothing what
but what we prefer is that we that this
interpretation is open in with the inter
standards within providers is a
converged well fixed wireless or mobile
networks and it's based on
infrastructure whatever this will be in
the future
I suppose more or less software-defined
Hardware operations okay and we have
only three slides so the first slide we
want to show I have a section other
somebody's already there we will start
with a summary okay so as you see there
are several carriers I think China MOBA
a charm No okay there they operator
before I also said that we want to find
to a solution how to provide this
control of a user plane split for in
specially in this PNG which is not a
central one disagreed or disputed so we
suppose that the infrastructure will be
used for SS or SH Y aligned fixed and
mobile access based all on the same
hardware so it should support a very low
layer like native I a the net access and
all of them the three types or even fam
what should you use them for we said me
to Ethernet services and especially what
my background is the wireless mobile
part so we think the conversions between
fixed and mobile networks like is
foreseen for 5g it's a good use case and
at PBF and 3gpp they are cooperating
Tosh thoughts such commonly used
infrastructure and here this split may
also work so what is the infrastructure
like so this I learned this thing stinks
you can buy and have it ready working
hardware nothing not much to be done
providing compute resources restores
resources and also networking
transmission and additional components
to improve for special services which
need acceleration or
adaptation what is we that is a TNT and
also a dodgy telecom are working on
proof of concepts for that and have
prototypes not so many at least we have
not so many as in China because we have
much less subscribers but we try to
build and prove something up and see
this convergence is well we talked about
that for 20 years or more
this is a slow roll app not something
which happens it tend to work they are
slower yeah and mmm
what we think that it's on the user
planned that do you supplying functions
of course use the plane is where the
most traffic is we already heard and
what the users interested in that the
traffic is transported to them at
different different relationships
different service level agreements of
course also doing costs and prices and
regulations also different in different
countries so therefore we are not able
to huge steady change in the user plane
this should be something which is
constant and just work and provide the
service yeah okay when this is the
deployment next year or after next year
at least we want to have a solution very
soon because operators are we are also
end up kind of focused pressure and want
to have a common solution and then
there's a figure how could such a
deployment look like very rough figure
showing different services all is based
on how to say margin Silicon
infrastructure which is kind of network
function virtualization infrastructure
so the hardware is used by different
software applications to provide
different services
maybe there's Rudy
aeration there's layer 2 tunneling and
management but then we have the PNG with
user pen and control plane splitted
perhaps other Phung other entities have
also this split and 5g control plane
function and choose the plane function
of services providing such functionality
should be able and ideally this should
all work on the same hardware preps with
same protocols and a pass of course
Iolaus for operation support systems
business of court system in doing the
remote user dial in and and anything
more and what may I have forgotten so of
course a slicing is also an important
topic to differentiate between different
requirements for different services
which would be odd provider for same
infrastructure yeah and of course there
should be some business value in because
we won't get it flown so I think but
that was all I want to say so we are
interested in some standardized work
which is usable by as much as
applications as possible and something
more no that was it yeah thank you good
sir thank you for being willing to stand
up unsurprisingly I'm also not surprised
by those strides because I've seen them
before anybody in the room want to ask
for clarification of what he said we
can't hear you unless you use a
microphone he wants to know what is a
pod delivery or something like this look
something what you can buy and you get
it from the REC in the the big storage
storehouse warehouse or something so I
also didn't know this words but but it
means easy to buy and working
that's yeah so so let's yeah maybe if
everybody would like to write their own
definition of POD and send it to the
mailing list mine is a family of killer
whales okay and then this one so Dave
Simic rope is has the joy of being
bi-directional liaison manager between
ITF and BBF and it's seems to us pretty
important to understand what BBF is
doing in this space and to inform those
of you who are IETF only participants
how the BBF works and and so on so thank
you Dave
thanks thanks Hadrian so there wasn't
another presentation from a carrier
before this no okay okay so as Adrian
said I there are just to be clear is for
this meeting I am speaking from the role
of the IETF liaison manager to broadband
forum there is a by two right there is
another direction to that I'm leaving
that off the table so this is the only
hat that will be seen today
and if you're wondering what an IETF
liaison manager is and does there's a
link off the main IETF that work page
that explains the concept of liaison
relationship between the IETF and other
stos standards development organizations
and then what a liaison manager does
from there so specifically with regard
to disaggregated bng the broadband forum
and the ITF so I put this in the form of
questions and answers because
it's just easier to think about it that
way but that's a bit tiny slide Oh pull
the mic up okay so no but not only do we
not have video is that better yeah okay
there we go all right so on this slide
basically the bottom line message here
is you know what is BBF been doing on B
NGS that list long list of TRS goes back
20-something years with that they've
been defining the architecture and
requirements on broadband network
gateways so chances are if you're using
a G pond or DSL service in the world
today it's running over one of those
specific a box that's using one of those
specifications is that the case are you
done with the eye chart I'm done with
the eye chart yeah not sure why okay so
that's what BBF has done in the past
what do they have now specifically in
the space that disaggregated bng there
are two projects underway one is WT
working text is what that stands for one
is specifically on disaggregated bng
that was started recently in first
quarter and it's all this is coming from
the liaisons that you can get to on the
lays on statements page but in a
synopsis they started work on the
control plane user plane separation
they're defining an architecture and the
nodal requirements on that on that
project the second project is working
text 4:58 that one is looking at the
very similar related piece of work that
redistributes the PNG functions across
the
fudgie core question then yeah I think
can you go back to a previous slide yes
can you tell us who you are please yes
sorry means own from college can I get
through the rest of the slides and then
we can go back into questions okay
thanks it's just given that they have to
scale the page don't want to tax the
chairs so yeah I should stand with my
back to them either right so what if so
the next thing is what is the BBF
communicated between how is the BBF and
commuted and I each have communicated
back and forth on these topics and here
the list lays on statements on the IETF
statements pages that record the
dialogue so it started last year March
15th with publication at TR 384 and has
progressed from there you'll note that
in October there was the second one that
came in that notified IETF of the work
that BBF was doing with regard to FM C
and then in December last year IETF sent
a response to both of the ones up here
notifying them of the progress going on
and the cut on the cups drafts and then
there were two successive BBF liaisons
that came in one on January 2nd one on 7
March the one on 7 March has the detail
of the work I've tried to paraphrase
down what those liaisons are into a
paragraph you can probably imagine how
successful that goes I would encourage
people to not only read the synopsis but
also go back and look at the full
liaison the full liaison is really what
matters here these are yes so I've been
trying to get the statements people to
make these visible but if you look at
the last thing in the URL to these you
look at the last thing in the URL
there's a four digit number that's
and index number the Lynx fine print
down here the Lynx that the lay isn't
supposed to be linked together the links
are broken I'm still working with
Secretariat on that
so Adrian mentioned before that the BBF
is a membership organization as many
many of the stos are in the industry
this means that a company joins the BBF
they pay dues right it's not so
different from ietf except that the
company is a member as opposed to
individual participation what does that
mean though it means that the
contribution and the work-in-progress
are restricted to members okay except
where the organization makes things
available work-in-progress available by
liaison so we the BBF in the ITF have a
long history of doing this as is in the
IETF with other stos has a long history
of doing this with membership
organizations we're work in progress
from the membership organization is
liaised to the IETF the full ITF body
can look at it write any feedback any
comments actually get put back in the
liaison and sent back to the
organisation the other so that that
would be how the communication is
facilitated across the stos from the
membership to the ie from the membership
work to the IETF from the IETF back it's
very simple because all of the IETF
facilities are open right so the the
other membership organization is usually
keeping track of what's going on in the
IETF by looking at data tracker and
email lists the key here though is
mutual participation okay
usually there's people on both sides in
both organizations that are progressing
the work in both organizations and to
date there's been no I mean this is
business as usual like for example I did
a little data mining on the because list
before I got to the mic except for two
folks whose affiliation I really can't
determine from their email addresses and
one of them's him
everybody everybody that's been vocal on
the lists is affiliated with a BBF
member company right so this mutual
participation is definitely possible so
what does it mean in practice and and
this is very key if the if work is done
in the ITF okay then work is done in the
ITF according to the IHF process on ITF
facilities if work is done in the BBF
work is done in the BBF according to the
BBF process on BBF facilities okay and I
can't make that more clear if number of
times not just on this topic but other
topics people try to send you know lays
on comet every technical comments and
liaisons it works much better if people
just come to the IETF list and put their
comments right in the other direction if
their member companies if they belong to
member companies it's easier for them to
just go comment and within the BBF or
within the membership organization so
for work I already said that for working
the BBF those participating who want to
participate in the BBF work okay those
members participate directly okay if
you're not members then you can still
provide input and comment and feedback
on the liaised work vilely as on
exchange it's that simple if you're not
members of course there's always that
option of joining the BBF but this is
not a public service announcement for
BBF and then like things like
coordination add dates and project scope
dependencies question in such etc
temperature are usually handled by
liaison so this is one organization
formally contacting the other I can't
stress this enough this is norm this is
business as usual what I've mentioned
here is nothing new it's been happening
for as long as I've been involved in
both groups any questions
Nate
so now you got to go back to the eye
chart again in zone from flowey this is
not question Jessica people may be more
vocal background you go back to the
first yeah I think it was a okay there's
a lot of you know TR publisher standard
in PBR for PNG but I would highlight
that in my opinion as far as I know a TR
384 is the latest and probably the only
one do dealing with see you see your
separation right TR 384 at this point is
the only one dealing with see your
separation okay I was trying to do is
provide the background because there's
been a lot of discussion on the list
about B and G requirements yeah and yet
that's what's being this is also
education is the next step right thanks
Shirley Cisco thanks Dave for the
presentation so I understand I think
your overall in explaining though the
IETF bvf coordination it's all fine but
in the context of this work right this
proposed this both are there any
specific technical problems in the last
three presentations I'm trying to
understand what exactly is a technical
problem in general its given that we
want to subject control and use a plain
b ng i work for my my employer cisco we
do have you know support such scheme so
what I'm trying to understand is what
exactly is a standardization aspect here
is it the control plane controller to
data plane interface is that or the
specific technical problems because the
so far from all of the slides is a to
jungle and to high-level I'm not I'm
able to identify the exact technical
problem here I I can't I can't tell you
in my ways are manager boss is in back
of you by the way so I failed to mention
liaison manager's report to the IAB and
ni be Shepherd Brian's the IEP Shepherd
so I what I can tell you and you're
probably going to be dissatisfied at
this answer because it secretly
level is a lot of the questions and
materials that are being shown here I'm
seeing extraordinarily similar questions
and materials being shown in PDF so all
right my question is I'll let the other
right things like I actually came in
here with my my Dave's boss hat on but
uh great job this isn't very thank you
for this presentation from Brian
Oh Brian Channel I'm wearing the IAB
liaison manager or manager manager
manager hat it's just a whole bunch a
stack on top of each other
yeah so my specific question was so
primarily you would see the interaction
between ongoing work and PBF and ongoing
work in this working group if chartered
being with respect to T or 384 there
other things coming down the pike that
would be I mean like so the work here
would build on top of a lot of this
stuff right but um that's all well and
good that the liaison though he is on no
other way where you know running us to
50 so okay the background the work the
work needed should this sorry I couldn't
see that all the way but yeah I'm sorry
okay um the work that would be
coordinated between the group to give if
the work young group is chartered yeah
be between these two projects and
they're follow-ons so that that okay so
that three 2019 date can you say
something about the V how how to put
this in an envelope has it has a set of
traditions around milestones we love to
hear the sailing the sailing sound as
they sail past and maybe sometimes we
update them two years later um how
realize that it's a target date so it's
not firm all right I'll say that however
but we're trying to hit we're trying to
hit that we are we're trying to hit that
and from what I'm seeing in the work
being progressed there that is a very
real
okay so the stuff in here is probably
going to have to follow what's going on
w2 459 and then like iterate is the like
so anything that had anything that
happens here that would it would follow
you into a update to 459 or to adult
work that's built on top before 39 in BB
F would just be another another piece of
work there's another number on it we
probably take this off point okay thanks
again so just want to clarify it scope
of tier 384 that was just mentioned so
tier 3 84 just defines a concept of a
disaggregated PNG it does not capture
requirements which is why WP 459 has
been spawned just want to clarify thanks
thanks Dave
can I ask a question because the ITF has
sometimes done joint work with other
bodies and sometimes other bodies all
the ITF has opened up for participation
on a specific topic in a more technical
day-by-day way than is allowed by formal
liaison so you know for more liaisons
tend to get a bit heavy and everybody
has to sign them before they progress so
yeah sometimes this is like joint
interim meetings or our meetings going
to be talking about this even if you're
not a member come along that sort of
thing does BBF would be the f possibly
entertain that that mode of working I
yeah I can't answer that I'm sorry so
you give a formal answer I understand if
it has it yeah it hasn't happened before
yes in some cases actually there are
projects now that involve non-members
right that's that's a decision to be
made yeah yeah sure so in this case the
decision would have to be made make it
certainly bring the request it's not
it's not a closed door to that yeah okay
that's that's that's useful in operation
and as far as the joint work you need to
be very right sound you need to be very
careful right
there's coordination there's cooperation
there's collaborations now last one
takes
legal normally people get shot for
collaborating yes especially when
there's lawyers involved yes know the
difference being is coordination is a
rough loose kind of tie to to work items
or to pieces of work and to SDOs
collaboration is much more technically
integrated I'm sorry cooperation is much
more technically integrated
collaboration implies a joint
deliverable according to joint
procedures and joint IPR policies and so
now you see what the lawyers come in
right and I I would recommend and I
usually recommend staying away from that
one so yes anything's possible practical
is another story then it's a I think in
the context of this discussion it will
be interesting to understand
historically how the division of work
has been done between ITF and BBF
because I think we can talk all day
about how great collaboration can be but
the point is that you gotta have to have
some distinct separation of concern you
use the resources with those most
knowledge and you kind of just have
touch base yes and I'd like to
understand that because this is this
this should be a good feed into you know
what should be next it makes no sense
for people to do swivel chair to go to
different meetings or to all sorts of
other things as long as you know they
know exactly what the responsibilities
are around both sides you don't need to
be in two places and and and you know
you maybe define some interface I don't
know I just right yes and how is that
definition of so in the work so I made
mention that there's a long history
right in particularly between the
routing area and the internet area and
the program forum and and I need to very
stress very strongly that past
performance is not an indicator an
indication of like future condition okay
so what's happened in the past has been
that for example on a number of specs
the broadband forum has defined the
architecture
and the nodal requirements the equipment
requirements and put as part of the
equipment requirements they actually
specify protocol now I don't mean design
protocol I mean specify protocol right
so we're going to use RFC XYZ and it's
mandatory or we're going to use this
part of our XE you know ABC and it's
optional right where there is the BB FN
in general has tended not to is tended
to try to reuse protocol that exists
right and not to find it themselves
however where they have found gaps they
have certainly defined extensions they
have in some cases found the gap so
large that they actually needed to
define their own protocol there TR 69
protocol is an example of that okay when
we get into data models that becomes
even more so
where they found gaps in the modeling
they've gone ahead and and constituted
their own models and then in fact in
some cases they've they've seen that
like for example work and I Triple E on
a doe 2.1 CFM has been lagging so they
get an interim and then they're gonna
come back and sync up with the I Triple
E model so the desire to work with those
defining the protocols is definitely
there now whether that's IET and I mean
it's not just IETF that's IETF 3gpp ITU
right so that's the way things have
worked in the past now
with this I mean it's a it's a body that
makes decisions by consensus so if the
consensus is we should work with IETF to
define a protocol that's what will
happen or that's what will be attempted
let me say that brilliant thanks Dave I
know you're in a few can we can we
transition to the general stuff so that
we'd we we get a bit of discussion
before the end but you're in front of
the queue so you can ask any or make any
point you want but not today
yeah so for this bit say who you are try
to be brief don't give a lecture because
other people may want to make comments
as well go for it yeah easier gone
who are we this is not new we have done
this before many times stos
where BBF is one of them on 3gpp much
larger interaction with IETF through the
liaison that they've mentioned so the
requirement from BBF can come here to
really lay the foundation for the
protocol or protocol extension work so
this is nothing new it's a
well-established process in place I
guess that's the reason that they was
here to basically follow on their
existing process this is nothing that
fear we are not reinventing the wheel
the process is a very mature the only
thing is the shorter of their future
working group has to really focus on the
set of requirements that are indeed part
of the liaison communication from BBF to
IETF if the BBF they have a set of core
requirement for defining a new protocol
or new protocol extension that makes
even IETF look good and make IETF more
relevant to their bigger industry
thank you I find it hard to believe that
nobody in this room has an opinion on
anything well maybe on anything related
to the boss I have an opinion romantics
Nokia and so I'm mainly going to focus
on the the questions being asked I think
I several operators have I requested
their requirements because some of these
are fixed only I think some of used is
our combination of the tools some of I
so you see that it's clear that there is
different let's say deployment models
that are asking for let's say similar
solution to the problem so I think I in
general we should look at all of these
and figure out what is the best way
forward to address that now if you look
at what work belongs in IETF
I personally I believe if you look to
what they've presented BBF has the
knowledge of what a bng
and a subscriber h is all about right so
it's a bit strange what what we are
doing right now we are trying to do
protocol work but we don't understand in
ITF exactly the the use case or the what
a B and G actually is if you look - I
scanned - all the ITF documents you
actually people B and G actually doesn't
exist in ITF as terminology I think what
you can find is nuts or something like
that right so as such I believe that we
are better off in general to have and
help and focus all our efforts in BB F
and make sure we understand exactly the
requirements we look at the protocol
which exists and I think we are not
going to discuss the protocol at such
right now because I think that's
probably contentious but have the BB F
focus on what is available what is the
protocol and whether they need help to
have extensions or not right and if so
then they should come to the ITF to help
with potential protocol words or not or
potentially do it themselves because
they have knowledge as they've already
was saying like they have extended
existing protocols with information
elements or they have defined new right
so and I think that should be the mode
of operation in my view for this
scenario is have the BB F focus on the
requirements and they started that work
and I think there are there is people
who are in a hurry to get a solution as
quickly as possible
so I think we are if we focus all our
effort in a single as the Oh
which would be BB F I think we are
better off to serve the industry and and
and go from there that's my opinion
thank you I want to hear everybody say
60 seconds each ignore mark I think part
of the reason you didn't get much
feedback was because you weren't
proposing anything so the question
should something be done in the idea of
it's like well no one has said here's a
proposal for here's what the actual
technical content is of this interface
between your ATF funding and the BBF
does this make sense
if you ask that question you would have
gotten people to sign up a lot quicker
this feels extremely nebulous and from a
manner so there's a technical sort of
question about the content there's also
given that
technically it's not well-defined
splitting it across two organizations
with some cumbersome efforts of working
together because of them being a
membership organization doesn't sound
like the best approach my two sons
Jeffrey down from juniper it seems to me
that it's clear that this CEO separation
is needed from everyone's point of view
and there there are some difference the
whether the solution should be fixed
access only or converged that there's
the difference that's there and then
there is also where to do the work I I
was second winds up he mean that's PBF
has an expertise there and then when
when they need the IDF's help they can
come here but otherwise so Sunday what
were Nokia so just continuing what sin
Dave cynic represented he showed an eye
chart of all those TRS so if you notice
if you notice every media transition
that has happened on the bng BBF has
come up with a set of requirements right
if you look at here 101 starting way
back ATM to Ethernet v6 introduction IPO
II sessions converged policy on and on
and on and this is again a bigger
architectural change I would say so
where are those requirements that's why
WP 459 has been spawned so I mean
putting you know cart before the horse
in ITF to me it doesn't make sense at
least the requirements need to be you
know provided by BBF where the expertise
is and then protocol can happen you know
anywhere that's that's fine
Greg Minsky city well ok I'm surprised
that
people one of the co-authors of the
requirement documents now says that
there is no ITF document oh it's not
ideal document the original draft with
the requirements no we have even two
individual documents requirements that
list requirements and we do have
material that we can work with whether
it's well captured requirements well
when we start working with them we'll
find out and I hope that as data pointed
out we have very good cross-pollination
between two zeros we can find the right
level of interaction between
organizations formal and informal to
progress it if we decide to do that so I
don't see the problem that ITF doesn't
have rich expertise on being G because
we do have a starting point to work with
what is clear is that saying that well
we need to wait for some documents to
mature and then we can start analyzing
it I don't think that it's a right
approach especially because in the first
presentation we were given a timeline of
operator that is they have their own
timeline okay point hood now now the Q's
got really long and you've all got 30
seconds max okay
very fast developers telefónica first
okay well rested the oberliga came with
many ideas and the arguments and it was
surprised that dork was stealing all of
them in their presentation so in this
part of whether we know where the party
is or not I think that the general
problem of addressing how to deal with
access notes how to decouple
control and data planes and how we take
advantage of new yorky textures or like
in general in axis not necessarily a
problem of they being G itself in access
is something that is quite interesting
first and it's fits very well here the
end rota based on what they've explained
the relationship and collaboration I
truly think that what BBF started is it
good as a good model and you know they
should be able to identify the gaps and
if there are gaps come back to ITF with
the protocol requirements very specific
very clear work done this is not
greenfield the development start the
requirements here in from highway I'm
gonna be the concern if people claim
that okay this kind of work for the
owning town country here in this
organization or or other another one
have to wait until some concrete outcome
here because I wanna clear see that is
the same group of people contribute both
to IETF and the ppl for example we have
a bunch of drugs both from you know
Xavier and Nokia we have also in PBF
organized some conference call to reveal
the IETF draft to to happy the crew
crest so also under the age and we think
that PBF is not blocking you know I trip
to gaining critical work so I think we
are you know in a good corporation way
so so I so yeah that I can see the
energy here so whoops I need to make a
quick intervention here yes in one of
the liaisons Davidson acro ITF liaison
manager BBF in one of the liaisons from
BBF it says says very clearly that the
BBF does not object to the IETF
continuing work it needs to be pointed
out that no organization should object
to any other organization doing anything
that's more cordiality hello this is a
win from a Juniper Networks I second
from Wayne and his son Jay it's another
Greenfield deployment so new protocol
should be work with the existing use
case be more general and its timeline
wise it's very hard to say which
organization will come the protocol
faster so it should be yeah hi Dave Alan
Erickson but I'm speaking with wearing
the hat of wireless wireline convergence
area director at broadband forum we're
currently working on fixed mobile
convergence which is providing broadband
forum defined access to the 5g core we
have been doing this in cooperation with
3gpp sa to the genesis was in 2016 when
we had some 10 major operators come to
us and ask us specifically to do this
now at the moment we have a pairwise
relationship between the broadband forum
and 3gpp that has been working very well
we are in the middle of doing normative
work in the release 16 time frame my
observation would be and yes we are
looking at cups as applied to the
broadband forum network and supporting
and providing support for legacy devices
our current intention with working text
for 58 was to use PFC P for this and for
at least the work that my working group
is doing it's not in my working groups
interest to turn this very nice pairwise
relationship into a threesome and and
that presents a bit of a conundrum now
because the fact that we want legacy
device support as part of perhaps a
carrier transition strategy migration
allow people to bring their own devices
to the party that means we're going to
have a lot of duplicated functionality
as far as the access facing aspects are
concerned and I don't know how we avoid
getting multiple solutions in the
industry to the same problem that part
scares me I've expressed this on
list I'm saying this again for the
benefit of the people in the room
okay thanks Dave not on do you need to
say something before we close
so if Martin talks quickly we might take
other points otherwise Martin's of our
speaker yeah because we are over time
and I think the meeting has officially
ended
thank you for your inputs it's a pity
that we didn't share the only enough
time to have a longer discussion but
what I've heard at least being said
across the room or by the different
speakers is that there is a tendency to
prefer waiting on BBF to complete its
work on requirements before we can
reasonably envies aged work I also
understand that waiting is not really a
notion in some cases but Dave reassured
us that the target was real so so I
think we're talking about a five-month
delay before we can have a serious
discussion on protocol work also yeah
I'm bad at math I wouldn't characterize
this delay I think I know that there's
no good number of mutual participants
and so delay doesn't necessarily need to
be the order of the day yeah okay fine
okay but understood let me reflect a bit
on that discuss with my ad colleagues
and get back on the list okay
thank you very much so thanks Marty I
think we're because we're out of time
we're done we do still have a mailing
list Martin does read the mailing list
so send your comments there Bellucci
back to the front please thank you to
the minute takers Thank You Barbara
goodbye