[Music]
okay good morning welcome to the
collaborative automated course of action
off also known as cacao is that the
right way to pronounce it / - a couple
different pronunciations but so you guys
I'm sure this is Friday morning the note
well if you're not familiar with it
then there's probably a problem but here
it is for you I think so our agenda is
going to be pretty simple today we have
all our of our administrivia taken care
of we're going to have a presentation on
the kind of problem statement and in the
space that cacao is is looking at and
then we'll go to find making sure
everybody kind of understands what that
is and ask some questions of the group
as to how we should move forward so I
think we'll ask Brett to come up and
start the show
thank you so I wanted to spend some so
we're here this morning to talk a little
bit about cacao and what it means from a
security defense cyber defense
perspective and I want to first start
talking about do some basic level
setting talk about the why why is this
important what is the problem statement
you know why is this in
shuh in modern-day socks security
operation center and and kind of what is
a proposed solution so the why what how
of this aspect I just do some basic
level setting I know not everyone here
actively works in a sock and may not
have a lot of familiarity with what goes
on day to day from an operational
standpoint note well so know that note
well they did so huh noted well so Alan
Thompson from Looking Glass
Jody Verma from Cisco and myself Bret
Jordan from Symantec have been working
with a large group of individuals for
about 18 months trying to find a
potential solution for this space we've
you know been working with a lot of
large enterprise a lot of banks a lot of
governments trying to look at a
different way that we could potentially
solve this we did a lot of work to flesh
out the possibility and then we got to a
point where okay now we need to take it
to an sto and try to see if we could
standardize it so we could do some
interoperability we could guarantee that
different systems and networks and
components and stacks could be able to
consume these things and do whatever so
we decided we try and come here to the
IETF we felt that this group would have
a lot of great experience and a lot of
things especially when it comes time to
do the picking of a protocol and and
those sort of things so so on the
problem statement just to do level
setting you know as you know and as
you've probably read through a lot of
the information that comes out you know
threat actors and their intrusion sets
are advancing and they're becoming more
prolific an intrusion set for those that
aren't familiar with the term if you
don't come from the IC the intelligence
community is basically a collection of
all of the tools and capabilities that
exist that make up an attack or attack
framework those intrusion sets can be
used you know by different threat actors
those threat actors can come and go they
can be sold off and use my
the ones and and overtime intrusion sets
do actually change and morph but an
intrusion said a lot of times in the
commodity literature they refer to them
as an apt like apt one or apt to those
sort of things and I think the most
important thing is the amount of time
available for organizations to respond
and to keep themselves adequately
protective is decreasing so you know
when we know when we look at like the
Lockheed Martin kill chain and you go
through the reconnaissance phase you
know a threat actor group may spend
months and months years doing
investigation doing you know
connaissance and then it takes minutes
to compromise the network and then
they're typically in the network for
months to years okay so the defense is
manual it's slow it's very reactive it's
very siloed various parts of the group
or various parts of the organization
don't typically talk well with each
other and especially if you're in a
larger enterprise where you have
different business units or different
enclaves you have a lot of coordination
that needs to take place so and there's
really not a great way currently to
share you know play books run books
courses of action across these groups
and there's no way to collaborate on
them across a trust group or an
ecosystem or like a vertical sector like
the telco space or financial services or
healthcare okay
so I drew a little picture here to kind
of help help everybody kind of
understand kind of what this would mean
and what this would look like so on this
problem statement if you look at you
know where that compromise might come in
and how it would prolific eight
throughout the network so say it comes
in across the mobile device and then it
moves laterally through the organization
you know it'll hit endpoint devices
it'll hear IOT devices potentially
security cameras move through the
network you know compromising servers
compromising applications and going on
the point from the this work from Kakao
is that all of these different groups
need to be involved through the
mitigation and remediation of this
attack it's not just one person or one
tiny little group so you're going to
have you know the mobile engineering
desktop
Network support you're gonna have
network engineering unit security
operations and these play books they
have to be shared and be communicated
and a lot of work has to be done today
play books are in prolific use they're
used in nearly every major sock on the
planet so this isn't a new concept the
difference is is a play book is
typically written down and put in a
binder or put in a PDF or put it in like
a knowledgebase article and there's no
way for these play books to be
collaborated or shared and in a sense
it's in a knowledgebase article a lot of
organizations think that oh this is a
trusted knowledge we don't want to share
this we don't want to leak information
we don't want to work with other
entities in this space so I wanted to
help try and do some level setting and
talk you know maybe some pictures might
help express that so what is cacao it's
a collaborative automative course of
action you know or series of operations
for defense for cyber security cyber
defense it's not for physical security
so we want to make sure that we're not
talking about that's basically well this
design could potentially be used for a
lot of other spaces we wanted to not
boil the ocean and we wanted to focus on
a pretty narrow problem space so it
deals with the creation distribution and
monitoring of the execution of the
individualized actions that would be
make that would be part of an overall
PlayBook so the goal with a playbook and
all of the individual actions is to
prevent mitigate remediate a threat and
then also to monitor to make sure that
the actions were processed correctly and
makes sure that the threat and attack
has actually been mitigated so the the
hope and the goal of all of this work is
to build upon a lot of existing
technologies that are used either here
in the IETF
or out of other SDO so I could see like
individual actions making use of I to
NSF or Netcom for or you know dots or
other pieces that are done either here
like I said in the IETF or that are done
in other SDOs
what cacao is not it's not a standard
for sharing arbitrary content or data
you know this is not about documenting
indicators of compromise you know thread
act or behavior documenting an incident
and like I said you know the hope is
that it could make use of a lot of other
technologies that already exist when it
comes time to define the individualized
actions so as I said you know playbooks
today you know their security processes
you know they involve procedures there's
technical there's human capabilities and
I can have an example here in a second
but sometimes part of the playbook might
be you know call this individual if they
don't respond within 20 minutes call
this individual if they don't respond in
20 minutes call the CIO and get them out
of bed you know go and block this on the
firewall and then go in and block this
on the proxy and then start working your
way down through the network because as
you know deploying solutions or
mitigation or mediation steps across the
large organization takes a lot of time
all of the end points aren't necessarily
always available and so you rely on the
various network pieces to actually to
get this done so all of that is
typically documented in a playbook now
play books can be very specific to an
organization but they can also be
somewhat generalized as well okay and so
as an example so I just make you know I
wasn't sure who would be in the room and
what you're familiar you'd be so I
wanted to document what a very basic
playbook might look like the help level
set so from a sample you know I you take
a piece of malware in this piece of
malware I'm calling fuzzy Panda X and
it's for a Windows 10 mitigation
remediation strategy so one of the first
things that might be in the PlayBook
would be for the security operation
center you know they would open a ticket
you know based on an indicator of
compromise that identifies this you know
level two they don't call network
support and they'll go through that
process of identifying the person the
network support to take it to the next
thing the network support is going to
quarantine the system into a sandbox
VLAN in your security zone architecture
and then it will probably go back to
security operations where they're going
to go in and start talking to desktop
support they're going to do the response
process they're going to do any
elevation and remediation that goes
desktop support is going to run through
a series of processes and things that
would need to be due for that specific
piece of malware in a non security
mature organization that doesn't have
their own playbooks typically what the
IT people will do is go out to a blog
post and try and figure out like what do
you do and you know there won't be you
know a lot of there might be competing
information some people say oh you just
got to delete this registry key and
delete this file other people will know
you can't do it in that order you've
actually got to delete this process then
you got to delete the registry key you
got a reboot in safe mode you got to go
through and delete these things and and
do this whatever so a lot of the things
you know like I said would either be
documented in a some sort of playbook or
if you're a lower in organization that
doesn't have the really high security
maturity you might be relying on on the
internet and blog posts and then as it
would come through it'll finish up you
know on the desktop support side where
they go through and they patch the OS
and they patch the security software
they rerun the various scans to do
various checking and then that traffic
that system would more than likely be
monitored for a period of time it'll
probably be then put into a different
VLAN where the computer can actually be
used for you know normal operations but
it's highly monitored I may be doing
full packet captures may be doing you
know an IPS you know right in front of
that machine to check for a you know
abnormal behavior and then after a
period of time that system will be moved
back into a production network obviously
the back out clause for any one of these
these line items is if this doesn't work
then the machine is just reimaged okay
and then also depending on your appetite
for risk and the type of system it is
that might be one of the things that
they first do they just you know format
the system and and reimage it but it
depends right there's different levels
of risk in your appetite for risk
changes so when we look at playbooks
obviously they can span multiple groups
and multiple technology stacks there's a
lot of different groups that need to be
involved if you have different business
units or different enclaves you know the
number of people that need to be
involved can can grow rapidly very
quickly and you know it's because those
are
axé they can you know it doesn't just
come in and keep itself within one or
two systems lateral movement is usually
very easy when I was on the other side
of the fence we used to refer to this as
the escargot model of security where
things are nice and hard and crunchy on
the outside but soft and chewy on the
inside and so you know thread actors can
usually move very quickly laterally
through the organization and so you have
a lot of people that you need to get
involved and then you know the you know
they're gonna you know these attacks
occur across multiple technologies
multiple technology stacks when you do
the remediation it would be nice if the
automated parts of the playbook of the
kakao playbook could actually be done
and shipped around between technology
stacks so the different you know tips or
different management consoles or
different tools could pick up process
the parts that they know how to process
and then report back so how do we get
there what does this coordinated
response look like so we have you know
the define piece we have the verify you
know that it was actually created
correctly and that it works and there's
the distribution and the the execute
part and then the monitoring to make
sure it's done and I'd like to pause
here and just see I know Alan who's one
of the co-authors on this he's on the
phone and I don't our first time using
the me deco stuff so I just like to
pause and see if he has any comments
before I continue Alan if you have any
yeah Alan you'll have to get yourself in
the in the queue if you want to talk and
then we can click in I mean you should
be online now yeah we can hear you
awesome yeah thank you thanks Brett I I
think you've done an excellent job
introducing the topic I think the the
key part of this this slide here is
really talking about five different
phases of where we are going to focus
our efforts and and I think one of the
first things that I think Brett has a
slide later on in the deck that talks
about one of the first things that we're
going to focus on is really
understanding what at defining a
playbook looks
and that's going to be our initial focus
and then we're going to start looking at
okay once you have a definition of that
playbook how do you then roll it out to
the different technologies and across
the different protocols and interfaces
that need to exist but that first pop
billet on the slide around definition is
really our initial focus to make sure
that we come up with a format of
defining playbooks that is going to be
truly you know able to support all the
different technologies that are part of
a security ecosystem as well as all the
different dynamics that Brett has done a
good job of introducing thank you thanks
Allen so one of the things so I've been
talking about this work with a lot of
groups I'm doing a lot of PR marketing
side to help drive awareness to get
people interested to find out what the
industry would look like to make sure
that we have a line of industry vendors
that are willing to implement this to
deploy it make sure that a lot of
organizations that would actually make
use of it are interested and so one of
the classic examples I give is a
financial services response from an
industry-wide response dealing with the
collaboration side of it and so what
this slide this graphic is meant to show
is how some of that could potentially
work and so and I talked with JPMorgan
Chase I've talked with Bank of America
I've talked with governments throughout
Japan the government entities in Japan
and the UK and I was in the US and a lot
of other enterprises and everyone
resonates with this and it's a model
that I think everyone can grok and
understand so you have a once again this
is maybe for a fuzzy Panda X type
malware exploit you know or pick your
favorite apt name of choice and you
might have some pieces that are defined
that say Apple goes through and figures
out how do they mitigate this for OS X
and then Google figures out how they
solve this for Android and Cisco
identifies well if you do this on your
Cisco aasa then you can mitigate this or
remediate this this threat and Microsoft
may go through and and figure out you
know what they need to do for Windows 10
and it may not be microsoft itself it
may be some other trusted enterprise or
some
their entity that does it but the idea
is that these various pieces could in
fact be digitally signed and then that
signature could be included you know as
a plain text signature inside of this
data and then that could be rolled up
and say it you know I'm gonna use you
know banks that people can understand or
at least you're here from the US but you
know you have one very large bank and it
goes through it says oh we've tested all
these things we've actually deployed it
we can guarantee or we verify that you
know these at least work for this
specific threat on these systems they
obviously you would need something like
the coast wid or the Szwed tags or
something like that in order to identify
the targeting of the systems that would
be affected but that could also then
turn around and be bubbled up to maybe
another large Bank you know go from Bank
of America to JP Morgan Chase and they
go in and they can verify oh yeah and so
we're gonna sign it as well so now when
this gets hooked into threat
intelligence and it gets distributed out
through the ice axe and ice house in
this case through FSI sack it'll get
disseminated out to all of the member
you know units all of the different
banks and credit unions all across the
fabric and so when they have their
indicators of compromised and it fires
and identifies that oh this is a threat
then you know oh and here is a course of
action or a kakao playbook that could
mitigate that threat now it might not be
a hundred percent applicable to their
organization but they would be able to
look at it and be able to say all for
these types of machines you know this is
what these different entities have done
and it worked for them and you know so
they have some level of assurance
because these larger entities have been
able to verify it and they've been able
to digitally sign it so when we look at
how you know back to the what playbooks
are and kind of how they work so we have
the concept of the security knowledge
that exists today that can come from a
sock the analysts in a sock you know
various vendors national search ice ax
and ice house and all of that threat
intelligence comes into the security
operation center and as secure a sock
security operation center is going to go
through and it's going to create these
playbooks and typically like I said
they're going to be in either PDF form
or they're going to be printed out and
put in a manual on a shelf or they're
gonna be in a knowledgebase article and
what we want to do is
want to get to where it's automated or
at least some parts of it or a lot of it
is automated there's always going to be
some parts it will always be human
process oriented but you know those
could be identified as manual steps and
then you know when it comes time for
delivery of items out of out of this
group if this actually gets chartered
and formed here in the IETF or in some
other SDO is we want to you know crawl
walk jog and run so we can't boil the
ocean we can't do everything upfront and
what's important is that we start to get
things out to industry and get industry
adopting so that it can can be rolled
out in phases and so some notional and
I'll stress this this notion alright
because it would be up to any working
group or study group or technical
committee to decide this isn't just my
you know my wish list but some notional
idea is for that you know the phase one
goal would be doing the JSON data model
you know which would be you know the
multiple actions you know any of the
logic the temporal logic conditional
logic being able to version them because
you're going to need to be able to
collaboratively work on them any
targeting you know the specification of
using Szwed tags or cosas wit or s
Kapoor and all these other little things
that might be available and then being
able to do syntax verification to make
sure that these are you know formed and
structured in a way that is
interoperable a stretch goal in my
opinion you know would be able to do
partial automation you know doing
digital signatures being able to do
distribution you know protocol so that
you could communicate either between
entities or potentially between
technology stacks or but you know maybe
even you know the connections off to
some devices you know actuators where
they could process it and then a phase 2
and phase 3 goal you know phase 2 would
be you know like a longer term maybe a
second release you know doing some of
the more automated action pieces you
know execution verification basically
what is the resource that you need to
send to the device and then what is the
resource that needs to come back to do
the verification and then you know phase
3 longer-term goal would be like full
automation some
yeah so well I think what we'd like to
do right now is I think Brett's given a
kind of pretty good overview of kind of
the problem space and like to have some
discussion now in the room just make
sure people understand because some
people are gonna be very familiar with
this space and for some people it's
going to be something that they're not
so if people are please feel free to
come the mic and and ask questions or
provide input oh sorry yeah yeah okay so
yeah take a bit forward yeah for making
this presentation so I have some
clarification a question about what you
had visited so far and the first
question with regard to the creation of
the playbook itself you because for me
this is just this one this single task
is really I would say Stefan's really
difficult to to be done in a generic
manner and for all the attacks so do you
do you think that this is this is really
a key a key I would say expected output
from this from this work or we assume
that the PlayBook is done somewhere
handed somewhere and then the problem is
how can I pass it through something
which is released on the rise in terms
of the communication interfaces between
evil parties this is my first question
the second one is that do you assume
that all this work because what you have
to present it so far is really for me is
really I would say one single network
provider there and which is dealing with
some I would say sources vendors and so
on this kind of stuff
I quite don't see the need for I would
say a standardized interface for that
one because you can receive for whatever
interface from a server just you connect
the server you received your file and
then you push it somewhere you're
running your machinery somewhere and
then you can correlate the various
playbook and you generate your own one
in your demand so do you exclude the
community I would say the collaboration
between multi multiple network providers
because for me this is this is this is
only which is really missing today we
we are we are confronting the I would
say distributed attacks and the attack
starts everywhere from the world and
everyone in his own network is trying to
dig into the problem and try to do to
look how can I fix this problem and we
are repeating the same story and some
are going to forums looking for I would
say hint suggestion for mitigation and
and so on so if we I would say if we add
up the same strategy for this
distributed attacks to have I would say
distributed mitigation if and if we
wanted this distributed mitigation we
have to open the collaboration between
the multiple involved party that are
network providers so I would like to see
this in the face to have something which
is more collaborative in term of
cheering just to say that I have this
kind of attacks this is what I am doing
just take it as an information you don't
stick it as a fact you can try it in
your own context if you have this kind
of problem and and so on so we are just
sharing the learning and the lessons
from from from the problems we are we
are second so clarified I would say the
specific context and justify why we need
to have something which is more
collaborative between little providers
thank you thank you for the question
so in looking at this you know at some
level you have to have the thing that
you are going to be able to exchange and
to be able to share and obviously I
think this this thing this this you know
structured object will evolve over time
but we need to have the basic
foundational pieces in in the beginning
in order for that to be shared and then
to be able to be action on it needs to
be able to be it needs to be able to be
processed and be able to be consumed in
a machine possible form we have a lot of
experience with this in the the threat
intelligence world and we understand
kind of how these things work across ice
axe and I sales and so we're we're
trying to build on that model and I'll
pause for Alan my co-author to try and
respond as well I think you're alive
Alan yeah yeah thank you
so one additional thing that I would add
to the answer that Brett gave was that
if some people may know be familiar but
there's a standard being developed by
oasis called open situ that is a basic
mechanism to respond to threats but it's
focused on individual actions across
different security infrastructure they
that group has specifically said that
they don't do not want to tackle the how
you connect all those commands together
in a sequence or in a temporal logic so
what we feel is that there is other
efforts trying to standardize and
normalize languages to be able to
respond to threats you know such as open
c2 as well as stakes for intelligence
aspects and what we're looking to do is
going to build a playbook that can have
wrapped some of those things together so
that you can start to chain them
together in a more coordinated fashion
so we are not going to be necessarily
relying or defining individual protocols
or commands to execute like for example
block actions or response to an
anti-virus etc we'll be chaining that
together as you see so thanks Greg this
is a very important topic I believe and
I think this coming having an enterprise
background myself I think this is very
relevant especially with transition to
cloud and enterprises having less and
less control over what gets deployed and
how things are deployed in the cloud so
I just wanted to ask you if you have how
do you envision this in the cloud
deployment and and how do you think this
lets fit this fits in the cloud story
because that seems to be the way forward
thanks for the question I think this is
very applicable for a cloud strategy as
well because it would just be a series
of actions and commands that would be
pertinent to mitigation remediation or
prevention of some threat and I think
you could argue that actually in a cloud
deployment it becomes easier from the
targeting standpoint or the
identification of the system because
there's more commonality you're going to
have less variability like you
enterprise so I think the cloud
deployment model works just as well and
being able to group all of these things
together and then to be able to do the
collaboration and have into our
organizations inside of a trust group be
able to share these play books back and
forth and be able to iterate on them and
improve them I think is going to be very
valuable I know some governments like
Australia for example they set up trust
groups specifically for identified
threat and so they will pull in people
across the nation and they will bring
them into a trust group and then they
share information and it but it's all
over slack or it's over Skype or things
like that and it would be nice if these
things were done in a machine possible
way so that tooling could process it and
an action on it yung from Kali my
questioning the face one is eight all
the year the year this share their
playbook all the action will be
performed manually by human I think
initially you know if I was to give
realistic expectations from a vendor
deployment model is initially that they
will be collaborated on and documented
in the machine possible form but they'll
still probably be human action some of
them may have the actual commands that
you would use on a device say like on a
Palo Alto firewall here is the CLI
command that you would copy and paste
and then over time the vendors will
begin to adopt this and be able to
process these commands and then you'll
start to see you know like if I'm not
gonna talk about my own company but we
could potentially consume this on our
ICD X infrastructure and process this
across our fabric but and I know other
vendors could do this as well so but the
phase one you know when we look at this
like how do we gain vendor adoption and
how do we gain people to start using
this and one of the first things that we
look at from experience with threat
intelligence is is you need to have the
data model and you need to have the
structured form so that tools like a tip
or something like that could
under it they could process it they
could link it into a case management
system they could be able to build
automatic you know messaging you know
back and forth between our teams and
stuff like that and so it's like you
know that's the first nut that we need
to get standardized and then my hope is
you know I'm like what the was a
Mohammed Mohammed from Orange has
mentioned you know that you know getting
this to be able to collaborate between
the various groups and in his case
telcos which which we're very partial to
and when we really want to help solve
that it's just maybe we look at it that
you know where we need to start his you
know some okay and thanks for the
question you know follow-up okay are we
going to define a set of atomic commands
to make it more easier to collaboration
um I think we you know we're possible it
would be great if we could use other
standards that exist either here or
elsewhere to define those atomic
commands whether they're like a dots
thing or I to NSF or whether it's you
know one of the other pieces Netcom or
open c2 on the other side but where
those solutions don't have you know an
option we can either request that they
add it and if they say no then then we
could out of here I think some things
we'll probably have to do like the
manual pieces will have to define what
that that part of the ontology actually
looks like but because most of the other
ones don't don't do that but I mean
there's gonna be a little bit of work
that we need to identify but I think
where we can leverage other technologies
I think that would be great
okay thank you hi there this is Steven
bang Hart channeling Nebel Betar on
jabber
how would this be different or related
to what is implemented by soar SOA our
systems and Jody Verma already responded
and mentioned that they could render and
execute the distributed Kakao playbooks
for mitigating and remediating the
threat forgot to give you a chance to
follow up if you have any other answers
to that Bret
I would respond very similar to a Jody
did so I I'm watsonline I just have a
few clarifications so when you talk
about a intrusion set is that the sort
of set of all the techniques one
particular group has or is it just sort
of in general anything that's out there
so I I so it's a set of techniques and
tooling and capabilities that exist as
and they're tracked as these atomic
things and thread actor individuals come
into these and use them and go away from
them over time it's it is a term that is
a little bit hard to grok at first and
it is definitely a term that's very
common across the IC but that's how
these these toolkits and these tool
chains or whatever are tracked and so
that you can begin to understand and
this isn't for this group but you can
begin to understand the capabilities and
techniques of a threat actor group by
how quickly their intrusions that
changes so if you have you know five
thousand servers in your toolkit that
are processing for your data
exfiltration and that changes from you
know one data center to another data
center every week then the number of
people you have involved is very large
because that takes a lot of work so but
if things are pretty static then you
might have a very smaller crime
syndicate other scoping question it's
something like patching within scope
wrist identified vulnerable versions and
say you should update these versions is
that saying we need to include as well I
think you would at least call out you
know you know the potential of even just
a string of you know patch to current
version or you know Microsoft releases
knowledgebase article four three two one
that you know mitigates this threat and
I'll pause for Alan to answer yeah just
on that point about patching one of the
most common things that people do is
exploit vulnerabilities are on public
infrastructure after they've discovered
that that is a vulnerable system so one
of the things that people want to do is
be able to do that scanning or detection
of vulnerabilities themselves and then
they run play books that patch those
systems so that those systems are novo
no longer vulnerable so it's not even
responding to an attack is actually
responding to defensive behavior that
you would take place on your own network
that scan you define things that are
vulnerable and then automatically patch
it that would be another use and cause
of why you would run want to run a
playbook yeah and a follow on that would
be maybe like a SAN stop 20 a preventive
or see is top 20 you know preventive you
know scenarios they may not be specific
to target specific systems but they
would be generalized things that could
be distributed and and then you know and
like I said in a trust group they could
be collaborated on and they could be
worked on
and refined and added to so and been
Caidic so you mentioned like being able
to collaboratively work on and
iteratively update these sorts of things
do you think it's important to have sort
of technical measures to foster that in
terms of like the versioning structure
or are we not gonna worry about that too
much like in the actual technical
details and these that's who a social
thanks for the question I did call that
out as a line item that would need to be
in the you know the phase one released
in the crawl phase you need to be able
to version these objects obviously I
have a set of requirements or you know
from my perspective in the follow-on
pieces of the slides that you can see
and obviously one of them also is a
unique identifier like a UUID v4 because
it needs to be able to be linked into a
graph for the rest of threat
intelligence so that you can make use of
it and needs to be able to be version so
you need a version number or some sort
of identifier that can be versioned
because as they go between different
groups and as people are adding stuff
you need to be able to understand do you
have the current version or not yeah I
guess a sort of a question of is it a
single global version number that has to
stay you know synchronized across
everyone or is it a little bit fuzzier I
think that would be a decision for the
group one way that I can only get too
often yeah I don't want to get into the
weeds but you know one thing that could
potentially be used is just a timestamp
with microsecond precision and I so you
know are in RFC 3339 timestamp with
microsecond
is a great way to do verging so from the
chair can we kind of stick hopefully a
little bit more to problem understanding
I mean so there's a whole nother part of
the presentation about requirements and
and solution space if you can what we're
trying to get to at this point is to
make sure that everybody has a chance to
make sure they understand the problem
definition and then we'll progress past
that hi Rome engineer so I think I
understood the vision but I'm trying to
understand what that means relative to
standards action with the phases so I
didn't exactly track it so if you could
help me clarify so I get the binder
issue you know we're passing around you
could have binders that are PDFs or in
wiki's and it seems like there's also
the other half was this idea of well now
that I have an automated version of or a
machine readable version of the binder I
want to task systems to act on that so
read wares though is the work is the
idea that we want to solve the binder
problem or the tasking once we have the
machine readable binder so I you know in
my personal perspective obviously this
would be a working group decision or you
know decision by whatever group allows
us to do this but the first thing that
needs to be done is the data model needs
to be defined so that there's a
structured way that you can document
them and so you know if you're sharing
these over HTTP or even if you're
sharing them over email they could then
turn around be processed by a machine
the goal being that tip vendors and
other management consoles in the network
or orchestration devices like a phantom
to misto swimlane something like that
could then turn around and consume this
and be able to render something to the
user or to the sock in a structured way
so obviously we have to crawl walk jog
run but then the follow-on phases would
be to enable vendors and solutions to be
able to pull out the atomic actions and
be able to you know operate on them in
somewhat you know of an automated way so
that piece about the vendors operating
them is that standards activity you're
suggesting for the ITF are you only
saying the making the binders machine
readable is the standard I think that
you know the most important thing is to
be able to get a structured ontology
for these for this data model so that
vendors can implement to it so we need
to make sure that when you define the
individualized actions and the
conditional logic and temporal logic
that binds those actions together that
they would be able to be consumed so
hypothetically an action might say you
know manual and you know do this or you
know phone call and you know call hook
into your Cisco call manager and wake
cio out of bed or another one might be
net comp and do this command to
configure your switch or I to NSF you
know do this and so there's gonna be
some things that we're going to need to
pull in to enable people to automate so
so I'm not quite sure how to answer your
question I I think I understand what
you're trying to get but I think the
first thing that we need to do is is the
data model the ontology for what this
would be but I'm sorry I'm not quite
sure how to answer your question hi
Michael Richardson um so I have a bit of
a scope question as well and I guess it
I was going to ask a question about you
know were these play books um procedural
or declarative and maybe I realized that
was too much of a solution space
question but it actually does go to my
scope question which is um is the point
here to mitigate an attack um is it to
identify an attack in which case we've
done some work and mile an inch and
other things like that or is the goal to
arm document a potential fix for the
intrusion or the issue and because they
seem to be kind of mixed together like
you know you said change some juice am i
to NSF to change some things for guest
protective devices then people are
talking about oh there's the mess magic
patch level that you should be at which
would be fixing things and I'm confused
by what seems to be a mishmash of
reactions and actions and things like
that
great thank you for the question
so the purpose is to be able to document
what is in play books and rum books
today so it's not about the
identification of the threat that is
handled through various means whether
they're here in the mile sockem you know
groups here or whether they're in the
Styx community which is outside of ietf
or you know through something else right
so indicators of compromise the industry
knows how to do that there is structured
oncology's for identifying and sharing
that information so that we're
definitely not doing that what we want
to be able to do is document you know
the the process the procedures that you
would use to mitigate remediate or
prevent a threat and those initially
will probably be very human oriented
human task commands but in a structured
ontology but over time they will be
automated and they will be call-outs
either to a native API to a CLI command
or to one of the other solutions like I
said like I to NSF or Netcom 4 or open C
2 or or one of those sort of things so
this is this is what play books are this
is how they're done today they're just
in PDF form or on in paper form on the
shelf and so and but I'm just I'm having
it's a stretch to my credit I'm a bit in
credit lists that these very specific
commands are are don't require
significant localization across
organizations right oh they do that
that's where I'm skeptical about the
automation part so I got the let's sign
this thing's this was what worked for me
I get that and I like the picture with
this the red boxes and that was really
cool I'm like ok looks like an
application of s mine to me right that
level but and maybe if we deploy that
between all those people the world we
better place anyway but I'm I'm having
difficulty because of the procedural
nature of what the sounds like it's in
the play books that well it could maybe
automatable in one organization
I'm skeptical about the
how that can be automatically translated
elsewhere and and that's where I having
a lot of problems with with the thing
and I had another another thing which I
wanted to ask but I I'm I I'm I'm
actually dealing with the question of
how do we bring I o T devices that are
identified as bad how do we recognize
that they are now good that they have
been through a playbook of some kind so
that's where my interest comes from but
I don't think that uh that we're ready
to discuss that question yet here so
thank you for the question I'll pause
for Alan to take a first stab at
answering and then I will try and answer
yeah there was the there were several
questions there if I go by to the
original question which I think you were
saying about is it mitigation or is it
detection one of the things that is not
a very black-and-white is exactly
whether something is a threat or not and
so oftentimes the ability to copy
traffic redirect traffic so that you can
do for closer inspection your behavioral
analytics for example may identify
something suspicious but you're not
exactly certain what it is and so the
ability to have automated playbooks so
that you can instruct the network and
potentially endpoints to do things to be
able to start looking at things more
closely is an aspect of investigation
and an analysis that would then
potentially determine this is absolutely
concrete a threat and then then you
would go into the phase of mitigation so
it is not just oh you've absolutely
defect detected something as a threat is
also be able to investigate to be able
to say that it's a threat for certain so
that's the first part I think the second
part of your question was about well how
do you make this reusable across
different customer specific environments
one of the things that we've defined in
the requirements is the specific ability
to modularize the playbooks so that you
can construct you know not just sign the
aspects but also modular aspects so you
could imagine a little module or
function
that can then be constructed to be able
to do very specific things that
ultimately are shareable so it's it's
almost like sharing open-source
functions that do very small things that
can then be constructed into larger play
books that is absolutely a goal so that
that customization for a specific
enterprise environment can be more
easily - made available - to people so
the idea that this is one huge
monolithic thing that somebody has to
figure out how to make customized to
their environment is it's gonna not be a
goal thank you let me just take one
quick stab at it - so another way that I
explain this when I talk about this with
industry is hypothetically I could see
an entire ecosystem of startup companies
getting created that produce playbooks
for identified threat for targeting
specific systems so you know Windows 10
service pack 3 Service Pack 4 serves
like five maybe there's a cloud service
you get an indicator of compromise for
some piece of malware you have the hash
like a virus total you could go up and
you could provide that hash and then say
what type of operating system may be the
Szwed tag and then you can download a
playbook and it would show you who it
cited who had verified it and give you
the commands in a structured form
obviously we have to crawl before we can
walk jog and run and so we need to be
able to get to where we can do what we
do today in playbooks but do those in a
structured way Dave Dave Walter Meyer so
I'm I thought it was clear on what the
what the problem was what the scope of
this was initially and now I'm a little
confused part of it is I hear things
like ontology my eyes start to you know
to glaze over but just to go back to
what Roman was was was saying so he
asked you know is the focus of this
least is the initial focus of this
effort on the binder making a machine
readable structured representation of
the binder or is it on the atomic
actions and what I'm hearing I think is
that this effort wants to
some framings a machine-readable framing
around that PDF binder in a way that
that becomes machine processes
processable you know which deals with
some of the conditional logic some of
the tracking as information is passed
between organizations maybe even the
integrity of that document as it's being
passed around that you were gonna defer
on the action piece the atomic action
piece to leverage existing standards at
least initially maybe fill gaps long
term there is that is that the right
view of that's a hundred percent my view
so you said that you answered his
question perfectly for me okay thank you
Boadicea for Deutsche Telekom in
multiple ways I feel in this session
very touristy I'm glad you're here
because yeah well and yeah well okay
kind of kind of touristy can mean in
IETF universe well okay you can also say
cross area
visitors or something I'm working at
torch telecom essentially as a routine
architect and so I'm dealing with the
threat with the fairly general general
general threat of well okay what's
happening in grouping system and my
observation and my observation when
talking with security folks is that it
looks that there seems to be a fairly
large gap between what the expertise and
the focus of of the typical security
guys is and yes it's obvious that
dealing with the end systems is very
interesting and most important on the
other hand a kind of understanding what
the infrastructure threats are is
something that is kind of a different
world
and some well okay sometimes or most of
the time I think not integrated very
well and integration for all of the
security functions obviously is
something that you would want to have
but it seems in some places to be hard
to do and I have been watching the
presentation and essentially everything
that I heard was telling me well okay
kind of the place were to in were
actually to integrate and cover the
infrastructure stuff well ok atomic
actions about well okay what do I do
about route hijack mmm
yeah kind of I would like to have that I
I completely a hundred percent agree
with our and kind of what I'm seeing is
that gap I think is not often discussed
explicitly like I'm trying to do right
now and as activity like this kicks off
I see that at least as an opportunity to
remind that there is this kind of gap
and one might within you or with a new
activity try to at least not extend it
more and make a lot of progress in some
parts and leave behind the
infrastructure stuff I can't I don't
have a lot of things to help I'm working
on V on the routing security but kind of
yes if I see something like a tool set
that you are for handling stuff and
processes a kind of yes I would like to
see something where I can tell my sock
that hey you usually don't know about
the routing and it's there is a
possibility to integrate exactly these
please please please please have an
explicit look into that direction again
I feel touristy here my day job my day
job is
demanding enough no I think you're thank
you for the question and thank you for
standing to the mic I I do talk about
that when I I mentioned this you know in
another context but I usually always
start with the Machine and the the
malware example simply because most
people can relate to that but I could
very well see you know you have an
indicator of compromise that identifies
you know bgp hat hijacking or maybe
domain fronting or something else you
know some sort of router compromise you
know your your sis you know protocol got
compromised your Eid you know protocol
is doing something weird and you know
what are the things for that and that
you could you know I would hope that our
our design of the data model would
easily allow you to document that a
solution for that you know I come from
your side of the fence so I'm very
familiar with you know with the network
side of it so I just don't usually lead
off with that because most people in the
room don't usually understand and so I'm
trying to phrase it in context of things
that hopefully people can can understand
so if you come from a sock then you
understand what these playbooks are but
if you don't come from a sock then it's
sometimes a little confusing room
engineer so yeah good with the
interchange with Dave that helped me
understand so machine readable binders
whose atomic actions are coming from
someplace else we're providing the
ability to procreate the more
complicated version of those actions and
then kind of follow up is and then we
want to provide tooling to exchange that
machine readable binder in an enterprise
across administrative domains can you
talk a little bit about what you think
we need to do with that machine well
which part which is that part of the
problem a very great question so I think
you know the sharing between
organizations I think you know could be
done in a lot of the same ways that
threat intelligence is done through ice
axe and I saw as you know defining some
you know mandatory to implement you know
solution like a rolly from here or some
other solution or just HTTP but having
this structured binding right the data
model is important
longer-term you're gonna want to be able
to integrate this in a consumable way
with various you know orchestration
tools like I said you know not to call
out vendor specifically but in case
you're familiar with them like a phantom
or Domestos or swimlane or something
like that with various tip solutions
like a looking-glass or an eclectic IQ
or other tools like that but initially
you have to have a data model so so the
chairs I want to get a sorry chairs want
to get a sense of the room how many
people we should get a show of hands how
many people think they really kind of
understand the problem and and you know
the the thing that that Brett's
proposing as the issue that needs to be
worked that's not so bad how many people
[Laughter]
how many don't understand what that's
the next question it we haven't gotten
there but I want to do the you know
contrapositive of this how many people
do not understand the problem whew
so looks like your problem looks like a
dependency but as I understand that the
oasis standard body they already have a
Styx and also top protocol of taxi so I
wondering what is that I'm a difference
between your proposal one and the Styx
so they already providing the threat
yeah information representin is very
good so yeah could you clarify
difference is it from there
yes yes and I can answer really briefly
here and we can talk
offline I am an editor on sticks an
author there so I understand that spec
very well so Stix is solving a slightly
different part of the problem they're
focusing on doing the cyber threat
intelligence side of it identifying the
threat actors their campaigns the
indicators of compromised the malware
the pieces like that and a very loose
binding to a course of action and if you
look at what Stix is doing for course of
action we've already put in a hook to
call out to link to a cacao playbook so
because sticks the sticks community does
not have the expertise nor the desire to
work on the PlayBook side because it's
outside of the scope of their charter
open situ it's also out of the scope of
their charter because they're dealing
with the atomic actions the
individualized you know command that
would be sent to an actuator and so what
we need is we need this this higher
level thing that can be shared across
the internet that can be shared between
business units enclaves trust groups
that allows collaborations of these
these larger things that are done today
so okay if you want if you have specific
detail things I can talk for hours about
six so the other question is that you're
talking about the playbook so could you
define clearly so I'm actually not
litchi your point what is the fiber
looks like so we have some example if
you were in the room and I went through
this but a playbook is a collection of
processes that an organization uses to
mitigate remediate or prevent a threat
they're typically today they can be very
elaborate but they're usually written
down in a knowledgebase article or in a
PDF document or in some organizations
they're in a binder on a shelf and that
you pull that binder off and then you go
through and you start processing through
the playbook so an example and this is
once again
I apologize for my friend at Deutsche
Telekom but this is not the network side
of it or you know the telco side of it
this is the system you know endpoint
malware side is to give an example so
you know your security operation center
is going to go through and it's going to
do various things it's going to open up
a ticket you're gonna probably have
escalation past you know you're going to
call the network operations team and
this person if they don't answer in 20
minutes you're gonna call this person
and then you're gonna call you know
further down the line it'll eventually
go to the network support team they're
gonna quarantine it it's going to go
back to security operations after the
machine has been quarantined to go out
to desktop support for them to do
mitigation remediation processing
desktop support is gonna run a series of
commands because they know the malware
because they have an indicator of
compromise that identified exactly what
what thing it is and if it's stage one
delivery or stage two or whether it was
lateral movement or whether was the rat
the remote access trojan or whatever
piece are in the you know like the lucky
Martin could kill chain and then for
this specific one for fuzzy Panda X you
know here is an example of some things
that would need to be done on from the
desktop engineering desktop support side
of it and they're gonna go through and
they're gonna process all of these steps
and then in the playbook it would then
go back to network support where they're
gonna monitor the machine to make sure
did it actually get cleaned up you know
after some other period of time it would
be moved out of the sandbox VLAN and
into a semi about production VLAN where
it's it's maybe more restricted but it
still can do basic things and it might
be there for say 24 hours and then
eventually if it shows no more sign of
compromise it'll move back to protect
production obviously a classic point on
any one of these things is if there is a
problem or something doesn't work the
conditional logic is to reimage the
machine so okay so this is kind of what
a playbook would look like this is very
simple but I wanted to give something
that everybody could kind of understand
you know a lot of these have you know
very elaborate things you know you might
imagine if it's a internet facing web
apple
you might need to involve PR because you
might need to you know identify the call
center because you're gonna have to
contact the press you may have mandatory
reporting you may have gdpr issues that
are involved and so playbooks can get
elaborate pretty quickly but once you
develop the basic structure in a data
model then it's just basically rinsing
and repeating you're just adding more of
these down the thing and so we want to
be able to document these in a machine
way that you could then collaborate on
okay and also be able to share okay I
think it is a pretty cool also a Linda
and they all they are working for I too
and I also I am working for a tone SF
Aeterna service I think is a very good a
platform to provide what you are
proposing because I turn except
consisting of security control the
network security functions such as you
are talking about some security some
application over system so we are having
some monitoring some interfaces to
monitor what they are doing something
like that so I think you take advantage
of i2 Network yeah yeah I mentioned that
several times in the slides is that I
envision us making use of ike unicef
comp you know other pieces that are
either done here in the ITF or that are
done in other SDO is because they have
solutions and we should not reinvent the
wheel and we also don't want to boil the
ocean yeah okay thank you again I'm
gonna go under the second question for
the chairs which is you know can we get
a show of hands how many people think
this is an appropriate problem or
suitable problem for the ITF to tackle I
have a question before that I just
didn't think it's art in the last set of
what you were looking for um okay Oh a
few efforts talk long sorry
a few efforts have already looked at
aspects of this there was some that were
mentioned already
iof had the has the ability to nest in
order respond
and rid had the signature aspect
well-defined
and nesting of signatures and multi-hop
authentication and policy aspects I
haven't seen a good analysis of the
overlap of each of these and the
barriers to adoption that each of those
have faced so if you're building on
sticks and taxi they're not well
deployed right now open c2 what's the
adoption rate well how will this differ
from those and actually work towards
something that would be adopted and if
you have good answers around that then
I'm all for it
you know we don't have to say like you
know I'm fine with you know my stuff is
old so I oh definitely stay rid piece
was it's pretty old so I'm sure it's not
perfect but I'd like to see what's the
the big difference and from the Karis
workshop one of the things that came out
of it when we looked at some of the
efforts that have failed because we were
trying to analyze what failed in this
space what went forward and why was
looking at what do people actually want
to exchange and it's small so and maybe
the models of sharing I think have been
a problem so I'd like to see how you
know what your thoughts are on why why
we need to do this and how it will
differ from past efforts and and I'd
really like a great analysis on that
thank you thanks for the question so on
the threat intelligence piece which I'm
very familiar with so let me tackle that
one first
standards take a while to get adopted I
know on the sticks and taxi piece it is
getting adopted pretty quickly at this
point most vendors are implementing it
IBM's new solution that they have just
released at RSA is all back ended off of
sticks and taxi I spoke about cacao at
the first conference last week in London
and nearly everybody there is using tips
that are using sticks and taxi so that
probably interoperable yes because
they're sharing
information through their eye sack and
ice house so so things but it's still
probably three years before that
actually goes like full main string open
situ is definitely much more nascent
it's it's still trying to get legs under
it and you know I would give it you know
maybe I shouldn't say this over the mics
if I recorded but they're there it's
just very nascent its up-and-coming and
it's you know going along I think a lot
of the work that you've done personally
is brilliant I would hope that a lot of
that could either be reused or
incorporated or something like that you
know going forward but the purpose of
this is really about understanding how
we can document you know the play books
and I know I've gone through the i/o
deaf stuff and I know sticks really well
and yes I could force this into both of
those but they're not really designed
for that piece so yeah and I'd also like
to see you know where those failed and
how yours will improve as as this is
developed further because that's
important right thank you thanks for
your comment Roman general quickly and
this is more for the chairs if we're
gonna ask the question is this suitable
problem for the IDF we actually
presented a very broad vision should we
be answering that question with a more
narrow version of something cuz I heard
different phases so retaking about all
the phases one of the phases okay
Jessica Fitzgerald okay and I say um I
wanted to point out that maybe this
vision maybe this is in line with what
REM saying actually maybe this vision
could be better captured as starting
with a data model that could be
incorporated into things like sticks and
tax lien could carry things like open
situ in order to sort of you know box it
appropriately so people aren't as
concerned about the overlap I see an
absolute need for something like this
but I think when we start talking about
maybe the distribution protocols that's
where people are
starting to get wrapped around an axle
of what what is this how is this
different maybe scoping it down would
help that yeah and I apologize for any
you know any confusion that I would give
in presenting of the material and kind
of you know I only have an hour and a
half to kind of talk through it so I'm
trying to get everybody up to at least
the base understanding but I would agree
with you that that is you know the
objective the the first and primary goal
is to get that basic data model done and
maybe that's where we stop right and
then we leave it to NIST or other
standards bodies to do further work on
it I don't know but but yeah it's I I
tried to put some of these things in
here to help people understand like what
this solution could look like
longer-term especially when you look at
how do we as an industry move the needle
to improve cyber defense and enable more
rapid response so hi let me go so I'm
hearing about that Emoto but I'm just
wondering how many demo that we would
need to have the core of this work to be
workable is it one two or it's wide you
perfect yeah just one data model so you
identify how you wrap atomic actions and
then how those actions obviously have
that basic targeting and versioning in
those atomic actions and then what is
the conditional temporal logic pieces
that would bind those together to form a
a more higher level structured they look
Thank You Alyssa cover you may have just
answered my question then but so that's
that's true
whether there's a human being executing
this thing or whether there's a machine
executing it that is correct and so yeah
so employee books today we document we
document the commands and some of them
may be process based some of them may be
human base some of them may be run this
command on your firewall and they'll
actually put in the CLI command from
your Cisco ASAE your Palo Alto firewall
or for Dannette or whatever you have and
you you know an operator you know in the
NOC or in sauk depending on who has
access rights to it would just copy and
paste that in so the idea being that you
would have a tool
like an orchestration device your hand
wavey around which one you you like the
flavor of the week that could consume
this playbook display it and then some
of them depending on your appetite for
risk and what your procedures are in
your organization some of them may be
processed automatically some of them may
be bubbled up to a human to say click
here if you want to process this some of
them may just be completely manual so
but it's the idea so that when
organizations produce these they can
collaborate across the trust group which
they do today so that we're not we're
not envisioning like something that
might happen in the future these trust
groups do this today and they share the
PlayBook information across site
channels usually over Skype or slack or
something like that and then somebody
will come along and they'll post various
blog post entries about it and so but
the automation does not happen today
automation does not happen today because
there is no structured way to do it okay
thank you that's what we're trying to
get to a some level of automation yes
automation has to come in phases and so
we have to start you have to learn to
crawl first and then hopefully over time
you know in overtime I mean over the you
know 5 7 10 year event horizon we can
get to where a stock can mostly operate
at automation at some level of risk
profile so I just wanted to add that
there are our enterprises that do have
automation of playbooks so I'm not sure
when you said yeah people don't automate
today I would disagree with that there
are definitely enterprises and
organizations that do have automation of
playbooks yeah and I can comment on that
I can't name which one but we worked
with a large group that has fully
implemented their own proprietary
internal solution to this and it's very
excited about this because then it would
add interoperability across technology
stacks and across organizations but
they've fully automated their playbooks
so and so this is this is being done so
okay thanks I mean so this is like way
outside my area so I might be you know
just really ill informed to my naive
mind it's it's very hard to understand
how you can possibly capture
all of those things and and also have
them mixed together off of the basis of
a single data model at a single set of
protocols that will be executing off of
individual pieces of data that are
exchanged in one of these playbooks I I
I think you explained it fully I'm just
saying that for me it's it's hard to
croc yeah you know I you can go and look
at any of the demos from you know
current providers of orchestration and
you can get a feel for what they can do
today so at least that would be the
commercially available solutions but in
your role at Cisco as a fellow I'm sure
you can talk to some of the same people
that I talk to you so I actually favored
the fact that we see automation is a
long-term and not a short-term
yeah let's make the themes well it's
realistic right we we have experience in
doing this and working with especially
on the threat intelligence side and what
can be automated and what needs to be
semi manual and we have to crawl before
we can walk jog and run hyper and
Trammell wearing no hats but as a
trainee site reliability engineer and I
think I'm I think Chris is typing
something up that answers my my question
but I'm gonna ask it anyway so we're
talking about a scope about a playbook
on data model for incident handling um
or prevention or prevention a lot of
these things seem really general to
incident handling without like so I mean
there are cyber instance their
availability incidents there are
somebody you know push some code and
something went down I mean it's this
this looks like a way to automate oh
sorry and I actually kind of like
automating us hurry because it's all
point of sre and I'm kind of trying
wondering you know how do we keep this
scope in this working group from going
bat large because that seems like now
we've boiled all the oceans on this
planet and now we're going to put oceans
back on Mars and boil them - I'm really
interested in boiling the oceans on Mars
right but um so I'm really concerned and
would like to see and I think Chris
you're typing us up right now so um
would like to see how we restrict this
so that it is only mostly impractical to
do as opposed to entirely impractical to
do and I and
and I'm not really sure how to do that
because like that the temptation will be
you know and a loss of availability um
due to a security incident is not that
much different in a loss of availability
due to something else failed reflux
there'll be a lot of temptation to scope
creep this and I'm gonna be if this
happens I'm gonna be one of the people
tend to disco creep it so I'm really
interested in in in making sure that we
have a way to at least draw the box and
I think it's by saying oh we're gonna
talk about raid in taxi or in talk about
all these things that are in the space
that are you know the it's not the
orchestration system that's going to
have the restriction of scope it's all
of the things that the orchestration
system it's built on top of that had
these assumptions about about cyber and
um like I said earlier on this is not
about anything in the physical security
space but there's other things that we
need to scope out very clearly so that
we're targeting a very it's not a
physical security space so I can run you
off your PlayBook if I just decide to
pop a lock in a data center so security
physical security has their own set of
play books but the intent is not to
document them in this yep yep yep I get
it but so you know yeah yeah when you
think about this a little bit more but I
I would I would so let me just make this
caution you know still no hats um you
know make sure that we scope this in a
way they it won't do that oh so then you
get to the michael again so now you're
adding your question back at the bottom
which I really wanted to understand so
maybe I can ask that everywhere in the
room anyone else
familiar with the concept of Jupiter
notebooks okay so alright so I I don't
haven't used them a much but for people
who haven't used them they're
essentially and Brian will correct me if
I'm really way off they're essentially
marked down documents with a Python or
our other code that you can do stuff
plus the results come back and something
you know edits them and can run the code
and but you have you have English text
about things
followed by executable stuff and the
results coming back and in there and
that maybe it's good enough for the
thing what I'm hearing is that play
books need to be something like that
but then I hear things about all these
protocols and other things in data
models and I think wow if it was just
something like a jupiter notebook then i
think that all we need to do is find a
way to sign multiply sign parts of
documents that don't always overlap such
that we can have those nice boxes on the
other side that would be the scope of
the the the the world of the solution to
me and i would say well that sounds like
an xml awaits this kind of thing and
it's not our problem then i hear about
data models and other stuff and then i I
don't actually can't actually imagine
what what the what the solution is and
so I find it very difficult to know if
it's suitable to the IETF and so that's
where I am and trying to understand what
is it you're going to do that giving me
difficulty that makes it suitable to the
IETF Dave Walter Meyer so comment on
what's up on the screen perfect so I
think the one thing I'm bristling at is
executed by humans because I think part
of what I heard we're trying to solve
here is to do better than the current
PDF model which is really designed to be
executed by humans I think what we want
is is that could be executed by machines
with the interaction of humans that is
correct because you need to be able to
consume these and render them by
machines and then certain parts of it
depending on your risk profile would be
bubbled to a human right and then to
speak a little bit to what Alyssa was
talking about or maybe it was Michael I
think there is some scope creep risk
when we start talking about how you
contextualize when a command should be
run or not I think as far as tightening
a charter around this we're probably
gonna have to try to put some safeguards
in to keep that scope small because yeah
when we start dealing with all of the
contextual information and the
enterprise
and you know some of the really complex
conditional logic that you know could
potentially exist here that starts to
get to be a really hard problem so we
need to find a way if we're gonna move
forward with this to scope that a
reasonable level maybe make it
extendable in a way that you know more
advanced capabilities could be added hey
micros is DHS so I personally have been
liking everything I hear so far DHS has
openly been supportive of playbooks for
a long time now we've collaborated with
NSA in the past as well working towards
this playbooks I agree
scope scope creep is definitely a
problem the Charter needs to make sure
that we're not going to get out of hand
focusing on these specific points that
we've been talking about today is
definitely important rather than running
amuck and trying to solve everyone's
problems but I'm not worried about it I
think the end game of where you're
looking at is is where it's going to be
and I hope we can actually automate this
moving forward but I'm glad we're
starting it at the curl phase at the
moment so Thank You Eliot Lehrer I agree
I'm not too worried about the scope
creep but what I would like to see is a
little bit better diagramming if you
will of the actors involved and as
you're going forward and also the trust
relationships that are expected and how
how those are intended to be implemented
as you move forward okay thank you yeah
I do have a lot more content and we we
spent a year and a half on this we have
a good 80 some odd pages of stuff but we
have some groups that have been
contributing that can't contribute that
work until there's an official working
group technical committee study group
something that locks in IPR because
they're oh gee C says we can't submit it
anywhere publicly until there
something there so so unfortunately we
have a lot of content that we can't
share yet because we don't have
something either in this sto or another
sto that locks in that IPR Sanjay Mishra
verison thanks Brett for the
presentation just a question on the
suitability for the IETF what I was
trying to get my hands around is that so
that play books are there and you know
much of that is PDF and as you said and
so forth but then there's also
automation that exists today and the
corporation's what they have you know
phishing malware viruses and all of that
you know automated you know running so I
just want to make sure that I understand
what you're proposing is that have a
data model that sort of machine links
all of these activities that that are
happening you know there's that's
ongoing all the time in the systems but
have have some ways of data model that
basically can sort of run these things
in a in a way that the output from those
machine you know code that is running 24
hours to be able to sort of get the
information parse it and present it and
then v1 I'm just trying to envision how
that what the data model will do that
really makes it an ITF work yeah so
we're looking close to time but in the
long term long vision view you know you
would have an indicator fire through
some means and then that would connect
to your graph you know for threat
intelligence it could pull down a kakao
playbook for the targeted systems that
you have and then bubble that up into
some sort of workflow process or through
an orchestration tool and then go
through and start processing down the
things that you know maybe you know you
your risk profile is as you immediately
block on your firewall and proxy
automatically just right out of the
get-go and then if it's a system that
you automatically reprovision that into
a sandbox VLAN and you completely
automate that that seems like a very you
know it's a step that a lot of people do
today you know there might be a set of
Perl scripts or Python scripts or
something that is used to to do that but
a lot of this happens today
and then you know the reason why I think
this might be IETF is we have 70 over 70
somewhat people in the room there's a
lot of people have interest here and you
know I see this as being used across the
Internet
in the form of being able to collaborate
across ecosystems and trust groups that
are not necessarily all inside with an
organization it does need to be
standardized either in this SDO or
another one because we need to get
vendor interoperability you know between
my company and maybe Alyssa's company
say I'm gonna give you the hook in a
second okay so so you there's some
notional boundaries about you can we
define scope up on the screen
you guys all saw me type it while you
were sitting here so I understand how
long this is then looked at so with that
in mind you know you given some kind of
rough boundary that looks a bit like
this do we feel can get a show of hands
for the chairs just to understand you
know how many people think that this is
a suitable area of work for the IETF at
this point
ELISA Cooper just
so the the sort of trust model implicit
here is anybody can send these to
anybody
yes okay thanks you may choose to only
send them inside of a certain trust
group you know that you have but the
general idea is that organizations you
know could publish these and share them
across as they're putting on a blog post
you could actually share it through an
AI Sakurai cell or to anybody else on
the internet or anybody on the internet
you could literally publish it as some
sort of data blob on our website and say
here you go okay thanks
thank virustotal all right so so do all
right can we get a show of hands how
many people think this is work that's
suitable for IETF to tackle about twenty
or so roughly yeah and how many people
think this is work is not suitable for
the IETF to tackle one one I think I
have two issues number one I agree with
with with Kathleen on unready is number
two is this really does seem to be very
closely related to the work that's going
on in Oasis and and I do and I'm
wondering and I'm wondering if if
they're the right people to do this
before us right because that with the
other work so can you comment on that I
have three minutes I think that there is
a group of individuals that we would
like to bring into this work that are
not in Oasis and there a lot of them are
here in this room so we we like the
expertise that exists in the IETF and I
think this is a little bit I'm very
familiar with the laces and ITU T's
Study Group 17 and I Triple E
some extent you know familiar with IETF
but I think that if it doesn't work here
then yes we will have to go somewhere
else
Dave altameyer from mistimed I'm a rep
to the open sea to group in Oasis and as
that rep I asked them if they would be
willing to do this kind of work and they
said no which is I think one of the
reasons why you know Brett is is here
today and we have one minute people and
I feel like the ITF is a good home for
this work if Oasis isn't gonna do it
keep it really short okay Kathleen
Moriarty since I said readiness I think
another iteration on this and building
out you know content and drafts and what
this is gonna look like and answering
the questions that were raised today
would go a long way thank you it was it
was a useful session jessica --this john
mckay NSA NSA chair is the open sea to
work group and we are very eager to
actually see this portion of the problem
be done in a more open shareable
environment rather than an oasis like
two seconds micros a DHS I also
participate in Oasis ITU and IETF and
being in all three of them I completely
agree that IETF would be a better focus
area for it
Watson very briefly please please please
do not be let's reinvent Sultan puppet
there's massive problems there and I
think that ultimately is where this work
ends up having to go when you want
target stuff and you wanna have commands
you want work across systems I work I
work with a package managing system
there are problems in package management
we haven't solved so even just updating
outdated versions and stuff it's hard
for programmatically like I said we want
to focus on what is done today and make
that in the Machine processable form
doesn't mean it's 100% automated how
many can we get a show of hands how many
people think this problem is tractable
about 10
how many people think this problem is
intractable about five high caste pnc si
just I'm confused because when we first
asked if people understand the problem
space there was a huge show of hands yes
I understand the problem space and then
I've heard some questions that may
suggest you don't know the problem space
and we're asking if the problem is
tractable or not if you know the problem
space you should know so you may be I'm
okay I'm surprised by the lack of
response on that last question given the
answers to you do you know the problem
space how many people need more
information to be able to answer the the
tractability yeah let's go with you know
roughly 20 yeah
we will bring what we've learned from
this to the to the mailing list
hopefully that will refine the
conversation and give us a way forward
can I get
notetaker to you Mike so 10 people
thought they said it was tractable 5
people who some of whom were vague said
it was probably untrackable and then I
wrote most of the room or maybe 20 I
said it way would need any more
information it was 19
okay roughly 20 but we got a lot of
answers just to be a little more
complete we got a lot of answers on you
know the vast majority of the room
thought they understood what the problem
was with with few saying they didn't so
there was a lot of talk about other work
that could be leveraged here I think
part of the tractability for me part of
the reason why I think this is tractable
is because I've seen some of the
existing work that might be leveraged
here and I think that work actually
makes this more tractable I would
encourage maybe some presentations on
how this could leverage that additional
work as part of maybe a next boss that's
true too