so good afternoon this is the comedy I
hope most of you have had lunch I
haven't gotten a chance meeting ran out
of lunch I'm Carson Bowman this time of
a few minutes and this is the core
working group so just a quick reminder
it's Tuesday so I think you are not
completely bought by this content yet we
assume people have read the draft this
is not a tutorial here meeting self to
advance difficult issues by making good
use of face-to-face communication that's
why we media we work as individuals and
try to be nice to each other
we were just reminded in the word noob
chairs meeting that maybe is worth
saying now and then so point are saying
that more often and now I have to go to
the legal side sorry about that the ITF
is working under some principles which
include IPR principles IPR doesn't exist
but anyway we have principles for them
and so we have to follow them and in
short if you know about patent claims to
some technology you cannot talk about
that technology all you can tell us
those are the two ways of doing that and
you've got some more detailed
information when you registered on how
to do that and other issues like what
happens when when harassment goes on and
so on okay
so this is the following part let's look
at the agenda we asked for three hours
for this meeting or three and
but we are still a little bit cramped
that's why we have minutes
clock so the minutes are meaningless so
we will spend 9 minutes on this
introduction then we will have a quick
check whether we are done with the
actual request hoping the draft may be a
quick check of stateless for three
minutes warehouse
oh right in front of me that's how to
see then we will spend 45 minutes on
group communication and the related
security issues
23 minutes on Centinela 14 minutes on
Calkins I hope we at that time we have
enough time accumulated that that we
have a little bit more than 40 minutes
and then we have some miscellaneous
items and if we are way too fast we
might be pulling up items from Friday as
the slide clearly says so on Friday we
are doing a number of things mostly
because people cannot be here today so
Frances Peter who is sitting over there
cannot be here today so we put the
resource directory work on Friday and
fortunately on stage today and we
are going to do various call
applications and we even have a new item
the the speedy block transfer proposal
by Jin who is sitting over there in the
first row yes so we would be possible on
Friday to have a few minutes for updates
on seed draft because yeah I mean we are
still discussing some things okay and
maybe we'll have some progress to report
there let's let's talk about that at the
end of the conf part so I spent 10
minutes
before the working of chests and talking
with Michelle cotton about ways of
running this and not quite everything is
in order it's almost done but a few
details probably need to be addressed so
we may have to come back on on Friday
okay a few other things are happening
this meeting I'm not pointing to other
retinal meetings this time but we we
have a number of holy discussions and
side meetings and also research room
meetings that fit into this so on the
subject of coral which we will discuss
on Friday in the the resourcedirectory
segment we have some some more extensive
meetings and so we have been discussing
this coral hypermedia format in the t2
TRG for a while and now it's getting
some interest also from core for example
in this Rd discussion which will happen
on Friday but because the core agenda is
already so packed I thought it would be
good to have a site meeting in between
and that is happening on Wednesday
between 3:00 and 5:00 in Rome Karaka and
right after this core meeting is the t2
TRG summary meeting where I will have
short introduction to coral for people
who don't know it yet and one
interesting thing that might interest
some people is that coral covers a lot
of use cases where we use linked format
right now so there have been ideas about
eventually replacing with link format
with coral if you're interested in that
please come to t2 a DRG meeting and the
site meeting on Wednesday thank you so
for those people who plan to go to the
how does the router work meeting on
Wednesday which is occurring in the same
time slot I have been assured that there
will be a YouTube video of that so you
can
that from the comfort of your own couch
and can go to this side meeting so is
there anything planned about protocol
negotiation microphone I built here from
a university so we do have a small
hallway discussion together with the
people from Christians side to discuss
this tomorrow at the after the morning
coffee break so about 11:00 11:00 27th
exactly finalized the location but
somewhere in that area so would anybody
in this room want to take part in this
or a meeting a lot of people so so
please coordinate with breaking soil I
will send a mail to the mailing list and
we can find a place for that okay great
yeah pub/sub security we actually
already had a side meeting at the
hackathon that turns out to be our new
unstructured trying repository at the
IDF so things get done at the hackathon
not just code and we will have some some
slides about the results from that later
and there also was some some time
planned for observe and pub/sub
microphone but I'd like to continue on
that I don't have a particular point in
time so I'll send to the meeting this
place coordinated with me so that we
could meet again yeah it would probably
be good to do this before the Friday
morning pops up slot yes
so like Friday maybe Friday 8 to 9 yeah
should we who would want to join that
part close Sanchez Jim great ok
yeah you're right we cannot celebrate
yet
this was the agenda Beijing for this
meeting but we actually plan to do the
the routine we have developed between
the previous meeting and this meeting
and have that you're entering
approximately every two weeks so what we
will probably do is between the working
groups we like doing that like call see
bar cozy they all have to start with a
CEO doesn't these will probably agree on
a common slot and then we will go back
and forth between car and SIBO and maybe
do a cosy meeting in between and things
like that so this is the current state
of the discussion and what we have to do
is find a time when we want to do it
this time because really works much
better when everybody knows it's Sunday
at 9:00 a.m. or whatever and so we will
have to find a good time for that last
time we tried that and I really do deal
and decided on something and then people
came and said doesn't work for me we
have to change it so in the end we had
different times for SIBO and core and
that was bit suboptimal so this time
there will be an announcement on the
mailing list and please go to the doodle
there and say how things work for you so
the general idea of doing this on a
widen state does appeal to a lot of
people but the the time of course is
difficult in an international
organization is that all I need to say
about that
okay so Francesca Jim various chairs who
would be in this pool of people
organizing that good and now we finally
can celebrate
[Applause]
yeah that was a long time yeah you want
to say something about the last minutes
until they finally happened what had to
be done there just thank you to
everybody who gave useful feedback and
participating in this work with my
designated expert hat on I have a
question to the authors I have now
received the request for a co-op option
number and there is confusion which one
you want knowing the number that has
been said you know this day but they
were introduced as a random number
generator and that always says nine when
you ask it but that was not it we had
discussed this and had come up with a
number nine for fun a lot of good
reasons so it wasn't specified anything
in the draft except desire for low
number yes and then we have been told
not to request numbers because this is
not how you do registration for Ana
but we had a note for Diana to say
please ask the designated expert to pick
the right number so nine so what just as
a hint to others if there is a number
that is kind of obvious that needs to be
chosen then I typed this number into
other draft and prefix it with the three
letters TBD so there is a TBD nine to be
defined nine in the draft and everybody
knows okay that that is supposed to be a
nine unless something weird perhaps okay
so that is one thing of the list
we still have 26 drafts on
various stages so we have to work a
little bit faster on getting them done
so the core mighty part is in ITF last
call so we have to wait until April H we
just come completed the working class
called on on cinema fetch fetch
everybody in this room was aware you can
still send in comments but I was
completed and the next version will
probably then be submitted because there
wasn't anything major the the hop limit
draft is really ready for a working
blast call and the dev you are in draft
I have told Yara that she doesn't really
have to come here because there are no
other issues so this is mostly waiting
for a chess review and and then we can
last call that as well so this is for
more documents and in various stages of
completion so we are not going to return
to these documents during the meetings
if you have anything to say about them
say them good so we can start with the
agenda and already used up half of the
time
so okay so um accurate echo request I
can token processing I think I missed
the last part on the introductory slide
is about fixing the few security issues
that have come up with various
interactions of a protocol we've
received chair review of that and
process several commands most of which
were editorial kind of the elephant in
the room that was that we are still
hoping that we are now hoping to have
adequately addressed but hadn't
confirmed that yet is the topic of token
processing where in earlier stages it
was a bit confusing whether everyone now
needs to use sequential tokens or
whether um or whether that's just the or
whether there is a smarter way to do
that so now the document has been
updated to require that the client
prevents prevents the the attack
scenarios that that is that a response
is being assigned to a different request
than it was intended for and make
suggestions on how that can be done but
doesn't release prescribe any particular
way of doing it so of course still doing
sequence numbers is one way not relying
on not not relying on the on for example
a DTLS layer for request response
matching because the requests and
responses are also protected as well is
another way there are others that
interact with the dpns tech so for
example if you know that your windows
are of a particular size and in a
particular state then this may also
allow you to use seconds in a different
way but it now states that the client
must take care of that because otherwise
there are requests response mismatch
attacks that can happen but in general
the document is in working group last
call so if you have comments please send
them I'll leave that slide here because
I if there is any feedback I'd expect it
kind of expected to go to this so that's
it from my side
any questions comments yeah I just would
like to comment that I sent a message to
the waiting list half an hour ago I'm
sorry at interest yeah that's just
mostly editorial comments on the section
5 so take your time looking at that
whether you want to process this and
think then we can do the group last four
and you found what I've been processing
yes I the two editorial comments of
course I can't mechanism mechanism even
improved further okay thank you I kept a
shot on no slides and we and chorus if
the while ago a request from the six
dish working group for a draft
describing how you could create co-op
proxies that don't maintain any kind of
per client state so they have the
scenario where a lot of plans go through
one co-op proxy and for DDoS reasons
they don't want to keep any state for
those clients at the proxy and we have
now written such a draft in core it is
stateless draft and it's in my opinion
ready for working group last call I'm so
there are no open issues left please
take a look and let me know what you
think so I think there has been some
recent discussion on the mailing list
this is anybody who were a part of that
discussion interested in bring this up
here
by the way our 6 dish people in the room
yes militia training area yeah so I'm
one of the others minimal security so I
would just like to thank you for the
work and the progress it was really
quick for us we were blocked
unfortunately with our drafts so we were
back in second second work working dope
last call but that would be happy like
to take a look during the working group
last call of stateless if this is still
fine with us but last time I checked it
was it was it was ok first so thank
thank you Marcus localize this is
another update to group score based
mostly on another review we got from
gmod after Bangkok and several
discussions with other people things
what about that so I'm going to quickly
summarize the main updates know the
toriel ones the texts and I have in line
to recap later on still open points for
discussion so we reverted the signature
bit in the flag by two reserved and set
to zero so we don't explicitly signal
the presence of the seizure that is
there anyway and we also in order to
admit more flexibility included a new
parameter in the common security context
that is then reflected with an analogous
parameter in the external EAD specifying
the exact parameters for the use time to
censure algorithms algorithm used if any
parameters apply of course and the exact
structure of this parameter indicating
the parameters is of course algorithm
dependent right now we are pointing at a
new registry that we have defined in
fact in this draft so one of my point
about this is if it's instant better to
have this registry defined somewhere
else and in particular in in cozy beasts
and they would require also a cozy
policy to specify for every signature
algorithm the corresponding parameters
and structures they are supposed to have
all
so there was a long discussion
especially between Jim and John about at
least integrity protecting additional
informations especially the group ID
that is used as context ID in group
score essentially including it together
possibly with other information in the
external aad there were in fact some
corner cases attack where it was
possible to forge messages to sign in
them in a valid way and injecting them
into the wrong group so the conclusion
was that the possible way to address
this would be to include also the value
of the score option as additional
parameter of the external ad and
essentially they'll solve the problem we
also relaxed a bit the initial
statements about her wrangling just in
case messages are not validated was
supposed to be a must to not reply with
error messages just not congest the
group and now it's just recommended so
that in the end the final decision is
left to the application and also
adversary can in principle try to fool
the server with messages just for the
sake of let the server creator is you
can context then the message fail
validation but what to do with our
second context itself and well it's left
against the application about destroying
that recipient context or keeping it
just in case is not malevolent we
triggered error and so on also we added
a kind of handling on the client side
against possible replies of responses in
this case because to be consistent with
7390 of course the client has to retain
the token for a given amount of time
during which responses can come but
under the assumption that only one
response at most per server is expected
it was same request the client should be
able to detect possible replications
malevolent or not so the approach we
suggest here at least is to have on the
client a per request list with a
recipient ID that has produced valid
response and that with this flushed
the moment the token the token value is
just to be discarded we had also a
number of requests this was from Peter
that was also I think horrified with
offline discussion during the meeting
was most about some conventional names
especially for parameters in the
external ad we also had other two issues
open right before the meeting I guess by
John one is still open for discussion
that was already some discussion in the
list about what are the good
countersignature algorithms to support
and especially the one mandatory to
implement that right now is another
curve mostly thinking about trading off
speed of computation against the size of
the signature and so on so in the past
we got good feedback actually from
manufacturers that it was good to
mandate implementation of the other work
here also to push for harder
implementations but what we can still
discuss that the wise support in general
personally I think the broader the
better
also there was another discussion
especially between John and Jim that we
catched up right before the meeting and
especially during the akhaten about some
use cases that were not specifically
addressed in the use case appendix we
have few especially involved the
presence of the possible gateway as an
entry point at domaine otherwise
isolated conclusions one that you say
use case hey here in particular kate can
just work with local score but is not
explicitly related to that while use
case be it's good to have justify is
even more difference of a signature
right outside everything so that can be
validated by this even on trusted
intermediary and we are thinking had
this use case at one more specific
covered in use case appendix
implementation wise to the best of our
knowledge there are three on going from
rise from peter m from jim and during
the academy we had some
test especially between the one horizon
Jim there was an actual exchange of
Grupo protected messages the request
sent of a multicast signature included
now we have to pick some things left
open and externally a B so I think as a
next step we can definitely consider a
Morse use interrupt with test cases yeah
speaking of next steps this is also
about closing a number of open points
that I also mentioned before based on
feedback we can have today already or or
in the list and extend security and
privacy considerations that we have
postponed so far otherwise we wonder
also if there are any other significant
issues left that we have been missing so
far then yeah we hope for interrupts at
the next round at least with three or
more implementations so the rest of the
time was intended mostly for discussions
on the open points especially to about
different ability protections the
registry possibly to be moved to cozy
beefs or Allen points I mentioned before
again cast aluminum too lazy to go to
that microphone under mandatory to
implement issues so to 55:19 it is right
now yes so I think that that's a
decision we should make very very very
consciously so 7 - 5 - says the
mandatory to implement curve is speed
256 we have a few other curves but I
don't know anyone who has implemented
the longer ones so anybody who is using
DTLS in this space it's P 256 C and now
this of course doesn't depend on DTLS at
all so
this is indeed the first place where we
can say okay let's make the jump but of
course there is a certain implication
that people who somehow have trouble
migrating from P 256 to 255 19 also are
kind of stuck with DTLS I think we have
to be a little careful how we how we
divide this field here I don't have a
specific recommendation at all but again
I think we should do this in a very
conscious way agree
John Watson yeah I think the main
trade-offs are is as you say P 256 is
already deployed it's easy to find
libraries for that the main benefits of
to perform online its speed and on the
list has been some proponents for p25
sucks but marker told me now that before
some of the people that has been
interested in using rock group oscar has
been keen on using curve 2 5 and 1 9
because of its speed but I think this
needs more discussion and more data to
illustrate the trade-offs so you just
expanded the the rift a little bit by
saying okay that DTLS world over there
that's still using 256 and the new Oscar
world that's all the 255 90 units
is this how of course you can always
implement something else but I mean from
the MTI
side here from the manatorian side here
is that the per to be the split if we if
I don't know if group Oscar would keep
curve to find 119 it's definitely
different algorithm out unica's Oscar
unicast Oscar that doesn't require any a
symmetric crypto no but at some point
there will be set up protocols and so on
so yeah in that ecosystem
it's a I agree it's bigger thing yeah it
would be good to have I think what we
missing is requirement from the from
user what kind of latency do they need
in software and hardware I don't know I
think that's that's kind of missing ok
so looks like this is a good subject for
for another hallway discussion thank you
I think you're up next as well
yes market price again this is a draft
we presented the first time in Bangkok
so it was subject to a double update
just recap think about just deploy
device that doesn't really know anything
and in particular right how to join
Oscar security group through the
internet group manager there's even a
corner case when you may deploy the
device very advanced even before the
group manager is deployed or the Oscar
groups have been created so we are
essentially proposing a way for the pod
device to use the resource director in
order to find a idea score groups to
join and the group manager is possible
for the score group is supposed to
register its join resource on the
resource directory so that a client
Johnny nod can retrieve the link at the
group manager to talk to that join
resource and then join the group this
approach is not limited but consistent
to the approach to join Oscar groups
that we have in the document and this is
about performing a resource lookup so as
I said the join resource the group
manager is registered as a resource of
the group manager in those directory and
the joining client can retrieve that
link together with possible attributes
representing additional information to
join the group in particular the group
ID that was a double update as I said
from version zero covering mostly two
aspects one was as we already
anticipated in Bangkok aligning this
approach with way now the resource
direct there's sauce territory
documentaries groups and also
considering feedback from an interim
discussion we had in January and
comments we thought about this from
Damon Francesca the main change changes
are as I said a line in this with the Rd
group usage pattern now in the resource
directory and clarifying something
mostly coming from Jim about confusions
between the two cones
some groups we are using here so we
consider both application groups as a
collection of devices sharing a common
pool of resources and this is
essentially defined as in the resource
directory document and instead of score
security groups whose members all share
a common key material to communicate
securely using a score I have a picture
summarizing this in the next slide we
have renamed a parameter from a score GP
to AB GP and that's what we actually
meant in the first version with that
it's supposed to be the name of an
application group it doesn't have to do
necessarily with those core security
groups also zoom requested clarified how
to use the parameters and their
semantics and of course we have dated
the examples in the document this is the
picture summarizing how we intended to
use application groups and security
groups differently and now the updated
version is essentially aligned to this
so in the context of multicast domain
you can have for instance two security
groups here and you can have two
application groups using the first
security group and another application
group using a totally different security
group so in terms of the material and as
you can see a same security group can be
used in principle by multiple
application groups as long as they have
the resources partition but a single
application group is instead related to
a single security group having said that
we have the example that I say I can
quickly go to one of the most important
ones fundamentally the approach is
unchanged anywhere here you have first
of all the group manager registering
itself and one of its resources at the
resource directory and especially you
can see in the pair this specifies among
other things the core group ID and the
name of the application group associated
to this security group that can actually
be a list of GP can appears multiple
times the same value can appears can
appear one only once only of course
so after this registration comes the
actually joining client that in this
case we have assumed
it knows only the name of the
application group it wants to join so
Group one doesn't know anything else
especially the group ID of your score
group the pointer to the join resources
at the group manager and the multicast
IP address used to communicate in that
application group so that's the first
query perform to the resource directory
specifying the name of the application
group in return there's almost
everything not yet everything this
response includes in particular a
pointer to the joy request at the group
manager framed in red and the group ID
frame in blue the joiner assisted
missing the multicast IP address used in
the group that we say it doesn't know in
advance for that it needs to perform a
psycho lookup just as described in
Appendix A of the resource directory
document this time using the same name
Group 1 the name of the application
group as value of the endpoint lookup
parameter and this time the response
includes just as per the resource
directory document the multicast IP
address used in this application group
as base parameter so to summarize the
updates were about aligning this
approach with the Rd group usage pattern
now considering the resource directory
and making clear distinction since the
introduction about what we mean with
Oscar security groups in this case and
application groups just as per vs.
directory we have dated the parameter
description their semantics and examples
consistently there are two open point
still mostly from Jim's comments of
course you'd be good to register the two
parameters we are introducing Oscar GID
and up ggp question is where because the
best venue would be a link attributes
registry but there is no such registry
so I don't know what we should do about
this a we should create registry where
and the other open point is Jim of
course suggest that in principle this
approach can be broad
can be generalized to address discovery
groups along your score groups thinking
for instance of topics for pub/sub I
think in principle it's possible but we
like to see how the pubsub activities
develop also in terms of security before
considering that too in this document or
in another document I don't know
other than this wing need reviews or
more reviews I'm sorry it seems we have
found some use case for resource
directory that is a bit beyond what was
very soft directory intended for but
according to your sites I get it seems
to work okay what is a bit funky and
utilizes the use of link format like
discovering addresses from base URLs and
things like that
you mean this stay this is just from the
resource directory it looks weird
this is not that that part of review
okay and one problem we have indeed with
link format is that the extensibility
story is a bit thin so as you say
there's no registry for link target
attributes and so on and one thing I
tried to improve with Koro as a
potential replacement for link format is
to solve this extension story one
interesting exercise might be how would
you do it the same thing but using coral
instead and then see if it solves your
problems of editing format Kristin I'm
just I agree that this this use of
looking into attribute values is a bit
weird
I would rather I would like to have all
the information that is passed around
here at all point of time as us your
eyes in links but the lookup that was
was established in 66 90 with respect to
what can you query from link format does
not lend itself to working with this
actors as you and I probably would
prefer them to have prefer to have them
and so this is something that stays in
the style of link format
and yes we would probably want to
express that differently when we have a
format with which we can follow through
links hop-by-hop
more easily so if you maybe could go
back a slide if that were represented
even with the yeah that one even with
coral as one idea of how the coral reef
could look like then that would be a
link from the registration resource to
to the to the kind of base address of
the of the device in I don't claim to
fully understand this example I'm just
seeing that you apparently it is
covering and multicast IP address by
extracting it from URL which is a base
URL and that looks I'd love to see the
example in coral as well yeah I'm just
not sure how well that works with x mean
it's it's something that we should look
into but at the same time it's something
where I don't see how the timescales
could easily a lot could easily align
beautifulness talk the discussion about
coral or link format is very interesting
of course but I don't know about the
timeline of coral will it be here
tomorrow or in ten years time we don't
know if you send a review by tomorrow
it's done by the day after well it
should be only discussing it here and
Friday yes not standardized when do you
want this stuff to be published
well next year good yeah I said there
are no comments anymore the obvious
question is who has read a version of
this document who has read the most
recent version I think we have a little
bit of a review problem still but given
that this is starting to converge maybe
now would be a good time you could time
to actually start reading it and
thinking about whether we want to work
on this as a working group item so it's
this kind of weird estar said we are
moving away from link from it on one end
and on the other end we are pushing
money forward but maybe that's just the
result of the the trance case if link
format works here in it's fine with me
to use the link from it that's against
that and I'm just looking at these
examples and they look like the use of
this make use of weird link format and
even more we like weird of ways and that
needs review good so who would be
willing to review this or the next
version of the document that many people
Jimmy
cows will
okay okay so let's go to the next we'll
just use again mark again this is the
last one
yeah there was some discussion with a
few people in Bangkok already and we
thought it was good to start this
document as essentially an update to 73
94 a number of reason
2014 now and considering only the cup
functionalities that were available at
the time where there was no security
mechanism for groups available and it
ended up published as an experimental
document it actually started
informational and then became
experimental later on in the very final
steps of the is the review if you look
back at its history and in the meanwhile
since then a number of things have
changed especially a new functionalities
for coop we brought forward like block
was an observer above all and this
feedback I got especially from Escala
first also seems the long description
for the rest for the restful interface
in 7390 is not really used by anyone
apparently
so there's something that can be just
forgotten or not included in a well
normative document so to say plus now we
have Drupal core we intend to provide
security in your contexts also we
realize that practically the group of
core document here definitely builds in
a normative way open 7390 but since
that's an experimental document we just
have to refer it in an informative way
that we are doing now but you just be
better to build normatively honest and
abstract document instead so putting all
these motivations together and after
early feedback instead meeting after
Bangkok we started the document yeah we
would the goal essentially to produce a
new standard track RFC has an update to
7390 and to refer to
three ninety as much as possible so try
to Rea include more or less verbatim of
revised only things that are really
important to stresses must essentially
this would also support work that follow
the experiment documented by 7390 and
you can especially see that California -
recently started to support also group
co-op Esper 7390 in the end of last year
I think you can also find no CF
implementation in go supporting co-op /
multicast so the scope of this document
is actually focused on updated or new
use cases that make sense for group
co-op in a much more compact way than in
7390 possible new functionalities
developed and released after 7390 both
unsecured and secured co-op and if there
is security there is group of score and
quick principles for mostly configuring
and maintaining secure communications I
quickly browse on the type of content we
start with a number of use case in a
much more compact way 2390 then we focus
on the use of coop and such so the
creation and maintenance of coop groups
as network groups and how it is used and
here we have a number of specific some
sections that are still to be defined
for the next version also we treat a
special observe because in the observer
FC nothing is said about multicast but
in 7392 said explicitly observed not
supposed to work on multicast so we are
essentially reintroducing it for the
sake of observation requests that can be
sent over multicast well so we are
explicitly
allowing that here and that's why
formally we are also intended to update
6:41 as well about this but it's
essentially about observing the same
resource over multicast multiple servers
that are sharing it we treat the no sec
mode for non-critical use cases when
that is doable that's essentially like
in 1790 but we have
fairly good amount of text already for
the secured case when you essentially
use group of score we recommend the
related document in ace for the sake of
group joining and key management we have
of course number of security
considerations both for no sick days
essentially do it in your own risk if
you know what you're doing and for the
case you go for group of score when you
want security in the groups and we
describe point to point we essentially
reprise what discussed in 7390 how this
essentially tackles and addresses a
number of security attacks that you have
in groups if you have unsecure
communication with group co-op as next
steps well we need to actually complete
document because there are a few
sections still TBD we would like to have
feedback a based on the current level of
content we are missing any fundamental
point that that should be included in
this document and otherwise whatever you
find it right there is totally readable
for every comments and reviews
we mostly welcome
so who has read RFC's at 7390 and who
has seen this attempted a revision well
that's more than than the discovery
doctrine okay so who would be willing to
review this Klaus Jim Lawson Jim that
maybe I would sin again
Cristian Cristian volunteers it's gonna
happen okay good that first we could
complete the document for the next IDF
meeting then let's see if that's enough
to take more formal actions with that or
we've made one more run with formal
reviews depends a bit of the matthias
kawatche just a quick question you
mentioned network groups now how do they
relate to the app groups that you
introduced previously right here we're
using network groups like in 7390
already so these groups should include
only the coop endpoints acting as
servers
so the network group is a subset of the
application group the way it is defined
here we are keeping the same definition
of 7390 Thomas Fossati also is willing
to review the 7390 B's Thank You Thomas
okay really quick summary of the pub/sub
a multicast discussion that happened
during the hackathon some people were
there so I put the list I might have
forgotten someone so the background and
the motivation for this discussion is
that we realize we have multicast and we
have observe and we have pops up and we
would like to use something like
multicast notification in a pub sub
scenario this seems like a good thing to
have for efficiency and once we have
that we also would like to have some
security mechanism to protect
communication such as the publication
protection mechanism to protect against
nodes that are not subscribers getting
unwillingly subscribed and so denial of
service and also terrorization and
authentication of nodes so this this
started from the work in ace for the pub
sub co-op pub sub profile and realized
okay there is more than can be done and
possibly might also fit in core
so we during this side meeting we
identified three challenges the first
one is the plumbing which is how to make
the pubs of architecture work with
multicast delivery notifications and
because of the way notifications are
defined right now as responses the
current multicast wouldn't work with
that the second point is how to protect
against these denial service attacks and
then more broadly how to protect the
communication so there's a publisher
broker publishing subscriber subscriber
broker and provide authentication
authorization for the notes so this is
some work that is starting now and
it would fit both both in ace and coring
some sense since the pub/sub and you
observe is done and the multicast is
done here and security nays yes question
in your security model did you include
anything about inference
so if about inference so as an attacker
can I infer something about another node
because I I'm part of the multicast
group and I see that this other node is
receiving some notifications
does that include it in the security we
were not that far yet we're just
starting this discussion so the answer
will be no right now but could you let
us know your name please Oh Dave wheeler
yeah and and so yeah there is the slides
that we use that the whole way anything
to have more detailed of what exactly
was discussed and how this was presented
which I'm not gonna go through but
please they could take a look at those
and see if they make any sense and if
you want to participate let's let's pick
it up you can quickly say something were
just talking about Jen about the slide
number 10 slide number 10 yeah the one
performance called multi casting
notifications that's that's why I
already said about being more efficient
and a security this setting up many
brokers subscriber DTLS connection is
not really optimal what kind of work do
we have to do to make this happen but
first of all what I would like to know
is where does this fit does it fit here
does it fit in ace somewhere else
are people interested from from the
reaction I got from starting this
hallway discussions in the people are
interested in this so this is more
question to the chairs Koren ace and/or
idea what is covered just was comes to
mind
we had these unsolicited notifications
we discussed this with ocf I have no
clue where that went
and what's the status about this but
this could be probably something that
goes together and was already identified
that something that we could work on
okay Alexei Melnikov has ad I don't have
an answer for you but if you send email
to me then I can talk to security a DS
and we'll figure it out okay ou will
give you a answer saying you know one of
the working groups need to reach out or
maybe I don't know okay if chairs or
some oh you can send me a reminder well
I think the thing we should argue about
this whether we need a cinema working
group all right before we go for
synagogue let's talk about one
cinemagraph so this is about the data
value content format indication it's a a
new draft but it's already in the
version zero one since we got bunch of
good comments before the IETF long story
short today the cinema records they can
contain arbitrary binary data values
there's the B field for that and how it
was specifies an original spec is that
the information how you actually decode
these values is established out of path
that's part of your application so you
can have if you don't have use for the
regular strings in googling on values
the rest you can basic put in there in
the video field so there you can see in
the example how it looks like there you
have three records first on it's using a
classic p-value second one is use a
boolean but the third record this NFC
reader has now an arbitrary binary value
out of it so that's why we envisioned
every we'll be using this ascending a
few bits and bytes of information use
the DD value turns out that there's a
lot of use for that even beyond we see
now currently rather substantial amount
of information out there which actually
does have structure and for structure
information at the IETF we do have a way
to express that that's the media types
and imported content formats when we use
in the in the core environment so our
proposal here is simply well let's add a
content for an indication the records
which have the video to indicate what is
the value there then you don't need
necessarily have that much out-of-band
negotiation there and also third parties
that do see these records can make
something out of that information
instead of just being computed find
what's being exchanged so here's an
example how it would look like right
before it's a similar kind of record but
we add this new field CT and equal six
to here and for those of you who can
decode base64 only and see bore in your
head it's probably already obvious we do
have here C bore array that contains a
string and an integer inside and it's
base64 encoded in the example because it
is the Chasen format if you're using the
Seaboard format you would use the binary
value as such in the field and then
because the CD valid else is 60 it
should be rather easy to decode that
that's the core of the proposal then it
gets slightly more complicated so we got
feedback that would be highly useful
perhaps to also support for media types
that do not have these content format
indications
with core you can of course easily
register for any kind of media types but
there might be some media types and and
there a permit resize versions that
maybe don't make sense in in the index
core environment or or or co-op and
cinema of course is can be used much
much wider context and test
Khoa so a proposal would be to extend
this and have also possibility instead
of using the CT to also use content type
and content coding fields to tell the
same information in a string format for
those types that you don't have a
content format register so you see an
example for that in in the bottom so you
have content type for example text CSV
and it could be using gzip content
coding and if you interested what is the
results there you can do a 64 and and G
unzip so this seems to be a rather
reasonable approach for solving this
although we did hit one interesting
challenge that we just realized
yesterday with this extra weight of two
ways of defining this encoding
information since you have all the base
values in insane ml and for those who
are not familiar with with sin ml you
have base fields and regular fields and
use the base fields or a polite for
those records that don't define any
field of that kind that makes it easier
to compress information don't have to
repeat same information in every single
record so we are proposing to register
base fields for all of these three
different ways to express this
information however in this case you
probably should not be mixing both the
content format and the content type and
color coding things because they
essentially can tell the same same piece
of information so we may need to come up
with a way to undo a base content type
or encoding information because now you
have the dependency that you for example
define base content type in the
beginning attend you want to for example
combine this with another
sentimental pack which is using the
other format and instead of changing all
those fields together you want to switch
that format that you don't want to be
reusing the same base CD value for for
the following records so that's the
maybe the big bigger challenge that we
have the basic format looks pretty
simple and straightforward thing thing
for us to do for this we may need to do
a bit more thinking but if we end up
extending sin ml in this kind of ways
also in the future this could be a
pattern that we want to establish how
can you basically undo a base value but
for all I think there's two quick
questions
does the group think this makes sense so
I see some some nodding there and
whether it's that make sense to go all
the way here so we got got to get some
feedback especially for those who are
using an on constraint space this seems
to be a very very useful useful
construct and if we say yes to both -
how do we solve number three so we have
one that's a tentative proposal that for
example if there's both city winds and
you can nullify the city by setting it
to minus one we can see it doesn't
different ways of doing that with that
may not be the optimal one but that was
always
okay while I was sitting here I came up
with a sick way of solving this problem
in coop we only have non-negative
content for my numbers
why don't we provide a way to define
negative content from the numbers within
a slimmer pack and then we don't have a
problem but I will explain that to you
negative content from a number so you
would have a record that says minus
seven is what was that text CSV +
content coding gzip and then in the
following you can switch back and forth
between minus 7 and 62 all your delight
okay and those who are not getting super
worried are we extend here is way too
long the good thing this is stuff you
don't have to understand so these are
not mandatory to understand fields so
for a system that doesn't care it just
like yeah whatever
but system that wants to make use of
this piece of information can actually
look in there and that the first format
this is pretty much straightforward the
question is here and here how far do we
want to push but yeah this is already
being being used out there so I thinking
you know doing this in this group in my
opinion would make a lot of sense but
I'll leave the call for that up to the
chairs the cost brought up the the meta
issue we have all these tiny
scenario documents being generated here
isn't that becoming a bit fragmented for
for the users and maybe that's good
reason to have another hallway meeting
on how to handle this but right now I
think call is the group that's owning
sin ml and when if people out there have
small things they want to have edit we
probably should be doing that so they
don't have to invent them on their own
and possibly mess them up in the process
so has anybody read this Charles his
right edge I cannot raise my hand I'm a
co-author but I haven't read the newest
version okay so that's certainly a
problem I mean some people from from the
riot project have implemented this stuff
so maybe this is one of the places where
we have to work harder on actually
getting the implementer in the loop okay
[Music]
okay so the next one more cinema units
actually it's not my traffic artist
rapid ah I was always the one poking
carsten that hey let's this should be
done so the background on the cinema
units si you know cinema has a units
registry that you can use in any of the
records to say hey this information is
of this kind of unit and it's you can
think of it as an a semantic tag telling
more context about the value there so in
the Olmec works we are working on this
like within protocol and if so models
and also the those if some models they
have in resources they have a unit
attribute its optional there but those
were where it makes sense you have to
define in the specification what is the
unit of this value and some objects even
have a unit resource so you can
dynamically configure what kind of unit
and a kind of an object is using for its
value it turns currently there is no
rich history for the unit so we were
looking okay what is the kind right way
to have this more consistent and well it
turns out the central unit register
seems like a good fit for this purpose
and it is also a good fit for the for
the reason that Sentinel JSON seaboards
all reuse as the serialization format
for life with an therm objects so having
those units aligned there would make
interoperability and translations in
general easier however there has been
quite some time already new objects and
resources registered for the OMA ready
and there are some units that are used
there that are not currently part of the
enemy units registry in particle there
is white vault impaired volt-ampere
reactive and joules per meter and also
decrease as in compass direction in the
sentimental document when we were
created register we were expressly
expressly saying that okay it should be
one unit for the one kind of eye
I think you are expressing we do already
have for example bit for for information
content so what the question is like
should should we still also register
byte only on the other hand we had the
similar discussion on the Carolinian
Celsius even Kelvin is like that one iso
spec is perhaps slightly more recomm
strongly recommended they also iso specs
I do recommend while to mentioned using
Celsius as a temperature unit so with
bit and bites his bite is much more
commonly used in certain contexts or
information content it perhaps it makes
sense to have along the same analogy
also also byte there so all I know seems
at the moment the analyst is still
ongoing if we register these missing
units or cinema we could be using the
same register for the hip so we don't
need to come up the new register new new
ways to do that and of course the good
thing is that also does support all
other use of sentinel so this is nothing
if so specific those units are universal
so anywhere where you would use
sentimental in ipso context or outside
you would be used same units so we are
actually serving both communities at
once so there's a draft for it that we
don't have to make it an RFC to do the
registrations for IANA cause it's just
expert approval for it but of course we
could be collecting more of these kind
of units in this draft over time and
eventually published as an RFC
hey how compete erson and just have a
question about the units
this recently saw on the Bluetooth
standard they have like a 15 page long
table of Units is there any chance we
can have some conversions there that was
one of the registries that was being
considered report for the hip so on the
one that we actually need here is this
source string auditor do you need the
Bluetooth one had and it was integers or
anyway they had a numbers for it here we
actually do need source strings there
was a bit emits much and then was also
the question of the registry control if
we come up let's say and if so context a
with a new unit that it's not in the
registry but who doesn't seem use for it
however these the if so use and cinema
use are very well aligned already so we
see a bit more natural fit there the
other one that was considered was the
you come rate registry of units but
actually you know in in send ml one of
the implied policies there is so if it's
in you whom we can actually easily fit
in there there are also some things in
you can we actually may not want to be
it's a rather rich set of units are some
stuff you may not want to have there but
also it's missing some so not remember
which one of these units but some of
them actually did not exist there but
they are still widely used in your
example ISO specs so it seems to be a
right thing to have it there but long
term actually one thing what we have on
the agenda is they had to have the chat
with the ukume guys and you know see
like how we can have alignment in this
face altogether this is Matias so in
terms of convergence I also wanted to
hint at this you come Burke I mean that
was something that was picked in the
very very early days of of core actually
to be something of interest but somehow
never progressed I learned that the
semantic sensor network ontology they
also now aligned with the you come
system and there's even some activity
going on that there is a Java
implementation there is I think even a
Java extension so something that should
end up at in in in the JDK at some point
where you can then automatically
basically resolve the different units
and get the actual value in the target I
mentioned that you want so it can also
with the weights sorry I couldn't we
don't know what's the proper term for
this this kilo mega and so on males yeah
the scales scale factors and so on and
and also converting between equivalent
kind of units and get as some work going
on to do this automatically so this is
quite interesting for machine to machine
where you always have to make sure that
there is something that can actually
match the units that are actually
compatible but because you use the
different string they're not yes and
that's something we were discussing in
the context of my spec works like where
what's the right place to express the
scale um if you have it in the numeric
value then like comparisons become
trivial you don't actually have to look
at that they unit but then luckily there
are there are some environments that
don't support floats very well so if you
don't have a floating-point
implementation you it might be hard for
you however for example in both in the
Chasen and c4 format it's an easy way to
go around that you can says use the
exponent so basically use your value as
such but you define the exponent in a
way that it actually matches your
schedule so if it's a kilo you put you
know they're three if it's a mega you or
if it's a microwave with -2 management
etc so there is a way around but without
doing floating-point operations actually
but but a good point about the Yukon on
the java part that's something
interesting to have a look at and also i
heard they are doing I think aligned
with the qu DT so there's some wider
alignment activity going on there and
yeah we have it on our list actually
have a closer look at that
I think these different registers an
interesting way to learn how different
efforts can different their objectives
so you come is pretty much trying to be
the the collection of the most obscure
things you can think about they have
about a half-dozen of definitions of
British thermal units because over time
British thermal units have changed a
little bit I mean this is something that
you have to know some
things like inch had a different
definition seventy years ago than they
have today so if you still have a map
that is based on the old one then you
may want to reduce this this unit this
is not quite what we need for for the
Internet of Things
so there we can can actually favor a
style of doing things that's actually
based on the base units that are
internationally accepted so the cinema
units registry actually tries to be
minimal so we have a dual parameter but
we don't have a what our per kilometer
because what one is just the other one
times three point six millions and that
of course simplifies working with the
stuff but it also means that if you have
a sense of that that happens to output
what hours per kilometer then you have
to do some work and so when people say
oh you come is so big let's adopt it
yeah it's big in a way that maybe we
don't like and also I was really
surprised to find out they didn't have
water pairs and for the PS rate of India
which is very strange if you come from
from Rio cheapo Mita kind of environment
where this is standard trail yeah the
powers that the ITF is not in the
business so we would be much happier if
we could just factor this out to someone
else and the the the group that is
closest to here is incredibly I saw they
have I saw eighty thousand and and we I
see parts of I saw eighteen thousand but
it's a needs to be translated into ASCII
and that that's the small piece of work
that we probably have to do
okay next item so if either do you want
to talk about Cochran for anybody else
doing that thank you
okay so hello everyone my name is
Gerardo Parra and I will be presenting
the advancement of cocoa so okay I will
start and I guess I will have my sites
in a moment I mean okay first about
Kamiya draft had there were no real
changes in the last idea and the last
idea there was interrupts between
different implementations so it seemed
that the draft is rather stable
and for me once we resolved issues with
the seat draft and the yangtze board
drafts we can go for working group
Roscoe anyone disagree okay okay
so next part okay
I mean I can start with the citrus which
is actually maybe the more interesting
part of the presentation and then I will
come back to the Yangtze bar trust
so for the seat draft we received quite
extensive reviewing comments from Peter
so thank you Peter
we tried to to adapt the draft
accordingly we had yes it was yesterday
a lot of discussions with people from
Ayane there are a lot of things we would
like to simplify due to those
discussions right now it seems that the
draft is a little bit still difficult to
understand so a lot of the changes are
editorial but there are some real I mean
no mandatory changes so let me just go
to the appropriate light okay okay a lot
of things being moved from the
introduction and from the seat life
cycle section to appendix because they
were just informational and explaining
how things could happen for getting a
seat assigned to some yank mod a number
of seats assigned to some young mod but
as this is not the only way and it might
drink some confusion to people we
decided to move them to appendix this
includes the automatic generation and
the seat life cycle part another quite
important parts from the modifications I
would say is the change of and this
range is 0 to 999 I mean some of the
seats range that's right now we're not
very clear how we want to handle them
for the a unmanaged repository and now
being reserved for future use so they
will need to be unlocked at a later
stage when we know a little bit more how
we want to use the seats from this
smaller
yeah the seats with the smaller numbers
we don't want to risk being something
support team Oh in recreating that in
the future and there was a section 5
that was informational but it we decided
that it cooked me to some more confusion
so we just removed okay that's fun okay
so yeah think I should check the PDF
that was generated ok so the next thing
was that the seat type of defining the
coma I yank module which was kind of
redundant so what we decided to us to
name it on the how to the seat act
module
it was also requested approximately at
the same time on the made increase so
this is good thing I mean that people
agree with our decision another point
which is also quite important I would
say that instead of creating kanuto
Satori where sit files are added we are
attaching the seat valves to the rank
name registry
and so this has been discussed to it I
am there were some details to be cleared
out about this but it is the way we plan
to go okay you don't know this because
we were just talking but we might
actually change where we post the CID
files it might not actually go into the
module registry for various different
reasons that we've been talking about
back there so that might be something
that changes so you'll we'll talk more
about it and if there's a change
obviously the draft will get updated and
then everybody can provide their
feedback but just wanted to let you know
that okay so I'll see what I will
present the rest of the time but
hopefully some of the other things that
I will be presenting could not be wrong
so Alexander here so just to get
everything here basically what we did
was really really simplify all the
things and it was super interesting
talking with the people from Vienna
because things that look really really
obvious when you talk on the process and
how things are working with Ayana
because they are the guys that will
actually be running the thing that we
define here and you're like okay here
that's really great idea but how do we
do whenever you have like an RFC
required and then later you need so we
are getting really really down into the
process of how things get registered and
even things that look super
straightforward when you put on the
process on top we say okay well that
there might be some little modifications
to do but it was really really
impressive the progress that we have so
we're basically fine-tuning some of the
some of the things and and then this is
when we were like talking in with Carson
were talking a little bit earlier and
and we basically said okay well we agree
it work and we need just to define that
little thing over here and so that was
the reason for that and sorry for
interruption yeah sure I would just need
to reverse a couple of I revert the cap
of commits by device it's fine so I
think the the the complexity here comes
from the fact that we have different
stakeholders we have the people who
actually want to write these modules we
have one of the people who actually want
to find those monuments we have Ayana
and in the first two groups we actually
have two subgroups which are the people
that that we're actually working for
that want to do this for the constraint
space but there are other people who
want to use zebra encoding and the
efficient form of zebra encoding and
they have much larger and many more yang
files and so on and to support that
constituency as well which of course
increases the availability of software
to do all the sorts I'll turn our
interest we have to be able to scale up
more than then we initially thought so
this is the reason why why this is
getting a little bit more complicated
than we thought so this is one part are
you going to say something about games
ago yeah and there is okay for example
here so yeah for young C bar what I can
say that it's rather stable the only
thing is that like on Saturday or
something like that we received some
comments very valuable reviews but the
input to assets oh great but there is
one thing like multiple items inside the
Union that currently is not handled like
very clearly different implementations
might get different results which is not
the
something who would want so now the
question is how do we resolve this
proposition that Carson might was to
have seats assigned to valor synonyms to
me personally that sounded that's a good
idea the only thing was to assign the
complexity yeah so just a small comment
so I the the point is that they aim to
see Boer is really getting interest so
people are from different communities
are really looking into it now and the
feeling that I get is that when yang was
made and and the encoding in XML and G
and Jason they were actually quite
permissive so people are doing stuff
that were not really well defined like
having these enemies so you send just a
string that says zero and the other end
just tries to figure out okay well is
the zero from the first anymore for the
second mmm for the third in them and
right now they figured out that all that
poses problems in some time in some
cases and they want to solve it well in
the yang to see Boer they want to have
something deterministic so this is where
it gets really interesting because we
need to answer some questions that arise
after the yin the yang community
operated things yeah Germany we call
these corpses in the basement so the the
problem we're having is that while ago
we decided we don't need much tripping
unions into in inside unions that's not
really something we had constraint
devices are interested in so we decided
to just not solve the problem and now
again what has happened is that that the
restaurant people have found out that
having a civil representation for the
interchange would make their service so
much faster so they want to use it and
again it is in our interest I believe
that maybe you see that differently it
is in our interest to have these
communities on board so we get much
better software support that then
if this were done only for for the ugly
space so we know that now that this is
from our point of view done and we push
it out and ask the young community to
review it we notice they they actually
want to use it as well and they are
actually interested in making the corner
cases of being actually work and the
most interesting part of this debate is
that there are already is a difference
between XML and JSON encoding that that
has been crossed over so what we would
be different yet again but maybe in a
slightly more destructive way so it's
probably worth fixing this and I have no
idea what will happen about these
annotations so far you're going to say
something about that so for the
annotations I still haven't looked into
them I mean obviously we would love to
find a good solution for that as you
said the wider the adoption the better
it is for us but so far I don't have a
solution that's worth mentioning
okay now let's comment so actually I'll
have a question to the chairs how do we
proceed with a into Siebel do we can
leave it open until the people from the
yang community they bring up new
questions and you know we find solution
to adapt to that or do we have like a
catch-all phrase saying well you know
this is the way it will be working into
SIBO v1 we try to - to - freeze it and
then when whenever you're going to have
a if you have new things to add there
will be a revision in in v2 in one year
and the at least we can focus on
something yeah that's a good question
what one important thing here of course
is
if we come up with any solutions that
would require us to change this advice
we better have that now so those may be
much harder to change that than anything
it's apart from that if we can stick
with the same seed files yes we might
have a partial solution I think it's a
bit of a perception whether this is just
a tiny thing we have to fix here or a
major thing that has to be added to make
it work and I think we're still in the
process of finding out which of
situation is the case so I don't really
have the answer here last time we said
we're ready to work with us call all
this except that we haven't done the
interview testing that we wanted to have
done how much further are we on that
line we are late on the inter
probability I mean we did the intro
probabilities like a year ago and thanks
for working since then we move so we
changed some things and we have not done
interrupts on these new things so even
though it seems straightforward I cannot
save 400 it is not like running code
that we can say well the thing is
running so into actually it is minor
details and simplifications compared to
the last the previous interrupts that
were working but today we still need to
forget interrupting the sense of two
companies working together or
open-source implementation working with
with another open-source implementation
so that probably if we are waiting for
this we need to to to focus on that
before then the new the next idea okay
so what one way to paralyze this a
little bit would be to get the net worth
net worth people involved and probably
the only way we can get them involved is
doing a wedding dress code
so we could decide to reverse this a
little bit and just do a reckoning
breath code to get their attention and
be aware that that the Interop work
might uncover other details even though
I don't think it's very likely it might
happen and there's always a second
pregnant girls call you don't you
haven't heard me said that yeah I think
that we at some point you know they were
in yang keeps changing also so it's like
a never-ending cycle so at the end it's
it's better at some point to say well
you know we have done a really great job
until now everything else it's like
trains strings so it's not going to be
really efficient but at least is going
to become behaving in the way that the
Jason encoding is working so that's good
for you and working group last call and
in case the people from medical mad
knots the scream really loud that okay
that doesn't work like this and we need
to fix it we'll fix it no problem but at
least to have this this deadline of you
know think about this really hard now
with some some items on the mailing list
like moving some stuff between the
documents and so on which I think needs
to be done before we can do that so when
will be the set of documents be ready
for such an exercise so I thought I had
the seed draft ready for review but
obviously this will still require a
little bit more work hopefully by the
end of the week yeah yeah so all the
things that I saw on the mailing list
but maybe we can go over it once again
all the things that that I saw are
already in there so the last review
sweetie I with Ayane were really
simplification so moving non normative
text into the appendix so nothing really
changes
we just renamed a couple of of titles -
sorry yes so so for me everything is
already done
we just need to the major work is done
in the verm in the draft that we have
with we're going to reveal it once again
and it will be done by the end of the
week okay so it seems the the plan is to
actually go home grass call this there
is a little detail that we haven't taken
care of yet which is the yang library
document which isn't even a regular
document so it's a bit hard to do a
working last call on that who in this
room is actually read that term the many
cameras as well and I think Alex of
course yeah this mean we should be doing
an adoption file for that document our
what we beta if there's more than three
people having read that
well it's Alex it's it's a very
straightforward document but it's just a
young module saying how do you get
information from a device like it's a
meta it's a young model that tells you
how do I get what are the modules on
this device and so forth so it's really
simple and straightforward stuff and I
think that place would be more in core
to do this work because we mostly know
how to interact with constrained devices
then in that mode its yang like it's
basic yang saying I can water move the
modules there water
blah blah blah so yeah it you can go and
read it if you wish but for me it's
really straightforward
and logical continuation of coke off
okay so I would expect that there will
be a resubmission of that together with
the other ones yeah and we try to be
ready at the end of the week and maybe
there would be a little bit more hallway
work going into that so we are actually
three minutes out of schedule so we are
in the miscellaneous section who had has
read this document of these who didn't
like it okay should we do this in this
working group see some nodding okay
Franciscan let me plus one in Java okay
thank you I mean it's definitely useful
and helpful and clarifies things that
might have been a bit unclear in the
past maybe we should make it larger and
try to go for a larger ITF audience than
just getting consensus in core yeah so
that would be the next step so one of
the the important things to get the the
attention of other people is to not load
it down with outreach specific things so
that that I wouldn't want to make it
larger I would like to make the carriage
larger that looks at it so that might
indeed be a next step to involve people
like HTTP this and so on and
see whether they can live with this
document whether that just stays our
terminology or other working groups I
actually also interested in this
technology that's a good point okay I
leave it to my co-chair to read this
room I recurrence quick comment you have
fun very useful I see myself calling the
document over and over again when I do
updates cuz that terminology is so easy
to get wrong so and there is no single
right or wrong until now so I'm glad
we're doing that
thank you so basically if I'm mistaken
there were about nine people in the room
that have read it out of which zero said
that it was a bad idea here good
positive comment so maybe we can move it
forward right all right you can talk
speed yeah anyone else I mean now is a
good time to voice any disagreements on
this otherwise we can do working up
adoption already on the mailing list all
right so then that's it thank you
so then there was this beautiful meeting
of the sec dispatch working group on
Monday who in this room was there
okay so quite a few people followed that
and as you know people are using x.509
certificates for many things not just
the same things it was designed for and
many people tell us they really would
like to have the flexibility provided by
CW cheese instead to get their
authenticated assertions and enter their
systems so the question was can we maybe
you write up a document that explains
how to do that this is not about
standardizing stuff because gwt's and
cosy already exists
and this CWT proof of possession
document but it's really about the
certificates that that we are seeing how
could these be translated into a CWT
word so that's one document we talked
about and I have have not paste it in
your slides genre there's also another
document that is for something
completely different except that it
actually looks very similar at the end
which is instead of doing something new
that solves the same problem we can of
course take the existing x.509
certificates and and well kind of give
them a new paint and we encode them in
NC ba and the the only problem of course
is that the signature that is in that
Excel valign certificate is computed
from an ace and one representation so
you are sending someone a SIBO
representation and that someone is
supposed to convert that back into an
x.509 specification extra line document
then compute the the fingerprint of that
and and verify the certificate so this
is a little bit of a wart the other one
is that it does inherit all the semantic
baggage and and uncertainties of x.509
although there is also a component to
the effort which is about profiling
x.509 itself so some of that baggage
will be taken away but still there's
some stuff in there that maybe is hard
to find out what it actually means but
in any case it means a constraint device
that wants to make use of these
certificates would either itself
implement AAS and one x.509 or would
possibly delegate this out to a verifier
that that has that
for the fridge so that that's related
work that is currently being submitted
to ace to the ACE working group the
other document that I talked about that
that that is actually in the car
submitted to the car working group and
now the question is does that even work
and if we read the charges of the two
working groups the answer is not really
so we had a side meeting about a month
ago mostly powered by by the cozy
working group chairs who had been toward
this might be something that could be
done in the cosy work group and they
were vehemently saying no that's not
something that should be done in the
course you know and so we try to look at
what what's out there and came up there
are essentially two candidates that make
sense which are ace and car is because a
zone CW T's which also was kind of a
very loose fit I mean took a while until
we found someone who was willing to do
CW T's and it landed in ace and the core
group on the other hand has the
requirements for getting these
assertions so these were the two groups
that kind of came out as the selection
of that cosy hallway meeting of course
there's also the ability to create
another working group or use another
existing working group but there's no no
obvious candidate for that and of course
there's also the the ability to just not
do the work and and live with x.509 as
it is but most likely people will still
be using cedar your teas for this and
just in a more uncoordinated fashion so
with that we went into the the SEC
dispatch meeting and of course everybody
started confusing the two efforts
and started thinking we wanted to redo
the whole mess that that x.509 is and
and decided redoing deafness needs above
and yeah so that's where we are at the
moment so most likely there will be
above four for doing this group forming
buff and we probably will have a charter
proposal and so on but as the core
working group we are of course
interested in making some of this happen
and and allow using these authenticated
sessions in our security mechanisms so
that's the situation we are in we will
have a little bit more delay before we
actually can start working on that and I
would be interested in additions from
anyone who was there on Monday as well
[Music]
so who has actually seen one of these
two blue dot things here so I need a
human or the seawall certificates
document one two three four five six
people okay good who would be willing to
contribute to an effort to get another
Wigner going on this one two three four
five six I think I'm seeing one hand
more unless they arrived at six but I
saw six David's militia Jim available
John this time okay good anything else
we can do on this at the moment
good so we are done with this one as
well and now we are on in the middle of
fighting from from the agenda so we have
nine minutes left so welcome to Friday
[Laughter]
[Music]
so Jim did the right thing and and and
escaped so he cannot be talking about
speedy blood trends the complications
really need miking who cannot make it
today I think and yeah the only other
thing we could talk about is the
resource directory there will be
different from you talk tomorrow right
yeah okay
go ahead let's use those nine minutes
[Music]
extensions um yes give me the give me
the TOC so hello this is Christine
answers on something that was planned
for Friday so the resource directory is
in a state where we are now officially
in working group last call and there are
some things that came up during the
discussions of resource directory that
could have been integrated there but we
were already trying to get the number of
pages down and we do have extension
mechanisms in resource directory that
allow many things to be defined later on
so I started a document in which I'll
I'm currently just enumerated and
drafting specification for things that
can be done with a resource directory
and that may assist in in operating it
okay so I think we can stick with the
with the table of contents for starts so
the largest part in there is its reverse
proxying now this is something that has
been introduced in the even in the in
the motivational examples of the
resource directory today a client
connects to the resource directory be
that by actually sending UDP messages
but making everything in between aware
that that UDP messages can now go back
and forth here be that via coop over TCP
and thus creating a more persistent
connection or be that by a coop over
WebSockets because that's the only thing
that device can do because it is a web
browser actually and when such a device
read and windows that device registers
with the resource directory it could ask
the resource directory to play from to
play
reverse proxy for it because in the coop
or WebSocket example if device is
actually a browser application no one
can connect can connect there this is
also something that conceptually is
happening in many likely templum
deployments where there are no other
connections than the one that the device
is opening towards its lightweight FM
server which is the resource directory
so basically what I am doing here is
just suggest a way of discovering
support for an option that can be set
with a resource directory at
registration time that says I suspect
that I can't be that I'm not reachable
from the outside
um please serve as a proxy for me and
rather than announcing the address from
which I am connecting which is utterly
useless to everyone who doesn't have the
connection open please mint
please mint an authority component and
announce me under that which is
basically aligning with the alternative
transports and the protocol negotiation
but from to the to the to the lookup
client that is working with the resource
directory it won't tell it it won't know
the difference it will just it might
observe that the maybe we have an
example bit lower here yeah
so the look yeah um the lookup client
may may notice that this your I here
looks like it is host it is somewhere
close to the resource directory but
without looking into a big identifiers
it doesn't really make much of a
difference so this is this is one thing
that I think it would be useful to have
spelled out somewhere before people
start doing it without having thought
about what could go wrong with it
so the another is a much smaller thing
that was um registering with infinite
lifetime so that was a request from from
Jim if I remember correctly that we
currently specify lifetimes on there
might be situations in which it may be
okay to say that my life
is infinite we don't need to specify
that in resourcedirectory that can be an
extension it can be discovered and it
should in my opinion look like that and
with that for example an application
that registers for being proxied can say
that my lifetime is practically infinite
because you will know when my connection
terminates and then you'll kick me out
and as long as that doesn't happen Here
I am that one that's and the third one
I'd like to point out is is so
identifiers that came in very late in
the in the in the resource directory
when we thought about what does it
actually mean if someone registers with
a link-local address because lookup
clients might not be on that link and
what the resource directory now says is
that there is a split horizon situation
the resource directory needs to know
that there are there are clients on this
side and on that side but to the
administrator this means that because
the administrator comes from some point
and then at work it might not even be
able to see some registrations so in
very particular situations it might be a
good idea to allow returning your eyes
that contain seven identifiers
if it was specifically requested and the
requester um it was adequately
authorized to obtain that information so
this is something that might be useful
to in in the management interface this
is something that I wouldn't expect to
be implemented by default in a resource
directory but if someone wants to use it
this is how it could be done and also
this service is an example of how the
resource directory can be can be
expanded what how those expansion points
are used I don't really know where to go
on was a document because I'm not using
all of the features that I'm describing
in there so my question is are there
features in here that that have an
appeal to the working group are there
features in here that you may be using
yourself or other
just that should go in here so who in
this room has a problem that one of
these extensions what Oliver would
address nobody using it let me kind of
Jim job I don't have any problems that
you need us ever solves because I don't
have any of this stuff the other place
that I was looking at the infinite
lifetime for is if you have somebody go
in and be a third party configure you
put it you put a device into the direct
resource directory it makes sense to
just go ahead and say it's there forever
rather than forcing the device to
register itself so I think that's
actually a really strong use case for
that particular thing it's like if you
decommission that the Nino to go back
and take it out of the directory so
maybe I cannot speak for our me but I
obviously see a value on the infinite
lifetime because that's a continuous
problem that you need to keep renewing
the registration of a lightweight and to
imply it maybe other people from oh I
make could also voice an opinion but I
think maybe the problem is that we
haven't read the draft so it's hard to
have an opinion yet but I I that's
another thing I will at least review it
for sure
thank you yeah so the time also is
community up so take you to the list is
the correct answer here so if any any of
this sounds like you might want to use
this please send a message to the list
that will help Christian decide which
are which of these we want to take up
and which of these stays on the back
burner for long thank you so see most of
you on Friday I hope I'll see what most
of you in the thing to think wizard good
meeting in
eight minutes one blush I know Alex will
be gone