good morning everybody we're gonna get
started here shortly
morning
welcome to cozy working group session if
you are not here for that
thank you for taking minutes so the blue
sheets should be making their way around
important that this is an official ITF
meeting so please note well IPR and kept
right and code of conduct items probably
already seen this at least once this
week so far but if not please do take
time to read this if you're not familiar
reminder of where we are having minutes
do we have anybody willing to jabber
scribe anybody
Thank You Russ
we'll find we'll find you a backup or I
will back up thank you
and then also other materials are
available on that link if you've
downloaded the slides already so here's
our agenda we're going to start off with
with well as we've already started off
with administrivia then going through
updates on abyss with hash algorithms
than the x.509 followed by the
additional web event and suit hash
signatures and then some next steps
after this
any-any bashing of this agenda all right
Jim you're up should be
set this thing up so I don't have to
move around okay okay so the first
document we're looking at is the
structure half which is the document
that we're going to try to actually get
moved up to full standard the biggest
open issue is some issues around counter
signatures so the first item is when I
was actually getting my counter
signature code running I found that it
was difficult to actually tell simply if
something was a single counter signature
or there were more than one because in
both cases the first stated the first
type tag that you looked at was a an
array so you actually had to look one
more level down to figure out whether
there was a single version a single
counter signature or two so the thing
I'm basically proposing is that we
remove the first option in terms of
what's there from the list we've gotten
one person who said yes I think that's
right - and I don't believe that there's
any countersignature code out there that
is actually standing countersink rushers
around and the wild which is going to be
affected by this does anybody know
anything differently
does anybody have any objections to have
making that change okay next item when
we compute all of our authentications
structures we've got a context string
into everything and right now the
context string that we use for the
countersignature one structure
is countersignature zero and it's that
way for historic reasons specifically i
renamed the structure and I forgot to
rename the strength little details it
wasn't something that I was horribly
interested in at the time was those
actually kind of putting it in under
protest but it actually is really needed
so from an aesthetic person's
perspective it makes sense to do the
rename it is however in an absolute
breaking change for any countersignature
or zeros messages which exists out in
the real world at this point in time the
only implementations I know of eff
countersignature zero are mine and as
long as we managed to get this changed
before the kontiki version no the
californian version is actually
published brocade
once the californium version is
published that's it's gonna be game over
on this so if we do it we really have to
do it this week do people have opinions
on this custom woman's a little bit like
looking at an object of art that has a
change somewhere in it and I think I'll
just differ in how they look at objects
of art with that property I think a
little bit of patina increases the value
and I really wouldn't want to send the
signal we are making gratuitous changes
here I mean it's from a technical point
of view it's gratuitous it could have
been fubar and would be doing well and
the only thing I see is that editorially
this needs to be clearly called out that
this is
maybe different from expected right
don't think there will be a lot of
people trapped by violating the
principle of least surprise here because
I mean it's obvious that it doesn't work
if you use the wrong John Watson
Erickson I think we should fix it while
we can as in a reason not to fix it and
I think even if people it's football
might have been better because here you
have some idea how it should look like
so people might get it wrong they might
write they made it wrong they won't be
able to run against VFL it will fail but
we we are creating annoying sense in
people implementing is for no reason
Mike Jones Microsoft when we violate the
principle of least surprise
it's the developers the implementers you
have to build this stuff that gets
surprised and may in fact do wrong
things because they're making
assumptions which might have been true
but aren't so I agree with the previous
speaker we should fix this while the
fixings good Brendan Morin arm while we
may only know of one implementation that
exists that doesn't mean there aren't
more out there and this potentially
could cause breaking changes within
infrastructure of people who haven't
published publicly I think this is a
really dangerous change and without
significant input from the community I
think it's quite concerning so one thing
I will know one thing I will notice we
did send out a notice a few weeks ago
asking about this and got very little
response so far
so this has been on the mainland with a
sigh I do like we understand the this is
why we're discussing it now also no I
understand that but I mean to me this is
a structure revision this this would
mean that you need to version this back
last moment also you actually have to
answer to ask the question at the time
this document is published because there
is this period of time when people still
only find it 1 5 2 in the ROC set and
they're just aren't aware that this is
happening here and we don't have the
perfect marketing machine that that
pushes this out so there is there is a
race condition and we don't have to have
this race race condition and even if we
put an errata on the document today
people have a strong tendency to miss
reading Aramis my advice yeah I'm scared
of making a change so I mean personally
other than then it's a little bit of a
jump for people who actually are doing
the implementations I think that given
that we may also immediately point to
test vectors that are out there and are
and are correct right now not doing it
is probably the correct answer
this is Russ Housley so that makes sense
to me maybe the thing to do is in the
new one add a small implementations
considerations that says no the tags are
the same here's how you deal with it
okay four notes then let's so we could
take we could take a home to see to get
verification on which way we want to go
here so with the the this is the counter
signature contact string if you think
that the existing counter signature 0
string is acceptable to keep with
potentially with with the implementation
note or the call-outs we'll do a hum for
that will do a hum for changing it to
counter signature one and so we'll let's
start with the first one so those that
think that we should leave well enough
alone and add a call-out please hum now
and for those that think we should
change it now to to match what the
actual structure is please hum now
[Music]
alright so we we've chairs we'll make
one more call on the list to get some
confirmations of see if we can we can
nail this down better so if we can take
a note that an action I on for the
chairs to verify and we need to make it
really really fast okay can I just know
that this was a hum between making a
technical change
not making it akin to change right so
there should be a folder well that
that's very fair we've the the chart
already says we're making make the
minimal changes we we believe so the
default answer is going to be if we
can't find consensus and things stay the
way they are okay
the countersignature zero stuff was
added kind of at the last minute and
we're doing the cosy the original
document so right now all of that stuff
is sitting in an appendix
so from it just pure editorial
reorganization we probably should move
the counter signatures there are stuff
out of the appendix and put it in with
the same countersignature stuff the
question that I have is should we make
counter signatures be a subsection of
signing which is what they currently are
or should they be a top-level section of
the of their own equivalent to doing
signing and encryption and acting
because it's kind of a the zone thing
kind of not is and it's basically for
people who read the document are they
going to find it easier to find things
that way than the other way this is
Russell you can't counter sign if you
didn't first sign yes you can you can
counter sign an encrypted message what
does that mean the SEC same thing No
that doesn't make sense to me I think if
you organize it so that counter
signatures are even if syntactically
what you said is true are part of
confirming someone else's signature then
people will use it in a in a way that
doesn't surprise receivers okay
the group a scored document which is in
the core group is doing counter
signatures on encrypted messages to mean
who actually is the person who sent the
message because everybody's sharing a
group key you need to use want to know
who in the group did it and what we're
doing to do that is we're signing the
out signed on the outside rather than
signing on the inside so right now we're
already violating the RUS thinks this is
not a bright idea I said it's really
principled but the actual evidence
doesn't have to be part of the data
structure I mean if I'm counter signing
something because of evidence that that
I'm not going to add to the data
structure that's a very valid thing I
have trouble understanding why this one
would not be valid so the
description of Mac encrypt sign moving
from the inside out we're actually doing
the encrypted inside yeah
encrypting with a group key and then
signing so that you would be no
different if you used a full signature
set of a counter signature you'd get the
same property
Franchesca panel mini personal opinion
I'd like to have it its own separate
section rather than under signature of
course you're gonna reference the
signature section for oh yeah I think
yeah when you're looking for that
it seems or to find I don't know okay
I think I know what I'm doing there
right yeah I think we've not heard
anybody say no please leave it as an
appendix definitely so I think I think
we could take your discretion at what
they at what it what they at it is and
then when we were going through going
through reviews then see you know we'll
address it then but at this point then
make the I think we can trust Jim to
make the changes that better relevant
last item on this slide we have gotten
seaboard tags assigned for encrypting
crip zero
Mac Mac zero sign sign sign one we
didn't do one for counter signatures
because I didn't think about it and I'm
not too sure that it makes sense I'm
basically bringing it up at this point
just purely as a completeness issue so I
don't know of any situation where one
would have a counter signature floating
around on its own a detached
countersignature such that it would
actually need to be tagged as a counter
signature
[Laughter]
okay I will take that as if we don't
deal with anything with that particular
with getting the tag if we really need
to take if someone comes up with
something interesting we can get it
later
I guess moment I'm very much against
proof by leg of imagination so I think
completeness just cause for doing this
it doesn't cost very much I mean it
costs one sea boat egg
depending on how long you make it that
cost can be very low and it makes it
available for when it's needed and you
then you don't need to or suddenly start
doing complicated things it definitely
doesn't need to be a one bite egg okay
does anyone else have an opinion
which way can you go well so the so this
was discussed at the virtual interim
briefly with a will ask for it when we
need it and now we've gotten at least
one opinion of we should just ask for it
now and so nobody else has has anything
I'd like to see on this one I suppose we
can run a home to see whether we should
at whether we should register for one
now so if you think we should register
for a countersignature seaboard tag with
this document at this point
please hum now and if you think we
should not register a tag at this point
please hum alright so I think what we're
hearing is we we leave well enough alone
for now oh you said for slightly for for
registering yeah okay so okay we will
register for one then we'll add that to
the document do you think it needs and
really I don't think it needs an early
registration well go ahead and put it in
a document and people can argue about it
once it's there things of things which
basically I don't necessarily know what
we're doing with or just to basically I
need input I rewrote the ionic
considerations to basically only have
the things that I am is supposed to do
when this document shows up rather than
having all of the old registrations in
the Ino sections to make it easier for I
ana and also because I've been getting
pushback on some other documents I've
written from the iesg about why does
this section say that you're making
these registrations when they have
already been done
so it makes if tri rather than trying to
say these are historic registrations and
these are current registrations
I'm just deleted everything that was
historic and just keeping what's current
we also the virtual talked briefly about
whether or not we needed to update the
instructions for the designated experts
at the that meet at that meeting I was
tasked with doing a poll of the current
set of designated experts to find out
what their opinions were and everybody
who replied to me which was I'm not sure
it was all of them but it was almost all
of them basically said we don't have
enough experience with things going
wrong yet to think that we need to
update them which i think is a perfectly
fair statement and if if we need to
change them later that's that's still
relatively easy to do
currently the document has a down ref
juice to the c4 document on the other
hand the Seaboard document in theory is
going to get out of the Seaboard working
group at some point in the or hopefully
not too long distant future at which
case we won't have the damn raft but if
we do end up base racing out before they
do we either need to justify the down
roof or we're gonna sit in the RSC other
to keep waiting for it to show up and
that's just I'm highlighting that as
something that may be an issue because
in talking to the chairs we're looking
at saying we want to try for a working
group last call somewhere around the
Montreal time frame so that we can get
this to the isg and hopefully done
before I start making wine in September
I now actually have a little bit more
control over that than I used to since
I'm now one of the co-chairs of that
working group I was about to ask the
co-chairs have any thoughts on this
they'd like to share
[Laughter]
Francesca bambini so the milestone was
October 2018 for for that document just
for your information we all know
milestones are suggestions yeah but but
in reality how do you feel like the
document yeah I think we are close yeah
I think it I think we should make it
probably by Montreal I hope so
one of the things that is part of the
issue of which document that we
reference is we do discuss some
canonical encoding issues um in our
document
and we currently right now refer to 70
49 in terms of defining how some of
those canonicalization things work the
new seaboard document now has a couple
of different things in it which say
different things one of the words which
I believe has completely disappeared at
this point is the word phenomenal
ization but the rules that we use can
refer to either of the two serialization
recommend the serialization things in
the document so I think we can update
this without a problem is just a
question of race conditions right so the
the syllabus
wording does not use the word
canonicalization of course it points
back through 70 49 because there is a
technical difference between the
recommendation and 70 49 the
recommendation that is in the right now
in either case it's a recommendation so
you need to specify even if you just say
do it like the recommendation says so
yeah I think we are fine and just as one
of the things for the taking your
checklist let's try to make sure that we
are not creating any difference so your
rules are a proper subset of the
recommendations in my roles are
definitely proper subset because the
only rules I with the only real rule
that I'm with that we use is minimal and
coding yes
Oh Lawrence Thunder lead the Seaboard
canonicalization and deterministic
encoding has always been a bit weird to
me my preference would be to just take
the canonicalization needed for cozy
into the cozies back and just drop the
reference just seems like that would be
cleaner to me is the the
canonicalization needed for cosy is
pretty small and specific where the the
general rule seemed no more general and
and it seems like it might be cleaner to
do that I'm gonna have to go back and
actually reread what's there I believe
the only thing we point back to is we
point back to to say that's that defines
how you do minimal and floating lights
because we don't actually have save we
don't have a method for saying that in
our document yeah so the editorial
intent is to improve on the section that
that defines this minimal encoding it's
no longer a part of the prefer of the
deterministic encoding it's called
preferred encoding now and the the
deterministic encoding is preferred
encoding plus map key sorting but in any
case I think the the what the
application the Seaboard application
protocol cosy does it's nice if you
follow the recommendations of Siva
Bastille but see what this really
doesn't have a busyness in making you
any tell you how to do it that that's
your decision and on the other hand the
application doesn't have any business
telling the the civilization protocol
what what the recommendation for other
application protocol should
and and the other thing too is is when
we point back in the Seaboard document
we can point back into the I mean the
bitch document has kept the 70 49 method
in the document and we can still just
refer to that method without having to
if I mean in terms of dad tells you how
to do minimum cocaine yes but that would
be confusing but because it would send
the message that you have to have the
old 70 the free world 70 49
canonicalization to do cozy and that's
not true if you have the the syllabus
deterministic encoding you have
everything you need to do cause you have
more than you need to do cost so I would
explicitly not refer to the old
recommendation which only differ in the
way they do math lease watching anyway
right yeah I mean in terms of encoding
integers and arrays and byte strings are
identical which is all we care about
okay I'm gonna look at it and see how
much work it is to pull the minimal
encoding lengths into our document and
it was too much work I'll just refer to
the new the newer sections in the new
document in off steps one of the things
that we're supposed to do is to provide
the iesg some level of yes we actually
have multiple implementations that in
Iraq and what we provide is whatever the
ADEs happen to want on that particular
day so the chairs and I and the ABS need
to sit down and at some point agree on
what it is that we're gonna send up we
actually have three different families
of implementations I've got three
implementations there's also an
implementation in JavaScript and an
implementation in Python they are not
complete in terms of then they don't all
do counter signatures they don't all
implement all of the different
algorithms that you could do the
JavaScript one I know only does ECDSA
and II CVH it doesn't do any of the
Edwards curves but from an inter option
operative from the point of doing
interoperability and we give me even the
report that I don't believe that matters
because that's underlying cryptographic
algorithms that has nothing to do with
how cozy itself is structured so you can
you can look at the messages you can
build signed messages you can care part
signed messages and they work it doesn't
matter which signature hugger than use
you know to the covers
I had we'd hoped to actually do a little
bit of interrupt testing at the
hackathon but we didn't have anybody
else who showed up so that didn't happen
we need to try to do a little bit of
formal interrupts testing sometime
between now and Montreal ways we can
Brendon Morin I just wanted to make a
note about Interop and some of the
content in the RFC and it's not spelt
out very clearly exactly what the
contents of a signature field are the
the problem that this is caused for me
has been that all of the crypto
libraries I have access to default to
producing an ASN one encoded signature
and so the two fields have to be
extracted from that to put them in a
cause a signature container and a naive
implementation will just put the whole
thing in there and thus not interrupt
okay that's that's the ECDSA yes it r NS
Roman genitive unrelated so given it
there's the family of all these
implementations you were pointed to some
of them where is the one unified place
where I can go and see a list of them if
you go to the cozy working group a
github repository you will find the
c-sharp version the java version and the
c versions or which is are the three of
mine and i am going to be putting
pointers on the readme page of the of
this particular document which is also
in the cozy working group to point to
the other two the other two
implementations great thanks so to leave
the subject of this group for a couple
of seconds that is of course a question
that comes up for other SIBO based
formulas like cinnamon and so on as well
and my plan is to extend the Seaboard at
our own site in such a way that it can
carry pointers to fermentations of cozy
cinema suits and so on so i will contact
you you
after the meeting sometime after the
meeting to collect that information
I started their implementation but I
don't even know if it's worth calling
implementation only in human planted
what was needed for group or score and
ad hoc and only one way encryptions I
can produce test vectors but again going
forward
anyone who's implementing and has
feedback on something that's not clear
something it needs to be done better I
want to hear about it because that's the
whole purpose of doing this revision is
to make things clearer for implementers
is anybody else have any other issues
with regarding the structure draft so
the algorithms draft it's got to get hub
repository there's almost no changes in
the actual contents at this point in
time given the the what you had I'm
pulled that in for the for the a CVS a
there's actually if you go to the root
of the readme there's actually two
pointers to RSC diff which will which
will actually compare the current
version and 80 81 52 so you can actually
look to see what changed between
everything I don't know of any open
issues on this particular document or I
didn't I've got one now but if I missed
anything I want to hear about it so
where we headed I need to clean up this
ticket there's security considerations I
didn't bother actually rewriting them so
that both the structure and the
algorithm graph currently have exactly
the same content and I don't think
that's probably correct
I needed a grammar and spelling pass I
need to check for some of the missing
pointers back to the original draft and
I want to copy over a bit of the code in
terms of what you need to put into the
protected headers fields and what you
need to protect put in the unprotected
header fields for some of the algorithms
just so people don't have to flip back
and forth between the two documents
does anybody else have any thing that
they want to talk about on that document
okay there been a few requests for Pete
for us doing new algorithms the biggest
one has been the paddock erupt and one
of the questions that I had for us it
went on the mailing list was are you
doing this as a Content encryption
algorithm or is a key rap algorithm and
what I got back was the primary use case
that he had in mind was for it to be a
Content encryption algorithm of a key
but not a key relative to the cozy
message we're just doing a key
distribution for something else the one
pushback that I have about doing this is
this is could be our first AE algorithm
only so it is not in a EAD algorithm as
near as I can I don't believe there is a
version which is is there okay I mean I
couldn't find it we're gonna all that
suppose have to sit down and looked
it could be but I don't know of anyone
who uses it that way right so there's no
external data that is MACT you in any
implementation are more in the center I
don't remember seeing one in the spec
that I read it may be one in a different
spec so the only question in in terms of
that is as a Content encryption
algorithm is do people think it's a
problem setting that precedent that we
have a Content encryption algorithm that
is not a EAP
okay
so there's a whole slew of potential
algorithms that we could put into this
hash algorithms that we don't currently
have although some of those hash
algorithms are in the hash draft they
could basic yeah this is all sorts of
signature algorithms that we could be
adding key rap algorithms Mac algorithms
ADF algorithms so basically at this
point it's if you have any particular
things that you want to have added in
this new draft speak up on the list be
prepared to take care of a case as to
why you think it should be added because
I will tend to push back on everything
even the ones I went to add I'll have to
make sure that the ad is happy that we
can do this in our charter because our
Charter says we'll do the things which
are needed by suit and other types of
people and these are probably algorithms
which they are not directly asking for
we're just doing them just more and so
my question would be what exactly is our
strategy with for dealing with things
like sha-3 so it's kind of inevitable
that this has to be added at some point
so why exactly want we do we want to
make it hard for people to use this why
do we want the first guy who wants to
use this have to jump through hoops I
think we have much better off if we ship
this with batteries included I mean it
is things like if you I mean the
question is you say sha-3 yes
so when you say sha-3 do you mean sha-3
256 sha-3 512 shake 128 or shape 256 yes
I mean as hash algorithms independently
as by a signature algorithm you're
starting to get a big growth and there
is a question as to how many people are
going to be switching to Edwards kurz as
opposed to staying with EC ba ma yeah
right so I think the the my question
wasn't it's presumably about Shari but
rather about what what is our plan and
and and in point of fact you know if
your justification is the IETF is headed
towards doing this then I think that's a
reasonable justification it's just you
know if you want to come in and say I
wanted your kangaroo 12 I mean okay the
King or 12 draft can do that
actually I think it should but they're
people who argue about that disease and
see frg draft it's a registry entry so
registry entries can can just be ended
by cfrt draft but the interesting
observation is that coffee is used by
other stos and it would be really useful
for them to to enable them to skip the
IANA thing I mean if this this other
standard where where ITU is squatting on
code points because they didn't
understand the IANA thing I mean they
are also doing it wrong but which is
even worse but the interesting
observations they're squatting on code
points because they didn't figure out
how to get the IANA registrations and I
would just like to take a little bit of
the sand out of the gears here and just
make it easy for other people so the
observation VI HF is going to do this is
is a good observation but maybe
something is really widely looked at
like shell 3 it should also be in a good
justification firing
John Watson Eriksson I think shot 3 is
something that should be discussed and
added now I think the hash algorithm a
good choice to standardize the shape but
not the main shortly I think that can be
discussed is that is needed as well but
I think shake should be added now having
kmac is also useful algorithm should be
added now that's a short read about the
right algorithm Quinn danged nest um I
saw from the previous slide if you and
the whooping group one day decided to do
the PDF which came back you could do it
with the HT DF or you could do just came
back alone that is an option we
specified and yep you could use it H PDF
or you just you you know one past kmac
myself and both options are affine to us
and by me and and you know part of this
is if we decide we want to add kmac
which i think is probably a good idea
that's the sort of discussions we need
to have as to how many different
variants of it exists so it's like
saying I want to add kmac is
unfortunately not a sufficient answer
you have to say ok so you know do I want
to add all the kit do I want to do it
with HK D F or start with this yeah with
HK D after I want to do a plane do I
want to have an implicit tied together
or do I want to do Chinese menu for
doing key agreement plus k di plus key
generation you know um so no I don't
want to do you know 6,000 different
things if people aren't going to be if
people don't think they're going to be
using them sure um so da is you and the
working group will have to decide but to
me and
to us both options are fine in turn
obscurity htif there's two stages and
kmac those only one stage means one step
so and going from from H max sha-2 to 2k
Mac is already be any new one step yeah
once one fewer steps that's right
oh yeah 2 or 3 because 4 4 th Mac you do
if the key is not the right size have to
hash it and then it has two key with the
XOR value and then you have seen the
message altogether so does so yeah and
that's and that's one of the reasons I
come yeah I put K Mac on the list is I
think it's is interesting I mean it's
the key ramp algorithms the k WF when I
put on there I don't know that anybody
knows what it was I didn't until the
middle of February when I was trying to
find something else and I ran across
this is a hash only key rap algorithm
and I haven't torn it apart to enough to
fit to figure out what it does and how
it works but you know if we're looking
at post quantum stuff then that may be
something that's of interest
so anyway if you have things that you
think you want to do send them to the
list and my current timeline is I kind
of like to get a rough draft put
together for Montreal of what what
things we should be doing and that's it
one thing the chairs will note is well
the while the current charter does say
we're doing doing essentially the
minimal for this group and our dependent
groups or groups groups have
dependencies on this work there is
nothing that necessarily stops us from
retiring to do additional algorithms if
we can't come to agreement relatively
quickly so something to keep in mind
hash algorithm document so what's
currently in the document sha-1 a few
different shot to variations and to
shake algorithms the sha-1 is going into
the registry marked as deprecated but it
is there because a lot of people it's
still perfectly good to use sha-1 for
certain types of things if what you're
doing the same I want to just filter out
of I've got a whole this Louis Lewis or
did because I want to get the ones that
are possible it's like if you get two or
three back doesn't really make a
difference because you just check each
of one of them until you find the one
with the right public key it's not
something that we recommend in signature
algorithms anymore but this is basically
just looking at hashes so depending on
how you're using it if it's not a huge
problem
do you sha-1 but we're really pushing
two people to move off the sha-1 so if
that's why it's marked as deprecated
um I don't know that there's a problem
with the fact that we don't have a 512
bit strength sha-3 but I don't know I'm
never positive that shake 256 and
sha-512 have the same security level
Queen dang again um I saw that you rose
something like shoppes / 64 or something
what what does that mean sha-256 trunk
82:6 the first 64 bits you take the only
signify bit stutters that's the hash
value yes
that's dangerous shouldn't do it if what
I'm doing is saying here's a thumbprint
of a certificate and I want to send
minimal bytes across it doesn't matter
if I find extra certificates I just
wanted to reduce the universe that I'm
looking at okay I not quite capture what
you're using for but I have a thing
about exactly what what the application
for so you he wants like it's a indexed
cut off looking for things not okay okay
then that's that's what this test would
be minimum but I'd have to go back and
look to see which RFC that is so with a
Kathleen
right not for what I'm talking about so
some like random index value for for
certain objects this is like and then
you had a question you got in to shake
256 and sha-3 512 yeah they are they the
same strength um they both provide 256
bits of security the SHA the shot three
has farter base of preimage in second
preimage resistance but that is
essentially you know but collision is to
the 56-bit of collision resistance
strength and so 256 bits of security is
more than enough so you don't you know
you you don't need or anything
go to file Topher for anything and but
by doing that you're burning it double
energy you know energy consumption and
your function will to be twice slow from
shake 512 shake 256 to char 3 5 12 so
yeah just 1 so back to the / 64 thing
there what I hear you saying I will
translate into this is not a
cryptographic hash function this is a
cryptographic hash function I'm not
using this one yeah so I think it is
useful to have these things that that
cannot really be used as a graphic edge
functions I recovered I would like
actually like to edge which most
definitely are not cryptographic and I'm
wondering whether this is the right
space to do it because it's really
useful to have numbers for those so we
have this other protocol called
constrained cost which which uses
different hash functions and it would be
nice to just have one registry where we
have these hash functions so we don't
have to create a hash function registry
just for constraint cust I think that
this is potentially a perfectly valid
place to do that because they could be
used yeah but then we should be very
very clearly called Assad yes
that yeah John Watson I think kangaroo
12 is interesting and supported adoption
see if orgy but I think it's too early
for cosy I think that has to wait a year
or more so right now as the recommended
value that I've got on the sha-256 slash
64 is no because it doesn't really
provide the the declension resistance
that you want but I think it makes sense
if especially if we're going to add the
additional algorithms into this table to
put another to know the column into it
which describes something about the
functions that they have the house this
that could be used for so in terms of if
you're looking for collision resistance
as opposed to just filtering so that's
clearer in the IANA registry Kathleen
looks puzzled
[Laughter]
Kathleen Moriarty so I just making sure
I heard what I thought I heard so you're
gonna drop the truncation no okay I mean
I call them into the registry which says
the things like sha-256 slash 64 should
not be used for X okay as and as as
opposed to just saying recommended is no
okay great I thought you're saying you
were dropping and completely I want to
think about this a bit more just in
terms of right if people want to give me
some input in terms of or the designated
experts of which I'm one input in terms
of how frequently they think these hash
algorithms are going to be used just in
terms of whether we assigns some of the
one byte space as opposed to assigning
two byte identifiers to them I what I'd
like to hear that as a right now is
probably the
that suit is going to be using all the
time it's gonna be a one bite and
everything else is gonna be a few bitin
your MOT some I think how often is it
used it's not the only criteria it's
probably how often it is going to use in
a very constrained environment if it's
very well used in the cloud environment
where you have no constraints you can
assign something to give it anyway so
yeah so just a comment from the suit
perspective the current version of the
draft is actually importing hash
identifiers from the named information
draft if that needs to be adjusted we
can do that but that's currently where
we're finding the algorithm identifiers
because there weren't any in cozy
Brendan Morin right and this draft is in
part response to the needs that were
expressed from suit I've been basically
kind of against to having cozy define a
hash structure and because if it tends
to be one of those things that well it
depends on what other information you're
using so the question at this point is
really do we put one into the hash draft
or do we put one into the x.509 draft so
what would be the use case we would be
addressing with an example well it's I
mean we need to do it define it for X 5
or 9 so we have we have to find a
structure which says I've got a hash and
I've got a value and the question is
whether people in general would want to
do that or as I generally recommend they
should be defining their own structure
so I said you know suit you should
define your own your own cozy strut your
own cc4 structure for this because you
may want to put in things other than
just
the hash identifier and the hash value
you may want to put in things like a
pointer to what it is that you're
hashing yeah that's why it would be an
example but okay mirroring something
that people know from the sn1 world and
say this is how you would do that in the
cosy world I think that's a good
criterion for chosen a an example okay
I'll put one in and we'll see that where
the big people object so documents
missing because the security
considerations at this point and then
there's just a couple of procedural
questions if suit wants to use this and
we need to do early assignment of the
identify of at least some of the
identifiers the ones that they want to
be using and there's a procedural
question in terms of timing this
potentially could be going into working
class call even before the bitch
documents evolve what I'm doing this is
writing considering considerations and
that's it
I mean we could we could see about a
last call before the 8150 to bits I
think the general track we've been
running is trying to make sure we're
focused on more drafts the core bisque
wraps first but if there's energy to get
more done we can certainly approach that
so what is stopping us from low-scoring
this right now the fact I need to put in
security considerations okay in an
editorial your past when you have
checkbox everything that was on the
slides is to any thing remaining nope so
I I don't see a reason to make our life
to be cured with early assignment and so
on it instead of just ripping this thing
okay so I think the action there is we
once Jim once you have those security
considerations and editorial and
preferably an editorial pass that we can
we can start a last call there goes
we've got a certificate for using or
we've got a draft for you for being able
to carry x.509 certificates in cozy
messages or something similar so right
now we have attributes defined for a bag
of certs chain asserts the thumbprint of
the cert and appoint a URL that points
to a certificate the defaults in terms
of which you are referring to whether
you're referring to something on the
signers and on the originators end or
something on the recipients and depends
upon whether you're looking at signing
or key agreement signing it's is refers
to the originators and
key agreement it refers to the
recipients and which Manson when I sat
down to actually start doing things I
said oh my gosh I need to do something
for static static as well so I defined
also I've added some duplicate stuff for
first static static I did not duplicate
the bag of sorts because that seemed
insane a single bag is sufficient you
shouldn't need to so some of the open
issues that we need to look at is there
anyone there are now two header
attributes that you would put in for a
static static one identifies the
sender's certificate one identifies the
recipient certificate
I know what I'm doing
so do we wanted to extend the key usage
my inclination is null but if there's
anyone who wants to restrict
certificates to just being cozy then it
makes sense to do it
do we want to worry about transporting
revocation information again my answer
is probably not if someone really needs
to do it then I want to know about it
but other than that I don't care this
actually does to find a cozy house
structure if we put it over into the
hash document we can just point to it
rather than using it rather than
defining another one here
Safa one six six
it doesn't really matter one with the
other as far as I'm concerned the sea
bore that that the URL right now is set
up to say put the Seaboard uri tag on it
and that's probably redundant since you
know that's the only thing that's going
to be in that field so my information
right now is I'm going to remove that
unless someone has a reason to say no
Cosmo and so if this is an extension
point where you might want to plug in
another type of fixed on a reference
instead the tag makes sense if it isn't
it shouldn't be there because it's just
inviting you to be used as an extension
point
Mike Jones Microsoft in the Jose context
as you probably recall when we were
asked to add the x.509 certificate
fields x5c and the thumbprint etc one of
the things that at least the Jose
working group decided to do was say
essentially that the certificate was
always extra information which you could
ignore if you didn't need it and the way
they did that was to say that if you had
a certificate the jwk representation of
the public key that's on it must also be
present if you have another slide please
please proceed I mean this is basically
I'm just pointing to it I don't have a
save it I don't have any
we don't carry keys in messages right
now that's a difference between closed E
and Jose so one of the questions is do
we do something what what do we want to
do with certificates and cosy he's as
Mike was saying what Jose did was say
that the certificate is parallel to the
key that's already in there which means
that you potentially have to do some
extra checks to make sure that what's in
the certificate and wasn't in the jwk
are consistent with each other the other
way you could do it is we can say we're
not going to make them because we're not
going to do that because you're either
gonna do one or the other you're not
going to end up doing both so what we
could do for that is we could basically
create a new key type for cozy keys
which says this is an x.509 certificate
it also give us gives us a way forward
because one of the issues that was
raised on the mailing lists but in the
last week is well what happens if what I
want to do is use a JWT so you could
basically identify a JWT the same sort
of way into if you want to carry it in a
key which makes my implementation easier
because then I'm still just carrying
keys passing keys into the
implementation and it's up to the
implementation if you get what to do
with a certificate or with a CWT we
don't have any implementation experience
playing with this but there is at least
one standards groups which wants to get
a code point for at least the things
that go into the cosy signature cozy
encryption document are objects so we
can basically get to potentially do
early adoption on those that is those
four things and but not actually process
finish process and document until we
have have some good discussion on how we
deal with fuzzy keys Mike again I guess
thinking about the jose context we put
in x.509 certificate representations
because a lot of people had and still do
have tools that if you were generating a
key that was the wrapper that they got
it in
and they had things to consume it but we
as an explicit transition step wanted to
also make it possible for people to
deploy without having to have an ASM dot
1 bar sir etc I realized the application
context and motivation here is a little
different and I don't have a firm
conclusion in my mind but I'd at least
like people to think about making an
explicit choice about do we always want
a C bar key representation even if
there's an ASN dot one key
representation this is Jeffery askin
signed exchanges don't use cosy so it's
not directly applicable but as a data
point let's see first your document says
that a chain has to be linear that each
one is signed by the next one in order
to support different routes on different
consumers we specified that the first
one is the leaf but then the ones after
that just are a collection of our kind
of a bag that you can build chains out
of that the system has to kind of search
through those certificates to its root
so think about whether that's what you
want and second this was for signed
exchanges for in web packaging so mostly
desktop and phones rather than really
constrained spaces does anyone know if
he LS has changed from TLS used to be a
straight chain and I don't know they
changed or not you know they didn't is
this it is it is now just the first one
is the indentity sir and then you can
have a random set after that you don't
you do not include the trust anchor
right and they and the leaf is included
and the rest or you may find these
helpful okay so it's the same sort of
thing
it makes sense to change that then Russ
Townsley
and the the second data point was we do
send revocation information we send an
OCSP response and we also include a
signed certificate timestamp for
certificate transparency so think about
including that in your list because mama
know that you talk about parallel copies
of the same thing how about the
thumbprint in the URL why do you think
those are oh you won't have up for both
of them int yes I don't know of any
reason why you couldn't
I don't we don't we do not the document
does not say you can only have one of
these Oh Russ Housley again I'm worried
about including both a Rakhi and a
certificate if you don't have any
ability to pull the public key out to do
a compare to make sure they are
consistent you're going to end up
essentially ignoring the cert so why did
you even put it in John Watson does the
document describe how to handle two of
these should be care if it's end or or
you have issues or do you need to make
sure that both match or two of which
thumbprint and URL now it doesn't if one
of them's wrong that's life this is
Jeffrey asking again um I haven't read
your penny in detail do you talk about
signing over the certificate and and if
so what kind of what do you sign over no
we don't talk about signing of this
certificate you could put this in as a
protected header
in which case the signature would pepper
it so you do have the option of making
it a protected or an unprotected ever
okay assignment believe the document
says this can be an unprotected header
because it is internally signed it needs
to be verified and if it is removed it
does not affect the evaluation of the
message per se right yeah TLS signs over
it
signed exchanges include both a URL and
a thumbprint and there's a question of
is it the thumbprint of the leaf
certificate or the whole chain and we
sign over the thumbprint
okay so those I think are still open
issues for discussion on the list and
then the first is the standard question
what did I miss
going forward still haven't written
there the the security considerations
for this document either I think we need
some implementation experience so we
know for sure what is happening on some
of these things but I've there's still
at least one person has asked for some
early early point assignments for an
external standards body and I think I'm
done they wanted to actually carry a CWT
in the message just like you would carry
an x.509 certificate so I you have
basically it a you know a signed thing
which does a bag of statements which
associated a person in Turkey as a CWT
as stated for next time I'll answer this
document does not cover that that is
something it was raised within the last
week and there's two questions one do we
want to do it to is if is this the
appropriate document to do it there
should be a separate document okay thank
you Jim so I think what what I'm hearing
for next steps is the document needs
some cleanup and then then we can see
where we go from there
good morning I'm Mike Jones from
Microsoft and I'm here to talk about an
individual draft that defines some
additional algorithms
so what spec does is register as a
number of algorithmic fires for
algorithms that are used by the World
Wide Web Consortium web authentication
meaning it's a final w3c standard
there's for RSI signing algorithms that
are registered which weren't already
registered for use in cozy as well as
the SEC P 256 K 1 curve and signing with
that I'll note that this draft is
explicitly intended to fulfill a charter
deliverable which is on the screen there
and just for reference if you're
downloading the slides this is the final
web authentication URL the chair is put
out a call for adoption as a working
group document for this on March 13th to
run until about today I'm not a chair
but I saw number of people saying yeah
do that and nobody's saying don't
thankfully I received two really good
sets of reviews already one from Jim
shod one from John Matson which I've
replied to you on West they both found a
number of things that they suggest made
the same suggestions for which tells me
that yeah we should probably do those
things and you can see those on list
those things that are not as obvious
will be the following subsequent slides
for input right here and now
Jim correctly pointed out that there's
two algorithms in web authenticate there
are a class of algorithms called
elliptic curve direct anonymous
attestation
EC DAA that have Jose style identifiers
82 56 and 85:12 these were defined by
yan comma mesh of IBM and some
additional people I think Ralph from
[Music]
knock-knock and originally done in a
Fido one
UAF text and web authentic can do at a
stations about the authentication that
occurred using these formats now I will
know that the web authentic
considerations section and proposes just
registering these referencing the spider
draft as the primary definitions we
could just decide as cozy to first just
ask Ayane to process this and have the
designated experts either say yes or no
and only if the designated experts say
no would we even have any work to do
there's also been questions about are
these great algorithms in the first
place but now we're batting out of my
league Jim shod coming to the microphone
I suspect us a designated expert Jim
Shaw designator
IV only will they do have difference
that's going to show up in the
registration between doing it here and
having the w3c do it is the recommended
column will be would be
know for sure the w3c does it and it
might be either yes you know if we do it
John Bradley walking to the microphone
while it is the ECD AAA stuff is the
product of fine quality crypto
researchers in Fido there have been a
number of external security researchers
who have expressed significant concerns
about those algorithms so we should
understand what the potential security
risks are before we set about blessing
them through a registration I it was
about three four months ago there was a
bunch of papers and things that came out
basically attacking web authentically
some people believed had significant
flaws so they're not widely implemented
outside of UAF and they're implemented
almost not at all in UAF in reality so
Tony probably has some opinion never
Tony nominees are not currently
implemented so I would not go forward
with doing these at this time it doesn't
until there's some implementations that
actually shake this stuff out right and
indeed I was not proposing to put these
in this draft this draft today consists
of well known algorithms with well-known
security properties and we could finish
it very quickly if we suck this stuff in
will be a year plus at least with CFR G
involvement and what-have-you but I did
want to point out that as chartered we
could have included these and I did not
for some of these reasons all right well
you know Charter says we
things that are needed by others that
doesn't necessarily mean we have to take
everything so just pointing that out
there I'm hearing a lot of these this is
really bad is there anybody that wants
to risk coming to the mic to have a
counter-argument yeah okay so I think
it's I think we I think we can continue
without without trying to add these okay
very good
I'm well just as a personal action item
bring this up in the web authentic
inclusion here the document title is as
usual the subject of more comments than
anything else I chose a very generic
title which was correct but probably not
totally descriptive and I would be glad
to have the title changed in a working
group document should such a thing be
adopted matt miller matthew miller to to
to color this bike shed i so i did i did
intend to post a list and I apologize
for not doing that
me I was ready for adoption myself
although I admit I would have preferred
a title that points out this is this is
targeting web authentic
other feedback and that's that would be
very helpful and I would be fine with
the working title something like
additional algorithms used by webathon I
see people nodding as anybody retching
okay that would be a fine working title
after adoption thank you
the other piece of feedback that I
receive from both reviewers
there was a string which came from one
implementation that already exists I
think by Vladimir Duchenne off of
connect ID where he implemented signing
using the SEC P 256 K one curve and he
called it P 256 K and both my reviewers
said just call it SEC P 256 K 1 and that
makes sense to me
or was it your implementation no Philip
spoken and zero the other algorithm name
that is of the other curve name commonly
algorithm name was Kay - 256 and that
one I see more common than this one this
is the name from the SEC to document
I believe Russ is probably SEC one okay
Jim shot um I don't care what you call
it in you knows a genius you can keep
that well that's the whole point of the
slide so it's just that the descriptive
string in in the registry was confusing
if for the cozy site because that's
going to be an integer it doesn't have
that value that's right anyplace minutes
I don't know if this is necessarily the
right room to be asking what that value
should be so I think we'll need to
consult the at least the Jose list and
maybe the Jose does need experts for
their opinion more than just the one and
that's fine again like so for the
minutes let's add a note that the chairs
will afford that request okay
Jim asks the question do we have a
recommendation for the sect P 256k one
whether to use uncompressed or
compressed point representations or
whether indeed both they're perfectly
acceptable
obviously uncompressed will work I would
be interested in having data on for this
curve what are people doing in the wild
I know for instance that no matter what
you think of them the Bitcoin people use
this I haven't looked into how they're
representing the points does anyone in
the room know here comes Russ Russ
Housley I don't know how it's done in
Bitcoin but I do know how it's done in a
bunch of other places and there was a
patent issue with compression but
patents like expired so do what you want
thank you for answering the question I
was going to ask ya I knew that to be
the case that you could do either now in
a legally successful way what I didn't
know whether there was existing practice
that it was worth mentioning and at
least that's what I thought because of
the previous patent issue
oh wait well we can discuss this more on
the list currently the draft doesn't say
anything at all maybe
so the next steps that I view or the
chairs need to make a call about whether
to adopt the draft and then assuming a
working group draft gets created at that
point I would start addressing feedback
from the reviews that have been received
in the discussions in this room so so as
Mike pointed out that working group last
call a working group call for adoption
does end today given all the feedback
we've gotten on the list and lack of any
objections here I believe we will be
adopting it I think the one question we
would have is for the two reviewers that
do happen to be in the room is it
important to address those concerns
before okay you've gotten headshakes
from both of them so we will send the
announcement on the list by but yes
please submit submit a draft IETF Cosi
item we can confer afterwards as far as
what the short name is because that gets
that's easier to get correct now versus
later okay Thank You Russ it's your turn
mmm-hmm Ross Housley I'm gonna talk
about the use of hash based signatures
yes okay so the CFR G has been working
on hash based signatures since 2013
basically the draft that for the
algorithm HSS LMS is in the RFC editors
queue it's an auth 48 so we know what
the number is going to be as soon as it
pops so it's eight five five four and it
describes an adaptation of some work
that goes back to the mid 90s original
work done by very famous cryptographers
you know planned for Diffie winters and
its end merkel so a lot of stuff going
on there but with this group probably
cares about is how does this what are
the characteristics of the algorithm so
you build a tree it's hash pastry Merkle
trees and the number of signatures that
you can use depends on the number of
leaf nodes in the tree so it has a
finite number of signatures that's one
of the biggest criticisms of this
algorithm but it has small public keys
and a low computational cost it's very
fast to validate those signatures sign
the and the amount of code that's needed
to validate one of those signatures is
very small which is why a lot of the IOT
folks are interested in it you just need
the hash function and then so tree
management stuff in terms of the signing
side you can have a small private key if
that's
anytime you're willing to do some extra
stuff you have a bigger private key if
you want faster signing time
that's a computational memory size trail
the signatures however are quite large
and key generation is rather slow of
course that's only done by the signer
one of the things that find that makes
this attractive is that they are quantum
safe signatures so even if a quantum
computer comes to pass these signature
stand so this slide can has the
conventions right out of the internet
draft I'm not going to read through you
know them but the what goes in each of
the fields in the for a signature is
there have comments about this please
talk about the list next so why why are
we carrying about this like I said the
small verification code size is very
attractive in the IOT space since it's
quantum safe a bunch of people are
advocating that we use these now to sign
firmware that way we have a way to
deploy the code that implements the next
generation of crypto in a safe way if
something comes along that makes this
difficult such as a large-scale quantum
computer
we still have confidence in the software
update integrity mechanism so suit has
been looking at this suit has already
decided they are using cozy that's a
decision we're looking at this is one of
the possible mandatory implement
algorithms that discussion is going to
happen later this week so I'm hoping
that
this discussion doesn't change that next
slide so we already had the working
group adoption of this some small errors
were found that basically we're done to
align the the document that is now in
the RFC editors queue and and this Jim
shod provided some comments they were
dealt with I think to his satisfaction
and Jim also has done an implementation
now so his cozy library now supports
this and he provided some test factors
that I could use to put at the end of
the document and I think once those two
additions are then it'll be ready for a
working group last call I think
questions Queen dang I have a question
since The Dispatch is it has a lot of
options I don't know what what option
did you pick in the draft so the way
that the options are the signature
itself tells you which options were
picked so this document doesn't have to
say anything about them okay awesome
okay so there's code points for Miami
that are signed to each possible step
and they are encoded in the signature
itself so you know how to so gonna
specify the options to be used but at
the time you build the tree you pick
them okay so it's uh alright so it's not
in this draft okay
that's right somewhere else Jamaat's on
something like you just said that
everything is included in the signature
that I think that would be very helpful
information to the draft for
implementers readers I'm sure I can add
that I if it's not there I think it is
but I'll check
any other comments all right so it
sounds like four fractions then you you
have one more revision to do with these
updates and then we should be able to do
a working group last call on that also I
mean this is arguably the most complete
of the documents that were that we
initially took on so if there's no
objections we can look at doing that
I think we've still got a number of
things to deal with that the core drafts
that this shouldn't be too much of a
distraction okay great so four minutes
yes we'll update them won't do okay
all right so the next steps for the
working group we were looking at over
the over the between now and ITF 105
mostly in consult 8 consulting with Jim
with the with the corpus graphs what
what we are looking to propose is having
a another virtual interim to discuss
some of these outstanding issues again
targeting sometime in May again focusing
on on any 152 bits with the idea that by
IETF 105 we're either if we're really
really really optimistic we might be
able to see if we can get it to the
state we feel we can pop wreck but most
likely to get to the state that we're
doing a working group last call on the
best drafts also for one at 105 talking
again with Jim and a couple other people
at the hackathon looking at attempting
to do a in Interop some form of
interrupt testing at the Montreal
hackathon
so the anybody that has implementations
please reach out to the chairs we'd like
to to start at least that planning
sooner rather than later and we'll start
to put together some some formal
something a little bit more formal ideas
on how to how to structure that does
anybody have any comments questions or
concerns with this this temporary path
forward all right
what this point we are done with what we
had scheduled so if there's any other
comments or discussion anybody wants to
bring up now is the time all right
if anybody has not signed the blue
sheets please come see us
thank you friends franceska for taking
minutes and Russ and Kathleen for for do
essentially transcribing since the Java
room also we're a wrap and you got an
extra 15
oh I'm sorry Carson I thought yeah just
one comment on the virtual interim stuff
there is a number of working groups that
are doing virtual inference repeatedly
and so on so I think it would be a nice
idea to just coordinate this so you
could use one of the slots of the
Seaboard working group so it's not so
much of a change for people okay we will
talk with the Seaport chairs all right
thank you everybody