so the chairs for 10 starting the DTN
working group session do sheets are
going through the room as usual we're
under note well which says essentially
you know everything you say or you write
is under is covered under those rules
please read when you have time proposed
agenda that my colleague eric has put
out the call for proposal I guess we
ought to get some convergence layer done
we had discussions with the ad this this
morning in the outgoing 80s and where we
would like to get this done ASAP any
agenda bashing or changes no change to
agenda okay Edie are you still you know
available to take notes you take very
good thanks accident you will be
presenting therefore we would like to
have another note takers during at least
the time where ed was is going to
present any volunteers
should I point someone
when someone comes to the front and you
know shake hands with the chairs then
you get a token of being the note-taker
that's why the thank you are you gonna
use ether pad for this or are you gonna
just type it in a in a notepad on your
laptop if you use ether pad pad then
Martin could pick up on it but okay well
whatever works for you because you
volunteered yeah we've done less calls I
don't I don't know if you remember that
we did but we did and well conversions
layer TCP conversion layer being
discussed hopefully the last time this
week will progress through sending to
the ihe for our ad for his new work you
know just as an introduction to his new
tenure that is the milestones that we
agreed a while ago to work on we on
purpose you know use a subset of them
because we want to focus on the base
spec which is the revision of 50/50 but
then other stuff need to be done to get
the full solution I think said that I
think Nick's is Scott
okay I'm Scott Burleigh I work at Jet
Propulsion lab in Pasadena California we
talking about minimal TCP convergence
layer adapter I can be very brief I've
got exactly one slide let me just go
ahead to that slide the intent of MTC
PCL is to provide a convergence their
adapter that is simple enough that we
can agree on it readily and provide it
along with the BP sex specification and
the BP disc specification as a as a
package so that we can start moving
everything together onto the RFC editors
queue to that end the M TCP Convergys
layer adapter is very short it's about
eight pages you can review it in about
ten minutes I think the we talked about
it a little bit after the last IETF
since then the only changes are first of
all changing the the name from simple
TCP convergence layer to minimal TCP
convergence there that seemed to be more
acceptable to everybody it was and and
it and the the working group also
adopted it so the name now is has got to
she can working group in it I think
instead of me
and the second and really the only
really significant change was adding a
language about establishing TLS sessions
in the same way that TLS needs to be
supported in the TCP convergence layer
and and in fact the language that I
added there is lifted all not exactly
verbatim but we're pretty close to
verbatim lifted from the TCP CL
document that that had already been
compiled and I'm assuming that's all
gonna be workable unacceptable
TLS language the only other has changed
that I made in the document as I was
going through it was there's one point
where describing the structure of the EM
TCP protocol data units the the
something had come up in another context
that there was possible ambiguity in in
saying that the encapsulated that the
encapsulated bundle that was being
shipped in the MPD you was a Seaborg
byte string we wanted to make it clear
that it was a simple byte string of
defined length rather than an undefined
indefinite length sepal string those are
the only changes the revised updated
spec was posted as an internet draft on
the 28th of February and at this point I
leave it to the working group as to
whether or not we can go ahead with it
any questions any questions did you
think it was there's one I thought I was
looking into the MVC l and also the the
bundle protocol v7 and I ran into just a
rough question for the working group as
far as the policy of seaboard tagging I
noticed that tags are mentioned in MVP
v7 and not really in the m TT PCL
is there is there a policy as far as
like tags just shouldn't be present at
all in DC board encodings has that been
thought about it looked at at all I'm
just wondering from the perspective of
the interoperability and troubleshooting
and message dissecting I'm not sure I've
answered for that the intent the VP b7
respect in the M TCP spec was to state
all of the C for representational
elements that were required and else so
there's there's I think no intent to say
that you can't do anything else and for
example a an extension block but I I
think both specifications are silent and
I will I will declare intentionally
silent on that question unless there
needs to be something said about it a
scope that Rick Taylor here as a
personal comment I seem to remember and
I'm sure a sea boar export expert will
correct me if I'm wrong that the
specification of tags in sea boar is
that they are to be parsed as
effectively metadata but do not affect
the actual fundamental data that's being
transported whether a tag is there or
not doesn't manifestly change the
meaning of what you are parsing sure if
you're doing a wire dissector or trying
to do this in in Fiji a then it's an
issue but I think if you want to tag
that this string is a date that's useful
perhaps for your domain so I'm not sure
where I'm going here but I'm I'm not
sure the presence of tags needs to be
specified canonically within the
specification and I yeah
and my question was just to make sure
that it from from the perspective I was
looking at of dissecting messages is
should I bother to care and skip tags
and the answer is yes I I think the
c-more spec says you should what you do
with the tags is your business so if you
just throw them away because it's
irrelevant to your team to what you're
doing that's fine but I think to be a
compliant Seaborg consumer you must
handle tags but we'll have to get the
actual sequence back to determine that
must or should that that sounds right to
me and and and it's certainly fine with
me inconsistent I think with the
specification specification so say you
can't do it though I think my intent has
been to to define stuff fully enough in
the specification that tags aren't
necessary and I think I would stick with
that intent but if somebody wanted to
insert a tag - for some purpose I I
don't see any any objection to it okay
thank you
anything else
Felix Walter efreeti and so just another
short question about the PDU so I saw in
the document that there is a length
value before the zebra white spring
which represents the bunler
yes so isn't this kind of redundant
because the super white string itself
has a length I think if it's a well
we've gone round the times and I can't
remember why we've gone back to having
it that somebody should have had some
notes on this this may have been a
conversation we had in a establishment
serving alcohol which doesn't help if I
remember was it something to do with
somebody had a situation where the
parser they were using wanted is this
the indefinite strangest thing again
where it's trying to load the whole
thing in one into memory and if you've
got a 2gig PD you yes they might not
want to in memory actually this was one
of our problems when writing the
serialize ER so I think because the the
ppb spec said that the length well you
should be the length of the serialized
part of the the bundle block data and
for that you first had to serialize the
block data to determine the length and
the length itself was of variable length
depending on its value and so it was
difficult to implement this in a like a
streaming serializer that didn't so yeah
but I I don't think this would be a
problem for the the MPD you because it
says that the length is the length of
the encapsulated binary bundle right but
it I think it would still be redundant
and was just just a question why
this is needed I mean probably I oversee
something there I'm it would have been
great to have this question on the
mailing list before we got here
yeah I would have to research in in
seaboard to give you a better answer but
I will say that I'm perfectly fine with
the removing the length field from the
protocol data unit that's if it's if
it's not necessary great that's the Rick
with chair hat on sorry to a drunk you
this is a classic mailing list
conversation and can I recommend we do
this properly on the mailing list so
there's a record of why we came to this
decision before we get asked again in
three months time probably by the same
people again because we've forgotten
yeah so definitely take this onto the
list of these guys anything else
yes mark you well I think we should do
with machine learning so to solve those
problems so we do we potentially have to
TCP conversions layers in the TCP / IP
world then we will connect to a port
number the TCP CLV for as a port number
as our part of the negotiation no no
it's it's a port defined it's our wine
port number yeah I own a port port
services Ridge 4 4 5 5 6
oh yeah yeah so are 5050 I think yeah
yeah
so so if I'm using your transport which
port do I'm I'm not using and if if it's
the same then we need some kind of a
right you know a way to it ought not to
be the same it won't be a different one
the spec is silent on that it says it's
established by by management I will
I will observe that this is in operation
24/7 now on the space station it can be
made to work it is being made to work
it's not an Super Bowl problem if we
need to define a port number for it in
Ayana
I'm fine with doing that but it
certainly is different from the port
number that we used for the TCP
convergence there well that's my point
either we use the same port then we have
a way to identify which protocol we're
using or we use another point and I
completely Abdur the former right we're
not doing that we're not using the same
port or not that's fine but no we're not
we're not either with some sort be it
disambiguation cool either way your
respect is that is it silent about this
and and if the spec needs to say
something about it that that's fine we
can establish a a port number in curtain
spec that is that is perfectly fine so
Rick Taylor here spinning to the top of
the document just to check so the latest
draftees standards track intended yes so
I'm looking at the ad for advice here
for a standards track document we ought
to have an eye on a request for a
reserved port sorry I mean if you
actually want to request a port and yes
you need to have an a section on it I
I'm not we try to keep down the port
usage if it's really I mean and we
shouldn't be spending a lot of ports if
it tells necessarily I don't understand
enough about this case to give a
recommendation from standing here but do
you have other methods of taking route
or is it local configuration for which
convergence that you're using etc you
might not be if you can use a dynamic
port for
that each particular or how do you find
your bundle and the convergence layers
the intent of the specification has been
that it's a local configuration matter
and it's and it's up to so it's managed
outside of the protocol and it doesn't
have to be as part of the standard
doesn't we don't have to do it that way
I'm happy to find a port if somebody
wants to reserve a port for it I I would
recommend against referring port unless
you really really need it and so Rick
responding to what we've just heard I
I personally not chair hat on personal
hats on I'd be perfectly happy to see
some text in the document that says we
don't need to reserve a port for this
it's it's a minimal tcp CL pre configure
it in some way out of that and as long
as that text is in there then fine
that's proceed there is on see any there
is text that says it's established
there's text that says it's established
out-of-band there is no text that says
there's no need for a preserved port
number but that's an easy thing to add
your god given the different encodings
wouldn't it be obvious or fairly obvious
for a receiver to figure out whether
this is a tcp CL or a minimum tcp CL
hecka so that you can at least fail
safely or rely in kind of a reliable way
determined determined that you have a
conversion say I miss me at least on one
end so that people could actually max
the two protocols on the same port hmm
that was my question before no I I would
I guess I would advocate against trying
amongst the two protocols on the same
port I don't think there's a I don't see
a significant operational advantage to
doing that and and if you're not going
to do that then I think it's unnecessary
to require implementations to be able to
distinguish between the two are given
that the first few bytes are different
how much do you have to do yeah but the
first few bytes are a length and then
some payload so I could craft something
that you know looks just like TCP CL
header but is actually a specially
lengthened packet I think that's a can
of worms
personally I wonder about sure you can
write an implementation which does both
and that's great but I think it's a
simple experience in the internet that
things tend to get misconfigured
occasionally intentionally across all
the broad routing protocols and so this
is what I'm just saying so if we have
some minimal wisdom we can provide in
this specification then that should go
in there and that's I I think the you
can certainly use this burst so patient
and infer from add sufficient wisdom to
do an implement an implementation that
distinguishes between the two I don't
think there's anything to add to the
specification itself to make that
possible or necessary Rick jumping in
again what I could hear there is what
yoga is proposing is is perhaps is this
specification and I'm gonna need to
check the TCP CL specification is is
there a unique enough header or preamble
on the connection establishment such
that the I know there's a there's a
version number in TCP CL then we need to
put a preamble at em TCP and ASCII or
something on the front end so we can say
Oh someone's pointed their web browser
at me by mistake or I'm looking at the
room for feedback on this because your
look makes a point everyone miss
configures everything but is it then
their problem rather than the protocol
specs problem III think the protocol
will will fail as soon as it starts
running because it's because the Miss
configuration and and you could infer
from that miss configuration that
there's a miss configuration adding
protocol elements that help you
distinguish exactly what sort of miss
configuration you've got kit can be done
I
my personal preference would be not to
do that hello Roman felt I don't
particularly care what what you do
special pilot for terminal notice at
least as you say something I agree with
with mark much it there
however I would very much like TC PCL to
have a port number and maybe reuse is
four or five five six for that and and
ICMP TCP I teach piano as a sort of a
stopgap for now and still sorry PC PCL
before as the real thing yeah
thank you and I'm perfectly fine with
that the intent of the MTC PCL
specification is to get us something so
that we can move forward
yes question uh ed brain just a comment
which was I think the value of having
both of them is that the minimum TCP CL
stays minimum and so I think while there
are many features that could go into it
having something that is really only
that which is necessary to show what we
need to for bundle protocol is the
rubric for determining what goes into M
TCP I agree with that
thank you Scott anything else no Brian
[Music]
okay so I have a very few number of
slides and the summary version is that
this is very close so the first couple
of slides can be skipped for the next no
changes have been made to the background
this is just for a copy of some of the
earlier presentation point is to update
what already exists and to make what
already exists in PC PC lv3
simpler and more robust where it was
possible and add extensions for the
benefit of the protocol can you get in
the next slide please so still the goals
are to not change the scope for the
workflow the the CL works in before much
the same way as it did in v3 there's
still the same phases of negotiation
there's still the same message headers
and message type codes and so ideally
this would make it easy for an
implementation to be adapted to move to
v4 or to be cross compliant with v3 and
v4 next slide please so the last edits
in the draft based on feedback from
George and the other IETF first was to
completely remove the transfer in a
message which originally was present
only because of compatibility issues in
TCP CL v3 and I'll talk a little bit
about this and a couple of later slides
about PDU sighs so the extension items
which were present in the transfer unit
message have just been moved into the
first transfer segment message which is
identified by a start date so this
simplifies the state machine if
reduces some PDU overhead and I'll talk
about the transfer total length but this
is is also moved into an extension item
for a simplification of the sequencing
and reduction in the message size the
total extension item length has been
reduced from 64 bits 32 bit there
already was some guidance in there about
make your extensions small a 32 bit
total length enforces small to an extent
of putting into still a relatively large
bucket of available size but the intent
here is is for extension capability so
32 bits allows a lot of potential future
stuff the default and minimum session
timeout was clarified to be compatible
with the recommended values from the CL
v3 so there's no change from v3 here and
then reply bit was added to the session
termination but just to avoid a feedback
loop so the whichever entity whichever
peer of the session sends the first
session termination the reply bit has
not said when the the reply message is
sent the reply bit is set so there's a
clear sequencing of the session
termination and in a valid session
there's only ever going to be one such
and termination message coming out of
each peer one of them is going to be
initiation and one of them is going to
be the reply and that's it and then the
session termination encoding was
simplified to avoid variability of the
message content now instead of the type
code being present or not present that
the code is always present and there's
just an unknown type code so this is all
simplification and then this has been
presented before but I'm just bringing
this up to show how small you can get
TCP zero before as a reference
or thinking about it so in a in a very
low and implementation this is not a
greatly compatible one but this is one
that if you had a controlled network
that you knew what was going on wouldn't
use TLS you wouldn't need to exchange
the IDS so those would be empty and you
wouldn't need extensions and if you
wanted to use always signals segment
transfers then these are some of the
numbers and that the summary version is
that it's 33 archives to get a session
running and it's 40 out cuts of overhead
beyond the actual bundle itself so this
this is the level that PCB CEO is
working at right now just as as some
numbers to think about in the context of
how big are these overheads relative to
how bigger the bundles being transported
and then in the sequence I break down
the individual items
so the took the transfer total length
was moved into an expansion item and the
reason for this is for a couple of
things one is to allow that minimum
number to be a bare minimum if you do
want to do single segment transfers then
the transfer that the total length
becomes redundant because it's all in
the one segment and segment already has
a length and also moving this moving
this out of that separate transferring
it message into an extension item
although there is some overhead with the
extension item the overhead of the
extension item is actually two out
that's smaller than the overhead of
transferring it message so there's no
overall penalty for doing what's been
done here and this this simplifies the
sequencing and it actually brings the
TCP seal or into more kind of logical
line without b3 with structure and even
when the transfer so even when the
transfer like the extension is used it
it still only adds on the order of like
it's of extra message size so separate
from the the protocol itself this is
more to do with interoperability and
working code side of things the example
agent that was done in Python has been
updated for the draft revision 11 Lester
sequencing and there's some other
embellishments have been made just to
show what can be done with the v4
protocol it now does graceful session
termination and this was something that
as a proof of concept as a kind of a
justification for some of these
behaviors I wanted to do this because
there have been four questions coming in
about the initialization and in
termination sequencing so this just
gives some some concrete evidence that
yes this is a workable behavior and it
does provide actual value to the
protocol and also is a proof of concept
because it was something that is
discussed but it wasn't really looked at
I don't think at all is the agent
actually has a feedback algorithm to
have adjustable segment size to hit in
this case the target metric is time to
acknowledge that the difference between
the time when the segment is being
encoded and when the acknowledgment
comes back for that segment and
operation I think this is the kind of
thing of it an agent really would look
we would be looking for want to work
with it you want to guarantee via your
urea unacknowledged akkad data is gonna
be no more than X number of seconds old
on a whatever your screen you never give
and I also implemented just this minimum
the programmatic generator to exercise
text refers to demo agent X by please
Vikram
one other thing that was done again
these days justification I for they were
to call itself points up I put together
of Wireshark technically and I really
your exercises I think all in the
behavior
before convergence layer it supersedes
the stock Wireshark I expected that was
what's called bundle and it was the TCP
Co b3
sohave years but this handles all the
messaging your handles actually Kiowas
yep within sessions and reassembling of
individual transfer segments into the
total transfer data so I think
interoperability and for example of a
pack working code this a pretty nice
thing to have and then I also did some
minimal implementation for the bundle
protocol itself but very basic because
that was about to be on that next slide
please it was just a picture of some of
the dissected CLV for messages I mean
nothing should stand out it yet I sector
like wires from before but again just
matter my justification for is a
realizable thing and is it a reasonable
thing to be organized array this and I
mean nothing image here nothing in the
corridors are actually too complex in
the cutting up they put together with
the way that the wire truck is
structured next slide please
right so the one open issue that is
really just a matter of opinion and how
much future use extensions are expected
to get is the each individual extension
item point now is sized for like 32 bit
that's certainly more than would be
expected to be used in any individual
extension item there was a comment about
reducing the individual item extension
length basically this is it
worth what it is that question but to
the working group is it worth saving two
octets in an optional PD you to produce
the besides the extension items I I
don't see any strong real strong locking
reason for or against other than
reducing the extension items by two
octets if a if an individual extension
needed to encode data longer than the
16-bit size would allow it to do then
the extension would have to define well
if you want to encode this then you have
to have multiple items and they get
stitched back together somehow
because items can be in multiples and
repeating sequence so it's not stopping
anything large from happening but it
makes it more complex on the extension
to do so but even rossik okay
sorry retain a quick quick question here
on the extension agent data little what
was the vision of the authors when they
were putting together the extensions of
what they felt an extension was it was a
small chunk of metadata or was it a
whole separate big blob of something
because I think that kind of guides
whether you're in 60 minutes or 32-bit
land the yeah the the my concept
originally of extensions was I had put
more more of the negotiated data into
extensions so the iya some of the key
IDs and some of the individual frames
small parameters and even he IDs being
related to URLs have processing limits
that are in the order of I expect
thousands of look that's not a single
digit thousands not hundreds of
thousands
okay thanks yeah but yeah it's really
intended for metadata associated with
potentially information about the things
that wouldn't be part of the bundle of l
have to do with sequencing or priority
or small puzzle that Rick again that
sounds a lot like 16 bits is what you're
suggesting and yeah I I really have no
problem with things thinking bits and if
you need something larger you figured
out yourself for your reference I'm
seeing a few nodes around the room in
here but that isn't a any indication of
consensus this might be a question for
the list yeah yeah this is the last one
of them the current status is I do have
some that last so like those copy and
paste naming big things face I did I'd
see that there were there were actual
reason codes numeric reason codes
included an Diana tabled but not in the
actual requirement body tables I think
it makes sense they include the reason
codes in both just because it's you
don't have to jump around nothing
different but some documents to look up
if you're trying to implement this thing
here but it's not any new data it's just
a little bit of redundant information in
the spec and then like I was just
talking about there's both of working
implementation pending there any changes
in the in coveting a working
implementation against the - 11 version
and a working dissector in Wireshark
they're available the same place so I I
think it's at least a a good position to
say yes this is this is a fully
functioning and as somebody had brought
up earlier in the
backwards-compatible in terms of being
able to and there are procedures in the
spec about how to interoperate with the
TCP CoV 3 on the same port Brian so you
need us change
do you have an agreement with your
co-authors about them please see it on
record yes we do we have been happy what
is your name we agree and you sign with
your blood not in the ITF okay so apart
from you know small changes and the
length of that field that you describe
do you think it's ready for going to the
ISDN right yes I believe the answer was
yes can you say again Brian oh yeah yeah
yeah do people the people in the room
think it's ready for sending for
publication or do anybody think it
should not go to publication no comments
you don't care diary anybody opposed
okay so I guess we're going to so Brian
if you could liken in one week he get
the final version so we can forward it
to the ihe with the bundle of the of the
other specs Edie you are identified as
the document shepherd so we would be
looking for you know the Shepherd right
up cool thank you very much are we Scott
are we ready for sending the your
document to for publication - I I would
say yes it's ready to go ahead for
publication
if discussion on the mailing list
uncovers need for a small change that's
an easy thing to do and could be done
within certainly than a week if we if we
decide that okay do people in the room
think we should also send this document
for publication Yes No maybe yeah okay
some notes okay cool so our beloved ad
you will receive Tim convergence later
but that's that's Christmas for a new ad
right so having said two documents to
Ciel's the presence of those two seals
means that we can also send BP version 7
and BP SEC are now unlocked and they can
also arrive so the ad will be getting
for documents and and and those cipher
suites extension so that's five
documents we bundled all the work for
the last two years and centers a single
transmission Spencer we've got a real
free ride
okay what's good next step
where's the agenda this one I think
that's yes present hi my name is ed
brain I wanted to talk about the most
recent updates to BP sac and the
interoperability cipher Suites the BP
sac has been went through a working
group last call there were some minor
changes to it we had some initial review
from over the security area we had some
review for a member of an external
standards organization security area and
we put those comments back in and this
latest version o nine represents sort of
the fusion of all of that and it's you
know not a lot but we can go through it
next slide and I think we already talked
through that and then the last part is a
comment that had come up was that
instead of interoperability cipher
suites or as we call them now security
context does need to go forward with the
documents so that we can do
interoperability testing we did not and
we chose in the working group not to
make those context part of the security
specification itself but to publish them
as a separate document next slide so
from the ITF 103 there was a single
question that came out of a review from
a different standards body called the
CCS yes that review came back and said
your specification of cipher Suites is
different notionally from how we like to
use security associations would it be a
good idea
IETF if we were to create a security
associations block and if you did what
would that look like
what value would it have in the in the
security suite we looked at it and we
drafted it to see what it would look
like and we presented it to the working
group and the working group resoundingly
said it's a terrible idea we think that
we can accomplish exactly what we need
to without these kinds of large changes
and without adding an additional
extension block we agreed with that
having then presented this comment from
another group and so we did not include
a security Association block in the spec
the compromise was to change some of the
terminology so that it was not confusing
and in the security document instead of
using the term cipher suite ID because
cipher suite has a particular meaning to
many people to say security context and
a security context could certainly be
used as a cipher suite identifier but
could also be used in a different way
particularly to carry an association or
Association information other than that
there were no changes with the security
documents next slide
and then in following through well so
there were no other significant changes
and we just went back and to apply that
change we removed the term cipher suite
in those areas we replace it with
security context instead of cipher suite
ID parameters results their security
context ID params and results and then
because we were only prototyping
notionally with the security Association
block would look like obviously we took
all of that out in the - oh nine and and
those were the changes was reacting to
that final decision in 103 so VP Seco
nine as it exists now has incorporated
the comments from the security area
which was simply to mandate that any
encryption is assigned a Crip Shin using
an AE ad cipher suite and to clarify
that integrity in this case means
signature on open text and then from the
CCSD s perspective we had gone back and
they gave and actually this might be on
the next slide so next slide please
yes they went back in and did one more
review of BP Seco nine and their exact
word was oh this looks very good so we
take that as a positive sign
they had just these comments coming back
three of them were minor clarifications
in the text which we will happily make
within the next week and they simply
said to clarify a little bit of the
language when you say ensure integrity
services don't ensure that data isn't
changed it just ensures that if it is
changed you can you can detect it so
little things like that
add seaboard to the terminology list
just say in Section three two we don't
allow nesting of certain operations
because if you allow nesting you it's
hard to tell when the nesting stops
there were two recommendations that we
recommend not adopting one of them is to
say why do you allow security source and
context parameters to be optional
because there are cases where you will
not need them and in those cases we
don't have to go through the overhead of
carrying empty fields and the other is
when you say that authenticated
encryption is used in a b c b there
should be a Showell statement in there
not just a note I think the author
missed it actually earlier in the
document there is a must associated with
the use of this suite so I think that
the spec actually already does what it's
being asked to do so I I don't have a
full overview that full up overview of
BP SEC onine because we've gone through
it in this working group several times
it has gone through the last call and
what I have done for the past two IETF
working groups is simply to describe the
changes that were made coming out of
reviews and how we have responded to
them other than those three comments
from CCS yes to clarify some of the
terminology there there are no other
open comments about the specification
that we are aware of so a question that
I had before moving on to the I
apologize for the title slide the
interoperability security context it is
to come back and say are there any other
comments associated with BP SEC we have
not seen them online we do have evidence
that there are reference implementations
that people have made for this without
issue but at this point we believe that
aside from those three nets we are done
okay one of the open questions as Rick
Taylor here with my chair hat on is the
working group asked aides to room well
so the SEC IDs asked for the
interoperability that the cipher Suites
document to be written and to be
maintained as a separate document so
that it could be updated independently
to the to the main document of the main
document is sat in last call at the
moment it's ready to go and it's going
forwards of course this document was a
personal document until very recently
because I forgot to press the button in
a timely manner
I had not gone to that second document
yet this oh sorry I'll shut up and hope
so all of the comments that I made were
specific to the BP SEC onine document
that there are no comments outstanding
for BP SEC oh nine and we think that it
is ready to go I will make a dash 10
version that this week that addresses
those three terminology changes because
I think those are good terminology
changes but it's just an editorial
change separately there is another
document called the interoperability
security context which had been a
personal draft and then was submitted as
a working group and the working group
had decided that we needed to put that
together with the BP SEC documents so
that the reviewers could review both a
protocol and an example of how you would
define and use a security context and
and that second is is these suites here
essentially the only changes from that
context is we changed the terminology
from cipher suite to security context
with the rather notable exception of the
title of this slide we updated the
references to point to the latest
release of BP biz and BP sac and we
submitted it as a working group document
and I don't know if I have another slide
behind this that speaks what I thought I
did and I was wrong yeah so so the the
two cipher suites that we proposed as
part of these security contexts are a
flavor of AES angles counter mode and a
particular H max I believe 256
which are which are non-controversial
standard interoperability suites that
you can use for integrity and
confidentiality the H max sha for
integrity a s4 for confidentiality that
they also have the benefit of being well
represented also in C bar with cozy and
we were able to point to some references
there in terms of how those items would
be seemed or encoded which we'd like to
have the c4 encodings so we think that
those are good interoperability suites
and we hadn't heard any concern from the
reviews the personal draft reviews that
we have had but we would need some
review at the working group level of
those security contents so continuing
from where I left off the Ed's personal
document is now a working group document
that was accepted after the last IETF in
Bangkok the and I press the button very
late but it is now a working group
documents of course the BP SEC itself
has been hanging in last call ready to
go and we're now going to send it to the
ad so really this document was intended
to go with it but it has not been last
called yet do we does the working group
believe this document is ready for last
call and that is a formal question we
will ask it on the mailing list as well
but I'm judging the room our intention
is to last call this get the comments
and then move it on as fast as possible
so people need to be prompt if they have
issues but we'll get that question to
the mailing list on the mailing list as
soon as possible thanks ed ed met
company MP is that Jean
so hello i'm zhang zhehan
so I will be presenting the work I've
done on interfacing the synchronous in
synchronous network management protocols
next slide please
so our network management is
administrating and monitoring different
set of nodes on a network protocol users
are usually very specific for network so
on my opinion work we would have an
account we would have an protocol would
have a low delay high bandwidth and we
will make use of these whereas and
conferences on dgn we don't have all of
these prerequisites so another we have
to do have different constraints so on
an IP network for instance we have what
we call the pool mechanism on the left
so we would send a request and it that I
would be sent back directly under reply
and each end the way is completely
different we would send comments to have
some ultimate and some automation with
incense for instance packages on the
right the graph a report will be sent
every 10 minutes and so this would be
called the pressure mechanism so both of
this approach every optimal for the only
networks but they wouldn't work on the
other one so if we wants it for instance
to manage some notes on a TN from notes
presence on an IP network we would
either use one or the other they
wouldn't be very efficient so what we
did was thinking we could combine the
two mechanisms and exactly so so our
goal was to interface in synchronization
protocol or amp and network infection
protocol negev so we wanted to create a
gateway on a node that would be on an IP
network and under the chain so I didn't
a phase between the two the we wanted to
for that we had to translate the data
models that are used by HTTP and so the
ATM and by Anakin's at a young data
model and finally we are proposed nian
would be from an account manager to be
able to send controls to an amp agent to
fetch data from this agent and then who
gets read and from we can't measure all
of this data in excited
so generally architecture is what's
presented here we would have on an IP
network you can furnitures that connects
you to an interface on the dgn we would
have the NP agents connected also 20
phase between NP so we would have only
left some synchronous call because
requests would have a reply directly
whereas on the N side which in
synchronous and requests some reports
will be sent with some specific role
they have been set before next I'd
listen so the protocol stack that we
used is present here and message would
be sent from an approved user interface
B since you given to the manager we sent
on the IP network we see the make of
agents on the Gateway that would be in a
face read by an in conduct role that
would translate it into amp sense given
to an integer if it's to give it to the
on the DTM and we receive only agent and
other way around it would do the exact
sorry and for this because we have these
synchronous and asynchronous mechanisms
we need to have something to get that
sir evenly so we have a cache on the
Gateway meaning to on one side to
register if you want to have a value but
the value is not available we would
register that this value is knitting and
on the other side when values I sent
from the impatience then we would store
all this value on the Gateway so the
Gateway itself has this architecture net
messages would be sent on the left to
the ancients given to the controller we
would extract it using the information
using transition function then
translated into and messages that would
be given to the manager in between we
also cache the value and on the other
side when data sent by the MTA agents
they would be given to the manager and
the control we extract all of these
dates are putting into the cache and
but initially send messages to the nakum
managers so translation approach should
be using is present in here
on the left you have an extract of the
ATM for amp agents so we have the
control here which is called gin rpts or
general reports these are two parameters
that you can see on the red one to our
collections of our ISO recently fire
that identifies any element on the right
we translated this control into our PC
into in Mein Kampf and so this obviously
has also two parameters which here leaf
lists which correspond to a collection
in account
so it means all these parameters can
have a lot of different values that
would be puts a new list somehow but
some you can see a comment that we used
so we as an account manager we using the
young high utility this utility is use
as an account manager said so for
instance if I want to send general
reports comment we use it here T's
syntax so the young that emoji would be
read and parsed by this it's routine and
we can it would be all those who use
this so we have here two parameters the
first would be an air I of value say for
instance you want to generate a report
that would sense the number of visual
diary and the agent so to do so we give
as an ID what's
value one generate here the namespace of
it and it's also needd so next time only
defined data and its name is BR so all
of this is good as one pointer the
second point models are the end points
of the manager word which the agent have
to send messages so here we have two of
them we have IPIN 4.5 in a pin 6.5 and
next slide please so this command sent
by the income manager which translates
it as an RPC XML RPC so you have it on
you have the parameters in the red
rectangle so this point is a PC will be
received on the Gateway the Gateway will
then radiate sparsit's and transform it
into the dictionary you have on the
right so this one is an internal
dictionary that we use in the Gateway so
you can see the area diptych all the
specific parameters so you have we can
see it's an amp agent it's a control the
name is it's from sorry it's the ATM is
an pigeons control the name is general
Hertz then you have the parameters first
parameter is again an RI with his name
space at the type and everything second
parameter is the lists that we sent
before and this this structure is used
in two with a function that will send
the control from the IMP manager and
that Delta G is a recruit's completely
to recur CBG so if you have parameters
we have partners in the air i that needs
to have parameters also itself and we
could recursively at them so you can see
we have zero and one which has first
parameter second parameter and also we
have list so if collisions have to be
sent and we can send different RI or
strings or integers and so on when this
message will be sent to the manager to
the agents report to be sent back to the
manager on the Gateway so you have here
an example of this such report the value
sent would be the ten this will be
stored on the database when then we have
created yang module miss no in Moodle
with several commands to fetch this data
from any managers so we have here gets
in key value even 32 to as forums and
integer it has two parameters the first
one value F is the name of the value we
want to fetch with namespace type and
name second parameter is two to decide
how all hunan the data to be so if we
want you if we give a small burden
the data to all would be considered
still under cache and if we give along a
very high number then we can have more
data from this guide from those cache so
it's the time it's the time in seconds
for instance if we had a data that is
less than the South second all on the
cache then the APIs you apply on the
bottom left would be sent back to the
neck of manager with the value 10 and
the three timestamp which are no means
the value was requested on the Gateway
the moment was persist on agents in the
moment it was sent back on the Gateway
on the right if we didn't have any value
in the cache or if the value were
considered tails at all we would then
wait for a value value to arrive and the
recent value will be sent as a
notification an application like a
mitigation to do to the manager so
instead of I mean a reply that would be
a scary request and any require bit
sense that would be it just like a push
mechanism the message will be sent
directly without any requests except so
I would do a small demonstration I have
it I have a video on the next line so we
create sacra tank
agents a gateway and manager I will then
starts a comment you create some recent
data from the MP agents that will be
sent to the Gateway then we would use
another comments you fetch this data
advertisements in YouTube the resolution
is all let's see what we can do about
making the resolution better
I hope you I hope you can see dagger was
him
so I'm using the here the mitre
simulator so from a technical detail
kids it combines the core simulator for
networks and it also uses the iron sword
in Ness implementation and I have a very
simple scenario with three notes so on
the Left it's under network IP network
on the right is a summation of the TN so
you have the notes that moves is another
new TN in the middle you have the gate
wing I have to create some directions
and port forwarding because for
networking it has to use the normal I P
Network so the notes on the dgn is
considered as another cell network which
means then using the LAN client up left
we can connect directly to as if he was
directly to the amp agent the gateway in
the bottom left you can see the
Lightning's several parameters are used
some most of them the SSH layer of neck
and others is for the directory where
all the young template that we want to
use our prisons so these gentle plates
are basically translation in yang from
no from Adm so on the bottom right you
also have the NIP health agents sorry
the agent which is working so now I'm
connecting to the Gateway but as if he
was connected to the agents I'm loading
the young data module which is on page
ins and then I will add ER so tempest
rolled on the Epogen to send
regularly time some information like
it's gateway so this has several
parameters the first one is the ID of
the at the time this rule you can see
you can use the jung-un Clyde a
compilation so the young is very this
data model is very understood by the
young high utility
so we will send everything seconds we
will generate some data on the agent and
we would do it five times so the action
here is given as an air eyes on MRI
which is the namespace the type of the
command that will be used the name of
the command and its parameters so all
given as a string so we have here I'm
agent control regions Jinnah reports so
I'm first parameter would be a
collection of two elements we will ask
for the number of its type is rule on
the aim agents or not the next year
the second parameter would be the number
of control the happy one on the end
agents and this would be the first
parameter second parameter I give it
simply an empty list so it would be four
sent who asked for which managers and
shoes we leave it empty here there was a
mistake in the name of the elite not on
purpose I would like to say it but I
didn't write it because it's nice so I
can show you that we if there is a
mistake in the type check or in the name
then Ike we can still check it using the
idiom and prevents the message from
these things so you can see here on the
top on the bottom right that the M agent
received the message and in between we
look into the database also on the
bottom left you can see that the gate
where is the message in between
[Music]
sorry so we have we re on the Gateway
and on the database on the gateway so we
have all of the ad DS controls in
constants prison there as a reference to
win the data a sense we can know which
to which elements of the database on the
a DM it's connected to also we will be
too fast we here I will present all the
data that are present on the database so
it would be empty
for the moments note that I receive no
data yes so here I actually had to cut
the video because it took two minutes
so two round-trips for the data to
arrive under the manager on the Gateway
here we could see we had more data there
is presence so far already reports has
been rested on the Gateway and if you
use the special yang comment that we
created if we always explain before then
we can ask for in Santa too so we will
ask first parameter for which we ask we
see which value once you have so here
the
agent EDG number of control run on the
agent and I will write here is not a
cache timeout to show you the if you
write a small cache timeout then there
is no enough
read more reason that we send soldiers
in a prettier place sense but if you
increase this tigers timeout then we get
the most recent send data again with
this three timestamp I explained before
on the soroban here is the cuts in the
video and now we have here more data and
we have to request values that have no
debt no value so this is just
registration to say we want this value
we don't know what's what is at least
the value baby wants these names
in between the values have been so this
message to ask for the value had been
sent to the agents and then reportedly
received for a gated value and you have
here in ratification certifications and
it's so with the fitted values you can
close the video now I'll try pressing
back it's a crock something's gonna
happen there we go so in conclusion we
be able to send any control define an
idiom using account we can also have in
these controls we can have several
parameters for you so parameters in
parameters and so on and we can retrieve
any data from the Gateway directly using
income and also if some dates new data
is arriving then notifications are sent
to do an account manager and exactly's
so there's two futures obviously so
currently focus is on the supporting
detail all templates from NP which are
heavily use it in some used in some
idioms so we want to be able to get the
reports and retrieving letting as make
it available for the neck of Niger also
we reduce the scope to having only one
gateway here if you had several gates
aware that could be connected all
together but so connected to all through
the same GTM then we need to have some
synchronization between all the gateways
which was not the focus of this work and
yes so we have also an irrational to
calculate the cash that how long we have
to wait we have default values for that
also if the data is in the setting
acceptance range arrive at the right
sound and we directly without asking for
a new value
this issue here is that we have to get
the value because it would be then you
work for optimization and it is not the
focus again on sweaty any questions
so just at borane I just wanted to make
one comment on the work which was the
other part of the optimization you would
see is the need to currently interface
with the amp manager which is what is
bundled in ion right now that is that is
not the cleanest way to interface with
something as maybe you would understand
but there's other work going on to
create either an RPC interface or other
kinds of interfaces that would be more
amenable to that so the other part of
the optimization is some of the stack
that was shown had things in there
because of the necessity of working with
an existing reference implementation
right Erik Voigt Cisco good stuff a
question for you on net comp and
protocols that can do locking or have
multiple clients connecting did you look
at all about or have any thoughts about
how to handle when you do a database
lock on one side and queuing up
transactions I haven't I know about it I
know that the conf is usually is
supposed to have some commits on the
database and everything and so I have
some small support that if you comment
is done at the time and all that the
second all they are waiting for it to be
done this is not as developed as in a
real net conf
database this is definitely something to
you days in the development now a Rick
Taylor I actually have a question for
Erik Voigt who's just asked who I happen
to know as finally got his yang push
drafts through net Kampf which is as I
understand it and I am NOT a net complex
but a it's neck off notifications on
steroids really isn't it do you have any
advice for the guys working on this on
whether it's that push-pull thing you
started your presentation with suddenly
made me think of the work that Eric's
been working on and whether that
interface could be more elegant I think
we could probably talk offline some the
net comp notifications of to type you
can
events with net comp notifications and
the stuff that yang push does which is
you can subscribe to datastore elements
to get push on change so this is less
relevant for for rights because we're
looking more at how do you push on a
subscription changes to the sustain of
store in the back so I think that the
difference between events which are when
an application knows something has
happened versus datastore when a some
recipient cares to say what they want to
receive our different data sources and
both can be relevant Oh comment just at
Berean again but it so agreed but in the
example that was presented here there
was a command to say go generate this
value you know every X amount of seconds
or minutes or days for this amount of
time and then a separate query had to
come in and say that's been running for
a while now I would like to see if that
data has changed and then you get the
data cache timeout which says hey do you
have a new version of this that is not
more than 10 seconds old and and that
would be a way to do it and a sort of a
standard net comp way to do it I believe
but if you had something like what Eric
has been working on you could say
generate this data every you know 10
days but whenever the value changes send
it to me and then that would also help
with that that that that push inside of
the you talk we talk about push and pull
but you don't always know when to pull
and this would help you understand when
to pull yes so Rick again says I think
we summarizing from my own since you're
saying the gateways data store that's
subscribing to yank push notifications
on the gateway data store which is being
updated by the amp management system but
your downstream net kampf system can say
oh hey the amp subsystem has changed the
data store in the gateway and therefore
I am now receiving notifications of
updates yeah
so comment at Berean again the the issue
that one runs into is when you're trying
to manage assets that are disconnected
from the network for a long period of
time and why we wanted those time-based
rules to begin with was you wanted to
say to the disconnected agent make sure
every ten seconds you're producing this
value with the appropriate timestamps
and with the appropriate history and
then when I come and see you again and I
haven't seen you for an hour or a week
or a month all of that appropriately
time-stamped historical data comes down
and and so the the one thing you have to
be careful of and in the push case is do
you get nothing for 10 days and then 10
days worth of information coming at you
all at once and and that's really the
only reason why you might not want to do
that what fun what great discussions yes
in this case if you're doing that I
would suggest use not subscribing to
data scores you subscribe to events we
actually built the protocol so that when
you log in it will give you the history
of events even previously created events
as a replay capabilities they have the
ability even if you lose connectivity
where it will actually give you a new
start from a last event that was sent so
it's been designed for filling in gaps
yeah mine was to have a question here
how big or how much risk for troubles
because of the nature of the determine
is this type of if you request something
to be reduced and then you actually
what's being produced exceeds the
delivery capacity of of the DTN what
happens then I'm looking at edge to draw
it out so that
um Magnus while it is going to the mic
it's it's not a new question you're
asking it's been it's been discussed so
so the the the short answer is there
there is no mechanism to say
don't overdo a quality of service that's
in a DTM because there it's not always
clear that you understand what that
breaking point is the way that amp talks
about it in terms of DTN is it will
create bundles it will so the way that
amp addresses it as a protocol separate
from this demonstration is to say that
we try and have very compact encodings
we try and bundle data that is going
back to an agent or going back to a
manager to not have to duplicate of data
which is interesting in the sense that
it is an open-loop approach so if if I
am constructing a bundle to go to a
manager I will put all data destined to
that manager in that one bundle even if
those data were produced as a result of
different requests from that manager so
as not to go through those overheads and
then lastly because we put it into the
DTN with the giving quality of service
how it gets back then becomes an issue
of the data within the DTN just like if
you had an instrument that was producing
too much data except that the management
data may be of lower priority because it
could potentially be regenerated mark
here I have a question for the speaker
um so my understanding is you have
somewhat implemented EMP or parts of it
to do your translation no because I use
use I you see basically that yet a
manager exists it's CLI somehow and I
have a Python script expects which is
it's what is happening and then right so
I was hoping you would say I have
implemented most of the mmm yeah this is
a different implementation
you need all the work but mark raises a
very important point which is although
the ANP work officially comes post are
sort of phase one DTN charter items I
know we have a current charter item on
the architecture of management in DTN
but there's been a lot of interest
around what Ed's been doing and his team
have been doing a lot of work and it's a
proposal that we should look at a MP and
work on this as part of kind of phase 2
of the DTN working group currently there
is only really one implementation so
those of you who are grad students have
grad students are just generally bored
at home of an evening having fun trying
to build an amp agents that's that would
be a real interest in the working group
otherwise thank you Joe Nexus I think
that's the one so hi I'm ed again and
well the two things are working were
security and network management we had
talked about security and we had started
talking through network management the I
did not have a video and was not clear
to me that I could share my screen so
what I have is a series of screenshots
and I apologize for that but either John
or I could could if anyone wants to stop
at the end of the meeting and get a live
demo neither of our laptops we can we
can show you what is going on we we have
a set of specifications they are
personal internet drafts right now for
an asynchronous management architecture
data model and binary encoding and
protocol and we've broken those out as
three so we can reason about them
separately within ion which is a an open
source with an ion open source which is
an open source implementation of those
protocols there is a fully compliant amp
manager and amp agent we are talking
with folks who maintain DT and two who
are discussing who will
be building an amp agent the thought is
that if you build one amp manager then
it can manage any agents regardless of
whether they're in ion or DTN 2 but we
will have at least two and then other
space agencies khari DLR are also
considering their own amp agents and
there are at least two different efforts
currently to build alternative
interfaces into an amp manager one being
a web interface and other being
something that's driven out of sequel
and sequel tables so so there is there
is some sense of what is implementable
and how easier hard is it to implement
and what features would we get out of it
what I wanted to talk through and we can
go to the next slide is what we're doing
under ion as a reference implementation
so just a few reminders of the things
that are presented here are based on
either personal internet draft or
something that you could and all the
software certainly can be downloaded off
of SourceForge and looked at just as a
piece of terminology I know that I see a
lot of new faces in the room I know we
had talked about network management
asynchronous management in the past we
draw a distinction between the
architecture and asynchronous management
architecture AMA which talks about why
we need time-based and state-based and
other kinds of functions and then we
have a data model and the data model
says here are the nine types of data
that we need tables reports strongly
type variables and so on and this is how
you would use them and why they should
exist and why it's not duplicative with
other elements of a model and then we
talk about adjacent encoding of that and
how you could represent we call them a
DMS but we could think of them as mids
or yang modules in the function that
they serve a JSON template for their
specification so we could write tools to
ingest and operate on them and then the
ANP is simply AC boring coding of those
models separate from a string encoding
or a JSON encoding so that we could have
more efficient messages on the wire
within ion there is a network management
subdirectory under the main open source
directory called nm and that's where all
of the implementations live in Doc's a
DMS is where
Jason ADM files live and in contrib camp
Python is where a particular code
generator is now show you some
screenshots for that when you build and
install ion you get a manager and an
agent that you can run next slide if you
want to start the manager you start it
by typing in nm Manager and as a
courtesy for bootstrapping just in this
reference implementation you give it you
tell it what a ID it should have it will
come up it will read any persisted
definitions from the I on simple data
recorder that is there and then it gives
you a glorious text-based interface for
which you can type text to your heart's
content
and while it is functional and we can
walk through it
if anyone is is so moved to continue to
create alternative interfaces into this
we would we would very much like to help
and support and encourage that with next
slide the agent similarly is started up
on the command line again once once ion
is running you've done make install you
get animation and a manager the agent
takes it Sony ID and a default manager
in the previous presentation there is a
discussion of the receive managers if
you don't specify a receive manager it
goes to a default manager which you can
specify here it also comes in sets off
and then when it does it sends a
registration message to its default
manager that says hello I exist it's not
required you can go in and tell the
manager that agents exist but it's a
courtesy next slide so what can you
manage on the agent when you go into
this text-based interface you see the
agents that have come up these are the
ones that this is the auto registered
one you can forget about the agents and
and you can print reports or persist
reports that come in and then you can
really just do commanding which is
mostly what you want to do anyway and
that's under build control there's the
ability to send raw hex to to the agents
as well which is something that we just
have is sort of an expert interface so
that we can capture and replay things
next slide so what does ion support it
right now what we have done is generated
JSON encoded ATMs which are also
published as personal drafts for the
agent ADM itself which is this is the
ADM all
trolls and the data and so on that every
a MP agent should be able to understand
and then we have done that similarly for
a generic bundle protocol agent a
generic LTP agent and a generic VP SEC
/sb SP agent and then we then created a
set of specific ATMs for ion itself if
you have ever used ion you know that
there are multiple not too many but a
couple of administrative functions that
you use to control IP n admin ion second
min BP admin and you can control ion by
SSH into the machine that it is running
on and running these commands but in
this way we took essentially the man
pages for all these created ATMs Auto
generated the code so now you can
control multiple instances of ion on
different agents over just a bundle
interface you know using the N P
protocol next slide so on so I just go
back one so in general that's not a very
large amount of data it's it's somewhat
large for for us where we are now with
these protocols but it's 158 data
definitions about 94 controls 22 tables
and so on
next slide so if we take just a few
examples if you are in that interface
and you say go show me all of the
controls that come out of say the BP SEC
interface that's the window on the right
a zoom in of just one of them is on
below and it's the example that says go
at ABC B rule which anion is a rule that
says if you are sending a block if you
are sending a bundle from source source
to destination destination and it has a
block type of that particular target it
must have a B C B and the B C B must use
this cipher suite ID and this key
identifier and you can then you know
start playing with those rules and
security configurations and policies
separately over over the ANP next slide
we have tables here's an excerpt of
tables for a generic BP agent one of the
tables
we call them table templates is for
example alt docks if you are configuring
ion and you would like to get a general
dump of what
the end points what are the index out
docs protocols supported schemes and so
on you can generate that information in
a table format and get it pretty quickly
and it's it's just a nice way to parse
that remotely next slide so here would
be an example of a poorly ASCII
formatted table result coming out of the
text interface which is if you just
bring up a loopback interface and one of
the loopback interfaces that is bundled
with ion you will get in this case I
used s TCP but this would be the out
ducts that are Auto configured on ion or
s TCP next slide and then you also have
a report and report templates they are a
bit like tables the difference is that
in our model users can generate custom
reports as well that pull in data from
various other ATMs as they need to and
you could parameterize reports and and
that bit of associative look up was
pretty motivating to the use cases that
we have so the generic BP ADM has two
reports one is a full report which is
all the stuff that we know about that is
specific to the agent at the overall
node for the agent and then a specific
end point report that says for every
endpoint here are a couple of pieces of
information that we track separately
next slide we can certainly request a
report if a report comes in we can print
it to the screen it has a lot of it has
43 data items in it but a data item just
like a report can also be parameterized
there are cases where it is helpful and
useful to do that in cases where it is
not an example of where we use it and
the available storage here is a
configuration issue I don't actually
have that much storage on my machine
they're tremendous well to some unit of
measurement I'm sure that I do but if we
look for example bundles by priority
that's a piece of data but you give it a
mask and you could say give me the
bundles by priority for all priorities
or just for low priority or medium
priority or high priority in the JSON
ATM when you specify this you can
specify I would like this data item with
this particular hard-coded parameter or
with a parameter that flows in from
somewhere else in this case the full
report has no parameter and it out lies
of these as they are
and that's how you get that particular
date and we do it one for each priority
type if we go to the next slide you
would see an endpoint report and on the
slide on the right you would ask the
agent to produce an endpoint report for
in this case IPIN 1.0 1.1 and 1.2 and it
would come back and say the endpoint
report itself has taken a parameter IP n
1.0 and it contains three pieces of data
which themselves are parameterised and
the parameter and the report flows down
to the parameter for each of these data
items and it pulls it out we
particularly like that because we don't
always understand how many different
types of things we will have so we don't
always size a static array we also don't
want to have to do one spin of
understanding how to match to an array
index a particular associative lookup
and and we like the idea of being able
to put the associative lookup in the
request itself next slide so if we look
at then with the JSON files themselves
are so in this case there's one called
the SP SP in iti think VP SEC agent and
this is how you define a control right
now we've tried to keep it simple as
simple as possible
you have the name you have the
parameters that it takes you have a
description there is some other metadata
associated with the a with the ADM
itself I'm sure there may be over time
some of the things we would like to add
when we define a control we are all ears
for that but again the BCB rule takes 5
parameters when sending from source to
destination this target use a b c b with
this cipher suite security context at
this point and keenan next slide
BP endpoint report parameterised report
you're able to come in and and say I
have a report and the report itself
takes a parameter in its definition and
the report template will have three
pieces of data in it and each of those
three pieces of data also happened to be
parameterised listed somewhere else in
the ADM and I would like to flow the
endpoint ID parameter into the
definition of the ones that contain the
report so so what is interesting about
that is the ADM has a way of specifying
whether and how you flow parameters into
contained objects and then you don't
have to worry about that
when you auto-generate the code or when
you specify it in some other way
eggs like it can I just jump in there
because I know from my conversations
because I'm pretty dumb when it comes to
these things the parameterization is is
a very strange concept and you wonder
while this effort has gone in the reason
is to make sure that pretty much all
these requests are one round trip
because unlike you know this is it this
is a DTN it's gotta be one round trip
because you could have four hours of
latency on this I'm particularly ok guys
for the neck home for my grant where you
say oh how many items have I got great
get me item one get me agent two gave me
agent three sorry no I know it's
appreciated ends an important point and
I it is also a point that we have talked
about in the AMA document which is sort
of our architecture and reasons and
rationale for why we made some design
decisions although we're certainly happy
to revisit any of them and and talk
through them next slide then if you if
you have these Jason scripts or these
Jason files we package a Python script
with the I on open source it lives in NM
/ contribs camp Python it is a capi
generator for amp and if you have it and
you can see in that first instance if
you type camp you'll get the usage out
of it the minimal usage is you type camp
in the name of a JSON file and it will
auto generate some I on dot H and C
files if you had previously
auto-generated and hand-tooled some dot
H and C files you can give those as
parameters back and it will carry your
changes through when you do updates and
that sort of code round-tripping and
what it will produce in an output
directory of your choosing our v dot h
d-- files that can be compiled into ion
to help with its adoption next slide so
it will create an agent directory with
three files that get compiled into an
agent it will create a manager directory
with a file that gets compiled into a
manager and then a shared dot H file
that can go between them what's
interesting is is that the manager file
does not need any user edits it has all
of the information in it as is and you
don't ever need to look at it again
the agent has one file that is non user
editable and then two files add a check
see where you go in and put
implementation information next slide
and here's an example of what that looks
like the the only thing that you have to
provide an implementation for are things
that you have to provide an
implementation for is if you define a
function you have to provide the body of
the function so this would be an example
of a function definition at BCB rule and
the stub that would be auto-generated
for it and the place where you would put
your custom implementation next slide
would just be an example of the custom
implementation coming out of the eye on
open source to actually add a BCB rule
we have some API parameters for
extracting and validating parameters and
Aion already has an eye on secondment
function that performs this purpose and
we just pull the parameters out and call
the function with some error checking
next slide in addition to if you define
a function you have to give
implementation for the function if you
describe a data value you must find a
way to sample that data value we had for
example in the BP endpoint report one
data item was whether the endpoint was
active this is the kind of stuff that is
auto-generated for a defined piece of
data if you then go to the next slide
you'll see an implementation of how to
go get and return that piece of data the
last one and I don't have an example for
it here although it is there is a table
if you define a table template you need
a function that will populate and send
back the table but otherwise for reports
for macros for variables for time-based
rules for state-based rules there is no
user action associated with that you
implement functions you implement data
collection you implement tables and then
everything else is auto-generated and
compiled in for you and it has made the
adoption of these ATMs in Aion go quite
quickly and next slide that might be it
so so that is where we are there is a
reference implementation in ion there
are scripts that will parse JSON ADM
files the formats for all of these the a
MP and the C Boer encoding the ADM and
the JSON template the overall
architecture and the design decisions
and all of the ATM's that we have talked
about which I think total is about 15
documents are are available and they are
published as I think personal
personal IDs but I think you can get to
them in some way from from the DTN page
so if anyone wants to see anything else
I'm happy to show you on my laptop but
otherwise thank you very much thank you
sohcahtoa Boris or Martin I wasn't sure
who was actually presenting so these are
the guys who've been doing some work at
the hackathon on the PYD TN
implementation and wanted to tell us
about it
hello my name is Martin Milkha
I'm from ex-works and we are working on
hackathon we did some work we would like
to present to you
we do have implementation of pi d TN
which is a python implementation of some
basic DT and stuff and although we are
communicating with Microvision so this
is integration work and microfiche TN is
developed by D free tea and network from
Felix and Felix Walter and Marie's money
like this so basically is the
presentation we shot on the hackathon
our use case is very simple we do have
two ground stations and we would like to
communicate with each other they do not
have any any other means of
communication just a satellite because
they might be they might be located on
different planets actually we we are not
planning to locate them outside of Earth
in 2020 so the youth is the actually
ground station one get some sensory data
like temperature or similar encodes them
into the bundle then eventually when the
satellite is in sight it will send it
over DT n bundle protocol seven
satellite
will not see the canal station - right
away so we will have to store this
bundle somewhere and eventually as it
continues on the orbit and we will see
the connotation to it will send this
bundle we are still discussing whether
we are going to beacon approach or
whether we are going to use or that
would be opportunistic routing or
deterministic that's under discussion
but for the purpose of this presentation
of what be implemented is that we have
one docker container per object that
would be ground station one - and
satellite and ground stations are
running parity N and satellite is
running Micronesian and we have some
demo which we can which you can see on
the laptop if you are interested it is
really works like slide please so we are
touching free free drafts here bundle
protocol version seven then there is TCP
CL conversion is where we are working
with the old version version well not
the one discussed today the previous
version for now and we are also using IP
nd actually there's a plan to use IP nd
code has been written but it's not used
yet we identified some issues there
for example the eye pain in draft is
expert but we would like to see that up
to date because it would simplify
testing of our approach because as far
as I know and please correct me if I'm
wrong of we are not aware of any other
way how to how to network discovery name
sorry neighbor discovery could be done
except this already expired protocol so
that was the issue we were trying to
address on the hackathon and our
solution was that let's check if the
document is still up to date now I mean
IP and IDO
and bring it back to life maybe up to
date means like okay it is expired that
something we know but maybe the
information contained inside is still
valid so that's what we are trying to to
confirm or reject next slide please so
this is just an information flight for
the hackathon purposes being basically
improved our implementation and you can
see our code if you are interested it's
publicly available by DT ending in good
luck next slide please
yeah this is probably the most
interesting flight of this ball
presentation of which would be the
feedback to DTN workgroup or we would
like to see IP and it draft up-to-date
and possibly adopted by workgroup unless
there are some other means how we can do
the discovery because what we are doing
today is that if you want to test
cooperation of multiple multiple
implementations and there are some for
example there is this as far as I know
implementation in go language just
recently showed on the on the email list
and there is Java implementation VR able
quite easily to put them into container
and communicate with them but they do
not know easily about each other because
this IP n D stuff does not work then
what we what we notice actually that IP
and D he uses Sdn V for encoding and
decoding numeric values which is kind of
different approach from what we are
using in bundle protocol C bar is used
so if the workgroup decides that the IP
any draft should be brought up to date
then probabilities would be one of the
things which should be fixed it should
be C or most probably involve drugs to
be consistent and then there was this
recommendation from Felix that IP and D
currently obviously depends on IP but it
would
not have to because the IP requirement
is not kind of it would be possible to
it would be possible to extract that so
we would have something like not IP and
D but D T N and E which still can name
but that would mean I'd be VIP whoa but
it would also support filter clas which
currently is not the case other option
would be like what we have today that
there would be one one draft pair where
CLA that's also an option so this is
something we would like to discuss today
feel free to express your opinion and
that's it thank you for your attention
thank you very much guys um Rick chair
hat on maybe discovery is an active
charter item and I know about shortly
before I started as a chair people were
looking at neighbor discovery I was a
proponent for I agreed with Felix that I
think a DTN nd using clas and maybe
event-driven would be a way to go I know
there are other people in the room
Ronald for example who wants to go the
other way so they're doing it if you
want to volunteer to start working on it
it would be very welcome your way if
there is a will that war group wants to
have any standardized it's a generation
do we we have to have it we have to have
a standardized we've agreed so that we
are answering to do that at least start
a discussion on the mailing list after
here but yeah I think people want to
talk about it but even an opening draft
of here are some ideas I've had and
we'll start the conversation we are
especially interested okay well it seems
we are in kind of agreement regarding
first point that we want to have the
draft up to date and regarding second
point possibly as well both at this as
the end we should be removed regarding
third point
what do you guys think I mean is it a
good idea to remove the IP tendency in
IP nd graft and call it DT N and D or
something similar do you think it's this
is not no way to go mark here we all
know that DT and may not work may not be
transported over IP anyway that's true
but I thought so you know the way oh the
why we are actually interested into into
this is that it all of us very easily to
test our application level changes with
other implementations so that's why we
care and well you know so you made a
point actually that the TCP CL is gonna
be the only only convert as layer
yeah that's a valid point what do you
what do you think fairly good actually
this was proposed by you and we
hopefully have some people in the queue
already yeah I was about wrong in felt I
was about to say that the only converts
layer data that we have so far is IP
based so I'm not saying that I PMD or
DTM E and E should be the only game in
town you can do other neighbor discovery
protocols later but I presented this in
Buenos Aires and it was killed within
five minutes which year was this 2016
and I'm happy to bring this back to life
and work with you to to do those first
two bullets and have a trust out before
Montreal but if this is going to be
something with a new architecture back
to the drawing board let's do a very
generic thing then then I'm often was
not interested thank you Ric Bucher
there's nothing to stop us doing both I
see real value in refreshing IP neighbor
discovery making progress on neighbor
discovery particularly as there's
interest here in the room great let's do
it
if in parallel people want to have a
long esoteric argument I'm happy to join
the longer esoteric argument on the
mailing list and hopefully that might
well it probably won't be productive at
all but it'll keep us all busy I can do
one and somebody else can do the other
I'll do the other staying right off here
I'll sign up for the esoteric argument
on the on the e mailing list I've got a
lot of heartburn and I don't think I'd
be the only one in having a non IP based
solution coming out of the internet
Engineering Task Force okay
no but however Rick here there are other
stos such as CC SDS I can see Scott
standing behind you in the queue whom
who will standardize through their own
body convergence layer adapters and
they're looking to the IETF for for
guidance on given the IETF owns bps v7
and is driving that forwards then I
think that defines the behavior if you
want to put on architecture together on
this neighbor discovery so that you can
slide at different train transports
underneath it where IP is the one we're
doing here and somebody else may do it
you know some other SDO may do it in a
non IP fashion great we can we can all
get together and knock our lights out on
that one but out of this standards body
it well I'm gonna lobby for it until
they come to shut up
Schiaparelli I'm I think I'm in strong
agreement with that last comment is that
there's I don't see any obstacle to
having an architecture that that draws a
clear interface between the portion of
neighbor discovery that is the exchange
of the discovery information and and the
portion of neighbor discovery that is
establishment of the connection over
which that information flows and the
latter obviously the first one to build
would be an IP base substrate for
neighbor discovery but I don't see any
advantage in having a proliferation of
vastly different neighbor discovery
protocols for different environments I
think it makes much more sense to have a
standard data exchange of neighbor
discovery information and and separate
from that connected through and through
an interface through a well defined
interface the convergence layer
connection establishment connection
management software that would initially
just do IP but could in the future do
something like Bluetooth Wi-Fi and and
not necessarily rely on IP I I think
would be a mistake to require that that
the only product of neighbor discovery
development be something that only does
IP and will never do anything else mark
here so it's great to see mark as a
chair great to see people interested in
the next topics because that were that
are you know neighborhood scurry is one
and
addressing architecture and a few others
have been you know sitting there waiting
for you know the ground the basic work
to be done which is we're done almost I
have to remind that we also have LTP as
an RC that was discussed here right
somewhere we're not only I ve just one
short note this is Martin Bilka again I
just want short note from what Scott
said oh we had a lot of feedback on the
hackathon people coming to our to our
group asking like I can be used this in
IOT world we have this problem that
actually we cannot see our sensor all
the time so it there seems to be an
interest from industry out part of the
world of using this because right now
they do use some proprietary things so
it's actually net neighbor discovery
might not be needed only in IP war but
maybe also it could be over over
Bluetooth or something something else I
agree with that and that's it thank you
very much
I think we're done with the agenda thank
you very much for our attention so
whoever wants to see the live demo
please come to us thank you so I took a
few I took a few notes of you know next
steps so BP base chairs will send the
request for propagation our Shepherd
Fred would be writing up finally TCP L
TCP CLV for Brian will post last version
quick change chairs will request SAP
application add bearing Shepherd will
submit the Shepherd right up BP sec had
to post the last version chairs to
request for publication scott burly to
write the do the write-up
em minimal tcp CL we will have to do a
working group last call because we
haven't so we will do if everything goes
fine we'll request for publication we
will be looking for a shepherd for this
M TCP 10 TCP CL document might be
premature II but if anyone is interested
in in volunteering for this run out okay
well no fine
BP SEC interrupt chairs to do working
group last call we haven't done a
working group last call on this one if
everything goes following request for a
provocation we need a shepherd anybody I
have someone in mind the same Shepherd
that does the BP say because it's kind
of a the two documents Scott do and you
know that would be a good results to do
all this and I guess probably at that
time would be a good time for chairs and
the working group to actually revisit
that were milestones and we actually
started this with you know a topic of
interest which is neighbor discovery and
obviously management would be another
you know clear possible mice on so we'll
have to you know have a chat on this and
I guess the chairs will start that
discussion you know when when the whole
pile is is is gone or I think it's
probably worth getting through those
last-minute panic comments as we get the
documents out the door and once they're
safely nestled with the iesg
then we can start our discussion I'd
also say I think addressing we've got to
start tackling addressing fairly soon
because we're pretending you don't need
to name anything but but you do any last
comments
sorry just zhang zhehan just for to say
that i have its well shown under the
video is present in my laptop so if
anybody wants to play with it can just
come to me from rick one last thing
other than thank you is a big thank you
to the hackathon guys and the guys
showing running code you go to a lot of
IETF meetings where people are talking
about the status of drafts and then
everyone types on their laptops it's
really nice to see stuff happening in
the working group involving running code
and that kind of stuff I personally
really like that kind of thing so big
thank you to you guys
otherwise are we done mark we're done
thank you very much guys thank you blue
sheets everyone sign them sorted goodbye