hello does it work no sir working is it
working now check check check okay good
afternoon is 150 now and we can get
started um so this is interface to
network security function just to brief
what is this group is for I think the
lots of people are here before that
I saw some new faces is really be able
to provide dynamic policies to network
security functions especially the
virtualized functions so that service
providers can do workload bonded
security policies depending on where you
instantiate the network security
functions you can dynamically set up
your policies when you move the function
to a different location with different
workload you can change the policies so
the working groups mandate is to be able
to come up with proper data model or the
controller to control those security
functions so here is the note well page
and hope everybody have read them let's
go to the next one so here's some trivia
the Charter that's being posted mailing
lists so let's go to the O the
note-taker we need people to help with
the etherpad
thank you your name we Penn thank you we
Penn and everybody else when you ask
questions please go to the etherpad to
put your questions your name affiliation
down so that make it easier for other
people to see your questions and if you
see other people's note-taking incorrect
please correct them it's pretty simple
and easy everybody contribute so agenda
is being posted and we have wiki's
showing some of the implementation in
the hackathon milestone okay so we
completed - I've seized already the
terminology sorry framework and problem
statement we have one document is on the
IES G's desk waiting to be reviewed has
been there for three months
and now we have a new ad so hopefully we
can
goes through faster there's the
applicability and there's we have a new
uni adopted working group draft so
together we have those working group
drafts one is on the IPSec flow policies
and ones on the capability that document
seems pretty stable now and hopefully
after this meeting we can call for
working group last call and then
remaining are the data models for
different of the interfaces one is for
the interface to the security function
one is the interface facing the client
and once the interface facing the
registration those three interface data
model need to be moved forward thus our
deliverable and we have this a client
interface requirement that document has
been installed so we're looking for
input if people are still interested in
pushing this forward or we can abandon
that anything else you want to add
something okay so here's the agenda any
people - or questions no and here are
some of the the birdeye view of all the
work we have and to be delivered so the
remaining work for this working group is
to finish the capability that's the
information model and then based on that
we have several data models which have
been becoming working group drafts
hopefully we can is all converge and
finish it and hopefully this is the last
time we need meaning to do that
hopefully
friendship I'm one of the course of the
capability information motor and the
take a motor I just want to clarify some
of the reason that a situation of this
draft for the capability information
model actually we don't bring a new
updated portion for this meeting that's
because we we also think that current
information model is relatively made
sure it's stable right now and because
it'll if it is a basica business motor
information model for a lot of data
motor based on it so and we also have
the data model based on it it has been
through a lot of several runs of Hexham
and interpret the test so I just want to
say that maybe I want to ask
good-looking group chair and if we can
ask for work in global aster Corps at
this stage because it's there's no new
thing for the information motor shaft
and the data model and we tend to have
the same feeling yeah yeah
okay so please state your name when you
talk in front of the microphone um next
one that's it right no that's first is
the Hakkasan oh just toasted hello oh
this is a fortune from sang-hyun
University Korea this hackathon is at
the Ace accustomed from ITF 97 through
this week
constructively our eight times so the
quarry that we tried to verify our three
major on interfaces restoration
interface and consumer-facing interface
and also another Pro facing or
especially restoration interface is a
face on capability Susan's data young
model so we verified that those seeing
the last eight yeah hackathons also this
time we implemented that era how was it
translation so my student Jinyoung will
present today and we believe this
translator or is a very important
functionality at security and
translation such as security policy or
error as IPSec policy comparation
translation so this is a build
environment
this is NSF okay you mean that
so kit okay okay frame oh could you go
next it makes us like please yeah okay
so this is the frame okay I believe you
guys they are familiar with this so we
on top over a Nepali based on the
OpenStack
we implemented the I to an SMS system
three interfaces next slide okay
that is okay
so especially we implemented a
translator such as user providing
security policy and it translate and
then it can deliver low-level policy
into MSM facing interfaces and then they
can configure also IPSec stop case also
we not implemented yet but we can easily
accommodate IPSec stop so IPSec
high-level policy is given to this such
as you don't want to use IPSec IPSec
like a case later than IPSec I could
list cases that kind information given
to this and the translate and then it
can configure easily
so this translator is a very important
for our working group and this is the
structure my student will explain a
young junior will explain so I can skip
it
so also we can implement using OpenStack
not talking as I proceed for a subset of
function chaining for services so we
proved a proven concept and also we
designed translator or also on the hair
custom project is open source project so
this is available especially the
translator also available so any a
vendor such as the highway Juniper Cisco
people can easily take out the advantage
of this project also we included the
video clip how to computer how to run
our code so that's it
thank you yeah just commented thank you
thank you that's a very good piece of
work thank you very much
and for people who are interested in
using open-source for doing the workload
bonnet policy please look at those
implementation and see if you can use
them
yeah
the patient can you go backwards okay
here we go
hello mmm hey you hear me
yeah yeah okay good
so okay I'll start so next slide so
basically just a reminder we are
defining in this ID in architecture and
also the interfaces for the SDM bayside
basic management in a centralized way of
the different their basic security
associations in the Korean version we
have we have changed the name of the
cases we have been discussing during the
past millions case one is now called
Ike case and the case to iCLASS case so
remember I case when the Ike version 2
is in the NSF and the I to this case
when the NSF doesn't implement Ike
person 2
so far we have a description about the
case of the hostage horse and gave way
to gateway rod war is not concerned the
current version but we have on some
question in in the final slide about the
this case niggaz assignation is not
included in the integrated version next
so we have after receiving a very deep
and extensive review from our powders
thank you for for double review and from
the church actually we have exchanged a
lot of emails in the Middle East we have
divided the original immorality part for
better reading and in order to you know
modify easily the different comments we
have we have a
come on Mario that contains common typed
ever grouping that can be used in both
additional models one of them is related
with the ID case which is ID fib Sakai
key Ike and then ID fib cyclase so
basically the same original information
beyond the changes we have countless we
have received is there but just
separated in this simply next so the
summary we have the ipsec comma we have
defined type def and groupings which are
common to both cases i case and eyeglass
case so for example we have defined
their integrity algorithm encryption
algorithms now following the discussion
in the mailing list what we have done is
true import additional module which is
cannot concrete two types so we don't
need to specify one a specific number if
a specific level the algorithms we are
going to use that was because there was
uncommon about what happen if this
algorithm may change so in our draft
where we are doing is importing another
module which is crypto types that has
been or is being defined in networking
guru
we have also changed their lifetime
action there was a no clear explanation
about that when we have defined these
three action related with the lifetime
the description is in the draft we have
removed forward from the IPSec traffic
direction we have only inbound outbound
we also had the speedy mark there was an
any conclusion about what to do with
that so far we have removed that that
piece of information and well regarding
the lifetime for example we have used
the typical type engine which is x term
in the selector grouping we have now
to fix the lecture we had a list from I
bleed Rosanna we have left and right
some and then in the processing info we
have clarified the usage of the a ad
support so next so regarding the module
relating with the AI case we have very
defined the concept of an outer starting
for the IKE implementation we have
include at only man and start we have
needed to add PF group we we didn't have
that at the beginning also from our
covers we have defined another type def
about the authentication mechanism based
on Fisher key or if or in general the
you know digital signature could be used
RSA or DSA or or even noon and also
using this fact that we have a container
which is an out method that include that
information using authentication based
on a prefer the you know digital
signature in the same way about the
common in the specific cave of Ag we
have import also important the IETF
crypto types and this is just an example
we have the signature algorithm type
that is referring something imported in
the fit to die it's not called module
um well how can such a question here or
ha that's for clarification and when you
said you remove the forward action in
limited it to inbound anomaly you didn't
lose the functionality you just have to
have two entries one for inbound what
fragment to be able to forward I decide
okay okay okay now
give up comments okay a friendship I I
think that it's a good way that your are
just imported existing crypto types your
mother in the Netcom cooking or I also
I'm also the one of the contributor of
that right but my suggestion is that
maybe you should just take a look at the
current crypto diaper now net coffee
Armando because that's a weird peek
crypto times definitions there we can't
really include episode courteous and SSH
so yeah it's a big set for all the
applications maybe you you know I'm not
I don't know they're young how to write
to your mother but my dad Union maybe
there are some you can either in your to
to support in your your mother rather
you can just to pick us a subset of that
you know the crypto diaper yamamoto
identifiers just the for use for IPSec
right because some may be not useful for
you all or you cannot use them true yeah
you essentially your take take a look
okay and powders here so one comment
about the the SPT marked that you've
removed actually recently I was made
aware of that there's a desire to have
more SPD selectors happen in the future
for instance people would like to set up
a VPN between to Europe East streams
that actually are VX LAN IDs and so you
only want is that one specific vehicle
and traffic to be carried so there's
probably a few more selectors that might
be useful to be be added in the future
and so and the other thing is I'm still
really confused about the algorithm
types and whether you used other
documents to define them I miss you I'm
not sure that other draft and lists the
ones that are valid for IPSec or not but
my general concern here is that these
types of documents basically put a
snapshot copy of the ini registry inside
in RFC and janna registry continuously
updates and so for instance because of
this document actually we started
an IPSec working group to to deprecate
some of the older ciphers when we saw
that other people were putting them into
their documents and I'm still sort of
concerned like isn't there a yang way
where you can say the the the valid
values of this keyword are indecent is
Ayana registry and I'll leave it more
because because someone who implements
whenever this becomes the RFC will have
a snapshot and you know a year later if
they start implementing it from there
they're missing the latest algorithm or
they're implementing obsoleted
algorithms like like I would really like
to just point to the IANA registry and
say you know if all the valid IPSec
encryption algorithms look there yeah
that's actually we did this because this
is the solution we take because in the
end we understand is moving the problem
from our drive to another drug that is
defined in other working group but
actually we need to investigate that so
because in the end you need to define
some kind of I don't know integral or
something to refer a number saying this
number would be in the beginning what we
have was a type def with several Adam so
actually the comment was what happened
is something new a beer or something
every move then do you need to change
the draft again so I don't really know
how should we refer that I am a registry
maybe they are starting an integer and
then say look at the China
yeah yeah I honor a registry and yes
that in the scripture I don't know the
English yes you know I mean her night
can also cost I think this is a very
good question I think we need to solve
this kind of a general problem not only
for this distract I think the better
ways to solve this problem in the crypt
attack Emoto chapter because that's such
after that we want to make it a
basically on title mode or document for
a lot of application
exactly it's just one of them so yes I
also hope so that
some young candy than that we can wecan
a periodically track the the the the
Elgar a secure crypto algorithms so you
know they are if they are if they are
still good or if they are duplicated
according to the angle and the
definition so yes I think because that
drafter the Crypt would quickly tap Java
is still in progress and improving I
think a way I will ever take a to take
care of this problem and to consider how
to solve this general program in that
just so so that every other document
that included that Java import that
traffic in tune on need to consider that
the same problem that's right right that
was actually that was actually our
approach I meaning okay this is a
problem that needs to be solved and and
there is some kind of draft trying to
compile of the cryptographic algorithms
though they will need to update that so
the only thing we need to do is to
import that that draft and included in
the in our drive okay one more comment
here young data model does allow you to
make changes expand and shrink so we
just need to pass this to the young
doctor and have them look into it I know
that several people I work with they
actually work on that how do you expand
the data model increase and decrease so
so we I just need to do that if I may
interpret what Paul was saying because I
was going to ask precisely for the self
of the same thing having the possibility
of referencing an Diana registry or any
other I mean because in my proposal for
going forward with the models cause it
precisely the idea of referencing from
the gem model another young mother of a
piece of a young model it would be
interesting that we've output to the gem
doctors not to us saying about the
particular value but about the
possibility of including references to
two values included in a registry
because that's a value of the registries
in it so the obvious not nice way of
doing that is the mean within the NA
three triple Gus is three and ASG cm is
twenty and we can just replace the
enumeration with the number and yeah
then the anything in the and the
registry is okay I don't know if that's
what we want to know to do it because
then our RFC becomes very unexpressive
just well this is a number and go to the
end and registry to see what it means
but it is future proof so just to answer
Linda yes I innocently you can update
the document and change it but then
whenever the ini registry updates we
have to write a new RC document which is
like proper cumbersome if it's just for
a few values so I would like to avoid
needing to do that and no there's a way
to do it I'll talk to a young doctor and
come back to write on the MIT mailing
list on how to achieve that okay okay so
next so we have now in the grouping like
proposal we have added something related
with a lifetime about the I say security
I mean I say because we didn't have any
lifetime we have defined hard and soft
and also after a government post comment
basically we have defined we haven't
defined no action related with heart in
their sense the action is always
terminate okay so that's also applicable
to some common about the related with
the lifetime of the IPSec s ad regarding
the container Ike version two we have
included there the container are
relating with the P ad so it's in the
related with the I configuration and
then we have a list of Aggie connections
so a pair each peer we have a note in
this list and each connection has the
different policy
is a list of acid SPD entries related
with that connection so right now in the
model what happen is we define a
connection with some between two peers
and then we define the SPD entries for
data connections if we define another
different connection and then we are the
policies related with that connection
and then we have also a container a list
of the child essays instead in the sense
that we provide only information about
the different SP is that the
implementation has created but not
additional information now our question
here in the you know slides we have is
if whether we need actually more
information that only the SP is or even
information about the different IPSec
security position that they I
lamentation has gravity it's a normal
question we have in the in the next
slide so this next step so this is their
model for the AI class regulus so we
have defined the lifetime hard with no
actual meaning permanent action with the
IPSec security Association is expired
with a hard lifetime there is then we
have to remove it we have simplified the
container I mean that the model so we
only have the container for the SPD and
the container for this ad and that's the
piece of information that they control
need to configure and then we have a
three notification Dex file acquire and
the mugs actually this is an old company
I know coming from that all mentioned in
the past so next so we have now two
slides about some open questions we have
right now what we have is an SPD model
with one policy I mean one engine SPD
one policy with multiple traffic
selectors actually that is fine and
there FC for 300
in the implementation we have film
actually or we have absurdities we have
one policy when one traffic selector so
our question is should we simplify the
speed model with re not just one topic
silikal another related question is I
think Paul mentioned is is is there any
support for multiple traffic selector
the middle of SPD's in a single child
essay right now this is not supporting
the reason is our assumption is this
child is a should have a traffic
selector wider than the policies that is
associated with that single child essay
and our download is that is allowed in
the standard it was our error dot so so
far is not supported but if it's okay to
re but we can do it another question
should we remove a h2 board we have been
discussing on this internally and whom
we are okay removing if they work
English okay we can remove the h2 board
and then only keeping the ESP
configuration there was a comment about
the encapsulation ESP encapsulation
about the missing port entry but
actually we have a group in saying we
have source port and destination port so
we are not sure what we are we missing
and that's why our question yeah you
have a question or today well with chair
cut off former implementer on I would
say that
a childís I should have one traffic
selector because when you try to support
more than you get interoperability
problems and yeah it's really how about
aah yeah nobody uses it so yeah I'm very
fine with losing it is being capsulation
well I'll leave the rest to prophetess
here I thought
um so that seems well going to me and I
just wanted to make you aware of another
recent thing that we've been doing is
where we are installing multiple
ipsec assays of the exact same traffic
selector kind because we are like
binding them to CPU so we can have like
four CPUs we bind four identical IPSec
assays to a single CPU and then if that
CPU generates traffic it goes over that
one IPSec assay so for us it's a way to
to get more and more throughput
performance so you could actually have
child essays that are completely
identical but you want more than one and
I don't know how you can express that in
your yang model yet you're referring to
Saigon bulletin - yeah the first two
bullets are sort of overlapping yeah
right now right now following we have
several policy policy can have several
traffic selectors and right now it's
traffic selector associated with the
policy will generate the wild IP Sega
set with that traffic selector right so
so I'm saying that we have use cases
where we have more than one identical
charla say oh the only thing that will
be different once we install it is like
the spy number but everything else it's
in the key hopefully oh yes sorry yeah
Nikki yeah yeah but SPI is because
different or is the same no that's guys
different yet so for RT actually for us
that is a different IP Sega say even
though it has the same traffic selector
right because s PA the identifier is
different no no that the SPD identifiers
are the same the identifiers meaning
pointing to the same policy that's right
the policies are tentacle exceptions
you're gonna read several I like it yes
good work here I don't remember
Archer if it's on your next slide or not
I think I convinced you to remove the
IKE port are being on the source and
destination and I would like to
apologize and ask for you to put it back
in because there's actually use cases
where people make bring kubernetes
containers that only get a very few UDP
ports and so they don't get UDP port for
Ike so they get like UDP port 662 680
and so then you need to pre configure
the Ike port on both the source and
destination what you expect to actually
set up a connection like that so so but
I also need to list all but this so we
will have to put that back in so you
were right sorry okay so okay slow for
this bus I want I want to ask a question
on a qualification and probably one
slide back and you said that you have a
flag that after heart's expiration
offices it must be a John Doe and
domestic don't disturb you right so the
actual meaning was because we define
like several actions in case we have a
hard life time and so the action now is
terminate so not multiple maybe the
Texas misleading is no multi-ball
actions just one actually I understand
but what does the action and delete say
and do NASA mean what is it if it is
traffic USA would be great it
automatically or what instead of routine
it's a hard life time so if it's a soft
lifetime then you Riggi you receive a
soft lifetime you Ricky but if you
receive a hard life time you have tried
before the soft life time nothing happen
something wrong happen and then reverse
it by you know peace treaty of the sort
of time or there are some other
conditions well why I'm asking
smart supplementation usually Ricky if
there is
terrific recently if there is no traffic
there's no need to rookie so it's a
permutation kettle kettle so otherwise
you will Hakeem indefinitely yeah it
depends of the the lifetime you have
because we have in terms of time or in
terms of VIPRE set by the Ibis I guess a
so I guess you are referring to the to
the bytes okay do you have enough time
yes yes we have a time and bytes yes not
only time so thank you I love that
little ditty sorry part is just to
clarify I'm there's a lifetime of the
IPSec assay but there's also what what
value is asks for an idle lifetime so
that you can say like if this connection
has been idle for 30 minutes just shut
it down but all of this happens in the
soft timers the hard time is really like
all your regular processing hasn't
happened and this is the emergency we
must not do more encryption with the key
so the only action we had is to kill the
SA and that's why there's no action
right yes yes just the tree was one yes
one common because it stopped there
there was a very common regarding
removing a name associated to the policy
we reflected that in our model because
they RFC 4301 assess that but we are
also fine for removed in age because
that cleans the actually I think you
mentioned Paul mention mentioned that
that name weird but as I said is define
the data RFC so we don't know what to do
who maybe it's not useful to have a name
for the policy yes that in a practical
sense and the final ballot each bullet
is the question is up in which should we
include road warrior support or generate
a new ID our idea in the Korean
established and considering all the
reviews we have received and taken into
account we have hostile house and
gateway to anyway maybe it would be good
to have a separate internet back that's
our our idea well I tend to agree that
this should be in a separate internet
draft well for if you for know of the
reasons that we are likely not
controlling the road warriors machine
with the SDN controller it's usually a
phone or a laptop or something that's
not really under our control so in that
case we're just configuring this sort of
a VPN gateway and then it's different
enough that it should be something I
think okay so so next so regarding the I
case alright now we have the SPD entries
the different policies where each I
connection with between two different
peers the PID is more global is outside
that
our question during the design of this
part is should we have this PD at the
same level of the P ad or is fine to
have the policy define where each
connection also here we have in the
eyeglass module we have this PD entry
lifetime actually we have observed not
even in Linux kernel notification with a
policy expire and that's why we have a
notification SPD be expiring likeliest
but what happen it like case because
that expiration will be managed by the I
implement a shoe and the question is
that will be useful to we report it to
the SDN controller so that's another
question we have right now we only
provide the third bullet is SP is a
state that related with the ABC cases in
there I case the question here is
whether I mean the controller need to
know it's know anything about the IP
Sega says yes maybe the number I don't
know
because after after all you send the
policies you want to the I complement
ation the equation will manage
everything about the ABC cases and
regarding their eyeglass maybe this is
related with the previous discussion
right now the relationship relationship
between entries in the SPD and the sa ID
is linked using traffic selector the
question is if whether we should have
explicit pointer like something like a
reg ID as you can may know in the IPSec
kernel in order to link both entries I
mean the SPD and then the there'll be
second set and yes that I knew again no
hats well when you do
the IQ case then I creates a pair of se
para faces one for the environment for
the outbound and they're linked by
virtue of having been created with the
same ike negotiation where I can change
sorry so it would make sense for the eye
class to have the same thing where
especially if we do the multiple
parallel assays that Paul talked about
earlier you have multiple well you have
multiple parallel pairs of essays and
you want the pairs to be connected to
one another
well partially because some of those DPN
implementations are also firewall
implementations and then they want to
have the connection go the packets of
the connection go through the same pair
and because it makes it things easier
for them so yeah I think the even in the
eyeglass case II should tell well add to
each si what the peril what the paired
SPI is so that the if if that makes a
difference for the kernel then the
kernel should know about it okay so
you're you're even even in the IPS you
make you make a pair of SPI one for
inbound or outbound or you make several
pairs like that so the pair's should be
connected to one another the same way
that they are with like so I thought
well but but you said maybe connect them
with the parent as a but parent infant
he put the other side of me of the
essayist yeah and so yeah I think the
NSA should should contain the SPI of the
of the other essay that is created at
the same time so this is okay but this
is then a different this is a different
comment as this one I we have in this
life because what we were referring is
if the SPD entry I mean the policy
des PD and then you have the ipsec
essays usually you for example you have
in Linux kernel you have the Reg ID like
you can use that like a pointer to to
the between oh oh you see on the Ibis
legacy so the question is we don't have
that kind of link we had in the past
that kind of thing but right now is okay
this policy have traffic selector and
then you have Devi Sega say that has
traffic selector so the relationship
between the AV Sega say and they in the
and the policy is based on that traffic
selector the other thing you mention is
that one inbound spi has a like related
outbound spi and they we should reflect
that relationship is that correct okay
see what you mean
is this reg idea part of the SPD that
you send it to thee and to the Linux
kernel it's something that you can
include if you want yes
all right so I guess it makes sense to
link them and I'm sure there's a reason
why stairs might as well tell them okay
okay and so next and not slight so we
would like the review Murs that they
have checked the the draft take another
look to the draft in order to see if
they are okay with the changes or the
main changes and then we think the
document should be really for they're
working or last call we would like to
thank a game to to ball because he said
he did a really amazing review of our
draft and we really have to say that
thank you okay thank you so lost time
theory I canna staff meeting and we
promised a bit of fancy coffee to
whoever makes the best review of this
document and obviously Paul wins you can
redeem your coffee wherever you want as
long as it's
he says it doesn't drink okay so you
sure you're Dutch okay anyway so um so
yeah we so the people in the room think
that the document is ready for working
last call because we kind of think so so
anybody has something to say that no
it's not ready for last call other than
that Paulo needs to review the new
version yeah right good so I think we'll
wait a week after the meeting and then
started working up last call and
hopefully we can get this done by the
next ITF because we are hearing a lot of
well a lot of noise from the industry of
people who want this buffer within the
ITF and outside the ITF because people
want to deploy IPSec mainly because
their TLS working group is not letting
them break TLS so they you might as well
fare better with IPSec so now yeah we'd
like to get this finished and hopefully
by before the next meeting I have a
question um David you have this IPSec a
key rekey mechanism how does that work
with this mechanism did it any conflict
or is a complementary might wait
so uh David Carol I think it could be
complimentary I had talked in the past
about trying to write up a case three
and I have not made the time and done
that and so it's not ready I could bring
something forward at some other point
soon but I don't know I think at this
point this document seems ready yeah and
I wouldn't want to be holding it up okay
you know I asked you you know thoughts
from from you but I don't think holding
it up would make sense now if this isn't
right so my questions really your rekey
mechanism does it apply to bose i ki and
oculus cases the applicable to both
cases only one of them it's different
than both its you're not doing an IKE
but it's not ike well it cyclist but
it's not the same as the i close okay
it's still doing you know there's
there's different messages that need to
be sent back and forth some of it some
some of the things that the SPD and the
and the pad are a little more similar to
what's done in ike but it's not the same
okay so one do you think you can write
something up there have to be included
in this draft it can be independent ID
I'll write something up separately okay
before the next meeting okay and also
about the child here we have the one
child purse I say for your case you
could have multiple child right I say
yes
so how is that aligned with this while
conflicting with this one any problem
with but anyway I'll think about that
okay I don't know thank you good night
okay III have another question about to
this document and maybe the option three
kind of document is about the many about
the configuration are you on data model
for the IKEA and a keyless case and I'm
not sure whether the the another
solution
I think that's um mmm that resolutions
contender is mainly about
t-distribution McKenna de for the sta or
Sdn controller our scenario so is it
also if it also includes some data how
to configure the the the pointer to
achieve this tricky treat key
distribution so I mean so I my question
is currently the younger demo divided in
this document trying to be directory
used for the other options or is there
some confliction or they're missing
something for other mechanisms in terms
of key distributions yes yes today I
think they still need to do some
configuration for achieve their key
distribution go right so so that's that
as all of that configuration is already
in your draft and there's no confliction
between you and the future possible
solution the solutions here are very
simple in the eye case you send
credentials for to allow the icon sent
occasion and in the case of the eyeglass
you are sending the IP sagesse so the
interlocutors usual you're sending the
cryptography material and algorithms you
need to establish the IPSec assay so I
don't see any conflict actually he said
young model could be extensible but I
don't see any conflict actually in as I
said the idea behind this drug is firmly
simple you configure IPSec assay then
you send all the parameters you need to
come for your debbie's baby sega say in
the case of the iCLASS case and when you
have to perform Ike
then you send credentials about
authentication in Ike and in the first
phase phase one or the authentication of
the I say so I don't see any particular
if I understood the question of course
yes thank you God I think you have you
have
you have persuaded me yeah I think yeah
your your proposal is very dear add to
it the simple so I also write on I also
cannot see yes any of conflicts okay
thank you okay thank you about it so
I'll try to sync up there it is so what
I think is the case is that in the
distributed eye cases where you you
still do an IKE exchange between two two
security controllers but then some of
the values are only transported in a
sort of similar to IQs case to the nodes
that actually use it and in this case it
means that the nodes actually only know
the private key and not security
controller so there might be some
additional configuration needed like you
know I'm proxying for unboxing like for
this other IP address but those are like
a few minor options other thing can be
grouped into like a separate document
okay okay so you're referring to the to
the communication between two Sdn
controllers right oh it's okay
okay thank you reference okay thank you
thank you for your time
hey what's next hello this is a porridge
young so at least documentary is about
the applicability of I to NSF in the
real world
so after are working on raw score the
error detector array La Scala are gave a
three major comment
the first one is it is insecure if we
allow TMS developer management the
system accesses the its own on that
really functions their time so so our
document clearly measure the TMS is not
allowed to access NSF online the only
access is allowed by critic on Salama
secondly the XML example required for
concrete example so we are provided the
time based our fiber so we provided the
code the third one is so we clarify how
to tell if a given software element in
an aqua blue in vironment such as an MSF
learning on top of what we adapt or just
virtual by 50 such as the STR switch so
we have of lien upon boarding system in
a memo system so we can easily clarify
using the description of a capability of
a PMF so we can easily resolve it so
those are three things are addressed in
the libyan so we believe this is related
to some committee solution to ISSG so
hopefully
working out of chairs can move it
forward okay thank you baby
you ready who is it okay eighty okay
okay okay so yeah we are just yet
commented you can yet yeah move forward
okay okay thank you yeah if there is no
question move out Tara
yeah models so this slider includes a
five there are young model the first one
in the students are capability there are
young model this is the debate basis for
the other young models and also we have
three a major or NSF interface and
consumer interface laceration interface
so also we have a monetary interface to
regulate NSF so this time we synchronize
among or five young models so also we
are verified there are last including
this I have wonderful accustomed project
we eight times we verify that the
interoperability and also functionality
about our young models so the major
update of thing is the first one is this
those are their young models are
synchronized with Frank ashiya's NSF
capabilities the information on model so
also during working or adoption call for
NSF monitoring data young model ops are
working group some person or providing a
valuable comment
the first one is Lee vision over our
Tara long model according to the young
Caroline such as RFC sixty eighty seven
so we synchronized among five young
model especially we added this time
three examples XML file one is dr.
security such as a fire and time-based
if I were the secondly content security
such as a reflector vo IP appeal I
people your LT security the last one is
attack mitigation such as HTTP or HTTPS
flood attack are mitigated so those the
conquer of the example are provided to
health developer how to use our terror
young model in leer scary services
firstly capability a terror model so we
devised and structured tourneys are no
major some changes in content so we
followed the guideline for young so 60
87 so we follow that ease Qaeda lines
the secondly NSF of facing interface or
the error model also we be structured
original content the major change apart
we added four or three scenario for
personally the Web Filter during work
time secondly malicious who you IP buyo
lt-col and certainly mitigation of HTTP
and HTTPS flood attack so you can see
this I just to show a time-based fiber
so time-based case we specify during
what time such as you are employee so
you cannot access Facebook and over some
YouTube during your work time right so
in that case we specify time range and
also this is the SNS IP address and such
as a Google YouTube and Facebook
something like that
that we can find out otherwise discrete
associated web filter so we providing a
source function training so firstly the
fiber secondly this fact afforded to a
recruiter that our security function so
that spirit function such as a filter
okay
investigate the content such as URL if
this is related to Facebook or some you
to eat raw so we provide the XML example
for on Fiverr and the filter suddenly a
consumer facing in to pace the consumer
face interface is providing to I to MSB
users such as the security of the
Mitchell writer specify high level
scripted policy such as during what time
employee cannot access as soon as our
site that kind of high level policy at
liberty to security our controller
secure controller which translate to
using our translator and then a Massa
facing interfaces it can be used to
deliver that so previous slide I showed
the fire a repeater scenario so this
time we changed as follows detailed
description for each more object in data
model and also we use the crew Fein to
reduce the petition over the common part
and also we provided a more generic yeah
data young motor so this is an example
so you can see the metadata IP address
the metadata has a name and also take
that one is just has a mnemonic name
meta and that this one can be used
rather than the Terra is many places
require data to this one so we can
accrue practice also IP address case
also we can exact exact matching
Overland matching can be provided using
this grouping feature so also generic a
data model so the PI word did that our
security
videos are take it in the attack
mitigation other custom condition threat
conditions wreck condition especially is
from the Oasis the standard e-series and
the body they are working for structured
the threat information from it so we
also take advantage of that file type
and a signature information for content
security so in this area are we
providing concrete example XML example
such as that we can you can see generate
high-level policy you can see during
this time employee cannot access this
SMS the website so employee we can
specify employee address and also the
SNS websites detected by this fiber vnf
SNF so you can see this website it can
be leased up like this so we can easily
specify how high-level policy and then
fourthly restoration interface
registration interface cases this time
week just focus on the last meeting
Thiago mentioned lifecycle management is
out of scope so we need of them and just
focus on restoration and the second rate
the quarry certain cases some helmet
policies given to secure security
control law 432 no registered NSF in
that time secure control law or contact
contact the developer manuals term to
ask whether such as NSF exists on that
so that kind of quarry is provided so we
devised a structure and also we added a
some description for young tree diagram
also we also provided the XML exam flows
so one example is a general or five
words so fire case you can see the
protocol
address photo number and also we specify
the possible actions this is a fire
feature and also we can providing the
performance yeah
cry tears criteria and also access
implemented this NSF if I were I to
address the ears right there and photo
number is right here so security control
lock can have this information to
provide security service for users so
and then fifthly and I said for
monitoring in tera
models so we merge the information model
in the data model and also we in
structured according to Caroline for
young terremoto and also we replace the
enumeration type with the identify for
scalable components so okay that is the
summary of changes of five tarae-hyung
model from now I briefly describe the
discussion with Diego and Frank as
though Tiago will explain in detail last
of of this recession so he is playing so
but I pre-plea explain why we do we why
need this kind of terror motor
compulsion so she's such as I said we
just discussed the lava is flamed right
so in the case certain you or Tara model
is is required so how to accommodate in
our Tara model so the approach is that
we can use like for us to that concrete
Tara young mothers so especially the Ike
and the i key IPSec I or I could list
cases we can easily specified using one
identity are left reference variable so
for young for so new
yeah you can see so this is a cop
ability there are models so when the
develop management system register fiber
into the security control law we can
specify this kind of IPSec Macerata
such as is a case or I detect ELISA
cases and the Leicester racial interface
can specify concretely so such this
intersect for support I could list cases
so we can easily and then we can provide
it on this kind of selection of Michael
is the script controller can tell the
security NSF's of a face interface which
kind of like master diesel used for NSF
so next steps so we believe last eight
hackathon project those especially the
Suzanne's
capability data model and three major
interface is a young go there are primo
mature so we believe we can last score
those for data young model trapped and
then monitoring cases still we needed
two more or some airports so next
accustomed we implement and that we can
prove the concept okay that's all okay
thank you thank you very much any
questions on this so lots of information
here so Diego you had some um slides
about the discrepancy
so he's are resolved okay okay okay
so I think that we need to discuss this
okay now it should be it should be see
once that Paul has neither has done all
the job basically give yes he plays that
well where should I point
yeah now yes well we have them we have
the problem that we have a slow
convergence of models and interfaces is
something that is happening because we
set it with a capability model but then
we had to let's let so bringing them
down to earth and make the real data
data models and there was a divergence
of how the capabilities were well
behaving and their cognition is killing
me how the capability model where were
working and interacting or intending to
interact with the with the different
data models well for some reflections
the pun is that the capabilities make
sense at the policy level when you're
going to register them to announce it
because all the IDS precisely we are
basing their whole thing is that the
functions announce their capabilities
and that the security controller can
manipulate them this makes sense saying
well what is a security control at north
wrong interface the consumer-facing
wants but if we do go round to
capabilities and to try to make all the
manipulations with the capabilities you
see is well basically they can become a
nightmare because they ring going
capability by capability taken in second
that the functions need to be managed
with concrete data models modifying
their perimeter parameters and
everything is something that would
require either Translate translators
innate at each function that doesn't
make sense if you think about it because
is that difficult that many of the
functions that are already available
will be start building translators from
capabilities down to to the
configuration all the other thing is is
a translator that is almighty that knows
everything that can translate
capabilities into all the different
kinds of mobiles that network security
function could follow for its
falafels for many being managed and well
something that held at least myself in
understanding the problem is when it
comes to this precisely the ipsec
controlling model that is brand new
how do you incorporate it into the
current mode so trying to look for a
solution the VA would be precisely to
decouple the the policy from the actual
management I used precisely the the
controller asked the source of the
translation of translating these
policies into action so there is that
that with each capability whenever the
function declares a capability registers
a capability being used to say well this
capability is associated with this
particular model ideally not not with
the whole mobile but with the fragment
or even if you like with a particular
barrier variable inside that particular
model but this is something this is one
of the things that we would like to ask
the giant doctors because I'm not sure
that can be this can be full freedom and
they be able B to say this is the way in
which you have to manage this capability
I have the capability of managing Ike
negotiations using option 1 and so you
have to use this piece of the giant to
do so this association the natural way
is that we we keep the capability model
without without being touched and what
we do is that we make this association
whenever there is a registration so the
developer vendo who knows about they
they say well I implement capability X
and to activate a man and control
capability X you should use this piece
of the of this model so it should be an
extension to registration interface and
both translate into a ratio of models
that are applicable for the set of
capabilities that the controller knows
about well that implies that the
security controller
both have to keep a registry of models
and associations is a database anyway
should have to keep array a database of
the capabilities so it's extending the
capability later is and rely on this
registry for Policy translations what
means makes recent proposal that Paul
made precisely about the policy
translator so it will be part of the
security controller and what probably
they in the draft about the policy
translator there should be a reference
to the capability register the means
well basically I mean this is something
that since well I must say this is an
idea while flying here this is an idiot
a little bit with Paul and Frank during
the during the hackathon so probably
there are a lot of problems inside but
the idea is that we should send the
registration interface I mean the
registration data mobile to make it to
put a mechanism to announce these these
reference to the air to the management
mobile we have to decide what to do with
the NS NSF facing interface because if
we transform the NSF phasing interface
to a way of using Jan to modify the
functions using the registry either we
think that is a wrapper and that inside
is the data model operating without me
they'd be data model at all because we
are going to use the reference ones this
is something that we have to think and
again it's more about the tooling using
jiying than anything else well that we
need to refine this essentially and well
yes I know this is a very rough idea let
me see what they think is important I
mean for making this advance and make it
this advanced as fast as we can because
otherwise we are risking to get stuck in
a situation in which we have the the
IPSec graph moving it let's say in the
wild not allowing with the capability
movin over lag and as you have said it
there is a demand for it I don't the
other had
the basic concept surrounding the
security controller the interfaces and
other like being completely left
isolated just for playing a little bit
with a view of the capability with this
way we keep a capability model for
reasoning and for making the smart
decisions and we warranty that the whole
thing becomes a Frager that can be
extended and will allocate in the future
new models and we don't touch I mean
this is a very important that seems
really affecting one draft that were to
they pick up the registration interface
and the NSF facing interfaces is
something that is I guess doable and can
be aligned in a reasonable time for sure
that everything is in the details
maybe that we ended up we end up finding
something that is completely impossible
I hope is it won't be the case and
probably we have to rely on region the
the help of a of the gen doctors thank
you
Iago and Peter complained about it is a
new idea but I I think about it and we
discuss it I think that that's a way to
achieve the consistency about the
current so so many data models to reach
your consistency between them because we
have a long time we have a consensus in
working group that capability data
murder and that information more the
capability is a very key terminology or
the basic block for the whole extended
attack interface data model so we
mastered a figure a way to to make Oda
statement or to be in a consistent way
so this is a good solution is a good way
to to achieve this or Cantonese and I
also say I also think that this is a
also our flexible way because a country
we have a visa is example that
IPSec statement or how to comply how to
a language that is not debilitated
moaner and maybe in the future they are
allowed or a statement of policy motor
for the
all security function management so I
think we should as soon as possible we
find our way to to provide it is the
kind of flexibility to add the future
new data model in our the general model
so this is a very good way so the only
problem is that a theater will bring a
big influence or changes to our
coordinate data model we have considered
it to some green I think there were no
picking fluence on candidate models
there will be some minor change I hope
so
so I think it was - yeah consider MOU
and trying so this problem yeah a
reflection thanks Frank my only what do
we have to do as well is to talk with
Aldo and young about this because they
are not here this is something that we
have and well we have to share this with
them I hope they will be I think this
will be acceptable for them because
doesn't affect that the capability model
at the end it doesn't change the
principles so this is a Porto from sa
Kiki you so yeah I think a Diego point
out a very important issue
so during a cousin project Diego prank
and I discussed this one also I
discussed it with my student how to
implement this new or suggestion into
the error model so my group are
disgusted during we can and then my
previous presentation we can conclude
the identity identity left can be used
because the ana space in case we can
have as an additional variable for
identity in laugh and that we can easily
import the Nahas ipsec there are no
there easily so I believe yeah we can
easily so my conclusion is this one
doesn't affect much about the capability
so we can easily extend them yeah there
are young wonderful
I do have questions just seems like this
proposal is uproot the entire data
models we've been done right so you're
saying that we need to change the
structure no no no no like the
registration interface data model and be
imported by the only only no only the
registration interface so there is that
the original sessions when you register
a capability you will use the same thing
everywhere everything will be equal
though but you will add a reference say
um my data model is this one and you put
other reference we have to discuss or we
have to find whether this how this
reference can be constructed in the best
possible way in terms of referencing
being able to verify etc but is a
reference to say AI is a little bit and
this is what I was asking before is a
little bit what Paul was asking about
the Yana registries something similar as
to say is to say look here I want to use
that thing basically so I mean that my
question is is it doable seems a good
idea don't believe so think so yeah and
also yeah if working would agree at this
proposal
my guru already a modified our
tarae-hyung model so after our meeting
we can unload the device yep trapped
yeah hi Roman did earlier maybe I'm
asking the same thing same question that
Linda is I'm trying to reconcile what we
just talked about here with the previous
presentation that said we're ready to go
to last call because we think we're done
with the four other things
the there is only one I mean that well
there are two later models that I mean
the capability model is not going to be
touched at all the and this is one of
the things that we were trying to find a
way of solving this race because a
capability model I don't know we do have
gone through the document that is heavy
something that is difficult to deal with
and so the capability model is not to be
touched the registration interface
should not go for La Scala because we
need to make this modification and we
have to open a reflection time for the
NSF facing interface all the rest I mean
that we took it to documents that say we
need to reconsider the rest are ready
for as far as I can as we can tell
because it's something that and it's a
facing registration next week next week
will be better yes tomorrow I guess most
practically I was concerned you
obviously going to resolve that before
you take whatever document that's gonna
get modified you know yeah yeah that's
no no no suck yeah yeah yeah sure
and I'm this is something that we the
Jang the giant gap see something that
would like to check with the jam that
service because so so the plan is after
this meeting maybe a month or so if you
can update the document I hope so and
then circulate we're going to circulate
you a few more reviewers and then
hopefully we can get it ready for
working group last call yeah a mantra
will be beers and celebrations and okay
we're gonna have a celebration montre
alright butene for all that's done that
so they surrender they now log in that
roughened area where one of the ideas I
would like to to users as a touchstone
possessive integration of their mode
Rapha your game translate so the
translator will be part of the sorry
okay thank you so the next one there is
the next one this one this is a part of
the controller Diego was talking about
being part of the SDN controller
so let me start so hello I'm Jun Hyuk
yeah
I'm from estate kill you and I will
present about security policy
translation and I to NSF then curious uh
here is the two types of sentence the
first one is the policy for I to nesaf
users and second one is policy for NSS
so and I turn us a future case they can
easily generate the first sentence but
because it's usual kindly but second one
isn't when I turn as a user doesn't have
any expert knowledge of security however
in NSF case and as NSF cannot recognize
the first first one because the data of
that first the first sentence is really
abstracted so even if I turn SF user
gives the first high-level policy then I
turn SF system needs to automatically
translate it into the low level policy
yeah so actually for translating the XML
based policy actually Excel silty is
popular method for doing that
so in sis ripple for example sis ripple
is for implementing the using the
net-net comp server yeah but it's really
popular but it has some limitation first
it's really difficult to construct the
security policy when they have no no
other expert knowledge and it is really
inhibition for managing the network
system so we propose the automata based
policy translation so we can solve the
two kinds of limitations so here
translation architecture so our purpose
is when I to an ACEF users then a
high-level policy geo are as the
critical controller then we can select
the proper target NSF's automatically
and translate the high dollar policy
into the low level policy and send it
via the network security function based
interface first we should extract the
main keywords in high-level policy based
on the consumer facing data model then
we can we should specify the abstracted
data because NSF cannot recognize the
abstracted data and also we should find
the proper NSF automatically so we
extract the unique capability for each
NSF so when the policy data has some
unique capability then we can select the
appropriate NSF automatically like that
then after select the proper NSF then we
should construct the low level policy by
using CFG is one of the automata theory
so the previous draft was the version 2
so actually the explanation have been
added or explaining the NSF data based
components and also implementation
consideration section is added for
providing the great guideline for
developer so security policy translation
is the core function for I to Anessa
implementation in the real world so for
emphasizing these draft so I will
introduce one draft RFC documents its
RFC eight
7:5 it's about the mapping
implementation between HTTP clients and
web server that purpose of that purpose
of that draft was just attaching the
HTTP client and clap server for exactly
IOT IOT network so that that was a
really necessary function in their work
and they gave the cat guideline for
mapping constructing environments and
yeah such the other things for
implementation and its success it to be
the RS RFC documents for that case so
this draft can provide the I to NSF
developers with the great guideline to
implement and mapping and constructing
the security controller so we already
had the a lot of approach in this
working group but there are no
guidelines or the security controller
exactly so we are aimed this draft at
the information no RFC and we already
proved dirty I ITF 1/4 hex on so yeah
can I share my opinion so i am paul john
kasich iike you i am also the court is
prepped so as you may observe the
translation is very important especially
the la paz IPSec that high labor some
policy given to the security controller
from i turn a polluter so our translator
also tells with that kind of policy
which means i core I could list case is
translate and then easily impressed into
NSF and also security policy for
security functions such as our recruiter
and other videos attack mitigation case
the
policy is a delivered to security
controller from I to another user or the
oedometer writer so we can easily
translate to using these framework so
this document is a more likely
architecture and also those on procedure
letter than some implementation detail
even though we have a guideline for
implementation for a developer but we
aim at informational atmosphere like the
core core working group has the ad 875
is a mapping from HTTP to coop so in the
same way I believe it is documented very
usable from our working group work in
the industry 8:07 file it is about
mapping implementation from HTTP to Co
correct yeah protocol yeah francha and i
think yeah i agree that this document
has some value that it came to right the
guidance for the working group to do the
translation functions engineering the
security controller a20 securing that is
value but based on the example you show
here I I think my personal feeling that
you may miss understand the the risk at
the the latest are security functions
implementation for example right now our
a lot of network firewall devices we
whatever work we we call it maybe we can
call it our next-generation firewall
right a lot of these kind of security
devices has already provided a lot of
application they are information to
manage them to directory for example we
can you put in director configure then
by using the user information the user
group and the application name or the
service name so that's that's so that
means that so those work to not need to
provider by the
to be provided by the network security
controller
security controller so if
all of your content in this document is
about to translate from this a fall for
this kind of information I don't think
is very useful for current we're more
than a security device so if you
otherwise if your provider are very high
level architecture to please spend how
to do these abstract translation
functions and what is architecture what
is a general mens order I think they are
helpful okay I want to take some more
time before you go for coffee Sibley is
that well I
at the beginning when I first saw these
these proposed this document I thought
it was that sort we are to have in the
in the group right now taking it again
the reason proposed all about the
registration interface and other like is
something that it makes much more sense
we possess an informational RFC because
it's one of the is it that says the new
functionality that the controller should
have precisely in this mechanism of
translating from the capabilities up to
the the models well to some extent
adjust to acknowledge that the idea was
somehow inspired in this in this
document so well I think we should go
for it okay then we can finish our
meeting early honey minutes early yeah
first time thank you thank you
let me a casserole in thunder or so
these are what I think one of very key
functionality so we add some a poll
adopt working group yeah document or not
analyzed we can we adopt this to you
working
now it's almost like a best practice yet
the information on our pussies so so I
see some other doctor working groups
have those best practice okay all right
see okay
okay thank you yeah thank you so we
should end and hopefully by Montreal
time we finish everything and then
celebrate yeah yeah has everybody signed
the blue sheet
I think there's one at the back rooms so
if not oh well see another meetings
hopefully