that was super deliberate nobody will
awake let's get started it's not just my
Mike Brian all right
I'm not repeating Brian's comments to
the mic but let's get started this is IC
c RG if you don't care much about
condition control you are in exactly the
right room
you might learn a few things this is an
IOT F meeting but we are going to still
use the note well I'm not going to read
this and if you haven't read it you
probably should moving along before I
get into the agenda I believe we have a
jab escribe do we have no sorry we have
we have somebody to cover jabber do we
have a note-taker you're counting jabber
right yes yeah sorry sorry you thank you
Tom you know I know Tom it's late in the
afternoon and late in the week I need
somebody to cover jabber then oh hang on
I mean somebody take notes I'll get this
right eventually don't worry there's
such a thing called eventual consistency
sorry yes that that would also work for
me but it's ideal if there's one person
at least who commits to doing this
thank you sir who's I heard a voice I
can see uh yes Brian thank you thank you
thank you thank you
moving on we have we have a packed
agenda today we have only four
presentations but all four of them
interesting talks and so there's a fair
bit of time for each one I'm going to be
I'm gonna try and stick to the time that
I have written out there and as always
you will all go past the time so we'll
see how this goes I don't have very much
else here to talk about for the agenda
anybody want to bash the agenda and done
all right Neil you're up let's see how's
this Mike that's pretty good all right
[Music]
so I'm going to be talking about bbr v2
which we think of as a model based
congestion control this is joint work
with my colleagues at Google you chung
Sohail ianvictoria Rajan you suck Matt
and Van Jacobson next slide please
so I'm gonna focus on the be BRB to
research update I'm talking about
improvements between VBR v1 and v2
talking briefly about the status and
recent results we're seeing in
experiments and then try a sort of
lightning review of the BB r v2 design
so in which we talked about previously
previous IT apps and then give a quick
status summary in and conclusion next
slide please
oh yes perfect
so in order to address some various
issues with the initial BB our v1
version we have undertaken a couple
improvements so the main issues we're
addressing here with v1 included low
throughput for renaming cubic flows
sharing bottlenecks with bulk PPR flows
in certain scenarios BB everyone was
Ross agnostic which in certain scenarios
with Banach buffers or a QMS keeping the
queue at 1.5 be Peters shorter that
could result in high packet loss rates
via v1 was easy on agnostic as well did
not use CCN signals and with the initial
release there could be low throughput
for paths with high degree of data or AK
aggregation and here the the biggest
issues you would see with Wi-Fi paths
with no our TTS say one to ten
milliseconds and then another issue with
me one was that there could be pretty
severe
throughput variation due to quite low
ceilings in when in a small period of
time that they're in probe RT t mode
then with BB r v2 we were trying to
tackle all of these issues and I'll give
some examples of the design changes in
the resulting behavior so for
coexistence with reno in cubic the basic
approach we take with PBR v2 is to try
to adopt the time scale of the bandwidth
probing so that we can coexist better
with reno in cubic and we talked about
the details of the algorithm
last July at ITF one or two and those
are basically the same in the latest
revision as well and here's a quick
diagram to sort of illustrate the flavor
of behavior that we're talking about
here so here's a scenario with a 15
megabit bottom link
a 40 milliseconds rip time one VDP a
buffer for cubic flows one PBR be to
flow and you can see the the BP RV to
flow is is playing along nicely there at
the bottom in the pink achieving an
approximately fair share
the reasonably low retransmitted rate
matching cubics here so the next major
improvement is is using packet loss as
an explicit signal with an approach that
sort of has an explicit target loss rate
ceiling which I'll talk a bit about a
bit about later on this we also talked
about it
ITF 102 and here's a quick scenario just
to sort of illustrate the behavior with
this algorithm so here we have six VP of
the two flows in a very shallow buffer
that's only 5% of the BDP only 49
packets but the flows start staggered
and achieve an approximately fair share
and with the reason being we transmit
rate given how shallow the buffers so be
BRB to uses ECN as a signal now DC TCP
style ecn if it's available to help keep
the queues short and to illustrate the
kind of behavior we're talking about
here we have 20bb our v2 flows starting
staggered every 100 milliseconds it's a
1 gigabit bottleneck link in a 1
millisecond round trip time the ECM
marks here are from the linux coddled
queue disk with the default settings
except for the c e marking threshold at
242 microseconds which is about 20
pounds worth of queue
okay we have 0 retransmits pretty decent
fairness and our TTS are fairly low the
median OTT is right around the marking
the threshold and the rest are
reasonably well controlled so there are
also improvements for high throughput
for paths with large SKUs of aggregation
notably as I said Wi-Fi and - to achieve
that v2 explicitly estimates the degree
of aggregation that had seen recently
and now maybe in the data path and maybe
in the act path either way the
aggregation shows up in the extreme and
bbr tries to characterize that
and we talked about the details of that
it ITF 101 last March you can find the
slides there on YouTube we're seeing be
BRB to match Kubek throughput for users
specifically on Wi-Fi links and overall
and in control tests for seeing
reasonable behavior you can see here on
the right is a time sequence plot of a
be BRB to transfer to my laptop at home
so it started at a pop in New York City
when I run a local internet to DOCSIS
link which has its own aggregation
behavior if their Wi-Fi link has its own
aggregation behavior and still behaves
reasonably well and the aggregation
modeling code is available in quick in
the chromium quick and now recently also
in linux 5.1 the final major design
change is to reduce the throughput
variation so when BB everyone if you had
to enter probe itt perhaps because it
was a bulk flow that's been going more
than 10 seconds or so bbr v1 would cut
the seal into 4 packets in v2 you know
we can cut the c1 to 50% of the bdp to
still achieve reasonable throughput even
while attempting to probe the the to a
propagation delay so those are the major
improvements in v2 as a quick summary
you can sort of consider how B to lines
up with v1 and cubic as I said the it's
a model based congestion control and
here specifically the model parameters
that we feed into the state machine for
BB are we to include the throughput the
RTT or men ou TT the max degree of
aggregation we've seen recently in the
max amount of data we think it's
reasonable to keep in flight and as I
said BB our v2 has this sort of explicit
loss rate target and an explicit
response to congestion to eat DC TCP
style congestion and the startup not
surprisingly has a sort of slow start
style behavior of doubling the
throughput until we see the either the
throughput
plateau or the ecn or loss rate exceed
the design parameter or threshold
so where are we with d BRB - right now
we're testing it with YouTube TCP
traffic we have our kernel with an
initial version of PBR v2 on all the
YouTube machines and it's running a
global experiment with a small
percentage of YouTube users results so
far are looking quite reasonable we see
the RT T's are of course vastly lower
than cubic and and even a little bit
lower than BER the one the packet loss
rates are considerably reduced versus vb
l v1 they're about halfway down to back
to cubic and while still matching cubic
throughput and we're continuing to
iterate using the youtube setup other
production tests and lab tests and we're
preparing to open source the code as
soon as we can and as we do that as soon
afterwards as possible we're gonna
update the BB our internet drafts to
[Music]
reflect the latest vb r v2 code because
I know there are people out there that
are interested in working with the
algorithm based on the draft rather than
the code I would note that the code we
try to we we have made a dual BSD GPL so
hopefully folks in the BSD ecosystem can
use it as is if if they are interested
but that ain't right so I'm gonna try to
do a lightning over year the PBR be to
design how much more time to have I
guess you took a clarifying question now
yes sure
so so this is a job ascribe um mr
Johansen asks which is the which RTT is
it on slide six that's the Monaro TT
estimating to a propagation delay so
just a quick I mean you're gonna try to
do a lightning overview the BRB to
design many of these slides we've shown
a previous IETF so I just thought it
would be useful have a quick overview
all in one spot for so
at a 10,000 foot view you can think of
the design as basically consisting of a
system that takes as inputs measurements
from the network traffic that it's
controlling and it's looking at a couple
different signals to the throughput or
delivery rate the delay that is the RTT
delay the loss events ecn mark events
and those are all fed into a network
path model inside PBR and then the
parameters of the network path model are
used to control the evolution of the
state inside the state machine inside
PBR and then that in turn makes
adjustments in the output parameters
which are the rate which you can think
of as a sort of pacing rate for the
sending process the maximum volume of
in-flight data otherwise known as a
congestion window or Sealand and and
then floor at I'm calling here a quantum
which is just sort of a chunk size for
the whatever off that mechanism might be
in play whether it's TSO or gso or
whatever that OS calls it and those
output parameters are fed into the
sending engine of the transport whether
it's TCP or quick or something else
which takes the data chops up into
quantum sized pieces and then paces them
out at the given rate until it has a
maximum amount of data or or until
pacing says you can't set any more right
now so so that's a the big picture if we
look at the drill down into the model
and what's inside the model you can sort
of visualize it as is depicted here in
the diagram that's a time sequence
diagram with a sequence on the y-axis
time on the x-axis the green is showing
send events the acts are showing up as
blue here here I've drawn them is as
pretty bursty acts because that these
days that's a pretty pretty typical
behavior whether it's high speed 8
Ethernet Wi-Fi cellular DOCSIS they all
have aggregation pretty significant
levels and you can sort of visualize
each of the parameters here the first
one is the maximum bandwidth that's
available recently to this flow the
second one you can think of as the min
RTT
seeing recently which serves as an
estimate of the tumor propagation delay
then there's the maximum amount of
inflator that we think is reasonable
based on my recent loss and ecn signals
and then there's the maximum measured
aggregation level that we've seen
recently in the extreme and two of these
in particular of course are going to
change quite rapidly based on the low
traffic levels that is the bandwidth and
maximum in flight that's reasonable to
keep maximum amount of data it's
reasonable to keep in flight so because
of that BB r v2 maintains both a
short-term bandwidth and in-flight
estimate and a long-term bandwidth and
in-flight estimate and you can think of
this as sort of being analogous to cubic
which has a sort of short term SS thrush
estimate and then a longer term W max
value that's a higher amount of
in-flight data that it's hoping to
quickly progress back up to you with if
everything goes well it's sort of
analogous to that so a high level the
adaptation of the model basically
estimates that then with an in-flight 2d
set of parameters over both the short
term in the long term with the goals
being not surprisingly a high throughput
and for bbr importantly we're trying to
be able to maintain that even when
experiencing some moderate particularly
amount of random packet loss and then
we're of course trying to keep low queue
pressure and the basic approach here is
sort of twofold we want to spend most of
the flows time in a face where it's
mostly adapting quickly to try to
maintain flow balance between the
extreme and the data stream while also
leaving some Headroom of unused capacity
either on the bottom IQ or in the bottom
link and to do that we have the this
short-term bandwidth an in-flight
estimate tuple that basically bounds the
behavior using the latest
delivery process and Lawson ECM signals
that we're seeing and the intuition here
is basically what's the bandwidth and
in-flight delivery process that we're
seeing right now and we're seeing you
see any lost signals that's an
indication that we need to adapt quickly
to those signals that we're seeing right
now to maintain reasonable queuing
levels and then the second part of this
picture is that of course periodically
we do need to probe beyond that flow
balance level to probe robustly to see
if higher bandwidth is available now
then say it was available before the
last time we probe for bandwidth and to
do that to control that behavior we have
that as I said that the longer-term
bandwidth in and flight estimates that
were have been most recently measured
before we saw signals of congestion in
the form of ecn or loss marks and the
intuition with that part of the picture
is that we're basically trying to say
what's the maximum bandwidth and
in-flight that can be achieved
consistent with the networks desired
loss rate in an ECM mark rate I solos or
service level objectives that's the
basic high-level picture of the model so
to consider the details of how it
evolves I think it's useful to consider
a more concrete example so it's an
interesting question how do we adapt to
a packet loss signal given the
ambiguities involved so if we consider
this this example we hear we have a
shallow buffered high-speed wind would
say 100 millisecond round-trip time and
app does occasional 200 mm packet writes
these are RPC requests RPC replies web
object replies something like that and
let's consider a case where the
available bandwidth drops from something
really high say 12 gigabits per second
down to 12 megabits per second which is
from a thousand packets per millisecond
on a one packet or a millisecond and of
course that's a big drop so in the first
right after that bandwidth drops if
we're continuing at the same rate there
will likely be very high packet loss and
there's an interesting idea though about
the low delivery rate that we see there
of two packets in their own trip time it
was a question of to what extent is that
due to with the lack of data that was
sent to extent it was due to bursty
traffic that may have caused that loss
or or it could be a sustained reduction
in the bandwidth available to that flow
so the question is how do we what do we
do there so the philosophy here the
design philosophy here is that to fully
utilize bottlenecks of all kinds
including the bottlenecks with shallow
buffers we want to adapt both the
maximum sending rate and the maximum
in-flight meal ow so in this example
should we have simply cut the Sealand
right down to to do to only two packets
being delivered
well it's interesting to consider that
if we actually find a way to pace at the
available bandwidth we can actually
deliver far more than two packets per
round trip time so the idea here is that
if if this last pattern or something
like it continues repeatedly we
basically want to gradually reduce the
sending way down to match the available
bandwidth and to try to converge to an
in-flight that matches the BGP so that
we can send the entire response without
anything being dropped that's the the
basic motivating idea so what does the
algorithm look like for the short term
model adaptation basically this this
strategy at a high level is to gradually
adapt as I said to to measure delivery
process which includes both the
bandwidth and the volume of data and
this adaptation applies generally
whether we're in fast recovery RTO
recovery not in recovery at all whether
application limited or not and the basic
idea is to maintain a very recent
estimate of the delivery process both
the rate and the volume of data and then
upon in once per round trip time make an
adjustment in those two model parameters
that is a multiplicative cut by 30%
someone like cubic except the the twist
here is that we try not to cut the model
parameters below the most recently
observed delivery process
values so that we try not to overreact
and try to match the recent or converged
on to in the recent delivery process so
that's a basic idea so if we so that's
the the model and how that evolves if we
switch over to the state machine at a
higher level the state machine is quite
similar to the v1 we're alternating
essentially between probing for
bandwidth and round-trip time when the
connection is warming up we have a
startup phase it's a lot like slow start
once the path we think is full we try to
drain the queue and then we alternate
between probing for bandwidth and
program for round-trip time so just to
quickly go through an example life cycle
of a a B B RB - flow here I'll try to
highlight an in bold the stuff that's
new and v2 versus v1 and this order this
may seem similar if you recall the
presentation from last July but I
thought it would be useful just to run
through it quickly again so a flow
starts out in start-up which like the
traditional slow start phase we're
trying to rapidly discover the available
bandwidth by doubling the sending radio
from a trip time until we see that it
looks like the path is full neither
because bandwidth samples are plateauing
or the loss or ecn mark rate becomes too
high when we think we fill the pipe then
we try to drain it draining that queue
and also if if we've seen ecn or less
marks that indicate that we've bumped up
against some queue level then we try to
leave some Headroom as well then we try
to spend most of our time in a phase
that you can think of as sort of a
cruising where we're trying to maintain
a low in-flight and adapting
continuously every round-trip time to
whatever loss and ecn signals that we
see based on the algorithm I just
described and then when we decide it's
time to probe for bandwidth first we try
to refill the the pipe by sending out
exactly the estimated bandwidth so
hopefully we would reform the pipe
without creating an EQ for doing well
and then we proceeded into a phase where
we're raising in flight to a level that
may indeed be likely to be creating some
kind of queue and we we don't know
whether that's a shallow buffer they
were dealing with or a deep one so we
started all cautiously with a one extra
packet in flight and then progressed to
exponentially higher amounts as we were
able to grow and fly without causing the
ECM mark rate or the loss rate to go
above the design SLO thresholds and then
once we do see some indication that we
filled the path either because we were
able to we apparently created a queue by
having in-flight reach some multiple of
the BDP or we hit ecn or less signals
then we try to drain the queue that
we've created and leave some unused
Headroom again if we saw a loss or or
ECM so that's the basic life cycle of a
BPM flow into summarize i can sort of
run through a quick comparison of reno
and cubic and PRP - so reno has this
sort of familiar sawtooth pattern with
putting an additional packet in-flight
every round-trip time until the
experience is any packet loss at all and
that responds to a me a level of packet
loss at all means it has sort of a
brittle loss response because the c1
increases are linear one packet per
round trip time it needs a long time to
fill a pipe so it needs a thousand times
more time to reach a thousand times
higher bandwidth which means for example
to fill a 10 gigabit hundred millisecond
path you mean more than an hour between
any sort of packet loss at all which
means you need a very very little packet
loss rate of two times 10 to the minus
10 which is not really achievable in
practice so people came up with cubic
which has a more scalable growth curve
using a cubic in cruise
function but it's still not as scalable
as we'd like
so you still need since it's a cubic
function
you still need ten times more time if
you want to reach a thousand times
higher bandwidth and so for example if
you have a 10 gigabit link with that I
thought 100 millisecond trip time you
need more than 40 seconds without any
packet loss whatsoever
so the still you need to further
illustrate of sort of one packet in 30
million so BRB to what we're trying to
achieve is more a more lost
tolerant design with a more scalable
growth function and also to to leave
more Headroom in in the steady state
then cubic does so the idea here is that
we try to have a scalable exponential
growth so that you can utilize nearly
available bandwidth in logarithmic time
and you because of the last times you
can fully utilize a in a big beauty
piece that even with a certain amount of
loss in every round determined by the
design parameter that's the lost Thresh
and this is a picture of a shallow
buffer a case where we do run into
packet loss if there is a deeper buffer
then we wouldn't even be running into
that Pecola's so quick status overview
the BRB one is running for most traffic
on Google and YouTube and backbone but
we are experimenting aprv - on YouTube
there there's some links there to other
documents that we've talked about before
and in conclusion were actively focused
on PBR v2 and making improvements there
including reducing pressure improving
coexistence with you know in cubic
there's also work going on on bbr for
FreeBSD TCP at the Netflix or in close
communication with their excellent team
and as always we're happy to see patches
here test results
look at packet traces we encourage
people to offer ideas about the
algorithm edits for the internet drafts
typos but fixes what do we have we're
happy to hear it
thank you very much I kill me only we
have about seven minutes for questions
and jabber scribe and Dave tat asks have
you tried the existing RFC three one six
eight compliant FQ color response we
have not experimented with that and in
the Google in the EB our Google version
the PBR TCP or quick no we are bigger
believers in a direction where ECM is
more like in DC TCP or l4 s where
there's an easy on response when that
happens at lower Q levels and where the
sender has a more graduated proportional
response to the EC onward we leave in
that direction is a is a good direction
to go okay I have two more from jabber
and then I'll drop back and Mario Hawk
asks which mechanism achieves a
convergence to fairness among multiple
bbrt vt2 flows yes so it's it's gonna
depend on whether we're running into a
buffer limit or not so if it's if it's
running into you an EC N or loss buffer
limit and setting implied high the
fairness is achieved by the
multiplicative decrease which leaves
that Headroom and the amount of headroom
that's left is proportional to the two
they imply hard the flow so bigger flows
have are leaning more Headroom it's very
similar to the convergence dynamics of
Moreno or cubic because of that
multiplicative decrease effect if
there's no buffer limit that's being run
into you then the convergence happens
because of the dynamics of the the way
that bandwidth probing works and the
it's a little more subtle and we can
cover it offline for anyone who's
interested in details but basically
smaller flows when they probe for
bandwidth variable they're
multiplicative increase makes a larger
proportional increase in their delivered
bandwidth than the proportional increase
that higher bandwidth flow sees when it
probes I can run through the details
offline or over email if people are
curious okay and then John border asks
is there something that can be done in a
browser to always get a bbr response
from YouTube no although from YouTube
you're early you're always going to get
a PBR of some flavor you know mostly p1
sometimes me too if you're randomly
selected hidden from buffer so green
face has changed now we are not draining
all the way as in we are not bringing
sending rate down to four packets but we
are at much higher rate now so I thought
the idea was to get main RTD out of it
right so that's the the property T face
there yeah instead of going down to four
packets then on to half of the BP the
intuition there is that at a high level
to first approximation if you can keep
exactly the bdp in flight then that will
give you an empty queue so if you if you
happen to know exactly the bandwidth
then exactly the the RTT then if you
pull it down to one bt p you'll get an
empty queue since you don't always know
exactly your available bandwidth and the
real underlying to a propagation aliy we
cut it down to half to give ourselves
the ability to gradually converge down
to everybody seeing that to a
propagation delay but the basic answer
to your question is that once the amount
of data in flight is less than the bt p
at any level then in theory you have the
ability to see that to a propagation
delay okay and I guess between 4 and 50%
big the rationale to get 50% is because
we are almost doubling is that the in
the start of phase what's there it's not
really related it's it's more question
of how far do we need to pull down the
in flight
be able to converge given that when the
flow start out there maybe there might
be quite a bit of queue and people might
not really have a good estimate of the
tool propagation delay so when they try
to estimate the BGP that estimate is not
gonna be perfect either so cutting to
half of something that's more than two
times bigger than a water that will be
is not going to give you a good answer
so there's some amount you need to pull
down to sort of compensate for the over
estimate so that you can gradually
converge downward the 50% came out to be
a good based on your based on my desk
yeah thanks pretty Microsoft so I have a
question about their target last rates
that you talked about yeah so you know
mentioned the numbers are you telling
them definitely for different workloads
or right I think this is it's gonna be
subject to tuning and for their research
and discussions for this particular
iteration of BB r b2 we're targeting a
loss rate around 1% so currently the
threshold at which it backs off is a 2%
loss rate in that measured round-trip
time so that the overall net effect
since a given flow is only going to be
probing for some fraction of the time
isn't much lower than 2% but that's the
basic dynamic is where we're setting the
max at 2% to try to achieve an overall
average well below 1% oh so if I
understand this correctly so there's no
immediate reaction the reaction is based
on the rate over a period of time
there's a once per round trip time
reaction to easier than or loss yeah now
I have a follow-up question to the 50%
so to measure the RTT it's really
because we have one or two minutes left
and we have this really quick ok so 50%
of bdp or 50% of the current sending
rate 50% of their estimate a PDP just
for folks in the line I'm gonna the line
now
and please keep it quick I'm happy to
talk after the ICC ochi session to
mother insula I was curious about dais
in the TCP style
Sen mechanism are you negotiating or
extradition how you're getting your
feedback right now we have internal to
Google we already have a private
negotiation mechanism and we're happy to
work with people on the public efforts
to negotiate a DC TCP style mechanism
such as l4s something like that right
now internally we have our own
negotiation mechanism and externally on
the public internet since there isn't a
lot of standard we're not using it yeah
the next public internet okay thank you
hey Jake Holland I was wondering about
the probe bandwidth I think you said it
responds to less and ECM version think I
heard you mention our tter your source
money to increase the GT yeah I forgot
to mention that yeah so talking image in
slide better Francis but basically as
before with PBR if we essentially see an
increase in our TT but more specifically
if we see a what looks like an inflight
that is basically one point two five
times the estimated VDP then we've
estimate that we have enough of a cue
that we've probed enough and it's time
to drain and and move on Andrew Berger I
have I have a pretty good idea how you
would do this inside Google and that you
would but I on the public Internet would
you be proposing to sit the ECM and loss
right targets as a function of the safe
code point that you're sending up I
don't know about diffserv code points
yeah I don't know we could talk about
that offline and if you haven't thought
about doing them on Google's backbones
you really should because that would fix
some things
Jonathan Morton here and I don't know if
you saw the some congestion you
experienced or come on Monday so
but do you think an SEM being would be a
useful mechanism for improving conduct
the ecn fidelity in terms of PBR I think
it would be better than no ecn style
signal at all yeah I think anything and
he my guess is any form of ECM signal
that gives you a fine grain picture that
sort of more than you know one bit per
round trip time I think any sort of more
detailed easy on signal I think would be
useful and yeah okay I'm sure you can
discuss this to more detail later yeah
absolutely
thank you thank you so much meal and
please find Neil outside for more
discussion and hopefully we'll hear more
about the results of your BRE to
experiment perhaps on the list as soon
as you have something to share
thank you so much and now we move on to
payment take it away
hi everyone my name is payment area and
I'll be talking about how to make easier
and more useful so let's see how first
I'll discuss about ASEAN you already
know about this but just a short
introduction about the issues that we
see I'm using is Ian and then the
network utility maximization framework
and how we use this framework and some
simulation results and the model
validation and the benefits that we get
from this and we will discuss some
applications and the advantages of using
ECM in this framework and I'll conclude
my presentation after that so you
already know about the ASEAN and how
this is TCP uses ecn based on and
instantaneous cue that marks PAC is
above threshold and it interprets a like
in my marking probability per article
and based on this probability it cuts
the window congestion window it doesn't
have the window as in TCP but it has a
bit less than TCP and like oscillates
more but in a shorter scale this is how
it case its benefits but about the
issues with the ECM if we interpret it
as a one bit information so there's no
problem with normally seeing how it is
defined in this RFC rather we only get
one signal peralta t so it's like too
little and too long but if we use DCT
CPU style marking so it for example in
VC TCP says that if the marking
probability is low it diminishes the
usefulness of ecn and also it's useful
only when it deals with a packet
dropping not just marking so it's better
to keep it a bit higher and get a better
signal out of the network about how much
it is congested so it's better to use a
higher marking probability in the
network but the problem is that this is
not an additive measure is
multiplicative and also it has problems
with using in the theory like the non
theory because the theory works with an
additive cost or additive signal with
the network so has a short overview of
the theory never utility maximization
deals with solving a rate allocation
problem based on some constraints in the
network so the goal is to maximize like
social welfare in the network subject to
some constraints and in the simplest
case these constraints are link
capacities you don't want to exceed link
capacities but we want to increase the
send rate of each source as much as we
can until everybody is happy so this is
how this maximization problem is defined
so in this case
you are is a utility function of each
sender or source are this utility
function represents the happiness each
source has or how much happy each source
is by sending for example a trait XR and
Link capacities which are denoted by CL
here the crossing traffic on each link
which is denoted by Y L shouldn't exceed
the link capacity so this is the
simplest case that you can represent
this rate allocation problem but what
happens if we use easy and with this
theory the problem is that if we have
higher marking probabilities as we have
for example in data center TCP and the
plot on the right side shows that the
data center TCP with different VDP can
it can reach to higher marking
probabilities we have the problem on the
plot on the left the two equations here
we plotted the deviation that these two
have the deviation shows that if the
marking probability in the network
increases the deviation is larger so we
have like an estimate bias that should
be removed and the theory because it
here it works only with Sigma but the
signal that we get from the network is
the first one which is multiplicative it
only works if the marking probability in
the network is much lower than one is
for example close to point zero five
point zero four or some numbers in that
range not higher but we see that in data
centers basically as shown in the right
plot which is plotted by some equation
about the theoretical marking property
with one button neck link and the number
of competing flows we see that is at
least around
find sixteen or cross the point if
that's a problem that we see with a
using ECM that we cannot use a higher
marking probabilities
although they are useful in the network
so what we did is that we turn a scene
into an additive signal actually with
david etherion somehow was extended to
adopt this and we used red because we
wanted to have a deployable solution not
something which is hard to be deployed
and it's just a matter of configuring
red in commodity hardware and as benefit
that we get faster convergence because
with higher marking probabilities as we
will show in the rest of the
presentation we see that we have a
faster convergence because we get more
signals from the network is a more
fine-tuned signal it's not just zero
zero zero and then after a while one as
a signal which is which shows that the
network is congested so if we get more
fine-tuned signal then you can have a
faster convergence and it could be used
actually to have an earlier feedback
with visual cues and we probably can my
start we can start marking packers even
below the capacity ah let's keep the
theory so just as to show how it looks
like the cake there are there's a
theorem on a solving a maximization or
optimization problems with some
constraints is called KKT theorem the
first condition here is the original
theory theorem which is how it works it
has two variables here mu I and lambda J
what we did was that we change these
with two functions here F
P I and KVJ so it has some proof that he
could find in the technical report that
I cited on the first slide and as the
function that we incorporated in the
theorem we use this function which is a
logarithmic function and we we derive a
new Lagrangian function which is the
base for deriving three types of
algorithms of primal dual and primal
dual depending on how we divide the
controller between sources or the
network as a simplest case we used red
as we talked about we use red as the
dual algorithm so the algorithm is on
the top it shows that the current
marking probability the prop marking
probability at a time step n or
iteration n is the backlog the current
backlog divided by some maximum
threshold so so and it's a limited to
the range 0 to 1 because marking
probability shouldn't be larger than 1
so how we can achieved it is easy but
just configuring red so we set a mean
threshold to 1 max threshold to should
be actually larger than some number
which is derived by stability proof in
the attack in the report for example how
to have a notion of this number if in a
scenario that we simulated we had a bdp
close through 1.7 megabytes and in this
case alpha is some bound on some
function of the second derivative of the
utility function l is the maximum path
length in the network and s is the
maximum number of competing flows so in
that case we had max threshold
larger than we or equal to 1.3 megabyte
but what we did in the simulation was
that we set this number to smaller value
but we didn't observe any instability
and also the average queue size in that
case was around 75 kilobytes much lower
than BBP gah so set the max p21 because
we wanted to use the whole range of
marking probabilities from 0 to 1 and
also WQ to want to have instantaneous q
marking we didn't do this like
exponential smoothing and the queue size
so this could be achieved by just
configuring reading commodity hardware
and as one of the actually benefits of
doing this and using that function that
we showed before is that we could remove
the bias that higher marking
probabilities has on the actually the
rate that each flow gets for example in
this case we have a like a partner
topology we have a number of 5 have
flows competing with a number of 1/2
flows like cross traffic so N 1 and n 2
we did a simple simulation the data
center TCP we actually instead of the
entrant marking probability that beta
Center TCP works means we use this
function so we see that in the
simulation the rate actually that each
flows gets five hot flows divided by the
rate that 1/2 flowers get actual ratio
doesn't change as the number of file
have flows increase this means that as
the number of fellow flows increase we
have a higher and higher marking
probabilities but it doesn't effect
the behavior of the controller so that's
the good point about the theory and we
derive some other optimization algorithm
the first one is a primal one is similar
to the one that Kelly had in his paper
but as you if you remember we have a
different cost here which is a
logarithmic function based on the
marking probability that we get into an
marking probability but in Kelly's
algorithm it's just cost and also to two
different dual algorithm but they need
actually implementation in routers
probably people might say that they're
not they cannot be deployed but to have
a phone set of algorithms we derive
these as well and also a combination of
these that you could have to have primal
dual algorithms so we validated all of
these algorithms algorithms here with a
utility function as this function as one
of the properties of this function we
should have actually proportional
fairness so in this case five hub flows
across five hops it means that the rate
should be one-fifth of the one hop flows
so the left plot is a numerical
evaluation with Mathematica
we see that the line below the purple
one is exactly 0.2 it shows that for
every number of crossing every number of
fire one of flows it means that this
ratio the theory doesn't have is not
affected by the number of computing
flows and also the marking probability
so it means that this you were
successful in coping with this easy and
usage problem
but if we don't use that you see that as
the number of flows increases we have
more and more deviation with this rate
ratio and the right plot is simulation
with omelet and we see that they're
pretty close to point to some
applications we actually can obtain
utility function of controllers when
demarking poverty is not low so as one
of the benefits of this but in the
literature probably you have seen that
this is approximated by some of the
marking probabilities and conditioned on
being the marking on the marking
probability being low but in this case
with this theorem we can use this to
obtain marking obtain the utility
function of the controllers with higher
marking probabilities and also we can
inflate deflate marking probability we
can play with it and by marking property
I mean the equilibrium marking
probability because there is a base in
the lock function fee and we can play
with this to have different marking
probabilities in equilibrium so just
also useful and you are not obliged to
have fixed mark in poverty depending
depending on the behavior of your
controller but you can have different
ones and we can see in the next slide
the benefits of playing with this and
also the potential to deal with virtual
queues they have two scenarios here they
have a high you have a link with one
gigabit per second bandwidth and also a
limited link on the left - plucks the
studio stage shorten furnace we see that
as we increase the space parameter to
get higher and higher marking
probabilities in the network the flow
flows behave smoothly on a smoother and
also then if new flow joins because we
get more marks from the network is like
a more fine-tuned and more signals
received from the network we have a
faster convergence rate and also on the
left side we limited the bandwidth to
see how much we can increase the
marketing poverty and does the theory
work with this or not you see that it
works up to for example point nine nine
marking probability but we see that
because that's like in this case you get
all the ones from the network at some
and at some time we get one is zero then
we lose some benefits from it so it's
better to have a high marking poverty
not so high and not so low low so that's
the benefit that we can get by playing
and increasing fee not too much to have
a like a marking probability in the
middle of this range but although it can
work with low and high marking
probabilities to conclude we try to
improve easy aim to avoid an estranged
we didn't want to limit the range to be
too low or maybe too high because model
controllers like it isn't a TCB and as i
just about PBR v2 because they use this
easy and DCT CPA style ECM like method
they can have a higher marking
probabilities and it's good to play with
it to have faster convergence or a
smoother behavior and get more signals
from the network about the congestion
and also the possibility of marking even
below the cue the capacity and as Nexus
steps we will focus on experiments
it was the American evaluation of
simulations and are some deployment
issues of this method thank you hey Jake
how could you go back to slides real
quick - one more yeah
what are those error bars is that like
variants across experiments within a
window or what 10 different line runs
the lines are the average and the error
was the minimum and maximum okay thank
you hello again existing acnd polymers
use the yellow marking probabilities as
DC tcp stone marking has its own
probability problems with deployment I
think but what if you think about an SCE
some congestion experienced using the
extra code point I mean using ECT one
isn't of Ziyi because I think that's a
way of getting the higher marking
probabilities that you rely on here
without breaking compatibility with
existing gp's yes actually the theory
just this theory just says that if you
if we have higher marking probabilities
so it doesn't matter if if you get it
from a DCT C psi aq mignonette or if
it's from something else as long as you
have a higher marking policy you can use
this oh we have some prototype code
which produces the SCE marking using the
DCT CP style of of trigger so we have we
can have a ramp function over a small
range of Q depth
yeah for example or a threshold function
that's a particular queue depth and I
think that's what do you see gcp style
thing it is what you have in mind
hmm yeah yeah I think you can apply this
theory on what you already said it
doesn't matter if is only TCPS style or
something else but we only test that
this with PCT cps I'm working but they
believe that it works that case as well
yeah I mean I think it's just something
to bear in mind with your plant
experiments yeah I Bob Brisco I just
posted a mine on the list pointing to
another way to get your additive
property with that within the number
space 0 to 1 by essentially you instead
of altering them love the network you
alter the end systems do you transform
the number space from P to P divided by
one minus P and then
so it's essentially taking the instead
of the number of marks divided by the
total it's the number of marks divided
by the number of unlocks and then it
transforms the whole space and you get
your additive property in a transformed
number space so the marking parity is
the same the same as the very
sophisticated
computes it is exponentially not just a
function you mean you when when you're
reading in the marks yes you just
calculate the fraction differently you
don't you don't use the total number of
packets use the total number of unmarked
packets and then you then you sort of
compress the numbers base into 0 1 the
your relative number space yes it's like
something like any more questions
Michael is not a question of
clarification I'm not sure if that was a
misunderstanding like that but just to
be very clear this calculations done in
the end system also the way it was
presented is done in December so it's
just a regular read with this slightly
weird configuration but other than that
everything is calculated in the sender
already in that so I said yeah thank you
well thank you so much Foreman thank you
who's up next Bob you're up next this
was going to be your team giving an
update on place chirping but he's felt
fell ill and had to go home so I'm gonna
give an update on the implementation
status of T Prague yep thank you and
just for those I actually don't think we
need this given the last three tours I
mean about this but essentially the DC
TCP style is the where we're trying to
get to with more tiniest salty so you
get a high utilization and low queuing
delay just a quick update on the
implementation implementation status of
all the bits of l4s and in fact I guess
we could say that or I've just heard
about VBR v2 I was I was hoping that I
wouldn't have to do the fallback part of
TCP prog to deal with all the lost stuff
it seems like we're very much converging
on all having the same pieces with maybe
I'll be to using the decent piece of
East our bit for the up for the when it
has got a CN and so it looks like that
you could call that an implementation as
well but I don't want to
co-opt it without looking at it further
but anyway so as now Linux
implementation of the network part
there's a TCP prog implementation a
quick prog implementation an
implementation of the real-time adaptive
screen throw 4s and all the bits of
creation as well which anyone can use
separately from l4s so and in particular
just wanted to make people aware of an
announcement I made in the transport
area working group that
DOCSIS 3.1 will support this DC TCP
style is t1 behavior as part of the new
specs that were released in January with
an feel for s support and the there's
also reduction in the requests grant
lived in the Mac but that's not really
why sue crg what I want to talk about
here is how the internals of TCP prog
and what we've been doing on that it's
based on they descent a TCP so if you
know that you know in good shape and
there's just a few deltas
there's the URLs for testing it and how
to enable it it's now ported up to the
tip of the ministry and what I want to
talk about today is all the parts we've
had to add to DC TCP to meet the what we
call the Prague l4s requirements that
were agreed in it here in Prague in July
2015 and we've renamed them from the TCP
prog requirements because they're not
just for TCP so we have now an
implementation of this congestion
control in quick it's very early days I
mean there's only built on Saturday so
but it's it took a day and a half to
build you know is it most of it was
already there it was just too changed
and very small change to the Reno
algorithm which is good news for quick
if you like you know but it's it's easy
to do these things assuming it works
that is that or assuming it works once
it's been fully tested I should say it's
been tested a little here these are
these are all those for us prog
requirements and where we are with the
implementation of them I'm not going to
go through this right now cuz I've got
it again at the end I just wanted to say
this is where we're trying to get to in
this presentation and and your what you
will see though is that about half of
the requirements are met by altering the
base TCP stack in Linux and a good half
of the remainder in other words a
quarter back portable if you like to DC
TCP as well but that's up to the DC TTP
maintain is obviously so I am gonna skip
this slide I had it hidden but I guess
this is the PDF set I didn't realize
that was going to happen the just just
because otherwise it's going to take too
long and I'm nearly gonna skip this
slide except to say that the accurate
easy an implementation there's one
little extra bit on the bottom there
which were added to the Linux version
for testing which allows you to force
the other end to give you fine-grained
feedback even if it doesn't support our
ATM so if it's a classic ecn receiver we
can we can certainly for testing I'm not
sure I'd advise this for production but
it essentially since cwr all the time to
the other end which means that whenever
it doesn t see any market then
immediately turns itself off so you
don't get a whole whole round-trip time
and also it's a test for a bug in bsd as
well before it does that which would
otherwise give you no marks at all so
moving on
fall back now I need to make it clear
but fall back on loss this this is what
I would say would satisfy a RFC 56 81
zealot so this is this is if you want to
keep absolutely through the RFC's that's
what we do
I'd like to fall back to something more
like baby are as just described and I
think now you could think of the two as
synonymous depending on well maybe I was
lost the the answers to praveen's
question I'd like to hear about but
anyway moving on the the full-back on
lost to be 58 681 compliant what we
realized is that well partly four years
ago we realized that there was a bug in
Linux but didn't fall back at all in the
DC tcp linux unless you had a time-out
but if you had a reach fast retransmit
it didn't even notice it we patched that
two years ago but it didn't go through
so we've patched it again and we've
certainly patched it in TCP prog but
what we want to do for the future is at
least not overreact by having and also
having an ACN response so the idea is to
as you can see in yeah as you can see
here the the ecn and the loss response
is a fairly independent so you've got
the sort of a WMA being calculated this
thing called alpha is the calculation of
the weighted moving average of the ecn
signal in DC TCP and that carries all
independently and if there's a loss you
sort of get a round of dealing with that
loss and then when it comes back alpha
is carrying on without having been
affected by it which is different from
how that cannot code it and the other
thing is we've reduced the amount of
loss so that when it's compounded with
you matter reduction
for the ACN they come to a half rather
than doing to reductions in for both
signals which is what you see there
let's move on because that's more in the
fifties excited one well right the next
one which probably more relates to what
Jonathan Morton was talking about fall
back to Reno friendly on classic ACN
it's the next requirement and
essentially you've got this this flow
diagram over here where if you get a
nice en mark is it from first of all is
it from a l4s aqm or a classic aqm and
if it's a classic aqm is it of fq 1 or
501 it's an F Q 1 you'll it is
protecting every everyone else from you
anyway so you don't have to fall back to
the Reno behavior because you're you
know you're in your own queue so the
only case we really need to worry about
is this 501 here and on all the or in
all these studies from the academic
world including our own and I'll call
that academic because I was in similar
at the time the ACN marking level found
on the internet seem to be virtually
near zero and in fact I think the latest
one that's unpublished at Brian Trammell
told me the other a couple of days ago I
think he found 13 C marks 16 right
however I've got a I've got a suspicion
that all those studies are wrong because
because they're not they're not they're
active studies they're sending traffic
that isn't big enough to congested yeah
to congest the links are only finding
the background level when they send
traffic or as the Apple data is looking
at the traffic all the time it's passive
and so they're much more likely to find
cases when it becomes congested this is
a picture of a slide from Padma boomer
from March 2017
this black one which showed that they
were seeing some CE Marking in certain
countries and particularly the Argentine
Republic 30% but when you just look at
that figure that 30% marking motive but
it's not it's 30% of Apple devices or at
least one mark in 12 hours all right so
that's that's not saying it's 30%
marking and Padma says that that was
that was the signature of that traffic
looked like ecn marking like what it
wasn't just something that was maybe
diffserv mangling or s to it but it was
mainly seen on the uplink and we haven't
got any data yet to dig into that find
out whether mainly means nearly always
and possibly when it was on the downlink
it may have been marked on the uplink
from someone else you know like a
peer-to-peer flow so because then that
determines whether we're in the always
in the FQ side of this flow diagram here
and therefore there there isn't a need
to deal with this FIFO case or whether
our actually maybe someone's turned on
some old Cisco Reuters with a FIFO queue
and ecn red or something like that so
that's that one that was also a hidden
slide all right this is a copy of slide
I showed in the echo I'm working group
when it existed to show that when you
remove the cue from you know when you
have such a small Q because you've dealt
with it using a qm + DC tcp style
congestion control you actually get a
situation where you you start hitting
TTP's minimum window of 2
which is built into the specs and the
code because you lose the out clock if
you go any lower than that and as you
can see from this just five flows in
this region here this this block shows
the range of possible capacities in the
range of possible round-trip times and
typical broadband is in this range and
typical datacenter is here and anything
below the line between red and green
there is potentially in a ceiling less
than 2 so effectively what happens in
those regions is when you've we've not
got a Q TCP can't go below 2 so it's
effectively become unresponsive because
the aqm is turning it go lower and it's
saying okay I'll go lower and now I ran
back up to 2 and then it forces the Q to
build because it's not going lower and
so it forces a larger round-trip time by
forcing a queue even though the ATM is
telling it not to so we we wanted to try
and solve that problem by fixing TCP so
that it can go below 2 and can go below
1 and so far managed to do it for Reno
we're still got a synchronization
problem when we do it with DT TCP that
were trying to fix but this is this is
with Reno and its user spacing you sort
of have to if you're lost you're out
o'clock you have to send a packet less
often than you're getting ax back so you
can't use that clock and we use a rather
than as if increase of one the other so
the other problem we've got is that when
you go below 2 or 1 as your congestion
window if you still use an additive
increase of 1 you're aiming at say and
1/2 1/2 a segment that you keep adding 1
+ and so the additive increase is too
great for the thing you're trying to aim
for so
got this sort of scaling every time you
change ssthresh
you change the constant that you add for
the for that until your next change
ssthresh so it's sort of like an
additive increase but not a constant
additive increase you modify the
constant depending on what region you're
in and anyway you can see it's it's
working on the right ear here you've got
all the congestion windows of a number
of flows and the the right-hand side
gives you the the congestion window in
segments the left in bytes so you can
see you're you're working below the two
segments previous limit it's working
very well but as I say we haven't yet
got it working with DC TCP and it's
something to do with the way we're doing
the WMA which also has to be adjusted
for it's calculated every round-trip
time but we're not getting a packet
every round-trip time because you're
sending your aunt returned so small
you're sending less packets packets less
often than your round-trip time and so
we have to do the calculation of the
value may adjust it for the every time
we get an event of a act coming in and
something's something's not right about
it at the moment anyway I won't go into
that here because I don't need you to
debug problems and what's going to jump
over that right the other aspect of TCP
Prague we wanted to do is make it before
better this is now there's three slides
on better performance first one is to be
able to send a TT on the control packets
particularly the syn and there's a draft
in the ITF to do that and we've
implemented that if you well actually no
DC TCP implements that already the issue
I want to raise here is that when you do
that on the public Internet we found
from a measurement study that 84% of
servers turn off ACN when you send them
a syn with ACN on
which didn't help much and what I mean
there is that normally ecn is
negotiators at the TCP level if it's TCP
but if we set a CT in the IP header
while we're trying to negotiate it in
TCP it turns off ecn for the rest of the
connection we traced back to a patch
that was put into the Linux servers and
I understand it's not in Windows which
is good and that probably explains the
84 percent that patch was put in in 2012
and we have submitted a patch on that
patch to make it specific only to our
Circe 3168 sins so if you're sending an
accurate ecn sin with ECT on the code
point the the install base of lyric
service will not turn off ecn anymore
once that patch has been back ported
it's a one-line patch so I'm hoping
it'll back port fairly widely and that
is actually the patch basically we're
just checking more of the TCP flag bits
than I can't be tested in the patch in
the previous patch of the patch of the
patch tests for the zeros as well right
finally the that was a talk on paste
chirping to get up to speed faster
that's particularly relevant when you're
using TC tcp/ip style feedback because
and and decent tcp style marking when
you've got such a shallow threshold it's
really difficult to get your slow start
under the threshold because you know
just a few packets and you can hit the
threshold get a nice ian mark and then
you you pop out of slow start now you
could just say well let's start
averaging the ecn but you don't know
what sort of e Sienna is and you don't
know whether the years ec n is coming
from the same bottleneck as where you're
getting delay from so we use only delay
and one of the extra bits we've done
since last time so I've just gone back
so we got very fast startup without
overshoot for the initial slow start or
slow start after idle we've been
thinking well how can we implement that
when you in the middle of a flow
suddenly want to jump up to a new amount
of capacity so say up your two flows in
a link the other flow starts and
normally hoobat takes quite a long time
to get out and in fact typically cubic
will take hundreds hundreds of
round-trip times before it attains that
new capacity if it's in the middle of
congestion avoidance and so what we do
we use the property of DT TCP that was
on the previous slide and I will go back
to it but you get a regular frequent
amount of marking with DC TCP unlike
something like cubic and so you can tell
when it stops very quickly it's like you
know if you're beating on the head every
two years it takes many years before you
realize someone stopped beating on the
head but if you're beating on the head
every few seconds you know when it
stopped within a few seconds and so in
this case took off a capacity limit this
was a simulation and this was because yo
Keem became ill so I've had to go back
to his last simulations just took off
the capacity limit as if a flow was
leaving and you can see DT TTP because
it's got the additive increase takes
what's that 60 seconds so that's 600
round-trip times cubic takes 150
15 seconds 150 round-trip times ignore
the pic and the one modified B post
chirping gets up
in seven minutes seven round-trip times
and the queuing delay is still under one
millisecond there whereas the cubic even
though it takes a lot longer is 150
round-trip times but it causes 20
milliseconds of overshoot so much faster
to get get up there and much less
overshoot all right
but this is research I'm not saying this
is production ready because it's got a
it's got to work in Wi-Fi environment in
all weather this is all fixed Ethernet
so but it looks very promising
all right so coming back to this slide
that summarizes everything we've got
some a few bits and pieces now in the
mainline kernel although most of them a
large part of the parts of TCP Prague
were already there and it was just
really a sort of mandatory configuration
of all the bits so the dark green parts
if your red green caliber and so sorry
if your red green colorblind the the
bold ones are for the green ones there
in the main line already
this is Linux the the one I mentioned
about scaling down to a window below low
to is you know is it's in progress we
out that code is not quite ready to
release yet so that's in a sort of
private repository the reducing rtd
dependence we've presented here before
still we've only simulated that we
haven't put that all it into the
framework and this is the one I
mentioned where we're still wanting to
see whether Apple data shows us anything
that means that we may not have to do
that because that's just going to make
things unnecessarily complicated in the
in the code if it's not actually needed
so
that is all just a quick one on
performance
I showed this in TS vwg but I'll show it
again
here we go for time okay this is the
last slide
yeah rodique notes left here umm yeah
what six to eight minutes left gives a
bit of question time so this shows a
complementary C complementary cumulative
distribution function with a log scale
so you can get CV very low yeah very low
levels of queuing delay it at the higher
percentiles so the five nines
percentiles here the reason for that is
we want to be able to have real time
media in this in this queue it's
essentially a FIFO queue so we this is
showing all the traffic in that queue
and what it does with the the DCTC p1 is
that blue one these are all paired so
like the jewel pi/2 is the blue and red
one the fq coddle is the green and
purple one and the pi is the and so all
of this traffic isn't there at once you
know it for the jewel pi/2 those two are
together for the fq coddle there's those
two are together and for the 2 pi ones
those two are together because you can't
have more than one ATM in a queue at the
same time so it's overlaid just for
comparison and the interesting thing is
that the the classic queue of the of the
l4 s the with cubic in it is roughly a
similar performance as all the other
what you might call second-generation
ATMs in over the pi e fq coddle so we're
doing no harm to existing traffic and
then the l4 s queue
at the median you've got one one to two
hundred microseconds which is confirmed
by what Neil showed he was getting
similar queuing delay but I think yours
was an F Q system wasn't it yeah I was
it okay
Oh so when you say coddled you meant
coddled not fq coddled yeah oh cool
and 99 percentile one to two
milliseconds and so on up to eight many
seconds there but the important thing to
notice about this is this isn't just a
single flow this is 300 web flows per
second hammering this thing it's 120
make link and there's 300 per second in
the L for sq and 300 per second in the
classic Q plus 2 long running flows with
these various traffic characteristics so
this is showing exactly the same thing
that Neil explained really and this is
the sort of philosophy of both DC TCP
and now bbr v2 that essentially you're
you're keeping Headroom when you've got
a lot of traffic coming in and out and
DC TCP does that by its ewm a so it sees
the general background level of marking
and a long-running flow will get out the
way enough for all the small flows to
get in but if there aren't any short
flows or there aren't any slow starts
the longer running flow sort of pulls
itself back up and increases the
utilization to 100% so I think the
intuition for them both even though
maybe our v2 is a model-based 1 and d2
TCP is more a deterministic algorithm
well if I have to turn this tick that's
not it's not a good way to it I don't
quite know how to describe the
difference but they're there they're
essentially that I think the intuition
is the same
so that's cool I think we're starting to
converge so summary we've got very good
performance and TCP Prague and I you
know I'd be happy to fall back to if I
have a look at baby baby RV - if we can
maybe have a bit longer to look at it
maybe falling back to that is the way to
go or you could look at it alternatively
as BB rb2 uses DC TCP so it's pulling it
forward I mean it depends which side of
a fence you're on whether you're falling
over one side or the other cool is for
questions but Jabba FERS
harab and so Delta has three points from
Jabra and one is a very good assumption
that the see marks from France are due
to free door fr as enormous 3 million
plus deployment of FQ caudal across
their dsr subscriber lines - has no idea
about Argentina Oakland Doherty is big
there 3bb are currently caps congestion
window reductions to 4 on my green oh
and he says as 4.1 all someone looking
at the day it has to do is pour the IP
addresses relates to fruit IFRS BT pas
that's it yeah yeah and that's actually
the conclusion we're come to that we
need to look at the CDN so I'd rather
meet in system side to try and get this
data could you expand the status page
for the implementation so directly large
in units of time is that suggestion that
we only directed what I realized on that
is that the existing RAC implementation
as long as you pay space your initial
window that meets the requirement we
need its then effectively implicitly
working in time even though it's still
doing the 3do pack roll because the
packets are spaced in time
easy incapable TCP control packet so it
seems we default on for TCP yes sorry I
jumped over that slide because I forgot
to make that point
the reason it's it's default oh that's
that's just at the moment just because
we haven't written all the fallback code
and so until we've written all the
full-back code we'd rather have it off
and you manually turn it on if you want
to use it and then once we've written
the full back code we can make it
default on yeah hello guess what you
gotta talk about well it's it has to do
a successor qcn bottleneck of course
it'll say let's keep it quick though
cause you have only a minute okay
I'm mostly looking at your data saying
that's it that the ecn is there I'm
wondering now if that could be do
because really where are we I'm not
saying it's wrong I'm saying that the
data that said it was rare is wrong
uh-huh that the Apple data is the one
we've got to look at okay I'm cutting
the mic here and and let's let's go
through this Cosby basically optimal
under the next talk all right now you
can ask quick if you if you just very
simply I presume given that you're
working with cable labs that you've
looked at aggregating max I don't see
anything in the presentation about it it
would be nice to see that especially for
the Wi-Fi cases yes right okay that's a
large element of what we've been doing
about so one question so when the van
rack now and the latest iteration has
that rule in there
and the rate just goes high enough then
you're basically reducing shrinking a
reordering interval in time again not
not if you place your initial window or
your entre time but eventually the the
rate goes high enough when are you
you've got a certain amount of packets
pasted over a round-trip time when you
start that's all and then later on when
you get your reordering window sorted
out you're out hey okay yeah all right
thank you so much Bob and so let's say
you're up next so I'm still astonished
makes the research and I would like to
present multi time scale branded profile
its application for bursts of our
furnace so what is this whole thing
about we give a definition of fan as a
multiple time scales based on betrayed
measurements on multiple time scales and
we give an implementation we build on
core statuses or sharing solutions and
we only update the edge marking trees
like the time scales in the mark and we
show potential advantages and
characteristics it is based on fluid
simulations assuming easier congestion
control behavior so instantaneous
convergence basically but it's we don't
use the congestion control fairness
itself itself forced by the COS theta C
so sharing and we compare our results to
curate 300 mark at the TCM surface so
betrayed measurement and time scales bit
rate is a derived measure and you have
to translate this case packet arrivals
to bits right and it always it always
has to have a time scale associate is
basically volume divided by time and
there are natural time scales like
oddity like one second like some kind of
session duration session duration target
maybe one minute ten minutes
months most of the time today mainly TVs
used
OTT and the most again in fairness so
how can we have furnace a multiple time
scales when we measure a bit rate and we
measure betrayed when the source is
active we use it to describe performers
but we can measure between during both
active and inactive periods to judge the
fairness of the resource sharing
themselves so if you want to have some
kind
furnace and multiple time scales we can
balance the balance all the timescales
and consider all the time scales and we
can allow a higher share on shorter time
scales for flows know their fair share
in the longer time scales so you can you
can see there are two examples one we
have when we have the same fairness on
all time scales we have yellow flow and
blue flow and the yellow flow starts
beating for a longer time so naturally
when the blue phone is not transmitting
it to get the capacity so it it has five
tomorrow so long term but even in the
shortest time if they have one tomorrow
so sharing so D download of the blue for
flow takes quite some time but if you
take into account the history of the
brief blue sauce you can allocate higher
capacity to the blue source temporarily
and have improved stupid for the blue
flow while having basic the same sweet
boot for the ll flow if you if you
measure it for the holder of time so
what the score status is so sharing
there's an example for that this is per
packet value place core stateless is so
sharing say so
it's a framework which allows a wide
variety of detailed facts about policies
it enforces these policies for mobile
traffic mixes and scales around with the
number of flows there is we have quite
amount of publications about this but
shortly there is a packet marker in the
edge yeah so there is there is packet
marker in the edge and there are
resource notes in there in the cover of
the network and the packet marker
encodes all policy and actually flow
information into a single value mark
mark on each packet and the resource
node can base its behavior on the packet
marking only you don't have it has no
need for for what what the policies were
which flow is it or it doesn't need
separate queues but flow maybe it might
need separate queues per delay
requirement but definitely not per se so
you do the same thing if you are a
singer flow if you have only on flows
and there are very fast and simp simple
implementations
so the simplest course status marker is
pretty valid it's a two or a three color
marker there is actually a drop
eligibility bid which can be set to
false for four committed information
rate that is that is usually something
like guarantee traffic and there is an
amount of excess information rate
allowed it can be up to the link speed
and this these packets are allowed into
that word but we don't say anything
about guarantees at all the only thing
we do is that we hollow it into the
network and then it basically depends on
condition control aggressiveness for
example which which flow will get which
amount of capacity and of course we can
drop some packets there so how can we
extend it we can we can increase the
number of drop residences so instead of
having a single sierra and access
information read rate we can have more
rates and we can control the resource
sharing more along these writes some
corsica's proposals have here I can have
like hundreds of rate and have a really
well fire grained resource sharing among
flows but you can also increase the
number of timescales so you can have for
example if you take this bucket based
approach of TR TCM you can have more
buckets per drop precedence and in an
example I will use in the rest of the
presentation we increased the number of
the presidencies to four and we increase
the number of times cast before also so
this is the example we call it multi x
cabin with popeye profile mts DVP
so we have again for draw percy dances
and for timescales and there is a matrix
setting the rate parameters of this so
we have rates associated with all of
these token buckets and we have maximum
packet size is calculated from time
scales maximum packet size around the
time scale x by the rates it's actually
slightly more complex but it's this is
this formula is much better for
understanding this and how we decide
whether we can mark a packet you're
given the precedence we check all of the
token bucket associated with that
hope to see this whether there are
enough stock tokens in these buckets and
decrease of course these McKay's and
marks packets accordingly and we do that
with our facilities so we have an
example scenario for access and
aggregation network we have we have five
nodes we have a common bottleneck
capacity of ten gigs and the long time
fair share of the nodes is to give it
per second there are several flows or
users in one node but there is only a
single bandit profiler and we want to
enforce fairness in this in this case in
this example among these nodes not among
the sub flows of the nodes and what
advantage are we looking for we want you
have knows with good host history to to
access high portion of the but on a
capacity temporarily as long as they
have good history so for example high
peak rates achieved for small birth
sites for do small births for those
nodes which have good stories it feels
like an under loaded system even when it
is overloaded and at the same time we
want to maintain the motif of time scale
fairness V we defined so as I said its
defined by my matrix I won't go into the
like very details of this of the design
of this matrix this is our B the token
buckets this is the matrix and the time
scales but I will highlight some of the
design features actually there are
there's a link to to our paper about
this and you can find the acceptor
organs there so what we can do we we
actually want to guarantee some bit rate
on different time scales so DP one is
dropped last so by these bit rates on
different time scales you can set which
bit rate is guaranteed to a given node
then you want to have a 3-2 target for
small and medium files in those with
good history and some kind of stupid
targets for node we still reasonable
history so DP 2 is dimensioned in a way
that ODB 2 pack is going through
then all but one notes are having bet
history so you have a single node with
good history all the others are
transmitting for quite amount of time to
achieve the state we call bat history
and then the single notes can then the
new note can reach this besides and we
want to convert the first share what
time scales including largest time scale
so we have this fair share of seeker and
in different places in the mod matrix so
what does the time scale mean time
scales determine the bucket sizes on the
same column so for example two-second
determines the bucket sizes on this
column and it's also means how long the
bit rates on the previous column can be
maintained so we have the first time
scale actually set to our tea tea and
the other time scales are the time
determined based on five sizes and based
on definition of active period one day
after this amount of activity the note
is considered high load so a fluid
simulation example in this example we
have nodes 2 & 5 having a really really
bad history transmitting for quite a
while and the roughly realized arrives
to the system so for awhile all over his
buckets are full so he can reach this 6
Naga feet per second throughput so it
starts on time scale 1 and in you can
see in this time scale and actually the
shakes here are the different
personalities so you can see that in at
this time scale 1 only VP 1 and DP 2
packets go through and after a pretty
short time its 0.1 second here it goes 2
times here too and can reach only 4
second for 4 megabits per second and
after after that its transmission stops
and the different flows have actually
slightly different history and are
changing timescales in a different way
but how actually DP free is distributed
among the nodes is determined by two
things the time scale of the nodes on on
that the drop acid and the number
flair is number of TCP flows and the and
the nutria sting thing here is that the
the high load notes were much more
aggressive having tens of TCP flows why
the normal not had a same single TCP
flow so we own on the same deeply
divided bandwidth on based on the number
of flows so we have simulations
advantages with this race tomato we had
traffic model prefer person arrivals
basically to five sizes small and large
and the last number of flows per node is
also set and we define here or something
called nominal load of a node that is
the load of the of the node divided by
its fair share several owners note is
having a nominal or smaller than one
meaning it generates less than 2 meter
per second traffic in this case and the
high load node is having women are a lot
larger than one and they also have a
system load so we renamed our scenario
according to the number of load notes a
number of high load nodes and Weaver I
the low load mode the load and the load
of the high load noise so the system
load and we can calculate the high load
load from the above to it's hard to say
so some selected simulation results
first I have to mention that node is
measured only when the node is active so
the low load nodes are not always active
because they have no relative load below
one so if you if you if you add up these
numbers you get more than the capacity
and that's that's the reason and what
you can see here we we have PR TCM as
the reference case so we have the
scenario I I've shown
TR TCM taking care of resource sharing
TFT see I'm only having seer to set T to
be able to second and a year can you use
the rest of the capacity and we have the
multi timescale bandwidth profile matrix
I have just shown
and let's concentrate in his to load too
low free high scenario when the low load
was 0.5 and we increase the system load
and you can see that when the system
load is below 1 or below 0.9 basically
there is there is a realist okay what
slots on the figure so it's again the
notes we pick measured when a note is
active the axes are the averages and the
top and bottom is the 10% worse than 10%
best capacity and and what you can see
is that there is no big change when the
load is small but when the system load
approaches 1 or this ha is well above 1
the no load notes see much much higher
average they can often reach even even
the 6 secondary we said and this is the
case when you have to load in the system
you can have similar but smaller gains
than when there are 4 high load node ads
and the singular lloyd nodes and at the
same time for the high load notes there
is not a big change the biggest change
is that actually the reversed one
percent go is below the to go for second
but the average is above the same
actually the the best 10% is better so
what you can experience here is that you
have increased quality for low node
nodes and almost no change for high
level nodes and based on based on
results in the previous time we drive
them or define the measure called
experienced system loads for low note
notes for multi time scale bandit
profile what is that measure is defined
as the system load in the equivalent ear
TCM scenario when the average node
bandwidth for lower notes is the same in
that scenario so in the TR t CM so how
does it look like so what does like a
concrete number 0.9 means here that we
have a system load of two in this
again one no no more than four high load
notes we have a system mode of two but
but the average secret seen by low notes
is as if as it was in the equivalent EFT
same system wrong and as the load of
that system was zero four nine so what
we can see here is that in all cases
basically shown here the experienced
system now this verb in a1 and if the
load of the landlord not is decreased
then this experience is increased so an
example here again it's it's basically
the example I have shown in the previous
slide to low note free high load no
system noticed you and the experience in
that overloaded system is like TRT cm
below zero point eight for when for the
case when the low node node is 0.5 and
0.65 for the case when the node for
lower note is zero point two and like
you know by emotionally if you if you
increase the number of learners nodes it
means that there is a single high load
not generating very high system load and
that the learners nodes have a smaller
percentage of traffic you have even
better performance so if you have small
if you have smaller load for the loaner
nodes then it's better performance so
basically the green ones are below the
blue ones that is because those with
smaller node have good history much more
awesome and also as you as I said as you
increase the number of lower notes from
a total five five notes even at very
high system nerves you experience very
good experience if he if you compared to
the trt sermon
and why is that that is that is because
in in in tier TCM access to extract
paucity above the fair share was
basically based on on condition or
aggressiveness and the high load not
have a much higher number of flows and
they receive much higher share of that
extra capacity
we actually did some preliminary packet
level simulations so this was an idea of
fluid model it's always a question
whether it works with the video TCP so
we did an s3 DCAA simulations we have
five cubic TCPS per node and and was and
these results are showing one one second
sliding window average and I had to we
had to scale down the the speeds here so
it's a 100 Meg bottleneck but otherwise
the site the things are the same and and
not you can see here is that there are
these four ability nodes having bet
achieving bet history after a while then
a new node comes and it can reach her
this perfect history state for a while
and after that why it goes to the good
history state and then after the 30
second period basically it will be
equally it will be equally having a bad
history like the others so there will be
a an equally so sherry so again in
summary we gave a definition of fairness
a mutative time scales based on the bit
rate measurement with time scales
proposed an implementation the really
good thing in the implementation is that
you don't have to change the the core
part of the course data scheduler is
scheduling remains the same you only
have to update the eight marking to take
into account we take measurements on
different time scales and we have shown
potential advantages and characteristics
you can find much more details about
this talk there article also there is
quite amount of work in in in about
course data see so sharing recently you
can find that it there that concludes my
presentations we have a few minutes for
questions
I have a comment on that work we have
done similar stuff called ABC
activity-based congestion management and
this work was motivated by region or
Konex because some years ago with
colleagues we wanted to achieve fair
resource sharing in the stateless no
stateless Network and also the effect
that you have this time scale stuff so
that a flow that starts gets more a
larger share than long-standing flow and
yeah so this work is basically how could
I say pursues similar goals as all the
chronic stuff and that means all the use
cases that we discussed in the conex
context also apply to this to this
approach I just want to make sure I
understand what's going on here because
this is a pretty different approach to
congestion and then most the ones we see
so if I understand correctly this is
gonna be within a domain you can deploy
a thing it doesn't really need tuning
it's got you know you can you can pick
values that are defined here and then
regardless so it's it's sold for static
non-responsive load kind of like like
what Facebook in the IRT F open was
describing the edge think did you see
that one okay so forget that so but it
it's sort of independent of the
downstream queuing discipline so even if
you're talking drop tails long we've got
the static static demand
that keeps happening then it's gonna
it's gonna force it to back off because
it just doesn't get the capacity right
understanding that's really why so I
mean it's an open-loop solution but you
do need new do you need to change things
at the decor you need to be need to take
intake of these dope residences and that
you have to change and and our normal
queuing these siblings today or for a
single drop residence okay so why by
having for example in in this work
forward or presidencies in some of our
articles we have actually 65,000 so by
having a number of drug presidencies
you can you can control resource sharing
in a in a openly play you have the
support and and we went down to four
because we believe that this kind of for
a person's behavior can be approximated
with with the right configuration of
unit hardware if you can figure out
according to these differences that's
very interesting thank you yeah but
Brisco yeah I wanted to just come back
on what Michael said about a PC and
Clinics and so on and yes you're right
Michael it it they have the same aims
and I think it doesn't need comics to do
what you're doing cuz you're doing this
at a 1:1 node yeah it's not for a
network you know it is supposed to be
for a network so if you if you mark your
packets according to that marking at the
edge and all your audio core but it's
just using local information it's not
using any information from anywhere else
in the network it's it realizes the use
case different yeah and and so I think
what you'd done Michael with ABC was do
it at a single node and then you don't
need comics and everything you're just
using the local congestion information
at your local node to do the multiple
time scale thing by
so what you need for drop decisions is
both the local the local congestion
information plus the packet value so
it's called here the packet value and
the local congestion information that's
the input for the decision-making
whether to drop a packet and and
actually I think as well as ABC
there is a commercial implementation of
something like a ABC that L occurred
over there traffic management as well so
you might want to look I don't think
they publish anything about it but I did
say I could say it existed thank you so
much and I'll give you a minute back
folks thank you for showing up here and
we'll see you again next time on trail
in the meanwhile keep the list busy as
you have