hey everybody
despite the fact that we have enough
space and no weird pillars in the middle
of the room and all that this is IDR and
we're going to start in just a minute or
two so you know please start finding a
place to sit if sitting is your thing
bring your conversation to a close
stuff like that
I don't see clipboards on the desk so I
hope that means that they're already
circulating around yeah I guess there
okay everybody I see sue coming back in
the room things are circulating people
have settled down let's get started
the note well is the same note well that
I projected last time it's still
attending little eye chart sorry and you
know as always by participating in the
ITF you actually are sort of implicitly
clicking on the the shrink-wrap having
to do with intellectual property you may
be walking into the room with if you
want to walk out of the room and still
have it be your intellectual property
you might want to keep it inside your
head instead of saying getting to the
mic but don't believe me talk to your
lawyer for the agenda bashing portion
the only thing that I have to say is you
know versus what the the published
agenda is as we mentioned on Monday
we'll have use extra time at the end of
the agenda of which we have a notional
30 minutes for additional conversation
about the PG pls update draft so that oh
do we have a minute taker that's right
here we'd appreciate because some of
this discussion may be free-flowing if
you do part of the discussion go back
and log on to the end of Padden check
that see Linda and those of us who are
trying to record your information have
done a good job thank you yep and as
always though actually this group is
pretty good at it please do remember to
state your name clearly if possible at
the mic when you make comments that was
sue Harris by the way so okay let me get
the first slide up it looks like it's
Mahesh
all right so I'm gonna talk about the
BGP yang model and before I get started
let me be clear I'm not a BGP expert I'm
on the staff simply because my yang
expertise so if you don't like the model
the way it's written you can complain to
me if you don't like BGP at the
structure of it I'll ask one of the
co-authors to pitch in alright so status
with the 0-5 version of the draft
we now have support for the routing
management module and that outing policy
module the RFC 83 49 brought us support
for it and you will see great many pages
in added to the to the draft for that
there was a request to support TTL
security I have added that as a feature
we're not going to support it in the
draft it allows for any implementation
to do it by declaring the feature we did
add support for BFT that not only the
features statement but also for PFD
configure client configuration for
liveliness check when I started I think
the exercise was leading to an explosion
of modules managed to collapse that into
three modules everything else now is a
sub-module
so it makes for easier reading alright
so I'm going to spend sorry Aysen know I
know everybody might not want to stay
around to the bitter end tomorrow so
that routing policy module we're getting
ready for to try and take it to at least
there were a first working group last
call and yang doctorate review so I'd
encourage everybody to read it I
clarified a lot of the ways the recurse
of Miss worked and the way I did it is I
did it the way we map the open config
model so it's a it's a bit biased the
way I documented it but I'd like
everybody to review it thanks all right
thanks for that desi all right so I'm
going to spend the rest of the time
discussing issues and really trying to
get a input on the draft as much as
possible all right so the first issue
that I've documented is do we need
action statements for something like
clear bgp do note that there are no
statistics in the model so you're not
trying to clear any statistics will
support statistics and then another
draft what I have for right now
documented that I we will add support
for is global level player per address
family and per neighbor
so unless I hear otherwise that's what
we're going to go with supporting in the
model all right no comments so I'll move
forward notifications so we will add
support for notifications as they relate
to the out updates and neighbor state
change any comments and see Jeff
actually had comments in the prior slide
as well but for well as did this one so
yes you do need to clear BGP in terms of
being able to reset neighbors as well
the clear routes is probably going to be
controversial just something because
most people don't allow you to so when
you get a little closer to the mic Jeff
thank you certainly sorry is this better
so actually wiping routes out from the
ribs is somewhat controversial some
implementations only allow you to do
that as part of knocking at peering
session over so that one probably needs
be protected by a feature at best okay
the statistics I think my comment there
is that the stuff covered by the nips
probably is worth putting into the base
module and I'd suggest that go in as
part of the base rather than extensions
a lot of implementations will have
plenty of additional things to put in
but the patient if they don't clear
those okay
so I'll talk to the Quartus to see what
we can do to add support for that simple
for FC 4273 mmm stuff next slide so
terminology caveat notification for us
means knock over the peering session but
I don't you mean here for route updates
what is meant in this context so at the
keel can probably clarify or maybe soup
can I think right so from a Yank
perspective what it refers to is anytime
that is changed to the route of entry in
the model that might result in a
notification okay you have a neighbor
can't state change if you go from a
particular state to another state
these are notifications which can or
cannot be turned off notice or the push
notification Joe you go back and go back
to the first issue nothing my brain was
in idea our chair mode just restate what
you had problems with yeah for issue
number one so yes we do need things like
clear PGP neighbor to reset during
sessions no administrative reset appears
we do what to prevent yes that's a
that's a common function is that a
common function that what we want in
yeah and your answer is yes absolutely
that's a common piece of our PC every
one day this is this is a checking
because that's a fairly substantial your
clearing not the statistics but you're
clearing the routes the right neighbor
family the per address yeah okay and
clearing statistics will be
controversial from one implementation or
another some never allow you to change
those some do so that one might have
been protected by feature so we're
clearing statistics
clearing routes is also very
controversial to pick on a certain
vendor that starts with a see they do
have the ability in some cases to
manually reset and throw away routes
that have been learned from BGP yes
other implementations all about you do
that via policy yes and my question is
are you're proposing that it's a good
thing that we do and you would like to
see the debate start I am saying that
for the controversial things yang lets
us protect those via feature ok so there
could they have been and if they're
confidential we can protect them and so
will the condition and fit the features
statement and you know a backdoor sly to
for issues number two notifications for
neighbor state change that makes sense
those correspond to the 4273
traps that we have for that although
there's some warnings and 4273 about
noises and the state machine from
backward transitions as we go through
the state machine I would suggest taking
the warning from that one the route
update this one if that is actually a
change of whatever you get a route
update is this unconditional or is this
by a subscription with a filter it would
be unconditional from the perspective of
the model of course if there's no one
subscribe to that you don't I guess you
don't get anything but from a model
perspective a notification is generated
so the problem with that is from the
filtering mechanisms that net comfort
defined this is so noisy you'll melt the
router this is something that should
only be able to be enabled by
configuring a filter in some fashion and
propagating down to the BTB module the
direct analogy is turning on tracing for
bgp updates and prefixes and usually and
about four out of the five
implementations of familiar with that
will increase your CPU used to like no
one hundred and fifteen percent of what
you previously did I see it's not a not
a good thing now have I my default
so by the way just a not exactly a point
of order but something this is good
conversation and please continue having
it it's fine to have it at the mic but a
lot of it is also stuff that is highly
appropriate for you know like actual
document review and feedback that goes
to the list because it's it's the kind
of detail that gets lost even in good
minutes
yeah and in fairness I have not gotten
around to reading the module and I'm
only responding here because it's being
raised as an issue the screen works so I
have a clarification on the previous
slide again the clear BGP most useful
form I have been using it for a long
time it's actually with the little knob
let's say with one limitation soft in
which doesn't clear so to say but
generates route refresh to appear and
then I'm synchronizing whatever I'm
getting again from the peer locally so
do you have that concept here or it's
foreign I CQ getting it yeah I'll be
incorporated as part of the route
refresh RFC support from a modeling
perspective all right moving on
and I know this is hard to read but
hopefully you can go back to the slides
what I'm showing is route metadata for
local rib and the set of parameters if
there's anything that you're missing
feel free to comment on the mailing list
or give me feedback bgp sound community
type definition this is what we have if
this is good enough let it be but if you
want to further constrain it do let us
know same thing for extended community
types I don't have the whole printout
here but it's in the draft issue 8
through 17 now we have placeholders for
specific configuration the expectation
is that each yang module for that for
each one of these P is going to augment
the BGP based model my very quick and
the last two days just going through
some of the draft says that there are
some tasks that do it like ipv4 unicast
l3 VPN is augmenting the base model but
then we have a whole set of drafts that
are not so just to point out to the
authors some of them who are sitting
here please make sure that your
augmenting the base model Argus again
this was highlighted some of this
speaking as a core this was highlighted
in best working group and I believe the
working group chairs made are going to
come back and ensure that this should be
taken care of
I'm simply relaying what account
highlight all right that's all I have
thanks coach airhead Thank You mahesh
for helping kara and I get the right
gangster
morning folks k Patel I'm going to talk
about the status of tunneling katstra so
as part of the status update version 11
was published fairly recently in
February and as part of version on as
part of version 12 going forward we have
we now have a new core through sri hari
from Juniper Eric Rosen has already
retired who was the primary co-author on
the draft the draft is in fairly stable
state we have received numerous
feedbacks from lots of folks including
shiri
we've also received a feedback as part
of chef Shepherd review from John
Scudder
the draft has changed and the text has
been simplified the comments have been
incorporated version 12 to be published
soon and multiple partial
implementations for this draft exists so
maybe an implementation report going
forward to document some of these things
here are the high-level changes that are
coming in from version 11 to 12 of
course all the references to the tunnel
types have been moved from informative
to normative error handling section has
been tightened up the language for a
particular X&Y kind of TLV ston little
ways restricted to MPLS in GRE and MPLS
in UDP and quite a lot of shirts have
been replaced with must so that the
implementation gets a lot more specific
in that regard
question yes this is Linda tumba from
Huawei I have sent several number of
emails asking to result some of the
issue in this draft for example you have
this introducer you have this remote
endpoint
tre sub theories and his stated can be
inserted with every tre so if I have a
route which you can go traverse like
multiple egress ports when ports
and I'm not sure I cannot find anywhere
in the document should I have like
multiple remote and pointy always attach
the route or should I have announced
this three times for that update I send
that question several times but nobody
answered that question so I didn't get
your complete question the error
handling section now covers text fourths
how the multiple same PL ways should be
handled but if you send the question out
again one more time with I'm sure you
get an answer now okay I hope so okay
yeah so can I just interject a thing
from the chair and or document Shepherd
I get mixed up with these hats but I
believe there's been sort of will it or
will have been enough provisions to the
draft that even though we completed one
working group last call it's probably
gonna be appropriate to take it through
another one so you know definitely make
sure that you get in your comments by
then if not before and you know that's
as part of the working group last call
we'll be tracking and making sure that
we've got you know issues closed one way
or another okay
that'd be great a second issue I see
that in the 5512 you have bgp speakers
local endpoint address to be included in
in a in the update and in this one
doesn't mention that so i asked the
question doesn't mean a third person
like if between our two sending the
route update if there's ex concern the
same route update on behalf of our two
whether that would be accepted or not it
is not clearly stated in the document so
that's one thing I thought removing the
speaker's endpoint address may mean that
but I can now find anywhere in the
document to address that I also express
that in the email nobody answered so we
left it or possibly open but if you
think there is any vulnerability issues
or if you think that has any
super say because typically the draft
text doesn't prohibit an implementation
from doing exactly what you say having
said that if you see an issue with that
or a concern with that now is a good
time to highlight it to the work on a
meaningless I do see issues with that
I see additional function provided by
that additional feature provide that but
also associated with some of the
problems with that so in the email and
then they find that since this drug the
author thinks maybe Eric was retiring so
nobody care to answer this yeah person
to take care of it review a review of
that draft found some of these questions
that Linda mentioned and we were looking
at the - 12 draft how do you want us to
handle questions are you in mid-flight
of making some other edits should we
refer to 12 do you want them private or
on list I mean normally you know I
always like on list stuff but if if
you're in the middle of edit for next
version how do you want to take the time
I think the I think a particular way to
handle it and from my perspective it'd
be super cool if we get it to that point
is to publish version 12 with all the
comments that we have received so far
and we have an agreement on the comments
and folks can take a jab at it and
follow it up with subsequent comments if
they have and we'll be more than happy
to take a here's here's here's my
suggestion is that like I said we we
have you know we got through working
group last call once and I'm hoping that
the authors and the group think that
it's going to be appropriate to move to
working group last call
pretty promptly again yeah so that's
exactly you know what you outlined is
like you've got a 12 almost ready to go
put it out there and then it'll be a
good time you know a good use of
people's time to go and review at that
point and let's just have the whole
conversation on the list just to be
clear John there's a - 12 out there
right now
okay sorry whatever you
it sounds like you have something in
your edit buffer ready to push out as
that
yes question 12 that incorporates all
the comments that we so are you saying
people should should review what's
already published exactly okay
sorry what is going to be published soon
to be a user of the draft I also noticed
that and this is where you prepare chair
hat off individual contributor hat on I
noticed there's a lot of things that wow
that's a lot to implement are you going
to segregate common versus base well
okay so before I would like to have that
conversation I I would like to give care
the opportunity to finish his last two
slides just in case it answers any of
the other questions that are coming up
to the mic if you're sure that you know
your question isn't going to be answered
if it's clarification about something
that's already come up go ahead
specifically on this light jeff has the
shoulds replaced with mas every person
in this room that cares about this draft
needs to refer to those changes and
double check things some of the changes
in implications may surprise you
sounds like a fair comment absolutely
again as part of changes separate IANA
registries have been now created to
cover flag fields within end caps of
tlvs this is just as a part of a good
cleanup
same for the label handling sub TLB
field as well there is a modification to
best part mechanism wherein a rule is
been added which says hey if a path is
considered paths to a path would be
considered unreachable
if tunnel and cap address is no longer
reachable so this has to be some kind of
an reach ability check that needs to be
done
the routing considerations section has
been modified to ensure data forwarding
prefers tunnel paths over a non tunnel
path or or rather a next hop path for
that particular path in which the
tunneling and
pay tribute was to seal which means if
you receive this attribute please make
sure to make use of it
section 8.1 is modified to cover label
stack for BG PLU as part of turn align
caps finally added a section for IP n IP
terminating into Worth and any minor
Nets that needed to be fixed are fixed
Robert hook so that's more general
observation how about historically Erik
didn't want to add anything here for
IPSec and DTLS because he didn't want to
put crypto in BGP and that's fine right
however there is use cases like you will
see in next presentation
we're just indication of that pier which
is willing to established IPSec with
someone else or DTLS for someone else
it's useful right so the question is why
don't you just address it here adding
twinned pipes and be done with that in
the same document so when we started off
this draft the idea of this draft at
least with the quarters that started of
this effort was to replace five five one
two and if you notice the old five I
won't do it in carry an IPSec attribute
it's done as part of a separate RFC so
we say it as follow on once we have
tunnel and caps in place and once we
have an appropriate infrastructure in
place we would go and cover the IPSec as
part of the separate document just so
happens someone has done it we already
have something that's updating five five
six six well that's your next
presentation and the question there
remains to be seen is is it updating or
is it doing more or less I'm simply
saying we were going to take that effort
after tunneling caps worse than this
okay that assumes you actually are
putting IPSec information to bgp but I'm
saying the subset of that it's also very
useful I don't disagree so on my
suggestion is again just like what I
would love to do as part of finishing
and working group class calling this dry
is I mean anything that that needs to be
changed fixed you know deleted whatever
about the the base spec obviously has to
be covered
anything that's in there that's wrong
obviously has to be covered if anything
that looks like you know a new tunnel
type or extension I I would love to see
that come along as a follow-on draft
just because I don't want to have this
thing open for writing forever and it's
designed as you know a modular and
extensible framework so let's move this
one forward and extend it and I think
that what you're describing is a perfect
I don't want to process more drafts than
we have to you know let's not have a
million drafts just for fun but on the
other hand you know we got to sort of
say you know close for writing now you
know at some point so you know I'm not
saying absolutely not but I am saying
let's let's not churn it infinitely yeah
and from our perspective as quarters
look we started off with a certain
approach because of how the RFC's were
laid out happy to consider it and cover
it as part of this if the work is
absolutely incremental and if that is
what working group wants and I'd like to
respond to the question working group
member sue brought up from the floor
which was you know it's it's a big draft
and you know kind of what what are we
gonna do about the you know our
implementation requirement I think I
addressed this some on Monday but now
that weíre talking about the specific
draft I'd like to address it again my
feeling right now so sort of you know
again this is towards the practicalities
of do we keep this thing in revision
mode for an eternity and you know try to
you know flip over into a 3-digit you
know draft number or do we just finish
it probably if I you know we had to go
back and do again I'd say you know what
would be awesome would be to do you know
kind of the the skeleton part and in one
document
you know or maybe do it with you know
just one exemplary atomic tunnel type
and then do all the tunnel types in
follow-ons because then it's clear that
your your implementation piece has
copper is covered but what we have is we
have a document that's got six tunnel
types call out in Section three plus you
know several other modes called out in
section three and my guess is that
either no one or almost no one is going
to go and you know implement all of
those tunnel types in their first ship
and if we insist on having every single
tunnel type checked off in our
implementation report this thing they
stay and draft for a long time so my
hope is that the working group is going
to be satisfied by saying you know what
we're gonna we're gonna check off the
you know sort of basic functionalities
and say we implement at least one tunnel
type and it seems to work and move
forward on that basis it's not it's not
perfect but I hope that sort of you know
satisfies enough of the requirement so
speaking as a co-author on the document
and I'm pretty sure I'm speaking on
behalf of all the other co-authors is as
we start to take on version 12 and
publish version 12 I am sure we will get
feedback that means we will be editing
the document and why we are editing the
document it'd be great if we can take
that call because we have no problem
splitting split splitting the documents
but we if we do it we do it now rather
than we don't take a call and year from
now we take that call y-yeah so if you
have input on that you know the Mike
which I CAC going for would be great or
you know to the list or the chairs
soon rather than late AC Linda yeah I
would really support bringing this to
completion and one thing we had with the
segment routing drafts in iGPS
we had a specific piece it was actually
an encoding of our SPE like ER o and
those and we talked to among the I was
the shepherd
I talked to him on the co-authors and I
said I know when nobody's implemented
this are we ever going to implement it
and they all said no probably not
so we took it out so if there's anything
in there you think nobody's ever gonna
implement just take it out now that's a
good suggestion
this is Linda dumper so I support having
those skeleton document explaining
really well how do you update the route
how do you go through the egress ports
and how do you report and then potential
problems of third party announced for
you all those mechanism to be described
well and then you may have may be
appended to describe different kind of
encapsulation because they are all can
be treated the similar way except IPSec
sridhara svami juniper just responding
John's question I agree with what kr is
saying maybe we put an additional
timeline based on the feedback I don't
know one month or some number of weeks
after we can make a call on either way
splitting now or should this how would
you like that timeline to be if you had
your choice oh you follow month out I'm
sorry I didn't hear
once is good okay
thanks very much Cooley so I'm going to
go ahead and publish version 12 and
solicit comments thank you guys
hello everyone
topic here is to use IB chick PGP to ice
Aikido the IP set configuration I think
five minutes discussion is about do we
want to put this into the current draft
or the one-stop race as separated
document for me I am fine with it either
way I mean but this presentation about
what it means
so let's put that aside for a minute
just focus on the air talking decide so
probably I think probably it's pretty
straight wood the problem I will try to
solve is that in some large networks
your big number of routers and then if
you want to secure either power traffic
or the traffic 850 million typically
today you have to do is that you create
a large number of IP second mesh tunnels
between then sometimes you know to
manager and the provision those
pycnometer knows it cumbersome and it's
a quite big overhead so we need a better
solution to address such a problem so
design considerations
first my proposal here is not trying to
be a solution for every use case out
there like I said in the previous slides
or I want to solve problem is that
trance of the confusion and imagine
problem of big number of tunnels second
the solution should not trade-off of
security we have moti tears in foreign
slides and last is to avoid dream
interviews so I will try to reuse exist
protocol whenever possible I'm not
trying to compare analytical with a
radically new Motoko here so the
proposal is that we cannot extend the
current
tunnel encapsulation draft to add the
IPSec part
BGP is only used for the signals in
certain opposite configuration but IP
sector itself will be still signaled by
the equity to itself so this
draft does not introduce any change
regarding I could be - there's only
small amount change based on a ton in
caption draft so here are the changes
first we need a new theory for IPSec
tunnel
so I here proposed to use we use current
look at the value of n o4 which is a
liquid by the 5s disks to reuse that as
a basic ESP tunnel mode because for a H
mode it's rarely used and I think
they're right now they'll change at
least well from nice things to deprecate
H mode so I propose that we only support
is returnable a second is there can be
new sub theory for public around
instance so the populations for IPSec is
where you the a piece of packets in
capture IPSec packets there are
instances for it in so which could be
different from the pillow packets of the
IPSec tonneau so today I know you many
deployments people actually using the
same or instance for both load and the
tunnel packets but for secure isn't
there should be possibility to separate
this to so we need a separate top tier V
to signal that and then there's a new
sub theory for remote address prefix so
in my piece of Caetano case there's the
idea of the there's a concept of the
trophy selector which defines what type
of our source and destination traffic is
allowed on a tunnel or the particular
traders say so we need to signal that
because that's quite important for the
greedy IPSec tunnel since user may want
to enforce what type Ralph or what type
sauce is allowed to access the somewhere
behind me so there are two so if I'm to
here it will rise for remote while for
the local
so those are all for receive point of
view and condition yesterday with the
robot I think the no one we could be
optional could be other way to freedom
by using recourse next I look up to
achieve same purpose but I think a local
band is that is necessary and also it
reuse some existing sub terribly
defining the counter craft for example
remote endpoint which give you the IP
sector nine point dress the color
actually the color we use here to signal
the large part of our preset confusion
like for example your most importantly
your crypto what crypto you want to
enforce that the other end to use to
reach you
and some just a mother whatever either
IPSec infusion you wish to map into this
color actually severity of II and last
real I also want to reuse the embedded
label hindering sub here we because
although IPSec tunnel is for IP tunnel
payload but in case for example in
unicast VPN address family there's a
label there but for IPSec case because
the during the icon of negotiation
you are aware which private or distance
that you are mapping to each so you
don't necessarily need that service
level in the updates to to talk is that
so in the draft or I propose to use like
value to of this embedded level so
basically you know that they were in the
update
so here's a operational example so you
have here example you have see two
routers route one now to right suddenly
I hand out one and southern PNC you can
route to and the user want to enforce
the traffic point we protected by the
IPSec tunnel by two type of China say so
red one and yellow one the red one using
like a s 256 which are easy for mapping
to color red and the yellow means it's
using now in Commission and with only
integrity protection Jasraj 256 which
map to yellow color yellow so in this
case given such requirements both R 1 R
2 or provision with the PKI keys and
certificate for us AMCA so again here so
this draft does not propose anything to
for the authentication credential in BGP
we leave that outside on purposely
outside the documents because it with BK
I can easily to achieve that scalable
credential provision in the network so
here
those are two provisions certificate
keys from same CA and are while we
advise upland a in BGP which has a
tunnel in custody attribute that contain
IPSec theories so which contain two
theories first why is our point with
panel our are wise endpoint address the
color will be red and sublet in the
local perfect subject V so basically two
verses in order for the source of her
own subnet P to reach some net a behind
me you need to use red configuration
actually conversion to reach me as
similar for theory 2 which is says most
remote subnets C to reach a from the a
you need to use color yellow as an IPSec
configure
except sedation then are two other also
advised subnet B which has a 1-ton or
encapsulate attribute that contains one
IPSec theory with more than power be the
are truth endpoint and colors of red and
a in the local preciousness sub Theory
so again so r2 will advance similar
saying for some nasty so now with this
for updates in pace so when I one
received a packet from top and a test
angel suffered B since BT update
inclusive a also conclude a clue
contains a IPSec tonneau encapsulate
repute and there's no existing try to
say that could use for the traffic so I
will choose theory one because he will
match the package source and destination
address with the local prefix in the
received updates and then here truth
here v1 and years accurate to three
steps eternal and also because the
there's a there's a carriage built in
the IPSec theory he will know what kind
crypto overcome for eyepiece the
confusion he should use to Estep Gitano
so that they will config they were
creating exactly to create his first try
testing and the corresponding ESP
transform the Kryptos and with a trophy
selector that accordingly and then after
the time is created I 1 R 2 now can for
traffic between
sublet a and B so what they try to say
well and if next hour received another
package from suffered a to this is
something to see because in this case
although I already have a try to say one
but that one is only for to each other
sublet a and B so that they cannot use
that so I try to say so he need to
create an
just try to say for these packets same
same same process happen in the previous
but now because there's already I can
say credit in previous step to the same
pier so can you use that I can say to
create a second child si with different
crypto in this case North Christian with
sha-256 and with a different set of
chopsticks elector so now after these
two steps our two can forward traffic
between subnet a and sub let's see with
the trial will try to sa to this way
both r1 r2 does not have provision
people in all those tunnels pretty
pretend it's all packet triggered or
dynamic okay
summary so I think the benefit of this
proposal is that it's typical the cap of
the IPSec confliction from the key
exchange and tunnel negotiation so which
means it able to be leveraged post world
of developments that can loud the boss
IPSec side and be decide to evolve in
independently
second is by reusing IP equity - which
is a field PO field proven mature
protocol which make sure that exchange
is secure and last we all need to do the
limit change track B to be no change to
activity - and and last is that we allow
interpreter routers that are not
supposed draft which allow gracefully
transition
this is Linda Dunbar I just put my hair
the head of the iTunes that working
group chair this particular IP sac
configurations through controller has
been discussed in the ITSM in the
security area for over a year so there
are lots of controversial is there and
so I think this starting here will be
better to align with what has
being discussed in the security area to
align with what they have done at least
maybe bring it over there or align with
there or wait until they finish and
adopt yeah it comments over there a
robot doctor while ago I think that is
very different from my draft
I mean you guys want to talk it directly
from the controller while I also discuss
the child relationship how the child sa
being created association so that's one
part so that's definitely need to be
aligned okay so the intent is similar
they have two cases and they actually
they have three cases one is Ikey whens
oculus was SD uncontrolled so those
three cases so that need to be addressed
so that's my first concern is the
duplication of the discussion parallel
discussion in security area and here
second concern I have is for the traffic
selection for IPSec traffic selection is
not only based on destination like the
route like you li PGP update you update
your your routes it can be associated
with source and destination and ports
and many other parameters so that using
PGP to to to advocate that propagate
that the remote end doesn't really know
the particular policy the policy has to
be coming from the controller not from
the peer third part is when you
advertise the traffic the routes the
local local device has to be able to be
secured enough to authenticate the peer
so the the IPSec introduced a whole
different dimension because you're
giving with the port facing the
untrusted Network it's different from
the other network we deal with where
everything is in the walk-in garden yeah
I think I said question one by one so
first one is that like I said I'm not
trying to be a stn solution here and not
everybody want to use a controller in
the network
and understand it pretty hard topically
right now but not that it's not like
everybody know what we're starting using
controller in tomorrow so second my
drafter really is just extension of a
current canon captioned patient dropped
within the idea to cover the IPSec
tunnel case nothing was in that and the
second and more that IPSec that traffic
has protocol port range I've been
working I'm secure for ten years now so
I'm aware that but here in specially in
the network routing internationally use
case people usually do not use protocol
or put range here so that's why I want
to simplify my draft that's wrong put
too much into the watch change on the
BGP
robert hooke so it's not the question to
you it's actually a general observation
for the working group you brought it up
that's why it comes now so you are
asking for edition of the local critics
and that's very useful but it's also
applicable to all types as currently
defined in the tunnel and capsulation
attribute because that's very useful
information to have ability to specify
from that source to the destination go
through that end cap versus the other
end cap so it is not in the base bag and
I think that will be very useful to
actually consider addition of that tiny
bit of information to the base back yes
I agree actually I won't ask opinio
about that we should cover more tonal
types you can Jeff as I have two
comments about two and half comments
first I do think this is very useful
work configuration and use of IPSec
tunnels has been somewhat painful and
BGP before people have several ways of
doing it and many of them are annoying
which brings me to my two points point
number one your you should add a
operational consideration section to
your draft talking about how issues that
I ke
now become part of your troubleshooting
mechanism for BGP
if Ike doesn't work your tunnel doesn't
come up your route stop resolved and no
this causes a lot of pain for the user
that looks like a beach bee problem when
it really is not yeah that's a good
point
the second one is your draft
intentionally calls out for this in a
single administrative domain which is a
good clear use case lots of value there
have you given thought to introduce a
notion of this so so the reason I say
this is the most fuzzy single discrete
domain because I per second IDO
syndication
I mean sometimes hard to consistent
addiction beckons across the mr. domain
especially in this route
interconnections case that's why I say
is for the single the the place where
this can be additionally useful and this
is somewhat problematic in terms of how
the T path attributes likely to be
deployed for a short period of time
having you know some general is PA and
some generally is pzd will completely
far ends of things trying to
interconnect with each other and
basically doing IPSec over the Internet
is a thing that is already done today
but again it's C prior comment it's a
very difficult thing because
coordinating things like the ike
services across the internet is a tricky
thing yeah I think I said nothing you to
drop of technically nothing to prevent
you to do that it's just I think what
most people would do it but ok I can put
some text to clarify that and I think it
goes back to the core draft which is how
is that attributed expected to propagate
over the general internet right and so
two things one is I'd like to say we're
cutting the line aftercare and the other
is this is valuable conversation and I
just I mean this is a general comment
any time you make a comment at the mic
actually is send a follow-up email
because it's really hard for presenters
who do not you know are not taking notes
as they're presenting to remember all
the comments and we try to get them in
the minutes but send email thank you go
ahead
Stephanie kersky from Owens speaking as
a best chair Mort small question to you
John we have now four drafts spread of
our idea on best talking about IPSec
with envy turnaround caps
my idea was to try to find just one
solution if it's possible to cover all
the cases I'm not sure that it will be
doable but yeah we need absolutely to
set up the minimum set of building
blocks that could be reused for the
various use case after eyes just where
is the home for his work do you do it in
idea how do we do it in vests because I
think area document maybe on VC has
developed via secure VPN which is being
able to secure all the service VPNs that
we could ever invest using IPSec so yeah
we're ISO home for this so I'm not gonna
try to answer from the chair but I think
we should talk maybe after the meeting
or you know something like that
Sioux hairs individual contributor in
this moment plus one on the last comment
and a specific question for the
presenter have you read draft the best
evpn internets internet subnet for ting
that is the secure VPN draft he had no
heaven okay
I would advise based on the work that
was done there in best for a while that
you read that they're looking at
multiple domain you want to restrict
your work and you clearly state that
thank you and your draft that it's a
single domain there's have both single
domains and multi domains some of the
things that are different with Linda's
in my graph is we're looking at gaps in
their draft okay and we're trying to
work with them and work with the I to
intercept I I would just note that it
might be useful for you as an author um
that's just a comment I have two
questions the new subnet he'll be for
remote address prefix and local address
prefix we explain why you felt that was
necessary in addition to the addresses
because they might be suck this trophy
select concept so with IPSec a user
could specify which source and
destination behind me are allowed over
this particular tunnel
it's not a basic protocol isn't it isn't
that policy that you're putting when you
get to prefix or or I'm confused why
it's just a list of subnets okay so you
feel you need the subnet in order to do
the appropriate IP set so if you're with
my example I read the sequence you did
the question the specific question is in
order to do the IP sex stuff you feel
you need the subnet it's mandatory okay
yeah
second when you re third excuse me when
you're reusing the color have you
thought about conflicts over color
amongst people who are using this I mean
you're defining color and policy
equivalently and you're overlaying every
time we overlaid things no somebody
forgets you no no so when I say color
it's it's a color sub TV right when you
put this up a color table theory and and
is the IP secretary that meets which
means they have special meaning for us
IPSec tunnel which is defined in my
draft
there's no I don't think there's a
confusion there but there are many
people in many ways are you going to lay
out exactly how it's going to be no no
I'm not trying to define any colorful
and what any other type of tano's laughs
a you've just let me repeat backs who
understand it you've said that it's only
under the IPSec color and that's where
it is be you've said that you're gonna
have multiple people using that IP upset
color otherwise you wouldn't be using
BGP and you're not gonna define how it's
going to be working my comment then
stands how are you gonna have people not
clash no that's just I don't see how
unless you specify color and you're
overloading the color I think I asked my
as you misunderstood your question
that's all you sit a typo to know I said
between I'd be sick another type dunno
if you say you're both using color there
may be computer but is it
it's like communities in BGP where the
consulting
exchangers agree on the color but my
point is that when you put the colors of
cherry and a nice IPSec Ratanakiri yes
that's very her very specific meaning
for IPSec it should not be any confusion
there so guys this is gone back and
forth a few times and I'd like to
suggest you like review the draft
language and continue that way thank you
ELISA Jesse Cisco even just the building
up on the question that who made the
security VPN I guess you haven't had a
chance to read it right sorry secure a
VPN Jeff I guess you haven't had a
chance to read it okay because some of
the material in here overlaps and would
be good to you know to see what the
overlap is and how we do it in that
secondly with respect to the in here
you're talking about discovering the
endpoints and setting up the IPSec
session via the IQ p2 and still we're
gonna have the mesh mesh of IP to
session among the peers I thought that
you were talking about that is scale you
want to I don't know but that is not a
dress I'm not trying to address the
scope habit here I'm going to try to
scare off the confusion here okay then
the other question have you had a chance
to read 55 RFC 5566
yes so this is basically the RFC 55 66
with the instead of using 5512 we are
using the tunnel attribute yeah more
like that I think we I put more stuff
there than five or six like that yeah
all right
one final question you're gonna you're
sending a list of prefixes with this
attribute of what follows gets mapped to
this tunnel right you were saying so you
know three fixes we were saying that yes
these are the prefixes that you send
these are the VPN traffic says no it's
basically traffic selective IPSec dunno
okay go ahead so
when you create a pizza Colonel Lansing
is mandatory
do you really okay all right so just a
quick note that in terms of the setting
it up the security VPN talks about how
to discover and set up the IP succession
as well as how we can in for take their
instead of using the I could beat you or
we can instead of having a measure of
the itv2 we can use one single
point-to-multipoint signaling you guys I
mean personally I try to avoid that I'm
saying that it's two parts I can I
understand but what I'm saying is both
parts are covered you're covering one
part of it and that's what I said there
is an overlap that needs to be looked
into right I think we've heard several
times now that you know both the authors
and the chairs need to go and kind of
untangle the overlapping things so point
taken
Kate Patel arcus the comment that Robert
made about taking the list of prefixes
and probably moving that TLB into the
base draft happy to do that happy to
work with you on that so no problem at
all the other side comment I have I
don't know who to probably target on
this but a general comment that there
are four different solutions none of
their those solutions list out what
route announcement rules should be
across the AAAS or whether should this
be at this attribute be leaked across
yes willingly and willingly
maybe it's wise to call out that at
least in the draft yeah thank you
thank you very much
okay so mercy is a first-time attendee
and a first-time presenter an idea let's
give her a nice warm welcome hello my
name is Masha Zhang from Cisco so I'm
going to present a new draft BGP PFD
sridham out this chapter was also
presented at the working group yesterday
problem statement PFD IFC v a2 enables
routers to monitor data playing
connectivity and detect boarding pass
failure in BGP leverages on this
specification by using EFT to enhance
the faster convergence II today BGP
neighbor session establishment is
independent from the PFD session a PFD
State because of that there are some
possible failure scenarios when BTP
interaction with PFD scenario a a PGP
session may be established while
EFT session is still down sanera PE
articulated or poor-quality link may be
lots in the corresponding PFD session
going up and down frequently when PTP
session is established so particularly
for a BGP a typical a BGP peel can be
multi hop away on those scenarios are
likely to be observed the consequence of
the impact will be the traffic being
black hole raj in june and the network
interruptions
so we proposed a solution years bgp PFD
straighten out this proposed draft that
defines PTP street mode operation as
preventing bgp section establishment on
Tia speakers have a stable PFD session
between them an LPG ppfd capability is
defined for the PTP protocol Sangamon
the definition of the snare BGP PFD
capability are the kerb is TBD and the
lens will be one octane the capability
value contents of one octave PFD flags
if the flux contains bit flux related to
the PFD the most significant bit MSB is
defined as a state of the street mode
also called a speed operations are first
rate amalgam a BGP speaker with PFD
street and mode enabled must advertise
the PTP PFD capability with a speed
value set to 1 a BGP speaker which
supports BGP PFD capability
advertisement must exam BGP PFD
capability received the form its peer
only if both the local PGP speaker and
its remotely to be peer have a PFD
Street mode enabled then BGP session
establishment will be prevented until
it's if these sessions up if is appear
has not advertised beach ppfd capability
with street mode enabled then a BGP
session should not be required prayer to
the BGP session establishment
conclusion we have identified a problem
of BGP and the PFD interaction
which could result in the return to in
the network interruptions we propose the
solution to the problem refers us a BGP
PFD Street mode there the prevent the
BGP session establishment until PFD
session is up and stabilized it also
enables a page of his speak to signal
its peer additional be of the extension
using an optional parameter PFD
capability follow in the proposed the
street mode operations we avoided a
situation which results in the routing
true and in minimized impact of
networking interruptions and next steps
just for the Rovira we are going to
raise revise the backward compatibility
section based on the IFC 5490 chain we
are also going to add a new section to
specify the detail on the bgp sessions
stay the transaction into the scrubber
check so the draft is a little bit vague
about 12 the problem is
so it says roughly this that there are
some situations in which the beardy
session doesn't get established well the
bgp session does could you describe an
example of such a situation and what
it's due to well I mean the situation
part of situation now come on to all the
control protocol I think if you refer to
the section 4 point wine of IFC 5 a 2 it
also described the control protocols
neighbor session establishment problem
this is the commencing right so if you
want using so we have to do the single
no need to break the the locking issue
of the reference again there are
since an RFC number yeah the IFC 580 SEC
shameful pundit yes Robert Rashad
so this strict mode has been proposed in
OSPF and and Averell groups as well for
BFD but your slides said something
interesting that you don't want to
establish
bgp session when the link quality is
poor that sounds perfectly great except
PFD today doesn't really determine link
quality as such an encounter may mean
different things for different people
BFD today gives you ability to sign out
the purists up or down right there are
proposals in VFD to actually enhance BFD
to do more than what is it actually
designed for but I think there is a
little bit of a gap if we are using the
right tool to evaluate the link quality
yeah this is just thank you this is just
part of a scenario yeah I'm the like for
example people who I handle this case
like PFT dampening or other saying so
maybe if they stay to see you down but I
mean this other so very briefly we're
starting to run short on leading time so
the line is cut after ridiger and please
keep you know make your comment but keep
them short Thank You Alexander Zima
Yandex I understand the goal but I don't
understand why you need to negotiate
this their capability between peers why
you don't why you can't just a figure
Eight's locally video question
so yeah you you are trying to not
establish a BGP session before you have
a BD session but if you have this
information from one side well you can
just stop establish a session is the
upswing chance it will be fine so why do
you need to negotiate right we need a
signal yes okay also and you
and you can correct them okay so the
major issue is to avoid that the
potential deadlock okay if you prevent
you peer doesn't know or sometimes you
hear maybe waiting for a session come up
before they create the PFD session
so deadlock situation coming they'll
never be able to step it should be a few
new session many vendors already support
strict mode including us there are
situations in which you you you have it
configured on both sides and normally
you want to use it but you may have a
situation like immediately after an
upgrade or something where you don't
want to use it one time when you come up
and this way by signaling it you can
handle those situations where you don't
want to use it and they're also what
pointed out there's been bugs where
there's been a deadlock between
different implementations of strict code
okay or brittle arcus I actually like
the document so I have no problems with
that but I would be really interested in
knowing exactly what Alexander asked why
would you need capability you could hold
the peering session at your end locally
when you need it and 42 71 which is the
base bgp specification actually as nice
section of connection collision in built
or define in there so at the worst both
ends will keep on retrying that's about
it but i really don't see the need of
capability so if you take it out if you
think that's the case then it makes it
even more simple i think we need it
Himanshu from Siena so this is good but
I think this has a limited application
in the sense that it doesn't take care
of the route reflector clients so you
have a you may be okay without
processing establishment with the route
reflector server in the client but
between the two clients where there is
no bgp session and you could have a bad
connection and all that stuff so it real
that part is missing here obviously for
the sessions they are fine I'm just
saying that it it has the scope of that
application is somewhat limited you are
saying no I would like to draw your
attention to draft bla bla bla RS BFD
bla bla bla each draft ietf IDR RS PFD
okay they did address is that it
addresses exactly that use case for for
secure for secure it addresses exactly
the case you described okay
jeff has speaking is EFT chair and also
as a day-to-day BGP developer this is a
real problem and as we sort of seen at
the microphone people have different
ideas about when BFD is used to protect
a BGP session the fundamental issue is
that at what point in the beach B state
machine do you insist that BFD either
get started or to be up and stable
before you do things and we do have
day-to-day Interop problems not always
necessarily for just bringing up the
session but first things like no keep
down type behaviors when the protocols
actually do say the FDS down when do
they allow to come back up this draft is
a useful place for us to standardize a
behavior that is not standardized either
in BFD or in BGP and that does actually
cause cause in draw problems Cisco and
juniper for example and the keep down
features do not interoperate and it
causes problems so can I ask a
clarifying question um several people
have brought up at the mic oh we don't
need a capability um so would you like
to respond to that absolutely so the
motivation here is that without some
sort of signaling it was like again what
part of the state machine do you bring
it up if you do it at connect or no
connect retry I pick your favorite piece
of that state machine you don't
necessarily know which behavior do you
do do you do the one that you've been
doing for years or do you do the one
that is tied into
the new behavior at a single point that
we can interoperate it so the signaling
is a good place to say now that we know
that we're going to look for the
capability we could at least use that as
a sinking point for the knowing solution
Thank You Lydia for Deutsche Telekom and
I'm looking at the description of what
you are trying to do and what you're
doing I note when I advise my customers
to establish PFD on bgp sessions my
thinking and my goal is that they tear
down the BGP when something bad happens
what you are doing here is kind of the
other end of a BGP session you only want
to open it or delay the actual open
until you know that the path is clean
and I think there might be a different
approach to deal with that situation I
would think that it is not necessary
that you delay trying to open the BGP
you just have to delay actually using
the announcements and potentially hold
back on the announcements and I have the
gut feeling that the deadlocking that
has been talking about is be can be
completely avoided if you take that
approach yeah I would I would encourage
you guys to discuss that further on the
mailing list because we're out of time
thank you thank you Alex you're next
and just as alex is getting set up here
i want to say i know that we promised a
discussion on the BG pls bissell and
anybody who's looking at their watch
will see that we just aren't going to
have time for that I'm very sorry I
encourage people who are interested in
contributing to that to find Katyn and
you know provide input in you know as
time allows hello everyone my name is
Alexandra Zenith Iveco yandex and today
I'm going to deliver to you
I hope final update on bgp open policy
drop so it was here for already three
years there was a lot of changes mergers
with other documents and again changes
in the finality so on so on but the key
principle was preserved unchanged so the
root leaks are happening because of
policy violations and the root cause of
these violations is mistakes mistakes
that amazed by network engineers that do
not understand how to apply peering for
a represent peering policy in their
configuration so these draft just fuels
this gap it provides a native way to
represent your peering policy into the
configuration so you're just sitting
you're you're impulsive the
configuration and after that every the
filtering is done automatically so let's
jump to the role specification as you
see most of the roles are native if you
are a customer your all's customer if
you are a provider you're always
provider but what is if you are route
server you know form from the
mathematical standpoint the answer is
clear there is no difference between
genetic change points that provides
partial connectivity and Internet
service provider that can also provide
partial connectivity so I thought that
everybody will be happy to
they're out server is a provider and go
on with this and I was wrong even people
that were carefully reading the draft
were confused and so the in the last
version of the draft we changed it so if
you are providing a router if your
router
you're always router if you are my
interpreter your own Kauai interpreter
so I hope these will solve the problem
with uncleanness and uncertain I was
really not happy dropping the idea math
model but simplicity is the winner so
with this I would like to ask for
working group last call we have three
open source implementations I would be
glad to see other vendors during the
party so that's all that's all any
questions we will absolutely add that to
our list of things to working group last
call thanks very much for the concise
update and yeah floor is open for
questions but please keep them brief if
you have them and in the meantime I will
get the next slide set queued up okay
okay
seeing no questions thank you very much
Alex
lately is this your first presentation
in IDR okay this is a very simple
actually very simple after about a BGP
for specification for a sorry six this
is the background of this draft I must
say actually in they are see I think
it's five five seven seven seven five
yeah have defined the BGP prospects
occasion as I for the beach refers back
and already defined in many many
component types were they acted before
IP prefix IP protocol and for some draft
have defined they layer 2 VPN VLANs for
the component types so for this draft
have adjusted to defined to new
component types were they seed of I
sorry six so the first the first
component I pays for the whole 128 bits
of seed even the host eight we also use
a pair of operator in the value 2 for
the match rule in the operator type
operator bytes we have seen the last
less than greater than and the yuko and
the value should be the whole seed 128
assist for together with the oak returns
at the value we can indicate how about
they are certain exactly in seed or a
range of the city to match for the i 36
so this is very easy to understand
together with the operator byte under
the value of field and but for as we all
know for this city is too long and for
some scenarios we can just too much some
bits or some feels about the seat
because in the i sorry 6 network of
programming we have seen that the seeds
of format should be locator from k ID
and some arguments so we give another
type come on and type 2 to match some
field or some feats of this city to
match such as we also use a pair of
operator and the Vario to indicate the
morrow so in the operator we defined the
type field to indicate which children or
which speeds who want to march so now it
gives four bits for the in the future we
may have very flexible extent so you
know we just came 44 times first one is
for the locator second is function ID
and also some group together with
function locator and a function or
function arguments so for the very
office we use seed and mosque two
flexible two together indicate the value
about there's some fielder's piece off
the seat so together they say it's for
the second component type so for this
two times so it gives not only the whole
128 in situ margin but also some beads
and feels too much okay so it's very
easy to understand
just to give two components for the
newest re6 Network so sorry okay quick
question why only sit and not let's say
SRH presence why you don't want too much
on the extension header type so if I see
accessor header type anywhere in the
packet I treat it differently let's say
right yes yes but for this I think we
can extend in other craft or something
else but in this draft adjustor defined
these two types yeah from Holly from our
point of view because the s are actually
the coulomb for the match but because of
the I sorry see that can be used as a v6
the destination but it is a totally
different from the ipv6 address so
that's either we properly so type user
can match the IP destination address of
the ipv6 the packet the path a user can
use that as a sorry succeed
I'm not sure let's go anywhere I'm sorry
for my ignorance I didn't read the draft
so good question which field from the
header you are going to compare with
that is it against the IP header or or
SR SR Heather it's actually for us our
headers that destination address at that
time and also for the seed or bonding
seed but I think we can use as our
policies first to end point so there's
two types I think all can't be matched
but if I received updates I know so if I
received at us from the flows back how
implementation should know what is your
intention which which what you want too
much on destination address or
destination header or you should either
yeah yeah any further questions or
comments all right thank you very much
we have two minutes left but that's just
clearly not enough time to have a useful
conversation about the BG pls miss I'm
again sorry about that encourage you to
find
k10 and talk to him about it thanks
everybody this was I thought a you know
very interactive interesting session see
you next time
blue sheets please