[Music]
I know but it's not but it just does its
broke it's a button yeah I know okay
everybody we're gonna get started this
is the Ellis our working group
maybe um Alistar could you shut that
door no ok so again this is the first
meeting the first session of Dallas our
working group we left off at no well
slide so this is the note well from the
the most current version does anybody
need me to read the note well slide you
stop nodding your head okay so we're
gonna move on to the agenda to these
status slides so see there okay I'm
gonna try and go through these quick we
we had a very prolific third of the year
and got through a lot of these are SCS
published I do have the one no SPF v2
extensions that was actually a beer
document but the other ones all
published granted they most of them are
pretty simple extensions but it was nice
there's there's a thing there it's not
there has nothing to do with Chinese
food the whining is is the MSG that's
MSD to next slide okay so we have a lot
of these we have the ton encapsulations
giraffe still waiting more than a year
now and on the it uses the Ayanna
registry and the BGP document there's a
lot of bests and BGP documents probably
half dozen documents depending on this
it's being presented tomorrow and IDR
hopefully we can move forward
oh we also have the OSPF OSPF and
OSPF III extensions and we're waiting on
the inter up with LD P draft and the M
POS data plane segment routing drafts
those are both spring documents and I'm
hoping the former I think the former is
almost done
the latter I'm not sure Interop with LD
P LD P is missing next slide okay the
first one H bit support that's been
waiting on the office they promised me
something this week so actually we have
updated the graph but we missed their
deadline so it will be done soon so it's
often right now it opens up it opens it
opens when the ITF starts okay so you
can you can update it and we can ping L
borrow and let them know this comments
eius eius extensions for now we'll have
all of our OS r documents or MPLS data
plane segment routing will be once we
satisfy we got two of them on the RFC
queue waiting for miss references with
miss refs and this one
once we get past LRO's review he just
gave us comments in the last week or two
we'll have them all done and we'll be
ready to start on other the flooding and
other documents we have these two yang
models their way down ad to review
they're kind of big but they've got they
they should be alright they've gone
through several yang doctor abuse and I
just requested this cross address family
publication for that one excellent
this is in working through a glass call
and encourage everybody to review it
this is the more deterministic restart
signaling for is
is similar to what we have before SPF so
you can do like a pre-planned Reese you
can you can request restart graceful
restart procedures prior to restarting
and we believe these two are ready for a
working grass call we have the intent to
do them they've been around quite a long
time there's at least for those bf one
there's some implementation work I don't
I don't know about is is I'm not sure
but I know we have OSPF and next slide
okay we're looking for both these two is
is and OSPF the ELC giraffes show who's
not here but I think Stefan's going to
update these and we'll probably we
actually have enough changes we'll
probably do another working group last
call I haven't talked to the offers but
at that time we may think about
combining them into one since we're
going to do another working book last
call anyway next slide and flex
algorithm there's some implementation
momentum I don't think we're ready for
working to the last call yet but it's
it's just moving along where else it
well one thing I did I talked to the IDR
chairs after the first IDR session and
especially for some of these simpler
extensions they'd like to have us
allocate an Dianna code point for BGP LS
and do it in the same draft so you don't
have you know for every extension in is
is and OSPF just like we we combined
some of the drafts with is is and OSPF
when they were really sitting exactly
the same extension just encoded two
different way in the same in the same
spirit
we'd also defined the bgp LS code point
right away and we got these two yang
models for sr now that we've got these
base i think before we did anything
those were just going at least wait till
we get
through the ad review on the bass yang
models before we try and working group
last qualities but we're gonna do that
shortly after that alright next
presentation oh yeah we've been pretty
busy as far as discussions and we're
gonna have updates on at least at least
the first two of these graphs these are
the more significant ones the other two
are sort of protocol maintenance that we
approved one is one request across from
the PCE working group we already have
PCE discovery just an extension on it
also discover the indication that the
PCE server my at the moment I can't
remember the name that what is it PC
what yeah yeah yeah oh yeah yeah they
learn the md5 but I was thinking of the
difference between the client and you
call it the PCs that's the client yeah
yeah for the client to discover the
server's security and that's it yeah so
I guess the sort of big thing that we've
managed to do is get everyone to mostly
agree to the resolution with the dynamic
flooding so that's a good say yes od I
think your
good morning so I'm very pleased to
report that we have accepted the dynamic
flooding draft as a working group
document we have there's no page let's
see I happen to show some friends some
of our simulation results and they
commented that they wanted to see a
whole lot more of them so have some of
those to show you thank you mr. Scudder
we have two outstanding issues we've
already discussed a little bit on the
mailing list these are the question of
how fast we add temporary additions to
the flooding topology when we realize
we've had partition and then also are we
going to include lands in the flooding
topology as an explicit part of the
topology description
we've had that hashed out a bit on the
mailing list but have not come to
consensus we this week had a little
lunch and arm wrestling match between
the parties in having the discussion we
think we have come to rough agreement
there and we will return that discussion
to the mailing list to achieve consensus
after IETF on with the pretty pictures
so just to show the flooding topology on
some simple dense graphs this is k5 the
complete graph on five nodes the dotted
lines show the links that are excluded
from the flooding topology so you see
that this is already winning about 50%
next slide okay 10 this is a full graph
a complete graph on 10 nodes as you can
see this is already having wonderful
effects right most of the links are no
longer included as we scale upwards next
slide this is K 160 160 nodes and very
Spartan next slide
some of you are interested in leaf spine
topologies this is a Lisa pint apology
with eight spines and 200 leaves and as
you can see it looks dense but actually
this is very sparse this is like 95% of
the links our block is this flooding
topology have two ways to get to
everything all these all these
simulations are one-way everything is by
connected the diameter is constrained
and also the degree of each node is
constrained so what that means here is
that all the spines are equally loaded
next slide we also were interested in
looking at close to apologies this is a
three stage with 16 top nodes 64 middles
and 160 leaves at the bottom as you can
see algorithm does all sorts of weird
things but turns out a beautiful picture
okay next slide there are topologies
where the algorithm doesn't do pretty
things this is an 8x8 grid just a
chessboard and as you can see the dotted
lines are relatively few and far between
this does not work very well why not
well it's not a dense graph the problem
that we're trying to solve is flooding
on dense graphs when you throw this on a
graph that's not dense
it doesn't help very much doesn't hurt
and that's actually more of the point
for our testing is to show that the
algorithm doesn't break anything but it
doesn't really help very much okay next
slide
so just to recap the two issues we have
outstanding temporary flooding so when
we realize we need to add temporary
flooding onto the the flooding topology
because we have had a partition then
there are two opinions ones do we add as
much stuff as
and folks some folks favor this because
it minimizes the convergence time we
want to get the flooding topology back
to covering everything as quickly as
possible that's certain
so do we turn just turn on all the links
and see what happens
flipside is well if we add on too many
links we can recreate a catastrophic
collapse and obviously that's got
infinite convergence time so that's not
good so how do we do this so we don't
trigger that and therefore the
conservative approach might be to add
links very slowly again we're gonna
continue discussing this on the mailing
list but those are the two prevailing
opinions so no one's asking for the
goldilocks solution well everybody wants
both of course and nobody has proposed
something that gives us both the second
issue is putting pseudo nodes in the
flooding topology currently as the craft
reads you cannot describe a LAN in as
being part of the flooding topology
this comes gives us some topological
constraints if we do have a flooding
topology that might include lands and
area leader cannot describe it then you
might get a topology that is radically
different than what the area leader
intended and that could be a problem we
I think we've come to the agreement that
if LAN is in the flooding topology that
all nodes should be flooding to and from
that lamp selectively flooding that gets
really complicated really quickly so
then the two opinions that have been put
forth on the mailing list either we put
all lands on the flooding topology and
this makes everything very very simple
or if we have too many lands that seems
like that could be problematic
so we need to be specific and that's
that allows us the the area leader to
describe exactly what should and should
not be on the topology so again we'll
have that discussion continued on
mailing list and that's all I have any
questions thank you very much
to clear it fast enough in my old age
year dave allen from erickson well this
speak up do you have any information on
the diameter of the flooding topology
relative to the type of graph the
question is do we have any information
on the diameter of the flooding topology
relative to the original graph so that
is algorithm specific in our
implementation yes we constrained the
diameter we definitely increase the
diameter okay for a complete graph the
diameter originally is one as you can
see the diameter in graphs we generate
much higher so that of course causes
increased flooding time but we do have a
diameter constraint in there trying to
minimize the diameter because we don't
want it to go unbounded okay thank you
AC Linda I got a I got a quick one here
I I definitely agree that you would not
want to do anything on a land but flood
you know you know basically because you
have designated I mean a dr or it is
it's gonna be a good flooded to all the
notes you don't want to change your on a
chain touch that but wouldn't it be
algorithm specific just whether you you
you made you know how you prefer glands
and how you didn't I don't see why you'd
need to maybe I don't understand the
problem I don't see why you need to put
all the lands on the flooding topology
if the algorithm didn't need to put them
all on so so the real question is
whether we are allowed to specify lands
in the signaling of the flooding apology
okay if you can't specify it then no
matter what your algorithm happens to do
there's no way to say so do we have the
specificity in the actual description
any other questions I just want to test
okay this isn't my keys work
going once going twice
done thank you I think it's less right
yes or less this is I this yes but this
is the alignment where can't see the
whole slide anyways unless Ginsburg
talking about the spine leaf draft of
next slide please
so this is just a summary we've
presented this before can run over
overview of what this draft achieves
it's a modest extension to is is so in
spine later topologies using these
modest modest extensions you can get a
great reduction in the amount of
flooding basically what we do is in most
cases we completely eliminate flooding
to the leaves entirely we also have some
support for zero-touch provisioning or
you can advertise your tier and just
discover it we do have provisions to
handle what you end up with basically if
it new leaf nodes is default routes to
the spines but in cases where spine
notes don't have full connectivity to
all of the leaves
we have provisions to get a subset of
the more specific routes that are
required so that we don't black hole
things and we have hooks so that
extensions like the flooding topology
that Tony was just talking about we can
advertise that the the links to the
leaves are not being used for flooding
so the algorithm can can know what those
links are and just basically take them
out of the calculation of the flooding
topology next slide
so what's happened since the previous
version we became a working group
document we had some comments about some
of the information that we were allowing
to be sent in homes we've simplified
that and split it
we had one TLV now we have two different
tlvs I'll talk about that a little more
and we've reintroduced support some
limited support for a connection leaf to
leaf connections next slide so when this
was actually a long time ago you had
this leaf Khalif support and it was the
one place it kind of scared me where
there was possibilities for like loops
it seemed like right
did you guys I mean do you think you
addressed did you see that as well and
do you think you addressed it yes but
I'll talk abouts more so you can ask
more a more specific question okay so we
have a spying leaf TLV in the hello
which does a couple of things one it
allows you to advertise your tier if you
are able to discover it and there's a
bit that just says the tier field is
valid and if that gets not set whatever
values in there is ignored and then we
have two flags one of which is sent by
the leaf node that says hey I would I
would like to be part of the reduce
flooding which means I don't want my spy
known neighbors to flood LSPs to me and
we have an AR bit that's sent by the spy
notes that indicates that they can be
used as a default gateway this TLV
previously had additional information
which we moved into a separate TLV so
now this is the information that's the
only information in our extensions
that's sent in halls next slide we
created a new TLV which we call the leaf
set TLV and this is going to be sent in
Circuit scope Dallas Peas
as defined by RFC 7356
and there are currently two sub tlvs
that we've defined associated with this
TLV we have a leaf neighbor's sub TOB
which is sent by the spine nodes and
that indicates the set of leaf nodes to
which this by known has connectivity
this information is useful to the leaf
nodes they could compare the set of leaf
node neighbors that each spine owned
advertises and therefore detect that og
this this by known neighbor that I might
be using as default gateway doesn't
actually have reach ability to the full
set of leaf nodes next slide the second
sub TLD and in the leaf set TLV is sent
by the leaf nodes so in the case I was
just talking about where the leaf node
discovers that hey there's a spy node I
was using him as a default gateway but
he doesn't seem to have full
connectivity to all the nodes the spine
node can send a request or the leaf node
excuse me can send a request to the
spine node to said could you pretty
please send me prefix reach ability
information associated with this set of
leaf nodes so it's just a list of the
system IDs of the leaf nodes which he's
retrieved from the sub TLD that we
showed on the previous slide the spine
node will then respond by sending and
yet again in the circuit scoped osp's
he'll simply send the standard prefix
for each ability tlvs such as 135 and
236 - the leaf node on request and say
okay here's you know here are the
prefixes that are associated with that
leaf node and that allows the leaf node
to install more specific routes to those
destinations next level okay as Chris's
question highlighted in in early
versions of the draft we had connections
between the leaf nodes there were some
issues raised with that we took it out
but there are deployment cases where
people would like to be able to send
traffic direct
from leaf to leaf so we put this back in
but I think I've jumped ahead of myself
here yeah yeah sorry you got me sorry I
was just thinking we're about to go to
that I'm sorry back back up let me get
this light because that's all so we
we've introduced to bits
one of them is is new to this version of
the draft that's associated with an
existing TLD the link attribute sub TLV
that was defined by RFC 50:29 the the
I've listed here all the bits that are
including the ones that are currently
defined so there's a local protection
and an excluded from local protection
those were defined many years ago the
two new bits one of them is sent by the
spines that says hey I am connected to
some leaf nodes that want to be excluded
from flooding you know and these are the
link this is the one of those links and
that tells an extension like the
flooding topology the optimized flooding
topology that says hey you don't need to
consider this link just part of your
flooding topology that's been defined
for some time in versions of the draft
the new bit that we added in in this new
version of the draft is sent by the leaf
nodes and this bit just simply indicates
I am connected to at least one spine
note and you'll see how we use that now
you can go to the next slide so again we
we put back in the ability to to support
leaf to leaf connections we're
recommending that you only have one leaf
neighbor because there are some
consequences of having many largely it
means you're going to increase flooding
unnecessarily
one things we want to do with the lease
we're trying to keep the leaf
implementation fairly simple so we're
not proposing that the leaf note do any
kind of special logic associated with
flooding so if you now connect if the
leaf node is not gonna doesn't have any
leaf node neighbors he simply sends his
own LSPs to the spy known as heat or
Moyer would do but now if he has a leaf
neighbor he's going to get the LS piece
from that leaf neighbor unless we define
some special rules in this case that
he's also going to send those LS B's to
the spine so the spines not going to get
in this case buying one for example
would get LS B's from Leafs one both
from leaf one and from leaf two
obviously you start having lots of leaf
neighbors you've increased the amount of
flooding so we're recommending that you
limit this to one leaf neighbor which I
think from a deployment standpoint meets
the the common deployment cases the that
there are two modes that the leaf to
leaf connection can be used in we really
only want if you only want to use the
leaf to leaf connection for local
traffic then the leaf node will set the
overload bit in its LSP which tells the
spy known do not use me for transit to
any of my other neighbors and in
particular the other my leaf neighbor if
you want to allow transit traffic in the
case where let's say I'm the leaf node I
got isolated from all of the other spine
nodes so the only way now for spine node
to get traffic delivered to me is to go
through another leaf node so in this
case you don't want the over a little
bit to be set but you want this to be
used as the link of last resort so you
set the hi metric we're recommending max
metric - 2
and this makes this the link of last
resort I think that's it or yeah so
that's the update and we welcome
comments so I think that the earlier
issue I had to look it was almost two
years ago it was like if you had you
would like defaulting over to the leaf
but then you could have a better metric
backer it was something weird like that
I guess yeah I considered that I'd have
to go back to the Russians but I think I
don't think we ever talked about setting
the overload bit before I think that
addresses that problem in it and so the
over this would be for both leaves so
everything would be configured in the
same mode correct yeah so what what what
I I guess I
I missed it that there was this biggest
thing update I haven't read the update
sorry
so the overload bit when a leaf gets
isolated the other leaf would have to
reach the leaf that still connected
would have to reset over a little bit
yeah this is not meant to be a dynamic
setting this is like how do I want to
use this link if I only want to use it
for local traffic then I set the
overload bit if I want to use this as
link of last resort in case isolated
okay okay oh but you oh I see I see I
understand now I thought this was it
would change okay makes more sense
sounds ooh how many have read the update
about know about or I advise everybody
to to read it this this has got a little
more complex than it was but not too
much more but I'd advise everybody
including myself to read it yeah I mean
if you it's always fun to find loops
right so they might be hiding here still
the go go okay bounty
what one reason we adopted this is
because it seemed like a limit it seemed
to address data centers and it was a lot
simpler than a generic flooding we said
okay we can we can we can do this and we
can do something more more generic so
I'm hoping it's not getting too complex
SID
when she cleared up the thing of the
leaf leak being a static configuration
makes it thanks okay
this draft was introduced in Bangkok and
I'll just be reporting on the updates I
think they from the biggest news or most
welcome change for me is we got some
additional authors next slide so what
were the the motivation for this largely
had to do with we've seen in the field
some interoperability issues in how
implementations handle tlvs which are on
either unrecognized or disallowed or
incorrectly formatted when we had
inconsistent behavior where osp's some
implementations would discard LS B's
some little implications wouldn't and
you end up with link state databases
that are inconsistent on routers in the
network which really leaves the network
in a broken state there's been
enhancements a few years ago in terms of
how purges are handled and these have
backwards compatibility issues and that
played into some of the stars we've seen
in the field as well as far as
interoperability problems so those were
the major motivations next slide
okay what's changed again additional
authors have been added in the course of
reviewing the draft with the new authors
we
discovered and I in a registry issue so
we're addressing that and we've added a
recommendation about controlling
behaviors that are not backwards
compatible next slide
so the registry issue RFC 62-38 sis
purge origination TLV so that you could
identify the source of a purge which is
a very important thing to be able to do
in troubleshooting some problems in
networks the text in the draft was
absolutely correct it said this TLV
should be found in all bridges and must
not be sent in an LS be basically a non
purged LSP an LSP with a nonzero
remaining lifetime unfortunately the Ino
section and this got put into the actual
INR registry the the flag for the LSP
that is the non Burke's Dallas piece got
set to yes and it should have been no so
we're correcting that so again the text
in the RFC was absolutely correct it's
just the the setting of the flag in the
registry was not next slide there was
also discussion we thought it would be
prudent to recommend that when you have
transitions to new behaviors that are
not backwards compatible that we
recommend that implementations put some
control zone as to when to enable that
one example not the only example but one
example of that has to do with the the
introduction of the purge origination
TLV if you look at the cryptographic
authentication as defined in fifty three
or four and 5310 it was very strict it
said the only TLV you can have an
approach if you have cryptographic
cryptographic authentication is the
authentication TLV when we introduced
Pio I that obviously meant there was at
least one additional T
viii that could legitimately be found in
a purge
so implementations which are following
5304 strictly as they should would then
reject purge that had a Pio I so you
need to be careful as to when you enable
this behavior if you have cryptographic
that is the use of the purge TLV in the
presence of cryptographic authentication
so what we've added to the drafts is
just the recommendation that says in
such cases it's prudent for
implementations to provide controls for
when to enable this next slide so I have
to say that this has been amazingly
enough and quite surprising to me this
has been the most popular draft I've
ever written whatever that says so we've
gotten a lot of support from this
there's also those we published
yesterday we actually published a update
to this based on the comments we have
received from Bruno it's mostly using
more clear language no real edition in
terms of the substance of the draft but
hopefully it's it's more clear so we
think this is ready for working group
adoption does anybody in the room
disagree with that
yes okay thanks I mean we'll ask on the
list if anybody objects as well but have
an obviously
Peter
okay so I'm beer from Cisco so I'm going
to just give a quick update on the SRB
6i sigh this extension draft so we just
added a single new flag in the locator
TOB which basically indicates that the
locator is users at any cost one one
reason to do this because there are
applications where you don't want to use
these seats from the locator which isn't
any cost one for example for a PA or
favor you really want to enforce the
traffic over a certain note so that's
the use case that's the B to be added
thanks fine and we also updated the
table in the draft which reference to
the supported end point behaviors which
are advertised by esaias it might choose
the latest network programming draft and
it also includes the endpoint behavior
identifier it's just for clarity so you
don't need to go and look in other
drafts would be what the identifiers are
so other than that the the draft is
stable there are implementations you can
go to next slide please
there are multiple implementations
available even working together so I
think this draft is ready for the
working group adoption if there are any
questions please feel free
yeah like I just Alaska how many people
have read the draft how many people were
sort of following the spring network
programming that that adoptions about
halfway through there's some there's a
lot of support in some discussion about
other issues but I think we're going to
ask for an adoption call on this one
especially if it if the immediately
after the network programming is adopted
in spring we were sort of waiting for it
they asked for adoption last in a
Bangkok but we were we delayed until the
net at least the network programming
call for adoption okay
okay so the next one is the OSP v3
extension for for beer next slide so we
have RFC eight four four four which
describes the OSP v2 extension for beer
with an TLS encapsulation we need the
same work to be done in OSP v3 so this
is the draft that deals with that the
flooding scope and all the machinery in
a protocol is exactly the same as in the
RFC eight four four four so next slide
please
so just to recap what so what we define
we defined the beer sub theory which is
carried within the prefix so it uses the
new II inter and inter area prefix OS
ice to distribute the beer specific
information I mean the fields in the
inner circle we are exactly the same I'm
not going to repeat them as India's PB
two extension this is a sub theory of
the beer the beer TLV which carries the
MPLS specific information for beer so
again I mean the fields in the in the
sub TLB match is the one in your spirit
too so this has been presented in the
beer working group I think they're going
to own the document if I'm not mistaken
so the reduction in request is basically
going to be a I'm presenting here
because it's an extension to the ITP so
if you guys have any concerns just let
me know and we can work it out so when
we chartered beer they wanted to go on a
fast track and on all the documents and
we agreed that they could own these
these sauce extensions in beer so it
makes sense since since OSPF and v2 and
is is are in beer it makes sense for
this one to go there as well especially
since this is just using the extended LS
ace the reason we didn't do OSPF v3
before was because the extended lsas
hadn't been published yet now that it's
published
implementations for going forward and
and finishing that work that's correct
so I I mean it'd be nice if I mean it'd
be good especially if oh s PF
implementers and people who debug and
deploy OSPF b3 networks would review
this mr. Michael S Gilbert so I'm just
asking does that mean there really is no
working group adoption request here no
it's in a in a bi working group that's
correct
obviously
by an attack yes
okay so the last one is the extension
for OSPF to advertise the admin tax so
it's not working anymore okay all right
so a little bit of a history in Nice BF
v2 and v3 we had a way to send attack
the admin tag with the prefix but this
was only limited to certain prefixes
namely the external and NSSA prefixes we
didn't have a way to advertise admin tag
with into our inter area prefix and we
were also limited to a single one every
fix I mean we all know we have different
use cases for tags we use them for a
distribution for a prefix prioritization
and various use cases for this so what
we actually are proposing is that we are
adding new tag sub TLB for either the
extended prefix TLB in OS p p2 or and
into our inter area or external the
prefix GL is in in the extended OS
baby's real essays what we also added is
the tags for the links and whether there
is something that we want to do is up to
the discussion because we have the si oh
geez where we can actually advertise
similar 32-bit values for each link it's
up to the working group to decide
whether we want to do it for prefix for
links as well but the draft itself
proposes the extension to be able to
associate the admin tag which the prefix
or link
okay all right so I mean the deal is
pretty simple it's a bunch of 32-bit
administered attacks in a sub theory so
it's very simple
we've seen this before so the draft also
says about what how we are going to
propagate the admin tags between the
between the areas and during the
translation it also says how to behave
during the summarization where we are
not going to advertise the tags of the
component routes go to the next place
and it also says that if you have a tag
associated with the external or an SSA
LSA in the you know old-fashioned way we
prefer that because we want to be
backward compatible and it also goes
into the discussion that there can be
multiple tags associated now is the
prefix etc so what what the behavior
what oil behaviors that we can use so I
mean natural this is a very simple and
natural extension we want to have the
possibility it's mainly I mean the way I
look at it is for the entire inter area
prefixes to be able to tag them and you
know use this I mean we have the similar
capability nice eyes so I guess it makes
a lot of sense to to adaptation and move
forward what's Ginsburg um I'll ask a
loaded question here and we made a
conscious decision not to support 64-bit
tags I put it in the appendix appendix
of it because the I found no
implementation of 64 bit pegs in eius
eius I asked I asked a lot of people and
nobody knew why yeah I'm complete
agreement with that I just wanted to
verify that we've consciously made that
decision
Stephanie Costa for orange you were
talking about adding tags to links what
was the use case you were targeting to
that you pointed s energy but we have
also admin hooks which could be
we didn't have any particular use case
we just thought you know if we are
adding this whether it makes sense again
I don't have a strong opinion we put it
there we can remove it people think
there's no use case for it I don't
really know
yeah I think we have sufficient
mechanism today to tag links fair enough
as a co-author I would agree as well
this was I did this draft a long time
ago there was no burning requirement for
it and we had full working group agendas
and things that we needed to get in
front of the working groups so we kind
of delayed it we had to session said
okay we now's the time it so there's
nothing too contentious until tomorrow
and so we put that we put it on the
agenda we said okay let's try and
socialize it but I agree now now we did
so we had not just with this this this
predated our whole discussion of
attributes okay okay okay that's the
link tag I think I think I think we can
take it out I think it's captain as he's
known as in the IDR working group
hopefully I won't get in trouble for
that hi Kate ontological Cisco so this
is an update on the OSPF reverse metric
draft just a recap it was presented in
London it was just named differently
back then and we have equivalent
functionality in is is already there
also we also have a SP of two part
metric draft which covers kind of
similar capable
or at least can be used for this use
cases for broadcast LAN so what is draft
essentially does is brings this
capability for you know point-to-point
links and other types reminder on water
draft is it enables OSPF router and
septa cable for both v2 and v3 to signal
to its neighbor the reverse matrix so
it's a metric that a neighbor should use
towards the link to this router and this
is done in a link-local signaling
mechanism using the LLS block in hello
messages when the neighbor receives in
this case r2 receives the reverse matrix
signaling then it may use that value or
it's a we have support for offset as
well as value in its router a let us say
towards r1 so this mechanism is
link-local so it works it's really
between routers on a link and it's it's
it's kind of transparent to other
routers in the network so for this we
have introduced the reverse metric DL
reverse metric TLV what's the new update
in this draft is we have also included
the reverse key metric TLV because this
was something that was not covered and
there was no support for I mean we had
missed multi topology ID which was not
there in the previous version so that's
the other update that's you know been
introduced apart from that there is
really no significant change in the
document except for some editorial
updates you know which was pointed by
reviews and so on so thing so look
for working group adoption of this draft
at this point nobody yeah how many have
read the draft
yeah about yeah don't count of you you
have yeah we'll take well we'll discuss
it a little bit on the list the use
cases I know one of the use cases is the
same use case that the large packets are
in VF d l2 VPN where that you know where
you're you don't know the
characteristics of the underlying l2 yes
yes yes that's yeah that's one of the
use cases and that's the same yeah
same motivation so does anybody object
to possibly taking those Ana's work no
there was nobody
so this this one is OSPF introducing PFD
strictmode just had a presentation of
this earlier today in the PFD working
group and this is something that we have
in multiple implementations already so
we are what we are trying to bring out
here is to define it more formally let
us say and to see how it helps in you
know some of the Interop issues and
concentration so the problem statement
here is that PFD is being used by OSPF
for detecting faults in the forwarding
plane and primarily detecting it fast
and bringing down the adjacency however
a PFD router does not know as part of
its signaling whether its neighbor has
support for PFD and as a result of this
the BFD OSPF adjacency is brought up
without you know considering the weather
the BFD session is brought up or not I
mean it's brought up independently now
in some scenarios we have seen or
observed issues where the SPF adjacency
may come up but the PFD may not come up
even though PFD is enable on both sides
of the link and this could be because of
some problem in the underlying path now
this you know could be for written
various reasons including transport
lossy links you know degraded links so
on so forth and what this results in is
even though the OSP of adjacency may
come up and we advertise it in routing
the traffic overhead would you know get
affected as well as in case of lossy
links you know you may suddenly find
sometimes OSPF adjacency is also
flapping so it's a term that is
introduced in the network so what the
draft proposes is
really to enable OSPF router to signal
to its neighbor that you know it's AIT's
running BFD and be that it does not want
to bring up the OSPF adjacency unless
the PFD session is up between them so
which means that the BFD has verified
the bi-directional connectivity and only
post that we try to bring up the OSPF
adjacency and this is what we are
referring to as PFD strictmode in this
document so this there is a similar
extension in ISS 6213 and it's kind of
similar functionality that we are
proving so how are we doing it we have
in the OSPF hello messages we have the
limp local signaling block and in there
we have a TLB where which allows it's
called LS extended option and fields
flags field which allows routers on the
link to indicate capability to each
other and where we've introduced a B bit
there and this B bit indicates you know
supports or capability or let's say
interest to operate in bf District mode
now the PFD session establishment when
when the routers two routers detect each
other they are supporting this bf
district more then as soon as a new
neighbor is detected PFD session is
requested immediately and the keychain
key thing is there is some we're trying
to clarify in how to do this in the
fitted into the OSPF neighbor as possum
and the proposal is that the neighbor is
held in the init state until the BFD
session is up between them what that
also means is that we do not the router
does not include the neighbor IP address
in its own hello
until the BRP session is that this is
essentially will block the adjacency of
the neighbors FSM to move into you know
to where next art so moment of BFD
session is up include the hello neighbor
address in the hello and then the FSM
proceeds as exists today so there is no
change after that from backward
compatibility aspects this mode is going
to get employed or come into action only
when the two neighbors agree or you know
exchange this capability and this is
only I mean if it's not there than
though SP of neighbor FSM goes like like
existent today and the change only
changes in this initial bring up so it's
basically the transition from init state
onwards the rest of the neighbor of SM
is not is unchanged there is also no
change in the way BFD is used to you
know bring down an OSP of adjacency
handing of bfk down events all of that
no nothing is changed from that
perspective so a little more details on
the bf be part so this is again only
changing only changes are in the initial
bring up there's also more details and
text in the draft we try to cover
scenarios where this capability or this
option is turned on for an adjacency
which is already up and there the
proposal is that we do not disturb and
adjacency thats already up it just
continues and you know removal of BFD or
the PRB strictmode also does not disrupt
adjacency that's already up so next
steps we are aware that multiple
implementations have this kind of a
feature support already and it's the way
it's been done is the kind of explicit
configuration support but we've had some
cases within drop
it's not really clear at what state in
the neighbor of SM let's say
implementation should all the neighbor
and how it should go about it
so it also makes troubleshooting
difficult in that aspect so we are
looking to trying to see a working group
was interested in standardizing this and
would appreciate feedback you know and
commit so you found incompatibilities
out there with which I understand that
there is no standard yes so I mean the
key aspect of improv issues is where the
neighbor FSM is held by an
implementation until the B of T is
brought up is it actually functional so
that two parts of it one is that we
don't know whether the neighbor is
strict mode enable so the first way to
get working between let's say to
implementation is that both have this
explicit configuration and then you know
they bring it up now in a case like a
LAN for example where there are you know
you may want to do it with between two
routers but not with the third one is
not capable
that's a provisioning aspect then within
the bring up as well
when the BFD session is every session
cannot be brought up due to some errors
or whatever we see the neighbor FSMs we
do not even see a neighbor let's say on
one router and we see it on a unit or a
two-way state or something it becomes
difficult to figure out what's happening
or where this is that so I guess where I
was going with this is it I mean it's
interesting you've already discovered
this do you cover these cases like it
might be interesting for an appendix or
you know for deployment right like if
this is deployed this is how well
interact with these various you know non
the interoperating and then these are
the results that we currently have with
these you know non-specified non
interoperating things it's not there in
the draft but
what provided some Texas to describe an
operation in kind of like operational
consideration what all information
should be shown or how what logs install
should be done to reflect the state and
you know if the neighbor is not going
beyond in it why is it not going yeah I
mean no such thing is it's interesting
it would probably be interesting to list
the Interop issues you've found that
you'll be fixing sure I mean it doesn't
have a very extensive okay and I mean
many look forward to inputs from other
implementation not sure if there are
implementations which are doing this
differently but we would like to get
feedback on that so let me understand it
so if you get a hello and it doesn't
have the strict bit set you just don't
use PFD as a precondition and just yes'm
it and just goes okay and then if the
bit flips anytime once the session is is
passed Annette you just ignore it you
just keep point yes okay I mean that's
kind of a subtle that naturally falls
out nice and the implementation that's
where it would be really nice to talk to
some other you know get some emitters
that want to do this to collaborate and
make sure yes yes so definitely need no
feedback and inputs there okay thanks we
moe
Hisoka we don't know if it's gonna work
we have to see we don't I don't know why
good yeah
okay it works so on one more from
following today I'm going to talk about
this issue beautiful at introduction
basically I just talked about the
updates in this version so in this
version we remove centralize the
fatality reduction and then we also
updated distributed faladi reduction to
get instructions from the leaders
because of this remove and then we added
a scheduler and consistence check so
firstly we talked about the scheduling
so scheduling for flooding topology
computation so there's a new RFC talking
about a skill for talking about a
scheduling for SPF so right now for some
network we have multiple schedulers I
mean yeah Nodoka normally we have our
routers from multiple vendors so the
wrong hood from one vendor may use a one
type of scheduling for SPF and some of
routers from a defender will use another
schedulers for SPF so the issue is that
using different the schedulers for SPF
we are create more routing moves than
using a same scheduler so this is a toka
instructor in forgive hell in this view
RFC's so as we know so that the suggest
the best practice is that we configure
similar timers are water routers so in
this case we want to have SP
to be triggered at almost at the same
time but sometimes is impossible
so here my example is that for
consecutive SPF executions if we have
two different schedulers that is almost
impossible to have SPF on water knows to
be triggered at the same time so here we
just have two two examples have two
schedulers so once the gradual is that
we just the schedule
SPF in constant delays for example first
SPF delay 200 seconds 200 meter second
and then second consecutive race 200
milliseconds and then serve and so on so
this is a constant delays so another
circuit law is that we have initial
delay for the first one and then for the
consecutive rain and then we use a whole
whole lot of time for example is maybe
100 milliseconds and then the next one
the whole time will be double the first
of the whole and therefore we have an
I'm just a latter run and then the delay
time will be double the first of the
delay so if we have these two kind of
schedulers so is it almost impossible to
configure one over time to have those
SPF to be triggered at the same time so
the this new RFC in fact that we have
was used same circuit less but the
reality is that for those schedule it
for SPF we already implement so we we
have no way to at least no way to do
that right now but for secure him for a
lot in towards computation so right now
we have a is a good point we could is
right for and we needed to have use the
same schedulers for scheduling the
flooding topology computations we were
yes I might be in a menorah
I don't agree that you can prepare FTC
and SPF I don't think they're the same
thing I mean I don't think they require
FTC requires a scheduler or like some
ask as because you don't update ribs and
fibs and yeah it's all internal to the
protocol and it can be done very quick I
don't but yeah it's a good question I
sing about that a lot because if we use
different schedulers
so the flow I don't I won't do it
different right something you need a
scheduler for this you don't with me
let's do it
possible yeah that's another way I think
I may be the batter I have a scheduler
and there was a control because we can
control the timer Paula get faster can i
it's better from Cisco I completely
agree with I see you don't need any
scheduler here yeah because I use the
batter to have a scheduler at least
because if we have a consecutive of
computations and then they may have some
issues yeah so with a scheduler and then
we can have control so you would control
you can compute those time if we're
smaller and then looks like is a we can
cheat with that one right first ask so
since the cane has been opened I don't
like this either but my dislike of this
is we've been able I know there's an RFC
there but we've been doing is eyes for a
really long time without standardizing
and unwire POVs to specify one timer
should fire this is this seems like a
big overreach and it just doesn't need
to be specified I there's other things
that I like in this trap wow this is not
one that says a working person
so another I saw because we right now
this transfer is focused on YouTube the
flight interaction so for this to be the
final action we need a get instructions
from the error leaders so we need a so
after operator configure the
distributive flatten reduction then
Evernote master receive the leader staff
at LV so in this leaders at supper TV
we're happy indication which algorithm
we have used and also should be
indication of what distributed mode and
then so we also should have received
those kind of parameters for the
schedulers evil those configuration is
done on the leader so the last one is a
about a lot in poverty consistencies
check so so for a lot in her body
because flat entomology is computed by
Evernote so one flight already computed
by one node so must be is the same as
the one computed by a master node so if
were to fall out in trouble yet
different
and then the inconsistency occurs so we
need to have some way to detect this
consistency and handle it accordingly
so those so here we just proposed a very
simple way we just define new beat in
the hollow extend the hollow we caught a
flattened hopper a bit or a link so for
each end of the mink each load each
internal order of link so when that this
node have a line table change we can
talk this link we just change that a
pata Pete so if two people are the same
and then regarding to this link the
following property is consistent if they
are different and then we force for
given time people in the for keep in
high and then we think that this a
polite ontology is not consistent
regarding to this link so we can
warning and then on the other side to
side maybe if one side the thing is not
not on the kavagi maybe we just
temporarily assume that were under an
apology that's the I think that's or um
maybe yeah I could provide some color
and that I'm sorry I'm sue hairs most
people know me as a IDR chair that's not
what I'm proposing right now but that'll
give you a place to find my email so two
things on this one just to provide some
color in in some research I've done on
why this problem might be useful one of
the deployments for IDPs is in IP ran
technology some of the IP ran technology
has been sold places and I don't want to
be pejorative because sometimes the for
any particular place in the world
sometimes the US has brownouts and so as
they have brownouts some of the links
transceivers get drowned out
unexpectedly and so I don't know if this
is going to help that I don't know if
it's going to hurt but it is a problem
that you know the research shows if
you're working on convergence and you
don't know if if things are working
right you make the IGP signal something
more to say that I've got the right to
apology or warn you and that that may
help you in the cases where the the link
connectivity you may try be a fee you
know Kate I'm sorry Kate on for my
mispronunciations has this other BFD I'm
just I'm trying to give color and why
some of these problems are are important
based on some research I was asked to do
into some customer problems that that's
comment one I hope that may help at
least that's why I understand the
need for some of the last couple
presentations because it matches some of
the problems that I've were reported and
I was asked to look at a GP convergence
simulations based on the long term work
that Angus lose enough and other people
have done in a GP convergence and how to
look at it in simulations I suspect Tony
simulation has that anyway just a side
comment I hope you don't mind me making
that comment where it might be a boat
window
I think everyone's in violent agreement
with about this yeah you don't have any
arguments okay that's great and what's
the one thing we'd ask does your least
what you looked into for this topology
does it support the mechanisms in this
draft the scheduler and no no mine is
strictly into the problem the the draft
that I put out is strictly the problem
because I wanted to III the first thing
was do the problem
I don't know if way most simulation has
gone into this with that thing I I won't
comment there are two groups doing
research in different solutions so you
may ask way mo and some of his team on
that question rather than me I my first
was to do a purely theoretical and then
look at some improvements and and do
some simulation based on aggregation so
I'll point back to way mo and other
places that that's just dodging because
I didn't do that particular work does
that it then I was I clear enough and my
caveat to say the theoretical points
that it would that that if you don't
have consistency but that's that's a
general no well known problem back to
2000 or 1995 because we used to have
early days of internet we used to have
the same problem 1997 we had blackout
half half done links people our Father
second question is for ACI if I've ended
this topic okay so
most open-source implementations that
I've worked with and I'll just say open
source and other code bases I've worked
with whether you have a scheduler or not
your code when you look at it has an
inherent ratio of scheduling for sending
out is is when you said I don't think
there should be a scheduler did you
really mean yeah
did you really could you give a little
color on that because that doesn't
really fit again the theoretical work
from the stuff for it yeah they always
assume you have some sort of range well
he's talking about the distributed
algorithm right so that would imply I
think the best schedule there is no
schedule err at all that's my opinion
for that because I think I think I think
that that is a very simple computation
and the the problem you really have is
the one that Tony was talking about
right with what what you do in the
transition periods whether you do a lot
or you try and do just the union of the
old and the new and do a little those
are those are that's more it isn't issue
us that than the scheduling yeah it is
it is in the transition but the self
synchronicity and jitter we once had was
to deal with the fact that if you have
no scheduler you can get into this
synchronicity problem so maybe I think
maybe sue you because AC said none my I
was saying something different than yes
yes like what I was saying was I don't
think this should be standardized
I'm not saying listen if you want to put
scheduling in I mean and we've got Dec
it decades of experience right I mean we
have we know how to we have ideas about
back off timers and and it's worked just
fine for decades for that not to be
standardized right it's not that I'm I'm
not saying you know if your
implementation needs based on you know I
mean this is an implementation thing
right like if if it has a if it's
cooperatively multitasks or who knows
what right like you you might have a
better timer set up for
for that particular thing to get the the
behavior that you're looking for that I
think you're alright but I shouldn't be
on the wire okay this is not on a wire
it's just for so we assume each note or
Evernote use the same schedule that
there's no Wi-Fi but if you're
standardizing what to use it's on the
wire yeah this one just the option this
one lv lv is option that's on the wire I
don't I don't want to take too much of
the working time but one of the reason
we early on put and I'm sure the the
experts like listen you put jitter and
this stuff is to get rid of cell
synchronicity and we're back into
redoing some of the algorithm and you
know I'm not seeing the same topic we
reiterating and I'm just wondering why
about for for Tony's algorithm if if
there's a you know are we gonna get into
the big Q calculation sending out big
bursts of stuff or do we just not have
the problem because our interfaces are
so faster I think this is an interesting
thing to talk about right i mean we are
under we're working on it right and i
think it's interesting to talk about you
know when links are added when they're
not added and all of this right but I
just when you actually calculate a
flooding topology could be a part of
that discussion I just don't see why we
have to I mean if we want to be agile
right you don't want to be specifying
this stuff right I mean Island wire
protocol it would be lovely if we didn't
have to specify anything and then less
is more in in much of the thing I think
the questions again the questions behind
some of these desires are what I'd like
to see us discuss in a revised thing
because we had the problem in the past
we had the problem self synchronous so
as we change these floodings are we
going to get into the same problem how
are we going to handle you know most of
the if our art is only you if you talk
to Lee and there are people but you guys
are wanting to do with some of this as
well they only take care
single link failure tomorrow I'll show
you where we have multiple in failures
that are rolling blackouts so just just
a call based on some of what he's doing
toward the problem behind it so I would
like to request for options for this one
because for distributor faladi reduction
and then we have discussing a modest for
a long time and so I have a chair
comment um you know we had a lot of
back-and-forth and we were trying to
figure out where things are going and
how to move forward and perhaps
something I think maybe got lost along
the way this my expectation from the
outcome of all of our discussions was
that this was going to be primarily your
draft was primarily going to be a
specification of a standardized
distributed algorithm and what this
looks that's now in its in your appendix
of your document it's not normative and
that this instead is talking more about
I think kind of a generic flooding thing
right I mean a generic dynamic floating
thing for example I actually I like your
FT bits so if you want to go that
there's also think so this is this is
calling out you know possible miss
configurations or problems in the
network this is very valuable
information for an operator okay
but this is work I think that you should
be working with you know on our now
working group adopted document right I
mean this should go into the generic
signaling signaling that something is
broken is a generally useful thing right
so don't you think that this should go
in the in the dynamic flooding no this
is is specific to distribute to your
distributed algorithm yeah that's good
question because of what distributed
algorithm Evernote will compute a lot in
topology right no I
your distributed algorithm that's
generally because the the working group
document that we adopted right covers is
about signaling either a centralized
flooding topology or it's also for
signaling the area leader
and the distribute algorithm number that
is the generic document that we're going
to use right yeah that's what this was
supposed to be about a concrete
distributed algorithm right if we're
gonna be monitoring this in other words
this is the wrong place or this is what
I think I'm trying to say because we
don't we don't want it's a working group
document now but Tony's draft that we
had dropped adopted right is is the
framework upon which centralized and
distributed is built on right going
forward we have distributed algorithms
need to be standardized centralized owns
so that's that branch is done but we
still have to work on distributed
algorithms that's where the I think
that's what I thought was gonna come out
of your revised draft and and things
like recognizing that things are broken
should I think be a more generally so
it's a generally useful thing right why
should it just be your algorithm of
benefits yeah that's good question so I
wanna clarify this one so you mention
that is stupid one so will receive the
instructions from the leaders so I
already described here so every node
will master receive instructions from
the leader indicated so there could be
broke me I mean you don't expect it to
be broken in either the centralized
distributor its distributed no case
that's why this is good to determine in
either case you know because if somebody
could have trouble they could not be
receiving and installing that in some
situations and and installing the the
centralized topology correctly I mean it
just just like the distributed could
could not work I mean both could not
work you don't you you expect it to work
all the time and that's why I think
generally applicable I know I think
needs more more cases of artistry what
kind of this case and then you wonder
generalize and how either did you
realize oh I got an idea but is most
this is supposed to be about an augur
you're not supposed to be we want the
draft we adopted to talk about
centralized and distributed right we
don't want to we don't want I think that
there was definitely this and maybe my
fault
and I will take this because I think I
was originally talking about moving
distributed out of the thing and that
was not where we landed right where we
landed was we have a general framework
document with sig how to signal the
information and then we were going to
have distributed algorithms that were
standardized outside of that and I think
when at first when we were first talking
about it on the mailing list it was
being called the centralized draft and
the distributed draft and that's why I
think the confusion is but that's not
where we ended up right because because
the work we adopted up front in order to
move forward covers both cases right say
covers signaling first centralized and
distributed so things like this like the
FT bit not this one with the FT bit I
mean this is this is generally useful it
should just go into the working groups
document that covers centralizing and
distributed signaling right because this
is signaling in a generic way about
distributed out distributed flooded
right yeah this is a because of using
the email you just ask her we removed a
centralized one at either remove the
centralized one I think we should have a
distributor of flagging relations
because what is tribulus forgotten
reduction okay with the process and I
mean we we want one document right we
don't we're it's not it's not Tony's
document anymore it's not anybody's
document it's LS are working group
document now right everybody gets credit
who works on it let's get past that
right let's just get work done and you
know and everyone should get credit for
the work they do and so that's not that
should not be an issue right but we
don't why would we have two documents
saying that anyway I thought we'd all
agreed to it it sounds like there's
still some confusion maybe we can talk
about it offline and also I think
therefore that is Jupiter 1 there are
some lists of a CBOC example are we for
this Rubin one we need a scheduler for
exam or for Evernote we'll use same
schedule our buddy
have agreement on that and that should
be discussed on the mailing list and if
for some reason you're able to convince
everyone that we should have a scheduler
it should go in the working group
document we've already adopted is it's a
generic thing unless it pertains if for
some reason the algorithm you come up
with that you want to standardize no no
where's this scheduler in particular
then it might be appropriate to go in
that specific draft right these are the
DISA gradual is just we just maybe use
adjust but Evernote I agree and then use
the same schedule as the same because
it's scheduled already well if you think
it's generally applicable to all all
distributed solutions and it should be
going into our generic signaling
document all right I mean not into a
separate one unless you're just
proposing as a way to talk about it
before we merge it in but you know again
I thought you were doing and distributed
algorithm hello and I'm from from Canada
comma you know I have also parties Casa
really at least for the TV remote and
the centralized mode and I know I I
think I think the start point and the
folks point of the counter working
dropped either for the centralized
signalized mode but in general
deployment I think the teachable
monetary is more prefer and you know
so there are overlap for these two
documents and after discussing how
separated separated and currently hermit
charger provides some issue for
especially for the mundo he's super the
most forged on what the f key beta I
think they did unfair to put his
solution or is the is easier into
account mode so I mean do you say unfair
yeah you know we're not talking fairness
this is standard right I got that I know
I know we are doing uh ideal señor about
the force that no standard yeah I think
the way so the
provide some different solution the
first thing is centralized honorees that
he secures Rosa yeah we all agree that
the distributed is is one of the things
we're now Larry and you know all the
easier the solution are coming first the
problem or after not a problem of the
Pawnee stopped it doesn't that doesn't
matter we separate we're separating the
two things it's not about the velocity
right it's we have a framework for
signaling which is not about the
algorithms there's no algorithm
specifying that document on purpose
because we want to divorce those two
things we have signaling which is easy
it's easy to figure that out it's hard
to figure the algorithms out that's
where the work is that's where the hook
if that's where the fame is if it's very
nice come up with a great algorithm
right but the signaling is boring work
we need to get out of the way so we can
work on the hard problems I think the
single union but they can't be and and
separated very clearly so you know I
think we we should the survey that
document so your opinion is we should
separate the signaling for distributed
and centralized as area there is no
overlap for some you know for FB people
why you by the way you're going against
the rough consensus of working prepare
the rough concerns of the working group
is that it's it should be combined into
a single document we adopted it on that
so we're probably not going to go back
but you know go back I think of a ways
to the go-go to achievement a solution
now there are you know kind of the folks
point that you the kind of working group
working document either for the personal
item or the vo froggie in the final tab
Freudian flabby in the final project you
know this is I think I need a better
understand I don't understand what your
objection is this is just how we do work
in the idea if we adopt a document we
all work on it people nobody's not going
to get credit for the work they do we do
discuss technical solutions we discussed
the problems we discuss solutions and we
pick the best we try to pick the best
technical solution for the problems that
are there right I mean if we need schizo
if we need to have tea bit we need to
have to keep it if we need a scheduler
we need to schedule the TLB none of that
nobody's saying no to any of this stuff
but I'm just saying it's in the wrong
place here right because we already have
a document for signaling yes I gave her
more details I think in your request
option in your statement is that Tony's
a draft we're focused on the centralized
centralized I said that was a mistake I
said I made a mistake when I initially
said that and and that wasn't what we
agreed to at the end of the process
that's not where we landed I think about
need to take that you know somewhere
else right because it's pretty clear
from the email Tony had sent a mail at
some point saying I think we're looking
at this wrong and and I said yes you're
right we are looking at this wrong and
everyone agreed to that at least most
people agree to it I'm not gonna say
everyone right but Tony Tony reframed it
as where this one is about signaling and
the other ones are about algorithms and
that was a much more useful way to look
at things and and we have tons of
agreement on that so yes if you know I
miss I misspoke originally and I'll take
that doesn't we're allowed to make
mistakes right she has a patent on good
because it because the offering is based
on that your statement and then ponies
like one one you just asked me to remove
the central centralizer one and then
I've you know it doesn't matter we're
the working you cares and we follow the
instructions and we move the second one
and then just the fact that this one to
to the new instructions right so you're
not happy
I understand but but what we need to do
is we come out of this working so happy
isn't not award for describe of my
feeling you see
so these are just my feeling so they say
that a big baby we have a guru people
working a very hoc by the way and now
we're in an hour back to credit and I
said there's no issue with credit
anything any work people do is not going
to be hidden somewhere right if your
work is adopted by the working group and
we standardize it of course your name's
gonna be on it like that why this is not
something we need to discuss if you if
some of your work shows up in a document
without your name on it
then I think you have something to
complain about that hasn't happened yet
has it yet there's no more cases there's
one guy in the middle you said so after
one program is about it is even harder
though people put a new idea in that
document that's a normal case right yeah
what you're saying is that you think
it's gonna be too hard to get any new
work into the working group document
that we adopted yes actually this is not
ILS our stuff this is ietf process stuff
so why don't we go offline we can talk
to the Hades to I think we're in a
circular a circular discussion here too
on this so so I think we need to take
that part of it offline are these
technical comments everybody's got not
processed yes okay les Ginsburg so full
disclosure I'm a co-author on the draft
that was adopted but the comment I would
make in regards to the EFT bit without
commenting whether it's a good idea or a
bad idea but operationally it overlaps
with the definition of how we signal
temporary flooding and so if we if we're
going to decide that this is a good idea
I think we have to take those two
mechanisms and decide how to signal it
and get both out of it if that's what we
think is the best solution which is why
it needs to be in the same document yeah
I think these are different from those
kind of requests a bit so request three
the means that we send a request to the
remote site and then we requires a
decent thing to add a temporary ID a
flattened topology these are unjust I
computer phalloidin Papaji
Ricardo dis link this link is on the fly
on the falada ontology so just that this
is a 44 cents Tony Lee Arista so the way
we make progress in the ITF is we make
proposals if you want to move forward
with this the right thing to do is to
send mail to the mailing list proposing
your idea we then discuss it on the
mailing list if we agree we then
incorporated into the document I have no
objections to your idea let's talk about
okay that's enough yeah regarding to
discussion I think when when the
proposal those Libre document I say
someone I remember the Dropbox for
positive as well as a year at the
centralized one sinner single Authority
should want it Sudan can do it this
revision by themself right you're right
maybe it'd be time to take this offline
and talk to the chairs and the AAP it's
just a suggestion as as a chair that
this whole process anyway so we'll
discuss these two mechanisms as
generalized mechanisms ah I as the
scheduler which I I agree that if you're
going to do a scheduler you don't need
to disseminate the timers unless you're
doing distributed but for the FT bit we
can discuss those two well discuss those
two okay thank you hey we're luckily
we're a little bit early but we're gonna
meet again tomorrow and I would advise
people to read the drafts giving
priority to the two we're talking again
about the two rad I mean two rather
radical extension styie sighs I'd
recommend everybody read
and the other one if you have time I'd
recommend you read Sue's document on the
use case that's gonna be tomorrow as
well
the other two I got a yang model I can
explain you don't really have to read I
can explain it in the ten minutes I'm
gonna talk about it yeah well you don't
have to read there's only so many hours
before the next meeting anyway and and
the one on the one on on te we're going
to have that presented maybe have some
comments but we're gonna move it to the
t's working group the one on packet
slicer use the segment routing because
it really didn't belong here but we got
the request late and I didn't really
read it till the plane and I said well
this doesn't belong here but it wasn't
scheduled in T's we had time we're gonna
leave it on that we cited leave it on
the agenda
it does have some minor te extensions in
it but that's the small part of the
graph relative to the framework that is
being proposed in that one so maybe I
got you curious enough to read that one
as well
by the way earlier you know since we've
got a little heated there if anybody if
everyone would go to the ether pad
that's what we're doing our minutes
let's make sure we captured everyone's
comments because you know it's not
always easy to understand each other and
you know if we put them down in the
minutes maybe it'll help move that that
process forward so make sure that your
your comments were there and captured
correctly we don't want to miss
anybody's opinions the discussion in the
end happens too fast too quick so I only
captured maybe 60% of the whole
discussion so please go on the ISA pad
and to you whatever you said
thank seeing Zen thanks everybody see
you tomorrow tomorrow tomorrow yeah if
anybody hasn't signed blue sheets grab
it on the way out
[Music]
because you know better yeah you know
what yourself exactly there are
differences
we find rats
I don't know