power hey with the MLS working group
starting at 1350 so that's right about
now so let's get going get close to Mike
okay
MLS at ITF 104 thanks everybody
oh okay this is the note well let's just
start just look familiar
basically whatever you say and do will
be held against you later uh-huh there
if you participate you're gonna be
recorded and videotaped like you are
here if you have any IPR you declare it
obviously we've got some processes and
procedures that you can read about from
the list there um it's about it requests
we have a jabber scribe Thank You dkg um
what who who who would okay so we need a
jabber scribe and we need a minute taker
so minute take her X oh you do minute
taker
all right great and if you have to bail
then we can swap that's awesome um
there's some blue sheets going around I
appreciate that if you do that if you do
the minutes in the ether pad then other
people can link into it as well do you
know where that is all right cool
please state your name into Mike and as
well keep a professional at the Mike
here's our agenda two days they were
generous we only actually asked for
three hours and they gave us three and a
half hours so today we're gonna do some
reviews some interrupts
stuff do the interim recap that we're
gonna do and then we're going to go over
our architecture document and then we're
gonna start kind of plowing through the
protocol issues that we have open then
we're gonna talk about a new draft that
Ahmad started talking about at the last
interim four federations and then Sophia
has some stuff on deniability and then
we're gonna do some planning for what
they're gonna have a next interim and
maybe ways of working as well anyone
want to agenda Bosh
great let's go forward I have the power
Richard burns one minor agenda bachelor
since I think you mad is not going to be
here until the Thursday session I might
propose taking the simplify key schedule
thing which is one of his big care
abouts and moving that to a Thursday and
moving the identifiers discussion
evidence that slot which I think I said
she slides for both yeah so that I'll do
the D couple identifier is thing in this
slot I've got there in the protocols
discussion all right Richard come on if
you want to come back up and give a
summary of the Interop call all right so
we get for having the first session
after one chance' turn on all the
equipment again so just a brief
interrupt
of dates we have four or five
implementations going raise your hand if
you have an implementation of MLS in
progress oh oh is that do go there
excellent cool good to see it so yeah
we've got Cisco wire Google trail of
bits and INRI all doing implementations
the approach we've been taking right now
is kind of operating off generating test
vectors for different chunks of the
protocol so we've got test vectors for
the tree math for the resolution
algorithm for the key schedule for the
core key scheduler for the application
key scheduling for some of the message
parsing so that's kind of the the
framework in which we've been doing
interrupts so far not doing kind of live
interrupts between stacks I'm trying to
kind of gradually work our way up to
that by getting the
the core parts the protocol so we we had
some calls you may have seen scheduled
on the list the first couple of calls we
had we realized that it wasn't really
useful to do a real-time interrupt we
use those more for kind of planning this
and establishing this framework figuring
out what worked and what didn't and then
we've been doing a bunch of offline
people refreshing the test factors and
testing against the test vectors that
debugging issues identifying issues
interrupts issues through the wire
channel a kind of async style instead of
doing kind of live Interop events
bigbang Interop revention and so we have
I believe linked from the
implementations repo an interrupt matrix
now where we are marking compliance
where people have are agreeing on the
test vectors and we're getting starting
to have a fair degree waiting for Diego
to report on something he's the laggard
here but we have at least that the Cisco
and trail of bits and wire
implementations interrupting and I think
Benjamin you used reports um recently as
well I saw some green in there for you
um so we've got a fair a fair you know
some some some slots in the matrix
filled in so we're starting to get some
inter up on core parts protocol I think
the like the tree math and resolution
stuff that doesn't involve any crypto
like that you know people have developed
their own implementations and and then
we're agreeing on that by and large and
they're starting to ratchet up and
verify that real crypto stuff starts to
match so by the time we get to the
interim I think we'll we get oh four
people upgraded oh four and we should
have some questions about interrupts all
right thanks
okay so now I'm going to do a quick
summary of the interim so the the
interim meeting we had between the last
ITF and this current one was held in
Mountain View right next to real world
crypto so we did get some other
interested parties who were in adjacent
conference for real-world crypto who
showed up and
there were some pretty substantive
conversations presentations about the
encryption of welcome messages add in
place
lazy handshake messages proxy rien
Krypton for server assists user
initiated add a brief update on analysis
as well as definitely some some
conversation about efficiency and one
other thing that was brought up that we
will talk about here is there's the
possibility to have a federation
component and a federation milestone as
well as a document that you might has
has published as an individual draft
that should become coming up as well
there are also alternative tree math
proposals made one of which was about a
two to three tree so we'll see if that
results in a draft being sent sent
forward to be discussed here or not but
um I have not seen seen that yet and it
was it was a pretty great event because
all the people who did show up
participated and there was a lot of a
lot of conversations that the notes are
are available in the on the data tracker
for this okay so any questions about the
interim meeting great all right let's
move forward to outstanding issues in
the protocol oh sorry architecture with
venture and first yeah I yes one second
is that lazy updates or lazy update is
anything I haven't heard of before okay
good there's the type of well corrupted
okay so I'm gonna quickly discuss about
the architecture stuff basically nothing
has changed much since the last few
interims because we focused a lot on the
on deonda protocol on the protocol
document so one thing that changed
across both document is the fact that we
are
on the architectural document
terminology instead of the protocol one
that was using something called
participants so now everything is using
client and the protocol document was
moved to effect those changes so really
I like like we had before
AI a 1 2 3 our clients owned by some
users and there are members of a group
while c2 funston's is not member of the
group so since there are not too many
things to say and I just took the slides
from ITF one or two when I when we are
go of explicit requirements and goals
and and basically we can see that like
most of the things we want we currently
have typically messages are accepted
only member of the group message spading
fork efika for protecting against
African and is this has been optionally
included in the protocol documents but
since that's that still I love all
architectural role that our G
notification with the authentication of
everybody who the authentication service
that we still keep abstract nothing
changed so that you can do whatever kind
of on education he wants the one thing
that's going to be discussed probably on
cells there is deniability because it
actually many people want some kind of
deniability and it's been very
interesting to discuss what what we
really want or not and we see and all
the main security codes have currently
in the protocol document which suppose
they are we don't have a proof yet that
ongoing progress but we think that we
respect those properties so it's good
scalability we have experiments that
show we can actually scale for fifty
thousand clients it's gonna be
interesting to see your 3d works feel
like on the on the network a
synchronicity
except for the group operations which
are like Karis tricky right now after
doctor left deliver service actually say
that they are
although and we might relax that
condition for date messages we are
actually interesting discussions on
least risk results I am sterically
something that we don't really looked at
it yet so that's one big point that we
need to look at and meta data protection
is is ongoing work the common framing
we'll discuss this a bit more I guess
Federation of using in progress and we
are running is something that's gonna be
discussed as well so the previous the
quickie open question that you actually
didn't look that frequency of the key
update I think that's something we left
to so is that we would click command and
updates frequency depending on the
number of people in the group exit they
are and that's I think I mean we need
feel we need a real that data to be able
to actually do these kind of
recommendations there is ongoing
discussion on whether it should be
whether we should do subtrees entry camp
or doing protecting the number of device
etc so that's also something that's
being discussed but nothing settled yet
and requirements on the south side for
when the several elapsed is something
right now the the in the Transpac boozy
architecture on paula cole the the
server doesn't know anything about the
groups membership it might change
depending on if we add the services tall
nuts so this is the questions
concurrency of group operations I talked
about it metadata its retention there is
an interesting questions that's probably
going to be discussed by a half file
about the fact that in the key schedule
when you pick when you pick the key to
decrypt
application messages you have the Sandow
in the player which is not the public
eats and so strong identifier I don't
you find
identifiers but it's like is the index
of the position of the Sandow in the
tree which is matrix emitted
that for some people it might not be
acceptable so we are gonna discuss this
as a the common same walk as well a
femoral signatures on the abilities so
how we'll talk about it on on Thursday
so on the editorial point of view since
nothing that's as change in terms of
security artists that we really want for
for the architectural draft
I mean we are gonna the editors will do
a round of actually trying to make
precise the text way more precise in
terms of security guarantees that we
want to achieve the the architectural
document is quite a long high level for
now and I think it's it's a good idea
that we actually spend time to detail
way more the all the informations in
there
so will between now and the next ITF
will make sure that this is a way more
strict and sort in depth
obviously there will be the changes due
to the existence of the Federation
document we might actually outsource to
the Federation document some constraints
or not or include some the Federation
constraints inside the architectural
document and we see that data and I
think that's all nothing nothing much
happened no so we just need to kind of
make sure that we pick the pace up on
the mailing list
ie sending messages the mailing list so
what I'm hoping is that we can do is
when you put an issue and github on this
you lose that people can you know
discuss it there as well as on the
mailing list and we'll try to do a
better job of actually driving these
four new questions to ground and making
sure the editorial stuff is done because
at the next IETF meeting I would like to
be in the place where we have no
outstanding comments on this draft and
we're actually ready to work and good
last call it and that would be a working
group last call not necessary the final
one but at least kind of like give
people
motivations I guess to actually put
their eyes on it and complete the
reading of it because I think it's it's
actually been fairly stable we just have
to once we get the terminology straight
which is a really funny discussion okay
it's like oh it's that under costs
laughs so I think that's that's really
good
great so that's it
now it is Richard sorry just has a
note-taker
I notice that the slides are not
uploaded on the data tracker I'll
refresh to make sure just wanted to make
sure that the plan was for them to be
there because I did not include any of
the contents of that presentation in
your notes all right so we are currently
on draft oh four that was published
shortly before the meeting due to us and
hiccups with deadlines and approvals so
I'll forgive you if you haven't done a
real thorough read through so I'll
provide some summary what we did since
since 303 I think was published right
before the interim so it's been a couple
months since we've graphed then we've
got a couple of open issues I think all
of which have pr's most of which fpr's
ready and so we'll kind of present what
the proposals we've got sketched out for
these various issues and solicit input
from the community so changes from oh
three bunch of relatively small stuff so
I've been I'm very grateful for Ben's I
you know looking through and thinking
carefully through what the terminology
should be and making sure it was all
aligned so that's all aligned now
consistent between the protocol document
and the architecture document so so
that's good there were some things about
the application key schedule you know
three that were ambiguous and so we got
those cleared up and kind of clearly
defined so now we have something we can
target for implementation where we've
got some Interop already on you know
four we've changed front now in this
version from using EC IES and kind of a
custom define
in this draft framework to using a
framework called HP ke hybrid public key
encryption that Karthik and I have
submitted to see if RG will be talking
about tomorrow morning tomorrow morning
anyway sometime this week but never see
if RG is meeting this week we'll be
presenting that draft proposing for
adoption there the idea is to have kind
of a reusable EC IES like primitive that
could be used in this protocol in ES and
I and TLS contexts in a couple of other
contexts where that's useful so we went
ahead and submitted that draft and so
we've changed the definition in in MLS
to use that down as well we've got some
version negotiation stuff in there which
we've got just a very shim thing you
know for that we'll have some more
discussion about today added a hash the
welcome and the add which there was a
thread on this on the mailing list that
we had some authentication
vulnerabilities do there being not
enough tying between the welcome message
that is sent to the new joiner and the
add messages it announces into the group
so adding I know in in the tamarind
model I did which you know I am NOT a
tamarind expert but I think it was more
or less correct in the Tamra model I did
having a hash with welcome info and the
add message was enough to address that
vulnerability so hopeful that the
academics in the crowd can help it build
some assurance around this I think it's
at least a step in the right direction
and then well I'll take it to two topics
I'll talk about here our key separation
with entry chem that Conrad Co Brooke
proposed and some this question about
garbage collection we addressed the
interim and kind of finalized to note
for just hold on back for a second from
a chair perspective right so they each
pke stuff actually does introduce of
dependency rate it doesn't reduce of
dependency okay my hope is that I was
just talking about this with Karthik if
we can get this a dot if CFR g to adopt
it now-ish it's in much it's a very it's
a pretty consolidated piece of work so
my hope is we can work it through CFR
gene expeditiously and not cause any
delay for this way yep okay so
key separation within shriek em so in
earlier versions of tree Kem right you
you start with a leaf secret and you
hash up the tree and the the secret
value of the parent node is the hash of
the child value
Conrad pointed out that you know this
this means that you now have some
relationship between the nodes
in a direct path which I guess is kind
of unfortunate it made him a made maybe
academics that hadn't Britta's nodding
here sighs soon yeah
academics are unhappy about that and you
know we try and keep our our academic
friends happy here so this seemed like a
low-cost way to do that so instead of
having this direct relationship between
the nodes what we've done instead in
this version with as we kind of derive
this these ephemeral secrets which are
the dashed lines here we start from this
the secret value and KDF it over to the
leaf value but separately KDF and a
successor value and KDF over to the node
so that you know once you've done this
you can throw away these values and once
those values are gone there's no evident
relationship between the things of the
tree so you have more independence of
the values in the tree but you still
need to be delivered the things in the
dotted box is right yes okay so you can
verify that the three subtracting
started yeah exactly the idea is that
instead of delivering the secret values
of the nodes you deliver the things in
the dotted line boxes yanks yeah
any other questions are coming to this
country cat trail the uod deliver the
bottom box right no so it's you know
entry CEM style um actually the bottom
box doesn't go anywhere so in in this
case the second - box would be encrypted
to this guy and the third - box be
encrypted to that guy - the same pattern
is trick em off our fair are not hash
are morally related - no
yes they are ok I got it thank you
the bold arrows here the solid arrows
are our kid yes I forget whether they're
just hash or whether they're it's some
sort of some chunk of each KDF yeah okay
that's that um finally this garbage
collection topic which we've talked
about a few times we discuss this at the
interim you know there's there's two
cases here you know you want to be able
to add people in place which is fairly
straightforward you just add them in a
slot and blank out their parents just
like you do if you got them on the edge
the thing that was more controversial
was removing people on garbage
collecting when you're removed so this
area we've got on the right here the
idea is we've got this this tree where
we used to have six members these three
intermediate members got removed and
we're left with the two on the left and
now we're going to remove the guy on the
right hand side and we'd like to clean
up the rest of this tree so that we only
have a little tree for the two members
and so the algorithm that's in the doc
now which is what was proposed what we
discuss in the interim you just wait
when you delete this last member you
delete nodes from the tree until you get
back to a non blank leaf and so you
delete everything to the right of that
leaf when you when you when you delete
the rightmost or delete a member that's
yeah the rightmost non blank member
that's the algorithm when we discussed
this at the interim we kind of decided
yes this kind of looks good on the face
of it if we can convince each other that
this tree and barring it still holds
remember our tree and Varian's the thing
we spend all our time trying to keep
which is that for every node in the tree
and for every member in the group that
member holds the secret for the node if
and only if it is a descendant of that
node in the tree and so my one line
argument here is that you've given that
definition of the tree invariance if you
simply take a subset of the nodes and
members which is what we're doing when
we throw away the tree that invariant
still holds and so the tree invariant
still holds and so it's okay to do this
this garbage collection in this way so
given that kind of loose argument we
went ahead and landed the P R and you
know hopefully further deeper analysis
will bear this out
anyone have concert remaining concerns
about that
I feel like Jonathan Harlan does making
skeptical faces at me all right so
that's that's the status as of o for any
further questions comments on on the
current draft Jonathan's I just have a
question I mean I'm not I believe that
this invariant holds I'm just wondering
if this is sufficient to actually do
garbage collection and real life you're
actually going to get in that situation
where you have significant numbers of
blank left nodes as opposed to just a
random distribution of likes across the
tree yeah no it's a fair question
because and then you know it's it's hard
to say because you know groups in
reality are are sociological things yeah
but I mean so I think I think the idea
is if you pair this one other thing we
discussed is the ability to move a
member from one leaf to another and you
notice if you combine remove with add in
place you effectively get a move on
right and so I had sketched something
out at the inner I'm about doing that as
a combo operation I mean they're they're
nice I'm sensitive organized way of
making sure - you know compact before
garbage collection yes that's possible
it's just a you know a thing you'd need
to court the application we need to
coordinate given a certain view of the
tree so the crypto is there it's just
you need some coordination to make it
actually happen yeah this is dkg do we
have any sense of how frequently this
sort of thing is going to need to happen
we're talking about actually being able
to do this kind of cleanup
I don't just I think maybe that we
should push off this question about if
you know efficient compaction and
garbage collection like it seems like we
don't even have evidence this is a
problem for a deployed scenario so I'm
happy with just having remove it out in
place and not trying to make some sort
of fancy compound Archy yeah I agree
that's kind of why we started with what
we did just defining updating the remove
operation so that it garbage collects
when you do remove I think in practice
should be
like your goal BG seeing two or three
slots maybe on a given time but yeah if
we find in practice that's you know you
need to do some compact compaction
before you garbage collects I think
that's something we could do plausibly
as a follow-up or handle later and yeah
since we know the general outline of
what you need to do alright there's
nothing else we'll move into new issues
for draft oh five oh right alright so
this is another issue we discussed
briefly at the interim so we want to
highlight here side by side the
identifiers we have for cryptographic
things in TLS and in MLS version of for
the current version right so as usually
92f protocols we have pluggable
primitives and we have identifier spaces
that identify either single primitives
or combinations of those primitives and
the trade spaces we do have to decide
like to what degree do we want to have
an a single identifier that identifies a
whole combination of primitives and to
what degree we want to make the
primitives plug-and-play
so TLS has kind of gone back and forth
on this earlier in TLS you had cipher
suites which defined a single value to
find all of the algorithms in use and
now until s13 we've decoupled that a lot
more so you have separate identifier
spaces for signature schemes and use the
D H groups in use and the cipher suite
now just identify as the aad cipher and
the hash function that's in use so
that's the only combination that's their
current version is current version of
MLS is a little bit more aggregated than
that so we have signature schemes broken
out so you can use say ECDSA together
with ex five two five five one nine but
the curve the hash function and the a
EAD function are all together in one
identifier space so the one value
defines all of those things and so the
question is I think ecker
proposed that we split this part that we
would have better experience with
evolvability of the protocol if we had
these Brooklyn separate things so the
general question is you know kind of
what groupings we want to have here so
the first line here is what we have
right now in MLS where we have the D H
group the AED and the hash all together
in one go to fire space the signature in
a different identifiers space the second
line here is what TLS has we have the
groups in one space a d-plus hash and
signature space the third line is one
that came to my head the thing that is
concerning that is potentially
concerning in the MLS context is that we
are using the hash function to derive D
H key pairs or CEM key pairs for
whatever we're doing and now whichever
can we're using to do tree Kim there
were Basecamp right so you for instance
if you're using 84 for 8 or p5 to 1 in a
high-security setting you might not you
might want to forbid the use of shots
you five six as for deriving key pair
step because you end up in some like low
entropy subspace of your big curve
spacing you're not getting the full
benefit of that curve so was that you
might I'm just proposing you might want
to match these things up it seems it
seems bad I think the numbers don't
match I guess but I mean I mean
presumably because when we you mean
you're like you know you're you give a
256-bit hash and that was in VC key
because inter Vista to hash that has
corresponding strength to a hundred
twenty one bitty you see you keep ulcer
- right fair enough
I mean maybe you'd like it me like a you
know a a two hundred and sixty bit hash
you're looking for yeah so I mean I
think we can we can do any one of these
like the usual concern here you here is
is phrases level matching here like is
it okay to use P 256 together with a yes
- five six which is going to so you
you're getting more strengths but weaker
keys going into the to the AED you know
TLS has decided that this is not worth
pursuing like you can you can have that
combination with TLS yeah I mean I think
that can you about your previous
I mean so um like um so I mean it's
worth noting that that if you actually
had a level matching three then what
would you use the cha-cha write an
answer BP 521 perhaps um so I don't
think a lot of magic as coherent never
has been um and I think that I mean
there might be some like there was a
crypto reason why you want to have a
much larger hash with with a with a
large group but I don't think I don't
think entropy is the answer unless car
facing like correct me here um you know
make me be want white or something my
impression was like the thesis to be
made to go up to a light if you
structure it properly what do you mean
by wide here like univie if for some
reason because you're need to generate
like more than you run the turn if it's
these bits right educate you have
concern about it is you want um so I
think it's probably okay um if we
treated it like it was okay in TLS I
think certainly as far as matching I
mean can you go back to the nice light
now um I guess um I know this any
sensible of a matching story about like
the group of the AE ad like that just
doesn't make in some you know um I think
maybe there's some coherent story about
the group in the hash which I defer if
you know CFR Vigo we do like I would
defer to that but I think that the
second tour the right other writes out I
mean the I think that if I review group
in hash I would do we did in TLS for
signatures which is basically to commit
to one hash for each group like how does
that reflected in TLS oh so if you look
at so it so if you look at the teal
Phyllis ensure things are named as if
there was some as if there's a match but
they're not really namely like you can't
use sexy 56k one along with the shell
three before saying ECDSA with p51 is
locked
yeah we just didn't we just didn't
define ko points that were like that and
you can do a five point nine which
hasn't has an implicit hash please don't
say what it is right so on you know the
only reason this first one's named this
way is because like it used to be you
could mix and match them right so I
think that if you
do services that means there's a degree
of consistency in this third option here
in which each thing is nailed to a hash
you really suck I just I'm just saying I
wouldn't build to come to her smorc
explosion of things I would just be like
you know who fixes user shot do it to
sex yeah but I guess um but I guess I
suspect her ended up with like if you
like so her for for eight you're gonna
use this all three before you need to
shut through to sex uh-huh I guess I
would just pick one I don't think we
have to like try to like right so the
the question I think the major question
here is like how what whether people are
concerned about you know shorter hashes
being used with bigger curves um and if
that's a concern then how we want to
constrain it you know you could
constraint it by just saying in the
definition of how you use the curve that
it has to be used as a hash function
that Bruce's at least X bits of output
and you handle that of the application
there or you could define these combined
group plus hash I kind of nail it up
that way it's like do people have
opinions about whether this is a problem
and if so how to handle it Martin yeah
not on Thompson oh that's good it may
send you may make sense to have a look
at the actual units that you're dealing
with in the protocols so the the D H
component that you use for this is one
thing and that and the ECE whatever the
thing is that you're using for
encryption is another thing and and the
heydays another thing entirely so rather
than saying are we have these groups and
we have these hashes and we have these
AEA DS have a look at the pieces of a
protocol that act on this so you have a
CEM and that can comprises of the
following group and maybe you need to
hash to the to the group so therefore
you need to put pair the hash up with
that and that sort of speaks to the last
one I think it to some extent and you
know the last one is just we're just
talking about protection of messages
once we have keys
so think about that way more than more
than you think actually that argues for
the
because when we're doing chem we're
doing ECI yes which means you're
deriving your D H you're deriving and
then you're plugging into a EP right so
if you have a unit that does all of
those things together then you may be
you don't need to split things out as
much in video this is unlike TLS well it
is like TLS and that a EAD is presumably
getting used for application messages
but the the CEM usage is unlike you I
mean any less right I mean so I mean at
some level like you might it like
doesn't argue for one it argues for one
prime which has a third which has a
second entry in between the first and
second entry is called AED you know
whatever is the message I thought we do
the bulk encryption with yeah yes
exactly so I think that's the module now
like I mean I think because HP key is
new like we don't really have to deal
with this question of library people or
or like or really people have our
oid iady's to their to their
community but I certainly don't
I guess what when I argued about this in
the interim my complaint was I don't
think you should tie the bulk encryption
to the key key establishment
I think the key establishment like if
you think if I get really turns out the
kids also much more convenient to like
tie all this together and fine but I
think you didn't have it together with a
bunker sure yeah and I think that's
that's probably the major point to
capture here is like we might need to AE
ad slots yeah okay all right well I
think it's a good feedback I will go
back and it Ponder's is not immediately
clear to me standing here which of these
you know what option all of this argues
for but I'll revise the appearance and
that's the lesson you could we can make
a decision it's nice that we all
randomly decided to use the same temper
alright so next we're gonna talk about
the server initiated removal and just
for context that is something that has
been requested by some vendors so just
to understand what it is some vendors
have made it quite clear that they would
like to use MLS but with the server
knowing what the roster is so the server
knows who's in a group and in that
scenario they wanted the server to be
able to remove someone from a group so
this means that we've been talking about
the server but really it could be any
external party it could be an
administrator or something in a
different context and so we started with
one proposal and then added another one
and I'm going to briefly explain both of
them one second so the reason the
rationale was for server and shaded
removed but it's because the users were
inactive right I mean it wasn't just
like hey I'm gonna get that guy out that
is one scenario but not necessarily the
only one okay so we yeah for example I
curse it because because he's fired yeah
because I mean like a lot of these
things are like you know corporate
systems and so you know someone gets
terminated and you wish to another
group or you know as someone said they
don't don't put their bill there's like
lots of reasons for managed systems to
one end in security but still walk
control of some group yeah yeah that's a
very good point so the first one just to
recap was inactivity to the extent that
the server can actually monitor the
inactivity which is not quite clear yet
it would be one reason and then yeah
manage environments in corporate
environments is the other one or maybe
simply for consumer messengers if
somebody closes their account and
therefore kind of do any crypto any more
that needs to be a way to remove that
person as well so first proposal under
the codename of external remove
so the external party meaning the server
can send a handshake message to the
group and that is of course not
encrypted under the group secret because
it is an external party that doesn't
know any of the group secrets but that
message would have to be signed in the
same way that hand check messages are
currently being signed except it will be
signed by an external identity and so
that is precisely the problem it's not
quite clear what that identity is how
that is being managed so none of that is
currently linked to the group state we
have the group state really only
contains the identities of the members
of the group but nothing else so that
raises the question how can a client
trusts this signature at the end of the
day and more importantly how can all of
the clients trust it because in order
for this to to work in a robust fashion
all of the clients would have to come to
the same conclusion that this is a
trustworthy signature and and would
remove the person from the group and now
the question is these external
identities are they going to be managed
and that seems to be completely out of
scope for the MLS protocol at this point
the assumption is that it might have to
be dynamic because groups don't have any
restriction on their lifetime so you
could probably assume that the server
identity or whatever it's going to be
might change over time might need to be
a revocation mechanism so the worst case
we're looking at is that if there are
some clients in the group that will
trust the signature and others don't and
some of them will remove a participant
and others wouldn't and then we have
partition of a group and then we have a
problem essentially sorry a question
then k-tec yeah so I'm not entirely
convinced that the clients all have to
agree on who to trust but perhaps we
don't like the other options I mean you
could say some scheme where the external
entities and
a new extra move message to all the
group participants and if any one of
them trusts that external part
participant they then like proxy that
message sign it you're you're too quick
that's the only thing here so that's
gonna be the next slide thank you for
the segue mr. Caidic uh yeah I think the
upshot of this one is that if we wanted
to have this then we would basically
need to extend the what is now the group
state that is the thing that everyone
agrees on by the key schedule and have
additional things that the group is
agreed on in there and include
information about the authorized
external parties there which you know is
doable but I agree is is probably not
worth the trouble
yeah I mean we could certainly try and
get a list of those external identities
into the group state however if it is a
requirement that this list is highly
dynamic then it might not be good enough
to just have it in there because it
might change in between so if the epic
never changes for whatever reason
because the group is completely inactive
but you have a change to the identity
list then you do have a problem so I
mean just just so I'm clear on the
behavior here so we have a group of you
know four people and some server sends a
you know a evict individual a and B&C
trust the server and D does not then now
you end up with basically do you know D
ignores the message and B and C take it
and now you have a partition right but
they but they know they were Perdition
because I'm not sure if I know about the
partition at that point I mean they can
no longer see message yet message each
other because they could okay and you
know find out the hard way yeah yeah
right I'm not sure I mean hopefully I'm
guessing fact this is proposal one meter
for littles knows problem
huh-huh-huh-huh right uh I I didn't live
with that property catriel
we punt on the external identities to
the application layer say you know if
why I want to stay instruct food to be
removed from a group why I must figure
out how to tell all of us clients to do
that right that could be one assumption
yeah I would support that over having to
include external identity management as
yet another thing we have to do in the
protocol but let's get it proposal to
write it's not quite fear so if we have
external identity management or
something similar it doesn't mean that
it has to be inside the protocol but it
has to happen somewhere so we can debate
about whether it's application error or
not it's not gonna be like proposal 3 ok
let's look at proposal to and then we
can debate some more so the idea here is
that the server or the external party
sends a request to the group that
somebody should be removed and then
probably the first member to come online
and to see that requests will honor it
by actually removing the member in
question and so that would be done
through a normal remove handshake
message which is not ambiguous because
everybody in the group is going to
follow up on that the only thing that is
a slightly strange at first is that say
if Bob was the one to be removed with a
normal remove message the user interface
of the messaging system would typically
say Alice removed Bob whereas in this
case it was requested by server so it
would have to be surfaced slightly
differently to the user to give some
more context of what happened here and
that could be achieved by somehow
including the the remove request that
came from the server so that other
clients can interpret what happened
correctly unfortunately it's not just
that so many systems have group systems
have one or two group administrators and
no one else can do can do kicking or
removal and so in those cases this
simply won't work at all in this case is
your
unless Appenzell don't want to do it but
I mean I often they're like not online
all the time right and so you get is you
get very very slow removal if any so
this doesn't seem this seems like only a
very partial solution what is the
concern at which scenario wouldn't it
work this is an area a scenario is you
have a group of like 200 people right
and there's two people or min Affairs
and only minister is gonna fix people
and so like you know um so you know like
to take go back to my example right
you know I'm fired and they want to be
kicked out of every group of the system
right and but it turns out that like
that the admins for those groups like
are on vacation and it's like nothing
happens and it's like that's I can
really dawn turn mystic behavior so I
think the problem is any system that
actually any system that wants forcible
removal as opposed it's just like people
who are who are like you know who are
just like not idle like it's gonna need
the effect of a half version one not
version two okay no it's a fair point
this is Daniel con Gilmore I'm just
observing that your proposal for how the
ux/ui change would look seems super
problematic to me yeah like you wouldn't
want to actually say that wouldn't want
to remove the picture of Alice being the
one who does the removal if this
proposal goes forward I mean yes I agree
with you that you would need to that it
would be reasonable for it to say bob
was removed by Alice at the request of
the external party but totally aligning
the fact that Alice was the agent of the
action would be a mistake yeah I mean
I'm not proposing a specific copy here
or what I'm highlighting is that just
saying Alice removed Bob is not the
whole truth
in this context and we do have the
chance to improve the copy so yeah we
have a chance to improve the copy but it
is actually the whole truth from the
perspective of the rest of the protocol
yes right the retrospective of the rest
of the protocol it really does like it
is still Alice who's making that call
and yeah we can offer some additional
cryptographic justification but we could
do that in many other types of removal
contexts as well if we wanted to
Alice could say I found this C RL online
that convinced me that this person need
to be removed or something I'm not I'm
not saying we should do that and I don't
even think we need to take it in it
scott reil again
just to push back on what echo said a
little bit because who can remove is
only an application-level policy anyway
in as as I understand it anyone
cryptographically can remove anyone and
the application law enforce our well
Alice wasn't actually allowed to do that
and therefore you could have a policy
that said only the admins can remove
somebody unless they attach an extra
remove request message and then you
should process it well I thought that
maybe I forgotten but I thought that
like you didn't need to issue the
request for graphical you mean part of
the group either of you right so I mean
like I means I guess I understand like
the that his entire story is about like
authorization the authorization of the
request not about the formation the
trait so yeah the thing the premise here
is that the remove request is
authenticated from the vendor right yeah
yeah absolutely but I think what catriel
saying is you know you're presuming that
the removed policy that the app enforces
is these two admins are allowed to
remove and no one else like what he's
saying is that you could have a policy
that says the people who can remove are
these two admins or anyone in possession
of a remove request I understand what
what's what constitutes being a remove
request and what comes to being remove
request it's assigned by the by the
vendor so like now we're just back to
part one the remove request is is at
this in that framing is basically a
capability to it right like you've
provided a capability to everybody to
evict just dkg what is the structure I
can go D let me print run again yeah so
maybe taking one step back in my mind at
least proposal two is basically saying
all of it should be solved on the
application layer we don't touch the
protocol as such
people are effectively being removed
with a standard remove handshake message
but the rest needs to be done on the
application there whereas proposal one
would potentially mandate that we change
things in the group state meaning we
effectively change how the protocol
works let's it's like like I think I
actually kind of like to catch rails
these controls question earlier right
it's like we're like all running wire
and like well you know that wouldn't it
be great and you know and presumably
we're all connected to wipe the wire
Update channel for like you know tells
me to get a new version of wire
occasionally right and so um you know so
why are just well perfect will somebody
mentioned on that channel that says like
listen um you know like this guy's been
kicked out of the system like take every
group is in and pull now right and I and
every and every user of the system
automatically reduce the tree with this
guy out of the system and that's like so
much but that's out of BAM from the
protocol entirely right and you mean
they like Ruby just spontaneously but
president the protocol everybody
spontaneously removed like Daniel for
the tree right um and um so I mean in
that respect you could certainly take it
instantly because really not not like
you don't have to find protocol messages
for it I suppose um but I think that
goes distinguish between like from a
from from a sort of a tree machinery
perspective this person he pulled out of
the tree from a formal occasion
perspective you know station about to
tell you to do it and like we could
define that here we could not to find
that here and that's kind of like a
separate question but I think from a
tree perspective he's got a pull out a
tree right
well the question is also in which order
that happens so everybody has to do it
at the same time at the same I'd milk
right but I mean but like but I mean
they so like okay well I get because but
but you know you have you right so I
mean the I mean is it's complicated
right but yeah but um you know you think
in the case of wire because you can do
because you can't roll both it with a
thick messaging server and the end up a
channel it's like pretty straightforward
right you like say like you know the
update channel you say like look at this
level at this point like pull them out
right I I'm I'm saying that they're the
systems which are both central at which
of resent was there like a one
monolithic system
that have like you know a that have a
that have like one administrative system
as well as one like as like what a
software vendor I have that property I'm
an advocate I don't think um but I mean
but you know you know like even a
delegate is you know even even the
system which is a more open system that
has like a but has some central group
manager sells us a property right I'm
just saying like it that the the thing
is the thing the application needs to
know is like someone is authorized to
tell me to do this told me to pull this
person out of the group but I mean just
to summarize so that is completely on
the application lever what you're
proposing so you're this doesn't matter
at any change on the protocol layer no
not for my side JoEllen so correct me if
I'm wrong but isn't it true that when
there's an update we also have to
refresh the secret we have to add new
entropy in the secret into the group
secret right and so my my concern is
where that entropy comes from and I
prefer proposal to even if proposal to
requires an identity a cryptographic
identity for the server whoever
initiates this removal because if we go
with proposal one that and we actually
let the server do that then we're asking
the surface to provide that entropy
which getting gets mixed into the new
group secret and we don't want that I
mean I don't think that's the right way
to go I think it's better if that
entropy comes from a user so I actually
prefer proposal to despite it still rek
you know probably being better to have
cryptographic identity yeah that's a
good argument I mean we never took it
that far for proposal number one to
think about where new freshness comes
from but I guess you're right about that
yeah which also means that even if we
have a way to synchronize through some
external Channel and so everybody in the
group realizes okay now we have to
remove fob there's still the question of
where that new entropy comes from and I
think the only source that makes sense
to me is somebody who's already in the
group who
privy to the group secret we shouldn't
be taking entropy from outside basically
so that's why I like proposal too good
point to them yeah I surprise I
sympathize with that but it doesn't seem
like catastrophic because whatever
entropy is being provided as being KDF
together with entropy that secret secret
yeah yeah yeah please repeat the
question or come to Mike my reasoning
behind why I think this entropy should
come from members of the group is
because in a PCS scenario so suppose you
have a you know the adversary's
corrupted the server and he corrupted
one of them group members he knows the
state now if you allow the server to
also add the entropy during the update
it means now the adversary's second
effectively knows both inputs to the KDF
and so he knows what the new state is so
the Refresh didn't do its job of
cleaning out the state and kicking it
verse three off the channel so that's
why you know I wouldn't allow it from
any external party who could then
potentially be the adversary I mean yeah
so that's a good point I think that
argue is pretty strongly for for
proposal to here having us be done
within the group by a group member you
know a bit on the author is a question
question III granted like there are
similar authorization problems here it's
a proposal one but actually why I got up
here is trying to argue that's even
those authorization issues are
equivalent to a previously unsolved
problem like namely if you if you have
any non-trivial authorization policy on
remove you know any policy other than
anyone can remove then there's if you
you're assuming that everyone is
synchronized on that policy or else you
have this fragmentation risk so adding
one more bit to that policy one more
authorized key to that policy doesn't
seem like something super tragic in
addition to what you already had to be
synchronized on so
if that seems like a tractable problem
is it seems like this is kind of the
protocol modality I think that raises
kind of the raises the question of what
the protocol impact here is do we need
to define the remove requests dude we
need to define what this capability
looks like we need to define a slot an
extension point where it could go so my
assumption so far was that the remove
request doesn't mandate any specific
changes to the protocol I mean we might
still want to write it up as a guideline
basically of how things could be done
but it fundamentally remains an
application layer solution and since we
don't standardize those I saw it as
outside of the scope but okay so so for
debate so basically this is this
proposal like doesn't results in a PR
the protocol document that was my
assumption yet and the idea is in order
to get your remove message accepted by
your peers in the group you would you
know glue on the outside of it a token
that says this is okay optionally yeah
yeah pretty Hale I completely agree with
observation about new entropy but I want
to say one comment on the proposal too I
think we changed slides there but if we
go back so one comment about the
proposal two is that the server cannot
actually enforce a removal of any group
member so words and proposal 1 they can
that's a very good point so what you're
saying is that the group could boycott
whatever the server is asking exactly
but that is also true for proposal 1 to
some extent people could do it
individually leading immediately to
partition obviously which is even worse
so that's a very very strange threat
model haven't contemplated yet work
basically clients do whatever they want
and they don't follow what the server
says for these things so
I see that's being a problem in both
proposals
this is dkg so the if the server isn't
prohibiting the client that kicked from
contacting the others and there really
is no way for the server to actually
defend to enforce that this member can't
participate right in both proposals yeah
and I mean that's just the nature of
yeah of how these things are fit
together I agree so maybe to go to the
last slide what is connected to that a
bit is that my proposal number two it
appears to not be in real time because
it's a request that's being sent out and
nobody knows really when that is going
to be enforced but that would have to be
a rule on the application layer
essentially that you don't do anything
before you haven't honored the remove
request but MLS is fundamentally
asynchronous there is no real-time
element in it by design so I don't think
this makes much of a difference it's
just maybe more of a psychological
feeling that things are not being
enforced immediately so this is dkd
again as far as the motivation for this
for this entire question will a server
operator in any of these cases need to
be able to say this action was done
right so the server operator might say
oh we need to kick this person because
of policy reason X let me start the
machinery in process that does that do I
know that it's completed so will you I
have a requirement to know that it's
completed it's a it's a good question so
the the initial requirement here was
that Ruster is known to the server so at
the very least the server would see a
change in the roster there and could
determine from that change whether or
not the action has been completed but
been Caidic so if you have
sort of like policy you're auditing
level reason to need to be able to
confirm that somebody was removed from
the group does that sort of force you
into having a like auditing agent that
is actually a member of the group it's a
good question I mean so far we've never
really looked into how manage groups
with different you know policy levels
clearance levels whatever look like
because simply on the cryptographic
level everything is egalitarian as
catriel said earlier so all of that is
something that again happens at the
application there yeah so we don't have
a precise idea about that the question
is whether we need to so I think this
argument about um the forward the author
the forwarding like really completes
authorization with PCs like you know et
I understand like if surfer dinner
sheets this that guarantees don't look
as good but people are gonna key update
and then they guarantees will look okay
again and so like gate wing the deletion
procedure on you know some group member
reflecting it just like does not like
feel like like I'm like a non brittle
protocols on much rather have a
situation where everybody immediate he's
actually on a deletion and then there's
some other separate operation which is
job it is to like fly pcs the family
should just to fini where to bring the
system but what what guarantee do you
get from that that the stuff is being
done immediately what problem does it
solve if everybody agrees on the rules
you don't do anything before you remove
someone and it makes me feel better
personally as well but they need partly
an aesthetic position it just feels like
you're like taking new protocol
functions including them together in a
really odd way and especially the fact
that like I mean I mean like the that in
in when Alice forwards it that is like
no meaningful semantics
about like the is like novena semantics
kind of authorization right like you
need to you're like so in the case where
in the case where alice is not an
administrator the only basis on what
you're accepting this is not that Alice
sent it to you if you're accepting it
because you're accepting it because it's
signed by their group from the buck-buck
by the route right I'm gonna rip with it
but by the authority and so like just
like so he's saying like I all should
forward it like I mean you might as I
mean you might as well have the like one
instead have a rule that you know if
that you know upon you know upon
receiving this like you won't you
shouldn't really keep you to your own
but have a basically the same fact right
John Linux you're saying about the
knowing of when it's complete is does
the requirement here the roster is done
to the external party meaning the roster
the external party knows every members
view or that you know whether
everybody's actually gotten the state up
it yet know the rest is really only the
list of members in the group I mean what
is the list mean when you know when not
everybody might not out not every mirror
might know the list yet I mean how the
server gets that I mean it could be
inferred if handshake message are than
unencrypted for example this seemed like
the minimum requirement for server
initiated removal to make sense at all
been connect I guess I'm still sort of
confused how this the server sends a
message and everybody acts on
immediately it would work because I mean
we do have sort of a synchronous message
delivery and doesn't there need to be
something to enforce like that happens
in the same a POC doesn't the external
thing need to know something I think so
as well
yeah I mean there would need to be
either some instruction at which a
pocket it should happen or some other
magic which I don't know how that would
work right now I am yeah and that sort
of gets us back into whether the
administrative agent does the removal
needs to be like a member of the group
to some extent yeah
cat will hear this might be a good one
to take to the list in particular
thinking about the threat model here I
believe a lot of this discussion is in
the context of a malicious client all
right not necessarily a client which is
not following the rules and is choosing
to not well if that were the case the
comment was a player rules are distinct
from crypto rules a malicious fine that
doesn't follow a player rules could also
tweet all messages so but few should
think through their threat model
slightly more directly like if the the
users in the group chose to have were
non-compliant enough that they all
decided to boycott not either not do the
remove or not process the server's
remove they could just as well do the
remove and back-channel all the messages
in the group to the guy that you just
got removed so I think that there's an
argument like if if the users in the
group are sufficiently bad then there's
nothing you can do to stop them from
keeping the guy in the group virtually
even yeah I think that's generally true
and we've found that too between other
circumstances as well so when I think
what what sticks here is the argument of
synchronicity of how that can be
achieved if it is on the application
there only and it comes as an
instruction from the server so how can
we agree that everybody removes the same
member at the same a book so that that
remains an engineering problem yet I
mean Jonathan hoiding table you you
could do fancy stuff with unsealing and
proving that you're from the people from
the group just return to the previous
question it is a crypto problem that you
could solve assuming that the clients
were honest right the question is
that is actually irrelevant in the
context of MLS at all or if that is
something very vendor specific that a
vendor wants to see exactly so on the
question of what we should do here I
think I want to come down as I often do
on the side of not doing work it sounds
like this it's worse because I didn't
even hear it so it sounded like this
proposal to like punting it entirely to
the a player can be done without
protocol changes just by doing some
authorization stuff in the a player so I
think I'm inclined to do that for now
like and and maybe you know make an
issue on the architecture graph this is
to describe how this could be done in
the overall framing but leave leave the
protocol draft as it is for now you know
that that has the advantage that you
know nothing changes so if we decide we
need to do something different the
future it's not that hard to come back
and do it so that's that's how it could
be inclined again and I tend to agree
that for specifically the reasons you
just said if we want to do anything
regarding proposal one we need more
concrete proposal with more details in
it and then discuss it doing proposal
two is basically doing nothing for now
that's true well if we want to go with
proposal two then would it make sense to
extend the message format for removal to
allow a field for justification
arbitrary justification string defined
by higher-level application that would
be then also in it that would have an
effect on our product on MLS yeah that's
that's a good question I'm personally
not entirely sure whether we need it or
whether we can do that again at the
transport application level somehow and
glue them together there yeah the reason
you would need that in MLS is the reason
you need that in MLS is if you needed
that to be signed by the member and in
kind of unforgeable by the server which
doesn't seem like if there's a like
let's put it this way like this server
you know if this is not bound into it's
not that in MLS the server can add or
remove it will which means that you
could have an implementation
architecture where some of the the
client is commanded in the server just
adds this authorization as it transits
the server which seems like it just fine
architecture to me so like I don't
really see the need to find it into the
protocol here okay so maybe then as an
intermediary results we stick with not
changing the protocol for now until we
have a better proposal on how to do
proposal one anyway does anybody want to
get to the mica and argue Lee
strenuously for proposal one great now
I'm not gonna argue for proposal one but
I am looking at Benjamin suggesting that
he file an issue on the architecture to
describe it there yeah that's good then
we have it documented somewhere all
right and we can move on version ago she
ation so it is a bit of a luxury to
think about version negotiation at this
point to the extent that we have maybe
bigger fish to fry but at the same time
it's something you want to think about
early so that you don't pinch yourself
in a corner so there is an addition to
the draft o4 and it's a fairly basic one
where we basically mimic what we do with
surface suits and so clients can
advertise what version they support in
the user init keys and essentially in a
very undemocratic way the group
initiator decides what version to use
for a group and then everybody sticks to
that and so whenever a user in a key is
retrieved by the group initiator and
somebody is invited in the Welcome
message the initiator indicated
which version is being used and of
course the downside from that is that if
a certain client doesn't support a
certain version it's not going to be
part of the group so these are the
concrete changes in the the structure
and the user in it key there is simply
an array of supported versions and the
same happens in the Welcome info so
there are some open questions I mean so
far this is rather straightforward
the major one is should be possibly to
ever upgrade an existing group to a
newer version and if that's a no than
the discussion ends there of course if
it's a yes then the question is how and
should that happen on the application
there should there be something in the
protocol that facilitates that and also
what are the security properties when
you do that which is of course very hard
to answer because we're working on
version 1 way of knowing if there's an I
ever gonna be version 2 and what it's
going to look like Dominick's I mean I
think you would also want the converse
and if you discover oh hey I wanted this
person to join but they don't support
the new version do you wanna be able to
downgrade existing groups to an older
version that would be nice for the
person but it also some very dangerous
it does yes and then the other question
I have is do you want in addition to
versions also have protocol extensions
or not necessarily you know all or
nothing but you know we support also
this additional feature which may be you
know either you know up you know
comprehension optional or comprehension
mandatory possibly having both like in
the capabilities that are advertised or
you would say I support extension 1 2 &
3 yeah yeah yeah I mean there's no and
we never might even be you know I
support 1 2 & 3 and if you don't that's
cool and I support 4 & 5 and if you
don't you can't join the group they
might have both categories of exemptions
well we don't really have the
sort of extensions it I guess my feeling
with no hat on though I'm sitting up
here is that it should be possible to
upgrade at this vision of like a
long-term group that's for a large
corporation and and like new version two
comes out and you're gonna you're gonna
send out a new message to everybody
you're gonna make everybody in that
company like they're gonna do what well
I mean it's always possible to upgrade a
group at the application layer by just
throwing everything away and
reinitializing the group all right
there's no UX impact like it's all just
crypto nonsense it happens under the
sheets well that's the question
like if it's obviously depend on the
version upgrade on the difference of the
version so the questions like should we
try and articulate any sort of thing we
would like to preserve across a reboot
like that you know would you know how it
takes some group secret from before and
fold it into the new thing like how much
can we specify in advance that well let
me try a simpler problem let us say
you're perfectly good group and then
some really fast new like aad algorithm
comes out and we'd like to upgrade to
that that doesn't require changing the
group at all so like like can we do that
we could do that yet I think that
because I think like even that it's like
some sort of like two general rules
problem look like figuring out that
everybody like speaks you know everybody
speaks you know cha-cha thirty um so
like I would suggest someone try to work
that problem first and then like if you
were ever worth that problem
successfully then we can like work the
problem of like upgrading the group well
I mean the underlying program is that if
you want to change something whether
it's a quick tour primitive or something
else you need to make sure that
everybody would understand what you're
doing yeah so I think this this this
slide is kind of focused on the crypto
ideas around the statement but I think
there's also even more basic protocol
understanding ideas actually yeah well
no it's not so that the cha-cha 30
problem is still a crypto problem
because it's like how do you get
everyone to do something different but
like even being able to part
the Welcome message that comes back but
it chooses version well okay means like
great okay so fine if you own it that
way okay like we I decide I want us I
just add a mood I just added emojis and
I'd like everyone even to like send
emojis but I want to send a movie but I
mode you look bad like when I send a
people no emojis so I need to know
everything the group supports emojis so
like doing head us all of that I mean I
think we may because all the things
ordered but I'm just saying like like
you know that's like a much easier
problem so like maybe something write
that down and then we can uh Korean like
how you upgrade from like you know or
you know from like ASCII text to like
mine or something like that and then
once that works then like we talked
about it do this Catherine could we not
solve that problem to be clear to be
clear in many deployment context you
will unilaterally control all endpoints
correct and therefore you can just
defied all my endpoint support emoji now
I mean maybe but I mean I mean so if you
feel in context is like we have clients
that's true for your Pokemon stack apps
that's not true because you don't know
people if update or not so yeah so um
like even then is a little is like
non-trivial but in open systems is like
much less trivial right but I would hope
that MLS doesn't have to solve the
problem of companies shipping different
versions of apps to different phones
yeah I agree that if a problem I'm not
sure that's a problem that MLS should
have to solve well I guess I guess mmm
but maybe not but I guess my point is
like if you can't describe how you solve
that problem in this context you can't
describe figure so the person update
problem this context so maybe you're
gonna write down my halves are all under
Center control and I make sure they're
all the same but like like it like that
but write that down them because like if
you're not if you're not going to tell
me how to solve that problem then you
can tell me there's all this one
this is dkg so cat rola like yes there
certainly are deployments where it seems
possible I'm sorry my back is to you
just because of where the microphone is
not I don't mean to yeah I could just
talk to you in my back um there are
situations where you can do that
solution but if what we're saying is MLS
will only work for long live groups in
scenarios where you can unilaterally
have a flag day then that means to be
written into the architectural draft and
it's currently not because I'm gonna
hear you that like you don't want to
deal with the open world problem because
it's really hard and it's what we
struggle hit with here at the IETF right
if you're John the Senators here at the
ITF then either we need to say by the
way you need to be sure that you have a
way to upgrade all your clients
synchronously or we need to say that we
have some idea about how we're gonna do
an upgrade path or we can say your your
conversation is good only for as long as
you're deployed clients are synchronized
and then you'll you'll have to find some
everyone will switch from wire to 3ma to
in order to upgrade I'll go away and
think about it but my I'm not sure I'm
convinced that solving you upgrade the
version of MLF is the famous solving you
want to negotiate some of your clients
supporting emoji but I'll go wait think
about it so I go back to my previous
comment which no I I think I was asking
an even worse and simple question than
that like I was going back to the not
upgrading a group that's starting a
group at all right in TLS I think in
quick I'm looking at Thompson because I
think quickest thought about this in
some detail is question of version what
stays constant among versions okay I'm
staying I'm like thank you
[Music]
right so so there's this question of
like what stays constant across versions
like in in TLS we've like tried to keep
compat in the client hello right so that
these server knows what versions of
clients of course and could do proper
version negotiation that way so one
could imagine writing some similar
invariants here and and you know what
are the considerations we want to take
into account here Thomson would you like
to like provide some background from the
TLS quick point of view yes so Thompson
the the thinking and quick has been
largely that we you need to have some
way of knowing signaling what version
you intend to have and that needs to be
invariant across all versions that's
kind of the baseline and then you need
some way of sort of signaling that that
version is not ok somehow and so tell us
has it has far more in its in his
baseline invariance because it says that
the client hello is this shape and shall
henceforth forever be this shape and so
everyone who understands any any version
of TLS can say well the table until I
said Clym hello is always this shape and
therefore I can I can rely on that fact
here that's sort of a second order
protocol consideration though I think
what I think you need to concentrate on
is what what are the states that you're
looking at what are the what information
exists in state 1 and information exists
in state 2 and what needs to be carry
across from from one to the other and
what needs to be changed in in the two
different ones and you could imagine a
world where you start a new group
because you wanted to change the color
of the pixels that were rendered right
and maybe you run two groups in parallel
that's at that point and they have some
constraints on how group membership to
synchronize will have you I don't really
know
but there's there's a number of ways you
can imagine this working and none of
them really sort of read on that
particular aspect of the problem
unfortunately hopefully that wasn't too
indecipherable I think one of the one of
the things that you might try to think
about to start start out this discussion
is cipher Suites because that's one
thing in which a group is going to be
different from other groups right yeah
cipher suites is one thing new messages
new message formats might be another so
to summarize what we have now in draft
or for is this and this seems to be
rather uncontroversial in the sense that
nobody has jumped up to the mic to
criticize that
so yeah going forward it's our question
how we channel that discussion if you
bytes fighting back one slide leaving it
up for a minute yeah okay too soon yeah
how do you imagine this working so you
have a disparate community of clients
and they have potentially non
overlapping sets of supported versions
right is the is the way this works the
first person who went to the room
determines the version is it's some sort
of negotiation process what at what
point does the final version which I
mentioned is this thing on the on the
right hand side what version point is
that committed to because you can
imagine a scenario where one person
joins and that determines the version
and then basically the whatever version
the server or that person decides right
so what happens is that there is one
group initiator always a design that is
going to retrieve a number of user and
keys of the members that should be part
of the graph and from that the initiator
can determine what's possible at all
I assume the initiative would go for the
highest possible version because it's
the best one but that remains to be seen
what I get to choose that day but they
get to choose and then they
commit to that in the world come in for
so everybody they invite they tell them
exactly which protocol version and this
is not an array this is just one version
right at that point is to be used so as
of that point you have a static group in
the version and that's it basically so
there's no negotiation as such between
people it is it is really just members
advertising their capabilities in the
user in keys and then an initiated
choosing from that yeah there's no
negotiation until I say this is dkg so
in this scenario the consequences are
just to state them clearly when you go
to add someone to this group and you
discover that they do not support the
version that the group is in you get
some sort of message that this person
cannot participate in this discussion so
low sodium and in the future when you
poll the members of group and find that
they are all capable of a new version
there's no way to upgrade the existing
conversation or there's no explicit not
something Jax and this is this is just
saying any particular conversation is
happens at one version that's negotiated
at the initial assembly of the group and
if you want to change it later that's we
punt that for further down the road yeah
you punt that potentially by starting a
home to group someone said behind me and
I couldn't see them yeah Jonathan Lennox
pointed out that you can start a whole
new group the question there is whether
there's anything that this group needs
to do to vote to ensure that starting a
whole new group remains secure in and
retains all the properties that were
interested in retain going across that
transition those are the open questions
so the last one well whether or not you
solve the migrated the current group to
a new version or not you're still
dealing with essentially the same
problem which is is it secure going from
state one to state two right relaying
from Java perhaps not the right question
for now omnia asks what about the
blanking problem
slash double joint that seems completely
unrelated in that sense that that's what
I thought happy to discuss it later but
maybe we conclude this first so yeah I
mean to me it seems that this rather
primitive mechanism could be a building
block for something more mature where
you can one day upgrade a group it
doesn't seem to prevent a credibility of
groups to me so I mean I would say that
we discussed the rest on the mailing
list preferably with concrete proposals
of either how a group could be torn down
and then resurrected on the application
layer or how we can smoothly up credit
group with maybe new kind of handshake
message or whatever makes sense I think
that's it so that's all that we had
scheduled for today actually it's a
little early but that's okay we got um
another hour and a half on Thursday
unless there's something else that we
want to add well I could like revert my
agenda bash and put that topic back on
the sessions agenda the key schedule
stuff the key schedule stuff yeah yeah I
mean if you want I can we want to go
over maybe we don't come to it again and
we can now we can do it quick as we have
30 minutes it's in ads I was waiting for
but when I his team is here I'm not
right his representative may come on put
him on the spot and enjoy it also
commented on that so I think we've got
we got quorum for that right
you can have the clicker back wonderful
all right so tree warning there's mostly
been free of trees today but I think
there's a couple minutes can give you a
line here so just to recap this is a
problem we've talked about a couple
times right now to confirm that all the
members agree on the state of the group
we have this group state object that
gets fed into the key schedule and then
used to confirm that agreement right now
that group state object includes the
roster the list of members in the group
and their signature keys and the tree
which has all of the d-h public keys
involved in this now each of those the
size of each of those is linear in the
size of the group so the group state
object is very really quite large when
you have a large group and that the
upshot of that is that whenever you do a
draw a secret operation which is the
core operation in the key schedule you
need to now hash this linear size thing
which is a lot of computation to do so
that that has made some people have
friendly faces on the list
we had some discussion about this
outlined a couple of objectives you
could envision here one is kind of
trying to simplify things in general you
could try and have a smaller coefficient
on the linear size amount of data you
could come by pre hash some things make
them smaller but I think where we where
is probably more useful to go here is to
try and reduce the amount of hashing you
need to do for the derived secret
operation this and get it down to a more
log like things that's more more
parallel to the amounts of operation
that we're used to in things like
updates and removes I am proposing that
we not take this the stronger form of
sub linearity here trying to enable two
folks to get along with a sub linear
amount of state I think we're still
going to the proposal here Institute's
that each member will still be required
to keep around the whole tree and the
whole roster but they won't have to hash
all of it every time they do they have
to
the key schedule they'll have to hash
some summary of it that will have log
size does anyone feel real strongly that
we should be aiming to allow endpoints
to get away with a log size state and
see Geralt shaking his head okay so no
one's leaping to the mic to to say that
I agree that's it's a desirable thing
but it requires a lot of extra
information the hikmah so I got a
summary and I think it's actually not
desirable to have the clients keep a sub
linear amount of state like I think the
clients in the secure messaging
application should know who's involved
in the messaging sorry that was dkg yep
fair enough
okay great so I've got a PRF right now
which sketches out as a solution here it
follows the the UM Pellman hash approach
that I'd outlined on the mailing list in
the in the PR it's called a tree hash
which is somewhat less colorful but also
less likely to run into trademark issues
okay and well the approach here is is
kind of Merkle tree like but with an
extra input in the intermediate notes so
you can align it to the tree structure
right so with the leaf nodes we've
collapsed the collapse the roster into
this struct so the leaf node info here
holds both the leaf public key as well
as the credential for the member holding
that leaf so you gather all that input
together and put it in to the the leaf
hash in this overall hash structure it's
optional obviously because leaves can be
blank if they're not occupied by a
member so that's how leaves leaves get
hashed and then when you have an
intermediate node you have its left and
right children you know represented by
their hashes and you then feed in the
public key at that node in hash form as
well there's an error in the PR because
that should be optional because you can
also have option blank intermediate
nodes just have to figure out how to do
that easily and TLS syntax but basically
you do this
in code and hash and code and hash dance
up the tree and you end up with a root
hash which is a summary of the whole
tree it's a commitment of the whole tree
just as a numerical tree so you're
committed to all of the public keys in
the tree as well as the credentials of
the leaves kind of by the transitive
property of hashing and the upshot what
that lets you do in protocol terms is
that instead of having the group state
contain the roster and the tree and have
this big linearize thing you can just
have the tree hash which is a single
hash value and so you have a constant
size group state object that gets fed
into the key schedule and it's and it's
all much faster you you do have to keep
this thing up-to-date as you change the
group but the upshot of that is because
we've aligned the the hashing to the
tree structure you just have to do a lot
you have to do the same number of hashes
as the nodes you change of the tree
so typically log worst-case linear so
that's the proposal on when it's a
briefly visit you know nobody was
calling for a ver trying gets the log
state but if you were if you were
inclined to go that way here's why you
might not and the reason for that is
like if you're going to try and a lot of
people get by with only log state then
you have to provide them the parts of
the tree that they're not seeing so you
have to provide the hashes of the the
alternate children and so you end up
multiplying the size of your handshake
messages by two or three times which
seems like kind of a lot of bloat in
order to get the smaller state for the
last line here like there was some
discussion of extension a little while
ago maybe this is something if people
were really keen on this that could be
added as an extension point in the in
the handshake messages so you could say
here's your public keys you need to
update the tree and as an extension here
is the hash values you need to update
the tree hash um could be there but it
doesn't sound like there's a whole lot
of energy and interest in the room so
overall like does it does this answer
the mail does it sound like a sane
proposal thumbs-up from Joelle questions
comments should we just merge the PR
[Music]
gothic by going from India so
there is value in having the hash of the
tree in many situations but also value
in having the some representative of the
transcript of all the operations that
have happened so far and they're kind of
related but somewhat different ways of
looking at it
so do we already have a notion of the
transcript and where is that getting
fair and well it's getting hashed yeah
that's perhaps a good discussion have
right now and in parallel with this I
think the current PR well so in O War as
in the previous versions there is a
transcript - there in addition to the
giant stuff I think in the PR it just
takes the gigantic stuff and collapses
that down to a tree hash so you end up
with a transcript hash and a tree hash
and the transcript hash has chains over
the tree houses no no no the transcript
has chains over the actual message that
were messages that were sent so it's
it's a hash chain over the the handshake
messages that were sent right so just
kind of abstractly if it were the case
it probably is that if you know the
initial tree and you know the transcript
if you're given initially maybe on the
transcript and deterministically you
should be agreeing also on the current
tree so this does seem to be somewhat
redundant perhaps in a good way perhaps
not necessarily where we have these two
representatives of essentially the same
state where the transcript - actually
has strictly more information it's a
great you are going on well you work
here more information in principle but I
think actually less information in
practice because if I'm a late joiner
and you just hand me this transcript
Cassius I have no way to interpret it
rightfully gender said that is a problem
right and so that there's I think the
question I think pension right discuss
some is whether you could get away with
only the tree hash and not using the
transcript hash at all because you know
the transcript hash doesn't add anything
unless you've been there the whole time
I just dis late - Jonathan Holland does
late joining mean anyone apart from the
first member well you you get you get
information from the transcript - in
purport
to the number of handshake messages
you've seen right so you can verify a
chunk of handshake messages but the hash
itself only authenticates messages that
you have so if you don't have if you
come into a group and you don't have the
history it doesn't give you anything so
so the first and second member then can
can fully interpret it or fully
understand this transcript - well if I
join at epoch five or I park two hundred
say and I'm given the transcript - at
that point that epic 501 like I can look
at the transcript - and the you know the
when I was handed when I joined in the
sequence of messages I received in the
mean time and verify that that is good
but I can't verify anything prior to
when I joined shell okay thank you yeah
this is Joelle when again step does the
the transcript hash includes actual
messages as well not just update group
update stuff it only includes the
handshake message just change the state
of the group it doesn't include the
application messages although the actual
messages are perfecting all right yeah
yes it's not quite wasn't the advertised
topic of this section but I think it's
it's a question that one could could ask
is like whether we should delete the
transcript hash from the protocol
because might not be adding any value
that we're not already getting from the
triage well Costigan in RIA so from the
transcript hash the thing is said there
could be multiple transcripts that lead
to the same state it was potentially
possible and considering that one path
might lead through a malicious node who
has done something and one other path
may lead through perhaps only non
malicious nodes in the analysis it
actually becomes important how we got
here not just where we got because of
what could have been influenced and
stuff so for the analysis when you do
the security analysis you certainly I
think would prefer to have more
information which is what is there in
the transcript - so one way of dealing
with
is to say that the transcript house
should contain I mean every the way you
update a transcript hash is you take the
the current rehash and then you add the
new operation whatever the new message
was and then you get the new transcript
- we could be we could define a
transcript as something that is some
treasure as something that's worth
builds on top of the tree hash now that
might be overkill on the cable whatever
we can think about that yeah I think
that's maybe one step too far one step
too fancy yeah I don't think there's a
whole lot of benefit to having one hash
to set up - in this case you know a
transcript that receives us the
transcript messages and the tree hash
which is just the tree and those two get
combined in the key schedule but yeah
I'm happy to keep the transcript -
around if you think it has some value
it's not it's not expensive really - the
protocol so ok sounds like folks are ok
with this tree hashing scheme so I guess
you can probably just go ahead and land
this I'll take another pass through the
PR and make sure we address like the
optionality blank intermediate nodes but
I think we're good to go all right get
to go eat cookies early see you all
Thursday
you