[Music]
so those who are standing up can you
find your seats someone to the back of
the room can you close the doors and yes
we are starting sewing so we are
starting please find your seats we have
a very low number of participant this
time I think it's a one of the reasons
are that I think people are going to
launch this is normal launch time isn't
it
the what worries me a bit more is that I
don't see some of the presenters so I'm
inclined to wait a couple of minutes can
someone stick a head out of the door and
I'll see if Adrienne is there we need
him
so one Stewart is doing that this is the
mpls working group meeting in Prague I
think for the fourth time and I actually
think we've been in this room once
before so you had the note well if
you've been to the here the entire week
you have seen it a couple of times
basically remember that anything you say
in the meeting or send a mail to the
mailing list I think this is this those
are contributions to the to the IETF and
will be considered as such if you
haven't read the BCP 79 go and do that
we can't hear you
sorry I need to eat the microphone yeah
okay so we're ready to start all the
admins that all the administrative
information are the same as before
please join us meet echo and help people
filling in the minutes that we get the
right name names to the right comment
and the right comment and that's
understood by the one that made it
ah you have to add free to the meet echo
link for now yeah you have to add free
101 plus three is 104 yeah okay thank
you and you find the the working group
data tracker page is useful
gyoon look at it now none mmm okay next
so this preparing this again that has
been a little bit of a roller coaster we
had six documents that people asked to
present very early and those six were
actually removed so now we have a little
bit of elbow room in the agenda we can
take time and discuss and that should
that's what it should be okay wait to go
back so this is the proposed agenda the
TBD actually stands for for Adrienne so
he has to decide whether whether he want
to come up here or he actually promised
to do it why why - my wife's name is in
capital letters the usual way
good in a good or bad way
are we actually be able to make the
traditions you can you can live with it
I don't know Oscar Eck yes anyone that
want to bash the agenda no okay so we're
going oh that's what I did
the blue sheet should be started pass
them on fill them in and when they get
to the back of room bring them forward
and try to capture if anyone actually
come in a field spot and return the blue
sheets to the working group chairs
okay we have a number of ear artists
going on some of them are resolved some
of them are a bit too beus one of them
is actually a technical change so you
have the information here
you can read it I don't don't want to go
through the details
I think the Debra actually handled one
of them so it shouldn't be out should be
it should be a I think it's really it
was enacted the one that Debra handle
and but there are four more in Deborah
and in working group chairs need to
discuss a bit what you want to do about
them next slide
yes dilly rotten okay we have a number
of license my eyes are too bad
so one liaison is from study group 15 on
the OTN work they're doing there and
they asked us for input on what we are
doing that liaison was actually sent
today so it or actually may be sent
yesterday Andy did you actually get the
pass working group on that one or ten
emails to answer questions Scott told me
you would be included but I have not yet
seen the final first you can do look at
the I don't think you were there that's
why I was asking so we probably should
send them Ilyas and telling that passes
also that I mean we go to the liaisons
page right now and take a look at it
yeah okay mmm the others are being
prepared the last one we don't need to
respond to just for information okay
next one document status up till five
meetings ago we had at least one our
seed per meeting cycles for the last
four we haven't had any the good thing
is now that we actually had we had
documents in the or associated askew and
they should actually be progressed quite
soon I wonder is Bruno in the room okay
the question I have for Bruna is about
the mistress and the status of that
document the mistress a mistress to a
spring document the mpls document in the
spring working group and it has been
misread for 345 days or something like
that
but I hope it's knowing we have
documents with the iesg and they just to
answer your previous question the PALS
drought the Pels
RFC is included but the pails working
good chairs were not included in the
signature but as long as they are
seasoned there that's important thing
you got off the halfway there
yes exactly I said what Danny is talking
about delays on the Senate started up 15
did go from there working group chairs
for five working groups
it's the PC ampulla C camp T's and else
though the pass is not less than an
alien it's Adrian with jumping around on
that we can live with that so the the
mr. F the this is that the one you're
interested in is that the base sr mpls
document yeah so that's completed its
second working Greg last call it had a
working group last call and it went
through the process and got major
revisions and went back it's completed
that last call it's just at the moment
waiting for the Shepherd right up to
move forward but it's because it's
already had quite a lot of review it
should be smooth from here on in word so
who was is the document Shepherd Chandra
I don't know okay
I could find out well I have to walk
they're not really that important but we
need to push a bit to get it done that's
actually I think it's six other
documents waiting for the same document
also as I said the document with the
eyes G is given through the normal
review processing I have an update on
one of the dress in that list okay draft
IAT fm+ sse encapsulation is now with
the RSC editor it's in the edit state
that's true when we did this two days
ago it wasn't it wasn't like that
and then we have a new working group
document it's also on the agenda but
it's the RC and
8270 8287 lengths clarification and we
have an ambition among the working group
shares and the authors to actually
progress this pretty fast so you expect
a working group last call quite soon yep
and here are the list of documents had
actually been updated in last time and
then we also have existing working group
documents the the or ahmad the erm our
extensions draft is actually just
waiting for the base RM our draft to be
progressed I talked to Miguel
about that one and he promised that they
were going to attend the the updated
parties as soon as possible
and I think I'm quite happy with that so
I will try to progress the aromatics
tensions just respond respond telefónica
so if they call four of these draft and
that is our commitment to move forward
as well as possible okay mmm yep you can
jump on most nine we also had a number
of new individual documents as you see
only five here but the the some of them
are in blue and I think for those five
documents they are they were intended to
know four of them were intended to be on
the working group list and actually
helped in we've drawn the one that's
still there is the SPL terminal Illium
will present seven the first the RMR
drafts here are also ready to be
progresses there will be adoption polls
and yeah again within a few weeks and
those of the rafts were and don't the
last three of those those those document
hasn't happened that much the draft
Shang mpls are more multi cause that is
basically a framework we talked about it
a little bit in peace yesterday and we
are ready to start probably progressing
it you will see an IPR call going out
today or tomorrow draft Shang ambulance
Ellis beeping yang configuration draft
Gregg with capital letters will actually
talk about it quite a bit and since we
have time we can you can take your time
there and try to explain what happens
progress reports those are the young
base young'uns that you can model we
have had further comments as the author
says that everything has been addressed
enough I believe them so the next step
is sexually to start a Jang doctor
review and the working group task all
next we are asking for status reports on
the working group document and we are
missing some of them but it only free
this time so it's kind of acceptable and
I'm not really sure that I was expecting
a status report on B if t directed
because that is with B shares and
authors to actually try to find out what
to do about it so basically nothing to
report
ah here is my favorite list so I list I
listed all the drafts that I have in my
my mail folders that does not are not
progressing and my feeling is I removed
the ones that people told me they won't
they are progressing somewhere else so
that we have actually progress them or
we're not killing to do anything about
it I'll remove those they're still free
pages of the drafts that you classify as
a sleeping beauty you know nothing
really happens I don't see anything
happening about this trap
yeah so there are errors in this list
tell me about the errors there are
duplicates in the list so I will remove
that but I want help from people that
has a draft that actually hasn't been
progress for a long time to actually say
no I don't want the progress anymore or
if you want to progress is tell me that
you will do God's now we kind of start
looking at it so it's Adrienne I think a
huge number of these are our missing
replaced by links in the data tracker if
you were to put these on a wiki page
then people can individually go in and
edit so if you put the column and the
what the right resolution should be
people can go and edit the resolutions
and that will be much easier for us to
process and trying to work with email on
such a long list at them okay I think we
have an ambulance working group wiki
page so I probably will use that one
thank you yeah I want to call the same
thing so one of the draft you know the
draft kinney just about spring MPLS LS
beeping that got merged but Kumar draft
Kumar kini and now it does you know
published as RFC 8287 okay thank you
so Andy
[Music]
while we're waiting for the presentation
come up amandime Alice this is a short
presentation on improving security for
for LBP so so if we go to the next slide
oh great thank you there it is
so here's some history LDP was first
published back in 2001 as a proposed
standard it was replaced by RC 503 six
which i think is still a draft standard
in october 2007 both specified the use
of TCP md5 signature option offered for
LBP authenticity and integrity checking
for LDP messages to prevent against LDP
message spoofing as far back as 1998 the
ITF was already aware of problems with
md5 and for example you can see RFC 2385
for example as an early RFC which talks
about the problems with md5 and RSC 59
25 back in 2010 deprecated the use of
the TCP md5 signature option which is
what LDP still is specified to use and
replaced it with the TCP authentication
option TCP a Oh and basically that our
seed describes the option itself it does
not talk about the actual cryptographic
algorithms that you would use with the
option that's discussed it with in our C
59 26 to allow the the cryptographic
algorithms to be updated separately from
the option itself so in May 2013
RFC 69 52 recommended that all TCP based
routing protocols move from md5 to TCP
AO
that would include l DP l DP runs over
tcp RC 74/54 and
fifteen did that for BGP so BGP has
successfully moved over to TCP a Oh at
least in the specification but it didn't
actually choose a particular
cryptographic algorithm not to use with
BGP and as we know LDP continues to
specify the use of md5 so what we want
to be able to do is basically ask some
questions of the working group come on
there we go so the the the goal of this
draft and it was written by the book by
the co-chairs of pals and MPLS working
groups is to update LDP to replace md5
with TCP ao
but the authors are really LDP experts
and we are not security experts and so
we have some questions to ask first we
asking here the MPLS working group and
then I will be presenting this in the in
the routing area working group as well
to have a larger discussion with the
routing area working group as well first
of all how successful has TCP AO been
for for BGP you know because if it's not
been successful for BGP why bother doing
this for LD P as well is it actually in
use in the field and if anyone can
answer that question please come on up
to the mic and then the question is well
if we specify TCP AO then we have to
choose a particular cryptographic
algorithm to use with TCP ao and we
would want that one one that works
reasonably well in routers without
basically you know slowing down the
processing of LDP messages and so on so
we want something which is reasonably
good in terms of the cryptographic
properties but but something that
doesn't degrade your performance either
and then the third question that we have
and then I'll start the line is does
anyone really care about this I mean is
anyone even using M
five currently with LDP so with that I'd
like to start with Joel Joel Halpern
with Erics and I'm certainly not
anywhere near the BGP expert many people
around here are from the discussions
I've seen nobody's using TCP äô on BGP
conversely attempting to put a draft
through the iesg which removed
LDP md5 and did not specify a
replacement would likely run into
serious difficulty so if we want to stop
saying md5 because frankly md5 isn't a
good idea which it isn't we probably
need to say a up TCP a Oh even if we
doubt anybody's implementing either one
right but but of course our alternative
is to just do nothing right and let
things sit as they are yeah and that may
be our best child relative that's why
were asking the question in the first
place
Rajeev oh sorry Cisco I'm aware of at
least 10 networks in the wild while in
production that actually used LDP with
md5 at least 10 that I could just name
right away I'm there perhaps more so it
is certainly a lot more commonly
deployed and then we would care for now
the question then I think you're really
asking would they care terrifically 75
with TCP a oh it's just about to ask you
that question
I was reading your mind I don't know
have I mean and and if I were to ask
them first question that I would need to
have the answer forest is it broken
I haven't seen any problem and network
with that yet so unless we come up with
a meaningful assertion that yep here the
challenges that you're gonna run into if
you haven't already well oh by the way I
should mention
almost all of them probably have bgp
with md5 enabled as well thank you okay
thank you very much that was very
helpful
Adrienne Farrell I think there's that
need to separate two things the use of
md5 as a a fat finger check and the use
of md5 as security and there's a a
problem with security when you say we
have never had a security breach so we
don't need secure security okay I've
never
nobody's ever robbed my house so I don't
need to lock the door if we're going to
have something we call security it needs
to be secure md5 is not if we want
something that checks configuration fat
fingers and things then we should and
then md5 is good enough but we should
mark it as such and say it is not secure
so wait on an alien are you saying that
security for LDP it's not really based
on md5 and it's not misunderstand me
correct correctly I am trying to source
a md5 it there was in some networks or
probably a lot of networks around but
it's not there because there is a strong
security need there is useful for checks
and other things so I can't answer
whether people are using it and believe
that they are getting security I can
answer that if they are using it because
they believe they're getting security
then they are mistaken and I agree what
they drink 100% so one of the things
that might be useful to do specifying
the drop is hey if you're using md5 to
get the security construct with LD 5
please consider moving away from it and
here's the alternative protocol that
would be very useful thing to do and
I'll send some text along that line that
would be great thank you
Deborah's Deaconess ad I'm very happy
Adrienne made the statement he did
because if there had been any security
abs in the room when we said hey
nothing's ever happened why we have to
fix it they they would have been lined
up at this mic in a flash so what they
want to see really is that we
acknowledge that there are risk and that
we definitely have a plan a target to
advise people using RFC's what they can
do and as the same clarify md5 is not
good for security TCPA o is a good
target and they will be more than happy
to help us to fine-tune if she use a
crypto algorithm or what we should be
saying there this is very important that
we're doing this I agree it's important
the the thing I'm wondering about is
really what are the threats and are
those threats remedied by md5 probably
not or the remedy by TCGA oh maybe but
as long as we don't really have it good
threaten all analysis it's hard to
actually say to get do give the correct
recommendation well we have the one RFC
from the we had MPLS security
considerations or something LAN had done
it and another's and I mean it's also
the security ATS are asking or they out
may be out in left field that they don't
understand our threats and nor use
models have those used models changed so
they they were actually asking for for
that type of information and to put in
the security considerations that they
don't have to every time
go through with a fine-tooth comb trying
to figure out well how are we deploying
this solo you're you're correct and
maybe we should update that document
maybe in this document we should put a
better analysis or what the threats
could be you know something like that
just to point out it was RC 69 52 that
did that analysis just one two-second re
this draft is recalling use of the md5
like it don't use it or just yes
well the the goal is basically to do
exactly what RFC 74/54 did with PGP you
know RC 74/54 for bgp said stop using
md5 use TCP AO instead right so the so
the goal is to do basically the exact
same thing for LD P so that means that
whoever used the md5 is out of spectrum
well no not yet
yeah well when we when we pass it yes
yeah yeah yeah when we publish it if
they want to to be conform it to the new
version of LD P that uses TCP AO then
yes they would need to update the
implementation well you know the vendor
would need to update the code and then
they would need to deploy that okay yeah
so as a piece of anecdotal information
was that when we actually put md5 into
the LDP when we did the document the
first time we already know that there
were doubts about md5 and we made a note
somewhere if you have to look into this
it only that we never had any indication
that it was necessary so that's why we
are where we are where we are
okay so I think okay thanks thank you
Andy
so next up is Aiden so sorry about that
if you're listening remotely that was me
fiddling with the microphone
my name is TBD
and I think on the original draft agenda
lower put down 15 minutes for this draft
and I made the argument that we needed
30 seconds so we'll compromise it's a
really small problem and a really small
draft to solve it the the problem
basically comes from when we wrote 70 to
74 which was clarifying the use of
special-purpose labels how you allocate
them how you retire them we thought we
had the terminology clear and consistent
with the IANA registry since then as
people have started to write drafts that
use especially the extended
special-purpose labels which are only
just coming into use we've found that
people a bit confused as to exactly what
terminology they should use so we've
written this tiny little draft which
tweaks the terminology and the idea is
then that we'll have something
consistent we can use going forward and
will be stable at least for six months
until we discover that this isn't clear
either so and there are two registries
in the Ayana maintains for this and they
are located on the same I on a web page
there are two ways into that way
Paige so when you go to the the full
list of registries you see two entries
separately but whichever one you click
on it takes you to this page and both
registries are there they are currently
called special-purpose MPLS label values
and extended special-purpose MPLS label
values which all looks perfectly cool
but both of those registries contain
label values that are special purpose so
now everyone is confused when they say
special purpose MPLS label which which
registry are they really pointing that
so we propose to make this clear by
further qualifying the the base registry
so now both registries have a have a
separate name base an extension extended
so if you talk about special purpose
your being generic if you mean one
registry you said base if you mean the
other registry you say extended and that
gives us then some shorthand
terminologies SPL as I say any special
purpose label ABI SPL for the base and
one of those of course is the extension
label and then espl for all the extended
special purpose labels and remember that
that's quite a big range of which naught
to 15 you're not allowed to use and the
others are chopped out for allocation
experimentation and something in the
future maybe and then we've added a new
term to cover the the pairing of the
extension label and an extended special
purpose label so that's a composite
special special purpose label I have
said this so often now my tongue is
getting special purpose label jr. on
this slider in general yes but I can
wait in America I was wondering does it
mean that you can have extended base SPL
from the second minute
when you use the extension label I'm
just wondering on how confusing the next
stage of the terminology you may end up
into so you cannot a thin extended base
would mean to you to have an extended
base you would have to have an a base
label with a value larger than 15 you
cannot do that okay because the the MPLS
architecture the reason we have extended
labels extended special purpose labels
is because you can't do that okay so
it's just anything as a base label
anything that is larger than 15 is a
real switching forwarding label and any
attempt to make a special reservation on
that would blow up in all the deployed
base so we had to steal one label for
the excel and make the extended okay
thank you but I'm all in favor of
confusing the terminology if we can find
a legitimate way to do it I can help you
so what does that look like in use this
is the normal label stack with a with a
what used to be just a regular SPL but
now we've got a a base SPL showing up in
the stack it goes yellow that's very
nice and and this is what it looks if
you have an extension label remember the
extension label is a base SPL and then
we follow that with an extended SPL and
the two of them together are called
composite SPL this is the it's been on
the on the mailing list but Wow
meet EKKO is like a week behind okay
right it's been on the mailing list only
for a week or something it's really
really short we would like to hear
people tell us we've got something wrong
or we don't need to do it at all
otherwise it looks like it's so short
that
I would expect I guess low I can't do it
but I would expect the chairs - just
like adopt and move through using their
process and and get it done quickly
questions okay how many has actually
read the draft fair number how many
things we should actually go ahead and
do this that is interesting because
that's more than actually read the draft
so you're not must you must have made a
good presentation thank you oh thank you
radium
hello everyone my name is Chen Xiang
from City my presentation today is the
SRM pstp inter-domain use cases first of
all let me explain the SRM pstp as we
are as we all know that in SRM pious
networks there sr pass must be
unidirectional but in some transport
networks for example and pstp networks
the SR bi-directional path must be
established it and the draft ITF spreem
M has passed segmented draft has defined
a path segments to support s are
bi-directional path correlation so based
on that the this document discussed in
the domain scenarios in SRM pstp
networks there in this document the SR
bidirectional end-to-end Puffy's must be
established across multiple domains and
the path segment is used to indicate the
into the may pass or end-to-end paths so
firstly there are two models over there
s are M POS into the main the first one
is the stitching in a domain domains are
isolated and thus teaching at the end
others teaching node or link will push
their list of the s ID to a further Lu
sub Turner and in nesting into domain
model global segments listed after their
interests law as our load and the juror
is an end-to-end process ID uniquely
across all domains and then in this
document we also discussed there as RMP
STP int working with MPs TP this is
achieved two shifts the to realize the
end-to-end
we pian surface by interlocking between
the SR and MPs TP lat works with their
path segments so first net net look at
their SR mph it is teaching into domain
there are intimates as a figure show in
there are just teaching models their end
to end parts can be divided into several
segments and we defined or intimated
path segments or into may pass as ID to
indicate each segment for example there
we we are established their end to end
path from A to C and it will be divided
into a to X X to Y and the Y to Z under
there are we we have there I pass a 2x f
has X to Y and I pass while Y to Z and
this is the forward pass and the read
reverse pass a star is the same for
example I pass c2 y Y to X in the X to a
so when we translate trans trans
forwards the packet in the editor in
ingress load for example in load a we
will poster the first segment we
gunpowder age who X srte
it is a 2x as ID list exactly and there
I pass a 2x and and the payload
following that then as as we know as our
translate load Bo Porter top of the
labels under when the trend when the
packets being forwarded to the load X
there I pass a to X will be the first
with the Pedro top label of their MPs
text then X we all switched their I pass
a 2x to the Lexus segment information
like this I I pass a 2x will switch to
the X to Y as our te and I pars X to Y
then and in at the reload why it is the
same with X and ER when the pack is free
being forwarded to the load of Z it will
be owning existed there I pass Y to Z
and then I pass Y to Z will correlate
their bidirectional tars for example I
pass Y to Z enter the load they will
switch to the 3/2 Y srte and 32y I pass
advance ID so they sisters teaching into
domain and lasting in the domain is
there is an end-to-end pass segment we
called h e+ h UT to indicate the
end-to-end part and this is the
forwarding parts and there is first part
is the 3 2 I pass and this is and after
the ingress load a we were pushed a to X
srte and the sub pass a to X and the
pounding si T X X to Y and there upon e
si tu Y to Z and the Valerii we will
push the epass a 2d then when the packet
forwarded to the X the neighbor will be
debunking si T X to Y and reporting si D
we use it to reduce the depth over there
vampires label stack so in this in here
here is we use the list to switch to
pumping si T to the executor in domains
srte enter is in photo may pass segment
for example at
Lord X the bounteous ITX - what a - X
will be switched to the x - y srte under
duress subparts x - y and there at the
load y it is the same stress procedure
and when the package being forwarded to
other low Z there are will be holding
their epass hoc existed then 30 will
switch their a 2t e parts to that z28
the reverse parts per segment so they're
in the to end
mmm EEP ours will create late correlate
their to the unidirectional parts so
melody we discussed the SRM PST P and NP
STP interworking as the figures show we
have as our domain and mps TP domain and
there they are they are the SR term and
MPs Turner they are all their
bidirectional trailer and we will we
will eat to achieve der and to ender VPN
service crossed SR and MP STP domains
then we will use the path segments from
eight one load one to load a and
teaching and under associated the MPS
label at the load a and this is the
forward forwarding paths and there in
the reverse pass at load a we will make
mapping their MPs labeled z28 you the
path segments from A to Z then we are
achieved arenda to enter a VPN service
so we in this document we discussed the
several years into the main use cases so
last step we were searched or solutions
for as our MPs TP into
mein and their comments and discussions
are very welcome thank you
any questions so I have one I'm looking
sorry I'm looking at this spring shorter
and the spring shorter says that SR
typically works within one single trust
domain and then it goes on and make some
statement about some cases might be
different so this type of work is
actually across what I understand are it
trust amounts so Debra okay and we have
it comment here but Debra do you have an
idea what we need if we were to do this
work what would we have to do regarding
the shorter from for spring or is there
anything else we need to do well
question is for Debra she never has a
mic I I would say without looking at the
document of course to be very careful on
the the word there domain in if how
about what that implies and and I do
know that segment browning has been very
careful in their definition of domain
because we went back and forth on that
quite a bit in is G so I would say you
know just work with the chairs and of
segment routing and and and just save it
as this is still just an early very
early document I think just cross your
T's and make sure you've defined domain
as they do and and and that everybody
can understand what it is that you if
you really mean intradomain as regards
psyche same m rounding right so just
work you know the charity lower if you
know you filled
those interests here to do this work
with the other chairs to see um if
there's a clash or something what
whatever and we can also we can always
see see their lists right to say that we
have this dog oh yeah we will discuss it
I just kind of wanted a immediate
reaction I point out that there is
something that needs to be addressed
here I think that this document would
probably need some discussion on the
relationship between trust domains and
the domains that you have in this
document it's not it's it's for me it's
kind of reasonable to say that those the
SR domain and the SRM fellows TP domain
or within the same trust domain but you
need to define that clearly to get
around later surprises omega2 for
example I see your Directorate reviews
an emotional dream per um when you say
domain right maybe that's a clear
identification of intentions here I
didn't read the draft sorry
you mean the administration domain or
like IGP floating domain I would have to
say technology domain because technology
domain yeah because it relates SR I need
to assign the seats right so my my first
get was okay this is one big
administration domain so it's one
operational organization they just slice
and dice internally for whatever reason
Joel Halpern again from Erickson let me
suggest looking at it slightly
differently getting at the point you
were making lower the point as I
understood the presentation
to inter work between SR mpls and
conventional MPLS when you're doing past
sensitive information well that's a
perfectly valid thing to run into in a
perfectly ordinary deployment scenario
I'm doing that over here I'm doing the
other over here they're all part of the
same domain if you simply get rid of the
notion that you're talking about inter
domain we now have a much simpler
question that clearly does fall within
our remit to address thank you well I
think that is a reasonable look at it I
my my my take is at the top of is Trust
or administrative domain that's the the
big thing and that could be slice and
dice in different ways internally but
then we are not really in the domain we
are going across different different
technologies domain is so vague so
anyone just want to write the
terminology graft over me okay I was say
differently again I understand Deborah's
suggestion is to clarify how the main is
used in the context of this proposal so
we don't have to boil the ocean and
provide explanation of all possible
interpretations but just discuss and
what we will agree on how we interpret
the main in the context of this work yes
only this work yes and I take clue that
been suggested look carefully how the
main is used throughout spring documents
and try to come up with
what is most suitable for this world so
basically try to reuse as much as
possible interpretation that already
being used in a spring orton group
specifically in SRM vos sorry is one of
course that's what we're gonna do
perfect this is Adrian
yeah so I think what spring did was they
used a term called SR domain to mean an
SR to him and that enabled them to say
that an SR domain has trust requirements
and also that SR does not leave that
domain that's actually the definition of
an SR domain that when an SR packet gets
to the edge of the domain it ceases to
be SR and if there's another SR domain
you have to restart you can't get this
hour across so looking at this document
very briefly just over a hundred uses of
the word domain and the document it
starts off talking about SR domain but
then I think it moves on to talking
about different types of domain where
yes our domain is big and within it
there are different domains so that's
kind of yes you're correct there there
is this unintended change of terminology
and that might be explained but at the
same time okay so just to say well we
have to be more disciplined with the
terminology and that's what we're gonna
do we'll review the document who
appreciate your comments please do it on
the mailing list and help us to make it
better document but yes we will need to
clarify their mapping between I start
the main and this use case okay any
further questions can I see how many
actually read the document
oh I see well that must be 200 mm why
not two or three hands yeah now the -
okay okay thank you
you have some ideas that what should be
done and go ahead and do that and send
them host a new doc new version of
document on the on the mailing list okay
thank you okay
so now it's Greg did you steal the okay
so as war already announced this is just
a an update
you might remember recall that we have a
working group adoption poor I should do
some of the background first we started
the working applause what a noob
adoption policy is document we found
that there are things to discuss so we
don't normally want to take that type of
discussion especially if we aim to do an
update during your working group
adoption Paul so I close the working
group adoption Paul I told Greg to go
and talk to the people making comments
and actually try to post a new version
or the document and then we restart the
working group adoption Paul later yes so
as part of their intelligent group
process before adoption Paul MPs review
team experts were asked and volunteered
to review will receive reviews from ACN
Rakesh many thanks to them and as we
discussed their comments some of the
comments got addressed in the document
that been published
in the course of this disk as a result
of discussion but some comments we
agreed with ASEAN Rakesh that would be
certainly addressed in the following
work and that can happen after working
group adoption as we received as the
working group adoption pool was
officially opened we received comments
from Tom and it was absolutely
appropriate comments and I accept all of
them but we couldn't communicate fast
enough to separate the comments that he
believes that needs to be addressed
before document adopted by the working
group and then can be worked later on so
that's exactly what we are doing now I
shared this slides with Tom and so here
they're issues that still outstanding
and this are a combination of issues
that been pointed out both by Tom and AC
and Rakesh specifically what tom is
pointing to is that lack of references
in the model makes it very hard to map
it in part this is because this draft
this model has a very long history so it
started as 43 79 model and then 80 29
updated I was P and LS l SP think RFC
came out so now we believe that it
should be pointing to 80 29 and there
are a lot of things that we need to
catch up and we will certainly do that
and we hope that the working group will
participate and contribute once it takes
ownership of this document so waiting
for Tom to respond on his opinion what
he thinks as a mandatory changes before
another working group adoption and what
with our agreement and commitment to
follow through all the comments that we
received so far what he agrees that
would be acceptable to address after
working group adoption and so that's
priorities for work that possibly after
working group adoption but it might
change based on Tom input and the last
one it expands go beyond eighty twenty
nine it was pointed as optional by ACN
Rakesh because yes there have been
several extensions to MPLS LSP to other
cases like point-to-multipoint LSP evpn
spring so we'll definitely need working
group input and suggestions where you
think that everything better be put into
one model or this new extension still
and they'll sls we think can be worked
as augmentation
but any questions I have one and I asked
you before the when you have RSVP or
actually rsvp-te in the same sentence as
effect that is that's problematic
because there's no way of doing effect
validation or fact signaling in in RSVP
well again if again if I remember
correctly that's the terminology used in
43 79 and then consequently in 80 29 so
but I'll take another look at the
terminology is used because again the
TLD is called target effectively so it
might be that it's more like in lingo
that we're talking about as this is a
FAQ whereas yeah it might be not really
a fact but it's basically we're
describing for which LSP this label was
allocated and that's we're verifying
that this OSP echo request arrived on
the LSP that this label been allocated
for so basically we one of their main om
or goals that our speaking achieves is
to verify their consistency between the
control plane and the data plane so that
their endpoint receives their LSP being
from the Elco request from their OSP
that the label being assigned for so
basically there there is a correlation
between the control plane when the label
was assigned to the data plane status
where this echo request arrived from so
what you're saying is that your first
sentence that should be reference to RCA
t29 in the existing target effect
TLV okay anyone that actually know if
the target effectively is defined for
poor are sleeping yeah and again it
could be lingo but yes it's called RSVP
not rsvp-te and that's I believe how
it's recorded in a Jana registry RSVP
Tarek Francisco yeah yeah the LSP FAQ
the 5-tuple basically its defined and I
believe RFC 3209 it is carried in the
OEM packet as a target fact is that what
you intend is that your model train you
yeah no I think that again third the
question is whether they're RSVP FAQ is
a correct or is the accurate name or it
shouldn't be our cpt FAQ right I think
it's enough identification to identify
that LSP or that label that right and
and there's five items there that at
least we're trying to model in the
rsvp-te model were using five tuple to
identify that LSP if that's what you
mean Nagato from Cisco in eighty twenty
nine we have it defined as RSVP ipv4 LSP
and ipv6 LSB the differentiates between
definite is family yeah right but again
if I understand your question correctly
is that should it be rsvp-te ipv4 ipv6
back yeah but my understanding is that
for one reason or another in Ayana it's
recorded as RSVP ipv4 if you
they expect this might be mode that I
need to go check it again but there
might be a couple of words something
they need to do in there to make it
clear okay yeah I think I mean again
it's like LBP ipv4 and RSVP ipv4 so it's
basically uses the protocols that we
used to I know instantiate the LSP path
so I'm not sure if we really need to
define if it is for traffic engineering
because I'm not aware of any other
application of RSVP to instantiate the
LS piece okay further questions okay
thank you Greg this is uh
Nagendra from Cisco this is a draft that
clarifies the length for the sub t elvis
that is defined in RFC 8287 this was
identified as part of Interop testing
with the NTC so RFC 8287 basically
defines the you know they targeted FEC
stacks of TLV for segment routing IGP
prefix said and not just since he said
so one off for the thing that was most
in RFC 8287 is to you know clarify if or
how the length of the sub TLB should be
you know computer so this is an example
of one off for the targeted FEC stacks
up tlv which is for y GP prefix segment
ID so as you could see one of the field
is a result field so there are you know
implementation where some implementation
considers the result field as part of
the length while defining the TLV but
another implementation does not include
this which basically created some
Interop issue so this draft basically
clarifies that to address the center of
issues so we basically defined that
the resort field must be considered
while you know computing the length
field so it explains are the different
sub tlvs and identifies you know what
would be the length along with a couple
of you know examples so it's a pretty
straightforward done a simple draft that
basically we believe is a logical fix
for one of the intra problem like Kalos
mentioning I know this is recently
adopted as a workgroup document and this
being a straightforward Dom or fix we
believe this is ready for workgroup loss
but any comments or feedback so welcome
okay thank you
one point that is more for procedure you
actually need to send a request for a
working group class call to the working
group shares it's more for our
bookkeeping them for anything else but
it makes it easier this is question from
Howie and this is a new trust named RSP
it's time for cyclic queuing and
forwarding or pundit or agency so let's
begin with the background of these
large-scale deterministic Network which
we are doing in the dead tonight working
group and LDN aims to achieve fondant
latency forwarding on layers three
networks and the contain long distance
links and large numbers of nodes and
flows and out in record sites all
packets sent from the upstream water in
a specific cycle must be sent to the
downstream water within another specific
cycle because in our DNA we maintains
three cues in a specific interface and
those cues are cyclic schedule therefore
in Audion its request at
dates prime animals is used to indicate
which optional cycle packets belongs to
so that a downstream node could use this
indication to put the packet into the
right receiving hue so if we consider a
specific package once the cycle for the
sending packets in the ingress node is
determined the one in the us node is
determined to such achieving into in
only the latency so this is the airspeed
is crying for a secure life the idea is
very single the downstream node
allocates three different empires labels
for each ESP and advertises information
to the upstream node by using signaling
protocols such as r2 Apte so each of
these levels is associated with a
specific queue in the abdominals as
throwing the right figure we assume that
if the package is sent from the upstream
node q1 it should be labeled waste 1003
and if the packet is informed
q2 it should be leveled waste one solid
and one so about the FIB installation we
assume that a package sent from the
upstream node q1 q2 and q3
should be put into the downstream nodes
q3 T 1 and Q 2 respectively
note that how to is establish such
making relationship will be described in
the future version of this document and
therefore the package since form
downstream North Q 1 will be put into
the time frame node q3 so on and so
forth
so in this way that into in the pounding
the latest thing could be achieved as
for the LD interrupt so next steps about
the straps we will describe how to
establish the mapping relationship we
have a self-learning McNamee indicates
prime and we need more suggestions and
comments on this new work
Thanks Rajiv oh sorry Cisco so I'm just
a drop also specify how the mapping how
the upstream neighbor would learn about
the distinct labels for the same prefix
but differentiated by the cues or the
class of services to the upstream
neighbor currently our solution it's
like it doesn't matter which lie both
extremely I would associate it to a
specific you because today we have a
self-learning
magnin's of mechanism in the downstream
node to learn this information for
example if I receive a package Labrador
is one solid and one in the downstream
note it can automatically send this
packet in a specific queue in a local
computation I can animate the loss if
the node one is sending the packet with
one label 1001 to node 2 node 2 locally
is somehow changing 1001 into 1,002
1,003 1,004 depending on the queues
internally yeah if I follow that right
then what's then it's local to the node
then why does it need to be or does it
not mean to be conveyed to the external
set of neighbors like node 1 and if if
there's no need then we can because the
chance to you know the master knows that
a group of package belongs to a cycle in
the upstream node and another group of
packets around to another cycle
in the optional so that's why we should
use three levels to identify this
deformation but is that supposed to be
the internal to the node it's supposed
to be external to the node the usage of
distinct labels per Q it's just the
local information it's at answering them
so ready we can I try to well clarify at
least for me your question so sending a
packet to a node does that has a
specific label depending on which Q
should go into that's what you mean with
external or is it just inside the node
and when it comes out again on the
outgoing interface it has a just one
single label for him right if you need
so if I really intending to specify the
internal node specific local behavior or
we are specifying something that changes
the either the data plane on the wire or
the control plane on the wire or both
and that's what I'm struggling with so
maybe I can clarify this if the
downstream node received a package this
is the first packet from this afternoon
node it's received and this level is
1001 and it will if it receives this
packet in psycho X so it will map this
rabble to psycho
X plus 2 so it will establish the
meta-narrative relationship size each
which level should be mapped to which
kill and use this mapping relationship
to instruct the subsequent packet so
it's just a local computation procedure
if it's a local computation and behavior
change mean most implementations today
do something similar from the queuing
point of view by looking at an MPLS TC
bits as an example of previously known
as exp and then what are the value might
be there map it to one of those many
cues that the implementation on the
platform may have that's all the local
behavior right I mean we don't really
specify how that gets done internal
inside the implementation say if the the
intent of the graph is to specify what's
what the implementation might intend to
do to map an incoming packet to one of
many cues and I'm not shift that needs
to be standardized so maybe I can
describe the detailed details in that
it's flying in the future version of the
document and they wouldn't say we can
talk about more sure yeah and maybe we
can talk offline as well actually a Greg
nurse kzt especially for the dead net if
even if it's a local behavior I think
that might be helpful and useful to do
the document that explains it because
there are a lot of needs to be required
coordination and everything has to act
in accord in order to achieve their
objectives of that net so yes it might
look like it's low chimera and
implementation but it might be important
and let's look at this more because it
should it might be just need to be
advertised as capability Yanis focus I
have a question for clarification first
the title mentions cqf cyclic Ewing and
forwarding and first slide refers to
the so-called large-scale I'm confused
what it is about the cyclic queueing
forwarding is to I typically standard
802 doctrine to see H that is fall into
a 2.1 queue 2018 I'm sorry
10 of misleading because this traveler
is target liked scale Network
deterministic networking and all right
our Tian Yu's and somehow enhanced
seeker I have to achieve upon data
latency so maybe the terms he's not
cracked I think that's a different
approach so it's misleading to the oscqr
okay and for that I would like to
mention just a previous session in this
room in that not that there was a
lengthy discussion on the basic proposal
you refer to and it's not clear what's
the next step forward and what what the
next step we are taking what is needed
it has been shown that the mathematical
proof is incorrect so it's up it's open
what's happening in that net and what
would be the next step thank you for the
questions can I ask how many actually
read the document like three four okay
there are clarifications that we are
asking for best understood so please go
ahead and do those and post in your
audition thank you
someone new
you know performance management
encapsulation oh you
okay so let's sorry let's do the mean
prayer first and then we so we swap in
the last two presentations because we
have a error in the data tracking
Jenny Kumar Broadcom before I go in this
drafts discussion I'll talk about the
background of the draft that how it came
into the existence so there was a work
which was done for customers in the IP
network where they wanted to collect the
data on a live packet which as we call
as in band Network telemetry that work
is being deployed into large MSD sees
quite a few deployments are there and
that's an v4 TCP UDP GRE IP and IP h ESP
it's a pretty large and cap set which is
being deployed so once that deployment
was done the requests were coming that
can we do the same thing into MPLS and
then based on that the evolution of this
raft happened which is in band Network
telemetry and MPLS domain and hence that
has the acronym mint great you are there
before I go you have a question okay I
can wait and just want to point that we
had the discussion when original
proposal for IOM as in band om came
about around and I think it's not
accurate and it's misleading because in
band means that om packet follows the
data packet and active om can be in band
and actually if it's not in band then
the value of this active om is very
limited so in particular in MPLS and
ecmp environment if the entropy label is
used to generate the hash in a CMP then
active who I am
is as much is in band as anything else
so
that's why I think that try to highlight
and differentiate that saying oh this is
in band implying that everything else is
not in band is not technically accurate
okay so I'm not aware of that discussion
so the reason I have used in band is
because the goal is that the OEM packet
as you're calling or the mint packet as
we call in the draft must reverse the
same data path in the data plate and you
know if in MPOs if we're talking about
active either it's BFD or info sls
beeping so if we be disciplined and use
entropy label on data flow and or active
or a.m. that's supposed to monitor at
the data flow then they are in then
because in band again my interpretation
is that you follow exactly the same path
same notes interfaces and links so use
of entropy label and the same income
label encapsulation and it's applicable
both to MPLS and SRM
alloys I see a point I get yeah I agree
with that so if you use the entropy
level in the NS beeping now it can also
follow the same path so if there is a
suggestion to change the name we are
open to that it's a first draft so
coming back to the draft so as I was
giving the background this has been
deployed in IP networks there are
conversations for deploying in in the
MPLS Network I don't know if I'll be
able to go in all the details but the
key point is the usage of the special
label composite special label as was
talked earlier this raft makes use of
that I don't know it's the first stuff
to make use of it but I realized there
are authors on this raft and the other
SPL draft which are common so that's why
probably they lean to use this all the
suggestion to use the CSB
so motivation is again that the protocol
itself should be very simple it should
be in band and we should be able to
trace the flow of the packet which is
exactly same as the original live packet
flow there are a few enhancements which
we can do in this which is captured in
the details which is a clone mode or in
band mode in man mode meaning that all
the data which is being collected by
inserting the metadata in the packet
itself is done for the live packets and
there is a clone mode we make a copy of
the packet and that can be done for
various reasons because the NTU the PMT
you is is less the part of the packet
may exceed the peon to you or there are
other reasons to do that in that case
there is ability to create a cloning of
the cup of the packet and then the in
bank collection of the data is done for
the clone mode
great okay there are two proposed at
least two proposals or if not actually
three in I ppm working group in no
particular order
one of them in inflow analyzer I say
another one is postcard and another one
is hybrid two-step they are not data
plane specific at least IFA does have or
discusses defines a use of cloning
method to obtain actually I personally
prefer for this type of telemetry
collection as on path telemeter
connection similar to on pass support
hybrid two step proposes to collection
of data in the follow-up packet that has
the same transport layer encapsulation
as a data packet so the data packet
effectively is only a trigger
all telemeter information is in the
follow-up vagin and actually the HCC
defines that if this packet is full then
another packet can be generated so
basically will arrive with the train of
telemetry information filled packets and
postcard is that when telemetry is
exported of each note that traversed by
the trigger packet right so thank you
for that so I can give a brief
background on that conversation which
Greg just talked about so if you look
carefully there are three parts to the
proposal and these proposal are also
moving in the IP PM group there is a
protocol and cap part especially in the
IP then there is a data header part that
how do you represent the data in a in a
way where you can figure out either to
check some of the data the length of the
data or put some control information and
then the data itself so there are
various proposal for the packet and cap
I agree and this is a proposal which is
very very simple in the IP and it's
deployed so we have a proof point that
it works right
I'm talking to various folks in area
where we can have some agreement on the
data header as well as the data types so
data types become a registry and then
based on the registry we can define
namespaces which is essentially the set
of data types which uses the common data
header and then they can be carried over
in different protocols protocols could
be a postcard could be IOM could be IFA
so and so forth and the same proposal
follows here in this case the protocol
becomes very simple because protocol and
cap is done using the CSV this is
use cases that a set of use cases and
they are very basic there are advanced
uses use cases which can be built on
that that was just a summary of those
use cases this is the terminology the
way we have defined and I believe based
on the input if mint or in-band network
telemetry is not the right acronym then
then we have to change the labels so I'm
okay with that but just to give you an
idea what essentially it says that mint
is a domain where all the nodes are
participating in mint essentially
collecting the data on a per packet
basis the node in a domain is called as
a mint node and the mint label which is
which is the CSP which is the extended
label using the label extension 15 is an
are located in the draft we have taken a
Liberty to use the first label which is
16 since nothing was used so far but
that's just an attempt if that's not the
right thing we can always change that
mint metadata is the information or is
the data set which is collected on a per
node per packet basis there are
functions on the node and these are the
these are the functions which either sit
on the edge of the domain or sit within
the middle of the domain the edge of the
domain is defined by the node which
performs the initiation function or the
termination function initiation means
that when the packet comes in there is
an insertion of mint header and also the
mint metadata by that node and then the
transit nodes all they do they do the
detection part that yes this is a mint
packet it has a presence of the CSP
label and then based on that it inserts
the method it adds some predefined
location and then the last node at the
edge which is the termination node does
the same thing that it detects that it's
a mint packet and then based on
it's a copy of the packet then it drops
it if it's a live packet or in-band
packet then it strips the foreign data
creates a report and report could be
anything it could be postcard for exact
example and then sends it out to the
collector so that's the domain and the
nodes and the functions this was the
terminology which is used in the draft
throughout right I wonder if you
consider it instead of using label to
indicate use just associate the channel
type that's also in the in the draft we
have not put the appendix of all the
considerations there is an issue with
that and I can have a side conversation
with using the ESS actually we cater it
in the draft that what are the other
options which will consider right
because again in 1588 propagation over
MPLS so in this RFC residence time
measurement we proposed to transport
1588 through the domain is associated
channel a new type and then collect on
each node residence time in a scratch
field and that can be used not only it
can be used either to measure residence
time across the path or it can be used
as well for correction of 1588 clock so
from the master to the slave and
actually there is a description of how
you can manipulate TTL on the label
because you can discover which nodes
participate in it so then not every node
can be compliant
the problem with their label might
happen
in SR MPLS because you you might then
have to insert this label multiple times
based on what their maximum depth of
label stack nodes can support any other
main right so this was the ACH header
was considered there were various issues
which were identified they are not
captured in the left I will send you
offline you can review provide me your
rebuttal if you agree or not and then I
think we will capture it in the appendix
yes but ok so I was reinvention so my
second question was assertive hog the
mic have you look at the applicability
of this approach to asaramji OS yes yes
and in the first iteration of the draft
it is not captured it works in the SRM
Paris but then you have to allow
multiple insertions of this label in a
stack so in this presentation I am not
covering s all what is considered and
there is a packet flow which we will
circulate in the next iteration Allah
it's Adrian can I make a plea to you to
take the explicit ion a value out of
your draft and replace it with the
letters TBD I will do that to get Marty
vio
you have to be anything you like because
it's really dangerous putting values in
drafts you've picked one that has been
allocated already by Ayane for something
else realize that yeah so
example of mint deployment where an MPLS
domain is actively be actively
participating in maintainer collection
as you can see in ER has been designated
with a mint initiation and the
termination function and by the way
there are logical functions same
physical node may be performing both the
functions that confusion happens
whenever we talk about it but there is
just a logical representation of the
topology and transit routers the LS R's
are the one which are acting as the mint
transit nodes or mint nodes inserting
the metadata and on the penultimate hop
both the behaviors are supported where
we can do the PHP and in that case the
last hops metadata actually is not
available some deployments it might be
okay some deployments it's not okay and
the reason this is being considered is
ability to put less stress stress on the
hardware if hardware has to do the label
pops and then the second set of lookups
it becomes very expensive to do the
hardware implementation I see a problem
you are you have like three four minutes
left
other than half just lies so you have to
come to conclusion I'll go faster this
is the packet format and in this case
the CSP is the extension label and the
mint label and then there is the stack
of mints which is present you can go on
the text the tunnel mood is supported
again this draft does not go in the
details of the tunnel mode but the basic
concept is propagation those edits will
come in the next set of draft which is
the propagation that whenever mint
packet enters into an another tunnel
just like TTL propagation we can have a
configuration which says that propagate
the
mint information when it enters into the
tunnel what essentially it means that we
can unable still a poor packet flow and
we will collect the data before it
enters into the tunnel mode in the
tunnel itself and when it transits the
tunnel then also the data is collected
so that's the tunnel mode in the
transport mode there is only a single
stack which is present and again this is
to ease the implementation that if there
are some hardware limitations where it's
not it's very expensive to support two
modes then the tunnel mode then
transport mode may be a good idea I'll
just quickly go over the header before
at this so that my time is close this is
the header and in this if you see by the
way here I use TBA but in the draft we
ended up using actually a label so there
are two headers one is a mint header
which has the control information and
this header influences the behavior of
the packet in the data path it tells
what to do what not to do then there is
a metadata header it has no control
information it does not control the
behavior of the packet all it has that
was the length of the metadata what kind
of metadata to collect is there a need
to take an action on the metadata itself
let's say we do some kind of
thresholding and what is the current
length there are some implicit checks
which can be done use this information
with sort of functions like a control
function but they're really not a
control function and the reason I am
bringing it in the IPP and working group
the other proposals ended up putting a
lot of information in the in the mint
metadata header and there was a feedback
that that really breaks the paradigm of
the layering of the header information
okay so next protocol feel is the one
which can be used to create a chain and
this is something very very interesting
because when you put the mint header
then you can actually indicate what kind
of payload is carrying I'm going to stop
on stop here the next steps is that we
are looking for review and comments on
the graph so
a little couple of slides back to the
tunnel mode yeah so I understand the
ingress you add or copy the the mint
label the overlay so what happens in the
egress and there's a transit tunnel and
if you want to recap slate and send it
out kind if you have data in the mint at
the outer layer what do you intend to do
so in this so that's a very good
question yeah so there are two ways we
can handle it I can with we can reflect
it back into the inner mint stack and
that's how that mint data can be carried
and it may may be OK for the flexible NP
use which can do much more flexible
processing of the data but fixed
pipelines it's not ok there is a mode
which is supported which is called as a
fragment in that case we can take this
data along with the packet send it out
to the collector instead of reflecting
it back into the inner ok it's not a
questioner crisp and clear yes 30
seconds yeah I strongly encourage you to
read hybrid to step and I afraid drafts
or the similarities and then being
around so let's think how can we work
together ok thank you very much you take
this to the list and I expect the
authors likely to be posting discussion
on the list
hello everyone I'm Sami from GTE I'm
going to present chapter 10 amperes in
Ben p.m. encapsulation this is a 0 0
version draft ok an intention of this
job is Jeff the defiance to the
encapsulation for amperes in band
performance measurement this method is
based on FC 8321
Audrey the marking method this method
requires amperes flow identification
which is a disgusting RFC 83 72 and the
Salone synonymous flow label is a way to
do this flow identification but it's a
bit complex to manage and it seems not
applicable to nested flow ID so this
chapter PI's a special-purpose label
this slide demonstrates the Indian PM
encapsulation it requests in band PM
indicator label it's a special-purpose
label and is followed by a flow ID label
that includes candidates flow ID values
one bit lost
marking a one bit delay marking and all
these fields are required by FC 8321
alternate marquee method this is the
first example to illustrate the stereo
how flow ID label can be applied to RSV
in this example you can see florida
label is not at the bottom of the label
stack
and the PW label or we RF label at the
bottom of labor stack this is the second
example to illustrate the scenario float
ID label is the bottom of the label
stack in this in our scenario it can be
used to measure the PW or PRF so that's
a different example with the previous
one this is the third example in this
scenario for right Nestea the flow ID
exists in a label stack so it can be
used and can be applied to SP as well as
PW or we have so among the two flow ID
label one is at the bottom of the label
stack and another one is not settled
bottom okay that's the step as former
review revise the draft
and they ask for working group adoption
I think question comments any questions
ok so we are at the end of agenda thank
you and you need to take this to the
list and actually authors need to push
the discussion on the list so we
concluded the meeting next time is where
monster all going back to we start this
kind of thing where we give him back to
the same set before a second or third or
the fourth time so Montreal is the place
been before
I don't know if it's the same motel but
I remember some good place so see you
there
safe trips
[Music]