[Music]
okay
it is time to start it's 150 you are
welcome to the NTP working group in
Prague you've already started the blue
sheet right or no the blue sheets
sitting right there so so the blue sheet
should be coming around folks should
sign that it's at 8:00 today's agenda do
you have that on display or okay it
doesn't so our agenda for today agenda
administration and agenda passing we
have towel for the minutes and we have
rich for jabber blue sheets are going
around be sure to sign them did you skip
I need to go back there we go the this
is an IHF meeting this is note well you
all acknowledge the note well when you
joined when you registered for the IETF
and so we everybody should be well aware
of it please abide by it okay so our
agenda this is the agenda bashing we
have the tic-tock working group status
then ntp working group status and basic
both of these are just quick reviews of
documents that would not going to need
to spend a lot of time talking about
today and just talk about what status
they're in we will cover the hackathon
activity over the weekend and then we
will talk about the rough time draft
that was submitted the I just lost the
name of the medes draft that is
technology but anyway this the draft
unsecure selection filtering from meta
Cronos there we go
I was thinking crony and I knew that was
the wrong word as like macaroni it's a
and very briefly on the yang data model
I know the author's can't be here but I
have an update from them and then the
piece that's that's currently missing
this any other business and housekeeping
so will at the end of these we're going
to talk about a number of the other
items if you look at the agenda online
you'll see the list of other things I
wanted to go through quickly that did
not have updates in advance of the IETF
if you've been following the mailing
list we got a ton of traffic today so I
haven't I've been busy today and I
haven't had time to even read at all
except seeing it go by so there we have
it so the first one however you're
displaying that it's not advancing one
slide at a time so this is not working
okay so the tick tock working group
status the yang data model has has made
it out and it's in the editor queue now
which is which is great news and the
second document which is the last
document remaining and the tick tock
working group is the enterprise profile
we addressed all of the nits yesterday
and an update thanks to her Heiko thanks
Danika and so that one is ready for
submission we will still have the same
the we will deal with the issue of the I
Triple E 1588 the same way we did last
time and hopefully that will will not
cause too many too much issue next Oh
Suresh is popping in the queue oh good
go ahead Suresh yeah thanks again so I'm
trying to formalize the process with
that ESG for that so I'm writing up
something so you will make this like a
standard procedure when the documents
are not freely available so this will be
like IETF white procedure that we follow
whenever some document is not freely
available then it goes telescope okay
great thank you
you always know you're being successful
when you require the development of a
new process or a new procedure so so
that's where we are with the 1588
Enterprise profile and then we've had a
number of conversations about this the
intention is when this document gets
through that we will close the tic-tock
working group and have a single time
working group in the IETF consolidate
all the resources in one place so next
slide so this is the NTP working group
status and these are documents that we
should not have too much to talk about
the BCP is in iesg evaluation it
currently has one outstanding discuss on
it and the authors of the document are
working to resolve that discuss and
hopefully we will we will have that done
shortly oh and suresh is coming back
into the queue thank you so the
outstanding discuss is from acre and
he's gonna leave the iesg so I had to
talk to him and figure out like you know
how he wants to followup on the
continuity or discuss so like whether
Roman is gonna take it off or like we
had to figure something out but either
way I will not have enough votes on the
ESG when the iesg turns over tomorrow so
I have to figure out like how to get the
additional reviews and to get this
document through but hopefully it should
not be too difficult
once the author's address like occurs
comments okay Dennis I know that I know
that you worked I don't know if you want
to say anything if you can you can hop
in the remote QR though oh there you go
Dennis hi there can you hear me we can
go ahead so Peter and I have been
working directly on the remaining on
those remaining discussed points and you
know I consider them you know valuable
feedback but nothing that really changes
the course of the document so regardless
of how what's going on with the iesg
dieter and I have agreed on the changes
that need to be made and Harlan's been
involved also in monitoring this and so
I plan to push out an update today I'm
not sure if that makes a difference in
terms of getting this pushed along but
you know regardless of whether or not
that that timeline works or not
I mean we're unprepared after this
meeting to go through and make these
minor edits and submit it okay if you
could go ahead and do that I think that
would be great I think and also respond
to Eric okay so I'm gonna pop you off
the queue and let Suresh talk for a
minute you can get back to ya Thanks hey
thanks Dennis okay like I really
appreciate your patience like I've been
talking to a core like it's discussed
has been there for a while but he's
trying to keep his own queue for the
incoming ad so he prioritize like his
documents which I totally understand
because he's swapping off and so thanks
for your patience on this and really
appreciate you trying to get this
resolved if you can push a document
today I'll try to get this on the next
possible tele chat and we can go from
there okay so but but the ball is really
in my court once you push the issues of
I'll try to find the other additional
ladies to vote no objection on this so
we can get enough votes to pass this
[Music]
okay thank you sir anything else on the
BCP okay there's two documents that have
been ready for submission for a while
now that we just haven't submitted and
we will be doing that very shortly now
and that's the control messages protocol
and the and this one as a reminder to
folks who haven't been following this is
it is basically cleaning up the work
that we did too
[Music]
we wrote in TP when we did the NTP v4
specification it's cleaning up a piece
that got left out so guidelines for
defining packet timestamps is also one
that's been ready for its submission
it's passed working group last call and
we just need to get it processed the
next one is NTS 4 ntp this is one we
spent a lot of time talking about did
you want to talk about after the last
until Envy making update there has been
some new content from Krista regarding
bono says Vanessa NTS key exchange
we caught messages and this has this has
been done and we are speaking about
hackathon we thought afterwards so yeah
this has has has been possible positive
and we are looking forward that we can
move this format I think we're going to
end up with a few minor clarifications
coming out of the hackathon well it's
what just discussed is one of them just
pointing out that NTS ke uses different
convention from from NTDs the second
clarification I'm going to drop in there
is up clarifying what cliff and I mean
is he coming what clients should do if
they maybe send an excessive number
above placeholders they'll it defrag
notation okay thank you I was trying to
determine if your voice was coming
through the microphone system or not
it's honor to speak more closely yeah so
everybody speak really close to the mic
retrieve it nobody has complained but
Ezra
but we do have a fairly long a fairly
long list of remote participants so
everybody remember to speak into the mic
alright so Thomas says you can thomas
can hear you so we're all great that's
that's fabulous okay so that's the NTP
working group status the next item on
the agenda is the no it's the hackathon
report so
okay hi my name is Chris Divine Eagle
I'm wondering you newbies here today
like Karen wanted me to make have this
presentation so well I was here a sad
day Sunday we sat in a big room for 13
hours hacking on NTS and I think who
were there what's on I'm sure all the
Richard dieter carry with her
did I forget somebody well all of them
were there in person and we had a bunch
of participants too so we have people
working on chrony on ntp check remotely
so a lot of things happened I guess next
slide please
so we did a lot of integration as I said
got emptiest to work inside of crony
insider NDP sake Martin lying near who's
not here today he has his own
implementation in c plus plus it was
interoperate with i have my own little
implementation a proofing concept in
python and that also worked and most at
work here was done on drop 17 richard
was also there worker and he was working
against version 11 i think and next
slide again thank you so this is the
compatibility matrix right now so
australia client that's martin longish
client in c++ the chrony client was an
LLC that's Miroslav who's working chrony
the NTP is a client how madre was
involved did a lot of work on that one
and a lot of other people who also ran
an entity sick and then my third client
is mine quick thing i did at work a few
weeks ago and we also had some people
from nap mode in malmö who were
participating on their own time and they
have a client in go which is sort of
partially completed and on top of that
what's allowed I'm sure are working on a
vast implementation and as you can see
all the sort of lost folio
chrony and pisac Python they all
interoperate with each other the goal
and client from the team in Malmo it can
they only have a client so far but and
it only does the key exchange but that
one works with Australia so recruit a
servant my server in Python it does not
currently work with the entropy six
server and that's this due to the NTP
sec server i think is using an old ssl
library that doesn't support a LPN so
that's a sort of known issue we need to
work around it but it's sort of
everything inside protocol works just
right there and then watson also indeed
a server in rust which in her master key
exchange we can talk to the sock all the
foundation can can talk to more since
implementation so all of us have had
bugs
I had a few crash bugs there were some
other issues we we were we had an issue
with open SSL open SSL one with one that
one has 1.1.1 a has a bug in the key
exporter function which means that we
have a rather long string for exporting
key material and that string doesn't
work with one with one with one so
Martin Langer when he did his
implantation he had to use a shorter
string so some of the issues we had was
that some people were using long string
and their clients while the saw was
using a short string and vice-versa
we've decided we'll just go with long
string around or everybody has switched
to long string
now because we there is both a new
version of business or so available and
an older version and we didn't really
find any issues with their NPS draft in
itself as far as I can tell not when it
comes to implementation we we followed
implementation if we read it by letter
it did work a few things were a bit
unclear
might need a bit of clarification but I
mean it all seems to work really well
I'm quite impressed that we have for
working implementations today maybe last
night you that's all the people that
were involved in the hackathon yesterday
both remotely and in person Thanks
all right so we've already sent NTS
through working group last call we've
now done three hackathons on it so I
think we are they're going to do that at
the we haven't done no that
clarification hasn't been pushed yet no
I hadn't looked yeah not yet so we're
gonna do a minor clarification on a
thing that a number of implementers
implemented wrong and then we will based
in in the sense that the spec was not
clear about what they needed to do that
once that clarification is done then
this will be ready to go to the iesg
all right all right so next up is I
think rough time right Angela oh I guess
I should have asked are there any
questions about the did you go ahead
sorry and Shawn slightly pedantic note
on the up on the clarity issue the spit
so the spec was perfectly clear on what
NTS ke requires and everybody did that
correctly the the clarification we're
going to be inserting is is about a is -
is that a lot of people didn't properly
read 78 22 and made an invalid
assumption about that so we're just
going to point out that that fall okay
great thank you it's a better
description of the clarification okay
now in chalk
you know I don't know that I don't think
it's synced well um can you hear me okay
hello everyone I'm Anton Malhotra from
Boston University and today I'm going to
talk about rough time a draft that be
submitted in collaboration with Adam
Langley who is the original author of
rough time from Google and Watson lad
from CloudFlare who implemented or
deployed this at CloudFlare you and
someone else yeah we submitted the first
version of this trapped back in January
of this year and following that we had a
virtual working group call avaran I
explained the protocol and we discussed
the issues that were not addressed in
the draft at the time some of them we
decided that need to be addressed and
the draft and some of some other issues
are not that pressing post that or we
updated the draft and we had some
comments on the mailing list some
clarification questions some of them
have been addressed on the mailing list
there are a few that needs a resolution
that needs some discussion so but the
questions clarification questions have
not been updated in the draft that
allowed will update in the next version
of the draft so for today's presentation
I'm going to give a very high-level
overview of what the protocol is and
then open the stage to comments and
discussions because that's what we want
to achieve at this IETF like have
people's input on the outstanding issues
okay so the motivation behind rough time
is basically we all it's undeniable the
fact that Security's important time is
important for
Internet security as many applications
and security protocols use time
unfortunately widely deployed protocols
such as network time protocol which is
standardized in RFC five 905 and a newer
proposal a variant of NTP Kronos they
are not authenticated and do not provide
do not provide any armed response
authentication then we have a symmetric
key proposal for NTP which uses md5
although that's been deprecated now it
does provide authentication but there
are serious issues with it which have
been known for years now so is the case
with NTP Auto key however the new
proposal network time security that we
just discussed that also provides
authentication but it does not provide a
proof of server misbehavior and what
that means I'll explain in the next
slide where as rough time achieves both
the goals it provides server
authentication as well as a proof of a
cryptographic proof of this behavior of
a server so what is rough time it's a
protocol that achieves rough time
synchronization it is not as accurate as
other time synchronization protocols as
it stands today second it detects the
servers that provides inaccurate time
and most importantly it provides a
cryptographic proof of servers in this
behavior that can be verified by a third
party there are several applications for
rough time the original motivation when
Google and when Adam Langley at Google
proposed this approach was a certificate
verification Google did a survey that
found that 25 percent of failures of
it's is because of bad clocks on the
clients so and we know that's a
certificate verification meaning does
not require accurate timestamps does it
does not require super accurate
timestamps it does require rough time a
drop it does require the client to be
roughly accurate and there are several
other applications where the client does
not necessarily require super accurate
and precise time information such as
delegated credentials lifetime delegated
credentials you can think of them
similar to certificates they have
validity periods which need to be
verified before they can be accepted
similarly IOT devices or other embedded
devices that cannot update system their
system time very frequently can use
rough time and towards recently someone
from Tor mentioned that they would
require they would be happy to implement
or use rough time for their service
directory so these are a few
applications I'm sure there are several
other applications for rough time but
these are a few motivation applications
for that now there are several issues
that were raised on the mailing list and
cheering during the virtual group
meeting so first issue is that of time
scale that what time scale should be
used for time stamps delivered by a
server in the response so what we have
currently in the draft are these three
values met P which are the number of
microseconds the server in his response
sends this value which is the number of
microseconds since the UNIX epoch then
we have another variable read ID which
is the server's estimate of the accuracy
of the time that it sends at the time
that they compose the response packet
and then there is this leap indicator
which is basically the arm offset which
the tie and UTC timescale at the time
that the server constructs this response
so there have been several suggestions
on the mailing list regarding what we
should do about this time scale but
there is no consensus yet and at the end
of this presentation I would like to
hear comments and thoughts about that
then there is another issue which is
less pressing but I guess we need to
address in the draft
it's about trust anchors and policies so
the bigger picture for rough time is to
to to construct to have to have an
environment where we can have several
trusted rough time servers and for that
we would need I think a trust anchor
that can basically maintain and
distribute at this list of trusted
servers and enforce certain policies
such as where the clients can submit or
discuss or complain about the
misbehaving misbehaving servers that
they detect through this rough time
protocol and there are several other
policies that the trust anchors can
enforce such as generally checking the
health of rough tine servers whether
they are checking their uptime or how
accurate they are compared to some
reference time so we need to decide on
we need to decide on who these trust
anchors can be and what kind of policies
they should be enforcing and with that
I need not to see anything
Thomas Rajib wahwee so I said this on
the mailing list said anyway I think
this is a security draft and one of the
most important things it should start
with is a threat analysis which
describes exactly what are the threats
we are trying to deal with and how we
are how we deal with each of them
some of them may not be relevant to this
draft some of them may be this draft
deals with others it doesn't deal with
it needs to be very clear can you go
back to slide 2 so go up one side so
this is not detailed enough in my
opinion when I read this in the draft I
couldn't understand what rough time does
and what it doesn't do in terms of
threats so that's in my opinion the
first thing the second thing is that
there is a fundamental problem of delay
attacks which is also something we
discussed on the mailing list and right
now the draft doesn't resolve this
problem understood from offline
discussions that in practice the
implementation of rough time does deal
with delay attacks in some form but this
needs to be described in the draft and
it needs to be explained exactly what is
the scope of the damage a delay attacker
can do so I think these are two very
major issues right now for this raft yes
yes some of the comments that you
mentioned were on the mailing list and
we that but definitely a threat model
Watson and I discussed need to be added
to the draft and we will do it in the
next revision of the draft
and regarding delay attacks yes yeah
that that's a part of the track model
and I think it's not only a threat model
it's also adding a new mechanism which
is not described in the draft because
right now the way it's described right
now the delay attacker can do anything
you want right we described examples on
the mailing list which show how a do
they attacker can basically completely
compromise rough time yes I did reply to
that I think we are not on the same page
with that particular attack that you
described but maybe we can discuss
discuss it more yeah okay so please
reply on the mailing list because I
haven't seen a reply from you to that
for the delay attack I did I did have I
did have an explanation on the mailing
in the response maybe you missed it but
I can point you to it again okay on the
issue of yeah on the issue of of policy
for maintaining list of servers end up
and what they should be expected to do
I think What's in scope for the draft is
mechanism for getting trusted lists
where end and were how exactly to to
construct a proof of malfeasance and
check that proof I do not want us to get
too far into layer 8 policy in this
draft let's not be the cat forum here
[Music]
secondly though I I do hope we can see a
see a call for adoption for this draft
soon I had I had some earlier objections
that the graft may not be within our
Charter but I got pretty clearly slapped
down by that slap down on that by the
area directors who basically said take
it up here and fix the Charter
so fair enough let's get a call for
adoption going yes regarding your first
comment I just mentioned it here because
it was about the trust anchors and
policies because it was briefly
discussed in the first virtual group
meeting yeah but as I said these are not
depressing issues that need to be
addressed in the draft but I just put it
for the sake of yeah Thomas Pearson VUE
Jabbar
I would like to contribute further to
the draft however the github repository
does not appear to be up to date please
use issues and keep the content there up
to date github issues all right it's a
clarification um yeah so as a daniel
mentioned the the first policy question
isn't really a question saying policy
it's really a question about mechanism
and more importantly I do think you want
one global place where the reports of
malfeasance are discussed because it is
going to be a sort of ecosystem impact
if there's one server at everybody
distress now maybe not everybody trusted
in the first place but I think that's
that's our thing regrets and policy
options said it but I'll emphasize it
unlike CAS there is no cost to
distrusting a server is that other
server is just as good you don't have
the problem that browsers have we're
kicking out a CA is extremely expensive
[Music]
right if you want I'd like to second the
first speaker in asking for a threat
analysis and the threat model because
it's like the first thing I did in this
industry back when I was a kid was to
set up entity infrastructure right and
the first on the first sentence or the
first page right there was I had
multiple sources of time right and the
objective of the exercise is not to have
I mean I don't I understand that there
is a this attraction to having provable
statements about models but the
interesting model it's actually the
clock on the machine because that's the
the thing that you use the system
operating systems view of time that's
what we use when you evaluate
certificate trust Frances
and it's you know there are many ways to
counteract single server single server
malfeasance in the other protocols are
having more sources of time right that's
what we traditionally done in in
deployments of MTP infrastructure so I I
think if we're gonna have like provable
security proofs that's having about
models that actually are relevant to
like the uses of secure time on the
operating system and that's not
necessarily about any given statements
about any given protocol we used to get
time onto the operators go ahead the
remote participants cannot see you I
know for me personally the thing I
wanted to talk about was Todd's comment
about delay attacks um having thought
about it back when the discussion was
had I'm not convinced that delay attacks
really affect the thing that rough time
does because rough time um does
explicitly refer to the ordering of
events and then the time stamps that are
connected to the events from from
different servers so even though delay
delay attacks are possible they would
look like like my reasons and I think at
least rough time should detect that
something is wrong and have
cryptographic proof that something is
wrong um although probably the client
could not differentiate between a server
that was being attacked and I said well
that was intentionally sending bad time
but still it would have a report that
something happened I think that is very
valuable I also don't think that there's
much more to be done from a client
perspective than seeing that the
incoming messages from us from serve are
somehow not right
differentiating whether that's because
the server is bad or because there's an
attacker seems impossible is at least a
very difficult task thank you
go ahead hi this is Marcus no sorry I'm
so I've mentioned before a couple of
times I really like this scratch and I
think it just promised it still needs
some work if you eat the microphone you
say don't like this
yes great thanks and so I'll just make a
couple of quick comments
the first is regarding the which x game
we should use the current is just one is
still t AI right yes so and I've had it
pointed out to me that the BA p.m.
explicitly recommends against using T AI
and recommends you to C instead and in
connection with that was also pointed
out to me that essentially any protocol
that distributes time needs to be able
to tell the user what the source of that
time is one reason is so you know which
actual timescale you are tracking which
probably isn't that important here since
we're only interested in rough time but
what is important is since first since
we're starting to track malfeasance here
and we're starting to distrust servers
that give us the wrong time we couldn't
enough end up in a situation where we
have several service that use the same
source of time where the client doesn't
know that say you have a bunch of
servers that are using GPS at the time
source and GPS starts distributing the
wrong time we can either end up with
accidentally starting to track this
erroneous GPS time or we can
accidentally start distrusting all the
servers that happen to use GPS so that's
one argument friction including some
sort of source information
oh I think I'll stop there and I'll just
not also that's trust anchoring and what
we really trusting is something we need
to but Duncan said before about lay rate
issues policy of are twice probably
shouldn't be in the draft
it's more of an implementation and
ecosystem issue okay yeah sorry for long
talk thanks thanks yeah the draft has a
section that says that the service
should use a common highly accurate
source of time such as GPS Richford well
actually for Jose and Tomas those they
had a question about what's the
precision and Thomas answered in jabber
that it's a microsecond so I Dana
frankly here I don't think
Christoph's earlier comment about delay
attacks is correct the the possibility
of a delay attack is already is already
baked into those um into into those
merkel proofs the impact of a delay
attack is rather that the be longer a
network adversary delays a packet the
more these the server might be able
might be able to be off on that before
the client would be able to construct
construct a proof that it's off so
there's there's there's no way for for
the client to distinguish in a proof um
between the case where the server is two
seconds slow versus the case where the
the server is accurate that a network
adversary delayed the packet for two
seconds
nonetheless the client can compute the
two-second found on on how much the time
it's getting might be off but just the
the longer the network adversary delays
something the harder it is for the
client to construct a proform Alfie's
yes and as I explained on the mailing
list this variable redeye that tells the
server's estimate also bounds the the
delay between my P - right eye and yeah
there is a whole explanation on the
mailing list that you can yeah
all right before you start are you on
the delay can I let Christoph respond
because my guess is he is can you
respond to Christoph from Hearst sorry
so a very simple example let's say we
have a server which is off by one second
so what we would expect is for rough
time to be able to identify that by
having the causality broken but what
that server can do is just delay the
message for 10 seconds before sending it
back to the client for 10 seconds which
would hide the fact that it's time is
off and would cause an error which is on
the order of 5 seconds and this would
would not be identified by rough time
because it's a positive delay rough time
only detects when there is a negative
difference between clocks so if you
delay the message in the server rough
time can't detect that unless you add a
specific mechanism to detect of the
attacks yes but with the next response
if that is okay I get what you're saying
all right yeah okay Christoph go ahead
um perhaps I don't we are talking about
request response scheme are we not um
and if we are then the client is going
to detect that the round trip took a
long time which in itself should raise a
certain kind of flag because net rise
was the uncertainty or I mean basically
Daniel you raised
um this issue the longer the message
round trip is the the less precise the
client's estimation about how accurate
the service time is um so that's a
problem in and of itself and so I don't
see the scenario where that the server
is off and then someone beat an attacker
or the server themselves delays their
packets to to hide that they're off by
intentionally making round trips like
unpleasantly long I don't really see a
case where that's under the radar
basically I'm saying this would raise an
alarm and that's an alarm so I think
Lantau Thomas rahi I think what you said
is exactly the solution which I'm
looking for in the draft by having the
client verify the round-trip time and
bounded to a specific value that would
mean that rough time is only accurate
the accuracy is on the order of the
maximum round-trip time so that's what
I'm looking for in the draft currently
doesn't have that it's not that I saw
okay into that um because it was obvious
to me yes if there's nothing in that
that looks at the round-trip time then
it should be what's near Coe a threat I
would very strongly appreciate you
submitting texts saying exactly that I
think I think it's important to remember
that what we're producing is not a
normal estimate of the errors of its way
we're cruising a guarantee that you are
within when the the time of the server
was within this bound where you have two
delays there's some formula part was
pretty much this square window and we're
interested in applications where you
have minutes of accuracy required
seconds of accuracy right but this needs
to be very high certainty that the
server is not lying because we are not
synchronizing gos clock um the reason
for this is that OS clocks are often
deliberately set wrong especially on
mobile and this is breaking security
protocols and training people to click
through certificate warnings
that sort of the broader context here
explaining why we're making choices okay
last comment if two to two comments oh I
think that should go in the draft but
the threat model actually doesn't again
its threat model right that actually
doesn't involve the operating system
clock that's an important thing the
other thing about Marcus think about GPS
you can actually spoofed GPS it's not
that hard right and so that's the reason
I think he's bringing that up right you
actually have to point out like time
scale comes from this so you know if you
know when stuff happens to this server
you might not want to go after the
server you might actually want to go
look at who's producing time for it okay
the queue is empty I think the only
thing I heard was do you all want to do
another Rev before a call for adoption
or do you want be nice if there was a
more conventional description of a
protocol exchange so that those of us
who come from the packet world rather
than that could I figure out what the
what was actually exchanges really just
sort of some text in one of the sections
okay so we'll do a call for adoption and
continue a discussion on the mailing
list okay next up is meta as a remote
presenter I think yes thank you all
right can you see your slides yep yeah
excellent can you hear me everything
okay yes you are loud and clear
okay thank you and so hi i'm nita and
today i'm going to present the update we
made in the third draft of collins
mechanism for MTP it's a joint work with
nine to live calm is rocky and massage
appear and next slide please
a short reminder and we consider the
following sweet model where the attacker
has full control of a large function of
the NTP servers in the pool and he can
change the content of NTP response and
can also delay them
of course the attacker is malicious and
we assume that he is trying to achieve
declines to the clock as much as
possible in the picture you can see that
the clients still received both good
time sample and bedtime samples and
might choose that shifted one and next
slide please thank you and we all and we
also wanted to remind a common solution
where on the one hand we use large pool
of NTP servers and on the other hand we
randomly choose all the tens and be
serviced and Thumba them lastly we use a
small filters in order to remove
outliers and next like this
Thanks and Ramos when compared to you
NTP uses greater variety of servers
changing over time and avoid the current
ntp filters and this allows to ask you
achieve probable security guarantees
however it may affect the precision and
a currency of corners well and we can
theoretically bound quarks error by a
Omega which means 25 millisecond
right right breathe Neda can you just
repeat your last sentence or two we lost
audio for about 30 seconds sorry about
that what I said that there well
theoretically we could bound Cronus a
procedural error by Omega 25 millisecond
we wanted to evaluate it in the wild and
have realistic bones so in the new draft
we discussed what everything okay yeah
okay and you know a new draft we
discussed preliminary result for
evaluating Hannes precision and the
texts were conducted in several
locations both in Europe and in the US
and we thought that the Economist chief
fair precision and less than a three
millisecond and moreover they offset
value in each update is similar to NTP
less than a two millisecond gap well
these results are not bad at all and we
want to see if they can be improved
without sacrificing security next like
this okay
can you move today next slide
he already has do you not sorry okay
yeah we tested a juice smoothie
mechanizing
the first one was the favorite small set
values within the remaining example
after filtering if they're not a file
format the average and it proved to be
very effective but in the second and
smoothing mechanism was to favor of
previous query server if they're an
average of set is not far from random
set approach they didn't yells a
significant improvement and next slide
please
thank you
in order to evaluate columns we measured
it both it's a average of that and it's
fluctuation and it's like 20 means the
average of offset derivative
we verified it in on several locations
and thanks in the graph for instance in
Oregon the X exists is the average
offset and the y axis is the fluctuation
the average of the derivative each of
the dots presents 30 minutes experiments
on of one of the algorithms we compare
Honus in orange to homes with the first
morning mechanism in green and to MTP in
blue in a location we can see that the
resource of Horus and with the volley
mechanism are closing to the NTP which
means that the green dots are a closer
to to the NTP presented in the blue dots
and next like this we can also see it in
a Frankfurt and next and in next slide
please and in Virginia yeah
next slide and in London and note that
the X exists varies between 0 and 2
millisecond and device is it varies
between 0 & 3 millisecond next slide
please
next we tested the security of a
algorithm under HX servers which shift
pockets timestamps and the error is
growing linearly with time and we used
two servers as part of the pool we are
DNS server to return our better server
IP instead of some of the
Severus IV we saw that rapidly
increasing shifts didn't affect both
corners and auntie P probably the shift
was too high and the bird servers were
ignored
next slide please
however for slowly increasing shifts the
NTP is shifting while and consume
anything next like so aim to conclude we
tested a a proof-of-concept course
implementation under normal scenarios
and Inara Chuck's a current say we saw
that corns precision is closer than to
NTP then they expected several minutes
instead of 25 milliseconds well the
smoothing algorithm heals even better
results and we also saw that Cronus is
secure even facing slowly increasing
shift while NTP isn't and the smoothing
didn't affect corner security and now we
are continuing to evaluate course
performance and security for different
attack strategies and different location
and thank you and I can take questions
now see all very Somalian I would like
to ask about the condition of of the
experiment
Oh increasing shift I presume this is
low what is increased or less a little
more soon about the experiment okay and
yeah sure um can you move to the to the
slide before the last one yep this one
so for example if for example when we
we're talking about rapidly shift we are
talking about a software which ad
a 0.01 second per second and here when
we are talking about slowly increasing
shift we're representing a an attack of
a adding 0.001 second pair every second
to a time that is of the order of
seconds more days what 10 milliseconds
hi sorry I want those zeros it's 10
millisecond 1 millisecond yeah ok and of
course it's only a preliminary result
and we're going to keep examining
warrant a this was also I didn't say
it's for Oregon and we would like to
expand our research so yeah basically
[Music]
how many servers did you use probably I
didn't get that so in order to get NTP
to jump between two servers as it looks
you probably how many of our time
sources basically did you choose for the
for this experiment so I chose a for the
NTP it's basically a running on the
default ntp am i choosing a a for
NTP servers and the homes and update
every 1664 second and four horse we we
chose 12 servers and from among them who
chose randomly for for each time but for
every update which was different
12 servers okay so you you you say that
you used four servers with the ntp
basically client yeah and four servers
they by the end here okay thank you okay
any other questions okay I think we need
to get a little bit more feedback on
this draft on that on the on the mailing
list
any thoughts on next steps or how to
work with it would also be appreciated
on the mailing list okay thank you very
much Neda thank you bye okay go back one
slide I think is it there
oh no I it's on the agenda slide but
that's okay you don't have to go back
because it'll only be a sentence so the
next thing on the agenda is actually the
ntp yang module and the authors are have
a conflicting meeting they have told me
that they have some additional changes
they want to make we have had an initial
mid doctor review it's gone through that
they want to do one more update and then
they believe it'll be ready for working
group last call so so that is pretty
close so this brings us to the end of
all of the stuff that we got in advance
of the meeting so if you go to the next
slide this is sort of my was originally
named on the agenda my housekeeping
section so it was drafts that we haven't
made a lot of progress on or didn't have
updates on so at this point
and I have to admit there is a ton of
traffic on this this morning we I had
asked an child to repost the data
minimization draft so that we could yeah
yeah it was well I guess the point being
it it was reposted and then there was a
ton of email but I haven't had time to
read so is there any is there a way
forward on that draft I mean we were
ready to wrap that up and send it on so
maybe we just think that objecting to a
draft on the basis that future work is
going to change the way it works is sort
of not not interesting okay um so the
the last the last point of this was it
had gone through working group last call
we were ready to send it on and we
needed it we were waiting for comments
and so okay go ahead Harlan was that
last comment directed toward me what
last comment the one that said objecting
to something based on something in the
future was not interesting yes
okay fair enough I would like to hear
how you make your decisions about
whether or not something needs to be a
standard and then implemented versus not
because you seem to switch back and
forth on whether or not you want it to
be proven or if you want to wait to
implement it until the standard has been
passed
my concern is simply that one one single
implementation shouldn't have a
privileged position to find the way a
speck works I mean I understand a
consideration that we need to use these
fields in other ways but I don't see any
conflict between having dynamization
draft and then in a later draft saying
well this is the other meanings are
needed for these fields if you wanna do
this with your dynamization don't see
why it isn't a suitable solution for
everyone okay well I will answer that by
saying you have your knowledge and
experience and I have mine so so that's
not dumb let's not let's not go there
that's not very helpful so one go ahead
and choose an option to update the draft
later if there is a need to be for some
future use of these fields okay all
right so I'm popping your out of the
queue Harlan all right so on this draft
hello Christophe regarding Colin's
comments um the thing that you didn't
really answer Harlan um and maybe we can
this can make a skip a whole lot of
discussion the only motion that I saw
put forward was to change a few
instances of should language into main
language um and I don't really think
that would even make that much of a
difference and also from the definition
of shouldn't made that is available I
think that should is just more
appropriate in these cases um but also I
don't think this is something that we
should get hung up on um in other case
and if that's the only thing then maybe
we can just skip this and
go ahead Arlen I have technical
objections to the proposal as written
and I think those are pretty clearly
stated it is a bad idea to tell people
they should which is effectively a must
send zeros for ref ID poll and leap
indicator when there is a clear
situation where a significant use case
will be prohibited by this and then to
come up and say well you know it's it's
okay to say no because people can always
you're either telling people to ignore
the standard and not follow what it says
or you're using a hammer to kill
something that shouldn't need to be done
and what we're doing here is the if this
was religion we'd be real we'd be
writing Canon we're writing standards
here and I think we need to hold
ourselves to a higher standard for what
we accomplish and what we're asking
people to do so if you don't agree with
me or you guys don't feel that my
technical objections are worth it that's
cool that's your choice so I think that
the the way the IETF deals with
technical objections is consensus calls
and I think what we need to do is take
the exchange of email that's happened
over the last like 12 hours and review
that and turn it into specific consensus
calls that we can ask on the mailing
list because I think that's the way the
IETF moves forward in this space
go ahead
so responding to Karen
I think if III think if we were I don't
think these objections are new and if we
were going back for mailing list
archives we would find there was already
pretty clear consensus but secondly
responding to Harlan your objections are
based on or not based on use cases that
exist today you've got they are based on
potential future use cases that would
require
that would require modifications to how
clients behave so and in particular if
clients want if if we want to advance
this thing from the future and have
clients implement that behavior the
right way to do that is to put the
information that we think servers will
need then went their end into an
extension field rather than put it in a
header because that way that way that
way those extension fields can be
encrypted using NPS and protect clients
privacy that way just to respond back to
you
I agree that we have had these
discussions I would also agree that and
and ditcher and I have have discussed
this we have not been as clear about
having a discussion and then declaring a
consensus and so I think for some of
these even though we've had the
conversations we need to go we just need
to do a tiny little exercise where we
can you know ask a clear question and
get a group of people to answer unless
we've done this before and I need to go
back and look so if any if any further
formality is necessary on the point I
would I wouldn't urge that it get done
quickly simply because data minimization
is a normative reference for NTS and
therefore one blocks the other yeah I
was aware of that so and it may be I
mean maybe you can help me go back to
the archives and figure out if we have a
consensus or not I just we haven't been
as clear you know about identifying
specifically consensus calls because in
general we we get to a point without
needing formal consensus calls on
individual issues we just do them on the
documents but but in some cases we might
may need to do that Kristof I think you
are in the speaking position if we
haven't already resolved this and
perhaps you know go ahead if you have
something that you know just skip it
don't want to discourage you but hey
thanks - so so one of the things I want
to like point out to Harlan is that
there's a reason there's a shirt right
like should actually means that there
could be like legitimate exceptions
where like you don't have to follow it
right so that's if adding some text like
you know saying like
for example or something like that some
exemplary text we'd say leaves out some
room for you to do the stuff if that
would work for you that could be like an
easy way to get rid of this deadlock
right because as I said it's not a must
right like so shoot is pretty strong but
like should actually means that there
could be legitimate reason so you don't
have to do it so think of that like as
like one way of like getting this
unstuck Karen okay so thanks all right
thank you Suresh Harlan Thank You Suresh
yes I know about the difference that
difference between should and must my
concern is this document doesn't even
mention any of these other cases and it
assumes that the blanket the blanket
should to zero these things out will it
I guess that's my complaint and I will
again point out that Daniel just stood
up there and said that there are times
he wants to see working code before
anything happens and there are other
times he says he wants to see a stand
before anybody does working code and I
really wish I could understand the
algorithm that fix that yeah well I
don't think I heard him say that so
really he said there was a sense it
wasn't in place and running today we
shouldn't bother with it know what what
he said was is it from an IETF process
perspective it's a block it's a
normative reference for NTS no the
normative reference for entia I don't
understand how that has a play in this
he was talking about how he didn't want
to my understanding as he didn't want to
lend any credence to my objection
objection because since there wasn't
code out there today in sufficient form
that would behave the way I recommend we
should completely ignore that case and
discount it these are so I'm so these
are these are our future use cases in
but in in both senses not God not
neither the code nor any draft standard
exists so what
okay this is suppose to capability and
what we want to do in the future
you guys you guys want to drive in snake
island okay Karen I'm sorry never mind
as I said right like so Harlan like what
I would recommend is write some
exemplary text right this is not like
actual thing I said like buddy might
need to go like bypass this shirt and
write it up and then we like do the
consensus process like Karen says right
so as I said like don't make it like
anything concrete say like exemplary
like why somebody would not follow the
and then let's discuss that and see
if that's something that's gonna be
useful right so and and and sometimes
like you know you're in the rough I've
been in the rough like multiple times so
but that's let's try it out right let's
try to write some exemplary text and
we'll go from there
thank you
so the next one I had in my housekeeping
list was interleave modes and I just
wanted I believe we talked about this
the interim I was Mary Slava I was
wondering if you would mind giving us a
quick status of where that is and what
we want to do with that or I don't know
an chil do you have a just leave it to
Miroslav if Marysol is online all right
well we do have a draft on interleave
modes we need to figure out what we're
doing with that oh here he comes
I'm holding you on the spot Miroslav
sorry okay I think yes sort of only one
remaining issue and that was whether the
service should be allowed to use the
same pair of x times multiple times as
it is currently specified I sent an
email about this and we discussed this
on the previous meeting and the issue is
that as
specified it's not tolerant to errors in
the processing of packets and clients if
we don't allow the service to you to
reuse the time stamps the protocol
should be able to fall back to the basic
mode and that's probably a good thing I
think we just need to update the
document and submit linear version okay
that would be great if you could do that
maybe appreciate thank you the next one
I wanted to ask about was the draft on
on implementing time did you want to say
anything about that one just what the
status or what the thoughts are on this
is what I call my housekeeping part of
the agenda so no this draft this draft
has not been updated since last
face-to-face probably in the next I yeah
we haven't if we don't have any updates
on right
do you anticipate continued work on it
that's what I'm yes okay that's all
that's all you really need to say I just
wanted to I just wanted to know if there
was continuing work on it or we're not
so the next set of drafts so Harlan you
submitted a bunch of drafts last night
so nobody has had any time to review
them so what I would like you to do is
to spend maybe two or three minutes on
each draft and tell us what you wanted
to accomplish and so hopefully people
can figure out which ones to review
first all right sure is there a list of
them somewhere we can look at I'll take
them in order for whatever it's worth
the updates I made don't contain any
significant changes it all goes to
language cleanups
other things people have requested I do
to make them okay so I I will I will
step you through them how's that but
okay the so the first one is the ref ID
updates okay and that is the ipv6 ref ID
and something else
the not you ref ID and the ipv6 RFID
okay yeah those are just not you is
Sharon's proposal so I don't really I
don't want I don't think we need to talk
about what they actually are what I want
to know is what what the what your
objective was in moving from the last
draft of this draft like what updates
have been made told me that they didn't
want the abstract to be so long they
wanted references to the github repo
they wanted a little bit more in the a
little bit more language in the security
stuff and I basically did a bunch of
cleanups Sam told me that it's bad form
to simply use pictures to show people
what a packet looks like and that it's
important to have descriptive text so I
added that stuff okay so on this
document for the working group this one
is it is a working group document
technically according to the to the data
tracker it's in working group last call
but basically what happened was it went
through working group last column we had
a lot of issues and we didn't actually
move it out of working group last call
so at the very least it needs another
another revision so I would encourage
people to read this one and comment on
the list the next one Harlan is
well the next one that we have here is
the that you updated last night was the
extension fields document what I'd like
to mention with that one is we had a
working group consensus call on that and
we declared it to be a dead document in
a sense that if what you have done is a
tweak on the previous document then
we've already decided that this is not
work we're going to progress so is the
update a change in strategy or is it
engine strategy and I'm waiting to hear
back from Sam about the ITF extension
field registry it's not quite ready -
it's not quite ready yet just a step
closer so I would I would like to remind
you that it has we have declared it dead
and so there has to be a good reason for
us to resurrect it I understand okay
then the next is the extended
information extension field did you want
to talk briefly about the changes in
this one from the and the next set of
documents these are all at this point
individual submissions we have not
adopted them as well if items yet the
last instruction that was given to the
working group was that we would proceed
with extension field specifications that
were compliant with 5c 78 22 and so it's
my number was 78 22 right so they can't
be they are or did you say are they they
are listed in a way that works and since
78 22 says things like the size of an
extension field is dependent upon
whether or not it's the last extension
field it's compatible with that I didn't
see any benefit to complicating the
individual proposal saying here's how
long this is if it's the if it's an
early packet and here's how long it is
if it's the last packet 78
twenty-two cares about that the proposal
will all say well you know make make
this extension feel the length that is
appropriate so the extended huh oh I
thought you were done and I was I was
giving Daniel the floor because he's at
the queue he's at the physical queue by
my quick route by my quick reading of
suggest ref ID last night and I didn't
go I may be missing something in the
text because ladies look at the diagrams
but it looks like the body for that is
only for our cats which can which
complies with RFC 78 22 in neither case
regardless of its position it can be as
long as anybody wants it and the and the
payload for a rough ideas for octet so
if it needs to be padded it's perfectly
fine to Pat it okay so so back to the so
I set the stage by saying that we are
open to extension fields if they are
compatible with RFC 78227 animal you
said that you didn't let me finish
so now what I'm going to do is go
through each of the new drafts that you
submitted not like you just speak
specifically to to what what has changed
and what action you would like the
working group to take on them so the
first one is the extended information
one yeah I'd like that going to last
call well it's not actually a working
group document yet there's a short
document and did you make any I
addressed all the feedback I got from
Sam and some of the stuff Danny
commented about and a couple of other
things and extended information may end
up getting another tweak from me soon
because I have another idea
but okay so all right so for this one we
want to do a call for adoption for the
working group the next one is also an
individual submission it's the I do
extension field you want to talk about
that one briefly it's just the I do
extension field has turned out to be
very important when dealing with a mix
of new and legacy clients and I
basically cleaned up the language and
hopefully Sam will look at it and decide
it's better than it was before but the
content of it is pretty much the same if
that isn't a working group document I'd
like it to become I'd like it to be
considered as one okay the next one is
the the last map last df1
those are pretty much the same if they
aren't working group documents they
should be all the problems we have with
a legacy Macker because it's not an
extension field and it's ambiguous so by
allowing people to put the Mac in an
extension field that completely goes
away similarly the last extension field
is an unambiguous way to say I'm the
last extension field and if you want to
make that 28 bytes long great without it
you know it is everything i can see says
it's not necessary and it's perfectly
fine as a four byte last extension field
but you can make it as however big you
want it's compatible is 78 22 okay and
then the last extension field that you
have a suggested ref ID that yeah that's
good for a bunch of things it's similar
to not you and the rest of it it's
there's no way for server a to tell
server B if you use me as your system
peer please use this ref ID and that's
what this proposal does since there's no
other way to communicate those this
allows people to increase their security
by using a nonce and effectively random
nonce
could be encrypted could be a bunch of
things but it's basically a way to
remove some of the some of the
exploitable aspects of a race ID and
it's also useful for example in the
leaps mirror ideas that are about to
happen okay so that's for proposals on
the floor for new extension fields
none of these are currently working
group documents so we will do a call for
adoption on these and see if the working
group is willing to take them up the
last document that was submitted is the
leaps may RFID I know this was
originally part of the other ref ID
updates and we pulled it out because the
leap smear piece was more controversial
do you want to talk about that sure
there needs to be a clearly visible
method in the core packet to identify
that a system pier is a leap smear its
following leaps animator time instead of
correct time and that's what this does
it makes it easy and obvious to see that
a system is synchronized to a leap
smearing server if you never use leap
smearing stuff then you'll never see it
if you are in a situation where you
might see leap smearing servers it can
be incredibly helpful both to the system
and systems in question as well as the
operators who want to keep an eye on
things to know whether or not somebody's
doing Lechmere okay so this is also so
do you have any additional changes you
want or is this also something you would
like to see adopted I would like to see
it adopted all right so with that I'm
popping you out of the queue
so basically my my motivation for doing
this was to go through all of the things
that we have that are outstanding and
see if we can get some of these things
wrapped up the is there there so when
these were calls for adoption come out I
need to be sure that people read the
document please and and comment on
whether this is something the working
group wishes to undertake the one thing
I'm not Christophe
yes Christophe in the leap see RFID
document would you consider um giving
the option of communicating other
information I'm scaling as information
for example people wanting to UM send
out tii instead of UTC basically says
I'm using a different time scale than
proper UTC um why limit it to just the
one the purpose of the leap smear rough
idea is to show that this data that
somebody's following a leap smearing
server that is different from true time
if you want to run your systems in a
different time scale that's not
something that I think we can use the
ref ID for because the primary purpose
of the ref ID is loop detection and if
you're going to be running a system and
ta I you and you use a special breath ID
you say that my system is Tia ta I
instead of something else you then lose
loop detection well you lose it
permanently as opposed to during a
24-hour period when you're making an
adjustment once every two years so there
are other there are other ways to handle
what time scale you're using and I've
got that those are on on our discussion
lists for NTP version 5
[Music]
Harlan III I think you're making a good
argument for why we should what for why
we shouldn't be putting this in the ref
ID at all and put it somewhere else
let ref ID be for loop protection and
stop and let's stop overloading it
semantics any more than it already is
go ahead Watson okay Christopher
okay go ahead Krista um no I was going
to say the same thing I'm supporting
down this point this opponents answer
sounded exactly like a good point for
why it was a bad idea to communicate in
that way go ahead Watson I think that
with and yes a lot of this lets stroke
try and negotiate extensions and DDP
packets we can do by extending the NTS
key exchange protocol it's very
extensible and then we don't have to
worry about package size limitations
which we're creeping up on okay yeah I
agree with Watson a lot a lot a lot of a
lot of these negotiation bit suck it can
be done quite easily with that with new
NT SKT retro types okay
any more discussion on the lists go
ahead if you don't want to use leaps
mirrors and you don't want to do the
other thing don't I'm more interested in
making sure you people don't prevent
folks who want to use this stuff from
doing it okay
any other comments or questions
[Music]
excellent the one thing I meant to
mention earlier that I forgot is I
wanted to acknowledge onchao with the
new RFC on the Mac so congratulations
thank you for doing that work any other
business working group items nope we
will in all likelihood try to schedule a
couple interims between now and whenever
the next meeting is I guess July so stay
tuned for the scheduling of those
anything else all right with that I give
you thirty minutes of your day back oh
those of you who are who are gonna join
us for dinner we'll be sending out an
email at some point about where we're
going
[Music]