[Music]
so that side of the building is for the
is G you should stretch out on CT sleep
[Music]
good morning
this is the PCU session
okay let's start but the usual not well
remember that the IGF has IPA rules
please buy them forget that anything say
right here is recorded and involves C's
as you seen as a contribution from the
80s perspective yeah
it should be going through so you know
process we are through a lot here so we
try to have a look at job or participant
questions what you have to remote
presentation so work as expected if you
come to the mic or to the presenter mic
please make sure to use it correctly and
we have pink cross over here down make
sure but you know even the cross when
you present for the video to be recorded
properly so as you noticed you John
stepped down from his chair position so
this is the opportunity for me to thank
him again I wasn't there last time but I
already told him directly
we hope to see him again VHF maybe not
as rigorous is a before oh we have now
two rookies who just on me first one on
my right his drive I think that if you
put on a newcomer tie on your badge you
certainly know already so is Adrian but
it needs quite fun to maybe someone
who's been the motorist excited to serve
as a soldier in to help to to solve to
two topics one of them is the
transitioning for drove who is involved
or used to be involved on many documents
in the group so to is this transitioning
in a step by step basis Adrian will be
able to to act on ensure that the load
is properly balanced because before he
leaves for for drove
and second goal help
flushing some of the cues we have for
the PC document so we hope that this
will progress quite efficiently and the
in term is to see everyone stepping down
from his position before the next ATF
meeting Montreal as you may be aware
there is an Asian responded by ETF quite
recently it involves the world so
working group from the routing area and
ETF it was a response to Qt
communication which came a while ago we
roughly just include some of the recent
PC document there to make sure the AG
which is aware of the walkway with
progress a shorty minor on using the
main list will have again this time
multiple draft that came out without any
discussion on the list just sometimes
and not each time announcements and the
mailing list
please remember that I first want to
progress the work is the mailing list
don't wait for a meeting to discuss
draft issues and try to send message as
much as possible on the list among the
new things we've got the wiki so I can
want by Mexico shell for that too one of
them suggested the other one make it
real so there is a wiki page that has
been which was there is been greatly
improved to include all the tombs and
all the commands we manage the good
thing is that anyone can update it so if
you have a document that which
significant milestone pass something and
that would share are late in updating
the wiki you might do it yourself so try
to make the best use of it on I think we
have
good tool to start with on this wiki you
may be aware also that in the routing
area there is an implementation policy
discussion we have to decide how we will
manage that for the PC working group
will certainly start a discussion on
implementation policy over the mailing
list or in the coming weeks we have to
talk all together on decide what would
be the reasonable way to end an
implementation policy for the PC working
group yet gender anyone wants to bash
something look standing over the road
nothing to do okay um let's start the
status of all our documents so these are
the documents that are beyond the
working group we have no new RFC's since
Bangkok but nothing to despair you can
see there is a lot coming your way we
have two documents which are in RFC
editor queue both are pending a mr. f1
from a document from spring and another
document from PC itself which is the
gmpls and that's the next document in
the drafts with is G which is on the
telly chat next week which is the gmpls
piece of extension so who is happy to
see finally this going through apart
from that we shipped various documents
to is G in the past one past months
there's they say there is stateful P to
MP her I key extension applicability of
PC and a CTN a very important document
Association group which is being used
and they are a bunch of other documents
which are built up on the generic
Association group and yesterday with the
help of John we also shipped the inter
area ace applicability document so bunch
of documents have been sent to the as
she so also request authors to when the
document goes to the is JB please
responsive when the comments are posted
and let's try and resolve those comments
from the direct rate as well as from the
from our 80s quickly
these are the early code pointer
locations which have been done in the
past luckily all these documents have
been sent to the SG so there is nothing
to worry and most of the things will be
taken care of matically this errata that
you see is is been pending from the last
last idea of meeting but finally we
closed it it was raised technical but
after discussion we decided that's
actually an editorial and we fixed the
our BNF issues and this errata is now
closed and verified now moving to
working group documents which are near
last call we have one document which is
waiting Shepard report this is the auto
bandwidth document we had a change in
the personnel for Shepherd that's the
reason for this to be pending but we
plan to act on it pretty soon there is
an ongoing
last call for stateful HPC which will
end next week so this is also an
opportunity that if you care about this
please respond we have not seen much
response for this on the list yet so
please do that and and this will also
help us chairs to make sure that yes
there is enough consensus in moving this
work forward what you see is the at the
bottom is the working group glass called
Q so this is the Q in which we will
start progressing the next set of
documents two of them are related to
Association protection and diversity and
one is a simple stateful extension which
allows PC to take control over LSP so
these has been discussed in the past
extensively and they are almost ready so
this is the Q for your information and
you can find all that information in
wiki as well so please keep checking to
know how your work is progressing
okay so these are our rest of
hard-working group documents this time
we asked everyone to update the status
in the wiki most mostly I made the
update and I think everybody was happy
with that update because nobody came and
shouted at me so this is what I have put
on the slides as well if you have
disagree you still have an opportunity
to come up to the mic and correct the
status so we have an association policy
document there is no update and there is
no pending actions from the author's as
well there was an update made for Pisa
flowspec based on the dis between the
last meeting and now the main thing that
we would require here is we need to
gather more implementation experience
for this document so if you are if you
have or if you are planning to implement
this please reach out to chairs provide
some information on the implementation
part this is a very important piece of
work so we would like a little
implementation feedback as well next
document which is the piece F yang we
send this document for only yang dr.
review my ish provided those reviews
during the week I posted the updated
version I'm still the editor for this
document and still back and forth you
would have seen their messages going on
to resolve this quickly but this
document imputs lot of other documents
which are still not RFC so anyway we
would have to wait for those document to
progress before we can take piece F yang
to RFC publication final we have
bidirectional this document was also
updated based on the comments that were
received on the mailing list basically
mainly from marina and this document is
also progressing quite well next we have
set of documents which are on the agenda
today the one that I wanted to highlight
was the stateful gmpls we made a request
to the authors of stateful gmpls and
remote initiated gmpls if these two
documents can be merged and luckily we
reached a conclusion and that will be
presented as well in the
so I will skip that for now and other
documents the three that you see on the
top they are all on the agenda so let's
get them and then we have documents
which are not on the agenda which is PCL
SP scheduling again this document is
progressing well but needs a little bit
more implementation feedback so please
provide that we have two recent
documents that we adopted since the last
meeting one is the PC flex grid and all
the comments that we received during the
adoption call those have also been
handled so that's very good to see that
the document already has a zero one
version which handles those comment and
we have SRV six document that we are
adopted we are still awaiting a zero one
version that handles the comments that
were raised during the adoption call
this is the pull queue adoption pole Q
that the chairs believe that based on
the last couple of meetings that there
is can there is enough information for
to us that we can start the adoption
poll
so we have the VN association pc c c sr
and the binding said which is in your
adoption poll Q so please look out for
these documents if you this is also good
don't wait for adoption poll if you have
comments on these document reach out now
let's fix them and resolve them quickly
and that will be the status so if
somebody has a disagreement on any of
the working group status or want to add
some information this is your time going
once going twice
and thank you while we try to run the
slides as inyoung your first presenter
good morning everyone
I'm young I think as true explain this
one is actually a merger of two draft
PCE pizza stay for PC gmpls
extend RFC 82 31 Adrienne donor is no
laser in and this this draft is
basically extension to cover stay for PC
for gmpls
and there was another RFC 8281 which is
called PCE initiated LSP set up in a
stateful PCE this one is basically you
know PCC delegation controller
locally configured LSP to PCE and this
draft is extension for gmpls and I think
this draft is quite mature and likewise
this one but I think working group
chairs felt this might just merge
together for the benefit of reducing the
process overhead and so on
so we basically merged that the second
draft into the first one because first
one covers with a bigger scope and we
published the published version and
ready for working of Lascaux
I think through mr. Dutchman Sheppard's
right and I believe I deflected your
comments on the first one before more 0
and after mojo you have some comments to
make it smooth as if you know you
suggest earnest to similarly now so that
it's one document rather than merger of
two documents
me just clarify this is true but much is
done we now just need to make sure that
the document feel as it's a one document
and not a disjoint two documents which I
just put in one place so just a
editorial pass and movement you do that
since this document was already in the
working group last you it will go back
into that queue and we can even let you
know get it a little bit more higher
preference than the other documents that
were added later one thing that I would
also suggest is that the state a normal
gmpls piece of extension is also in the
is G so please look out for any comments
that you that we received there and
align this work with it so just also
keep looking for this thing in the next
week so once you finish that I think
it's back on the cable okay
as I don't see any question from the
room we move to next presentation by how
many okay this is how me speaking and
I'm going to present of this work is
extension to the PCE communication
protocol for he has Tara and
notification so this is a road work so
let me go through something background
because this work has not been presented
in recent nursing five or six years so
we need to emphasize again that we need
this work because this is motivated by
that we issue the address Eric how the
handling issues between the PCs
originally in the fifty forty I feel you
there is ever code that sniffing
handling process SS in between the PC
and PC C's but this one is a kind of
more intricacy needed and we also try to
review all the error code has been
become defined in so far in the working
group and we also define how to process
between the PCs so we assume that every
draft to who has been working on the
multiple pcs in areas including McCann
be multi layer or multi domain or
hierarchical whatever so we need to
specify okay whether we should handle
the errors in this way and this work was
studied in 2010 and the doctor in 2012
so some of the authors I ever don't know
but it is now reactive we still alive
again and so currently I feel that there
are quite not many attention so and but
we believe this one is still necessary
so I'm presenting here to draw your
attentions to take a look at this one so
what's what's in the
trust actually we have specified two
different section one is forever
handling and the other for the
notification so error handling will we
have two separate objects and we decide
whether we propagate this kind of error
yes or no and what is a critically
critically T level of this kind of error
can be low middle high so we will
comprise the existing every County to
all the combination of the propagate
categories and there's a credibility
level classes for notification part it
would be a little bit simpler and it
only need to notify whether it is a
local or it's a kind of best request the
specific so here we provide very
detailed handling rule how to allocate
the propagation value and the critic
ability level for each given PC era a
clarification question what do you mean
by on demand here all the bound a is a
kind of we have not specified anything
it's a first time for example if the
class 11 the quick particularly is
recommended to be low
that's the propagation you can decide
whether you want or you don't want
basically you want unspecified
as the right word like we are not giving
a specification you can put 0 or 1 based
on your requirement right so actually
this is not exclusive and seem because
some of them have multiple values
depending on the urgency or some kind of
that and
yeah another motivation with we we had
to present here is because we have some
quick check on the existing path and
this will definitely impact as a kind of
work
and we are assume all of the works will
be good and some of the inter PC we
assume that we need this kind of error
handling but we currently don't have it
so far so this is some potential
comments there can be but I just find a
issue here I wasn't aware the first one
is an informational one so the objective
is to have every multiple PC related
craft in standard track to have this
kind of descriptors in session
indicating whether the new arrow types
would be needed and how the propagation
type and critically Atilla tea level
would be encoded I mean are you
expecting that the authors of drafts
will do this in which case you may be
ambitious or will you talk to the
authors of the drafts and help them by
suggesting text yeah we can do that
offline and I can but I believe this
part should be in the separate in their
cosmonium draft are not present in the
draft so we're looking forward to see
some discussions or whether this is kind
of agreement we can reach in the working
group to do the error handling sessions
in corresponding drafts it's certainly
an important work but yeah we have too
many important works so it may not be an
urgent one I agree
but I'm just wondering one - I want to
understand from the working group
whether this kind of inter PC
publication may have this kind of
dependency all this work if yes it may
become more urgent than before and we're
also disclosing discussing how to close
this work because everything current so
far is stable and we hear requests for
the working group to have a some
attention have some review and we are
preparing for the last call of this work
that's all for presentation comments
please any questions while we are
waiting for someone to stand I second
what Adrian is saying I suggested that
earlier as well that let's just provide
text on the mailing list to these
authors that I would like you to add
this section and this is the text and if
they disagree then we really are seeing
that your your work users the people
that you are writing this document for
if they are not convinced that this is
needed then yeah I think our work is not
going to be that successful but we know
that there are a lot of documents HPC is
there we have one document today on the
agenda as well so maybe we can use this
time also to talk to them and see if the
error codes that are being defined there
are the mechanism what is the
criticality level and this can also be
specified now at least and all the new
documents that are coming through and we
have our ad yes Deborah I would like to
suggest since you have now wikipage
possible you could put some other
guidelines there and this would be very
useful security considerations would be
useful that would really be helpful so
let me try to confirm whether the last
item here can be consensus D in the
working group saying that we only focus
on those kind of not spoke PC related
crafting standard FAC so I don't think
we need to specify too much on the
informational or a single PC you want I
think you're all right
about not needing to do too much but I
don't think that's nothing so I the
comparison I would make is with security
considerations an informational document
is not going to need to do protocol
specification for security but it
probably points out security issues and
I think the same thing here so the an
informational Monte PC thing might just
have one line that says this is multi PC
so it
also consider thank you thank you
[Music]
we're moving to the United I
presentation by each oh yeah all right
her just to give some description for
appetite habitation for the PC PC
extension for the networking so here are
just the what's the proper role for the
PC peace a prejudgment were your PC to
assist an assist our traffic engineering
our network network network so here we
proper to UM TCP facility for two
reasons first is the PID MPP pure
dynamically and rapidly sir the secondly
the proper popular different prefix
epithelium certainly is many clearly to
the past each evening kapa on demand
based on the network consider is this is
main aim for the for the released
protocol release drugs
and the employers document the way just
the propeller suite please have object
which is charity the PC in this LSP
request the following is real detail of
project but after we discussed with our
observed her least physically attention
for PC controller proposed the PCC
architecture for the for the instruction
controller instruction download so we
think peace and unity IP network held
also some flavor of the pieces is a
character so we after discuss with each
page of with other also of the job that
we
had to take the similar procedure to
proton is a kinky object so here we just
the proper define my new and since I
objected type and I put the information
into unity newly defined the CCI object
as it was
Subterra way so the main content of the
way not trained here is the key field
the first day the apparel will be
downloaded appear IDs and IP address the
second is previa courses in PPA what we
were terrible idea NOS circita prefix
the shoulder is for a PR for your magna
purely deposit will next hopper towards
a PT PP R so here we just look for some
comment Australian for the newly
proposed and clearly especially from the
implementation will point we also
considering the the future called reason
between the commander from with
tradition on it nakum young or Sarah and
the dynamic piece aybe protocol so this
is all for the application any comment
question thanks agent has this been
circulated to the idea of working group
not for them to work on but so that they
know we're doing it
I just ascended the the leader person to
for DeMeo these document oh sure and
also discusses the medium of line of our
solution so maybe just having a back of
your head
periodically just to send an
to their mailing lists just to say don't
forget we're doing this work because we
clearly it's related to how BGP works
yeah and we we need them to be aware out
here I was just going through and I
realized that in the teas working group
all the related documents are
experimental but in the PC we are aiming
for this in standard track so is that is
that the plan or is it just a mistake in
picking the track but I think then we
need to talk to T's yes as well that
there the work is going experimental
ideally I think we have oven there as
well so you have any concerns no the two
documents that we have both our own
experimental track yeah there's there's
no plan to move it out of experimental
media so unless there is some feedback
received here we don't see it getting
out of experimental anytime soon
so I put you on the spot as to why
that's experimental there were a few
reasons before adoption there wasn't
much support for the document but there
was some interest from a few people to
see fair this focus so given the lack of
interest and yeah we decided that was
the best way to make take it forward how
can he change the later yeah yeah and
everything can change right right until
versus possibly even after so I I don't
see why this needs to be a scientist
track until the problem yeah I would
also prefer if this is remains
experimental but I think it's up to the
working group as well so I think we can
take that discussion to the list as well
that what should be the ideal track for
this work another suggestion would be
and first
I would like to thank you for my
personal comment that I gave that if
instead of introducing new objects if he
couldn't put it within the PCC
architecture which you kinda greedy so
which actually makes the document also
much easier to follow the second comment
that I would have is without my chair
hat on first time I said it that that we
need some more description in the sense
you have three different parameters one
is to create dynamic bgp session another
to put prefix which are in my point of
view aiming towards the towards the end
points but then you also have one more
TL v which might be needed on all the
nodes in between so that clarity is not
there in the document right now we have
justified the tlvs but we need to go a
step further and explain the procedures
and the interaction between piece F and
BGP if there is any and error codes all
those things so there's still a lot of
work that needs to be done in clarifying
itself that what how this will is
actually used beyond what is the
messages and what is the object thank
you toppers beginners ad yet
experimental just clarify what Adrienne
said it's it's simply um that you can go
through and publish it as experimental
and then come back three months later
five years later and take it standards
track once you once this has some
maturity you know it just so so don't
worry that it it's experimental but what
needs to be shown is interest maturity
implementations that can be stable so I
got a little more on this that the t's
documents are more in the position that
being framework and use cases so there I
think the choice was experimental or
informational here it's protocol said
the choice is more experimental or
standards track I think this whole
question is going to come back to what
the Russian group thinks about
implementation status if
we move forward but ultimately we don't
have to make this decision until we make
a publication request so when we go to
the ad in section we have an RFC then we
need to make a proper decision now it's
just just it's just a flag thank you and
now cross your fingers
we're moving to a remote presentation
the one on PC is central controller yeah
yeah I could see you could hear me drew
yes yeah well good good yeah well
morning everyone this is Mahinda Meggie
from India I just have buzz
update on PC CC extensions these two IDs
quickly go through that can we move the
next slide I think I'm once I do yeah so
just about background PC has a central
controller the main RFC the architecture
RFC is already published and we have
basic PCC draft recently I'm not adopted
by PC WG and the PCC see Assad the
specific to segment routing extensions
for PCP it is in adoption q2 next slide
roofies
yes a major update on these two IDs are
supporting binding sida location by PC
and we are reusing the path binding PLA
which is already there in use and PCC is
a PCC a PCE request PCC to allocate
binding level using this t path binding
TLV so we are still using the same TLB
bye-bye in which PCC request PC to
allocate level by PC request message or
PC itself can allocate the level and
binding level and push to PCC so this we
are reusing and the another one is PCC a
location they label a location by PCC on
PC PCC sees request so this one will see
a bit in detail the first part we are
just reusing the another part we will
see in detail next one please
are you seeing the dislike yeah yeah in
this case in this case PC requests PCC
to allocate label instead of having
explicit you know control over pcc's
level level range or level block so this
we feel could be so disable the video
and continue
I think he's dropped off ok so save you
time let me take over and of this
without taking too much time so this is
Ruth without the chair hat without the
auto' hat just a contributor to this
document and and so as Mahindra was
saying that we have a see flag this flag
basically says I'm not gonna allocate
the label but I would like the PCC to do
their location on behalf of me and to do
that I set the flag don't put the label
value send the message to the node and
node allocates the label and send it
back to me so how does this work
the PCC C goes to the egress goes to the
egress says can you allocate a label for
me but this is my instruction the egress
allocates a label and reported back to
the PCC see now at the transit you have
two instructions one where you are
specifying a particular label which is
the green which is the out label and on
the in label side you request the node
to make their location and the node
makes a new location which is the label
yellow and kind of report it back to the
PCC see and same thing happens at the at
the ingress as well so in this way you
basically have the label allocation
going from egress transit ingress in a
sequential manner this is different from
the case that we were we had earlier in
the draft where all the label management
was done by PC CC itself so the things
can be done in a more parallel fashion
in this case labels are coming from the
node so you have to do it in the
sequential fashion from the back to the
front the main reason why we added that
in some cases it was difficult for us to
know the delegation of the label space
at the PCE for some reason because the
node may not be in directly or control
it could be a border router or it could
be various different things so we wanted
to allow ECCC
to also just tell I would like you to
execute this instruction but I'm not
specifying what be able to use you pick
a label from your space and reported
back to me that's the small change that
the author's have done in this latest
update so the question I think the yeah
manga do you wanna place yeah yeah yeah
yeah almost you finished it right yes
[Laughter]
yeah okay thanks for that so so authors
you know expect comments on the the
recent updates and feedback from other
implementers and we have we request the
adoption call for PC CC s our draft suit
so any any question on this particular
update case yes hi my name is Eric from
juniper in the case why are you mixing
the allocation mode from PC PC ECC and
distributed on the device there could be
cases where you have collision are you
thinking of carving the label space like
you know something managed by the
controller or something managed by the
device is that the recommendation and
okay thanks
my no you can answer but I kind of shake
my head which we communicate by head
movements yes yes yes yes you're right
you know comment or question
if not we'll move to the next
presentation thank you oh the next one
is a tune again well thank you thank you
very much here thank you bye bye bye
[Music]
here I just probe negativism for the
tckontis I give space and the culture
[Music]
motivation for this raft is you know the
PC the pvp extension for PC controller
specifies the procedure and protocol
system for the PC Ellison controller so
your label can be disappeared the town
stands for device select any PC P and
there are no draft deleted for the SR
deployment also specifies the procedure
for a piece of Education for to Daniel
is our label however the document
assembly to the label around you to be
used by PC you know and the second piece
of approach it appears by the Samsung
have some mechanism to spotted their
hunger other situation from holdup
identical location and the parity second
epistle only the PC controller now your
ID space reversely
so in order to a local IT directly from
a PC
and the underlying he says it should be
so the under under under Isis control
ice-t space and twenty pieces this is
the main motivation for the draft this
is a hurry the message flow for the
fully staffed so forth allocated in the
controller control IT space the delete
your ID ID especially on away must be
included you know open up message and
for each each each carrot hope it should
be included once you note message
currently we can consider mainly that
token the theory for the first day's
labor contrast based and here in the
second area is only six function ID
control space TR away this is the format
of the control lever controls bestie
only and he's a chance to describe a
block as the start while you're under
around you so after knowing this
controller space your PC can assign the
label such as the bride incident I said
formerly the space
the second is SLE six songs ID control
ID space is he handsome your structure
is for materially her he defines the
valid is no say mattifying the hello
Frank
to indicate the look with her either
exists or not so if this is a fact
easily flag he said then look at her
tyranny associative incision look at her
fulfilled our societal
regarding creating that is the order if
it not said then it will not increase
again survey her listen the carpet we
just element a flake let's define the
universe which after the
the main aim of a flag adjuster until
indicated pc-12 dedicate all space to
look easy but after his cousin is such a
scenario not really common so it is a
very increment the PC needed to define
the labor want you to hold it pcs or it
is not necessary for this flag and the
secondly the we under your culture
problem under Cisco and with other small
needs so the experiment may only see
missing the meeting in function you
can't PC and GCC and is all related
after so convexity inquire useful for
the derivative work so is asking for a
comment and the question walking
adoption any comment from the room I
went question related to the previous
one in your other document currently PID
is flagged as experimental can we
confirm this is on purpose the Eid
document is a experimental on the header
instead of standards track this document
is currently under experimental so
Julian is asking what is the reason is
that is that a thought behind making
this document an experimental actually
from always occurs first of all we
choose the type of experimental because
we think he's maybe no so easy for cold
for dead track but if you want we can go
for stair jack that would be better
thank you for you must answer in a
recomment okay so let's move on thank
you the following one is Mike we don't
clean yeah yes we can hear me okay great
yes I'll be presenting this draft piece
of extensions to support segment routing
a policy candidate passed next slide
please
next slide so there's been three
versions of this draft
oh sorry previous slide there's a little
bit of lag between the slide change so
right now you are on history of the
draft right yep so there's been three
publications in this draft first we
introduced the overall structure of you
know tying the piece of LSPs into an
association group to represent the SR
policy in the second publication we
defined the three TVs
that signal the different policy
attributes and the in the third or yeah
in the third publication we just did
some clarifications next slide please
so the purpose of this draft is there
was recently introduced this concept of
segment routing policy which adds extra
structure to segment routing it
basically unifies kind of different
candidate paths into a single SR policy
and it adds the concept of color and
other things and so piece up was lacking
a way to signal this information so our
current draft is meant to address this
gap and piece up by allowing both the
PCE and the BCC to signal these extra
pieces of information that were
introduced in the second routing policy
draft next slide please so basically
this is just like an overview of of the
draft so we define a piece up LSP to
correspond to a segment out in candidate
path and the group of psi powers piece
is tied into an association group and
that represents the SR policy and the SR
segment list corresponds to the P sub
arrow and we define the TVs to signal
these various values next slide please
so this is the TV that gives the ID of
the policy within the context of the
headend so basically all the piece of
LSPs that are within the same as our
policy must have the same value of this
govt and correspondingly OPA power
speeds that are not within the same as
our policy must have different values of
this govt so this yeah thanks and this
is the candidate path govt gendered path
identifier too so basically it must be
different among different candidate
paths in the same as our policy excuse
me so this this encodes stuff like the
protocol origin and the originator in
the case that the PCC may want to report
non PISA candidate paths to the PC for
example if you have a configured
candidate path the PCC can report that
configured candidate path to the PCE and
specify the protocol origin as
configuration and similarly if you have
a BGP te instantiated candidate path on
the PCC then the PCC can report that to
the PCE and set the protocol origin to
be BGP okay next slide please
[Music]
and this is just the attributes of the
candidate path that do not serve as the
key and they I believe they can
theoretically be even more
during the lifetime of the of the PC
powers b-but the previous other TVs must
not be modified during the lifetime of
the LSP next slide please
so next step is we plan to initiate
workgroup adoption and that's it that's
it for the presentation time for
questions question coming just interrupt
so number of comments you've been using
to the policy terminals P term
interchangeably I think you should put a
big letter that one means another I mean
no I mean policy s our policy is a group
of piece of LSPs that's how so as our
policy equals P sub Association that's
what like this if you go to the overview
slide the number of places where you
specifically sr l SP term so s our LSB
yes is that like in the actual text of
the draft let me get my gloves okay yeah
well I think if that is the case we will
correct that it shouldn't it should be P
sub L SP not srl SP any thinking about
using binding seats in case where you
cannot instantiate LS space / policy /
and to end binding Sid should work as
before like there is no we do not kind
of add any new process for the binding
SID so binding said this still belongs
to the P sub LSP which for us is a
candidate path so so basically it's the
same the turning point might not be the
same as end point where bagging
would be expanded to reach again if you
cannot push enough labels instantiate
full policy sorry could you clarify the
question I didn't think I understood the
question so you'll be human SDS one of
the constraints to compute the path
right
if you cannot push enough flavor then
you shouldn't be doing it and you'll
know your MSD a time of computation
right so you might decide to use binding
Sid instead in order to segment the
tunnel okay
I think what's happening is that all
you're saying is valid but it might be
there in the normal SR document itself
because this document is not talking
about how to compute the candidate path
and what computation to can consider it
is talking about when you have multiple
candidate paths how to group them into
an SR policy using an association object
understand however yes lower when you
implement it it should interwork yeah
it's sure I think you're putting a right
hook that yes it should into work in
fact I wanted to also ask the room that
one thing that the document currently
says also is that they assume that
within a candidate path they have only
one CID list and but the SR policy
allows a candidate part to have multiple
set lists so there is still lot of work
to be done in this space okay point
thank you thank you making that you
point I also wanted to use this
opportunity to like you know talk to the
all the author's working on s our
document spatially make sure that the
there is some alignment between BGP work
and the piece of work recently we had
come in from Tariq earlier also while we
were progressing s our document there
were some issues between the some flags
are different between the two documents
and they share the authors between the
BGP and piece F so we request specially
those authors who are involved in both
documents - please help in making sure
the alignment is there thank you yeah I
think the next one is Michael my
question is related to candidate paths
now can PCC initiated and PCC initiated
candidate paths can coexist in this yeah
absolutely the protocol origin can be
set to piece piece up if we go back a
couple of slides if we go back a couple
of slides please the question I think we
can move on yeah thank you
yeah thanks you okay thank you we move
to the next presentation then which is
change I'm chun-li from Horry and my
topic today is about a suppose segment
and my bad Russian oppose in p-set and I
won't repeat the whole details of the
draft assume that you have read the jobs
already since I have presented these for
several times so let's let me repeat the
motivation why we do this first of all
in other words you know use cases like n
2 n + 1 + 1 and pass protection and and
like bi-directional pass correlation we
need the power segment you identified as
a path especially in as I'm Pierce
network so we proposed a draft in spring
to change it instead and recently these
charts has been adopted as I each F
working through a draft and then we also
proposed a draft to introduce our
segment in hobby 6 network so for
allocating the power segment we suppose
that the piece of extensions in piece F
annotate right so we proposed this to
document to describe the the mechanism
to allocate the power segment and the
use cases of by the rational pass a
correlation so the mainly the bank
updates of this document as we move the
RSVP flag to PC allocation flag since we
noticed that this flag can be used for
multi for multiple use cases s such as
biting seed allocation and power seed
allocation some time some something like
that so we we change the flag from post
segment allocation flag to a PC
allocation track also this has been
mentioned in PC ECC drafts already so
just update to sync up and the second is
we we adding we add some text to
describe a mesquite consideration in the
first segment an allocation so the rest
is some the rest are some minor changes
such as reference sync up and some needs
so basically we add a new cause a
junction from ZT to join this draft and
for implementation status basically a
highway is implementing this in PC and
PC C products and I suppose that he is
if he would do the same thing as well I
suppose
and the updates for this draft we
basically we mentioned we described how
to propose a new Association group to
bite the the the s passed to be a
bi-directional house in Assad networks
and this term we we update the jobs to
address the Commons from Marina marina
and Chen Chen Xiang and and then we we
fixed the the the earth based in figure
which represents the direction of LSP
from PCC point of view instead of PCE
point of view and the others are some
minor auditory changes also we added
Chen Chen shown as a new Corsa and next
plan since the draft stable for a wire
so we suppose that we are ready for
working through adoption because the
commercial delivery are going on and and
this mechanism are this mechanisms
supported by the operators and vendors
so so we click request the hooking group
adoption just like we did in on the
mailing list and comments and
contributors are very welcome thank you
question carick from Jennifer so it's
about the terminology actually SR path
LSP
and what is it everyone oh yeah I
Candida path or maybe segment list
that's what I was looking for segment
list so could this be the segment list
ID for example mm-hmm or is it the LSP
ID or is it what basically the past
maybe we just need terminology the past
document can be useful identifier see
least Oh Canada pass Oh as oh and as a
policy as you want the way I understand
it is the candidate path can be many
segment lists yes so how can you
identify with one path ID many segment
list for example there are two parsec
Canada pause within as a policy and then
we use one candidate path many segments
lists one can infer many okay so I
suppose that you okay from Cisco so it
depends on the use case right it's a
path segments depending on your use case
you can have it for the whole policy or
for the candidate pack or for the
segment list so the it defines the
concept and how you allocate it it it's
based on how you want to use it yeah
exactly
okay maybe expand on this in the draft
so that it's well understood and I think
the right place for that would be the
spring document where this thing is
defined thank you thank you anyway
any comment that's it thank you
last time when this was presented I
think John asked the question that we
will progress this work once the spring
working group has adopted so luckily
that has happened
so I think this would also be a right
time for us to see whether in the PC
working group whether we should adopt
this work so do you give for one of them
that before other or do you want both of
them what's your preference
I suppose the boost of them would you
like to expand in it sorry would you
like to clarify why she's the perfect
man is the basic mechanism for
allocating the segments in this set and
this is the basic solution and then the
key use case for post camp our segment
is about the rationale post correlation
and those two jobs has been stable for a
wire so I suppose that they can be yeah
yes so it sounds reasonable
so we've got these now in the wiki in in
our pending queue and then we will move
them to the pending so there are there
are a few documents for adoption in the
queue before then yeah we should be
rippling them up okay understand but
working group that does not prevent you
from making comments now you are allowed
to read the drafts and talk about them
no problem thank you so that's all thank
you
[Music]
okay so this is a summary of the latest
change in the draft that has been
presented it's actually merging to draft
one which was focusing on the state rule
will enter the main PC
on the chain bizzy's a new RPC like
approach under the one which was
focusing on the euro Kiko method pools
are addressing very similar problem
space inter-domain a mistake for pc
context so we managed to match pose it
to a common document on the point that
it clearly clarified where the various
approach that can be under there there
have been some improvement also we know
draft itself verification fixes
correction context we believe that the
text now is quite clear to be considered
for further move welcome to my little
show your interest there was a major
change in the section number 6 on the
selection between VP te and segment
booting types when for a yes type the
the chain of also this was piece of key
information which was part of the draft
and it's greatly improved now we still
believe that there is a hot topic behind
this problem statement there are some
proposals at heart trying to address
some data synthetic connections or all
those good fit that benefit from this
solution we see also some interest
coming from the community when it comes
to
combination stitching nesting by ninive
pass type of pass or tunnels from a mix
of meteors emigrating we also noticed
that there are some common ones on
proposal even though it doesn't fully
addressed our problem here it's also a
bit connected and we felt that the full
picture wasn't fully there so we propose
to refine the solution to the problem
coming here in for social I see someone
queuing you have a question for me okay
pressure technical solution that has
been included in the graph is one option
we believe it was reasonable enough
because so far it doesn't extend the
protocol at all it just allocate I
propose to allocate some new code bite
over existing registries and those
footprints are triggering behavior that
are defined properly in the draft of
course is working with feels that this
is a problem we want to work on has a
working group any other alternative
option to specify the way to incur those
is follow up on it is the solution that
we consider reasonable for the first
step
others are possible on hopefully if we
adopt I will talk more about the details
of whatever the idea is to work on the
problem define how it behaves also work
on your calling and then consider that
the proposal coming here are the only
way even though the good news is that we
have an implementation using those
including you is that it's not the
commission of the rotation so it will be
updated according to any modification of
the specified own career if the draft
becomes working on the
um if you want if you are interested
there is a YouTube chain on YouTube
content that you can click onto to watch
the demo firmly so currently the draft
as far as our concern is really for what
will be production Oh
since it's too late working to join the
queue for orkut interruption there is a
technical solution to the problem
knowing that is not fixed it's open to
discussion for any further work it's
applicable to stay for context but we
try to keep this pair autonomous system
policy naming that I mean yes can evolve
using SVT signaling maybe one may use
second routing it allows to combine boss
on a common service into n with the two
technologies and there are some
interesting use case on the road so we
request to join the walking a bit from Q
question alright this is Adrian proving
we need three working group chair so
Rankine chair or one present someone
asks a question I have two questions
is there an assumption about the end
domains and and whether they are under
the same administrative control or not
there is no on the contrary the RPC
based approach was built on the
assumption that different as opposed to
be working alone who usually on that in
situation where you have a common entity
controlling all the child's the children
you know pc-like approach doesn't assume
any client server or parent or child
relationship it's a flat which if you
like approach like in the autonomous
systems over Internet second members are
you aware
that there's a document in Bess on
rather it's it's a bit suspiciously
called domain gateway discovery but
actually it's much more about how you
get end-to-end connectivity similar to
the picture that you've got on that
slide with the additional thing of
finding out what the points of
attachment are from those edge domains
to the transport motor oldest one but
something definitely need to talk is
that's approaching last call
okay good to know I talked to the best
chair and a question for the chair has
everybody in the room sign the blue
sheets thank you good morning everyone
I'm then promised a te the topic I want
to talk is P CEP Ignace for parity in
Ferguson yes this this document
specifies a consistent to the past
compute PC sorry
this document specify citizens to see if
he that allow a stem for PC to compute
and initiate the path for the beauty
extensions in our draft we have defined
for in for his essence the first a spear
Kappa
the world Testament we define a new path
set up time for beer and that they find
the beer te PCE capability slapped your
way to exchange fear capability the
second reactant a P and a sappy object
they find a new path set up type
property the throw is in points object
there are two of options the first is we
use the P 2 MP and points object protein
for ipv4 and ipv6 which depend in FZ 83
the road six and depend on the the other
option is to find a new pier and point
object to can reach a PFR IT
informations the last a tenth year or
object with defines a new and imperial
or sub objects to carry artists assist
with strength psi au sub domain and si
yes this is the details of the existence
for beer capability the world has meant
for extensions beer capability yes a new
path setup type and the beauty PC
capabilities of Jia Wei are required to
form it is below and this is a key as a
key object the order to set up a beauty
a new path segments a setup type TL way
must be content are key as we object
the which means passes said huh Buren
beer T this is the endpoints object for
specifying the beer information of the
past for which surpassed
computation is required requests and the
points object is required
they are two of since we use the PDMP
endpoint object called a for ipv4 and
ipv6 which city we tilted finally up c8
stress there were six optional a we
defined a new peer and point object for
peer 4pf ID the format is below account
in the contest leaf type sauce tfiid and
one or more destination PA parties yes
the last a yahoo object for carrying the
beauty explicit passes a new period are
all sub object is required at the
contest PS they are sub domain as i and
associate a bit stress for PSL the max
last of of the biggest tree is 5 in turn
it in the it indicates the last of rapid
train is Westerlund 24 because because
tellin ya all object which defined the
length is limited to 2 8 bits so we
limited the max the value of psi to the
1020 base in case the beer euro sub
object is too long' yes next step
comments we work a welcome and wish
think that we should kiss ASSA is to the
extent 8 for peered he is needed and the
way well the next walk we we would like
to add this this part where chrome
option hope to enjoy our work this how
it may be another rough days ok yeah
any comments from anyone
I was in the beer working group where
this document was also presented yes and
then I further talked to the beer chairs
as well I think BHS suggested that this
work it should be done in within the PC
working group so that's something that I
need to further talk to my chairs as
well and conclude and the second point
also that came up was that there is the
yang work that is going on in the beer
working group so what they suggested the
Bayeux chair suggested since the beer
yang work could be the key reference for
us when we develop the PC PC extensions
and most of the things that is there in
the yang can be used as a reference when
we are developing the PCF protocol so
that there is alignment between the yang
work as well as as well as the piece of
extension that's something that we might
need to consider I'm not hundred percent
sure how to work that thing out but
that's something that we can take into
consideration the short answer on itself
thus far has lots to do this beer it's
especially for beauty and about
ambiguity should specify a number to
Young's mother for beer is not going to
include beauty so the Youngs model is
going to be to be defined in future and
I agree it should be cool aligned
between acid Jeff there is a tiny bit of
a confusion there I also was confused by
that point so what has happened is that
there is a beer yank there is a beer
tae-young and then this document as
presented is only for beer teehee but
DCCC for beer could be for a location of
bfr IDs that can include both beer and
beauty so that's why there is a bit of
overlap happening there but it needs to
be clarified right now it's a bit
confusing yes Lou burger this is
actually more of a comment for the beer
working group but since it keeps coming
up I feel like I have to say it this is
a yet another case where we're having
confusion over terms so we went through
this with spring now we're going to go
through it with beer that we're really
talking about
your policy and past steering and that's
what what the terminology that we that
we have at spring and it's this it we're
providing the same function with beer
here we should be consistent in that
terminology and the nice thing is is the
person sitting to your right is yet
Adrian who's trying to duck is actually
helping us through an update on the what
te means in the IETF so this is going to
be a great topic I look forward to
seeing his future document on the topic
that well make it so we stop having the
same conversation over and over again so
policy and past steering when we're not
doing the resource allocation is that
what least what we're using in spring
and in teas son isn't he mmm I just
still want to clarification as a
discussion just happened because they're
te can be used to resolve beer so it's a
separate two things yeah believe me so
you can use PC ECC to allocate tfiid for
peer and the also you can allocate the
agency ID for peer te yes it can be used
in peer to the ECC and but as this
document is the extension for purity
pass steering so it can be used to
calculate the pass impurity but not in
peer uvr we needn't calculate as a pass
yes so it's the difference yeah the good
thing is we are in agreement thank you
thank you it's funny to note that more
people get involved when it comes to
beer okay I think we're done for today
thank you everyone for attending the
session tomorrow hopefully
Thank You Pam where's the other blue
sheet please