I'm gonna start handing up the blue
sheets are at time but I think the snack
break may be impacting us low we'll get
started in a minute
I'm just doing you get started all right
since we have a full docket I'm gonna go
ahead and get started good afternoon
everyone you are in the rats working
group and it's the remote at the station
and procedures we are actually meeting
for the first time and thank you
everyone who helped cooperate and carry
this to a working group so before I
begin I want to thank Roman for being my
co-chair during the boss and thank him
again for being our area director so
welcome Roman and I also want to welcome
my two new co-chairs Ned Smith on my far
right and Kathleen Smith that's nice no
they're not related can you tell it's
Thursday afternoon um and Kathleen
Moriarty okay now we can cry I have an
uncle Ned Moriarty okay so given that
it's Thursday afternoon and I'm already
messing up this is the ietf note well I
will not go through it I'm presuming
that my now you would have attended a
few sessions and now understand the ITF
procedures so you just click yeah okay
so let's do a quick agenda bash and I
like let you guys read this as you can
see from the agenda structure we are
going to be quite full I've asked
Lawrence to help facilitate the
discussion for what we do with the
claims definition potentially
information model at the end so I try to
allocate as much time as possible for
that discussion so if we can defer some
of those questions to the end would
greatly appreciate it we're going to
kick it off with the intent in trying to
build the use cases
that we're going to publish them as an
RFC but the help serve as a guideline
followed with the architecture and
interaction models by Hank and then some
of the proposals visa vie the yang Tuna
the token vine and the e so with that
any discussion questions on the agenda
going once twice
okay good let's go okay administratively
I want to thank Stephen Bain heart for
being our jabber scribe and Eric for
being one of our note kick takers but we
could really use a second
so please somebody please pretty please
thank you Chris all right so so sorry
Eric
we are you I did put the link for
etherpad
tools but Chris can you do that
perfect no no actually if you can just
do the etherpad dot ITF dot org because
that's what eric is using all right so
with that um I'm gonna let Ned since
this is our first official working group
meeting I thought it would be good to
just provide an overview of what we
signed up for visa B the Charter okay so
there was discussion on the list about
the Charter I'm gonna overview that for
you now basically the the high-level
Charter is to improve their confidence
in the system components trustworthiness
that a relying party may require
evidence about and so we're listing some
of these types of types of evidence we
would expect to be exchanged in the
context of an attestation this would be
system component identity integrity or
configuration information could be
composition of the system components it
where there's there could have been
nested components and also roots of
trust it can be associated with
manufacturing and assertion or claim
origination or provenance again some of
these terms are not are defined or in
the architecture
so we're we're but we had to define some
of them to some degree in order to to
come up with the Charter but just
acknowledge this there may be some
ambiguities in some of these words add
to station' evidence could include
operational state and measurement
measurements of steps leading to
operational state for example it could
also include factors that could
influence trust decisions so sort of a
variety of other things in terms of the
goals the focus should be on
interoperable attestation where the
focus is on evidence there's a comma
missing so it's evidence formats and
conveyance we want to cooperate with
other IETF working groups we've listed a
few here like Sock'em suit and t p--
there may be others this isn't intended
to be a closed list we also intend to
evaluate prior work such as work done in
knights you have Nia which is a working
groups closed down there's also work
done in the TCG phyto Alliance and Roy
keystore and there may be others out of
scope there was discussion on the list
about what should be out of scope we
finally arrived on definition use in
conveyance of expected values thresholds
and procedures for evaluation of
attestation evidence so there'll be some
some slides to help you sort of
visualize what this means in the context
of the architecture talk but there you
know we we had we did identify some some
out of scope out areas here so the next
slide the program of work we're
basically we're going to specify use
cases for remote attestation specify
terminology and architecture that
enables the attestation so this could
include system security model for
security for assigning keys system
components component providers and
relying authorities we're going to
standardize an information model for
assertion claims that that have to do
with trustworthiness and I think that's
an important context is
in terms of limiting our scope is is
assertions ought to in some way relate
to trustworthiness of the testing device
we standardized data models that
implement and secure the information
model and so for example seaboard web
token does this JSON web token this is
an example there may be others that we
want to look at and then standardize on
interoperable protocols and I think this
should say that we're not going to
define protocols but we're going to
standardize on bindings to protocols to
securely convey assertions and claims so
any questions all right okay so as
Cheers we have to put some milestones
they actually haven't been approved yet
which is a good thing it's just meant to
be a template we had hoped that we could
do call for adoption so that's why if we
can get through the agenda I'd like to
leave some time at the end based on the
discussions we can then determine
whether we're actually ready to adopt
some of the documents or not so we
figured the architecture draft has to
align all of the work that we're doing
here so that's why we're deferring the
timeline for that as we settle in the
workgroup items that we're going to
adopt we don't expect the architecture
to be quite ready until we have that
body work somewhat stable or at least on
in some known path so the way we had
laid this out is once we adopt the
working group items that it would take
us about a year to get it to publication
so if we have enough time at the end we
can discuss about the timelines that
some of that will be dependent on the
draft as well otherwise we will continue
discussing this and try to come up with
something fairly quickly so that we can
put it on the on the rats milestones so
with that I want to give us much time
to the presenters so with that let's
have Michel Europe with the use cases
he got my timer okay she says I get like
eight minutes next slide please
so I put together a use case document
posted it in hours before the deadline
and zero one was posted this morning
based upon the feedback I received in
the list to clarify I think we put this
in the Charter as well that this use
case document if you wish to adopt this
one is not intended to be published it's
for the working groups use only and
maybe someone will put it as a appendix
to an architecture document to our
solution document or something but
that's not the intention
so I gone through the next slide please
gone through the things that were called
it in the Charter and I have received a
number of documents on TCG number of
pointers number of updates and many of
them this week and I've tried to update
things as clearly as possible and the
key thing and we saw presentation in 103
about and there was a demo about some of
this use it's about operators being able
to attest to the software visions
running on their networks I think that
their network is pretty important
because many of the other use cases are
about testing a device just on someone
else's network which doesn't belong to
you so it's I think an important
distinction between I believe Hanks
phone is untampered versus I believe
that my home router is you know or my
corporate router isn't that I own is in
fact intact Fido is more of a web-based
thing and they've done a lot of work and
if you go through their specifications
you'll find out that there's a redirect
to the w3c
and I have more work to do to pull some
of their stuff out but they're primarily
want to make sure that the device the
end has authenticated the human properly
and to that the software that has
authenticated the human properly is
intact but it converts opposites that
ECG group they really don't care about
the layers of operating system and
hardware below the system so much as the
layers above it into the web browsers
and other things like that
Android Keys torrent I believe lineman
told that I have an update and last hour
to pointing me to more of the
interesting parts of that up to this
point it has looked like a there is a
TPM like interface and that's good and
that's all I know about it so those are
the three things that we've listed in
our Charter I know there are probably
six more and I would love to hear from
you are there in the form of documents
or in the form of discussions or phone
calls a little bit would prefer to
particularly if the content is under any
kind of NDA I would in some ways prefer
to speak to you and paraphrase what you
say rather than sign your NDA but if
you'd rather me D the other way and then
you'll have to I'm trial I'll try to
exfiltrate your data your use case out
from that I'm happy to do that part for
the working group next slide I think
that's last one discussion there you go
they finished in nine minutes there we
go
all right so think they were and either
an extension to the CTC g1 or maybe
another use case of the TCG one and you
in your ECG description you talked about
the network operator there's a variation
of use case whereas not the network
operator it's the device operator right
so the device operator has you know a
server and a device and once we test
those independent of who's running the
network of a device operator an
enterprise and oh it entered price so so
right whether we're the part of the
operation
team that manages the devices is
different from the part of the
organization that manages the network oh
oh I see in the enterprise constant that
so you're saying that the guys that own
the the server don't own the plumbing
between them and the server but they
want to make sure the server is intact
is that what you're trying to tell me or
the client correct either what yellow
the client okay thank you I understand
the use case now I I'm the network
device window I see in the last pager
you mentioned different use case from
different standard organization for the
TV tea party there are actually there's
not only one use case from TCG they are
for PC for the mobile for the IOT and
for the network device so I just want to
note that at least there are some
interested for the network device we
want attestation use case so so I did
get I did get thank you I did get some
feedback from some other TCG people
saying that oh it looks like the
document that are our internal document
doesn't clearly articulate that things
like Linux is Linux processes are going
to be testable and so I would prefer I
would want to receive your feedback
there and Jessica there's given me some
already about this and so clarifying
which parts are are in scope and which
parts are not I think what I would
prefer is that some TCG people like you
standing there would tell me what
specifically you want in scope and what
specifically you don't so this is
Jessica Jerome okay and I say I'm
authoring the TCG document that Michaels
working with went along with guy Fedora
cow from Juniper that particular
document has a specific network
equipment focus TCG more broadly
addresses attestation for other types of
devices as well we thought that was the
one that was specifically in scope for
rats how much like um the Sunnis ie
I think you should change the name of
hold on so just the document is
proprietary it is but currently we're
working with the TCG boards
enables under sharing right so it would
be useful if you could at least cut that
snippet and put it in the mail list just
so we have it on record as well that
it's opened and yeah michael has uh so
I've been trying to do that and trying
to as I say exfiltrate they're there to
do that yeah and that's what I would
prefer as well as that you guys posted
because then I don't have to worry about
which parts you want to disclose which
parts yeah we're getting conflicting
feedback from the TCP port on that so
that's what when as soon as I want to
say that I'll share it I can or perhaps
you could indicate just the use case and
the requirements as an individual
without having to extract it from TCG
yeah I this again I I would suggest you
I was going to cut the line at Honus by
the way sorry I would suggest you
changed and title of the document from
the case to technology survey also
because as mentioned earlier like they
have different use cases and even at the
IOT use kis tends to be rather broad by
itself and you're not even describing
the any of the use case you're talking
about like what did Fido do and Fido
actually does more I'm claiming uncle
thank you for that V whereas I'm
claiming the document is deficient not
the title okay so I'm aspiring to so you
actually trying to use cases right
you're not there yet but I'm not getting
you use cases out of people I'm getting
rather these are some components to put
together to do things here's some Lego
bricks they're yellow green and orange
and I'm like and what do you intend to
build it like we can build anything you
like I know but which what do you what
would you like to build today is it a
bridge or a building tell me because I
want to write bridge or building exactly
what you just said and I'm not getting
that out of out of things at this point
and so it's my goal to get there so your
criticism is three hundred percent well
taken and help me get help us get there
right and it's part of the process when
you look at the Charter we said that the
use cases were really meant to be how
these claims are going to get used not
the technologies yep yep okay so with
them and I also
to capture the terminology that they use
for their variety of parties so that we
could say the TCG relying party which
may be different than the Android
keystore relying party in terms of how
it what assumptions it makes right thank
you thank you thank you think I'm trying
to be a concise and with hybridity
so I'm trying to aspire to that so I'm
presented first the a draft exists
architecture and terminology document
please so and I will begin with a small
recap of the last ITF where we had our
first off and there was as an
intermediate solution a diagram
introduces three boxes and lines between
them and there was a little bit of
confusion but these boxes actually meant
they always somehow connected to all the
things people were saying but they were
not really focusing in the discussion
next slide please
so what we basically did is in a month
we on the mail list had a lot of
discussions about how to map all these
interesting ideas of fido and key stores
and remote integrity verification into a
simple let's say common collapsed
architecture and so we introduced at
least three concepts that I highlight
here which are actors
it's basically a dotted line where you
put your roles and and then these actors
actually refer to the things that you
are always talking about like the device
my cell phone your router there's a
resource manager it could be a bank it
could be a enterprise that wants to know
that the devices are healthy and there's
a supply chain entity copy manufacturer
could be a manufacturer for component of
a device and there is an attestation
service which is both basically the most
essential
thing we'd want to build here because
that's the service that is going to tell
you yeah you're fine
this device under certain policies and
certain conditions is in your consent a
scenario considered trustworthy this
then actually makes more a little more
sense if you have the actual rules that
are placed on these actors and there are
four essential roles that we are working
and starting with we do not claim
completeness and we noted we don't claim
correctness but this is where we start
the discussion and the definition and
this is first of all the attest sir the
thing that wants to prove to another
thing or to an entity that is
trustworthy typically the Rhinehart it
wants to know that but how do you know
that it's very complicated a thousand of
different things they are how do you
assess that that's why you have the
assert which probably is for example the
producer of the device or some other
entity for example a certification
entity that tells you call this device
those vetted well and is really really
really trustworthy built and then
there's the verify again which is um the
thing that brings all of it together and
tells the relying party yes you are okay
with that device you can talk to it if
trusted and it's trustworthy so all this
is done between interaction between all
these roles and they also specified as
example company compositions in the
architecture we call that composability
big surprise next slide so there are
some fundamental principles here we will
need an information model I think that
was already highlighted but net from the
introduction slides I didn't know that
it was come up that we have to represent
the evidence created by the a tester
that wants to prove somehow that it is
trustworthy or at least give indications
about to verify that it's trustworthy
and yeah it's going to interact with
other things we are in part hysterically
with a verifier or coming back home to
the manufacturer so in order to do that
we need the data modes there's some
solution paths that are already out
there and we want to have this
flexibility with this architecture
allows us to address use cases that will
emerge and be be actually you see since
I'm fine so this is a very good process
we want to use the existing protocols
that we have here in the IETF and
probably some welds and we want to have
an integration of the emerging public
hearings or structure that is required
for this because they're different level
of trust flavors here as there are
different types of routes of trusts and
those has to be taken account the
architecture we'll try to elaborate on
all of this and it will try to be not
too long we hope to make it really
readable next slide please
so this is what came up on the email
list of us I think published shortly
before the call for consensus for
creating this working group this is some
combination of entities that are actors
so this are the things you combine roles
on and let me highlight already on this
slide that we are not doing all of this
that is here the architecture includes
some things and some components and
actor definitions that are technically
out of scope for the architecture but in
order to convey the bigger picture are
required otherwise you will not get why
this will function at the end next slide
please
then we have the actual roles again
complemented was sort of said we now
have it instead of device a tester
instead of the resource manager others
relying party instead of a service that
is remote associations of the verifier
and instead of the manufacturer we call
it in a search because a manufacturer
can tell you an imprint like immutable
into the device properties about it and
this properties can be conveyed to for
example to airline party next life is
also a example composability sometimes
those roads will be completely complex
into a single actor in this case we
collapsed the supply chain integers
let's color the manufacturer and they're
verifying service into the same actor
what does that mean now we don't need a
protocol between those see those two we
are not interested in that
in this scenario so if there is a
existing workflow of there that uses
this architectural combination
of course they'll have no interest in
creating or using proper corset as
talking between in a shirt and a
verifier but in outside the globe big
growth that is the Internet
probably other entities want to have to
do that next type is so that's a out of
scope triangle here and it's very hard
to say everything that is under the gray
area is out of scope what I can tell you
is that everything that has a red dot on
this diagram is out of scope but the
eSATA roll most certain is not and
probably the attestation assertions that
are created by a manufacturer are also
not out of scope because they will be
part of the information model so it's
very hard for us in the moment to draw
this demarcation line which is really
otoscope which really inside the school
so the architecture will make a good
effort to better highlight that next
slide sweet so the relationships we we
were talking about the little bits there
are a lot of architectures already out
there starting with cheep cheep has a 10
for example attempt is at the very least
a relying party and most likely also
verifier and there is a device in the
chip architecture that has a rustic
execution environment that thing most
certainly is no tester we have the PSA
draft it's very news from arm and they
are defined the network and EPS services
that's an actor that's probably
combining the roles of party area in
partying verifier and again it's talking
through some Javier's getting
information about some hardware that
again will take on the role of the
tester and then we have the actually
best fitting thing we saw yet that is
the heed overall system component
provided by Lawrence which has all of
them in there so we like party there
it's actually colouring party they have
you have multiple types of entities they
are from IOT device to I don't know also
mobiles and that what's going to be
their testers and the manufacturer is
really spelled out as an actor here and
it is specifically defined as providing
both the assertion definitions s also be
the verifier for those assertion at
least as a source next slide please
so again in consequence there will be
overlap other working groups and
creating this architectural document as
highlighted cheap where the manifest and
the attestation provenance they're very
interested in because they want to a
provision D correct te it's kind of
really important to them there will be a
suit manifest and the software update
for the internal things working group
they also have an information model
which is interesting for this work there
is a security automation continuous
monitoring working groups they have an
information information model but at
least they have a manifest about
software and we are talking about remote
integrity verification some cases so
there will be software Netcom provides a
young module for the immense trust in
Carrozza tories so you can query a thing
if they have trust anchors who want to
rely on and then back in the days was a
temp working group that actually did
order your protocol up configure and
configure in those trust anchors next
slide please
so there will be overlap there some work
is already done some work has to be
combined it all has to make sense there
will be a lot of mapping and there will
be some new terms so we have sources for
definitions like the National Institute
for Standards and Technology global
platform already has a big thing about
you love trust out there and Fido also
defines a lot of new cool processes that
we can reuse and it's ECG as we just
heard is struggling with giving us
openly more information but they have a
lot of them so all of this estate as a
station Germany should make sense to all
of them and it should mean the same
thing to all of them otherwise
interoperability
will be an illusion and we will attest
to something that is actually not
trustworthiness and this will not work
so yeah is the consensus of author core
vocabulary is essential and that is why
the terminology is being pulled into the
architecture draft because it is
basically the basis for everything we
talk about here yeah terms next slide
please
so in the end there is one specific
terminology for the problem I wanted to
highlight first we are always talking or
often talking about claims but the term
claim has already claimed by GWT and the
things that a device can present about
itself the device characteristics
basically assertions they do not
necessarily come with a proof of
validity which makes them assertions if
there are company to have the proof of
validity they become evidence so in any
case assertions are represented as
claims in CWT so it's very easy to use
every assertion we define an information
model in a CWT data format and
assertions might also be represented and
other ways data model terminology then
claims it's fun to highlight there is a
difference there
I'll skip the last one next slide so
what is important here is not only the
assertion itself but what it means so we
have to have people bashing the meaning
of the terms and because we were always
using weren't claimant and it's so
strongly associated of the claim we were
switching it to a searcher so we can
create assertions that's just the
terminology thing for the abstraction of
an architecture the architecture has to
be abstract enough to map to all
existing and to be created solutions so
we need yeah actually net said that we
need an information model and the
provisioning which relies on what are
you actually attesting to how do you
find that owls is out of scope for now
this we call phasing there will be a
time when we will need this and then we
have to pay more attention in focus and
time on to that topic but not now x6 mm
in time you are very much on time do you
want to you have one minute left you
wanna lie for one or two questions if
anyone has a question of
very very fast talk yeah sure I'm sorry
that I ran through this but I wanted to
get Gary my name for calm if you go
quickly back to slide 5 we are sorry for
not including numbers by the way and
thank you for counting yeah hey I think
I with the architecture can you describe
the slide it's a boy it just it's a
block diagram where there we go
yeah and as far as one being two
interfaces are concerned I kind of
compared this to you a Wi-Fi door lines
white paper on identity Federation
systems that I actually co-authored we
took the we took the approach that in
that case we in that case the verifier
could be the verifier was distinctly
different from the relying party in the
sense that the verifier could be an IDP
and we felt that that interface was a
b2b interface what you call 1b and 2 and
in my opinion we should make as far as
this work working groups work is
concerned we should be very clear on
what our b2b interfaces and what
requiring a Roth bill interoperability
between manufactures equipment that may
not have business relationships I think
we'll really have a lot of difficulty
defining such interfaces if we that's my
opinion so so so quick look like 1b and
2 has the very big spectrum it can range
from a hash of a public key to all the
evidence every for a root of class of
measurement can provide so there's a big
spectrum there first of all also
composing verify and relying party is
very usually so they can be the same
actor that's very often the case and
then there would be no so is it quick
yeah this is a question from the jabber
quick clarifying question what is the TA
MP working group from the overlap slide
oh that's a very good question I sort of
keep that in mind it's older it's
completed and it's about provisioning
trust anchor
information the configuring the trust
anchors it's on the data tracker so
googling data tracker temp and work
group works sorry
they have clarifying question and a
question but if we're short on time
we'll just go with a clarifying question
now on the same slide because you talked
about things like you know CW T's and JW
t s and so on I'm the one that had note
the one they have all the lines and the
boxes and stuff which lines on there are
you talking about as using you know CW
TS u JW T's or whatever is at line 1a or
2 or both as my clarifying questions in
this case here the assertions conveyed
could be assigned and therefore it could
be a GWT assigned the relying party
would not be able to make most sense of
most of them probably ands relaying them
in a secure manner this is why I called
1b to the verifier so that would be one
path it could be directly between a test
and verify it would be another path and
actually the reference values via the
JavaScript in theory also be packaged in
CW T's so in theory all of these lines
could be done with a token format I'm
hesitant to call them talking if their
manifests for example the reference
value is probably it's more like a
manifest but the format effectively is C
WTS we're at the time okay
please give to the entitle the telephone
yeah sorry so we wrote something very
obvious here um and that is an
interaction model for challenge response
based remote attestation next slide so
this is the thing where you challenge
someone with the nuns and they do
something for progressively and give you
an answer and by doing that they show
you that this answer was created recent
very recent it's called freshness so and
the remotest age is important that the
evidence that you get is not a year old
so that would be like really useful
phone and attackers will give you a
healthy state about the device that is
basically out eight
so this procedure is very common and it
is used through approval provide
freshness
actually it's recentness so this
procedure is done in many places which
is very good and it is always
re-explained over and over again with
small little variation in detail which
is kind of bad so this is why we created
this small draft that illustrates how
this is done and it could be just based
on that reference if you want to do a
challenge response based nun's freshness
proof we are hand shakes just reference
this document highlight which of the
elements you want to use there and don't
clone the normative text anymore please
and if you are not okay with the card
next slide please and if you're not okay
with the content of this valve if you
find anything missing just speak out
create an issue or write on the email
list and then highlight that that is
very important to us I think
unfortunately we already had got a good
bunch of like two sets of real thorough
feedback that there's additions and some
modifications and we haven't proved that
in yet just not enough time so it is
already in the state of being improved
but I'm sure there's more this is my
last time do we have time for a question
okay so Romi dear you know hat so as we
talk about protocols for rats can you
help me understand why this would be a
good starting point why as we talked
about have you from all the different
protocols you might need we need this
one first um there's a young module
coming up that is using that interaction
model and it is the first instance of
not cloning this normative text and
there will be a protocol in next and we
use the same mechanism and they're not -
the cloning next so we have a show that
we have two documents that will use the
same mechanism and then an induction
then when we talk about specific
instances of the information model when
we talk about the token we're gonna it
is another solid
not information mother I think he's
saying that's part of the interface or
transport it is not an information other
than interaction what it's you start
with this and then you go with this no I
appreciate that but on the back half of
the agenda we're actually gonna talk
about actual things we're gonna actual
claims we're talking about including to
trade yeah our is the technology we're
gonna use to encode the actual claims
going to align with this this work which
talks about the interfaces that which
has absolute to be aligned so the
assertions included in the interaction
whether that like fire to do it have to
be mirrored in the information but I
want one or even referenced in the way
that but that would be most of the
references we have to know how not to
clone that again but yes they have
deadlines exactly does it right now or
is that future work that needs to get
more information models so it kind of
the lion what why don't we take that
once we have work items so so yeah I'm
coming back to the highlighted solution
draft which is a yang module for this
basic challege response based remote as
a station a lot of network vendors are
interested this is the awfulest shows
and next slide please
I'm giving a very quick background about
Yang because I think everybody knows
what yang is but there's always some
uncertainty so yang is a language for to
do the difference data repositories for
data at rest
it rests for example at a network device
and then it defines a set of operations
to operate on this data at rest and
there are different encoding for this
opera for those operations that are just
net con for this XML as restaurant with
Jason and nscaw conf is assessable so
just different implementations of
protocols that have all the same
operations and the semantically
equivalent they're all operating on the
data address this is the data store so
also Jung has our pcs you can do
basically challenge-response thing is
with it and they can create geometry but
this is basically a site
information so if you're curious about
how yang actually works pistols go to
net confer net mod and read the basic
IRC or join their working groups so yang
is widely used and deployed finally and
especially on network equipment and
service or virtual services so adding
remote attestation procedures on this
existing management interface was a
low-hanging fruit to let it say this
another fruit forms a chalk bind
and it's also already there just fill in
the stuff you need for example so the
contribution of this document is we use
the yang our PCs to effectively
implement the highlighted interaction
model and to enable a non spaced remote
attestation procedure and we require for
this in this specific document a set at
least one root of trust for reporting so
that it can be a trust for proof that
the composite advice network devices
where you have components is actually
Integra therefore trust worthiness doing
exactly what is intended to do anything
else
next slide please so the current game
audio is actually already quite mature
and very very designed there are some
requirements so we don't only have an
RPC but we have some complementary
information like identity documents and
other endorsement documents that talk
about the devices and the components
those don't have to be included in the
RPC those you can get at any time of
convenience they're basically in their
own data store but we've been told that
the other yang enforces you to give
semantics to every single statement in
the yang module it's called description
that's not enough we have to give more a
glue text in the draft
how it is applied and how it's working
but that's frosting I think that's an
easy thing to do and please look at this
graph there was some confusion about how
does this really work and if you
highlight what you do not understand and
just post it on a list and we've
addressed
since to the yang module I think we're
running out of time okay I'm trying hard
to do five minutes this is ten minutes
so there's a variation to do remote
education announce last one it needs
something else it's based on time and
time stamps next slide please
so typically do handshakes they're
bi-directional this is not always
feasible this approach was called time
based unidirectional attestation and
they're using an external trusted time
source this is actually defined by the
ITF where long ago is thirty one sixty
one the timestamp authority that is
creating timestamp tokens for you if you
want them as a result we can now if this
time that is trusted on every site at
the attest and the verifier create
unique directional communication between
a tester and verifier and there is no
response required from the very fair
there are actually quite used some you
say usage scenarios that really make
could benefit from this also a very very
important side effect is here you create
secure audit locks of the integrity and
trustworthiness of your device or
whatever it is network function that can
stay there forever and will ever be
valid improve instead of the thing that
you just convey with the nonce which is
only recent at a certain point of time
next slide please
this is hard it is a rather complex
mechanism basically you prove that there
is a time that time spend on your device
that is aligning with the trust time
sauce should you take your own time stem
from the local time your crypto coverage
binded with the external times them and
then again trips go through binded with
the local time spread this takes some
time and everything that is measured as
evidence or we are it would of trust of
measurement in this time stem can be
proven to be exactly made at that point
of time which is important and the
equivalent to the nonce effectively so
this document is effectively really
mature
sure but it is a tad bit ugly so the
structure in layout needs improvement
you have two bindings included which is
an SNP map which is mature and done we
have a yang module which we just derived
from the myth which is therefore kind of
broken we have to refactor to make it
actually like nice and beautiful so also
we need some better terminology because
this document is like over a year old
now and we will try to create new
terminology here and that has not been
taken into account in the Tuda a draft
so therefore it is using some terms that
are misaligned with the things I just
was telling you about
we very immediate as over time it will
just take time and also at the moment we
are conveying Seeb or arrays as the
elements if an root of trust of
reporting or a root of trust of
measurement could natively create and
sign a web token then we could take CWT
into account but a lot of solutions out
there at the moment
cannot do this so at the moment it is a
see what array just like the x5 or 9c
well profile the end so clarifying
question on the drafts can you clarify
when you say mature and stable what does
that mean because they're not adopted
documents they include one in Croton
were tested by multiple companies and
ancestral environments they have running
code that is that is not trashing it is
validated by industry companies today in
their production environment
so this is why I claim now I give out
the assertion that it is rather mature
so relating to what you just asked Nancy
Dave Walter Meyer there looks like
there's a lot of work that's been done
here which i think is great but it's not
clear after having a handful of
presentations what work needs to be done
next on on these documents and and can
you share maybe some thoughts on
you know how I mean I came to this
thinking this is the first working group
meeting part of this would be about
orienting as to how we can help yeah how
can we help so this is worth five
minutes such talks in essence all the
time so it's very hard to get to that
point the the yang module it is kinda
very easy you have to understand yang
modules and you have in your own use
case if you don't find yourself in that
use case and that yang module please
speak out this is the contribution we
really expect a lot of network vendors
already did this maybe some other
entities out there also want to have
that in use and they are missing
something or they're using identifying
their route of trust for measurement
differently or the device component
differently if they cannot identify a
component their own network device with
this module it is useless to them they
would have to create an argument just
weave that's for them and it probably
won't never publish it because it's just
for them so this would be a thing to
contribute now with the time based you
need time based unidirectional
attestation there could be other
applications to the scenario like if you
really want to have this data diode
where you can only push evidence out of
something and never talk back so it's
like a high security area whatever if
you have the scenario are working in a
field like that please pick up and tell
us okay this looks cool but so this is
the contributions we have open file
because these drafts are there for a
long time already they were here before
this working group formed or was started
will be formed and therefore maturity
already is there a little bit the
architecture document though is the one
that we really need input on if you're
unhappy with a composability for the
concepts provided all of the terms used
that is very important this is the most
important thing to focus on now I think
I'm struggling with the arrangement of
the sequencing you just described and
maybe I'm just hung up back on what I
saw in the milestones so what we're
saying is here are some
very mature things that pre-existed kind
of rats they work we should take them
into the working group but at the same
time we're saying we have this
architecture we got to talk about a lot
or kind of not sure but in the long term
we want these things that we want on top
right now that are really mature we want
to plug them into the thing we don't
know what it actually is
that's it seems asymmetric to me it
feels like we should decide what is kind
of the architecture and then figure out
what we need to plug in that already
exists or where we got to define you
work this is the same problem as we had
with quite India at the Charter we had
to define terms without having a
document that defines them the same goes
here so everything that it has to be
used terminology architects arise in the
solution drafts today the office of
solutions should hurry up and get that
in there now and bring it to discussion
for their use cases the information
order therefore has not been complete in
the end and the architecture also not
but it has to be mapable as soon as
possible
that is the the the solution that I
would propose that everybody who has
something now contributes now and if
something is being developed and slowly
integrated have more time okay so I'd be
interested here what the yeah so let me
speak a little bit on the chair since I
set up the yes the agenda so this is the
first working group which is why we
wanted to make sure that we had so your
comments Roman and and Dave are very
valid so we wanted to go through the
Charter and the Charter we went through
this is the program of work we need to
define the architecture we need to
define an information model we need to
define the set of claims that we want to
standardize when we did the call for
agenda there is some work that has to be
done my opinion having read through the
drafts is that some of them go more
towards the interfaces my question later
which I may cut myself off is to
determine which pieces you think are
part of information model versus data
model versus the operations on the data
model which is
I was construing the yang module so
Romans questions are very valid because
those things really should come after we
know the set of claims or at the
stations that we want to work through
not that the work that you've done isn't
relevant
it's the are we putting the cart before
the horse yes and that is okay we don't
have to do working that's called
necessary for a solution draft without
the the architecture you put that in the
myosin that way but that is not the
other we have to do it well I know I
know put it there just to get people's
attention so it's good that everybody's
reading okay okay so with that Steven
I'm gonna catch you laughs after that so
we can get on to the next one okay do
you have time for my question or yeah
okay so um this was a lot of stuff and
I'm just trying to kind of contextualize
all of it so I can understand it could
you really quickly and maybe going back
to like slide eight actually show the
architecture where does two to fit in
there like which which piece is it so I
can understand where it fits in what
you're imagining here yeah that one's
good and Tudor talks between the ax
tester and the verifier so it does not
rely on a relying party it just proves
to you the yes/no quote in the end
because it is based on an audit log so I
don't see any reaction that's the
composability feature I was talking
about you can draw on more lines this is
the a composition another composition
for the collapsing of a test and verify
as an example you could collapse verify
underlying party or you could do another
edge the talks directly between a test
and verify which I think in the TCG
sometimes happens and there's a bigger
slide set this is on the list before the
group consensus to funders that is like
fifty two slides long and includes
exactly this diagonal line okay so the
composability is cool it just it just
doesn't help me understand what's
actually going on here so especially yes
at the end when we have time which is
one time to accelerate process you don't
have two hours so I'm believing that
we're gonna need an interim just to
level set and get us going forward
progress and no takers will have a lot
of questions and then outs so we can
address them accordingly I think in
terms a fabulous idea
so again until good yeah okay okay Gary
and time wait Thank You Hank yes and you
did it in time
okay thank you I'm gonna try to see if I
can give five minutes back to Lawrence
because they know that that discussion
was going to be quite could be quite
long so I'm going to introduce the topic
of the tested TLS tell combining this is
based on a draft that I've had in the
talk mine group for a couple of years
now I'm not going to really do justice
to the car into the topic of token
binding itself but the first few slides
are about this it's basic basically
token binding came about because of
vulnerabilities and I did it in identity
Federation system tokens if a token
actually gets extracted from a client
then then those tokens can actually be
used to spoof on behalf of the client
and fool relying parties the the tokens
could the the tokens could cause
vulnerabilities to man-in-the-middle
attacks and as a result the ietf a
couple years back started the whole talk
mind effort now we've had recently three
RS C's approved that describe how token
binding worried the token binding
protocol and the TLS handshake handshake
requirements go to the next slide please
so top a token binding currently it
currently consists of first off
negotiating token binding between the
endpoints and then passing a token
binding message an HTTP bound message
that a that actually signs over a
payload unique to the TLS a TLS
connection primarily the exported key
material ekm right now the
implementations in browser is basically
all the implementations out there have
the browser's maintained private keys
associated with with the TOS token
binding those good though its user a
browsers user agents I use the term
interchangeably they're implemented in
user space and as a result of that those
keys themselves can be vulnerable
and you're back to the same problems
that that that tow combining was
designed to actually address which is
extraction of private material from the
client by hostile parties even if you go
away from boundaries a lot of there's
there's proposals to actually implement
TLS token binding in one call native
applications like Android uh Android App
Store applications and such many of the
applications will be relying on on open
source code like open SSL and and
therefore vulnerabilities can be
potentially be exploited if attackers
can actually attack your hey if
attackers can actually extract keys from
these letter from these libraries once
again the primary vulnerability isn't
running in user space please continue
so I'll define I'll define what I call
Hardware secured signing for TLS token
binding so these are my definitions
alone you can tell you can you can take
issue with them I don't mind
I've defined what I call a signing
process and it's just any application or
any kind of platform functionality that
can execute a crypto operation so
deciding so that the browser can
actually delegate to that so hardware
bound or Harvard secured signing would
actually run in a in the context of what
we would consider a route of trust
examples of trust are not just he PM's
and secure elements but also trusted
execution environments as well so such
processes can be used for generating
signature for token binding and the
relying party in this case can make
decisions as to whether to continue a
TLS session with the client based on
based on security assurances related to
storage of the private keys well how do
they how does a relying party make that
decision please next slide
remote attestation I have a definition
here I don't want to go through it
because I think we've talked it and we
talked about it not just in this IETF
meeting but in previous to you and I
think Hank actually did a decent job of
saying how a relying party and a
verifier play into consuming an
attestation statement generated from the
device now one of the things that's
actually been a little bit challenging
for browser vendors to actually
implement carriage of attestation data
related to you a hardware secured a
hardware secured private keys for token
binding is performance they're very
worried not just over TLS handshake but
anything that can affect http
performance even post handshake and
verifying the token is are the top
binding message is already tough enough
now you're talking about verifying an
attestation statement as well so these
are some of the things that I've run
into you and I've run into several
different options as to how to actually
do this in such a way that that takes
into account the performance
considerations so the token binding
Batak mine group actually wants to see
attestation and once see solution they
defined an extension message mechanism
for talk-line messages and it
specifically cited in 84-71 that the
intended use is for attestation
the ID that i have currently currently
proposes defining in a unique extension
for each attestation type in the current
draft i put in an android key store
attestation the TPM version two
compliant attestation along with the
corresponding verification procedures
you can also we can also have the group
decides to it decides to you do this
kind of work and Hank also mentioned
this in this presentation we can
certainly look at other different other
attestation types as we go through the
definition more importantly I think we
can also look at how this can be
conveyed so this is um
you know does it even make sense to
define and if ur intention for each
attestation type shouldn't you should we
just define one extension for all
attestation types and build it and put
in sort of an in in in band protocol
within that extension type to actually
describe which attestation is being
conveyed which let's move on yeah okay
you mean yeah next slide please
so why take up this topic in this in
this working group well a talk line
private key provenance is not really it
is not really current being verified by
any relying parties today and
attestation is one way to it way to do
that and also I've read through the
Charter again and I believe we've uh it
is covered by the program of work as far
as standardizing interoperable protocols
and I think we've seen some recent
contributions where you can actually see
some value in if we can actually bring
the attestation data in a tot mine
context for instance the the arm the
contribution by honest and his
colleagues at arm on the PSA token
actually mentioned something called
software competence well whatever I what
if one of the things that we could call
a software confident is browser itself
that can actually be quite useful to the
relying party they as far as as far as
their determination of what can be done
with the particular TLS connection so
this is my last slide my recommendation
is that the rats working group take up
it take on an effort to define token
bodytalk mind extensions for attestation
I volunteered the draft that I have in
the talk binding working group as a
starting point doesn't have to be but I
am but I think we can include this in a
program that work and based on that we
can determine the initial attestation
formats coming and going from the use
cases the use case document that we
discussed at the beginning of the me
that is all thank you thank you make it
quick
yeah hi this is Hank making it quick
I've been following this book since zero
zero because I am aware of everything
that uses CD DL which answer you were
using that plus plus and also I'm in
favor of this idea of creating a like a
attestation formats meta head out to the
to the so that we talk just what one
protocol here that that is busy in the
truck by definition and not enough for
everything that we can make that
extensible I don't know how much
overhead that creates effectively but it
sounds like a very good idea to pursue
and test out okay thank you one of the
things that browser vendors actually
said and this is this is even related to
our Fido experience is they want the app
they want the ability also to not send
an attestation at all but at least at
least have the relying party have that
capability so I think that's one of the
things that I think we will need to
figure out what talk mine is how do we
actually do that in such a way that we
actually enable that capability in such
a way that the client isn't sending out
of stations when the relying party in
certain cases doesn't want it and don't
and has no use for it and it's not just
because they have no capability to
verify they don't want to take
responsibility for a device identifying
the information may be a privacy issue
depending on the nature of the service
so that's another thing that when we
define these in banned protocols we
should consider a mechanism right next
we have Lawrence with eat and then
discussion
hello next slide please
so I'm gonna first describe eat as it
sort of exists and is written up today
not really saying too much about what I
expect it to change and expand and morph
a bit as it B becomes part of rats so
but first explanation is just really
kind of how he is was just was it
created and folks have been to the box
and others have seen some of these sites
already but I'll go over them quickly
here so so this very top level the idea
here is you've got some good devices
lots of different kinds of devices and
you've got some bad devices they might
be trying to emulate a real device they
might be tampered with they might be
cloned or they might be rooted so we're
trying to collect a bunch of claims I've
used the term claims comfortable with
that until we actually settled on have
it have agreement on another term so I'm
going to stick with the term claims for
or my discussion um so you collect a
bunch of claims sign them send them to
the relying party which could be this is
represent some use cases you know
banking use case like a risk engine some
IOT that's and back in this trying to
determine whether it's a real device or
not network infrastructure or car
component it's talking to each other
cars talking to each other enterprise or
public utilities kind of use cases next
slide please
so this is Hank kind of referred to this
slide and I think there's some
reasonable alignment with the four boxes
slide here who thinks four boxes slide
but the basic idea is you have a device
we we used to term entity because we
wanted it to be either a chip a device a
subsystem a car a refrigerator just very
broad range or part of a refrigerator
part of a car a very broad range of
things that's why we use the term entity
there and it has the the ability to
collect claims and sign them
those those claims that group of sign
claim
is a token the token is transmitted to
the relying party and then the relying
party verifies it and looks at the
claims then makes a decision about what
the relying party is going to do so the
ruling party you know may care more
about the geographic location than
anything else because they're gonna use
look at that in relationship to other
financial transactions that that
particular user has made and realized
well if he's if he's ten thousand miles
away from where the last one was and
it's been an hour something's wrong it
could be it could be a decision in that
in that in that vein so so eat was very
interested in is very interested in in
the claims standardizing claims it
seemed like the low-hanging fruit and
the most interesting thing to focus on
first so that was why we looked at that
and you know originally the vision for
eat was the claims going from the entity
to the relying party as we saw thanks
diagram but we can expand that so the
claims can go other directions on other
interfaces as well I thought that was a
reasonably good idea and a way to
characterize it next eat is basically
the the proposal was basically to use
the CWT kind of repurpose it had a lot
of really good characteristics for the
IOT world and similar to stuff that was
done in Fido and not really a fan of
asn.1 myself and Jose or GWT was a
little bit large for IOT devices so CWT
seem like a really great fit I don't
think I'm gonna go into any more on that
that's it's basically COEs a format
message there so one of the things that
thought about with eat in terms of
signing schemes like how the classic way
to do it would be CDSA
signatures but in my kind of an
understanding of IOT and some of the
other issues there we really do want a
lot of flexibility in the signing scheme
because they're the ghosts of complexity
and chip manufacturing there's also
privacy issues with signing so we might
want signing schemes that are privacy
preserving like ec DAA so we start with
things like ECDSA but even symmetric
signing would be reasonable or other
things like EC DAA and you know cuz it
gives us the flexibility for all of
those sorts of things and it seemed a
bit scary to try to standardize on all
of those because there's a lot of use
cases and a lot of variations there so
just the moment leaving those things
open and let cozy handle that next slide
here's an example token I think most of
us are familiar enough so I'm not going
to go into that it's just an example of
a CWT nice and small and compact next
slide I want to mention privacy
it's varies a lot by use case in the
case of a something like a light bulb
which really only has one user in one
use case and very simple the privacy
issues are not very large if you're
talking about an attestation for an
Android app where you might have a lot
of claims and you have a device that
talks to dozens maybe hundreds of
relying parties and correlation between
that relying parties for that device is
a big issue privacy becomes a very big
issue and has to be handled carefully so
my example here you know a light bulb
might be something with two or three
claims a an attestation of an Android
app might have a hundred claims so you
know how do you handle privacy three
options really I think you privacy
violating claims so you just don't do
that don't have
you redesign the claim so that it can
work with privacy regulations and I
think have some ideas how to do that on
some claims some claims it'll be easy
sometimes it'll be impossible or you ask
permission so classic example is
permission to use location in an android
app then as i mentioned also signing
schemes if you're doing one key every
day every individual device has a unique
key just the the key itself becomes a
advise identifier and you have a privacy
you may have a privacy problem you for
example in Fido or Android attestation
you definitely have a problem so you
can't just do one key per device for
Fido or Android so that's why you might
need some solutions that like a CDA or
group keys next slide so I'm going to
finish this I think I just I think this
is the last slide and then for this
presentation and then I'll maybe a few
questions very brief I'm and then I'll
go to the the next one which is more
about claims definition so eat defined a
this basically this set of claims this
is a high-level description of claims
this was an initial set this was getting
started seemed like there would be lots
of claims we can we can spend a lot of
time on and that I was anticipating that
this work group would you know spend a
year or two defining lots of lots more
interesting claim so that's really the
sort of some of the meat and potatoes
work I have started a categorization
scheme for claims they're just trying to
chunk them into like okay let's work on
this group or work on that group so I
started to listing that on the right so
there's some basic claims which are
things that are standalone simple and
then some claims related to sub modules
where you have one device that has a sub
module and from I have another sub
module and and how devices are put
together there's a lot of a modern cell
phone has a
a lot of different subsystems so many of
them which are interested in that a
station so the next slide deck I'll go
into a little bit more about how the
areas for the claims and what to do
about them so questions hi Robert Wilson
could you just go back one slide please
arms okay I I just get uneasy when I
when if there's an implication that the
potential privacy impact of a device or
a given attestation is is a factor of
how many of them there are clearly a
thing a thing that may only exposed two
or three claims could be devastatingly
privacy invasive so the implication
there that there's just a purely
quantitative aspect to this makes me
nervous yeah I didn't mean to imply that
thank you
Brendon Morin I I just want to object to
the idea that single-use IOT devices are
less complex for privacy I don't know
how much it overlaps specifically with
attestation but just to give an example
of where this falls down things like
lights IOT lights which are single-use
and supposedly simple have been used to
harass ex-partners after breakups
so just because they're simple does not
mean the privacy implications are not
significant okay sure
okay let's let's move on to the next
slide deck here next slide so you know
in the in the work on the Charter we
came up with the idea of a an
information model document my
understanding of that is to be a
document that defines the claims that
that can be in a token
we've had some back-and-forth to
discussion the side side discussions and
stuff about whether the syntax of the
claim is defined in this in this
information model document or not I know
we certainly want to support more than
one syntax so seaboard based and JSON
based and maybe others so I'm sure we
want to describe the claims in a syntax
or serialization neutral way certainly
we have to do that and then we also have
to define how you serialize it in C bar
or in Jason or something else I I don't
have a super strong feel on where those
things all go but to me what's most
important is we do have an informational
document that's natural and we are in a
description of the claim that's neutral
for serialization and then we do the
specific so so this when they made this
slide I was assuming there would be
separate documents but I've had some
other discussions where maybe because
because some of the serialization
descriptions are going to be really
simple so Remmington a just wanted to
jump in on exactly that to your point I
mean you charter doesn't explicitly say
they have to be separate documents there
is prior precedent to having an
information model in a document then the
data model that aligns with that and
then another data model that just
references the information model not a
portion of that so so the worker can
decide what makes most so if I had to
pick now I'd say let's put it all in one
document and see how it goes and if we
don't like it we can split it Tony
Madeline are you also pulling in JW s
and E also I'm
are you pulling in the signature and
encryption also from a JW yeah I would
assume if we're doing Jason style claims
we're assigning JWT
format and seaboard style claims we
would see yeah I just want to make sure
you're considering encryption and
signing and yeah yeah yeah absolutely
yeah
but I opened you know how we want to do
this I mean I think there's some options
there without that was the assumption
okay next all right so I actually wish
I'd spent more time making a fancier
slide here on on these because I think
this is probably the kind of kind of
that some of the core discussion here so
you know I'm gonna start at the bottom
of this slide so the the vision I had
here was that all claims are optional
there's no mandatory claims at all just
seem like it's hard to to come up with
any particular claim that was absolutely
mandatory maybe in knots but now we have
to decide not even that the same way so
this is you know for many use cases now
you can have profile documents that say
for this use case you must have this
claim but in a general way our claims
are optional next one up from the bottom
here the idea is that claims should be
generally applicable so they're not
specific to TPMS or trust soundless
jacks or Android or Linux or Mac OS or
whatever so we're really trying to make
the claims as general you know thinking
about the relying party as the audience
so the relying party could be lots of
different things and they're they're
going to be getting out of stations from
lots of different types of devices so
it's up to the we want to make it so the
relying party can figure out what's
going on so that really the audience or
the claims is the relying party similar
I think it should work the claim should
work with different levels of
device security so sometimes the other
stations are going to get generated
inside secure elements and TPMS are
smart cards sometimes they're going to
get generated by an app running in
Windows or some very low security device
or something with no special
characteristics of all so so to me that
the that's an important thing you know
we're going to spend a lot of time
thinking about claims in TPMS and secure
elements but I also want to think about
those claims coming out of other places
that are not that don't have the same
security like that okay so now the the
five areas I'm proposing for claim
definition work I know I wouldn't
consider these particularly sacred but
it seems like a really good starting
point
so there's basic claims which things
like the identification of the device
the the identification of the who made
the device the position location of the
device sir how what state did it boot in
and things like that typically these are
simple unstructured claims and this is
what it has defined a number of already
so that's one one group next would be a
description of software components
claims so so these are I've looked at
Cisco's big giant file of software
components and some work done with arm
there's a list of software components in
the PSA design and as a you know there's
the other working group that I think was
SACM that has done some one work here so
I think of the software components
claims as describing software that was
released by an organization that is to
be installed not running software not
the software running on this TE not the
software you know in this application
not this off
system in an existing example to me is
like a library that's released it's a
simple library it gets dynamically
linked into the tea because it's such a
general library like I don't know string
compare it'll it gets linked into the te
kernel it get link gets lit gets
dynamically linked to a trusted
application gets dynamically linked to
an android application same thing right
so the software component describes the
library not where it's running so that
was my thought on on what software
components where and how to structure
them you know you might they might have
a name they might have a hash they might
have some some other characteristics
describing some type or something like
that so that was it's almost like you
could imagine a subgroup of us going off
and say where the where the the software
components subcommittee and we're gonna
design those claims I'm thinking about
all the different use cases so that's
the second one third one is measurement
and integrity check so this is now
you're trying to look at running
software in a subsystem and see if it's
the software you think it is you might
be reporting the hashes TPM style
integrity check is a different kind of
architecture and I think most people are
familiar with the TPM style samsung has
a product called tema where they run and
a an integrity checker in trustzone that
checks the integrity of components of
android and it reports a yes or a No it
doesn't report a hash because trust zone
is isolated from Android so trust zone
can measure something because that's
outside of that's a trust zone and trust
zone in this case has the correct
measurements the known values it knows
what it's supposed to be so that's a
different style of integrity measurement
and just real world products
at least one or two or three that do
that so so to me one include both with
us so that's the third one these are
some what I'm sort of listening them
from easiest to hardest as well it's the
least one when I worked on you know
thinking about the designs here the ones
that I thought were easier and harder so
forth one here is public keys and the
characteristics of those those keys and
the the really good example is the
Android key store I sent a link I think
it to the to the mailing list like two
hours ago that showed the the basically
there are all the claims that Android
key star makes about a public key and
there's a bunch of really interesting
things I think I've also seen these
kinds of let me back up a minute here so
the idea is you put a public key in as a
claim and then all of the other
surrounding claims tell you something
about that key like it so it tells you
that that public key is running on a
device that was booted in a secure way
or that that public key is and the and
the corresponding private key is in a
device that we we did a measurement of
the Android kernel and it's this so you
kind of know something about how
trustworthy that key might be so you put
the public key in you know and in in the
end reviews case you can the Android app
can tell it the server or something
about how the keys are stored I've seen
public keys embedded almost or a CSR
being embedded in the token as a way to
set up a key key agreement or provision
keys for IMT use cases or what's a DTLS
so that's an in this category as well
and phyto in a way is in this category
for the phyto registration step where
Afeni Kate the user and then you
generate a key pair for the combination
of the device the user and the relying
party and then you set you a test that
key and send it to the relying party so
so public key and maybe even CSRs I mean
this is gonna start tuning in towards
Acme and some other things to I which I
don't know very much about but so that's
another area and then the final area sub
modules the nested claims so yeah you
can imagine you can start with a chip
that's in a module a module being a
circuit board it's designed to do some
particular thing that's integrated into
some sort of a box like you know ABS
system and anti-lock brake system in a
car that's integrated into a car so now
you got four layers of nesting what's
the attestation there do you use the
chip to attest to all the layers up or
or what so another thing is you you do
add a stations inside the inside trust
zone and it can attest to trust adapts
to the Android kernel to Android apps so
the that's all how you dealt with with
modules and sub-modules and it really
gets into device architecture so that's
it seems like the hardest one and the
one I struggled with the most how am i
doing on time yeah okay okay so I think
next slide so I want to just show a
couple of claims that some of the
details
a couple of claims that were defined in
eight knots that's I think very
straightforward yeah so so Universal
entity ID so this is one we've spent a
very bit of time trying to define it's
like a serial number it you know
identifies an individual device chip a
box if you've got
chips you've got a million different
idea IDs so not a model number not a
device class like that um so that this
point here then that it's Universal and
universally and globally unique across
all devices from all manufacturers
that's really the key characteristic
here we didn't want to didn't want it to
be qualified in any way so that a
relying party receiving one of those
things no matter what kind of device
where it came from what manufacturer can
trusted this thing is truly globally
unique and they don't have to do any
extra work in their database to say okay
yeah these are these unique ideas are
from Samsung and those are from I don't
know Ford and those are from Infineon
the chip vendor they don't have to
qualify any of those so there was a
design attempt here to try to do that
it's a couple different types one based
on just a gue at a large random number
another based on I Triple E EUI which is
basically a MAC address and then IMEI
which is common in the mobile phone so
I'm mostly giving this as an example of
how some of the thinking is around claim
definition I mean I think this one is
fairly complete and but I'm sure we'll
have lots of discussion about it so
question about this one or yes this one
specifically um is there the story this
is Brendon Morin is there something that
was missing out of RFC for one to two
I'm sorry what RFC for one to two a
system for creating universally unique
IDs I I haven't looked at that so I
don't know okay I just was wondering if
there was something that wasn't covered
in it
maybe we should just reference that one
too - yeah okay thank you alright next
like um and Kathleen Moriarty pretend
I'm over there I'm also just worrying
about the identify our type and privacy
implications because anytime you have an
identifier you have to worry about that
yeah absolutely yeah
alright so identifying an OEM so who
made the device today yeah could be the
maker of the the the chip circuit board
module some sort of finished product
even a larger aggregation right so the
proposal in the eat was to use I Triple
E oh you is because I Triple E does do a
global registry of companies basically
it's part of a MAC address there is some
entanglement with I Triple E because
gotta pay for for those so perhaps we
can use it gooood here as well
go ahead just for information
this is Brenda Martin again in suit we
are using or we are recommending RFC for
one to two GU IDs derived from the
vendors domain name okay okay sure so
next slide so this was a attempt that
are designed to describe the boot and
debug state of the entity creating the
claims so the first you know is secure
boot enabled basically that's a boolean
it seemed like that was enough at least
from our thinking in the te world and I
know some people say secure booty to
trust a boot and it means different
things and I'm sure but we can have some
discussion about that the the my intent
here though was and I think a lot of
that comes from the te world being
different from the TPM world where the
te world the end user cannot install
software on the device really kind of
locked that locked that down the OEM
power locks that down so and in some
ways it was simpler um so the main idea
here was it secure boot enabled that
means the software was authorized and by
the OEM and that's the only suffer right
and then debug state
really four different states here going
from a full permanent debug disable such
that not even though oh um can enable
reenable debug and this is thinking also
from a harbor point of view like arm
coresight hardware debugging hardware is
really powerful I can look at buses and
all sorts of things so disabling that is
it matters right and so permanent debug
disable is such that only the OEM could
and Riaan able debugging and that might
be an RMA situation where they're trying
to find out why that chip is failing and
then disabled since boot and then just
general yes I think so so that was
enough to just to give a flavor of some
of the way the claims are been thinking
about the claim so I'll stop there and
we can have discussion thanks Ned Smith
until so and thinking about the
information model I think there's
several options that we could think we
can consider there's some and I think
this is the heart of the hard problem
for information models essentially what
we see with the examples with TPM and
and keystore and so forth is an example
where you have a vendor or a standards
body who have gotten together and define
the information model already so TPM
attestation information model is done
and so we have some so this gives us
some some questions to ask ourselves you
know we want to move forward
should we have a situation we're going
to define a set of claims or assertions
that are essentially a mapping from a
semantic mapping from an information
model that already exists but isn't done
by this this this standards group so we
need to do some mapping from from one
error mission model to another
information model and potentially back
to another information model if you're
trying to get our complete semantic
interoperability or another choice is we
could say well let's not try and do the
mapping but let's just make it easy to
be able to convey
information that's represented in an
information model that's already defined
but more focus on the the the
interoperable representation but not on
the the semantics of the information
model right so this gives us so that
sort of points us in a direction of
focusing more on say what a manifest
rupture might look like to be able to
represent an information model that's
all ready to find somewhere else so
that's one that's one hard problem now
another problem to consider is well what
if somebody who is building a new system
and hasn't defined an information model
do that go to the IETF for help in
providing the building blocks for doing
that in which case we could define an
information model with a bunch of sort
of useful stuff but not try to pin it
down necessary to any particular you
know structure in terms of how the
system is put together what the various
components are what the nesting looks
like what the software pieces look like
but provide sort of just useful parts
and then define it in such a way that
the the sort of in designer of this
system could put those useful parts
together using just IETF to find stuff
so that's to to sort of important
questions that we should think about
when we are thinking about information
models garrymon um Qualcomm and just
want to give a partial response to that
I think you know I can say for instance
with the early versions of e we did the
exam and the TPM model I think I'm kind
of glad that we didn't bring in concepts
such as measured boot into this because
I think that we would have that
benefited more from actually getting
getting the group's opinion as to how
they could actually best fit into the
information model we're not necessarily
trying to supplant existing ecosystems I
think in this effort we would actually
try to get leverage that as part of the
overall information model that we come
up with in this group and I think even
in we would actually want to augment the
existing in the existing attestation
ecosystems to
I'll give an example with phyto Alliance
oh I mean we when you have TPM
attestation there but it was necessary
for that particularly for our particular
use case in defining the fight or two
that oh spec to actually augment it in
the form of a C or tight structure
around that was built around the TPM
attestation format so we could I could
envision you know for instance like a
location claim being used to augment a
TPM attestation in a similar fashion so
I think it is possible to meet the to
address your concerns if I understood
them correctly met Lawrence lund blade
so I think to talk to Nets point there
can you speak up louder please Laurie
yeah okay so - Annette's point there
some in some cases there's going to be
pre-existing things that are really easy
to reference I think the like position
location I believe there are already
thinks so that's that's is sort of a
slam-dunk and we should use that we
would be very silly and foolish not to
do that when to me that but to me that a
lot of the hard work and interesting
work here is to try to come up with an
information model that is universal and
and I'm really thinking about the
relying party here where the relying
parties are kind of all sorts of
different things you know they might be
a credit union or a bank or an IOT
backend or something but the the the
more we can come up with universal
claims that any relying party can pick
up and know what they are they don't
have to go read the you know the chipset
spec to know what this particular the
bit fields in this chip mean or you know
understand how you know this this
particular module vendor interprets this
particular field though the more we can
be universal of the claims the more
powerful and useful this isn't really so
I think that's kind of a critical
orientation that we should adopt here
I know it will be hard and I know in
some cases it'll be really hard in some
cases will fail and there will always be
the option for a vendor to put claims in
of whatever style and shape and size
they want to put in maybe you know we
have some my Anna registry for dealing
with all kinds of new new claims but I
would be I'm really very interested in
coming up with a standard set of
universal clients so just to make sure I
understand Lauren's you're speaking in
favor of creating and an information
model that puts a structure into which
new claims can be mapped to some
semantic interpretation and that is
platform agnostic is that I guess the
information well I'm a little unclear
sometimes what the term information
model means here but um I mean is my
suggestion here is we actually create a
list of standard claims 20 claims 30
claims something like that that we we in
this group say this is what this claim
means and if you receive this claim you
should be able to trust that that's what
that's what the vendor intended by that
and those those claims will be done in a
platform and vendor use case and
Industry agnostic way okay so to
regurgitated esting that the group work
on a set of claims that we put structure
and semantic meaning on as well as the
interfaces to allow for the
interoperability and then potentially
protocols to relay communication as in
transport or training yeah i mean i to
me the the claims are all bundled into a
token so
and sign so it's the the transport and
the method of securing the claim is sort
of orthogonal to the semantics of the
claim and so it's also kind of the
beauty of using chose a that you can
define the claim that for position
location and you can sign it with EC DAA
or you can sign out with a symmetric key
or however however you want to define
that in cozy but cosy but they are there
they're really orthogonal the method of
securing the claim and the method the
semantics of the claimants are thought
and also and that's why we've decoupled
if you look at the scope of work we
decoupled the information model from the
actual interfaces and right so coming
back to the information model you're
saying let's just define a set that have
a standard semantics meaning so that as
they get carried through the different
interfaces and protocols you can get
interoperability got it okay thank ya
exactly hi this is think I'm okay with
defining a lot of assertion slash claims
that's fine there were some other things
in your slide sets for example software
components you were calling them and I'm
not sure if you can define them VI
claimed it would be a huge value I mean
you can put a software that if I attack
and s evaluate to a claim or even
complete manifests then that value of
that claim would be gargantuan I'm not
sure if that is the intent of the claim
in CWT but but it's just discussable
also there is for example the integrity
measurement architecture today and every
linux system and they create
measurements from staging the like
secure boot and and I I'm not sure if
you want to put all of them in a single
claim or and it came said again that
would be Kirk entrance so some things I
think are variable to be defined as a
type in the information model but they I
don't think they were
being claims okay Hank I'm gonna speak
for Lawrence here
he had the categorizations and where he
had the sub-modules it's how do you nest
claims yeah so that's that's why I think
that said software modules I know I know
of these and and ima was not in there
and and and I think those might not be
claims they're an information type and
the information model there might be a
huge type of assertion but they are
probably enough claims Brendan Moore in
here and I just want to speak to the the
sort of interaction between software
composability and privacy and I think
that there is something there's a
fundamental assumption I've seen in the
slides
maybe it's covered elsewhere in the
documents I'm not sure but it seems to
assume that there is a single verifier
in the system and I'm not convinced just
just bear with me for a minute
and I'm not convinced that's true and
Hank tells me that it is in fact not
true so that's good but the there's
something else that goes along with this
which is that there may be a need for
ensuring the privacy of certain claims
with respect to a given verifier and the
privacy of other claims when sent to
another verifier so it looks to me like
there's actually going to be or need to
be some kind of structure to establish a
secure session if you will between each
of the sub components and it's
equivalent verifier how dishonest to
pick up on what Lauren said so I think
if we could spend some time in the
working group to discuss what the
semantics of the claim the sort of a
standard set of claims are that would be
very useful in my opinion and and I
don't want to go into the details of the
what the software component claimed us
but we are using that in a PSA now PSA
at the station token
and but we can change the name and we
can also change the semantics but
there's a there's an example for that in
terms of transport that's of course a
separate decision but it's mentioned
sort of there's some focus on a civil
web token because of its size maybe
others want to have a more JSON web
token but I think the number of formats
that will be then dumped into protocols
would be rather limited at least I hope
so
and they can be daeun carried as Gary
mentioned in in a couple of these
different protocols they already have
some containers ambition to where we
would put them so III see that that's a
rather straightforward process and
shouldn't be too complicated I don't I
the separation between information model
and then the serialization that's
something else looks like a great idea
and putting them in a separate document
like in separating it out conceptually I
think is useful but then moving it
necessarily out into separate documents
I'm not very honest mm-hm
we haven't gotten to is it one document
is it multiple but I hear your point
okay I'm gonna cut line off at med Dave
vault right so maybe one way of thinking
about the claims problem is not directly
trying to tackle a standardized set of
claims but instead to develop some
framing around how claims can be
standardized so you know what I'm
thinking is maybe an i an a registry of
claims so that within that namespace it
can be partitioned so that you know
vendors can have their space for claims
that we could have you know standards
track claims that may represent that you
know that standardized set really
getting at sort of the structure around
how to define a claim maybe that would
be the information model and then and
then instances of those claims could
then be expressed in a data model and
and exchanged as an idea yep that's a
valid point
so as to what is a claim and what is not
a claim the way I was thinking about it
was basically any sort of member of the
token is a claim even if it's huge and
complicated it's a claim and big
complicated nested claims you know a
claim with substructure with arrays and
maps and as a part of it it's still a
claim and so it may be ugly and you may
not want to call it a claim or something
but I would still call it a claim um and
I just also point out like the the the
Sisko knowing good values thing for
describing software components is really
simple I think it's just a name and two
hashes so that seems useful so that's
and the the definition of a software
component that PSA took is I think has
five different fields per software
component so there are examples of
software components claims that are
reasonable I don't know if we come up
with something Universal that may be
difficult but anyway that was just to
the point that a you know anything
that's part of the token is a claim
that's that was the way I was thinking
on that Smith until I want to throw out
another what I think is a hard problem
this has to do with with the sort of the
starting point for the data structure
that were that were relying on for
interoperability and I think of this as
a manifest as the starting point however
in the TOC bind draft the starting point
is is the TLS message of some sort and
if you look around in other places
there'll be other there are other
assumptions like the assumption might be
that it's a it's a cozy structure is the
starting point if we look at with the
kiss within an IETF there's several
different manifest structures out there
to choose from okay sorry so if there
are if we look around just for manifest
structures there's several different
manifest ruptures in different working
groups within the IETF alone
and so there's some question of you know
can you mannequin you can you nest
manifest structures I think that's being
done already in suit so some that are
you suggesting that we this this
creature is nesting already in manifests
there's there's nesting semantics and
manifests already and but this group
needs to have an opinion on where is the
starting point okay so you're not
suggesting that the manifests that for
example that we work towards manifests
because that would be rolling a tight
dependency I would think what's you I
might be suggesting that it seems that
if as we have some of these discussions
about about nesting of claims what I
think what's really going on is we're
saying there's that we have to be able
to describe the complexity and richness
of of things and so those things are
combinations of hardware and software
and whatever and they tend to be you
know complex are nested and and so forth
and so we have to have structures that
can deal with that complexity and I
think that that the complexity that we
see in manifests exists because they're
trying to replicate you know that what's
really out there I don't think that we
get away from that just very easily and
I also think that within that that the
that the the the context of where you
are in the particular in the system
where in the component is where the
claims are relevant so for example you
might have a system with a te that has
some strong security assertions but if
the claim was associated with the
platform surrounding the te then it
would be a it would be a security
mistake if the verifier assumed that
that property applied to the entire
since 30:19 not the te ok ok ok so i had
cut the line
so can you be quick is it a quick
comment yeah so it does I I was just
thinking that whether RFC 8 2 to 5 will
be applicable here because there is an
eye on a register and pass
is actually defining that and lot of
nested claims are actually defined there
so and also an eye on a registry is
created based on the different claims so
I don't know that RFC 8 2 to 5 will be
applicable there yet another thing that
we need to review ok so we've got five
minutes left so I want to discuss next
steps forward so just for interest can
let me get the list yeah yeah can I get
a show of hands how many people have
read the eat draft well actually a fair
number okay how many people have read
the token bind draft oh my hmm
how many people have read the
interaction model draft it's the same
people - a couple okay what about the
yang module draft okay a little less and
the Tudor draft
oh and less still okay so there was some
discussion about having potentially use
the eat draft as a starting point as
information model and an example of how
you carry that using CWT so in the
interest of time I don't think I have
okay she says I have a couple minutes so
can I can I have a show of hands cuz I
can't hear anything with the fan um can
I have a show of hands if there's
interest to have that draft be adopted
as the starting point for the eat draft
as the starting point
for information model and potentially
example of the data model can I have a
show of hands please okay we I get eight
how many did you get sorry I missed them
up here
I still get nine we can't see and we
can't hear this is a bad location I can
say that the mic - so it's recorded who
would be against the EEP draft as a
starting point
show of hands
okay very good so we can take this to
the list to confirm sorry after if you
have to ask a question and we were
talking about an information model draft
that is not on this list because it
doesn't exist yet right we can't adopt
it and so the question if you would be
willing to adopt the eat draft as
information slash examples two minutes
French Iron III I'm not against it
that's a starting point but I mean that
I I'm not sure whether that specifically
use case based solution yeah well a
general wants to prepare an older
solution or the information model may I
suggest
that we as the chairs will post it to
the mail list to confirm and so you guys
should voice concerns and opinions
because if there is enough negative
there then we won't adopt it how's that
okay okay
similarly there were quite a few shows
of hands on the token buying draft but
that's more of a data model so without
an information model I don't know oh
sorry it's a virtual Friday for me so
how about are there any objections to
adopt the token bind as a protocol
binding starting point any objections
going once going twice okay well confirm
that in the list as well okay last
question if they read it it's different
and they support it but so reading is -
I think it's it's useful just to get a
show of hands if you support it sorry at
this point I don't remember how what was
the number about how many people read
the token binding draft was that but no
the number there was a lot yeah yes it
was a lot actually it was more than 12
I'm just nitpicking so there okay I
think it's worth asking who supports
adoption
raise your hands please who supports
adoption if your hands raised no that
doesn't out I think we need a get to the
list and honestly at the interest of
time I mean we're over time and I'm
concerned we're trying to really
compress these kind of adoption calls
okay defer we don't have time but I'll
give you the heads-up we're gonna see if
there is enough interest I think we
really should have an interim so I will
put that to the list and hopefully we
can do something in the April mid end it
end of April timeframe and blue sheets
could you please bring up the blue
sheets and sign them if you have not yet
thank you all thank you everyone
blue sheets up here where's the second
one did everybody sign the blue sheet
no need