all the objects
goodnight
we're citizens are not taking jabber
someone would volunteer
you know taking ups
my mother very much
first breath is enough Americans it's
absolutely worthless
oops
guys and enough takers Sunday would you
take notes
would you take notes
thank you so good morning everybody
welcome to Prague and we're about to
start
RIF meeting they give one up for well so
please read not well if you haven't
before and we're about to start okay so
very quick update on the working group
status and plan we have the base
protocol settled Toni will provide
detail update so in this session we also
have two interoperating implementations
except that security envelope in the
post implementations and except some
teachers in the open source
implementation again a detailed actually
what we provide later so our plan and
ongoing activities are that by now for
the best protocol basically into a
soaking time mode we plan to issue the
last organ group last call at the next
idea we're already a requested security
idea early review and we are looking for
reviewers for the protocol and
specification itself the core team has
been working diligently on this all the
time we do want to get reviewers from
outside the core team so that we have
actual scrutinize ation on this
particles discussions are ongoing we
will have a presentation on that as well
today young mother working is ongoing we
are still looking for volunteers working
on the applicability statement and
threat analysis documents those other
the milestones already set for this
group when he was shattered there are
other work that like a party together
prefixes and SI extensions we have
drats that's got splitted out of the
base spec we have not really had not
started serious work on those yet those
working on get started once we settle
the the base protocol so the protocol
spec itself has been promising really
nicely young model hasn't really need to
catch up on the latest development in
the protocol spec to have young model
matching it so I'm looking at authors
please make sure datum Ellison sync with
the protocol itself yes now as the cause
of rift you know we have tried to keep
the consistence with the protocol draft
and we need a more implementation and
the verifying for it yes absolutely
thank you I'm going
I'll order if I'm not just being a pain
about the process the threat analysis we
had agreed that it would go from
relegation with the protocol aspect
sorry we had agreement of the charter of
the threat analysis would go for
publication with the burgle spec so just
to reinforce what you said please you
know let's work on that if we're going
to last call the spec by the next night
yeah if we need to really get working on
the other stuff certain we also
requested the early review from security
to get first set of inputs
blue sheets please sign them so we have
a slight update on the agenda Gregg
muskies PFT presentation it was already
scheduled at the very end by we're going
to put forward after Tony's provides
update on the base protocol
specification Tony young
you should work sure okay morning Oh
starts to look like the only OSPF worker
of meetings just act like the crowd I'm
slightly under the weather so don't
expect my usual you know witness chairs
are closed as well I downloaded earlier
but I some I'm having trouble find it
now haha sorry so Bruno is hanging out
somewhere in Argentina having fun
refused to come and give you no show his
struts just test very good all right so
we published Oh for like a clock what
happened in very rough terms yeah three
bump to for pretty much the whole spec
is done lots of open-source code has
been written we interrupt the staff on a
regular basis Bruno's framework allows
basically to plug any kind of
implementation there was talk of some 30
implementation but you know talk is
cheap code this heart and we had this
once or sometimes twice a week these
meetings and zoom it works like a charm
it just push record and for like an hour
hour and a half it just share stuff and
toss stuff extremely productive normally
three four maybe five people some
providers come in just to listen and
like three people are cranking the stuff
the whole aspect is on get so you know
all the people can go and modify the
stuff basically action items are taken
at the end of the meeting and then
people too can work on the gate election
verge it's extremely productive model I
mean if you can go and tackle a problem
like that in ITF I think all right so
see all green very good so last time
about the third was still yellow there's
this little outlier little tail hanging
off which is orange on purpose because
there are some excellent multicast ideas
being taught
around we went through a couple of
iterations it looked a bit like a pimp
idea but we realized that to build pimp
ideas kind of beside the point if I'd
you can run pimp ideas as overlay but
the ideas that are being tossed around
now actually quite novel revolutionary I
think Pascal has a press all and we'll
walk you through some of the thinking I
one hard problem remains unresolved by
my gut feeling will resolve that and
then we see whether the multik has
become part of rift but it will not be
part of the base back I think even the
timelines until something changes and I
talk very quickly about why that is not
a problem
alright so rough statistic just to give
you an idea again you know how much work
is being done so we have this core
contributor list
somehow it evolved that way I don't know
why we don't do it on the rift list but
you know that's the chairs so we have
hundreds of threats right flying around
we have on the open source version about
three hundred eighty commits so if
anything is really accelerated we have
two hundred five no between the last
eight years and one oh I'm sorry we're
just real quick why don't you do this on
the idea of mailing list I don't know
just a loud way can you please do that
look my monkeys I'm happy stuffs
progressing you don't have a problem
right you don't have a problem with the
discussions about the protocol happening
on the mailing list for the working
group the the decor design team
basically they it's a they have their
they have but their daily weekly
discussions just happened is on the own
that it's actually not a not a mini list
it's just the people just use the
nothing nefarious about that memberships
okay because people pick me at them and
they mostly fall off
don't ask me but you saw I mean on the
weekly basis recording the synopsis
so that's where everything happens
anyway I don't know I mean perfectly
happy I'm just saying already it would
be nice
the ATF process is open there is etc you
know if I look at the list there's
nothing right yeah there's very little
because everything is going on this you
know this and it's not even a list it's
justice everybody copies everybody
that's pretty much you know I I don't
have a problem in the future I want to
avoid problems when you go to the ASG
and we look at the list and there's
nothing and you know be nice if there
was some discussion there that's all you
know I can copy/paste this stuff well I
have some kind of a folder and I post
this couple hundred things on the email
and we can always do that that's a big
deal so like I said we had about twice
the volume of you know of commits on the
open-source bunch you know if people
started to contribute lots of stuff
started to get poured pulled in if you
also see the size of the patch which is
you know a very rough indicative when
you run just did from last ITF to this
you know what is the diff coming out
it's you know like 25k lines of code the
last time was about 16 K I expect this
stuff to trail off significantly now
yeah I mean most of the spec has been
done also in open source but what you
see is that the spec slowed down
significantly right so we have like 5 K
diff lines compared to like 7 K deep
lines and last time we had seven
Mobile's change on the protocol you know
encoding at the models and now we have
three is it's really like drilling off
of course no millions of ideas
laughter dynamics right extremely open
stuff is being tossed lots of stuff is
being scrapped the very good dynamics be
kind of a pity when it starts to wind
down but that's the weapon no way of the
world so what changed now what did we do
to actually make everything green so
there was a lot of discussion on the
security envelope and it led all the way
to secure it the models and you know
talking to a bunch of people actually
running fabrics what security models
looked what would you what do you desire
not what can you have today if like what
would you desire so we have kind of a
security model for the fabrics and you
can basically go up down and scale and
trade-off out of that the security
envelope went through a couple of
iterations because we had to accommodate
those security models and my ambition
was actually to address all the threats
that the ITP so they cannot address for
historical reasons I think we did a
decent job on that we move this we
shorten a lot of types include sequence
number arithmetic in that's kind of you
know minor but still you know something
that needs to be done and has to be done
carefully to not to break things some
link up abilities moved in we someone
probably just run no bias update over
the internet on the microphone or
something
so the flooding so we did a lot of
flooding scaling a lot of we talked
about the hackathon monkey testing and
one corner casey marched on i don't
remember so we actually i think we have
to flooding now completely in place and
we highly confident that this stuff
works which is like in autumn the main
engine right clarification or flood
reduction because bruno implemented frog
reduction zone here of course asked a
lot of stuff and when this stuff was
going on more discussions happened and
pascal i think started to talk more in
depth about the in caste problem which
explains a falling in caste which
already had a solution but in explain
why this in the spec so when they asked
the question we started to tear the
problem apart alright so the security
came over nicely misaligned so i think
this is this is quite quintessential and
down brought most of the staff and there
was some point all right I can oh yeah
cool all right so yeah I can't like
really a pointer so so we what we
realize that there is like the
convenience of zero touch provisioning
it's actually
a counter force to security right so if
you really want to run a zero
configuration fabric you really don't
get much of a security at all because
anything can plug in and just work with
it and when you move up the scale you
you know you can start to start to fix
things to make sure that it doesn't show
up in funky places so you can say ok
this is your land or don't show up in
any other place but then you can go to
something that you call the fabric
association model which is a funky word
for everybody has the same key right
shared key and even if you have the
share key on the fabric you cannot you
out the fabric so well that's kind of
intuitive then we move to something
which we called north association model
which is basically in our
everybody has to verify the guy he's
talking to and you thought that state of
it but actually it's not date of it
there's a far more interesting case
which we call the port Association
Marvel so if I bring up a node and I
have a lot of neighbors north or south I
could just take any of my ports and just
plug it on the correct structure and it
would work but certain people are very
concerned that a correct port is plugged
into the correct port on the other node
so that kind of corresponds to a keep
error on each interface all right so
that of course becomes more and more
provisioning intensive and integrity of
the fabric goes up all right
whereas if you go down it becomes more
more convenient and zero configuration
you know there's literally no rift
configuration everything just comes up
when you plug it in or you know when
it's miss Moorea it doesn't come up all
right so when we looked at so there is
actually already a section which is kind
of a threat analysis in Reverse we
basically describe all the attacks and
how they are mitigated so maybe that can
be just ripped out and didn't a new
clothes of the necessary and no threat
and now it is draft and what we do more
above the traditional routing protocols
is that
we protect a lifetime and I talked about
the stuff which was kind of the last
threat which is open and iGPS I think
you know we published something Ania
sighs but those are more like band-aids
you know making it harder to attack but
not really preventing the attack
we have nonce exchanges adjacencies
which basically prevents any kind of
replay attacks all right when you read
the spec we have been very pragmatic how
we go about the nonsense so we live open
a window otherwise you have basically to
sign every single packet it's just you
know the load is is excessive we do not
encrypt so we see what a tease come back
from we do not consider that contingency
allottee is a desirable you know
property of a routing solution and the
cost is you know very high
we provide origin integrity which means
that if people inject something the
network they can only do it if they have
the correct private key and we do
provide the integrity of the adjacency
but that does not mean that we'll be
able to trust of chain of trust
those are subtle differences I'm sure
the security areas will have discussions
with that so you could pass something
which is origin integrity through
adjacency which is not protected and
then put it into protected adjacency
which means that you did don't have a
chain of trust right that we cannot
guarantee and we can talk why this is
not necessarily desirable because
operational it's basically on deploying
all right so we do not provide
contingent of confidentiality and we
don't provide a chain of trust all right
so now of course we do the you know the
usual
hasta packet all right so what a couple
of things now went into this envelope I
was kind of bent against the envelope
thing I wanted everything that just
being tomorrow but that does not work
for other practical purposes and the
envelope kind of takes stuff out that
cannot really be modelled that is the
kernel of how protocols worked
is not very amenable to modeling and I
walked it quickly through it's kind of
interesting so we stuck with magic just
because we have some bytes left it's
kind of cool because then the silicon
can look into it right because right now
we run on UDP any kind of torque
if you you know want to build silicon
that knows this is rift give it priority
whatever snoop the stuff there's no way
you can do that so what we stuck in is
basically a rift magic behind the UDP
and that gives you a good chance that
your intention gratest
right we didn't have a better idea
behind that we have something which is
kind of novel for adding protocols we
put in a packet number which is an
optional thing you rev up on every
packet art that you're sending and that
allows for very nice debug ability
because you know when you're losing or
when you miss ordering and you can
actu'ly that in different ways all right
so that is not protected but there are
no really we couldn't imagine any
meaningful attack it's optional and if
someone gives you this indication it's
kind of nice to have makes for a nice
debug ability you know a lot of stuff
that came out from talking to operators
like for example we sent on adjacencies
all the names of all the ports and
everything people laughter because today
when they miss block that they have a
hard time to figure out who is on the
other side right
whereas this thing worth to
automatically you see who is on the
other side right deploy it in the name
and then we have an outer key envelope
and Iraq al key key envelope carries the
major version which is very important
because that tells you can I even
decode the model when you bump up the
major version you're not running to your
EIN 3 which means if you - you cannot
decode the model that is very important
otherwise basically you try to decode
you this you realize just breaks down
you have no idea what's happening
corrupt packet something we have an
outer key ID which is basically a local
key on the interface so that way I can I
can do the interface integrity right we
can both agree and roll over the keys on
the interface then you have a finger
print length which is basically the
fingerprint and from there everything is
fingerprinted below the fingerprint you
have two things that you need to protect
and
and the remote nonce the border nonsense
if people are not security aware does
such as random numbers that people bump
up regularly every couple of seconds on
both sides and that prevents replay
attacks how because this fingerprint
protects the whole thing so if you give
me a nonce which is too far from my
local nonce or I saw your remote nonce
and I now I see the package where you
send a remote nonce which is too far
from what you gave us or remote knowns I
know that someone's trying to play to do
a replay attack and those noises don't
have to be particularly big because it's
always the combination of both sides so
that's for all practical purposes closes
any attack window down to like few
seconds and if you try to record those
things you have to wait for the right
combination record it and then you have
a very short window because someone will
bump up the knowns right which you
cannot replay that has been done before
in things like secure pnni and so on but
it's not that well-known United especial
and the routing protocol so that's you
know we put the whole thing and then we
also have to remain in lifetime which is
protected so that's kind of the new
stuff but it's taken out the mobile the
model sits all the way in the back and
there is a reason for that so when you
push it over an adjacency you can change
the lifetime of the tie very very
quickly very easily without mucking
around with this you realize model
object actually you should note mock
with the object and I'll tell you why in
a sec and then what we have is an inner
key idea which is really origin
validation why it is bigger because this
has to be agreed on the fabric right I
have to know that this guy send it but I
have to know which key is it uniquely on
the whole fabric actually from the inner
key ID I know who sent it who originated
it sorry
right so that's the originator ID
innocence and fingerprint land and that
fingerprints the model object which
means when I'm originating I'm taking
this key that everybody knows on the ID
and I fingerprint the serialize object
now
thus you realized object is now being
carried around as a binary blob so why
because we did also some work to
understand how we extend this protocol
right so how do you extend these models
this these schemas and we found that if
you run an object through a third
deesser you may very well this you
realize something's reach you realize
the day in after changing and you may
may end up with semantically the same
thing but a complete different binary
object because your serialize err just
encodes things differently which means
that you would lose the origin
validation right so if I receive that
stuff this you realize it's change the
lifetime Rhys you realize I lost origin
validation because I cannot fingerprint
it I don't have to originate or key that
also is very very good for so it gives
us backwards compatibility people can
stick optional elements and if i DC
realize and I cannot DC realize it you
I'm still running that through basically
equivalent to ISI is unknown TLD model
plus it's very good for speed right
because I don't have to reseal realize
every time sending out lifetime changes
and so on all right
Ling capabilities basically what we
realize you have to announcer that the
other side supports PFD because you have
to know whether it be of these suppose I
should to come up or not we kind of
missed that we were exchanging
discriminators then we realize like what
does it mean should we send an unknown
discriminators or we just put the link
capability saying I run the FTO I don't
and you know with the assumption then
there will be thing added in the future
to it all right so flooding rules yeah
open-source implementers ask a lot of
questions the one thing that was not
very well specified is when you flirt
and you have lifetimes
you don't look precisely at the
lifetimes right because there's a
transmission time there's some queuing
delay so if you become too hung up on
the life times you will always say oh
those are not the two different the ties
always different because the lifetime is
mention is match
so there's always this Fajr factor you
say like if these lifetimes are pretty
close to each other
it's the same time that's his usual IGP
stuff though he had to spec out a
constant I think there was another
constant or Bruna's questions we hit the
last case of flooding inconsistency
which was kind of interesting in the
sense that you needed to have three
levels on top of each other and you
needed the right sequence of reboots
though you have to reboot those notes in
certain sequences and you also need that
a specific property of the initial
sequence number that was originated
because sequence numbers return start
from zero one we actually fetched them
for a lot of reasons so we start from
something from the range and it had to
start from a lower range than the last
range and so long you can read that up
it's explained but it was kind of cute
and it's a in a sense it's a property of
rift because we only flood north right
another protocol could flood south but
we don't flood South down so if
something flooded north is newer that
the stuff that comes up there is no way
to flat down again the fix is actually
not very hard but you know it was it was
interesting it behaves very very
differently from this traditional
protocol there was a cosmetic change
which already come from kind of like
playing people playing doing weird stuff
with it is that if you have z TP z TP
the strange stuff before it really
settles and looks like the thing that is
supposed to move because people it's
completely unsynchronized protocol right
so you may end up having server thinking
there are roots or whatever or you know
tours coming under the servers because
they didn't see the root yet and so on
and when the flocking kicks in it's
misdirected because people were actually
ultimately know things ourselves or
they're being flooded the information
where they're not supposed to have so
when everything settles you know it's
hard to cause it of course I mean know
this stuff was like monkey testing
interrupt stuff doing weird things
jumping up and down on the bed
but we saw cases where there's useless
information right because the SPF and so
on were disregarded but you still stuck
up with some stuff that looks why is it
here so the fix was also relatively
simple we basically
that that when you change your level on
gtp you just have to flush out all the
other ties and works like a charm but
it's also no unusual all right so that's
kind of flowing I think it's all right
now ah not that will definitely not work
can you give me the PowerPoint because I
need those pictures
I only have the PDF I sent you a
PowerPoint yesterday so we need to pull
that up because that's kind of no
interesting and meaningful discussion
how we doing on time we good I already
over round yeah yeah I only like five
minutes plus yeah I'm kind of know
slowly winding down well I don't have to
next slide yeah okay what did I write
the stuff down I still had something to
say
no I talked about extensibility and we
actually wrote code with a Bruno over a
couple of languages couple of utilizing
this realized to make sure that we can
actually move in practical sense we can
move the protocol forward with optional
schema elements and everything will work
and also can flooded through people who
don't understand it the decoders will
not hang up you know this kind of stuff
but I think I talk to other stuff all
right all right so that will be
interesting discussions once they
managed to pull up the PowerPoint and
there's a slower stuff so packet
numbering I talked about that stuff so
we actually have this and we also have
throttling from the other side so I can
for example see that if the guy throws
to start with me and I see a lot of Miss
ordering and losses I can squelch on the
guy on the lie saying like you're
sending too fast throttle and that
allows pretty much the flooding rates to
be adaptive and basically always run
with the maximum you know flooding rate
so the flooding rates are on rift or you
know like orders an orders of magnitudes
better than any other protocol right now
pipe tightening so we may types much
smaller like sequence number peckin
affected numbers like no loans is where
64-bit was used last and we also had to
fit them in a security envelope and also
that's where we did to work with the
sequence number all overstaffed
arithmetic I put there Atlantic in the
draft and so on and we also advertise
unsolicited optional downstream label on
the lies so it's basically you get
in a sense you get to LDP for free okay
because people asked for it I know how
they use it and that's it they're only
there in cast discussion is still open
and that was already in a draft but
again you know I just cryptically roll
down do this don't ask but then of
course Bruno and Pascal asked so I
explained and I put explanation the
draft why it is you know cool and
necessary especially cool
so this thing doesn't work on me so you
have to stroke you have to score me
forward please yeah just I just need
these two pictures one thing yeah
[Music]
fantastic all the tools we have and
everything is broken
[Music]
for yet an eligible picture now you have
no picture you pick otherwise I pull up
my laptop and we hook it up you want to
do that oh no you have only this thing
ok the times of the overhead projectors
weren't all that bad after all no all
right so I try to give you like you know
a story which of course won't work is
too complex so I had one picture to
explain again how flood reduction in
rift works which is kind of a pass cause
idea which is you know an interesting
bastardization of the way Manette was
working so every note from below is
basically picking enough notes above it
to make sure that you get you know
double coverage of people even one layer
higher and that's all recursive and it's
also load balances because each of the
southbound nodes can pick up a different
set of what we call for our repeaters
right I think you can follow that I just
take all these people above me and I
look for enough random people to make
sure that people above them everybody
gets two copies but not more because
that's where all the flat overhead
starts so that both reduces and balances
and for actually five level fault it's
close it's arguably also optimal when
you go higher it you get you do a little
bit too much but it's still I mean
ridiculous we're talking extremely good
numbers but now an interesting problem
starts when you reboot the node because
you start to advertise that you have
nothing so everybody tries to give you
everything because don't forget know if
everybody still holds everything it is
just they don't repeat to a level ah but
if the level up reboots then everybody
will try to give them the stuff right
and
you could say oh yeah okay so if you
have flood reducer if you know the flood
leader for this type of information
don't propagate it but it's kind of
fragile when start reboots so the Incas
reduction works like that the first time
I see a description and it would force
me to send the information but I'm not
flood leader I suppress it the second
time I send it so it has a lot of
positive stabilization properties right
which means that on the coming up you
get an Incas reduction you have all
these people spread and the information
is only repeated twice each type of
information from different nodes but if
you're in any kind of transients and you
re request the stuff the whole thing
will stabilize because then people have
no choice but send you a copy which
means like this the flood leaders
somehow didn't do their job the whole
protocol would possibly positively self
stabilized then it's pretty much the
trick I don't even dare to ask who
followed that okay well you know there
I'm sure the picture problem will get
solved and you can look it up in
material on my two beautiful cryptic
sketches and then the stuff will make
sense all right otherwise you see me
after the session and we chatted on
paper the PowerPoint you see on indirect
where where the slides are not uploaded
if you open it from your PC and you
should be able to see the picture it's
just somehow that's on this Chromebook
[Music]
yeah not this no sniper at companies and
tools all right that's it
so Mike's empty any questions we good
there's none confused all right
[Music]
no questions means it went either
extremely well or extremely bad or all
the questions or comments people
implement it all ends too late Rex T
okay and thank you I appreciate their
consideration disability letting me
present it today
so it's called extended BFD often VFD
working group we refer to it as d 2.0 no
I'm not that ambitious but we'll see
where it leads
so what a motivation in discussions be
the working group and many ideas being
proposed and appear some of them were
accepted some deemed to be well yeah we
would like to do it but that's probably
not the way to do it it became clear
that BFD it was designed does great job
as was it was intended to do to monitor
and continuity between to be of these
systems and over many different network
layer encapsulations that we would like
to do something more and what to do it
what we would like probably to piggyback
some quality performance monitoring path
MTU discovery and quality I'll give this
session itself how stable it is because
the only thing that we know is when B of
this session fails so misses and packets
in a row and n is a parameter of detect
multiplier but we don't know if if the
technology poorer usually by default its
value 3 if we lose every other BD packet
so we're very close we're there a bad
situation on the edge
and we don't know about it so to extend
the beyond what it can does now is to
ensure backward compatibility and
extensibility for whatever features
possible that offers of this proposal
haven't thought about and okay you want
now or you want to hold it just we
didn't sink you know didn't get to sing
so just one question or it actually I
mean does that not overlap overlap with
warm very quickly okay first of all
clarification don't want to pump does
require control plane so this if
anything I can compare I will compare
probably to stamp which is only data
plane test packet format and procedure
enough yeah thanks that was what I look
for mmm-hmm so you have here the format
in a you know 64k view we have the same
original BFD control message as defined
by 58 eighty we have a guard work which
kind of you know our fraud off maybe
extra caution to detect whether it's
really extended BFD or something weird
and then followed by t of ease until
these can be contained sub chillies so
to me until they even probably might be
for some other reason another to be
inside the whole thing starts with the
capability negotiation and that's
insurance backward compatibility so how
the idea is that the if the control
message does have length field and
length field stays as defined by 58
eighty so it reflects the length of BFD
control message in IP encapsulation
total length field
reflects their length of extended be of
the tacit okay Tony has an opinion so
that's again in a discussion there are
some implementations that do look at IP
total length and expect it to be
reflective to only be FD control message
length plus header but some
implementations don't
so for implementations that don't make
this check that will work normally or
you basically get their implementation
that supports it so if there's a
classical 58 a b b of the implementation
it will not send final back because this
negotiation uses post sequence post
sequence is you send a control message
with a tor bit set and you expect that
acknowledgment if it's acceptable to you
appear that he sends the message with
the final bit set so if you receive with
the final bit set and you receive
extended packet with a ability
agreed-upon then you're set you can do
proceed with extended B of this session
if you don't receive final bit set after
your timer expires or you receive PFD
packet 58 a B without extension then
well you have to fall back to the
classical BFD that's it
question no aspirations to do jitter
jitter what jitter measurement or yeah
jitter quality just like you do delay
loss
we'll get to that because that's in
following us the first the first step we
need to determine capability okay we
need to determine whether we can use BFD
extended or we have to use B of D let's
call it classical but jitter you have to
do double marking so you also have to
negotiate it okay I'll get it so
basically I'm Sarah Tory in capability
negotiation so this capability is a
little bit ambiguous because I didn't
want to go into it we'll get to that
what how to measure loss and delay and
everything next slide so let's assume we
are conforming to extended B of these
implementations they agreed upon and we
want to do a performance measurement so
the performance measurement can be
realized in two ways one it could be
that extended packets will include okay
that's an old slides and it's a typo
it's not 6470 363 74 so my apologies
it's MPLS packet loss and delay
measurement so the idea is we we take
these messages that are already being
defined and implemented by many and we
insert them in the Tobs in a VFD packet
so that allows us to do direct or infirm
synthetic loss measurement and it allows
us to do delay measurement and use the
timestamp formats whether it's p TP or
ntp by sender and reflector
independently because there is explicit
indication of the timestamp format by
the side that feels it so yes we can
measure jitter and it can be measured
either one way putting extending B of D
with a performance measurement T of ease
in
control messages send in a synchronous
mode periodically or it can be used in
pro sequence as a echo request reply
because pro sequence will be followed by
the packet with a final bit sent by the
far end and again 63 74 supports
collection of four timers for counters
or combinations so basically you can do
either was measurement either delay
measurement or combined was delay
measurement so that's basically capture
of control message from 63 74 4 was
measurement this is for delay
measurement and this is when they
combine the only what we introduced is
just one word of type and length to be
included in extended BFD packet format
again there was an it there is interest
in doing path MTU monitoring might be
plan a path MTU discovery if you wish so
again use extra padding TLV and you can
operate it the way you want it and again
it's nice because you can do it either
as a false sequence echo request reply
right or you can use it one way too far
end and if you wish if MTU changes for
some reason or you like over a multi hop
BFD using so you have a convergence
underneath then if you're using in
conjunction with the s antonius mode
then your session will fail because
empty you change so your packet is too
big
then the far-end would not receive it
three messages in a row you have federal
detection again it could be used either
way as monitoring or as detection of the
failure next steps will be continuing
adding details because for direct mode
this extended BFD can be used to fetch
results from the far end because in one
way our measurements other measurement
results and calculated performance
metrics are still sitting at the far end
and there might be interest on fetching
them at the same time it will definitely
be interesting to do their yang model
because then this performance metrics
can be just exported for the yang
well discuss discuss discuss welcome
comment suggestion in cooperation
and if you want some entertainment then
I will be presenting this just 15
minutes from now I'd be of the working
group and I hope there will be more
discussion
so right now a specifically on the rift
which is extending discriminator
exchanging discriminator sorry nothing
else right musics and BFD kicks in I
mean there's no far information you know
yeah this excellent yeah especially like
this and cue things and so on which have
been piggybacked into the wrong
protocols for historic reasons if we do
that yeah you're absolutely right so
basically it doesn't need anything more
than discriminator
yeah and means it's very interesting
interesting for this IP fabric Fox
because know the jitter the delay the
stuff is this is very relevant for them
you know is discussion of that stuff on
the periodic pay you know before the
bring up the links on the periodic pays
is no monitoring the link quality and so
it's very important for them yeah okay
thank you and if you have any questions
comments please include BFD working
group mailing list
much appreciated thank you
see he wondered about open source up a
force field hackathon is good token is
good
all right so we had a hackathon on rift
this is not a participant and Brunel's
ensured me that when he took the
photograph of the gentleman the
gentleman signed away all his rights so
he has the waiver
I don't know if it was taken somewhere
in South America the brewery is some
interesting places I have the fun job to
take his material and present it I don't
even know what is on the neat thingy we
thought maybe a record a presentation or
something but you know experience has
been poor with remote presentation so we
just go with the standard deck okay we
did cows monkey testing on the protocol
first iterations I think that will be
the future of this august body if we
want to stay relevant we have to learn
how to do modeling and we have to learn
how to count monkey test modeling just
to ensure the quality of what we deliver
it on extremely short time scales
right I mean it's well known methodology
invented on 360s long forgotten and now
pretty common while we didn't catch on
yet all right so so was there that was
about four people and like three or four
hanger-ons who didn't write code so they
don't get to be mentioned so all these
guys were hacking code and what we were
doing we took the open-source
implementation that largely chucked out
we generated some configuration for what
bruno consider large I consider North
Valley smallish data center topology and
then we're end raised if you bought a
bunch of AWS instances and we just
started to bring the stuff up I
explained you know actually maybe the
other presentation explains how this
stuff is multi instantiated we basically
started with containers there okay
but so Bruno went to namespaces which
have lower scalability but it's very
very easy to break in on the Linux
kernel topologies up stripped together
and then when we brought the stuff up
which is jumping down a little bit on it
using random scripts and then we
basically started to look east the
protocol converged which actually on the
protocol of that complexity is not a
trivial thing to assure so no we ended
up in hackathon writing a lot of code
actually figuring out whether we got
what we expect there's a heck of an
instruction document any chance I can
install the staff there is like an
instruction video if you put out on
YouTube and so on so it's very very
accessible it's you know exceedingly
well documented so that comes all hard
from the scripts topologies generated
and what we do is each is router is
basically Python processors it runs its
own network namespace and we just
brought the points of ve th which like
virtual ethers and just wrap the stuff
together and no particular magic and
that's like one of those graphs is the
things generates the way we generate
those topologies is that there's a meta
configuration describing a fabric it's
the same so it doesn't allow you more
than like you know five fivefold its
claws or parts with uneven height it
will evolve that staff generates a
configuration for every router scripts
to start and stop because you have to be
able to log into different namespaces
and then generate scales monkey scripts
which shake stuff up and down and
generates also the check script right to
check actually to go out all these
things gather all this information
reconcile it and figure out yeah you
have that apology actually works right
and it does pinging back and forth and
these kind of things all right so like I
said we generate these Carroll script
that generates perturbation you know
like brings things up and down jumps up
and down we'll talk about all the way
the next things also right now link
failure is node failures so what we
observe you need direct link failures
will be interesting packet drops
reordering delays
and of course corrupting packets about
the problems just corrupting peckers
randomly shooting bytes doesn't buy you
anything much because the Peugeot will
not convert right it does the expect
that so you have to understand what the
variables mean a boundary condition
which you know like when you do the
Google chaos monkey testing and software
that is like oh methodology then you
repair all the breakage ease and you see
whether you know the protocol is an
expected state all right so that's one
of the sequences you start from the
state break clean kill something break
another lane bring something restored
like bah bah bah bah right green red
green red green at the end you have a
sequence of greens that fix everything
and you go ok did this thing survive are
we in a full colored state some example
kills wrong again documents videos all
exceedingly well documented in our stuff
breaks breaks breaks whatever fixes at
the end so the check script is actually
topology aware and it knows where to
look and I show what it looks at it
pings from every leaf to a relief with
interesting discussion people start of
course to play with it and they start to
ask question you recognize that riff
does doesn't do certain things or expect
certain deployment mode right there's
nothing like running code and in an
environment like that which you start to
understand what the hell's going on
right so we think from out leaves
whether all the notes data apologizes
you stayed up whether the northbound
default routes were in the rip and the
FIP and the kernel all right because
there is a local rip
then you get I broken on the fifth based
on the route preferences and then you
push it into the Linux kernel so you
have to verify the whole chain same
thing for the southbound
there's always more things in the future
so that's a some convergence around
where the check is being done right
checks all kind of consistencies and
does some pings and so on what helps
enormously with Bruno's code is that you
can generate this kind of SVG protocol
runs so you can basically slice out any
kind of protocol interaction put them on
SVG and you see all the packets
timed how to flying through the network
and you can flip things on/off and
reorder and whatever not so this is
actually if you truly want to understand
how the whole thing works this is a
fantastic educational tool alright so we
had we generated us topologies of the
Randalls topologies and local machines
and we did the curls monkey testing we
wrote code to know more and more
consistency checking because we were
looking manually for things what we
learned so a the open source
implementation had a couple of issues
with this thing shook out for example
ipv6 flooding issue where it is
absolutely valid for if to come up and
one side flats on the ipv4 lots an ipv6
if you're running both address family
and they had timing issues depending how
he was coming up they ended up on the
wrong socket or missing stuff of course
always the shutdown scenario and
exceptions when you break things stuff
starts you know to shake added multiple
show commands because you start to
inspect state if things doesn't go well
especially it doesn't go well with very
weird ways
the protocol spec we found nothing right
so they in in this sense that looks very
solid and that's the heck of them yeah I
don't think we want it but I wasn't even
there it was a zoo 350 people 30 minutes
presentation for two hours what you
expect you give people food and you
don't charge for it that's what will
happen right questions observations
nothing general apathy all right I take
the uppity resistance is futile anyway
right
so that's not a beautiful picture Bruna
took summer at the end of the world I
think it's Patagonia or something so
that's basically what happened on the
open source that's his update
so let me write all that down so usually
it's only github stuck around 102
hackathon so which is within basically
or at six months we had stayed where we
have you see how much is implemented
it's chucking along to become a complete
rift implementation issues I felt
originally with just a small subset
maybe just a server site it was very
successful in improving the
specification no discussion there right
and I could I give him that I would
consider that a reference rest
implementation absolutely I mean the
code is extremely good quality it is
completely geared toward someone to
understand and learn the protocol not
for high performance but for that as a
reference implementation beautiful and
again the emphasis is emphasis in being
user-friendly educational very
transparent very debuggable you can look
at the stuff very easily and not all
performance are understandable extensive
documentation and two completely
unencumbered but any kind of you know
roadblocks like IPR or any kind of
vendor you know nefarious influences it
always is good so how to get started
just one thing to get you bootstrapped
when you get into the github torus
installation start up everything just
nicely rattled up good so what was added
so Bruno added quite a significant
amount of stuff since last time
ipv6 adjacency so it supports fully the
ipv6 which he didn't believe and then
have a lot of fun learning how
bizarre ipv6 multicast works actually
until you get to stop working because
needed for the lies right especially if
you have leaned locals and they overlap
and whatever not so you send both IP v4
and v6 back that's taking a while to
understand how the spec is written right
and the order does not matter and how
the AFS come up does not matter and the
implication that if you support v6 you
can also throw it before I don't know
precisely what he means but the lie FSM
must be and is item 210 which means like
if you receive the same packet yeah you
don't do it state transition was somehow
important all right so here he missed
actually appoint the v6 rise imply that
the to notice V interlinked as v6
forwarding and if he for detour but you
can also forward v4 our v6 only and we
didn't go through all the complications
of trying to tear down address families
once you opt you up even if you stop
sending he'll also if you want to remove
an address family from a link you just
have to bounce it if people are highly
concerned which I cannot imagine in the
fabrics about that and you know we go an
extent aspect but this kind of things
are exceedingly complicated and then
what took him awhile was all of a sudden
to understand how the flooding well you
know just bounce into the stuff started
to read the spec and ask the questions
that you can either float on before or
v6 so you have to open sockets for both
and listens and when do you open the
socket you know like detailed
implementation stuff and you may end up
sending v4 flooding one way and e6
longing the other way and is perfectly
valid and that was what the counts
monkey caught him because no the stop
was coming random sequences breaking
coming up and we ended up in this a
symmetric configuration which respect is
perfectly valid so yeah so here it is
ITV salt all these sixes where is
dependent on the OS or assertion
distribution right magic options to make
the stuff work reformat occurs is much
easy
respect so he has everything right now
and this kind of cute things you start
to understand how or if two works right
so this is show interface circuits you
understand how many circuits you
actually have open an interface to
support all the stuff it could be less
we could receive and send on the same
circuits but he'd split it we had
discussions about this now it makes for
much easier logic on the protocol
implemented a flag reduction so the
example algorithm in the draft is
complex it's kind of like really cute
doing all kind of stuff the beauty of
the flower reduction rift is that
everybody can run a different algorithm
it's completely you know a synchronous
distributed algorithm that what makes it
so blazingly fast and stable so we
talked about the implications of he
really implemented the stuff that Pascal
put in with the fishy AIDS and a lot of
clarification questions you actually
know fix they are great notation couple
of prices it wasn't simply clear what
that means right and here's for example
to show flooding reduction and then is
way too small to read it it shows you
like the flood leaders and I don't know
what it's all showing I I think front
liters last election and what yeah I I
forgot it is too small to read he
implemented the whole SPF so all that
things in once you start to write code
right so he was asking questions there
as well so that shows you the SPF and
which destination fell out through which
system IDs next ups south and north
split and some stats actually this
former expenses that expensive stats
laters are way around you know SPF see
both directions and it's not really SPF
you can actually cover all the paths on
the fabric because loop free so he did
that then he implements the whole right
right because he didn't have a local
read because when you have the solder
out slope and routes external routes
coming in local
a lot of prefixes are all over the place
then you have to tiebreak for
preferences which specify their local
rep was implemented including dcmp and
then you have to show that things which
shows you an hour all the next starts
and where to stuff comes from from the
north and six routes which are here in C
and Pete over know multiple interfaces
and Flint locals so that's all working
and then of course so sorry so the rip
holds of course all their routes right
for the same prefix even you come from
north south external it holds it and
then it's tie tie breaks it into the
local fit which is just the best just
the BET's best right so you can go ahead
look at the show forwarding which is all
the typos and stuff ready to be pushed
into the kernel and then of course the
kernel rots so those you can also look
at the kernel routes that he pushed down
and this is raise it to the local fit
being pushed or being pushed down I
don't know so I didn't play with that
stuff extensively except you know like
collate it to make sure that the
convergence is correct and you also see
the waitstaff so the bandwidth balancing
is not implemented yet extensive
statistics work you to bring to face
note and gene you know because when you
start to implement SPF load balancing
you know a flood reduction all of a
sudden you're not just even
understanding what's going wrong without
stats is hard there's so much stuff
lying around so the stats give you you
know at this interface all over side and
you you retransmitted all the time your
packet right when to enter circ or your
packet right collapsed so you see four
different packet types you see all kind
of you know rates and when was the last
change that's all constants in framework
which I've already shown you okay so
those years a plugin
there's a proposal to implement the rift
in FL hi Alice woman net deaf yes we're
looking for folks who are interested in
collaborating with the FRR community on
a c implementation of this so anybody
wants to talk about this can contact me
directly after this meeting I'll be
hanging around or you can come along at
2 o'clock this afternoon to the FRR
meetup yeah yes I assume it's well known
water ferrari's like a the quagga for
that lots of people are running Bruno is
interesting fermented stuff in seeds or
there's you know they want to build the
community with the rift Python he pretty
much you know explored all the red holes
so it's kind of a straight port for high
performance stuff and of course then
that would allow to add the yang morals
and you know they look alike get people
engaged alright so the current status
summary the adjacencies are pretty much
done I don't know what's missing I have
to quickly look as ATP's done since a
while and that has proven extremely some
points they buggers were no surprises
what CDP accept is stale information and
there were no large fabrics heavy load
flooding I don't know what's missing
there route calculation is half done
because of probably of the bandwidth
balancing management interface to chain
I don't even know what it is but it's
basically there is what has been done
between the last and this one so
adjacencies I are clear
all right so v6 adjacency I talked about
the starboard is not completely security
envelope so we still have to implement
the security envelope and so Kate that's
why we are kind of holding back on the
last hole and then you know I didn't
consider the documents that are requests
that are a greeting to charcoal
need to be delivered we don't expect any
surprises much that has been discussed
very extensively and we worked a couple
of times zero touches done flooding all
right so the v6 running has been added
and the flood reduction is done so what
is not complete so the efficient type
propagation without the code
optimization positive desegregation so
that's the status as of two days ago
three days ago Bruno Motta has shown me
yesterday night and told me to say that
he is like freak water down with the
positivity segregation beauty of
symmetric wellspect protocols once you
crank code you can go really fast so he
already has all the positivity
segregation implies it isn't here of
course an interesting question where the
spec is has language of an Oracle so if
you implement you understand wine has to
be written that way but there's no
surprises negative disaggregation which
of course is a little bit of harder not
to choose I didn't say that we also on
the spec we have to update Pascal wrote
quite an extensive example session
section of the negativity segregation I
mean all seems to compute but still
needs to be implemented that's of course
only of interest for multiplying fabric
so you know either very low radix
fabrics or very large fabrics the key
value store external ties which of
course very helpful right if you
redistribute in the protocol policy
guarded prefixes are jobs optional yeah
a little bit did indeed overload bit
which is important and the clock
comparisons of as mobility a rat
calculation what's not done yet
east-west for worrying east-west links
positive he largely has done the fabric
bandwidth balance which is of course
interesting label binding is to roll and
the multicast is something that the sky
will talk about the optional extension
outside of the base back most likely
managed
no interest in implementing sshd li
client unless somebody really deploys
the started start to run production
comment completion yang data morals and
granule debugging in tracing i think
here so i'm just selling himself this
stuff trace is quite well and is very
easy to debunk especially like I say
hackathon for me and someone else who
wrote you know a good amount of code
like show commands and status statistic
have lots of stats have been added and
there that also the comment history to
the CLI I didn't even know there and
development chain so likes other person
code coverage she's like at eighty
something that bugs him and yeah there
is a there's a demand and this
correction quite interesting from people
already you know like blabbing and
playing with the staff together
Wireshark plugin which does not seem
like an excessively difficult project to
do except that somebody has so that is
interesting in the sense that you have
to put into Wireshark the model compiled
the model now they include the model but
beside that it looks like it adjuster by
a shark clogging and it's also one of
the reasons why the unit people to magic
it's kind of simpler to like what the
stuff you don't have to say a that's the
portal running where stop yeah I think
it's it I mentioned everything yeah
questions observations just to clarify
the other implementation does have
everything by the security alright so
the security envelop was just gelling it
went through a couple iterations all we
have two security envelope on in a
different version so that's pretty much
it yeah the poaching implementation
experience the way there to virtually
just to say that the proto
developments and design was accompanied
by the implementation stop answer yeah
right so it's old-style ago SPF you
don't have two independent limitation
and the
cannot hook them up and they work
flawlessly don't even show up orthogonal
to to standardize the stuff yes it was
very successful in this respect and
we're talking six months pretty much
from I expect publishing to shaking out
the spec wild implementation we're
progressing basically being interrupted
all the time so the monkey testing will
be not the interesting thing I would say
you know to understand how can you tell
your protocol spec which is modeled and
then somehow from the model understand
what you were supposed to shake to
actually maybe we need to analyze
annotate the models and maybe needs like
a meta model description like you shall
shake that and expect this I don't know
we were breaking ground in a certain
sense all exciting you do not share my
sense of elation it's okay all right
why should either you are Alistair do
you have any timelines for another
open-source implementation nor it since
landing sorry for our implementation do
you have any timelines our stored
Minette def responded to the chairs
question no we don't have any time nines
at the moment that's why we're asking
for folks to get involved see how many
people turned up what happens so thanks
[Music]
so next one is about the multicast me
and Pascal world between this
presentation I'll get it started and now
I'll hand it over to Pascal so the the
core design team while they were working
on the flooding reduction they realized
that a byproduct of the flooding
reduction is actually a Marcus Marcus or
even better a broadcast tree that you
can use to send traffic anywhere from
anywhere and so that and that does not
require any additional cygnus already
built in and so the one thought was that
that could be used for multicast Merkers
then we had more discussions and turns
out that well this is actually very
similar to the team by their concept in
that the track the traffic travels north
all the way and then along the way
they've worked them to the south to
reach the receivers so but further
considerations and discussions that was
thinking that we probably should still
use separate signaling for Marcus after
all so that we can have better load
balancing for elephant rolls and nice
flows because if you just used as a few
tree to send traffic anywhere everywhere
then it that works well for for for low
volume flow rate flows but if you have
we call elephant flows then it's not
good so the kind of thinking nothing has
been decided it's just a kind of
thinking is that some we would just
enhance an extent in bi-directional
concept and and use the native great
signaling to set up multicast trees so a
little bit of background up in
bi-directional in pimp either if you
need you want to receive a group market
traffic yoo-hoo
send started joins towards a rendezvous
point address that that address were
called our PA is either on a particular
router or it's just an address on a land
that is not bound to any router it could
be it's just a virtual address out there
and the link that hosts that our PA is
we call it called our P link or RPL it
could be a loopback interface a router
or could be a lying interface so the
started joins
what is that British sub trees that are
routed on the routers on the RPL and the
RPL the RP link will connect the sub
trees into a tree so when you when you
need to send traffic you the the first
hop router was send the traffic upstream
towards the RP a following in that sub
tree and eventually it will arrive at
RPI routers and along the way the
traffic ORS
so fork to downstream routers where you
have received the starchy joins one and
then for the traffic that arrived at RPI
routers they just flood travel to each
other if you if the dis language on the
line step on loopback interface if you
are a pizza on loopback interface then
you're the only are PR router there so
in LAN case they just fly to each other
that's fine it's a it's a lamb and and
then eaten at the IP router when they
receive the traffic on the land that are
PR you will just send the traffic back
down to two receivers on the saw on the
downstream side so if we were adopted at
that base for rate there is actually no
need for that
said RP a RP address anymore you just
because of the nice south-north topology
just simply send your joints upstream to
your north neighbors
well you just - Wow there your North's
neighbors you can do a hash to decide
which neighbor you should send to there
is one problem that there is no up here
in this case you could have several top
of the fabric or call talk table routers
at the top and they are not connected to
each other
mrs. cook another way of saying exactly
what you're saying is that the LPL is a
non broadcast not access network as
opposed to a broadcast network so you
have to undo those always think what
you're saying okay the RPL is done
broadcast 30 access right so the the so
how do we solve that is that that Pascal
we'll talk about that and then instead
of a starchy trees we actually star is
debby established by their channel star
she prefix trees that G protects can be
either a Qi host or a star to the tweak
streams so in a star star case it's a
it's a tree that can be useful for any
group if you if you don't care that the
traffic goes where there is actually no
receiver those can be used for mice
floats and then you can have starchy
host trees you can use that for elephant
floats then the traffic is sent on only
where there are actual receivers and in
the middle you have the starchy prefix
trees it can be useful because your
outflows or whatever flows basically the
flows that you can allow you to go
somewhere where there is no receiver but
it's not going anywhere so
this gives us very good flexibility
because you can start with a single star
star tree and if you know your your
traffic pattern is that you don't have
much you don't have any elephant close
you then you don't have need much stayed
you don't need much signaling you just
use a single star start a course in
traffic everywhere traffic
and first you can establish a few more
starchy prefixes for your uploads and
eventually if you realize that oh I have
one group or a hundred group or a
thousand group that where I have high
rates floats then what I will establish
those trees accordingly only when you
when you need it
so the joins in the p.m. butter here
will be down by the northbound pgps
parts the guided prefix pies is consumed
and merged and we originate every hop so
an instant but the PGP is normally sent
to all your neighbors down north
neighbors or South neighbors but here
when it's used for I established the
tree we were send it to just one of the
North's neighbors and that is chosen by
the Hessian down by the dancer a result
neighbor the hashing should have this
kept characteristics that you different
nodes should choose the same a stream
nodes but you do not cause the upstream
node 2 to have to replicate to many many
downstream notes so let's say you have
at one layer you have say you have an EU
a node that what's the word okay so
because the the
in the factory you have many many years
impe paths though it could be that some
or 128 knows at one layer could be
connected to the same or another 100 in
da nose in the next up layer so you want
to avoid that situation where the
upstream a North neighbor is central
taking 128 times to other downstream
neighbors so ideally you will be like
that some of the neighboring there's a
hatch to one upstream
some other downstream neighbors - yet
another upstream and and but eventually
they were converge at the top so that
way the replication is more efficient
and yet it's not too demanding for for
any node so that's with that those joins
with those we establish the sub trees
and we also established a corresponding
protein state and that holding state
include the interface list that in the
interface lists including the northbound
interface that is produced by the
Hessian and also southbound interface on
which a joint has been received from and
then traffic arriving on any of the
interfaces are forwarded out of a other
interface in the list the traffic
received on any other interfaces will be
will be dropped that's the way your
provenza looking so coming back to the
RPL problems we need to join that the
CSUN subtree rooted at the sub top note
and I will handle that - Pascal he is
the better person to explain this
thank you okay side first yet we are
here I just asked the chairs how much
time they gave me for this and they said
plenty plenty is good so I'm gonna use
plenty first thing is I will I will
paraphrase you somehow because doesn't
hurt saying things twice I assume now we
have illustration to just say what you
just said Jeffrey so so we started with
something we thought very simple as
Jeffrey said in his first slide what we
wanted to do is basically reuse the
topology that we built for the optimized
flooding and as you know this this
flooding as the property that there are
pretty much redundant paths between any
leaf and then it off so you forget
whatever is in the middle but between
any particular leaf and any particular
type of fabric node there is a redundant
way to get there so we thought a what if
we just send the multicast packets north
whatever there are to any type of spy
the top of fabric node and that
particular top of fabric node would
reflect the the packet over the
redundant path that reaches any leaf
that was the initial thought without
changing anything else as Jeffrey said
we thought we could achieve an efficient
multicast just using the fabric and the
state that exists in the fabric if you
wanted to filter by star G you would
just flood the star G information north
only through the flood repeaters which
would make it so that only the the
traffic to to to that particular group
would would flood through the repeaters
only if there is a leaf which is
actually listening for it I mean with
this simple assumption we were already
there we had a redundant way to
distribute the multicast traffic to
groups or to everybody if we wanted to
as a broadcast there were
two issues with that the first issue was
we had to make a different routing
decision for a packet going north and a
packet going south and that three what
probably killed work not killed because
everything is still on the table we have
not written the text yet but but the
reason why we are opting out of using
the optimized flooding topology is to
avoid having to make this different
decision if the packets coming from
south of the packet is going from north
right with this this pretty much is fast
mode like model that we had if you get a
packet from from south then you
propagate it north to any of the parents
north to enrich any of the turf which
will reflect itself so that that was one
behavior now if you get the packet from
the north then you would have to to pass
it down to everybody we elected you as
flood repeater so that's a different
behavior you would have to basically do
two different operations and depending
on the silicon etc to try that that
could hurt so we kind of did not prefer
this way the other problem you could
have with this design was the Fallen
Leaf prom if you have a particular leaf
which is not reachable by a particular
type of fabric node to fallen leaf by
definition then if the multi-cat packet
as it flows a randomly north reaches
that particular type of fabric and there
is a listener on the particular felony
for that type of a right note that
listener would not get the multicast
packet right it's the prime of the
felony so how to under that that was
that was also something which which made
the proposal which looked initially very
simple and efficient having to under
this kind of corner case would we
disaggregate or whatever else that kind
of looks painful and then on the side
there is this Miss optimization
versus by dear but as you know if you
have by dear
then when you propagate north you can at
each level you can start sending the
pack itself which means that you get
more efficient use of your fabric so we
kind of moved from that model on to
another model whereby we as Jeffrey said
again we be able to sub trees and the
sub trees are very dynamic that has the
nice property of the of the optimized
flooding which is any node at a certain
level say level zero in this slide say
not al for to pick an example can pick
any of the nodes above as his parent as
we build this tree that can amaze many
reasons why we rebuild a tree but you
can pick any of your parent and change
that over time doesn't mean you have to
reshuffle and deliver but in a network
it's an individual decision by every
node and four can pick them to at some
point of time it's basically beyond the
orange tree but five minutes later if he
decides to it can join em for and you
don't have to tell anybody above or do
anything so fancy at least as long as
you don't advertise subgroups but just
to be on trees it's a local an efficient
decision so we can offset a let's be do
sub trees which are rooted at the set up
at the subt of being what we define as
the level right below the top so we have
to define us that we are beasts which is
the sub tough and we build those trees
and we might decide to build different
trees that we would access for different
groups etc but I'm just describing what
we do for just one the first multi big
multi Kasturi so let's let's have any
node select one parent and that ends up
building a collection of non congruent
trees which are rooted at the cept off
just by individual decision of every
node of finding one on strictly one part
so the big prime with we have this that
now is to to interconnect those trees
into a bigger tree and now we are back
to the pin by their question of all this
big thing here
now this level I have illustrated with
this kind of circle becomes virtually
the FPL that's the link on which all the
small trees we discussed a whole rooted
but the interesting problem we have with
rift here is that this LPL is non
broadcast multi-access it's not a token
ring it's not an Ethernet it's not the
air you can't push a packet there from
you no packet coming from the south swim
one say the packet comes from there if
it was an Ethernet you would just
broadcast it and then every other n1
into it's rare for would get the packet
and be able to flood itself but that's
not the case it's non broadcast so we
have to under this network and again
make it so that if a packet comes from
any one is injected in this area it can
go out of and two and three and four and
five so what kind of structure do we put
in place to enable this NDMA air PL and
that's again a point that Geoffrey made
and I will paraphrase how can we make it
so that the tree is well balanced if the
tree is too fat like we pick the same
guy here to reflect to everybody then if
there are 100 nodes your this guy will
have to make 100 copies that that's a
very fat tree that's kind of efficient
in terms of how many hops a packet will
take but that's a lot of load for that
packet on that particular node on the
other hand if we make a very lean tree
like we could say Oh connect this guy in
a Z then a particular packet going it
being injected here would be echoed all
the way before I can reach this guy in
go down this tree so there is this this
prime of building a spanning structure
that that would enable the RPL operation
in a way that's balanced enough fat
enough but not too fat kind of so that
that's what we've we've been looking at
so I have represented I have to slice to
explain
this the final solution we are not there
yet but kind of the thinking where we
are and that's when you know inputs are
so so great so the thinking we have is
so let's be let's build this
non-broadcast multi-access RPL and there
is how we could do it because we want
like I said to balance the level of
fatness of the tree that we are building
between the sub turf at the top the idea
is basically to fold even tree we're
building elect a subset of those guys as
the the the level of the tree that will
be building to do this FBI thing and for
instance we could be again using a rush
and the rush would elect like the five
for the 10 best those nodes to be the
reflectors in that and VMA appear so in
my slide sure the rush has pretty much
determined that those two guys are the
best candidates s3 and s4 as the best
you know the best hash for whatever we
are doing so everybody will pick one of
those two as the reflector for them so
in this case and three and then five
parent 2 s 3 and n 4 4 instead as 4 and
so what we've done is we've extended the
sub trees all the way to the top now ok
so we still have non congruent trees but
instead of being rooted at the sub tough
they are rooted at the top and we have
kind of convert them in a way that it's
not distributed over all the tough it
was kind of distributed over all of a
set of but now we have kind of
constrained the number of tough nodes
which participate to this game and now
what we have to do is basically complete
the tree so that s3 can talk to as 4 so
that's kind of the second step that we
illustrate here and that's the piece
that requires an additional signaling we
have not found a way to do that without
a mini more additional signaling and the
additional signaling that we need is to
make sure that all those sub trees
converge onto a same tree as opposed to
making islands of
for instance if there was s3 s4 s5 s6 s7
s9 which could all be roots of the
subtree if we try to join them blindly
maybe we that we could build to two
islands as three s5 s6 and as for s7 s9
I don't know how do you make it sure
that that if they can they all merge
into a single structure which is what we
want to build and the way to do that is
to to expose like a token to expose
something which will they all will want
to reach and so what we said so far is
that we could use the system ID of we
could expose the system ID of the
highest of those roots right so far we
had s3 and s4 so they both are system
IDs and actually represent the nodes
left or right to the smallest most to
our system ID and so as we expose if if
all the nodes and 3 and 4 and 5 exposed
the system ID of the parent so and 4
here would expose that it's it's root
kind of is s 4 and 3 and then 5 would
expose that downward is s 3 now through
through through this information s we
can realize there is a root with the IR
system ID themself so what it would try
to do is establish a link this link here
between it and the child of this higher
system ID right it might be that because
of this jointness and partition stuff
and 3 doesn't see a child of s 4 right
but it might see a child of another node
with with AA system ready themself and
that node would see the the main road so
that's in order to be able to make this
single tree you need to expose the not
only yourself but also the tree you
belong to you need to say as SS 3 joints
you know s 4 s 4 3 it needs now to
expose a I'm a link to the tree risk
super routed by s 4 so that's the thing
which is not in Akron signaling is how
to expose
I actually the main street i belong to
is is s4 and now we could talk so that's
why we are in the thinking we would have
to expose s4 as part of the signaling
and to relay it that's the name of the
tree that i'm building to be on this
area and well is it agreeable to do that
and we can at the next step start
seeking a now what what if there is a
chance challenge etc and that's one we
probably would need to introduce a
distance so basically it's all about
building a tree of those roots which was
selected by the sub tough so now we have
joined them together and the result of
what we build with this is a spanning
structure that spans all the leafs
pretty much all the sub tough all those
which was selected as a parent and some
of the tough know delimited set and we
can decide the size of this limited set
because that's what decides how fat the
the the tree that we build for the FPL
is and that's pretty much where we are
this is for the particular example that
i designed here so you see i just put
some of the tough and some tough nodes i
establish those links what you can see
now is the resulting spanning structure
and like we said earlier we can build a
number of them and the operation of this
pending structure is as Jeffrey said if
you inject the packet anywhere say m1
injects a packet anyone will copy the
packet along the structure just like a
spanning tree thing on all the other
interface on the structure and the
result of this operation is a basic
flooding of the structure which will
make it so that the packet is
distributed everywhere along the
structure now we can do the exact same
thing if we want to install a route like
stodgy right if this guy installs wants
to say I have a listener for stodgy we
can send the advertisement I ever
listener for stodgy but then one will
advertise that and it will be flooded
through the structure and that can also
be a listener here which will be flooded
through the structure
now not in the middle we'll know through
which interfaces it got the flooding
fall is now too stodgy and is now able
to sound the packet too starchy only on
those interfaces as a filter so you see
you don't that's what Geoffrey said
again earlier you don't need to have the
concept of of a super route up there
like we usually do in the idea we just
have this this flooding structure and we
can install you know other the filters
if you want to send a starchy or me to
some destinations or we can use it as a
broadcast and for half-assing you
against I'm sure or the message is fast
we built one tree I can build 100 trees
right as many as I like and then we can
decide which multicast flows go into
which tree the thinking what we wanted
to achieve is build those trees
proactively so we don't make them
dependent on the star geez we may make
them dependent on the giraffe floes I
mean that you introduced your flows but
your juries don't dynamically try to
build a structure like this is to each
time you have a new group coming in just
build a number of the structures and
then decide for our newest algae of our
flow do you use one of the structures
broadcast form ice floes or what or do
you just affect a particular strategy on
one of those particular pre-existing
spending structures and that's pretty
much where we are I don't think we have
another slide so was it clear two
approaches on the table one is like
space modes and everything love which is
any any leaf an illness or any tough and
that tough we use the reverse flooding
or addition or a reduction path to reach
the leaves that's option what Prime with
option one we have to have different
routing between things coming from South
and things coming from north option to
build the number of the spanning
structures use the tough to set off
network as a non broadcast multi-access
RPL build something into it which is not
too fast not too lean not too long and
that completes the whole sub trees into
a bigger
spend instruction these are kind of the
two options we have on the table right
now any question what did you say about
no question Daniel yeah when there's no
question it means what hi Bill Fenner
Arista networks I just have a question
that I think it's just an oversight on
this slide but the purple tree is
actually isolated there should be a link
to the oh yes and so sorry okay
it was either really confusing or just a
little mistake so that's I think this
slide was completed like yesterday and
because all the other explanation I had
to take out some notes and when I
completed this slide with the other ones
I forgot to draw this line yes sorry it
will fix it so you see the origin I mean
some of those end nodes set off our
parents you know for free is going to
Leeds and then you have to join them
the another question which is an option
here is whether you Johanna interested
is if the tree after CC for instance and
one anyone has leaves down this tree so
so is an interesting guy iconic code if
if all the listeners are on leaves then
if you have somebody like M 3 and n 2
are you interested in those guys because
they don't which leaves so the idea the
point was oh let's be on the trees even
for guys like I'm free which don't have
leaves behind them because it might be
that later on because of a breakage or
anything else free might decide to
repair on two M's free and if it's the
only time when we start to build the
whole thing all the way north then we
will incur delay finishing the formation
of the tree so we decided to form the
tree even from nodes like m3 which don't
have leaves so probably will not have
listeners
because maybe someday as real for
whether we're a parent to them and want
the tree to be ready to operate so
that's pretty much why you see this end
to towards reading here even if there is
a leaf behind it so putting those sub
tops into the tree you may if they don't
have children that's basically
simulating a leg up here here right so
yeah we always get traffic even if you
don't have it at downstream receivers
it's just exactly like the pin batter
case where the RPO is aligned we are
doing enough yeah it's just it's an nvme
network so it's a bit more complex than
doing broadcast um I think it was a
couple of subtleties that you missed so
we also thought through the problem if
some of the more notes on Antarctica's
capable right we talked about it stuff
yeah you could parent would only be
selective or if he expresses the
capability right so it will work also if
you have a mix of multicast kept on non
capable this solution does not reach all
the toughs right that's what we
concluded so if you have receivers on
the tops that won't work if if the TUF
wants to be including in the tree they
will operates just like the subbed off
they will select and then to you so we
could if we want it to have not
represented it right now it's kind of
built with the South thought that the
listeners on the Leafs but if it's easy
for any first one for instance if s1 is
not part of the games here to see that
the trees building and to join any just
like we did s3 so you see at some point
s3 decided to join the tree this one
could have decided to join the tree
fights on purples so if we want it to
have listeners on the on this one then
we could we could take the same step as
we did and this one okay so that's a new
signaling so I actually didn't see the
signaling stuff that you guys converging
I don't see much of a problem there
that's just with the add things to the
note ties and that's it well the only
signaling we really want is the route
idea of the main routes that we are
joining
we might want to avoid you know weird
case of loops so this notion of distance
if you have to go through a number of
those routes to reaches yeah let's not
get too cute but I think you know that
the basic signaling is not a problem so
we don't showing in PGP at all to build
this kind of structure so the star comma
star would just fall out for free right
yeah
it's only the star Comanche when we have
to start to push PGP and store state if
we want to prove right if the structures
like I said we can build a hundred of
these trees if you like and there will
be we can also control our concurrent er
we looked at all these options but right
now I just I just represented out to be
able to up just for the sake of
understanding how we do that yeah and I
think the idea is not to put it in the
base back because all the stuff we can
you know put on optionally on the
existing schema without breaking the
major right including the capability
whether you're multicast cable alright
so I mean maybe one question to the
group is check if we work wise to kind
of forget about the north
well the the sparse mode way of doing
things which like I said takes
everything to want off and then uses the
reverse flooding prediction path to
reach the reefs we cannot remove that I
just put it on on the side because of
the difference of writing north south to
Sue's north if there is any hint on that
we were right to do that then it's good
time to tell us chain because this is my
first time to see the solution the first
question is is there any star G on and
the SG stating the topology okay so we
said that for mice flows we could
actually be a little G which would be
like a broadcast and would send to every
leaf through that broadcast apology and
then there would not be
nostalgie or SG Eskimo G state to the
network then we said a if we have what
we call elephant flows you can come back
to to Jefferies slicer if you have very
fat flows we don't want to flood them
through the whole network and that's
when we would like to install star G or
whatever state in the tree the key thing
is that we want to be on the tree first
and not wait for having a new group show
up so we build to spending structures
and if we want to use one of the
structures for a particular star G say
what we're going to do is it's populate
state for instance if there is a G
listener here it would flood I have a
listener for starchy and this guy will
learn oh there is a listener on that
interface and then he will flood it so
this guy would learn oh I have actually
this guy would learn I have a listener
on that interface etc so you know on
which side you've got listeners and yes
you would need to install that and then
when there is a packet you would only
instead of flooding it through all the
other interface but the one you got it
from you would add as an additional
filter only if there is a starchy
listener so we have not yet please
explain written text about exactly how
that works but you may figure that this
structure is a logical topology like a
virtual topology overlaid over the whole
fabric and that's inside that you
apology you flood just to add that you
can you could just have simple a few
star star or star C cryptic state in the
network and then if you start sending
traffic then the the traffic or match of
those foreign state whether it's a star
star or star C critics or it could be a
US exist
starchy states and then before it
basically you it's like the the longest
match for unicast case you will measure
out the existing state yeah okay thank
you
then a cellphone said we need to use the
list so don't hesitate posting questions
on the list and and let's discuss that
bill Fenner one more question about the
star star versus star G etc do you
imagine dynamically deciding whether a
given group is going to have be an
elephant or use the star right now we
don't know how to make those two leaves
together on the same structure because
it we would need the negative G kind of
right sure it's more like the other band
determination okay if you know that a
star 100 group is the elephant flow than
you and you can figure that on all the
nodes not not configure oh all right
yeah he somehow didn't know they need to
receive chapter they they work and
notify so that they can begin join that
establish a separate tree for that yeah
right
it's just everybody needs to know when
they're establishing the tree whether
they're establishing a star G or they
can use the star surgery yes right we
talked about that the various various
possible means it could be that you use
the existing star star tree to plot a
notification sure that's one way or
another auto band way to to somehow and
a controller kind of thing if you will
in the initial approach to the one that
goes north and then south we basically
could have just flooded G as if it was a
unique esta try so at any cast address
yet so the packets would had gone off
and then they would have been flooded
because recognized iced multicast and
flooded along the flooding or addition
path so the signaling was pretty much
the one we already have if you want to
do if you want to have s in the picture
obviously you don't so we were not
taking a well so far we have not been
asked to go all the way to us yeah I
wasn't thinking about us I was just
thinking about the distinction between
the mice and the elephants and the
giraffes yeah the problem with the mice
is you don't have any stage for it right
so if there is a packet is it a g4 which
I have no listener or is it is it a mice
and so that's why I say just
elliptically said we would need to be
able to signal negative G there is this
G but I don't want it great okay great
as long as you're thinking about that
problem Thanks so there is none
observation and I know you guys didn't
think about the stuff yet but the star
star without the singling could also
build a beer structure that would also
work fine it would be the beer
forwarding that way so we have finished
our agenda any further question comments
on any more things yeah
blue sheets