[Music]
so yes I think it's time to get started
so this is the Orem cat session so I'm
on a bernstrom this is my kosher column
Perkins and we also have Martin's
demeaning as a share this is the note
well applies to all our meetings if
you're not familiar with it then please
read it carefully so as usual you have
the slides available in the data tracker
we have some people connected through
medical do we have someone on jabber
that can thank you you know Tom someone
that can help out with the minutes
should be a easy task
today we have a fairly short agenda so I
see Alan you have been very reliable
made me take it for us can you take if
you on the etherpad
thank you so we have a fairly short
agenda today so we're going to go over
the status of the working group and the
different documents
jonathan has promised to give a short
update on the hackathon that was during
the weekend and
Colleen is gonna talk about the RTC the
feedback work that is now driven in abt
core so let's start with overview of our
working group documents so we are
finishing up our algorithm document so
we already have the screamin SPD that
has been published
Naida is ready Martinus writing this up
he was gonna submit it before today but
he got sick so I hope we will get this
submitted very shortly and otherwise
your column will have to help on this
one and of course the GCC draft is
dormant and we don't really expect any
updates on that so the algorithm draft
that has had some activities since the
last meeting is the coupled CC draft so
this draft was finished quite some time
ago but it has been waiting in the
editor queue for the norther draft
because of the normative reference so in
the meantime there was experimentation
with this draft and there was a corner
case detected that in some instances all
the bandwidth was not fully used so this
was detected by julius in doing some of
the measurements and experiments with
the draft and this was also presented in
our last meeting so the decision there
was to try and solve this corner case
before we got the draft published as an
RFC so as a result of that the draft has
been returned to the working group to
solve this issue and the authors have
also made an update to the draft that
has been sent on the list for any
comments there were some things that
could be a bit more optimized in the
presentation so the shares are working
together with the authors to use refine
and have a bit more compact and general
description of the the solution that was
in the draft so as soon as we finish up
that part which should be very soon we
expect to then return the draft it first
needs to go to our aid
for approval and then if we have
understood the process correctly we can
return the draft directly into the RFC
editors q so this is the status of this
dis draft and media wants to say
something yeah yeah even if I remember
correctly the discussion was last time
we have to see the changes to figure out
what to do next right yes the
alternative would be to run another
working group last call and everything
so I mean it's be my working group for
Clements the draft was the sole draft
was fixed there I mean we can run the
short around the comments also on the
final version before it goes to you then
the way I understood it from the ROC
editors was that then you basically have
to approve or decide what to do no
change anymore so maybe just like
officially running the last call again
and then I can also put it as a
returning write and when the I use
gender I mean it shouldn't it doesn't
really doesn't have any implications for
you just to follow the process correctly
I think it's the right thing to do okay
yes sure the process was not fully clear
to us or but if if you prepare we can
run a formal working group last call
when we done put and I think we used to
do that on the new version because we
have a new version that has been based
on the discussions between the shares
and the waters to refine the
presentation okay
Thank You Miriam so we will do that but
still I think this will be solved and
finished up very soon then we have the
requirements and the valuation draft
requirements still waiting in the editor
queue has been there for quite some time
we now also have the video traffic model
draft finished so that is now in the RFC
editor skew the valtor's draft has also
been submitted to the eye
gee and the waters are working to solve
that the last comments that are coming
through that review so I think that this
draft will also very soon be passed on
to the RFC editor then we have the eval
criteria draft this draft is basically
also done it's passed the working group
last call but we are waiting for the
authors to make the final update so I
think it's the security section that
needs a little bit of a work still and
then this draft will be submitted to the
IEC and then we have the orange at the
wireless test draft this draft is also
passed the working group last call and
we're waiting for an author update to
take care of the comments that came up
during the working group last call there
were not so many but there were with you
so we need a water update there still so
I hope that we can also get these two
drafts out very soon to finish up of the
evaluation and the requirements part of
the work then we have the work related
to the feedback so here the the draft on
the feedback message is now with a BT
core and it's also a larger agenda that
column will give the working group an
update on what how this draft is
progressing there and the work that has
been done and then we have the RT PCC
feedback draft that is Oran kept draft
and that will be updated once the
feedback message draft is completed to
reflect the the final version of that
draft
we've had some draft related to
interfaces and this is on hold and will
be eventually picked up again when the
candidate algorithms are progressing
towards proposed standards if we get
there the milestones we are finishing up
most of our milestones so we had the
milestone in December for the
requirements and evaluation drafts we
submitted the most of them but we have
the
the two that was just mentioned that
needs to also be finished up and go
there and then we need to move into the
evaluation results of the algorithms and
see if we can also move some of them
forward so that are the upcoming
milestones for the working group okay
that was the last slide on the overview
let's see if I can get rid of our slides
but the second point on the agenda is
Jonathan giving us some update from the
hackathon they won't have exactly you
don't have any slide so I can work on
the slides for you give us a update
hello
so okay so yeah so Sergio Ana is in the
driver Munich oh and I worked on but
then with Nils on Sunday then on
Saturday worked on getting Interop of CC
feedback working and it actually worked
so we had an interrupt flow between me
and the hackathon room and Sergio in
every Azura greeting Switzerland with
him using Firefox which and be using our
proprietary algorithm successfully under
operating I mean we didn't do clever we
didn't do careful studies because it
basically got it working dishes the
hackathon finished but it stabilized at
about 350 kbps which for the VIP mount
of video we were sending and for the
link we were using seemed pretty
plausible number I think he has was
feeding that whatever the algorithm is
in the web RTC which were is some flavor
of GCC
so that should be so and then ours is
our proprietary algorithm which was able
to adapt pretty easily to CC feedback
there were a few interesting things we
ran into one is the tricky thing for an
algorithm of distinguishing between lost
packets on the forward path not reacting
to lost feedback as though they were
lost packets because that can be you
know that obviously you can you don't
want to lost feedback too cause I oh my
god there's terrible congestion slam
down but you also don't want it to be oh
no I'm sure everything's fine I think it
possibly be wrong so exactly how that's
something that the algorithms need to
think about a little bit another issue
there you ran into I mean partially
because of some bugs and are working on
our interrupt but the CC feedback unlike
most our CP messages isn't actually
inherently bounded in size so we ran
into the issue that we had CC set when
you know one side of the other was
getting its that feedback interval badly
wrong we ended up blowing out the our
MTU with the feedback messages we had a
duplicate like 2k or 3k of feedback in a
single packet which doesn't work well so
unfortunately that you can break it the
format's fairly easy to break out but
you had to actually take that into
account and and do that so that's that's
not normal behavior that's about correct
oh I mean it's it was it was I guess but
I mean it basically become but I mean I
could imagine situations where you have
sufficiently asymmetric bandwidths
between the two sides where you know one
side is getting quite large bit rate the
other side is has very little bit rates
and so has to have a relatively slow
feedback interval so I mean the place is
in just a matter of okay you know when
you hit an empty you stop putting this
back and put in the next packet but it
was a yeah I mean that this sounds like
guidance for the there's like guidance
for the RM cat draft which is giving
advice on how to
but also draft saying do stop and start
a new packet when you go to them to you
the other issue is that because SDP a B
and F is arcane it wasn't immediately
clear to serchio what exactly the a
equals syntax was so we might want to
have examples in the draft like I said
we have we didn't really do any
performance analysis or anything like
that yet but hopefully now that we have
it working we could start work looking
at that and pretty who I'd like to do is
check what is the relative usage of this
versus the equivalent transports CC
feedbacks so that's something we could
potentially look at any comments or
surge or senior here does anything else
you wanted to say yeah I don't I'm the
Java scrap you'd have to actually do it
in the meet ago or no all right so
that's basically the status of it I
don't think we found anything spec wise
that was wrong yeah Sergio did note that
transport CC has like I think a feedback
sequence number which makes it a little
easier to discover when you've lost
something but after we discussed I
realized that because you have the RTP
sequence numbers you can figure out
unnecessarily how many feedbacks you
lost but how many feedbacks of how many
packets were lost so that's probably
sufficient for anything you need to do a
sure sure sure okay so you're on hello
I don't know if the audio I mean the
audio is taupey I don't know if you can
you guys can hear me well the audio was
not great there talk again okay so I'll
talk slowly I think from the experience
we had this weekend I think that the
draft it included a way to basically
merge all the vectors of sequence
numbers that are we are getting at the
sender into one single sequence number
which is what most congestion
controllers are expecting especially for
four losses
so he was saying that you know most most
kadesha -1 a single sequence number
space across all streams I mean I think
that was what the transports CC did I
mean you can do with this level of
indirection you can do that basically
just have to keep of the structure
locally mapping your sequence number and
SRC pair to a the sequence yeah so Colin
Perkins as an individual I just you know
too hard to walk to the microphone so
yeah I mean that has certainly been
suggested before as Johnson says he if
you give the sequence numbers per s si
si you can reconstruct a single sequence
number space and by doing that you can
congestion control each flow separately
which you can't do if they're all
combined into a single C we have the
choice of for flow congestion control or
markets yeah or aggregate and then also
you don't have to have the order to send
that extra sequence number anywhere so
you just save it save the header
extension yes yeah I mean yes I mean so
it saves on the header extension and I
think the main benefit is that you can
control each flow separately if you want
to do so I mean the converse would be
true - if you had a little single signal
number you could maintain the opposite
mapping and remember which one is on
each flow yeah yeah I guess so yeah if
you then need the header extension also
it sort of matches I think how RTP works
better in the data peak has sequence
numbers per SSL sees using the existing
thing rather than trying to sort of
twist RTP into something else seems
seems more natural to me yeah I mean I
agree with Colin but you know it's still
I think that's something that I think we
should put I mean one of the open issues
in draft is to put some rationale for
the design choices yeah rationale and
then also guidance things like hey you
probably want to maintainer if you need
a single sequence number just you know
maintain a mapping and you know maybe
even guidance like this is how big a
window open window you'll need
in terms of things like that so right
okay
Thank You Sergio did you want your still
in the queue did you want to make some
more comment or hello can you hello can
you hear me yeah unfortunately were I'm
guessing you said no but she disappeared
from the queue
and unfortunately the audio was not
great so if there was something else
please please post it and thank you
Jonathan and for the work in the
hackathon I think this is very useful
feedback so then we move on to the next
presentation and that is calling on the
RTP congestion control feedback all
right so I'm just working can you hear
me yeah okay so I'm Colin Perkins so we
talked about the RTP congestion control
feedback draft this is a draft which is
joint with ahead and Varun and Michael
talked about for a while so we had some
feedback from the hackathon in the
Bangkok meeting which we discussed in FA
VT core and our MCATs based on the
implementation experience from jonathan
and i figure who else those three or
four people in that crowd and we had a
long discussion in the bangkok meeting
going through the comments trying to
come to some resolution and i submitted
the zero free draft I believe it was
just before Christmas to try and address
those those comments we've got one
hopefully final change to the packet
format and a bunch of clarifications but
the ones any major changes in this
version of the draft
okay so the intro was with the latest
Russian here okay good alright so the
the the only real technical change was
that the packet format rather than
having begin sequence number and n
sequence number plus one now has begin
sequence number and number of reports
and this simplifies the logic in the
rest of it and simplifies explanations
in the rest of the document
significantly and it makes it very easy
just to put a number of reports 0 in the
case where you haven't received anything
to report
so that clarified a bunch of things and
it doesn't doesn't use anymore anymore
bits I believe this is quite a nice
simplification to the spec other than
that we've made a bunch of
clarifications there was a long
discussion in the last meeting about
what to do with packets which arrived
after the report and what what case is
that in what cases that could happen and
so on so I can't hear the co-enrollment
yeah drunk legs I don't think we
actually implemented I think we have met
at the other direction we had it does
offset after so we'd need to the way
this is has been written was that the of
the report times then all the offsets
are how far before in time as though
four times some represents essentially
right thing you used to say the time in
which the report was generated but at
that time I was your report yeah
everything else is still work amazing
but there were some issues with what
happens if you send her if you want need
to report on a packet which came after
the reports time stamp because you're
sending a delayed report for some reason
so we clarified that we clarified
exactly what the the meaning of the
report time stamp was just to make it
clearer what you were basing all the
time stamps aren't we clarified that
rather than reporting on every SSRC this
being condition controlled you reports
on every active SSRC since there's a
receiver you can tell which SSR sees are
being congestion controlled on months so
you have to report on them all and let
the sender do the right thing you should
just stay at the microphone no I did
don't that I just thought have another
thing that came up in our you know in
and they interrupt so the question is
because of the way SDP negotiation maybe
this is more appropriate décor than here
but we can talk about any way that
because it's not clear if it's
legitimate to list this feedback on some
but not all M lines in a bundle so so
and so that needs to be clarified you
know should it be allowed if so what
does it mean yeah so and the other thing
that came up which is not directly about
its but it just occurred to me also is
that you need to make sure an offer
answer that at least for an answer or
they you only negotiate one congestion
feedback mechanism because we had a
situation where
like you know your offering you know
transport CC and RAM and CC FB and the
other side can happily say sure I'll do
all of those at once which doesn't tend
to produce good iris yeah yeah if you
can send email then I will make sure
that gets put in yeah other than that
what do we do we clarified that
overlapping reports may be sent and
specified what happens when you get
overlapping reports you know in that if
a packet is reported as received and you
then send a later report which give us
the same sequence number range then you
need to mark the packet has received in
that so you don't see you avoid
contradictions we also clarified what
happens with duplicate packets saying
that you report the arrival time of the
first copy of you know the first of the
copies of the duplicate that arrives and
if any of the duplicates of ECM
congestion experienced marked you report
it as congestion experienced otherwise
you report the ec n mark of the first
copy and the en mark should be
consistent but who knows so we at least
specified what to do is there not the
draft had some long discussion about
what you do if there's an outage when
you stop receiving packets for a while
and how you recover from that and how
you detect the outage which we just took
out since it's a general RT CP issue RTP
issue rather than something which is
specific to that draft so you should
just use whatever mechanism you're doing
for the rest of your rtcp implementation
to detect that things have failed and
you're recovering and we clarified some
of the SDP that there was a comment that
whether you whether you allowed to
signal this for particular payload types
within the SDP however it has to apply
to all payload types and that the
suggestion of the last meeting was that
issued apply to all payload types so
that's like I wrote that into the draft
and I think the final if I'm remembering
right thing we added was a section
clarifying how it relates to the ECM
capable RTP in the previous ECM feedback
formats since that they both allow you
to report on ec n so we've provided some
guidance on what to do and what's the
right things doing that space other than
that at the time I wrote the slides when
I open issues but Jonathan has just
given me a couple more so there are a
couple of things we all have to clarify
I think we also need to clarify the the
relation to the alternative solutions in
the space and in particular that there's
the proposal of the Google draft that
the Google browser uses and highlight
the the sort of benefits and the
trade-off and I am hope hoping that this
can go to working group last call fairly
soon although it seems like we will need
at least one more revision thank your
collegues any other questions
no seems not okay then we are at the end
of our agenda so thank you all for
attending and if you're an author on the
two outstanding in well draft let's try
to get those final pieces submitted so
we can get those drafts also something
and then we hope to maybe have some
results on experimenting with algorithms
in the next meeting so if you're working
on that and want to present something
next time then let us know and we have
one more comment on music oh so please
so just point out that even if we are
not presenting anything this during this
aren't cut meeting searching myself and
others we are actively working on
getting nada
into Firefox in order to do experimental
results searching already showed some
preliminary ones based on our RTT and
we're now working on one way delay which
for which we need actually to combine
our work which is B so expect some
results soon
okay Thank You Sergio that's very good
to hear and I know that
Ingmar has also been working on the
screen some scream experiments so maybe
that next time we will see both some
results for both scream and nada which
will be nice okay thank you all for
attending and this concludes our meeting
for today
you