good morning crowd
to prep we're about to start our first
meeting that ITF final four and the
routing working group here we go so
we're gonna start today with a usual
update of the routing area working group
document status
first of course no well you've probably
seen this several times but if you you
haven't really taken the time to to read
it yet please do so I wanted to point
out that for the routing area working
group we have the general IETF IPR
disclosure policy and the way that we
handle that specifically in the routing
area working group is requiring the
authors and contributors to state
whether or not they're aware of any
relevant IPR for a document in question
at the two main gates for the document
process that is at working group
adoption and also when doing working
group last call and sometimes we'll do
this concurrently sometimes before
depending on the specific document we
have our minute taker who's just arrived
and I also have Dhruv taking doing the
jabber scribe work thank you the blue
sheets are in circulation so please sign
them they're used to figure out what
size room we get next time so please
please sign them I think I'm going to
jump right into the document status
update and then we'll start the actual
agenda
so we've had three documents published
recently the LFA multi-home prefix draft
became an RFC and also the to the
network instance yang model and the
logical network element yang model were
published we have three drafts that have
been submitted to the ISD for
publication the yang model for rip is
awaiting a normative reference so
there's there's not much that the
authors or the working group need to do
there
I think it's waiting on is is and OSPF
yang models the micro blue problem
statement is in off 48 or rather off 48
is done so that's pretty well along the
PA multihoming draft it's in 80
evaluation and it actually the authors
need to respond to some feedback so the
authors will we'll be doing that we have
one document that's passed working group
last call quite a long time ago the BGP
pick draft and we're really expecting a
shepherd right up very soon on that
we've nudged the the shepherd recently
adopted working group drafts the segment
routing gif a draft was adopted and the
net to cloud problem statement and gap
analysis drafts were adopted as well as
the rib yang model they were adopted so
in terms of existing working group
documents the ATN BGP draft has has been
document for a while
we're gonna hear about that today the
routing policy model draft is also the
source test routing draft it was adopted
quite a while ago it sort of recently
been unexpired and we also have the VRP
PFD point-to-point draft and the routing
timer parameter synchronization draft
which were adopted quite a while ago but
we they've expired so we probably need
to to figure out you know how we're
proceeding with those either the authors
bring them back into into circulation or
we'll we'll figure out you know if
there's still still interest in pursuing
them okay so the policy model will be
presented on Friday so in addition
several drafts that have been discussed
over the last several IDF's in the
routing area working group related to
control and usually playing separation
for B and G there's a baath occurring
basically in the next session this
morning after the break related to those
drafts so we're not going to discuss
them here because there'll be a
dedicated to them so I think I will
bring up the agenda now and we'll start
with the DD scheduled presentations
so first up we have Fred Templin
presenting on the ATN draft as well as
scalable BGP related to that okay so
this is a document that's been in the
working group for a little while now
it's paralleling the efforts that are
going on in a Organization for civil
aviation called the International Civil
Aviation Organization and this is the
routing system that we're looking at for
air traffic management for AI for civil
aviation the documents titled a simple
BGP based mobile routing system for the
aeronautical telecommunications network
so in terms of aviation and
communication standards bodies the
International Civil Aviation
Organization is developing an
aeronautical telecommunications network
with Internet Protocol services for
worldwide air traffic management we have
other standards bodies that are involved
in this to RTC a special committee 2:23
is identifying an IPS architecture for
remotely piloted Aram's which are also
known as unmanned air systems RTC ASC
228 is identifying communications data
links for our past coordination ARINC
and the AEC also have a stake in
defining their own standards and then
finally the internet Engineering Task
Forces the worldwide Authority for M
networking standards so we think the way
this is going to go is that these
communication network standards have
begun in ICAO are being harmonized in
RTC aring can dec and will end in the
IETF and that's why we're here today
so in terms of what the ATN IPS looks
like again it's currently under
investigation ICAO working group I it's
based on Internet Protocol version 6
it's an overlay network over an
underlying Internet work that could be
either secured tunnels over the public
Internet or a private infrastructure and
we want to have a single air traffic
management service for all
Aviation each aircraft gets an ipv6
prefix that travels with the aircraft
wherever it goes and we need to have
remote pilots air traffic controllers
and aircraft global globally addressable
at all times so in terms of scaling
considerations for aviation each
aircraft is a mobile network and it
receives an ipv6 mobile network prefix
for example a slash 56 and that prefix
goes with the airplane wherever the
airplane travels worldwide today we have
on the order of 10,000 possibly going to
a hundred thousand airplanes in
operation today
however with unmanned air systems
personal air vehicles gross is a bit in
their future we're going to need to
consider soon large orders of magnitude
and then mobility plays a role in
control message overhead and aircraft
are highly mobile so we need a system
that scales not only in terms of the
numbers of nodes but in accommodating
mobility so one alternative that is
being looked at is what we can call
centralized mobility management and now
it would be a case where we have one
mobility anchor point for the entire
worldwide aviation so you see all these
airplanes here grouped around a single
Anchor Point I the advantages of
centralized mobility management are that
we have an immediate mobility signaling
and cube quality of service signaling
since all aircraft are serviced by the
same mobility Anchor Point disadvantages
are that you have scale and limitations
not only in the numbers of aircraft but
also in the amount of mobility signaling
and also localized mobility events cause
global instability so we believe that
this is not going to scale and so now we
have this option that we call
distributed mobility management and this
is where we get to the ATM BGP document
with the ATN BGP document we have a hub
and spokes architecture with a BGP
routing core in the middle as an overlay
network over the underlying network
and stop autonomous systems in this in
the spokes where you see those mobility
anchor points with aircraft grouped
around them so this is the way we can
distribute the mobility and the the
quality of service signaling is by
having smaller mobility anchor points
this servers smaller numbers of aircraft
and the global arounded system tracks
which aircraft er are associated with
which mobility anchor point advantage of
the distributed mobility management
approach is that it distributes the load
among many mobility anchor points and
it's scalable in terms of the number of
aircraft we can handle out of a BGP
routing core now the internet is proof
of concept that we can handle upwards of
close to a million routes in the BGP
routing tables with the distributed
mobility management approach we also
have scalable mobility signaling and
localized mobility events are kept local
without causing global instability the
advantage of this advantages of the this
approach though is that it requires an
effective route optimisation service to
reduce congestion in the core otherwise
we would have all traffic going through
that core and we would have you know
concentration of congestion in the core
routers but the good news is that we
know how to do the route optimization so
in terms of the draft in the routing
working group we have a BGP overlay
routing system for distributed mobility
management again a hub and spokes
autonomous system border router
arrangement we have core autonomous
system border routers in the hub and
stub autonomous system board routers in
the spokes BGP updates are
unidirectional from the stub autonomous
system border routers to the core
autonomous system border routers and the
core autonomous system border routers in
the reverse direction simply originate
default so we have partial topology
knowledge and the stub autonomous
systems and full topology knowledge in
the core now BGP is that the design is
for carrying short-term forward of
initial data packets only and then route
optimisation kicks in to keep the data
traffic out of the core
this is a very important point we've had
some experimental evidence over the
course of the last several weeks showing
that when you withdraw a BGP route from
the routing system it can take several
hundred milliseconds for that route to
disappear and for the new routing
information to come through so that we
found that after we've done route
optimisation if we remember where the
aircraft was before the BGP update
happened then we can continue to forward
at the link layer without going through
the BGP routing and in that way we avoid
periods where we wouldn't have it might
have several hundred milliseconds of
packet loss and that's very important
for aviation applications where we can't
have dropouts and in voice-over-ip
we can't have loss of position
information and things like that so so
even though we have a BGP convergence
time we take care of that at the link
layer without impacting the routing
system the mobility management services
in the stub autonomous system border
routers ICAO is looking at three
alternatives for the mobility management
proxy mobile ipv6 Lisp and Aero are the
three candidates that are being looked
at right now now in terms of the
document status of the routing working
group document we did update to a
version - zero and one recently we
incorporated clarifications do to list
comments and questions also we had a
routing area pre review that we
responded to we have a new section seven
on the stub autonomous system mobile
routing services where we talk about PMF
list Manero and then we operate updated
references and including new references
for permit v6 and lists now I want to
talk about did I miss a sign
I'm missing a charge my deck okay so now
we have this concept that we call
massively distributed mobility
management and this is a case where we
have not just one BGP core with its
router information base but many bgp
cores that each have a separate routing
information base so we want to size the
system to support a mobility service
prefix on the order of the slash 32 now
each one of these bgp routing cores
maintains an independent rib with up to
1 million rounds per mobile of mobile
network prefix routes per rib each rib
would service a different sliver of the
mobility service prefix and we're
calling that the mobility group prefix
so for example if each rib serviced a
slash 44 in ipv6 slash 44 then if we had
a thousand ribs that would get us to a
billion BGP routes and again the way we
we get to that level of scale is by
having multiple ribs that are
independent of one another but even
though we have these multiple ribs the
aircraft when they move from mobility
anchor points a mobility anchor point I
can get the service that is being
provided by their sliver no matter which
mobility anchor point they move to so
this is how we get our scalable D
aggregation for massively distributed
mobility management and I think that's
that's all I had so in terms of draft
status we have the simple BGP based
mobility routing system through the or
nautical telecommunications network
that's a working group document of this
working group and we have the new
document on scaleable D aggregation for
overlays using the border gateway
protocol so that that's a document that
we have aligned with this working group
but we haven't asked for adoption on
that one yet that's what I have Jeff so
I had a question you referred to some
like experimental data and I think at
least this second draft free first you
know kind of talks about that a little
bit but could you just elaborate a
little more on what you know what you're
you're doing to sort of test the
scalability of the whole solution and
yeah so we're actually working with the
group in Austria from a company called
free cuentas and frequentist was
chartered to evaluate these mobility
solutions for the ICAO work they ran an
experiment where they were sending a
hundred packets per second through the
BGP routing system and then with through
a route from the routing table and they
noticed that over that one second period
they were losing twenty to thirty
packets out of that 100 packets per
second strength so that's where we get
the notion that we're talking about
several hundred milliseconds of outage
when a BGP route is withdrawn before the
system realizes that that route is no
longer there so do you think you you
would be able to reference some work
that's done or maybe have an appendix
that describes the problem found and how
it was fixed I think it was very useful
for people look into this work I think
that's a great suggestion and we can
work with it's requires people to get
some text for that thank you
[Music]
so good morning everyone
this is Hugh from Huawei I'm here to
discuss how do we use leverage the ITA I
found a model to automate the management
to deliver service and so this is the
job that we actually pack for a long
time actually burn out because recently
we see a lot of ITF to find a motorcade
perhaps you didn't mature enough
actually so when a motivation actually
is we want to you know raise to some
idea of young tekmoto standardization
issue to inspire some discussion on this
so we we also see actually you know for
so many young Taylor model actually how
they can put together to deliver service
configure devices and many different
people have given a solution so we
really want to get people you know to
understand how how do we use this model
secondary actually you know is one when
I pick a challenger for operator because
we talk with a lot of operator the
people challenge is the facing actually
how to use this moto how do you select
the idea of different models that can
fit it to their use cases so this is
something we need to face actually for
the ITF and so the Charter proposal here
and the Walker proposed here actually to
provide a framework of the peril the
developer implementer operator how to
implement the ITF defender model also
discussed top-down subsidiaries through
the coordinator young data model these
or in a young model will cover
high-level model and lower-level how
they can coordinate it is not clear to
everybody if we get time actually where
you can you know kyo to use cases to
discuss this so before we get to discuss
actually we I wanted in to - you know
concept of what is data modelling
layering secondary data modern
representation data model layering
actually allow you to abstract and that
was infrastructure from bottom also
allow you to abstract the PCA needs
several requirements that from the top
so the service so the young data model
in ITF can be split into two layer we
have service model can carry water
services what is the customer service
needs and for device model we can tell
you how to you know get a network set up
to program in and walker and deliver
that service realize these service
lisa has already be specified in
obviously 81 1990 but we see actually
what is missing is mindo in the middle
is a nano resource model actually this
metal resource model is a very crucial
for you to liver the service the for
number you need to schedule the results
so to meet the customer needs or you
also you can reschedule resource to
adapt to the network change so it's very
crucial so we introduced these you know
another layer also for theta model
representation we make a elegy to the
house building process for example you
possibly you need to plan the house
building and then you can put into the
production for the house building
process you your custom actually can all
of the house describe their requirements
for example you wanna order a house with
three room and living room bedroom and
these can be actually represented by the
blue printer so the approve blueprint
can be compared to the service model so
the service model can be used by the
customer to communicate with operator
committee who is managing system so in
addition actually when you get approved
by the customer and also Regulation
Authority
this can put you into the pro Tanjung
and actually you can you can actually
select the site you can put a foundation
for the house building and you also can
actually step choose a change for the
water supply erection supply and
sewerage actually there is a water
supply electricity can be compared to
this a nano resource model and also for
the foundation with how the house
building and the building block in the
house can be compared to the device
model so did question yes Greg mercy
City so are you familiar with the work
at MAF on services uni-y circle
orchestration I think that it should be
actually the list as actually service
model you know provide the service
definition so this service definition
actually very close to the surface model
define night have no because there at
least they're there to service model the
three service model defined by ITF
defines it from operator perspective
knife approach is defining unity in and
I and defining the model from their
subscriber perspective so what you're
describing here is very much what MAF is
already doing so I think the the
similarity for MAF walk an idea because
they both activities described the
connected service actually for air so
it's an USM model actually to actually
describe the service from the customer
perspective with number how many of it
be inside you want to describe it but
you want to just establish it and what a
location of this which inside how to
establish the connectivity what is the
KPI or SLA for the for each connectivity
so it's very close to the Uni you
mentioned actually we already compare
this with M UFO terminology and we were
lying with them you I think as it says
know
conflicted but I would do near the
college if I may have an idea
yeah well Carol Ethernet model that
[Music]
defined by math being used to order
services I don't know where L 2sm being
used to offer order services networks on
layer 3 uni its MF 61 document already
been published and continuous working on
operation in and I also it works on
service L AM service activation testing
so I would really suggest to be very
careful not the duplication of the work
but it's do we have already being aware
of this so thank you for your
information actually we already try to a
language them you have I think a way
actually it's a suggested to ecosystem
which we need to need a more
coordination bring accepted really so
that's why I bring up the topic about
then not the focal to this topic
actually we can take this off nine and
four how do you know each other
sto yeah okay so for next actually I
want to give updated for the idea
network of young work actually I think
recently we already published in more
than 50 FC and also in addition we have
more than eighty more than eighty
working with jobs actually you know get
a progress that procedure unite have
another made more than eighty innovative
jobs and we have enough young to the
model many yamaoka the popular recently
especially before this idea meetings so
and we all I think this is should a
sense for the design team formed by the
idea for like many design team formed by
the vendor and operator and distribution
given a vertical working group and also
we have young doctor design team a young
correlation design team and I singly
fulfill their mission but I think so we
have summer work I mean we need to
actually to put some results titute to
see how to get get some more work
actually can really be used for some
real use cases so also I want to mention
IDM have good correlation with different
organization also have a you know can
get a lot of input from the open source
community and like open configure
actually many open company innovating
actually you know has already the import
to the ITF and drive a lot of innovation
in the idea so this is a very heavy so
we hope actually for open source and
idea can commercialize is very
challenging but it really is our hope
but you you know see you know different
organizations even a open source can
align with each other
yeah so this is the overview the idea
for yamamoto standing we have a high
level model service layer model we have
actually a common building block in the
middle we call the natural resource
model we also actually define some
mechanism like secure mount actually
collaborative compositive in a model
together to actually to to configure the
device to to program the networker so
this is a very crucial to automate the
network management on and I actually we
have a large amount of young lady model
actually cover given a technology spec
actually you know this model actually
you know many of them have written
together popular and but we also see
some of issue one issue we want to raise
here to inspire some discussion is you
know for all of these you know we call
the device model southbound interfaces
model actually is this distributed in
Tiffin upper the working go actually
it's hard to for user or for the
operator to select this model for to fit
in their use case it's hard to keep
chatter with a maturity for this model
for all these more because the reactive
she will give in a protocol working
group actually maturity may be may be
different you know we also have very
slow idea process and maybe many you
know problem in idea the lack of
there's resources put into it so they
were all delays and some of the young in
modest ambition so this is really
serious you we should you know pay more
attention
yeah actually for actually for the trend
actually we really you know involved
from Chinese you know service delivery
to the motor driven service delivery and
the big difference is actually you know
for channel service delivery oncbs
actually you know they didn't really
they actually conquered the surface
efficient from how the service is
realized
so that calls actually you may build a
lot of OS LPS application and butyl otto
sidle over years actually the lacquer
stand are in the face and and I may move
a lot of data entry and a manual
provision and so these actually cannot
automate a service activation or
provisioning and another so that's so so
to address is actually what we can do is
in the motor driven sensitive area we
can take copper the service definition
from how the service is realized so for
the management system we can split into
two subsystem why we call the service
activation provision system the second
is service the enforcement system so the
service activation and a provision
system just take a standard model from
the standard interface and these will
literally you know you know reduce the
service period time and go back to the
the Trantino service delivery for
managing system management systems they
need to you know tackle the money vendor
environment you know they need to manage
your different vendor device so it's
very Chinese because you need to do is
the different vendor say or is creeper
and so how do you automate this metal
magic väri Channing you based on our
talk with operator actually many orbiter
actually chance the integrative and
vendors Eri scrip and try to identify
the
vendor device and and call the different
vendors Eri so this is something we
should address that's why I do you know
proposed to stand on a model a to to to
to address this challenge actually so so
how do you automate that the management
actually I sing away Ottoman imagine can
from two different layer one is the
service layer the second is a network
layer for source of service layer as so
as I discussed in a previous slide
actually we can actually define top-down
service delivery model I'm going to
describe the service requirements KPI a
necessary and and associative is a
connectivity service and are you ready
you really want to automate a sub
statement you also what is missing
actually you need to have when you get a
network setup or you also need to you
know expose a network performance or
expose of formal VPN performs a to the
chasm or to the or P that they can use
these powers that resolve the to
reoptimize a networker so you can you
know form the closed-loop imagine and
full lifecycle management and you know
the here as a net were later you also
become motive automated network
management in IPA we already you know
developer a young push a notification as
a telemetry maximum even average disease
and to connect the data and actually you
you review all too many days network
management what is missing is you know
policy metal policy model this can be
part of this magical system they
actually can you know to hook the the
telemetry data with provision theater
and to really ultimately the network
management and a single we already
developed a lot of building block in
night here is vegetated South Boniface
device model we can leverage it is but
what is the missing is actually policy
ready
so I see some of the policy promoter has
already progressed and I got a say oh
and routine policy but what about the
other policy cuckoos always say maybe
generic and then okolloh say this is
still very important building block that
can help to automate the narrow
management so yeah Gregory egt so
speaking of oil psycho orchestration I
think we at ATF is a far back far behind
comparing to efforts being done for
example at MAF in oil circle
orchestration for now Carol either met
and now for there are three services I
would probably I would encourage you to
really look at what AF is now at the
level and what are the components
because for example it seems to me that
you're dismissing for example service
activation testing model service om
model so these are very important
ordering models and at the same or is
carrier service a you know specific you
know an idea you can never change in
Eric okay so she and telemetry okay
I was working to find the most part of
his telemetry Maxim to connect all the
data okay I don't want to turn it into
tutorial board service orchestration why
circle orchestration is I just encourage
you to look at what MAF is doing and
might be revisit what you're proposing
okay thank you versus robots and Cisco
it's actually a question for Greg in
terms what's happening MF is obviously
they defined the LSO model at the top
layer of service layer they writing any
draft walls to say how you map those
services down on to for example IETF
yeah models to stand state those
services on the devices was that left
open it is there somebody doing that
piece of work between the two is one of
the top there's models at the bottom
who's who's to say how you bridge
between those two things again so work
on layer 3 is only being developing they
do have already our psyche for Carroll
Ethernet so it's layer two and layer -
they have demos and they have real
working system to do and and service
ordering and provisioning and monitoring
and decommissioning so again it's not
layer 3 ok so I think the question is
identified like and again III think
that's better we take it offline but
again I suggest you to avoid duplication
and incomplete proposal look at what MAF
is doing already because they're using
own app and they have pretty good lead
on that yeah I understand actually
that's just a cursor you know I think we
do need some reference architecture we
may actually leverage this area so by
the ITF oh I think we do need actually
maybe you know have such a reference
architecture to have you know developer
operator to see how to position
different model independent interface
and help either implement this a young
model and also I think it's a very
important to help her you know to to
understand how to map amia for service
definition or service model to ITF de
panamá is a very crucial is that what is
the missing I mean I would encourage you
to do this so that's why we already you
know engage with em you have to talk
about that how to fill this gap yeah
yeah Charles a Cole Cisco and I'm active
in in math I chair the co-chair the
application committee where we're
defining and s
service and what that is and obviously
it overlaps and perhaps even conflicts
in some places with work going on in
IETF Jen and I have already talked this
is something we're going to try to align
better overall what I've seen in math is
there there are service level models
they don't the way math define service
is different than the way IETF defines
service any most places in math do not
have a complete stack built out yet
that's all using math specifications at
some point it starts with a math service
model and it's and then switches
somewhere to either some proprietary
implementation or some models that are
being defined within math and we see
this as a problem because we'd like to
be able to reuse a lot of the underlying
IETF device models and perhaps other
models as well so one of the things
we're going to do with SD Wan is really
look at trying to align those two bits
of work since they're both being defined
actively and in IETF and in meso I think
we have a good chance to kind of show
the way this can work and that's
something we're going to actively work
on this week and afterwards him Leo away
actually I'm also at the participant of
math I think
chintz approach here is data model
driven with Rath connect on consistent
from layer seven to layer zero and math
approach sometimes on depending on the
interface they don't have data driven
approach they'd rather do some open API
or some other spec without a young model
so I don't see any conflict between what
Qin is trying to do here and what mefist
doing architectural II there's some
similarities but in terms of approach
how to implement there's some difference
so I think as charge talk talk about sd1
same thing layer one service model
developed here actually I brought it to
math so that they can take it so that we
have same consistent model but they have
a little bit different idea they don't
want to sometimes use young model
they were neural spec driven - UML -
JSON schema - open API it's a REST API
but slightly different flavor I think
Marshall will decide which one is the
right way to go but I think definitely
would unite young and Roskam has
security built in so I think it's much
easier to implement from security
perspective as well so I don't see much
conflict so I disagree with what Craig
is saying in some sense thank you Rob
Walton Cisco so just to find some other
general comments on the presentation of
a material you're presenting here I have
a lot of sympathy with what you're
saying in terms of IETF producing a lot
of models by independent working groups
and there's some efforts to make sure
those models are consistently each other
but I don't think there's very much
looking at the bigger picture of how do
you actually then implement services how
does a an ISP take this large set of
models and then implement the services
and sometimes it's obvious and in other
cases it's not it's actually having some
informational draft that gives some
guidance that says if you want an
improvement this surface service these
are the molds you'll need to use on the
device this is the set we recommend so I
think that more work to actually look at
the bigger picture as providing services
for both on the device ease and off the
devices is a useful thing I think
there's useful work to be done here
I think the work of trying to map like
these service models being produced by
other stos into the ITF device once
again I think that's very useful work
that otherwise is left to the ISPs to
actually figure out how you connect
these two things together I don't know
if I understand exactly you're asking
about into these extra layers and things
yeah I don't know they're required but
in terms of providing the documentation
how you can take those top-level service
young models and the bottom level device
the earlier models and say look this is
how these things map I think that's a
lot of value in that area yes thank you
yeah this is something it's a one of a
clean motivation would really bring
operatives toppika not sure these jobs
actually you know ready for that about a
we really want to provide a reference
actually to have you know to define the
the model is that can actually to to
provide it support different nurseries
you know that's exactly what a way
positive we also talked with best
walking or actually try to see if we
need to you know have such a mapping
from service layer model to the device
level model and maybe is very
challenging to do that but we do try to
actually you know freedom of contacts
ready to you know so to say the feedback
from the operator to see what is the key
service or hard propriety serve is a
really deployed and what kind of thing
really used and but I'm not sure how to
you know you know you know try to
achieve this goal and so that so there's
a chapter child to you know bring bring
up or summer issue and inspire some
discussion and I get a some feedback to
see whether we need to you know peanut
bring about some new work and I think if
people have interesting we do need to
work together to see if we can actually
help to address this channeling usual
the face wide-eyed have defined a model
yeah and then so one other piece of work
I've brought to net mod is a yang
packages draft you know I do and that is
to take sets of modules could be ITF
modules have group them together into
say this set of modules is what you'd
use for a basic router on this provides
high level routing or provides LT VPN
service and you can piece these things
together in a hierarchical way to build
up larger complex systems I still go to
manage those independently said that is
potentially one solution to this problem
another way it's been proposed is to use
the module tags that's I think last call
that's another way of labeling things
are grouping them together so there are
different ways you can solve this
problem with different pros and cons but
it is interesting
yeah yeah you are right after that I
didn't imagine this dream on and Walker
and another option I want to mention is
a young catalog actually I sing good
idea for a lot hope we put a lot of
resulting hacks on to actually develop
the young caliber right now migrated to
the idea for repository and these are
very very important actually reference
for have you to for a hyper operator
developer to select our young beta model
but maybe this is not enough we do
you know some additional you know
importa to see how how to you know you
know you know magazines a young catalog
more you know be aware by the outside
the community and also operators
operator can never do this contour to
mail the maturity of the young in the
model yeah that would be very you know
deciding oh yeah
just ensure up strong so who left
disagree with grab and overlap if you
look at any of the comments I see me of
61 they are not obstructed enough to
provide service definition they're not
detailed enough to provision the service
so people who work in was is just would
be great if you facilitate the process
of building some that could be used in
more Lehrman so Greg and young can just
we've been working with me a fun enough
for number of years right it just
there's very little progress yeah this
is true phonetic are assume to me that
notably Yamato has been deveined but
actually most of them has not been
widely using care network so I think
that this draft provide systematic
framework to integrate the young models
into a production system which can be
used in a you know network of carriers
and focusing on making the sudden load
into the network models and provide a
service automation with very crucial
important for okay so I think this work
is very useful I give support to this
work thank you thank you yeah I think
carriage as carriers as the one user or
consumer these the idea of different
model we also have some other cost
customer so so I I want to put these two
separately model as the customer service
you know we to me to satisfy the
customer needs yeah actually
you know we already discussed the you
know service management automation and
then women for the mission we also see
you know you need to hook the service in
managing automation with Neto imagine
automation you can provide the the
end-to-end the whole full automation
system here what is very important piece
actually is to do the service mapping so
we have two cases in a piece an error in
an icky scenario in a piece naira you
need to actually map for number the
layer 3 VPN service parameter into the
conversion parameter that can be enabled
eg P ACR OSPF in the P and C and fourth
he service mapping you really need to
you know map the service type fishing
within that the that he service into
that he tunnel and into that he topology
and this also very crucial to help to
automate the resource management so so
the resource management is very crucial
but it also is very challenging you know
based on our talk with our Peter and and
so last actually is our you know take a
take away and we actually have to use
case and maybe we don't have time to
introduce so I just jump to the the
claim which we really want to convey in
this presentation is the poster with
sink for idea for you know young the
process is slow we already know this we
company a lot about a sing with you can
do something you know for we can focus
on some model you know
for example the BGP and weep here and
related young data model is crucial to
deliver the VPN service so we we
shouldn't you know you know put more
attention to this and kind of operator
to you both to see what is the musing
and trying to drive the majority of
these kind of young model also we sync
is very important to engage the
operative community you know right now
we already met Ahmad already you know
kind of publish it and make sure enough
so we within
- you know create a you know young
standards actually that can meet the
relevant metal operator requirements
actually what do we can do actually we
can condense the rate as I mentioned
also a young catalog we also actually
already discussed that is very powerful
tour so how do you leverage this tool to
measure the maturity of the younger
model also the bigger issue is ITF
llamado is not use case driven this
young model you know distributing
different work in cooking global so how
to you know cake chat code is the
maturity of young in the model you know
so we're really when the need to shift
to the use case driven or project
dreaming and until help to you know make
a some of the young more the more useful
for for some specific cases to really
address the you know pimping or robbery
family phone operator or from the
customers so last actually we defined in
the reference frame worker to tell you
how to you know do these top-down
service delivery so accordingly young in
the model this is something one one big
motivation to write this work also last
we like to advocate for developer for
operator is time to deploy this idea
from model to you know identify some
implementation issue get as the
operation you experience the feedback
you idea community to have a job the
majority of Ikea model that's all so
personally I find your goals
great and hopefully we achieve them
Ignis who is upside D in the room and
think he's going to save yours but it
was book Donna's the wrong type of a tea
in this room so thanks for raising this
there are quite many of painful points
that you are mentioning on another hand
you seem to be kind of proposing certain
solutions and that solution seems to be
let's add another lay of the models and
it will solve the problems that probably
will not happen at all so a few few of
the specific topics ITF flow processes
slow yes that's a fact but proper
cooking takes time and looking at the
deliverables of
an element level models and technology
level models I think that time is worth
waiting then another aspect about the
secret sauce between the service models
and the element models that is just a
reality if the vision is that we will
define one set of service models for all
interconnection products which I even
built from a standard technology
components that that is not realistic
different users different operators
implement their own connectivity
products in different ways for different
reasons and valid reasons and the secret
sauce component will always stay that
the question is - what proportion but I
don't believe it is practical to try to
even to try to eliminate this then about
the quality of the models and ability to
use them in here or here I think that is
a big problematic area IETF is
historically very good at working on
techno and unfragmented technology
components but not necessary on
end-to-end systems and we see clear
results of that we do have technology
models which which work for that
particular technology domain but they
implement the same functionality not
necessary and a workable way and if you
try to stack different technology
components one on top of the other you
you end up with problems this I think is
an area which needs to be addressed
first by this and if your work can start
by this direction that I think would be
a good outcome yeah that's just an
overall general comment from a
manageability point thank you for the
work thank you thank you can i sir come
so stiffened from oranges so you say
that it's time for para it was to deploy
which in fact we can't because first
there is almost no implementation and
there is no implementation because of
else too few models that could be
deployed today so let's say that for
example I have only IETF interface which
is available in my advice I can't use it
because it does not make sense if I
cannot also configure my si yes of the
GP or whatever I need all the full stuff
so this come back to the point which is
yes I do but it's not only a matter of
assess it's also a matter of people
because we I think or know that we are
slow to progress documents and it's not
a matter of processes it's just a matter
of people and resources that we are
allocating to focus about documents
actually just want to mention you know
you in tank the to actually have multi
vendor into Apogee tested it has to
summon service model and some of the new
animal model you know so they could be
actually first-ever to to say how to
deploy the ITF definer model yeah so
we're running five minutes behind at
this point so we probably just one is
very small comment if you have a point
about a chief model is that from an
operator point of view we have now a lot
of implementations of open config which
is ready to use now so we will will we
really use ITF model it's almost not
show yeah we we can you know I think
that there's no company will hopefully
we can convert you for IT departments a
Yamoto and do the the OSI on actually
they do have some deployment made sure
butter and icing IBM model if they can
catch happen and that they actually can
you know I think they focus on different
use cases you know they so I hear the
amount of a more promising you know
because they shouldn't try to have an
otherwise I would say young yeah that's
thanks a lot next up is Donald Eastlake
hi I'm Donald Eastlake with Huawei for a
little behind schedule maybe I can catch
up I think this is a fairly short simple
presentation on a point-to-point tunnel
policy yang data model so it kind of has
policies because there are these variety
of tunnel types you might have to
provide VPN services and you need to be
able to select between these they're not
necessarily all available depending on
what you have implemented and what's
currently functioning hasn't yet failed
or whatever so this draft provides a
yang data model can be used to configure
and manage your point-to-point tunnel
policy and it kinda assumes there's two
flavors of policy a sort of a selection
sequence and a tunnel binding selection
sequence assumes that you have the
series of different tunnel types and you
sort of select from those based on the
priority they've effectively been given
for a particular VPN service it's you
know if you the tunnels can be flagged
as a particular tunnel can be applied to
whether it's up or not and you select
from wobbling from the ones that were up
if you have multiple tunnels you if you
slip and select them for a load
balancing purposes and things like that
but obviously avoid any tunnel that
might be marked as being down and the
tunnel binding is a case where you serve
find the the particular policy to a
particular kind of te tunnel
you can specify multiple ones of those
to the same IP destination to get load
balancing effects and things like that
and you can kind of say what happens if
they're not available you might want to
restrict it to only the the ones you
specifically bound or if those tones are
all unavailable you might want to just
be the best you can so there's a tribute
which you can associate which indicates
which of those sort of meta policies you
would like to have these kind of a
selection sequence order for different
tunnel types if there's no no te tunnel
available in basically there's a case
where if the designated tunnel is
unavailable it looks at this switch to
determine what other tunnel to select
and then it has a sort of ordering
between those tunnels depending on
tunnel type and then of course there's
always the possibility that no tunnel
will be available that your policies
allow in which case you can't establish
the VPN connection so the top level
there these panel tall tunnel policy
selectors and that's an ordered list of
these you've got to go through an order
until you you'd get one that that
matches so the each one of these policy
nodes whatever has a set of matching
conditions based on various conditions
next-hop Rd or whatever is obviously
more details in the graph and to do back
to a particular policy node the you need
to basically match all of these
selectors and if they do then there's
various PI policies which specify the
the tunnel moats suctioned tunnel mode
and which tunnels he specifically would
want to use and there's also the
possibility of including in there the
the mode that if if none of those
matched and you deny your route so it's
a fairly simple model I think
so we think the craft is in moderately
good shape in terms of possibly being
eligible for adoption vote we'd like to
ask people to look at the draft and send
comments to us we did happy to improve
it and working on update it and at some
point we think it'd be appropriate to
ask for working group adoption Rob
Wilson Cisco just one question is this
is this intended only as a device level
model or is intended as a service level
model or is it something could be used
in both places I think it's a little
more of a service level model right okay
hi my name is tarik sad whenever there
is some work that we're doing in these
working group to model the tunnels on
the device of the device as well as
steering on the tunnels so I'm not sure
if the scope is the provision the tunnel
in your model or for service steering on
the tunnels a little bit confused and is
it only packet layer tunnels that you're
interested in or basically maybe
stealing on SR policies also is in scope
its I think it's really kind of to do
with the the assumption that you're
you've established you said you're
establishing a VPN and you need to
select tunnel mechanisms that are being
used for that VP and that's the point of
view it came from if there's a related
drafts we yeah these are all your
attention key this into the authors are
to the list whatever sure okay thank you
Pawan biram speaking is TCA the drafts
that Tariq alluded to both of them are
on the agenda this afternoon
if you want to check it out I don't
remember if I were conflict but it
sounds good Thank You Igor Pushkin
however basically I just wanted to add
same thing with Derek and poana saying
we have quite a few documents which
describe how services are mapped on
tunnels and explicitly and implicitly
for say for example through tunnel pools
and how you actually separate the couple
services from the mapping and who
exactly maps services or tunnels and
stuff like that so it seems like overlap
here so basically it may be well wrap
things should be merged or whatever then
around Jeff as I looked at your draft
you know the you know model is perfectly
fine for a lot of applications I think
the thing you're gonna run into is
something some of the other models an
ITF have a tendency to run into is your
sort of namespace squatting on a really
nice name for an application that is
potentially too narrow so I can offer by
example the access control model that
got worked out and also partially here
which gets used in very specific
applications that really is not a
completely generalize ACL model but it
was very useful for things like mud and
other applications so my suggestion is
the models file could you be working on
it I consider changing the name to be
something a little less generic okay
tough my suggestion on the reading of
the document was that it's more better
for a device model as in when you
configure vrf you want to configure the
tunnel policy along with it and specify
that this is my preference or this is
the particular tunnel that I wanted to
be binded so when I read it to me my gut
feeling is device and the other work
that's happening in T's with respect to
service mapping at a higher there so
then I think it will be a very clear
demarcation or where the work stops and
where the work is happening my
suggestion okay
we Berger the other T's co-chair if your
focus is really on tunnels
I think the work should come to T's and
you'll find that
all of it is there except that maybe a
couple of pieces of information you
might want to add or you may find it's
all there if your focus is more on the
VPN information you you do whatever you
want maybe best this is a better place
but you'll need to coordinate with those
models that are being developed in T's
so either way you want to know about
those but depending on what your focus
is you may find you just want to either
merge or use what's there in T's okay
all right thanks thanks for all the
informative comments and I would expect
you to coordinate with TS to see what
should and could be done okay thank you
so next up is Rob Wilton talking about
the ARP yang model and I apologize I
left this off the list of the working
group documents but I've added it now so
this is a working group document that
we're talking about here
you've probably hit saturation on yang
model say this one would be quite quick
so hopefully you won't fall asleep it's
not very much just recap what this model
cover there are some basic art
functionality in the ITF IPM what also
that allows you to configure dynamic
artworks then static ARP entries so what
this draft is covering is the extra bits
of art that are not in ITF IP the lots
of vendors have support for as I've
covered examples this like our packet
statistics on interfaces proxy up
configuration and great arc
configuration so this is the current
free on the latest draft we've actually
into the updates and I go there's the
next couple of slides what we've been
doing we've simplified it and taken some
stuff out that we didn't have consensus
on between the authors on the fact that
everyone's implementing these in the
same way and I've highlighted two leaves
there that I'll talk about a little bit
more one is the in a belief for grata
and the second one is a discontinuity
time timestamp 3 for the statistics but
as you can see here this is a pretty
basic model there's one extra global
leaf there's a bit more stuff on the
interfaces and then augment ation in
terms of an expiry time next slide
please
so what have we changed mainly it's been
editorial improvements to improve the
introduction text the security sections
we just tried to improve that those
we've also gone through and cleaned up
their model a little bit more we
simplified it in places as I said we've
taken a few things out we try to line
the line the configuration at the global
level and at the interface level to make
it more consistent for hierarchical
config we've taken out global static ARP
in trees and I take taken out the art
probe configuration again that wasn't
standard and there was a great ARP drop
configuration flags also also been
removed what else we've done so there
was a dynamic global default setting
that's now on by default and to try and
make that more intuitive as I said align
the global interface configuration
together so that these are the same
names and the same defaults formatting
has been improved and then I've added
this content this continuity timestamp
for the ARP counters now this is the one
one of the issues I would like to raise
to get feedback what people think about
this as the next slide so of the two
issues the first one is there's a set of
art statistics that we're reporting that
unlike the number of part packets
received what the type of those packets
were and the ones that were sent and the
question is is whether the art
statistics should have their own
discontinuity counter to say when those
counters are from a what point to those
counters actually count from now there's
a few choices here I've added one in
here another choice would be to say just
reuse the interfaces interface counters
discontinuity counter so you'll assume
that the ARP counters would get reset if
you reset the interface counters and the
to align that's one choice you could
keep this separate as I've done here or
perhaps you could say it's
implementation to fine so you could say
that if this count is provided by the
implementation that's what it means and
it doesn't then it's up to the
implementation to specify so there's
anyone have any opinions on this on how
which way we think we should go we don't
hear anything back then we'll discuss
with the authors we're all updating one
way or another and see if anyone objects
working with law school and thoughts
jeff has so it does seem a little bit
weird that you do have it there and I
have two pieces of thinking and that
based on classical SNMP type your moobs
if you really do have to separate
internal subsystems that can have
distinct discontinuities having that
sort of thing make sense yeah
that said in not paying as much
attention to gang models as I used to
but I think this is the first time I've
actually seen
a specific sub-module have its own just
can't do anything yang has been sort of
architecting itself towards like a
cohesive view of things so you're now
putting in a hint to the system that
some pieces of a tree could have a
completely different idea of counters
than the other one and that makes
correlating the two very tricky so and I
think mean like when the root is
rebooted which is one standard
discontinuity time I'm thinking more
that sometimes if somebody's come along
and clear statistics for some purposes
and that's the one I'm worried about and
maybe in the young model you just don't
allow that you don't clear the
statistics you always just take her if
you want to see the change you take a
stamp at one point of time and look at
another one and in terms of the
subsystems in terms what you say it
might be better then for this not to be
in the model and if a vendor wants to do
that they Anna added in their own model
and they modify the description States
to say this is how it's changed that
might be a bit safer right so okay yeah
I don't think it's necessarily a wrong
idea but I do think that it's sort of
novel and rather making arty gwg the the
victim of something that's interesting
maybe the core conversation off the net
mad because this is a more journal at
that one yeah okay thank you the second
issue again is a minor one so at the
moment in the model the gratuitous ARP
settings the interface has been left as
effectively no no standard default so
it's up to the vendor implementations to
decide whether they do gratuitous art by
default and whether it's on or off by
default and then it gets explicit use a
way for a client to be able to decide to
turn it on or off I wonder I sort of
don't like these ambiguous defaults in
yeah models I think it makes them harder
to use so my question is would it be
better to actually say the crow Tudor
SARP is on by default and that would
make life a bit easier for clients and
things but I didn't know whether that's
okay to actually say well that's right
thing to do
sorry Bob likes the microphone this is a
thing that platforms are going to have
an opinion and if you choose something
in the default battle you'll be wrong
for some platforms
that's maybe okay because they still
have a choice to deviate it and they
have a choice to deviate and remove it
they have a choice to deviate and change
it I so we've had this case with has
come up internally about autonegotiation
on interfaces watch the default billion
and I Triple E has changed what their
position is over time was that as that
technology has matured and so in I
Triple E that's on by default whereas
our management model has it off and
people arguing internally to say all
this make it ambiguous but I just see
that's really hard nobody knows whether
it's on or off until they explicitly
configure I don't think it's easier so
that's why I'm are you need to try and
say look try and get rid of these
ambiguous e-force where we can but Eve
if it's truly the case that everyone's
different here then you have to leave it
vague I think I think what's people that
have a good security standpoint but
argue that off is probably the same
thing to do the thing that I based on
your comment you may want to it
specifically put a comment in the module
that the module should survive
deviations to actually cover the system
for other things okay that seems
practical and I think I've got one more
slide and suggest in terms of the
remaining work I think we're fairly
close to being done on this I thing and
there's made a little bit more tied up
and clean up those two issues we can act
as an update the draft so I think for
maybe we might not have that much more
to be done before we're ready so would
be fair to say after resolve both issues
we'll start with young the three of you
yes I think so great thank you next up
is Greg mirskiy
thank you um so this is okay this is
update on talk I had probably one
meeting that we're getting there well
yeah thank you so when how it started
looking at how new encapsulation define
om whether it's om that in a header of
encapsulation or active om special
specialist specially constructed test
packet came to realize that there is
some inconsistency in might be
discussion would be helpful to bring
solution that make it useful for
different protocols thank you appreciate
it okay so that was the problem
statement looked at new encapsulations
in SFC beer and we were three that
includes GUI genève the excellent GPE
and beer okay next slide so we had some
progress made in SFC nsh definition of
interpretation of opiate and how active
I am defined RFC 8300 defined orbit as
when it said it indicates an oem packet
and in a document with effectively
addresses and discusses SFC active om we
agreed to clarify that setting this bit
indicates that om command or data are in
an SH context header or packet payload
so and this document proposes active om
encapsulation so can we go to the next
slide because with the fact that we have
obit and we have next protocol field
there will come number of combinations
and this draft now defines the
combinations so if we have a beach set
and the value of next protocol is not
one of a em protocols because we might
have activeness of coem or we might have
I am or might be some other protocol
then there oh em dad ER are included in
either fixed header or variable length
context header that followed directly
the based header of NS H so this example
demonstrates that so let's go next if
obit set and the next protocol is one of
the protocols associated with OEM then
the payload that follows immediately
after an SH header includes OAM data or
command
and so this illustrates whether it's a
fixed header or variable length context
header next if Oh beat is clear and next
protocol is not one of the protocols
associated with OEM then this is a user
data in the payload next protocol if a
beat is clear and the next protocol is
one of the protocols associated with OEM
this is erroneous situation okay next
breath so looked at what happen in other
protocols progress genève it was going
through a working group last call and
there was a discussion but the only
change that offer us did is they changed
attribution of obut from Orion packet to
control packet and which I believe still
leaves the question of our am
identification in Geneva very ambiguous
next slide well with the fixed size
header OEM well there is no change
because beer I believe already defined
it so it doesn't have all beat it uses
next protocol and om type of protocol
already being assigned by iana and the
explained GPE
yes there was introduced or bit but
draft expired so I don't know how it
will be revived progressed I would like
to discuss it with offers if they're
interested we might find some solution
for
the Excel NGP next slide well again
appreciate your questions comments I
don't see that this document has to
progress very far I'll be very happy if
there will be some consideration of what
we've done for
SFC a message for other variable-length
[Music]
encapsulations and that will enable work
on om for this network layers
thank you any questions to Greg and you
invert the draft Greg I think would be
great if you asked for reading on
mailing list and ask people to
participate no can do
thank you
yes on next presentation is about TI LFA
okay just as a reminder so today refa
stands for topology independent LFA so
it's a knight PFS reward mechanism it is
based on segment routing to build via
the backup path however it can protect
any kind of traffic whatever its IP MPLS
LDP or even MPLS RSVP if you want could
work as it could be seen as an evolution
of refe remotely Fillion and direct the
forwarding RFA just one step further the
added value we see in two pretty
independent NFA that first of all its
topology independence so we'll nffa
matter if a we always add an issue with
the coverage because sometimes depending
on the topology there was no possibility
to found the packet path and with jefa
whatever also topology you will have you
will always have a backup path available
which is pretty good and we ever think
you have a benefit coming with operation
independent RFA is that we are trying to
optimize the backup path that we are
using so ever was social document has
been added to the recently but Farwest
bunches of comments received even before
he adoptions a lot of comments were
about this notion of post convergence
path we were using which was quite
unclear but we will come back to that a
bit later there as was also some
question about the scaling of the
computation especially if we are trying
to compute a queue space for each
destination some comments were also
pointing some anchor points in the data
plane procedure especially in case of
snps when PHP was involved
yeah and
some of our comments but we would try to
cover them in the next slide so first of
all post-conversion staff the idea
behind LFA is to try to provide a backup
path which is I would say optimal this
could be this what could be a bit
challenge but yeah this is we global
right so let's take an example with this
topology so I have how to X which is
where with some P ingress P p1 and p4
which will send some traffic to P 3 and
P 2 and if the xB link is failing
forget via first we world for a moment
so traffic will be X will reroute the
traffic on XH or xD depending on the
destination so the traffic to p3 will be
sent on XH and the traffic to p2 will be
sent on xD but at the same time during
the convergence p1 will also possible
out some traffic so the traffic going to
p3 will still use the path a X and then
X - H but the traffic to p2 will not be
sent to X anymore so p1 we reroute the
traffic to cdef and p2 what could be
concluded from that from the X point of
view I would say optimal and well sized
path is to use X H of X d-link so from a
capacity planning point of view of the
network I need to ensure that when the x
building is failing I have enough
capacity on XH + XD link to support the
traffic that was previously on X B this
is true but not completely optimal
because some of traffic on xB is not
splitted on XH + XD because some of the
traffic
coming from p1 will go out from X naught
so some other traffic's that was
previously going through this path will
be rerouted there however depending on
the convergence order so if P one is
converging before X and if I'm sizing
the extension XD to support the traffic
on xB I'm old my oversizing a bit
zerlings which are there
however if X is converging before p1 am
i sizing my network sizing is good
because I'm able to support all the
traffic so the IDB int RFA is to try to
reuse this capacity planning concept so
from the point of local repair point of
view we will try to use the next
shortest path taking into account the
failure of the link so if we take into
account that xB link will potentially
fail now you want to protect against
this failure my I would say best optimal
path would be on XH or XD ok so the idea
of jefa is to build a backup path using
what we are calling s'posed convergence
path okay which is a wealth I staff this
is an assumption in terms of network
capacity planning some networks could do
other capacity planning in another way
if people are not really happy with this
post convergence path idea of jefa
we can still use the policy mechanism
that has been defined in a 1716 to be
able to tune of a backup path using
other criterias and hasan visa post
convergence perform next HP shortest
path
if you ever comments that we have
received about this post convergence
path is that it's not really the post
convergence path why because geography
is a first-world mechanism so it pre
computes a path for an expected failure
so let's say that I'm doing not
protection I will free computer path
taking into account that this node will
potentially fail however in reality
maybe the node will not fail maybe just
one link will fail our set of links will
fail so this leads to the fact that the
backup path that I will put on Shelly
use is not completely optimal because
it's optimal from an expected failure
point of view but it's not really
optimal of if the failure that is
happening is not the failure that I was
predicting and protecting for so that's
why before so we were using the notion
of post convergence path but we have
changed the wording to expected post
convergence that because we are
expecting so traffic to use this path
but yeah maybe if the failure is
different from the one I'm protecting
yeah so post convergence path will not
be exactly this one so in terms of
update to address this post convergence
path concerns that has been raised on
the list so we have added some reference
to the RFE 79 16 which was already
talking about via path optimality issue
especially in LFA on a remote area on
vironment so we also changed the warning
from post convergence path to expected
post convergence path to deal with this
potential not full optimality of the
Bekaa path and we have also really
explained the use case and the benefits
of using the
post comments before expected post
comment on special term of I don't need
anymore
policies to implement in a fast free
world if my capacity planning rule is
following just VI chips in shortest path
so it's really easy to easier to deploy
now regarding the scaling considerations
of a queue space computation that's not
really an easy issue because yeah an
easy topic because this is one of the
points that we need to discuss for this
draft is what is the level of detail we
want to put in in term of computation
algorithm do we want to do we expect to
have a full definition of an algorithm
to compute the backup path for a just a
concept that we are presenting in the
current version are enough because today
what we are doing is just to say that
okay we compute the post convergence
path so we compute an SPF based on are
taking into account the failure of the
component so SLG is another author link
and then we need to express this post
convergence path as a loop free path by
using not sidon adjacency but the
challenge is how to compress as this
labor stack to be to be minimum and here
we can reuse the p space and Q space
concept that we are defined in the
remote LFA drafts or RC 7490 and this
RFC was already talking about the
scaling issue if we are trying to
compute a queue space per destination so
this means computing your rivers SPF
rooted at each destination which is a
bit painful so remote LFA was
restricting itself to compute it just
from the point of view of the remote end
of link in case of link protection to
reduce the computer
but we are not at least today defining a
full algorithm we are just defining the
principles of the technology so we are
pointing miscarrying considerations to
the paragraph which is already existing
in the remote NFA RFC and we just say
that it will be implementation dependent
fight the good fight off between
optimization and computational that's
our proposal today to dealer to deal
with that now in case of data point
procedures so we did some work on
million the text try to be more
consistent in the wording we were using
because sometimes we were mixing I said
that a plain words like push next
continue and so on and sometimes we were
using MPLS push swept and so on so now
we are more consistent and we are using
unleash terminology we have also
introduced a normative language which
was clearly missing in the previous
version and the important point is that
in case of SNMP RS there are special
behaviors to deal with especially when a
penalty meta popping is involved so just
to give you one example when I'm trying
to protect a link which is called SF and
let's say that I have an incoming packet
so MPLS packets coming with an adjacency
seed at the top of the stack which is a
via SF in and not followed by a note
segment going to another 20 so the basic
behavior of CIL failing protection will
be to create a back path which match
back on the F node so we will create a
repair list which is a called year at EF
followed by another segment going to F
which is merging back as two to the
limit and over link however if our
repair lists
is so the fgf which is also a
combination of adjacency segment and
noodle segment is terminating by an
adjacency segment which will forward the
traffic on F we have an issue in case of
PHP because not you know the F is not
expecting to receive the node or segment
F because PHP has been requested so what
we need to do in this case is to not
push V naught V naught F we just put V
at least and via video segment so there
is a special behavior in case of PHP so
the draft was also limited in the
previous version to local SNL GK so we
have removed this restriction normally
there is nothing preventing is that to
make it working with global SLG and the
last one of the last points that we have
added is the relationship between
geography and the different algorithm
because when the idea of jefa was was
built it was at the time where only the
default algorithm was available in a
segment routing so the default algorithm
is just a regular SPF but now we have
the strictest PF and we have also v-flex
algo one comment that has been raised is
that when i'm trying to protect a noodle
segment which is using the default SPF
and when I'm using a noodle segment in
the repair list which is also using the
default SPF there is a possibility that
a local policy may override the path
that the noodle segment is using because
the default a SPF algorithm allows an
operator to add local policies that
could override this path
which the cuckoo's consequence of that
is that possibly the path may not be
looped free anymore if the local policy
is changing the path towards something
which is different from the shortest
path so one remark about that is that
such local policy could even break today
LFA or remotely fail or even Vig be
shortest path it's not just not
something related to TI LFA so it's
really a matter of network design to
create local policies that will keep the
network loop free so that's why you
think that it's a responsibility of the
operator to ensure that this local
policy will not break the loop free
nests of the shortest path the other
solution which could be to protect an Al
Gore zero not seed by using nodal
segments that are using the algorithm
number one so algorithm number one is
called a strict SPF and restrict SPF is
exactly the regular xpf except that we
can't have a local policy okay it can't
be overridden it's always via shortest
path so by using strict SPF instead of
regular instead of algorithm algo zero
sorry in the repair list we ensure that
the root freeness will never be broken
the second point about flex algo is that
we could make a nfa working with flex
algo we just need to ensure that if I'm
protecting not seed which is using a
particular flex algo I just need to use
in the repair list some not seeds that
are using exactly the same flex I'll go
and eat all my optimization algorithm
instead of using the regular SPF for
every SPF I'm using the same C SPF
constraints
that are part of the spec salvo but in
theory it should work
so next step so we try to address all
the comments that we have received on
the list I hope that we have not missed
any better if we missed some comments or
if you have additional comments feel
free to raise your voice they are of
course points to discuss especially this
last point about tal FA jana si algo
relationship and if we want to set a
strict rule for example to protect and
not cede with alcohol only with some
nodal segments with algo one do we want
to set it as a master or not and yeah
the main point of so that we need to
agree on is what is the level of details
that we are expecting in this document
in terms of computation steps
is it enough to set only the concept as
we are doing today or the working group
does a working upfront to a full
algorithm to date in the document so I'd
like to comment on your previous slide
so I'm kind of worried that we're losing
the unconditional correctness that we
had in the original fast reroute
concepts particularly is if anything
goes wrong in fast reader not only will
you've lost all the reasons that you've
put it there but it's going to be an
absolute devil to debug because these
are really transient the bugs will be
transient because these properties are
only supposed to be in place transiently
now I suppose your second suggestion is
probably the the least worse in the
Thunder fundamentally you should really
repair within the topology that the that
you're operating in and that would
suggest that unless you do - you really
are headed off to all kinds of very
strange bugs in your network
eggwin
I would support the suggestion perhaps
stronger language to only support single
algorithm real with regards to
computation and perhaps we could talk to
you
Alice Aris well to see their opinion so
so um I'm with respect to that point I
think perhaps for you know option one of
you know local policy sort of spelling
out the scenarios where or an example
scenario where you could create create
loops even in a normal you know
unexpectedly you can spell that out a
little better so that you know what what
level of consistency do you need like to
to to avoid that in and mainly just in
the the topic of the local policy being
in fact TILs hmm right now what what
consistency do you need to avoid loose
yeah yeah the main touch video an issue
not a concern but uh it sounds just
strange to me to say that let's say that
for Al Gore's you will not sit I'm just
able to use algo one not sit and for
let's say that we want to apply this to
flex algo which means also that we need
to define a kind of sibling algorithm
for each flex algo to be a strict flex
algo yeah I agree
why not but yeah this means the
consequence of that is that we need
twice times the number of algorithms
that we are really requiring I'm not
sure the I'm not sure whether you need
twice to part again whether you need
twice as many algorithms but I think the
fundamental is
that you need to operate entirely within
a single Tripoli a single what I call
topology I don't sure where that's the
right term so that there is always
mutual consistency in the in the network
in terms of what the path and what the
alternative paths are and the packets
are tracked within that topology so it's
true anything else I think is a a route
to all kinds of there's a really serious
transient bugs that are so difficult to
debug that people will never deploy it
hmm I agree a bit of shock from Cisco so
I don't think we need a strict topology
or I'll go for every regular algo that'd
be that very fine I mean it has been
expressed here that we can have these
loops which the regular algorithm right
so I think that will be an over
engineering honestly Peter your
statements really generic so from your
point of view should allow TILs play
with non congruent outdoor spaces is it
what your suggestion absolutely not
I think the the LFA should be computed
within the context of the single
operator okay so we we all agree on the
constraints yeah
so next up we have a remote presentation
of perfect timing from Stephen wood -
okay
another
[Music]
okay great Jeff are you getting cocaine
yes the money's coming very good
excellent
okay so this is kind of first step from
after the Montreal meeting where we were
presenting on SD possible iced tea when
it's working models and so this is our
first cut a draft to define OSD service
delivery models for inter working
between and different vendor estimates
so good my name is Steve wood I'm
Francisco getting a SD mine and
architecture a bit technical marketing
and my contributors are both which
enable from Huawei has both Conrad
missus HP please continue so just to
again overall motivation what we're
trying to do we're not trying to create
a standard protocol and management
protocols control protocols for the
interoperability of devices in an SD
when we are trying to create into
working protocol at standardization
between and wealth between SD lands at
well-defined interfaces next so this is
our reference architecture which we have
created in the open estimate exchange as
part of the open network users group our
own luck which I am one of the chairs of
so this model attempts to define the
interfaces of which around which we will
stand it up and you can see the
interfaces around the outside focus of
today's presentation is primarily
interfaces to allow for communication
and setting of path management
information sending a path management
information into the SD when transport
network so the next slide so this gives
a better view of how the how they use
case maps
right now to the previous whoever can be
stopped right now
when is he sending that management I'll
see for the vendor within each estimate
I made to do the proper enforcement of
that path of management let's see let me
interrupt you for one moment could you
sort of go back 30 seconds because your
voice was completely garbled by the
transmission Thanks
okay go back no just start from the
beginning of the slide okay this slide
covers the initially used cases we have
in the draft you can see up here that we
have a definition of act surf management
service model the goal of that service
model is to define the parameters needed
to put particular applications and flows
on a specific path within an SD when the
third use case number one as to define
the path management policy service model
and the definition of the enforcement
how that path management service model
should be enforced within each st LAN
domain okay
the second use case or model we've
created is a gateway service model which
defines the interoperability
interoperate interoperating
and I between two SP one as you can see
here at the gateway edges for achieving
a connection between two sp1 vendors so
of course there are many ways to do this
[Music]
there are many ways to do this so we are
trying to lock down a standard way so
that it can be exported in all different
vendor controllers mmm okay let's go to
the next slide so this gets in to the
structure now of the game model for each
of those use cases so you can see here
we have defining a set of parameters to
allow communication between an upper
layer Orchestrator which is not defined
as part of the the RFC but the idea is
to create a set of yang
which could be used to create an API
that could define reach ability the
parameters between the gateways so we
have a reach ability service model which
has roughly the functionality singing
here
oscy gateway creation within each domain
the Gateway configuration for PGP or
multi port called BGP and Cokely parent
as well as the underlay connection setup
and the overlay tunnel setup either a
grea or IB CENTCOM in addition in
addition we have an API we have got a
model that allows us to do a segment
instance creations or cross connect
between the Kea the segments on one st
one domain and the companion st
Lindemann as well the new models created
containing path service model that can
is set up to the specified parameters
needed for dynamic path selection
already across the main traffic and
configuration next slide
ok gets here into a little bit more of
the guts of the gateway service model
design itself so this is specifically
looking at some of the details of the
Gateway service model we have here as
you can see a list of our gateways
basically the ability to create a
gateway work query where Gateway lists
within an st Winder domain and then you
can see that we have as well tunnel
parameters parameters control control
plane configuration so you have two
options there we have a reach ability
exchange using multiple high speed
Steve the meet echo team wants you to
disable your video so that the audio
goes through so that we can avoid issues
thank you
okay hopefully this will be better
okay great
okay so we have two options for control
plane carrying one is using both the
protocol php-based evpn or l3 VPN style
of communication or either working and
then they have fuss you know standard
simply simple opportunity birth flight
type of control plane and different
interfaces capability so this capability
can be negotiated between controllers
what's supported and then set up the
data planning configuration parameters
that we have here are for setting up GRE
capsulation
as my voice covering some clicking ok
and also of and security and open have a
face I xx and a VPN so we're expecting
for the most part that IV site VPN will
be the option that's used alright and
then you can see as well we have a
segment mapping list a lot of users to
not even from us connect you know it's
definition is to be we need SP wet
islands ok let's go ahead and do it to
the next month
okay this this is the path management
service model design so the path
management policy is really ordered list
of traffic classifiers along with an SLA
list and then the selection old or
preferred path selection policy okay
what we will do is have a first match
against air traffic classifiers that
believe then would be applied to the
linking path policy which is then
contained in the SLA that's associated
with those links in past we can see that
tree model diagram up here the idea here
is that we have a definition of
application or application flow with
classifiers you can see that is attached
to a link in path definition policy so
which meant I should prefer based on
based on the conditions on the link or
based on my policy if I want to prefer a
specific private network or as a
specific business party flying for
example and then any kind of unique and
performance SLA information so we have a
name for that isolating we have delayed
parameter lost you mean opinion score as
the main performance as initiative
parameters yes Steve we lost about 50
percent I'm serving as cosmonaut
expecting such a bad form it's in the
middle of thank you I don't know if this
is going to work or not is I can kind of
hear some clicking of mine good line
anyway I'll try one more time
but the yes one of your colors is here
and we've been losing about 60 70
percent of what you were saying so it
could you could probably create a study
we have that back up so please go ahead
and apologize and thank you for goodness
yes thank you
and actually Steve okay sorry further
connection and this past management
service model is actually used for the
traffic for cross domain the domain a
belongs to one vendor domain and domain
B belong to another one so there is a
because in UNIX reference model that the
oxidation layer is a quite light quite
light one that ox just oxidative for the
application they aware service policy or
other like the previous one that the
Steve just described about the owner the
gateway and then I interface connection
setup model so these two model can can
help the owner that this UNIX reference
model architecture to to describe the
what their service requirements is
actually they they don't want to touch
the like the domain ace a device setup
or the infrastructure setup all the UNIX
reference a framework is based on the
the each domains infrastructure setup
belongs to the each domains controller
as the one controller and orchestration
will just help the how to set have the
cross domain traffic to that kind of
policy so and the past management here
is very typical as divine service that
it needs to that it it means that in
anak scenario there will be like
multiple paths
for each site that connected to the the
one network maybe like private MPR's
network or the internet work so but in
the ox tration have the like the two
domains topology or the like and an SLA
information so they can divide the like
the cross domains
traffic s s SL a's requirements dividing
into two separate domain then the end
and SLA can be guaranteed so that's a
this model so we'll go five minutes over
till 11:05 just so you have a reference
point because of the technical
difficulties and so on yes so I will on
to the open issues because this is just
a very initial draft here and we are
working on to make it more clear and
more complete because right now the own
acts service modeling is a customer
facing model so they rely on the the
infrastructures control playing protocol
defined in IETF because that's ITF
expertise and and ona also notice there
are some work on the ITF to do this kind
of work so so we will like update our
service model depending on those work
the ITF and also we still have other
open issue with paths like specific
domains a traitor loss that kind of a
sow a measurement requirements how can
we do that with you that's the an open
issue choose so so this time it's a
quite initial draft so we would like to
have more were review and feedback can
we can like to collect more review and
feedback to help us to create a very
yes oh yes women Eric's from Nokia okay
I think I I think it's good work that is
it's going on in general I was wondering
with respect to the services itself like
layer 2 VPNs and layer 3 VPN are you in
I haven't really read the draft in all
details are you going to reuse l2 as I'm
and I'll 3sm for depth in this draft or
because the focus of this draft is
mainly about the gateway and the
interoperability yes as well as the port
management but what are you i is the
proposal to be used for let's say l2 or
l3 VPN actually I do as you want
are you it we don't touch that part
because it depends on the domain
specific implementation that belongs to
the service controller in each domain
that would how can those you use either
use a VPN based as d1 or l3 VPN based as
the one is depends on the different
domain yes but I think ITF did some work
on l2 as M&L 3sm as a as an abstraction
layer on top of that so I think it would
be good to also leverage that work
somehow in the space yeah oh that has
their own specific requirements because
they don't they just described the
enterprise own network they don't like
designed this reference architecture for
the managed service provider they don't
touch that scenario so are you talking
about between the gateway device itself
to their send off we assume we have I
haven't looked at those traps but is
that you talking about yes yeah I
actually actually across the board
because what you're trying to define is
an end-to-end service right so we should
actually try to abstract the
implementations on the needs and I think
then it's not only about interconnection
it's not only about the path selection
mechanism but also the end-to-end
service which you define either within
or even across the different scenarios
the what's the service is almost like as
a piecewise service it's SD window main
one whatever it gets done in their
gateway SD when ku so we're trying to
stitch things together and I'm trying to
create a single line but what I'm trying
what I'm getting to it
it's to have a full service definition
for SD wanna as a service as a complete
service suite rather than doing a bit
here and a bit there so that you have
one definition and you say okay this
draft is what you have to look for this
is your as the one service definition
model and this will not only cover the
bad management not only the interworking
but also the end-to-end service layer I
think if we do that yes we probably
serve the industry at good it's it's
good for the industry because then they
can say okay this draft this is your
this reference model from the yang for
SD want services okay so we should
probably cut this off here you know
potentially we could have more
discussion on Friday but also discuss
discuss this offline and and you know
thank you thank you thank you for
stepping in we apologize for the
technical difficulties thank you and we
have another session on Friday so we'll
see whoever wants to be there then see
on Friday
[Music]
you