[Music]
hello see spring working with whoever
added a so we are about to start please
find a seat
there are plenty of seats
so hello
as you can see Robby's onliner
having a coffee hi Rob so it's a Bing
remote an emetic oh and so does a
Martina so we're going to start in
square footage on ah so this is the
usual node whele
so please please read it and you have to
not impact occurs at by participating in
the IDF you agree to flow IGF processes
on policies more details on the
following PCB we need a JavaScript with
any volunteer and also a minute taker is
that is to to relate the questions for
remote participants any volunteer for
algebra
thank you so two slides on the joint
progress since the IGF 103 we have draft
MSD C which has been approved by iesg
Antron status is our editorial so it's
mostly finished for for working group
then you have the assalam PS document
which we have submitted to iesg for
publication and current status is
waiting for writer and then we have NP
dispatch segment with which we have just
adapted as a working document for the
remaining document a duck we have a
service six network programming which is
currently in coal for adoptions for at
least a week so please please comment on
on radio we're segment routing policy
which would be ready for watching what
Nebraska also we have SRA owner which
also should be ready for one last column
so this is a proposed agenda for today
its a four-dollar so please stick to
your timer which include presentation on
questions any any comment on general
we don't have come under cherries for
Daniella the full floor chose a pink
pink rs.12 okay so my name is Daniel -
Bell Canada I'm going to present similar
rotting point-to-multipoint but just
before I start just a few points right
now one of my co-conspirator woman is
giving the same presentation on the pin
working group we are collaborating a lot
also with jeffrey from Jennifer who's I
think he's in the room somewhere yeah
okay another point also is the version
zero of this graph has been published
for June last June for Montreal then we
have version one for the last ITF
Bangkok and the third one is right now
so the motivation for this graph is
pretty straightforward for the service
provider is the IPTV use case we are
also open and there's other use cases
for point to any kind of point to
multi-point MP as multicast technologies
also valid the goal and the motivation
is also to simplify multicast by
removing some particles RSP Tem LTP
while providing traffic engineering
similar thing Boyce these attributes
which also refer to the signal routing
policy drive it also to make the network
infrastructure friendly programmable so
this is a crusade of trying to remove
and use less particle as possible okay
so SR education it's a
point-to-multipoint segment that connect
a root node to a set of leaves node in
the segment rotting domain so it is
expected that this is to be run in the
same irritating environment
we define two type of
point-to-multipoint segments spray and
tree said stray point-to-multipoint
segment enables a root node to directly
replicate a packet using a sr path to
each leaf node it's kind of ingress
replication
whereas tree said will run with a
controller so the controller computes a
tree from a root node to a set of
beliefs node via a set of Ricochet
replication node a packet is relegated
from the node the root node and
replicated throwers each note at the end
of the tree we rely on the current asar
policy as i mentioned so the SR
education policy is a variant of NSR
policy as the Jeff as a per se stated
and applies equally to spray or tree set
point to multi-point segment unless
explicitly specified it can be
provisioned on the root or on via a
controller everything happens at the
contour finally it's defined the
following element the root node this is
the adhan of the point multi-point
segment leaf node is a set of note that
determined the point to multi-point
segment and there is some constraint
from a traffic engine perspective with
the PCE for the calculation of the tree
a segment or a thing application
policies and a fight through the topple
root load and tree ID so in a natural SR
Education use extensively PC everything
happened at the PCE it is expected that
it will run in the Syngman writing
environment as I explained explained a
tree set point to multi-point cement
packet replicate occurs at the root node
and on the replication note or worse the
leaf node he could sue to the drawings
nothing happened at the transit node or
anywhere if there is more than one
transit note a SR vacation policy can be
Estancia 'td and maintained in a
centralized fashion using a path
competition element as I mentioned no
Barnaby I will be used to
delete and update the tree a tree can be
accentuated from a PC via an account
piece a PGP te cetera
local protection and pap petition can be
applied using a cell policy compute
computed at a PC
now there's other working progress these
are the working progress that will fit
in this architecture framework it is
already published the SR PCE draft
version 0 you can find it with this name
there's also an MVP end draft that is
also published version 0 upcoming work
will be a sabe 6-3 said there's nothing
published yet but it will come maybe by
the time of the next ITF and the
reference document as I mentioned a
couple times DSR policy as we know that
is in this working group and that's it
we're looking for working group adoption
questions comment from Holly I have a
comment as we all know that there are
draft to describe as a v6 for beer so I
could like to know what's the difference
between these two solutions thank you
I haven't looked at the services or beer
maybe I can come back to you with this
question
the oesophagus the spray one is is an
ingress in a v6 environment maybe there
would be a good question with the Asahi
six upcoming tree said ok thanks yeah
could you could you send an email on the
mailing list with the numbers a draft
could you send an email on the list with
the name of the drives because I don't
think we've ever seen the drafting in
spring
so far yes just one comment is the
retainer here is a different data plane
and this is using existing data pain or
for Assad we see if we use against how
this is it a plane so there is a
difference anything else
no more questions
so please a filter it will comment on
joist to Mac Sigma routing based
abundant latency I believe the draft is
to be worked on in debt net so one
question I do not tell you to give me
yes you not work you need what is the
plan first we take some time is through
to see there are comments on the list um
and we discuss between Charlson but I'd
normally wait for the previous call for
adoption to finish which is calling
network programming but we will
definitely come back to you in a few
weeks itself Schumann's but before the
next meeting and can be good to see some
form of discussion on the list of it I
don't know if if we've kind of announced
this draft or discussed on the list at
all no it has been discussed quite a bit
then did a fantastic but yeah
in your document so thank you Mike okay
okay hello everyone this is an action
I'm going to present this signal routing
based upon it latency they stripped
submitted to attend networking group
represent here because that we tried
because we are trying to use Sigma
routing to support on the latency so we
would like to solicit solicit comments
and feedback from this working group and
maybe I follow-up work to be done in
this working group so here's the
motivation of this trapped so as if you
are familiar to the 80s on internet you
will know that one of the cause of the
net is to achieve untoned on the latency
and the time based scheduling is one of
them and when we load that signal team
is a very scalable solution that can
support large number of flows without
returning per flow state as interim area
node and it was not so restrict try to
combine signal routing and time-based
scheduling to him to implement only
vacancy then we can try to provide fun
scalable Android latency control
solution so here it is a example shows
how time based scheduling verbs the
cycling queuing and forwarding is a
mechanism defending a troponin 40s on
but it can also apply to ten eight
network in city of the sending time of
an interface is divided into a series
time interval and each interval is
called cycle and the situation tag
assumed and required that when sending a
packet from a load in a cycle that
packet must be received in the same
cycle at the downstream end node
and the tongue streaming out must
translate that package out in the next
cycle in this way you can see that a
packet where only is the one cycle at
the hop on the pass so you can see that
the end to end on the latency can be
very easy to calculate it that is the
hobbs times they cycle so you can see
does Sekulow feels very smart solution
but it also has its own limitations so
it is more suitable for small networks
where the dink delay is trivial and the
processing delay in general is small
otherwise more balloons has to be
reserved to as gulp and for each cycle
in order to make sure that a secure F
can be can work as designed so there's
an undergrad in the networking group
which is called not skilled
deterministic IP networking it is using
tend to be a framework document that
introduces several ways to to implement
cycle based that is a latency can
control so you want to know some details
to read a draft so hairy description is
written quite sweet world we call it
psycho specifically and forwarding as I
introduced in the previous slides CTO of
does not consider intelligence it'll
link delay and other constraints and if
just assume that a packet will only one
like one cycle and it's at all but this
will not work for a lab work really link
delay is not trivial and the percentile
a and the other constraints are not can
be you know not so here the search care
just you can just treat it as an
improvement to a city of it by
introducing our Pascal calculation and
take the link delay and other
constraints into consideration after the
pass calculation we can do that for a
packet which cycle is appropriate to
transmit it with the it will state
calculate in a result information we can
specify our this any cycle of a of a
packet at every node on the path so this
way we can you know direct how to
transmit a packet and on the path and
then depending on this it can be
achieved
Sabino figure is our example shows how
this circle if it works you can see that
Rebecca X it is supposed just supposed
to be transmitted from load a through BC
and to Elodie and after the pass
calculation the Peck is supposed to be
send it out in cycle 1 at node a and the
in cycle or 3 an don't be a cycle for a
lot C and psycho sex LOD so well at the
universe you can just attach a saddle
list to the packet then the packet can
use to direct how to trust me the packet
are on the path so you can find that
this is very similar to signal routing
the list so in order to achieve this we
introduce a new segment which is called
a cycle segment the psycho segment has
two meanings the first one yes either
just as the adjacent segment it identify
you can identify our interface on length
in addition to that you can also
identify our cycle of that link for
example interphase collocate 3 says but
all from the routing point of view all 3
says just identify that link but it's
each seeds can identify different
psychos
so by attaching or sight a psycho safe
segment to the package it can specify
which interface in which psycho or
package should be sent out so by
attaching a list of sites acumen to the
packet then you can specify the Sun in
cycle the each load along the path and
and result introduce any per flow state
at the intermediate intermediate load
and request note and the most
importantly the bundle latency can be
achieved in this way so here it is
unknown instead example shows how SR
amperes can be used to support
CSUF I think the figure is very
straightforward a big ingress we can use
the classical computation is more
information to specify the satellites
and attach the subtlest to the packet
and the fact that list will be used by
each load on the path to determine
whether and which which cycle should be
sent out similar to the SR NP r--'s
there are six can be also used as well
so the next step would like to know so
less is more requirement and more review
and comments and refine the track
economy and those certain may be known
follow-up extension working this
wouldn't grow to you know to advertise
the sec psycho Sigmund so far I think
the only comment I have is if you can
come cycles for me cycles and then you
have links and it has to be much better
than that would be and then all the
images
are you talking about yeah I think the
cycle can be grow favor but it's not
necessary to allocate you know for each
cycle to allocate corresponding seeds we
can be for example fine interface based
our practice I think is it's may be
enough to allocate three sales for
interface then we can use the seeds in
our cyclic way for example our cycle one
you seek one cycle two we will see two
cycles reuse century and so for you said
one can use this in a cyclic whaling
from your broadcast to gives us an
example with recycles but it's not clear
if it's an example or if it's real
number indeed it would be good if you
can elaborate on to scatter its clarity
because we are not familiar with that
net so Himanshu from sierra i have a
clarification question as well how would
an intermediate known would know that
all the head and would know that this
cycle i was not already filled I mean
how can you be so deterministic there
could be other non other traffic also
going on right so it could be very
difficult to know that particular packet
will go at the right time at right cycle
because that middle node would also be
doing something else right this cycle
can only be used by the critic
homelessness for other no best-effort
traffic you can use other seats fix them
for the best terraces man maybe but this
is the only use for those traffic
cricket records it would in to work with
other segments Road in traffic yeah you
have to differentiate
dead net flow and non-tender flow so we
used the same
to differentiate that so that means you
have to your different seat for
different traffic okay yeah I guess the
big girls are in your draft okay yeah
and then what happens if you miss the
cycle if there's a miscalculation you
think they don't mean to any way we can
yes I I didn't like Shelley Spears let's
hear from your search and no a flan
discussion about it no what I'm saying
is that if you went to a node and the
cycle means I think this will be cyclic
right if I sum some slot in the in the
video fair queuing so that is amazing
then you do you wait for the next one or
what happens would be good to have it so
if I could are not clear since I can
often discussion alright but what Java
is saying is that if you missed a
specific slot on that particular
interface now you will have to wait for
next cycle right and that would increase
the latency that you were expecting
yeah that that means there are some
arrow happen on that load that's yeah
that's a no failure condition so then
that doesn't have some requirement on
the traffic pattern that means the
traffic has been no transmitted as known
as a way it required that means for the
the rate the packing rate is is no
before ways established pass that means
we know the traffic pattern
so it would be good if you could try
fire what you're asking from the spring
working group in your draft I'm just
seeing one one section which is a spring
latina it's about alpha alpha beta is it
that that section that we that we would
you'd like us to review or yes I think
here we just want to know solicit more
comments and feedbacks from the signor
important point of you know whether it
is available not during the enhancement
and optimizations and suggestions and
there may be known as as I said inner
side not sites may be follow-up works to
be telling this watcher working group
that means there's some no need to some
extensions today IDP and something like
that you know to advertise this psycho
segment can you initiate an email the
very least least your questions okay no
discussion there is a question is that
you're only talking both segments up
just as segments is it in proposal or do
you plan to extend to prefix segment
biding Theodore because we have
different kind of segments within the
autumn systems on between alternate
systems and you're just talking about
one so do you new an in wanna yeah I
think we actually we have considered the
existing segment segment types that we
think there is better to know to define
new type of segments because this is you
know the tenor traffic has to be you
know field
different from the other packet so they
have you need to have some dedicated
segments to differentiate that
I understand you want a different
segment but my question is the scope of
the change that you would need to bring
to spraying it's okay I think for me
it's okay domine from Holly I think
until now because this is the resource
to occur in here so the bounty the
latency is the Pahlavi the agency so we
think and now we first think about this
agency segment but maybe later we can
think more about other types of the
segment if we use the relate here is the
chemical and here this is for worthy
okay I think we need to move to the next
presentation thank you okay thank you
next is Josue Evans in Francois
before giving the floor to Francois
nef 103 we had proposed to add a
discussion about segment service
chaining with segment routine and we
proposed to meet for that tf-idf so we
have a ALPHAN our discussion about
segment routing on service chaining we
have two presentation from to draft the
good is not ready to detail the draft
not to discuss the graph but to provide
an overview to to initiate the
description so we have two to sort of
six minutes
one for each draft and then the main
goal is to discuss the subject and then
we have 20 minutes
one two good
so I'm from San Francisco and I'm going
to present disrupt on on the alpha of my
cultures this is the service programming
with segment roti
so first the scope of this draft in this
draft we define basically two things
first how to process a service segment
with MPLS sign with sigma13 v6 and also
how to enter service metadata that would
be attached to the packet we also
illustrate into draft how service
segments can be integrated with other
types of segments of for example
underlay of topological segments but the
fact that a service can be associated
with a segment is not something new
the concept of service segment has been
defined in RFC 84 2 and there's a
monitoring policy architecture in draft
IETF spring segmentation policy also
allows for the combination of service
and topological segments in the same
seed list this combination is actually a
seamless integration between the between
the segments and it is important that
the service segments and the other
segment types do not negatively impact
each other when combining the same
segment list so for example the presence
of a service fragment in a message list
should not make it more complex from
your endpoint processing underlay
segment to do their packet processing
and similarly the presence of non
service segments so for example underlay
segment should not limit the
capabilities of service segments so
quickly the services behaviors that we
described in the draft we have we
differentiate two types of
services first one is basic marketing
capable service and on that one we
simply process the packet on the service
with the segment routing information on
it if there is some metadata at the
packet and if the the segment behavior
implies the processing of that metadata
then that metadata will be processed
then we simply move to the next set by
doing an MPLS park or and the solicits
end function this is nothing particular
we also define the some proxy behaviors
former legacy services that would not
natively support segment routing and for
this we just have the proxy doing the
segmentation processing on behalf of the
of the service and delivering to that
service that network function the packet
without dsl information or hiding some
howdy-hi information from the party that
is delivered food to the service then we
move to the next segment isolation so
these two types of segments can be a
well babe the proxy service and the
segmentation capable service can be
combined in the same seed list obviously
and this would allow for for progressive
deployment of acceptable services if
service becomes as acceptable and it was
before behind access behind the proxy
then it is sufficient to deploy the new
service and we configure the head end on
the entity that computes the segment to
use the new segment instead of the proxy
statement in terms of metadata so this
is mostly similar to other proposals
that have been inform for service
training the metadata is carried within
the packet headers it is set by the
Helen or by an intermediate solution
point that would need to such a metadata
and it is usually usable but I
intermediate salvation point that would
need but what's important is that the
metadata lookup is not it's not
automatic at the enemy segment routing
end point it is triggered by the segment
redeeming function so if a segment
rating end point has nothing to do with
some particular metadata it will not
look for it in the packet we have we
have developed proof of concept
implementation of this using using IP
tables so far our basic firewall and
this implementation does exactly that it
matches on on the active segment of the
packet and then we look for metadata
that is that is pirate within two packet
headers and it has some matching rules
tile to to drop or to Lord or to make
the packet us depending on the value of
this metadata in the packet headers so
the next step for these draft is to ask
for the working reproduction and also if
there is any any comment or any any
question from the working group then
you're welcome to speak and to let us
know so except you have a clarification
question we will move to the
presentation from FEMA and then we will
start for discussion
okay so I do get off from Iowa so I'll
try and keep this brief I just want to
give you a brief overview of a draft
that I put together which was basically
a draft that allowed us to do what we
would call stateful service training as
opposed to stateless
so what Francois kind of presented was
really a stateless implementation where
we're using SRP six source routing
capabilities to do the service chaining
but obviously there are cases where we
have service chaining using the
encapsulations that have been defined by
the SFC working group which I guess we
can call stateful because we need a
certain amount of State at the routers
so this draft describes two scenarios
where we would use the network service
headers to either have segment routing
as the transport that carries the NS age
or where we would actually integrate nsh
and segment routing together to do a
stateful type of service channel so this
is a quick picture of using SR as the
transport so this is very much in line
with the SFC architecture where the the
service plane is independent of the
transport so in this case SR is just the
transport like any other transport that
we might use to carry on Sage the second
one is where we want to actually
integrate the nsh service plane with the
SR based SFC and in this case basically
what we're going to do is carry NS 8
beneath the segment routing stack but
have the capability to indicate in the
segment list that the service plane is
being dealt with by NS age and therefore
when we send the packet to the service
we should remove the segment routing
header and use something in the nsh
encapsulation to indicate which segment
list to push back on to the pack
when it comes back from the service
itself so the draft goes into the
details of that I still need to update
to add a function that basically has all
the semantics that says what to actually
do with the packet as you strip off the
segment routing header because obviously
we need to cash that we need to be able
to push it back on with the pointers
moved and so forth all of that detail
needs to be put into the draft and I'll
do that before the next IDF so really
the purpose of this is really give the
combination of second gravamen essays
for a transport independent SFC but the
key point here is that it's not in
competition with an S r v6
service chain and these are two
independent ways of doing this so
they're kind of complementary so I don't
want to get into a one is better than
the other it's really going to be
dependent on what a particular operator
wants to deploy and so next steps with
this is request working period option in
spring and we would want to pursue this
in conjunction with what Francois just
talked about and come up with those
solutions that cover all at this space
and we'll continue to refine the
technical details in the draft as we
move forward once that's it
any questions specifically on that
clarification questions know what's what
maybe if you can you'll you may have
questions I hope there are some because
we've got 20 minutes on the agenda so
unless you want me to sing you are so in
to discuss a very general subject of
doing service chaining it with Sigma
pudding and what we're saying is for
deployment scenarios so the goal is not
to to choose one because which media may
be
we didn't need different depending on
the different scenario so before we
we're saying is one where any section s
are coexist
so as is used as transport from one
service for water to another one to the
next one and that's the scenario
described in June draft in Section two
please correct me if it's a great second
scenario is we use a SM policy and
Dwayne so for topological and service
bus and it's followed by nsh2 under the
service service instance and also carry
metadata if needed so it's also in a Jif
draft section three foreign section then
we also add some policy for and to enter
particular on service paths but in this
case there is no message because you
have no better data and you have sao web
service or SSL proxy and again as far as
our error on the first post first one is
the same but with metadata added in the
data been specific structure native
structure so one specific structure for
SIDS on one was one specific structure
for srt-6
so we are not using any search for
metadata but there is a specific product
online a specific extension to Korea
metadata
this is a very high-level picture we
would like feedback on Nara
so the constraint on each HTTP not
winner yeah when I drink from Nokia I
just want to complain it's not a
question or a comment
I just want to complement what Jim set
is actually those two proposals because
I'm actually a code on both they are
actually having different environments
as a use case right and I think what I
they are very complimentary to each
other one requires the I assuming there
is no clock see one will require to have
the service function to support Anna's
age whereas in the other case you have
to support segment routing so but you
will see that there is I people have
expressed interest in both of them so I
believe that there is need for both of
them and they are very complementary to
each other
Adrian Farrell and there's some things I
see as definitely necessary and some I
see as open to discussion so being able
to carry nsh over an Anasazi six
transport seems to me like an absolute
requirement we have nsh service function
trained and they have SR v6 networks so
we need it I had a strange strangely
passionate conversation where John
Halpin earlier in the week about the
merits and demerits of two approaches to
the same requirement in which he told me
that he has an SFC co-chair had
reluctantly allowed for the MPS SFC work
because it was about getting service
lunch and training in a legacy
environment it seems to me that s our v6
networks are not a legacy environment
yet
we actually have the choice here to not
have two ways of doing the same thing in
the same network I have no particular
feeling for going with let's use n SH
and say that is the way you do all
service function training and I have no
particular feeling saying let's use that
solving six to always do that but I
think that there's this decision point
so this is the right timing for talking
about this where we should try to
understand these two ways of doing the
same thing or should we and therefore
focus on this one or are they two things
for two different use cases and
therefore hey let's go ahead so let me
comment on that Adrienne I think there's
a very simple answer to be honest and
you know I'm an SFC working group chair
as well so I you know I've put a lot of
time and effort into n sh and but I
don't want to become biased to one or
the other
the simple answer from my perspective is
that I have operators asking for both
and because I have operators asking for
both then I'm gonna provide both so I
and because I don't see them as being
they're not fighting against each other
they're complementary so I really don't
personally have an issue with with
pursuing both both solutions that will
satisfy you know the operators that are
asking me for this kind of service the
people on the line too but the point is
that
complete the resolution that you do one
or the other is not that I trace their
complete so I mean I completely agree
with them in relation that she's not one
or the other this is completely a
complete confusion
fully integrated with reviews with this
and and and it is stateless we cannot
say this if I'm sorry can you clarify so
women said that he thinks these two
solutions are complementary to each
other and can't there's different
deployment scenarios about it seemed
like there was general consensus to that
did you just say do you think there
shouldn't be more than once no no I'm
not saying communicative one is on this
slide and what Jim says or what France
Weston what I'm saying is them
responding to Adrian who said that dude
this working would be looking into doing
a solution in SR or the philosophy fix
then you get ugly it does Canadians it
and and my answer to that is we should
record this solution has nothing to do
with the way that service training is
done with an essential when this NSA
distribution is the mission which is
integrated fully in Assam where service
segments are integrated in myself that
the solution group if I may comment
Chow's hopping from Ericsson whose name
was recently invoked and I actually
agree with the invocation I'm not coming
up here to disagree it is the whole
point of chartering the SFC working
group and defining in SH was to define
an interoperable mechanism to represent
service paths and carry metadata and
interoperable mechanism across
transports asar v6 is one such transport
MPLS including segments routed MPLS is
another such transport Ethernet is
another such transport we can go on and
on there's a lot of them that's why we
wanted an interoperable mechanism to
carry this information creating a
different mechanism to carry this kind
of information that does not use nsh
does not meet this it fails the Charter
that we as a community spelled out as
desirable carrying nsh in SR v6 is
entirely fine I expected I wanted but
taking an SH apart and putting the
information into an SRH header and some
other piece of TLV as some another
proposal did there was another tunnel
protocol that said we're gonna just take
the metadata apart and put it in other
TL DS and you can put it back together
if you need to interoperate excuse me
the whole point was to avoid an end
squared and capsulation problem so I
have a problem with why would we do this
with a new thing as Adrienne said I
understand why we did it for MPLS stuff
but as Adrienne quoted me he quoted me
correctly but I don't get it for this
let me answer why okay so so Robert
Redford Bloomberg so as if she makes
sense not only in the network and
transport but end-to-end compute to
computers and in if I'm building the
header in the compute node the VCS
header off SS RH is very easy for me to
insert a function which in the same time
can be useful by never number of network
elements I don't have a visibility into
n SH in compute nodes very often but for
building the function for the SRH I have
that's a big difference and that's the
application I have if you have that much
visibility you have enough information
to put an NSA chatter on I don't think
you're gonna very often have that
visibility but if you do use the NSA
chatter correctly
Kate ontological Cisco I'd like to go
back to what Jim mentioned in his
introduction the main difference is
stateful and stateless so I just come
from Maui a circle cause of the
stainless as a paste as a draft I think
there are lots of difference between
these two drafts because as we know that
the solutions described in and Jamie's
draft is kind of stifle solution which
means that the SFF we maintain the
information of forwarding and then in
this way we do not need to change the
advance which means the fast can be can
can support an SH as it this right now
so it is a complementary solution for
stateless SR based SFC yep thank you
it's agent again and I think stateless
may well be the absolute key to all of
this so so Joel is right that the SFC
working with charter to do SFC but
Spring has also been chartered to do
service training it's risen I'm
clutching my laptop it says that one of
your one of your work items is source
relative stateless service training so
unless the ADEs want to tell us that
there's a screw up in the chartering and
one of them one of the shelters has to
be fixed it's in it's in both is in
scope and state there seems to be the
word Daniel Daniel Canada my point of
view in this is a goal is to simplify
the network but I think that for example
Jim's traffic helps with inter ability
of existing vnf that already support an
SH you can't just carry them across so
being able to have both is a good use
case so I'll do it Joel talked about the
SSU working group
I agree with any units part of the
charter of spring and having that
ability to interrupt like this is I
think it's a goose useful for a useful
solution for us I wonder I have a
graduation question for Audrey I'm sorry
for asking late you say that we have a
solution for service chaining it's
called NSA true we don't have we don't
need a second one but I think at the
point where we have to one with the
generic any search on one with an
impedance on kodi neeya and you know
because you're zero so my question is
whether you're fine on not with the 7ps
doing size chaining given that it's
already done that
the PS that a pen can be used for
service chaining oh you disagree with us
on penis or soul so winding back I think
I was I was trying to channel what Joe
had said to me before rather than
expressing an opinion but I'll do that
now the MPLS SFC brands itself as a
transition technology not competing with
nsh but saying there's a world out there
that has non nsh capable boxes but could
do some SFC based forwarding here's a
way to achieve it I personally think
letting in lots of flowers bloom is a
great way to arrive at the right
technology so you know I would say knock
yourselves out and come up with a third
way as well and yeah I I think you go
ahead there's not there doesn't appear
to me to be a conflict between
stateless and stateful and and so on so
I rambled and probably lost your
question no no my point is that Asylum
Paris Olympia says this is the same kind
of lame exactly so if you realize that
the plane is accepted as a way to boost
our is chaining okay I don't see why I
saw I guess would be different house is
exactly the same data pane we are not
inventing a new that I'm playing for
service chaining right yeah so while the
conversation has been largely about SL
v6 service chaining right thing and an
MPLS SR service training approach
stateless works well and that is
actually covered in the MPs SSC document
not deeply but covered okay so that's do
not have an issue with her service
training and with the therapy honest I
always have issue with the rubbish I
right no I don't have an issue and I
suppose that does make then for for
approaches on the kicking around NSA
tunneled over whatever MPLS SFC in a
stateful way in pls SFC in a stateless
way and it's a v6 SFC in a state that's
way but just a common so so this is
exactly the same determining Mandrax
Nokia one more thing actually is if you
look at the end of the day I think if
you look a lot of the vendors here or
transport and and and doing things in
data center which as a vests and stuff
like that I think the biggest the
biggest implication of this of multiple
solutions is going to be the value added
services elements which need to
interpret the headers right and they
need to take into account an his age
segment routing and stuff like that and
the question is what is their view on
this because at the end of the day
multiple people will ask to be
supporting those type of things in those
products and so far
I've seen the adoption in that space
slow in general right and the reason is
because typically they are they are in a
different world i they are living in
more than the application like firewalls
vendors load-balancing vendors and stuff
like that so they need to support this
and I think it's also a question to
those people is are they willing and are
we having sufficient information from
them that they are okay with all of
these approaches which you are putting
to the table I think that's an important
consideration but women what that
doesn't mean that we shouldn't define
them right brain shouldn't define them
no no I think that's an industry problem
at the end of the day because people
need to support and implement and I see
most of the people here which are
discussing or mainly people who are
doing the transport the encapsulations
and and they are more working in that
area but it's the application area where
where you actually see that there is a
need for adoption of these type of
things and my personal view is that
Ana's age adoption in that world has
been slow in general yeah I think in
some ways I will concur with Jo with wim
it's a at the end what I like is I have
a simpler network but if we're talking
about carrying metadata I like more more
work being done on what actually can
emit using metadata and Clara get across
can simplify the work and create the
value and add value to my network and
that's what I think at some point there
are will be multiple implement
implementations of encapsulations I'm
sure somebody will invent a new one some
really soon
we should not have that they've been
around this but how to create which is
still a problem for a lot of providers
in the world creating chains and come
and create they're adding by components
together if you're able to start working
more on the the use of metadata and
those kind of mechanisms I think this
would be more valuable to me at some
point actually I don't have you seen it
but Francois and I actually just
published a new draft which has an exact
use case for the
what one comment I do want to make
because I think this is going to be very
important as we move forward with this
service chaining is that the one area
where I can see us getting into a whole
bunch of trouble is as we start to talk
about metadata and the structure of the
TVs and so forth there needs to be
coordination between spring and SFC
because we've been doing some TLV stuff
in the SFC working group and defining
that what we don't want to end up with
is spring defining separate TVs to what
we've defined in SFC and vice versa so
there needs to be coordination there
obviously how we carry those TVs in the
two different encapsulations is
different but we do need to be agreed
upon as to what those TVs are in the
structure of them and I think that's
going to be very important I agree it
looks doable for us every six yes for
MPS what would you define a way to carry
metadata it's different and also that is
very very limited but specific it's not
difficult to carry for some TVs in
Olympia nice yeah I mean my personal
view is it makes an Adrian might hit me
but it makes no sense to carry metadata
in an MPLS data plane it's too difficult
but in SRV six then we have the tail V's
at least currently in the SRH but I want
to make sure that any TVs that are
service chaining related are not
different to the ones that are used in
the SFC nsh environment because
otherwise we get into a mess we need to
make sure that those are coordinated and
and big because they're the same TLV
these basically just interrupts turn so
few comments first ala and I concur with
what we've said the industry outside of
ATF is very slow so I'm reading report
by Softnet published February this year
where they try to research for they
could you signature out do traffic city
into B&S and their conclusion no
because that not enough V&F that
actually can do it so the fact that we
are having a discussion here trying to
figure out whether we compare apples or
apples to oranges is good and Industry
clarification what is it we are going to
do in order to do anything with it so we
really need to provide clarity and
proceed with it and also let our peers
outside of networking industry know what
is it we are going to do and what we've
taught them today otherwise this vicious
circle us talking here they are not
doing anything any other comment so the
subject is not enough truth so so it's
you're welcome to to keep discussing on
the Middle East and we'll see we see you
as an exit are so I think it would be
good there seems like there's a couple
of things here I think we've kind of
said bizzy's for deployment scenarios
and in general it didn't sound like
there's any opposition to those it'd be
good if two here on the mailing list if
there is I think it'd be good to also
get some debate around what around what
we're going to do for metadata I think
what Jim said makes a lot of sense to be
able to say let's define for us a v6 and
then it's HS common set of tlvs
I would like to see some statement that
we're not going to try and do anything
more in MPLS SR MPLS if that's the the
consensus because I also tend to agree
that is it kind of fool's errand that
way
so I think your comment is if you want
to do something pls we should use NSA's
really so we shouldn't be trying to
encode second in theater right
I'm not putting drafts in your text
editor but yes please I'm just asking
Jim and I think this is what you know I
guess my comment is I don't think it
makes sense to try and carry metadata in
a label stack yeah one comment is a
appears that the plane is defined by the
MPs walking woman not not by Sprenger
actually see I've already defined a
document which has been approved by the
working group on is he is J if I'm not
incorrect and so what you have to find a
way to carry a limited set of Kennedy I
would say but I don't we and what would
know better I want to agree with Jim I
don't think it's sensible to carry
metadata and I in a label stack and
that's why nobody's proposed it it's not
that's not what the draft does the draft
index is the metadata carries the index
of the metadata in the label stack yes
Joe now you know because it would also
equally not make sense to carry metadata
in a sit-stay
you carry metadata and metadata to clear
these the NPS draft uses the NS HK of
A's and we're probably in perfect
agreement it's just maybe the way you
said it was a bit so I think we've made
progress in in defining the problem
space in thermo-firm stateless on Ted
for size Channel that's pretty clear I
think for everyone
so the coexistence of srn etc I think
constructors and in nobody's against and
if we want to if we want to do
stateless service chaining which is part
of our charter think we were going to
work on that so we're still going to to
wait for a few a few weeks to see there
are remaining discussions on the list
then we'll see with will discuss with
with gel on gel and I'd expect some some
progress before next next meeting but
the definite is a so different between
stateless on stateful solutioning it's a
good the good way to structure the
discussion okay I'm a thank you very
much for those of you and we have just
on time for the next one which is our
cache so Rakesh you have 3 oh sweet raft
on 15 it's a good afternoon everyone my
name is Jacques Gandhi and presenting
three drafts on SR p.m. first one being
on the Trump using firm for a Sofia
presenting on behalf of the coitus
so we will look at the requirements and
scope for the Trump s rpm the probe
messages a CMP and the next steps so the
requirements for slpm basically doing
the delay and loss measurement for links
and b2b NSP to NPSL policies for both
SRM pls NS r v6 data planes to keep
things simple moving away from the
signaling and state in the network for
both one-way n2o measurements and we
also have the AC mp4s are policies that
we had to worry about the scope for this
draft is the RFC 5357 the Trump and the
using the user configured the IP IDP
probes so for the probe query messages
the user defined IP UDP ports being used
for both the links as well as the
policies the payload is basically the
5357 there is a DP port here port 1 so
as you as you see this the packet format
is basically at from the saw the comm
packet would look like there is a
message proposed for the direct motor a
loss measurement the proposal here is
that there is harder friendly because it
has fixed offsets for the transmit and
receive counters and I don't have to
worry about the existing womp delay
measurement message there there is also
one defined for authenticated mode and
there is another really report that lets
use to identify this message there is an
LM TLB proposed in a in another draft so
we will have some discussion with with
Greg so
into n s our policy for asylum pls we
use segment list to drop to transport
the pro packet to the tail end of the
policy and for s our v6 we use SRH with
CID list and the N function the OTP for
DM and Opie for L M similarly a response
message again is used in information
from the query message to reply back
again for asylum policy there is a CMP
that we need to support so we use the
existing mechanisms for ipv4 ipv6 that
the destination address based sleeping
ISIL MPLS available as a v6 low-level as
well so there is a quite a bit of work
that in IBM gag driving for stamp
definitely the this is also applicable
to stamp as well may want to use a
different UDP port for it to identify
that the system was this prompt to make
life easier
so our next step so this is 0 0 wasn't
draft so there is some more work to be
done some work to be done for the last
measurement payload so there is checksum
flags for counters is an alternate TLV
proposal so we need to discuss with the
authors of the other draft there is some
update media to for the two a
measurement defining the written part
for example some there was some comments
review comments on the mailing list for
from Greg for p3 MPs so we would address
that as well as for the authentication
the utility protection they welcome your
review comments and suggestions so we're
not asking for working adoption at this
point just welcome your comments and
thoughts Greg
thank you Greg mercy City I have some
comments so you can't like go to the
beginning of the presentation it will be
help to our discussion yeah
so again I need to point out to the
group that RFC fifty-three seven defined
the t1 control and t1 test and if anyone
does new extension to t1 test packet
from the sender or reflector that this
as a new option needs to be negotiated
through t1 control protocol because if
you add some fields after their standard
body then you cannot expect that these
fields will be reflected by
non-conforming reflector because then
you need to have reflected option so
basically you're changing protocol next
question so you mentioned use the port
reflector port did you mean to use port
862 or you mean to use the port that is
being dynamically negotiated between
session client and server for the
control protocol so there is no control
protocol here this is using the user
configure port so there is no signaling
that is no but what rangy used for their
port number so this is configured by
user so it's it's from the dynamic hook
so for that from the dynamic port range
yes okay I I think that you need to
state it explicitly but again it's
in in Ryan with Roc 5357 that it can use
only dynamic port numbers but again
there are negotiated between because I
think that you mean that saying that
this is applicable to t1 pride but t1
part is not standard it's informational
appendix though RFC 357 and because of
that there is no interoperability
between implementations yeah this is
more like to your own life so there is
no control in basically UDP ports are
configured on both sides right I'm
familiar with their several till employ
implementations and there exists their
industry technical reference how to use
t1 provide for performance measurement
but the concern is interoperability
between different vendors that try to
use T one part that's why we have effort
work on stamp which been cleared for the
working group last call and we'll go for
ad consideration and an eyes G so it
doesn't have control protocol as you
mentioned it has still v4 extensions it
already has direct measurement till we
defined and it's much more extent
extensible additional advantage is it
has well known UDP port for the
reflector which makes configuration
easier so if we go to the next slide so
you mentioned use of 63 74 there was
interesting we started interesting
discussion at the the working group to
do extended BFD and use informational
elements from 63 74 to you two
BFD and give it up ability to do
performance monitoring so there is no
success is only for this one is for that
one so again this is the same it uses
the 12 message format with the same IP
UDP header and the ports are configured
on both sides so it would work with the
swot stamp as well it would work with
trump as well it will work with om as
well so all is saying is that you do you
use or you can figure UDP protocol on
both sides and say I'm going to send our
message and you both parties understand
it and there is no entropy sure here
no I respectfully disagree the thing is
that you are testing it against
conforming implementation the t-bone pie
doesn't have a normative specification
and because if you go beyond there 53:57
packet you don't know how the pairing is
being processed so if you look at this
packet this is this is the Trump packet
you have IP UDP header the payload is
from Tom only difference here is that
UDP port is configured by user instead
of a signal but other than that there is
absolutely no difference the packet on
the wire but in your first that you if
you go back you mean which yes you know
one forward so buok number block number
is not part of their T wa'n't format
right which number
well after sender sender TTL the
information field block number it's not
part of T one standard message so you
don't know how this memory so yeah so
this stuff does define the new message
for direct mode loss measurement which
is not there in 5357 so existing
protocol does not define direct mode
loss measurement so this is a new
proposal so this one there is no
in trop issue we're talking what this is
it is it is because if you are sending
this packet to reflector that doesn't
support this extension what you get back
can you in the discussion on juries
because we are going to run out of time
and you're eating your on time it's
interesting description interrupt but
it's just that we okay that's fine I
agree let's take it at least that that's
that's the thing that you assume that on
other end is conforming reflector no
this is user configures it so user has
to go to both ends and you can you in
Shaitan Gregor can you start those right
on the wrist thank you very much Roger
hey Roger sorry I'll make it quick I
think useful work clarification question
I had was it it's it am I correct
conditions defining probes and response
in the SR context where the probes and
responses are not sent inside the user
packets rather these are dedicated
packets did I get that right so say Amen
to the packets yeah it is a program such
as synthetic probe messages so then it's
not like the typical IOM where we're
sending them it they use a packet search
yeah this is not in situ om this is just
probes coming from the crafted probes
rhetoric it would be good to reflect
that in the in this draft as well okay I
think we useful thank you thanks
so this is the second slpm dart out of
three the something on behalf of the the
co-author Sam raucous candy so this
draft was presented at the last ITF in
Spain as well as in I ppm we did receive
some good comments and we had done some
updates so the requirement is that the
delay and loss measurement for links and
into and policies this is for SR MPLS
for both one-way and two-way
measurements the scope is using so this
is the one using 60cc only for RFC and
the 7876 for the written part so we have
done some updates based on the review
comments we have received renamed the
draft to reflect the scope is sixty to
seventy four with this editorial changes
there was a request to elaborate on the
in band performance measurement also
added some text for the ecmp support
that's required for SLM pls gal does
lack the support of a CFP so we would
need to use a entropy label for example
there was a comment from C were to add
the rated part information which which
is still pending
so welcome your comments and suggestions
and the RFC success is 74 there are many
implementations so we do like to request
working app adoption I think a question
was raised last meeting that should this
be in a spring will MPLS but other than
that I think we are from our side we we
do request the adoption greg mostly city
so this is informational draft
this is informational yeah okay and may
ask you what you see is our cairo value
so there are many questions that ask how
does the path segment identifier that's
defined for s are applicable to p.m.
how do you do Law School's I mean where
does that go hi border bidirectional
measurement for sr what about doing the
link measurement do you use the
adjacency see how does it work so there
are many questions so drop it it's an
informational so it just goes and said
this is how we think it should work but
again any comments thoughts you have you
mentioned bi-directional measurement but
I don't think that we yet agreed on what
bi-directional a certain L is so there
is some work going on in piece F so it
was presented this morning on the
bi-directional SL part and so you may
want to think up there again I know that
there is a proposal to do a segment path
ID pass segment no no then the path
segment I did that is also as another
draft for bi-directional SR path right
but again there are a lot of in my
opinion there are a lot of things that
has to happen before we get to the point
when we are concerned and about
performance measurement on
bi-directional path so I think that this
draft says quite obvious thing
RFC 63 74 works over a certain pls in 63
74 is described that you can provide a
return address so you know if somebody
reads 63 74 and takes a minute to think
about it it becomes of this now we does
not say you cannot specify the exact
path right the seed leaves on the really
fast no you don't again return path
doesn't have to go with the CID return
path can go over IP MPLS network it
could but in a in a segment routine
world it was Stewart front or it would
make sense to also be able to do it in a
sibling that was the common fire
well again if if we want to use it to
measure another tunnel in a return
direction well it's possible but it's
it's a very different scenario it's just
it's fundamental to me that if you want
to say that in a network where you
specify the paths and you may have some
reason for specifying that you should be
able to specify how you get the packet
back she's nothing to do with doing the
measurement in that direction
it's that in a separate routed Network
you may want to lay out a segment rooted
path to send your messages around it's
similar than to the concept of MPLS LSP
being the option of how you define that
how to reply back yes okay so if you
want to for performance measurement for
each packet to specify how you buy that
I think that's an overkill if you want
to specify how you returned this session
back you can provision it do it in each
and every packet defining each and every
packet or you send this packet this way
you send this packet that way I think
it's asking for inconsistencies in
measurements excuse me like we are going
to have to cut the description just one
small element
yeah just one comment I think this is a
good one and I think we should continue
this work okay thanks so sure again I
just have a minor preference for
happening in MPLS with all of the other
of its the similar set of drafts that
sort of said they're all in the same
place but it's only a minor preference
what do you mean my set of references
three ones well we did a bunch of work
after 63 74 for example the work we're
doing on synonymous play was all the
drafts in that sort of 63 74 world
currently live in MPLS so it would just
seem reasonable put it over there if
possible but I hear it's only a minor
reference really okay thank you
you could be quite fast or a swan please
yeah so this is the third draft the last
one this is using RFC 66 74 using IP UDP
header it's suitable for both the SR
MPLS NS r v6 americas panda presenting
on behalf of their authors listed so
reviewed the requirements and scope of
this draft again this is the same as the
table for sr link policies eliminating
the signaling the negotiation of the UDP
port and the state in the network
basically simplifying it taking
advantage of the controller based
provisioning for IP UDP ports for sixty
six hundred and seventy eight seventy
six written part so we presented this
draft at last ITF in both IP pm and
spring we see the number of good
comments so many thanks for everyone who
commented so the first comment was that
we would have hard time getting the IANA
L to allocate the ports and he was
indeed true we talked to a number of
people and we would need many a UDP port
so I think we going with the user
configure UDP ports approach for SL v6
policies we are using the segment
routing header to transport the probe
back as to the tail end using the end
RTP or end of OB functions we we address
the comments to align the TLB structure
for the return path clarify the sequence
number TL we added authenticated mode
updated security system security section
as well as the elaborating and
performance measurement so there is a
new TL v that we are there for
authenticated more the four sequence
number so we
welcome your comments and suggestions
and multiple implementations do exist
for sixty to seventy four we don't have
any open if I turns right now for this
dog
so we do like to request a working
reproduction thank you hi Ron Bonica
here to talk about the compressed
routing header on behalf of all the
folks on the slide and we made an
observation that there are really two
classes of SIDS in the world there are
transport SIDS that are used to steer a
packet to the terminal segment of a sr
v6 tunnel they're processed at non
terminal segment end points when
segments left is greater than zero an
examples of these are the SR v6 ends it
in the end exit there are relative to
relatively few of these and their
semantics are simple they carry very
very little information they can be
encoded in very few bits in contrast
there's something called a service set
it determines the behavior at a terminal
segment it's processed only at the
terminal segment when segments left
equals zero
there are lots of these examples are end
the DX for end d x6 and dt for and so on
and they have relatively rich semantics
you need a lot of bits to encode these
well similarly an ipv6 there are two
ways to deliver in store
to downstream nodes there are routing
extension headers that are used to steer
packets from an ingress to an egress
they're processed at non-terminal
segments end points when segments left
equal is greater than zero and they're
well positioned to carry transport sets
by contrast there are destination
options they determine behavior at the
egress they're processed at the terminal
segment only when segments left equals
zero or when there's no routing header
at all and they're well positioned to
carry services so it's pretty obvious
where we're going with this
Oh before we go there we have to talk
about one more issue the problem with
routing header is in general not just
the SRH but the routing headers we've
seen in the IETF so far they get very
long typically they have eight bytes of
overhead four bytes are required by RFC
8200 typically they take another 16
bytes per said they encode acid' as a
hundred 28 bits so a routing header with
three SIDS is 56 bytes long this isn't a
sex friendly once once the routing
header gets beyond maybe five six SIDS
it just becomes impractical and they
impose on reasonable bandwidth overhead
short packets no less than 500 bytes are
pretty common on the internet routing
header with three SIDS may become common
and that means a 10% overhead just for
routing extension headers so where do we
go with this we propose encoding
transport SIDS and a new compress
routing header that's engraft Bonica
six-man compressed routing header it's
the topic of the talk today and we
encode talked about encoding service
SIDS and a new ipv6 destination option
crafts Bonica 6-man BPM desktop we'll
talk about that in six-man tomorrow the
compressed routing header that we're
talking about today can be used with the
SRH use one when it's appropriate use
the other when it's appropriate what
does this new compress
routing header look like well the first
five bytes are exactly the same as the
cr8 as the SRH then we have two bits
that tell you how SIDS are encoded SIDS
can be encoded as 8 16 or 32 bits um and
let's say
so let's what we've talked about that
we've talked about the comm field each
Sid maps to an ipv6 address either
through a table lookup or an algorithm
and that ipv6 address is copied to the
destination address of the ipv6 header
exactly like any other routing header
what's interesting here is what's copied
to the ipv6 address as a real ipv6
address that's not a said it has no
semantics beyond the ipv6 address this
is what the routing header looks like
when SIDS are encoded in 8 bits and in
16 and in 32 so what's the status of
this operators were expressing interest
um there are a few operators who are
co-authors of the draft prototypes are
under development both on the forwarding
plane and Isis extensions to support the
CID and we would ask for wide review in
sec spring and six-man and would ask for
call for adoption in six-man questions
comments rotten fruit i guess we're back
on schedule
[Music]
hi everyone I'm a homo from Bali today
I'm going to talk about a segment about
him proxy forwarding so in existing SRT
pass fast protection so when one node of
fails
so it's option note where do the local
protection however when the ITP
convergence and then this kind of local
protection will not work so in this
draft we're proposing solutions to rot
and resolve these issues so first let's
look at the program in details so here
in this picture we have a SRT pass so
this path will go through nota N and
then the traffic will go from node a BP
MMC so when node n fails so the load P
were detected is failure and then where
do the faster route and get around at
this failure point and then send traffic
to know to see so this works
however when IDP convergence for exam
are not a and not B and then at this
point the traffic where work will be
dropped
so this traffic interruption will
continue until a new SRT pass is
computed and installed so we can see
from the p8 from the Dirac a DP
converges and then half after a data
point then a new SRT has installed and
during this period the traffic traffic
get lost
so we will provide a solution to resolve
this problems to the rough idea is that
we will do some product
extension and then we'll make sure that
even after ITP converges the nodoby
will continue in the traffic to know to
pee and then note of he will continue to
the faster route so we can resolve this
dis problems so here we define a proxy
forwarding note so for note we have no
time
send the proxy note for note han is the
note here if P were to the proxy
forwarding for n when not n fails so the
protein extension is a very simple so
for for example phone or PE so no the P
is adjacent not of note an exam or our
other adjacent note so when no the P is
ready to do the approach forwarding for
not an or oh Sh isn't note so no the PE
where edify advertise is capabilities
for this kind of a project forwarding
and then the other node in the network
after gather receive this kind of
capability for pornography or he knows
that if he were to the protocol
forwarding for psi Jason note so when we
know the N fails and then even after the
IDP converges the other node will
continue to forward traffic to data note
of P which is computer protein
forwarding so the detail extensions I
give for all PFD exchanges so basically
is this persimmon we use the existing
kappa b GTA v i just use one bit so this
one bit indicate our i can support a
forwarding proxy for link abilities so
for example one p and pi advertise his
community and then the also note in
Maddog will receive these kind of
capabilities for examined over x so
after not IX received is this kind of a
capability for other photons by P which
means that P
well where do the proxy forwarding for
all it's a dishes note so in normal
operation that note X will submit the
traffic to another end
so after know the end fails and then
even after IDP converge converges and
then note note X will continue sending
the traffic attune tonotopy that works
you note and then the third approach
note way to approach forwarding to the
not end the failure load so in addition
to the this kind of a simple case we
also do the protein extensions for
pending because of or not N and that no
time we may have a pending so this
bundling we abandon s ID to a list of
segments so this information will be
advertised only to the adjacent node
this is not advertise to the whole area
so this we also improved the scalability
so when so when the edge is not P
received inside nobody you mention he
can do the process forwarding to these
kind of abundance so this information is
tell these are public information will
be contained in this curvy this curvy
well it's just a nuclear V so similarly
we can do the similar thing for the ISS
this is equivalent to the OSPF or the
capability and also for the for panting
yes Inga that's all any comments just
ensure so this to address traffic
engineer environment on the right
because you don't have this problem when
you follow shortest path so you're using
traffic engineering for reason you're
deviating from trucks bus so in this
case a would compute a pass and you are
trying to protect it from proxy
prospective
however
probably you wouldn't use IGBT feet were
out and fell you would use sounds like
be multiple BFD are some other fast
detection mechanism to notify a that
passes unavailable wouldn't be than a
who should be compute better pass if
such required that meets all the
constraints and provision it in a way
avoids and I mean you mean the you so
the question is that we need uh some
kind of all so pike a pass also mirror
satisfied conscience is that your
question
yeah because P would just huge
potentially short pass it wouldn't do
proper computation to include all the
constraints been delayed and such yeah
that's good question yes what that
parties are you hard
it's better we have a backup pass we
just satisfy the constraints but at this
point because the approach you know
don't have those kind of informations we
just made some kind of passive effort
something cuz it's like potentially
should be done by hasn't and not all
right so this is the for temporary
protection because after the converges
and then the hide end will compute metal
in the past and then after that and then
we can go because after the new passage
is thought so the traffic goes to the
new past we didn't have backwards
messages such as energy PT and waiting
for a GP to converge flunk so now I'm
not sure about use case here if you're
wrapping engineering to you want you
have even your back up to meet your
constraints otherwise not valid
configuration the time from yeah so
these are so if we just wait for the new
path to be restored and then in this
period at the traffic work at lost you
don't way you pre computed and your
pre-install that if you want to be fast
yeah you want the pre you store that's
another this is how we do pass
protection in so that one I think if you
you freeze
and then you needed to have some kind of
undertone the PMP to detect their past
failures right yeah that one if we have
admit when the BFB and then we also may
have some issues for another on the PFD
and right yeah otherwise he wouldn't do
traffic engineering to begin with yeah I
know whether we want to guarantee or we
just want to have a kind of or faster
protection first and then what is a very
short period of time a seal and I got
one detailed comment I didn't read the
draft but I can see you using the wrong
bit vector in the informational
capabilities you should be using the
functional capabilities rather than a
professional yeah in RFC 7770 you should
be using the functional capabilities and
the other one is I've never heard it
called proxy forwarding before I and and
then I looked at it and I said oh this
is this is a node protection in and so
it was kind of a funny and I'm not sure
I haven't really since I didn't read
that off I haven't thought how it fits
with all the existing mechanisms you
know that have been done for years with
normal LSPs or anything like that it
seems like a funny terminology yeah
come up with exam we can beat up shellac
Cisco so I have no problem if you use or
you should try to protect the segment's
in the packet core note protection for a
protection itself but I don't think that
trying to pretend that some seed exists
which is gone is a good idea especially
you may have a secondary failures during
that time and in that case I don't think
how I don't see how this is going to
work so the suggestion is or Jeff said
if you want to provide the protection
then for a node failure in a long term
then pre-computer Beca pass which is
disjoint and use that piece PFD and to
end
yeah well consider data and the toy in
the pasta even more details
yeah that's an option okay Rajeev oh
sorry um so Jeff summed up first of my
comments already sold focus on the
second so the applicability that I was
stretching to see was if n was more of
bond brave are between say to rodding
domains or or two domains as her domains
and n so lose mode from the path point
of view where n had to be at the
boundary so you say alright come take
the packet up to node n and exit the
packet out of this her domain and then
notes he is someplace else in another
domain and I can see you would want to
protect against the node n so I think
the problem somewhere makes sense but
then if that was the case wouldn't we
want to use something like tal FA assign
the same prefix said on the the nodes
that is backing up node n in that
specific construct and solve the problem
that way if not using something like
path protection so you questions we can
use a our fate or LF a with the same
prefix it assigns in that in then you
know power to hypothesize that problem
scenario where this problem would be
relevant would be node N and this
unnamed node next down to it is actually
the exit boundary nodes of SR domain
right N and you say my loose mode as our
policy is to actually get the node up to
node n get the packet up to node N and
then choose which opportunity chosen of
node n feels of course we would have a
problem like you destroy but then di LF
I should take care of it with so your
questions or your concerns or your
prophecies that we we focus on no turn
and please note is that the punker node
of a domain yes there it makes sense
otherwise you go back to doing just
solve with path protection you know have
a pre computed path right from node a
and
here's done with that you don't need to
define I'm struggling if it really
requires solving this problem using
other enhancements I think a protection
regarding the protection the mainly
pointed to be protected so we for
example suggest that the boundary node
or egress node and then we need apart I
provide protection and sync the trenches
note or mute a note we also need to
provide protection right so I think here
we focus on the on the meeting of the
protections I think for the egress no
traction I think we also have some
couple proposals we are presenting in
Friday I'm writing tomorrow okay
maybe after this session we could just
draw yeah yeah we can talk about those
kind of protection for girls person and
then in details okay thank you I have
one just question less individual on
slide for you say you keep forwarding
this packet but when you talk about to
see the it's a prefix ADA yeah so you
both have a IP prefix on an imperious
either the idea the node as ID
yes it's an IP prefix or so are you
talking about keeping both the Imperius
forwarding plane on the IP forwarding
plane or just the impedance forwarding
plane because IP prefix can be used as a
be next up on it needs to disappear from
the folks on the MLS so they need first
of all so for the IP as as you mean IP
v6 no image before well whatever it is
in the 70s
yeah node ID prefix is the IP prefix
see the ID pop predicts yeah do you keep
forwarding the IP
pheeba yeah yeah in the u n-- for this
ad we also have some kind of information
there so I think we it would be good to
clarify that in the doctrine
yes draft okay keep the prefix up BGP
will not see
next up as disappear this is not a P P
only yes yes but critics nice GP yes he
used by bgp-4 using Bible year maybe
later we can use my PGP yes okay so we
can put up them yeah we're gonna thank
you next is good hello everyone I'm Tran
Tran shown from DT my presentation today
SRM pstp in the domain use cases and the
draft has been presented in yesterday
NPR's working group I received many
great comments from NPRM we appreciate
more comments from spring working group
ok
as our MPs we defined it to transport
profiling as as our MPs as we all known
that in SMPS lat works to as our past is
unidirectional but in some transports
that roxtor assault by the earth by
directional past must be establish it
for example in MPs TP lat works so the
draft ITF spring amperes per segment and
the draft has been approved to their
working group draft just now and they're
a different path segments to support us
are bi-directional has correlation so
based on the drafts this document
discourses third into two main scenarios
in SRM pstp let works in this document
we defined an energy and power segment
they're into map has segments and in
this scenario the s are bi-directional
end-to-end passes can be established
across her multiple domains then the
there are two models in SRM pstp into
domain the first one is a splitting and
domain model the mames are isolated and
the stitching SR load we approached
their list of SIDS for the loose ab
turner and for lasting in the domain
model global segments listed at the
ingress SR and the end-to-end a pass as
ID where you'll across all the domains
in the waste also discussed the SNP LTP
into working wisdom as our MPs TP we
were achieved the end to end the wicked
surface and by inter working between SR
and MPs TP let worse with thirst path
segments so let's look at the SSR and ps
t ps preaching in the domain as the
figures show there are string as our
domains stitching together we will
establish an end-to-end pass drone load
a tool ology and the parts will be
divided into several paths of several
segments and each segment will be
identified by in by herb has segments we
defined to automate how segment or into
may pass s ID so for example exeter in
at the end interest load a we will push
their a 2x as RT e and the I pass a 2x2
their load ace MPs stack and Esther s
our MPs procedural there mmm trust
transy knows where pop pops out at the
top label and when their packets being
forwarded to the load X and then the I
pass a to X will be top label and at the
load X it will do the matching from
there I pass a to X switch to there X to
Y srte and that I pass away X to Y then
at the Lord why did the same with the
procedure at load X and then their
packets of being forwarded after load D
and it will owning their I pass Y to the
existed at the top lab stack each at low
today it will correlate in the forward
forwarding path and the reverse parts
bakudan powder at the load Z the label
is the I pass Y to Z and it will switch
the I passed you the reverse pars 3 to Y
and the Z 2 is RTE and there I passed
three two one so the reverse pass it's
the same we stir for impossible and
they're a nesting inter-domain the
difference is that Jo is an end-to-end
path segments to identified eight from A
to Z the editor the interest alone a we
were pushed her sad past a 2x and the
bounteous ID x to y fungicide ey to Z
and their Valerie we pushed her into in
the past it is a pass for short and
thereupon esad we used it to reduce the
depth of the pious label and when their
packet being forwarded to the reload X
then the bounteous ID x to y will be
mapped to the x to x RT
there's a path segment X to Y then
epidural
Lord why it's the same and they're at
the loaded Z juror will be owning their
a and two and pass a to t existed and
their the end to I pass a 2d you will be
will correlate the two unidirectional
parts for example from a path from A to
Z we have switched to the c2 a pass
ended the 3/2 Y X R T then the reverse
process will be the same procedure with
the boarding pass so we will discuss
their assam here's T P and NP STP into
working as a figure shoulder a there are
s are interim SR domain and their MPs to
TP domain they eclectic ways or with
loes Porter loss in SR networks we built
as our Turner and in MPs TV networks we
built an PST Peter they are or
bi-directional Turner's we wanted to
achieve and to enter
whip Ian's service and then we we are
used in SR networks there from a to one
we will use the SI the list and the path
segments from one to a to translate
pushed who stays there editor load one
and after their load a it will be the
path segments of a 2-1 and at the Lord a
we it will switch the path segments to
their amperes label and this is the
forwarding path and the reverse possibly
the same their MPs label we all switched
a cuter path segments and enter as are
Turner so this is their into working
so which are we just er discussed the
use case about their SMPS TP into domain
and their their inter working so
comments and the discussions are very
welcome
it's very confusing your isn't T P and T
interchangeably right why would they
need label stacking TP where there's no
control plane and all the labels are
provision true management plane I always
need one label to get to the next nut oh
you mean the lasting into the mayo
stitching in the domain anywhere in the
middle s TP domain only need one label i
don't need labels that because there's
not consciously knowledge Gregory et nos
TP is just the profile of MPLS network
right so it's no different than in Paris
network we try to look at SR and OS as
or southern belle STP is a profile of
asaram us
well actually impair STP can be
provisioned with a control plane to
again there are control plane for MPLS
TP is gmpls and then that they've been
discussed so began there are different
options and they're in different
considerations but MPLS TP does have GM
LS control point that been stated in ITF
document scanner gmpls
well again we are not offering the
solution for the control plane here so
this is not about the control
well again that's absolutely legitimate
question I appreciate the question so
yeah we need to think about the control
plane aspect of this and how this all
works I think that what is now reflected
in this that there are controller
centralized controller or hierarchical
controllers may be used to address
distributed control plane it's
absolutely valid scenario well let's
think about it we need to to Catalina
maybe a flirt a nun question from from
Jeff it's not clear for artists the
spring working up what CSR has to be
profile it is or would be because I
don't think we've ever discuss Asylum
pstp so if you say it's a profile of a
Sheraton yes
they go to to define it so that we know
what's inside the profile or outside
your profile yes thank you very much
meeting is as admin okay thank you
ablutions browser thank you
very much