the part about managing expectations
right hi amar no I have a software
problem um let me just shortly say a few
words about me I've I'm a local boy here
I'm from Zurich I've been to eat eh do
ghouls Erick and then I started founding
companies and that's the second 1 i'm
now at vision we do devops and then in
my spare time I like to do event
networks so for example the Wi-Fi here I
built it last night so I hope it works
anyway my twitter handle i'll probably
put on the slides tweet about it and
there probably will be online at some
point so you can have a look at them
later so what what is this talk about
what i'm going to talk about so first
what is this devops thing right so it's
like cloud marketing buzzword bingo I
hope you all will have your bingo sheets
with you um and the second thing is
where where is the security right I mean
how how is this going to work and then I
brought to customer examples with me so
you can have a look how this all looks
like then there's room for questions I
assume but actually we just talked to
Florian that if you have any questions
or stuff you want to discuss when they
pop up please raise your hand and wave
and make yourself heard to Florian and
you get a mic to ask them right away I
think that's maybe more no discussion
thing what is DevOps right apart from
all the marketing and buzz word thingy
um let me introduce it to you and
discuss it a little bit so we all on are
on the same page so DevOps the word
comes from development and operations
dev ops and there's two core things that
that it entitles which is bring agile
software engineering tools and processes
to operations people so stuff that
software developers have been doing for
decades automation testing operation has
been struggling with or has been
adopting a last maybe five years but
there's still much room for improvement
so automation infrastructure is co
versioning rollback testing conine's
integration testing and deployment for
code and for especially for the
infrastructure as code and on the other
hand there is a lot of operations
experience and try to bring the back to
developers so for example for
scalability the independent
microservices so if one part of an
application or application stack falls
over not everything should be down and
at the end for production inside
monitoring logging metrics that
operations people use for their daily
bread right make that available to
developers as well to make them to help
them make informed decisions about the
architecture but also on the development
of their applications they're doing and
of course together it's make the the
guys who pay the bill so the business
owner application owner make them more
happy and let them decide what to do let
me go into do those things a bit more
with more deeper the collaboration thing
is probably one of the the new things
right I mean it's the whole culture
thing it's their spin this you know
worked fine in deaf and it's knobs
problem now mentalities that there was a
huge wall different teams of course also
different know-how and different types
of people right I mean left the creative
calipers we have the 21st 7 being up at
night operations people and of course
there are different kinds of people and
different teams and so that has been a
mostly communications problem right it's
also been a delegation from the
developers that they're not a
responsible for water code right because
we if it crashes at night it's your
operations people that have to wake up
and that's been a problem that's painful
I call it I say it's been escalating but
it's been a problem that's been
addressed by let the teams collaborate
make common teams put operations people
together with software engineers in
teams and let them together handle the
problems that arise agile operations
engineering it's let me come back to
that later
counter fear of change with automated
testing that means there's always going
to be changes right we heard it this
morning in the opening talk you have to
plan for changes you have to plan for
updates and if you you should feel
comfortable doing them because then the
barrier of changing stuff gets lower and
lower you feel more comfortable to do it
more often and that of course means
smaller changes and that of course means
less risk to break stuff and put the
developers in control at least to some
point give them self-service tools that
they can use and interact with with the
application when it's running so also to
take the operations people may be out of
the critical path and enable the
developers to do their jobs basically
right infrastructure as code that what I
was starting to tell before change from
hand grumster servers to operations
engineering so basically instead of
making service by hand and configuring
by hand or by short sell scripts treated
as an engineering problem as a software
engineering problem and make or use
readily available solutions to fix that
and of course if you have that if your
servers are automatically set up like
those or almost you gain speed and
reliability you humans make errors
that's normal if the servers are set up
automatically there's much less room for
error you gain versioning and roll back
so basically you know standard software
engineering benefits and of course you
need to be automated so that the
developers can do themselves so for
example give each developer a full stack
of the application including databases
and back ends and caches and web servers
and out of whatever it needs to run so
they can try out their code without
breaking it into production no money
will change is in production
da so if they wanted to have something
changed in production they change it in
a tool that does all the operations
engineering you can test the change you
can roll it out to a testing environment
you can then rolled out controlled in
production environment and it's a it's
you know it's an engineering solution
for that and of course if you can do it
once in production you can do as many
times as you need for testing different
branches for testing different versions
there's there's different combinations
different migration scenario that's the
whole point of automating the
infrastructure as well there's a lot a
lot of tools and there's a whole
category of DevOps tools and sourceforge
and github and you name it and DevOps
has been also reduced to the tools that
it uses right there's more there's the
whole trust thing there's the automation
thing but of course the tools enable you
to automate and you can reuse them and
you don't have to do it all from scratch
so of course for atomic deployment and
rollback you need some sort of packaging
right that includes all the dependencies
for the application you want to deploy
for example we we've been using Debian
packages and RPM packages for attack
packages and now slowly moving into a
ducker so basically to have a consistent
package of everything of the application
all its dependencies or the libraries or
the runt an environment as far as
possible in one place so that you can so
what you see and what your test is
actually what you're going to get in
production as well infrastructure state
management configuration management also
called there is different readily made
of tools available puppets all chef
ansible you name it um there do about
the same thing and it's then again a
matter of taste which one you want to
choose continues integration testing
deployment the tools you've probably
heard of Jenkins very popular
open-source to Travis CI is a hosted
solution very well known for their
free open-source work to do gitlab CI is
an to integrating to get management I'll
come to that later and of course
atlassian bamboo from that class Ian
suit of tools help you to do that all
and then the self-service part there's
tools you can use for that for example
vagrant which is a virtual machine and
provisioning tool that you can use to
provision the testing environments for
example developers so that then they
just get pull a repository with the
discrete declaration of the test machine
and then they can instantiate as many of
them as needed or through continuous
deployment so for example through the
Jenkins tools you can use them to order
deploy stuff to an essential environment
so you don't need to keep track or
update or support basically the
developers doing stuff from their own
machines infrastructure testing so of
course the instructure tools you would
use to build it up infrastructure
testing is something as soon as you have
it deployed or Britain in code you can
use the code qualities tools to run on
them and make your own infrastructure
code better so that's the bring soft
engineering best practices back to
operations you have a lot of moving
parts if you have a normal web
application as we use it has at least
one or two databases some cash some web
servers or modification server and they
all need to be configured to talk to
each other with credentials and stuff so
that's why we should be uni testing each
of those components separately plus then
the instantiating one of those stacks so
that they all know where the components
are a service discovery works so that we
can be sure that we don't do any
regressions from the infrastructure side
when changing something based you know
basic software engineering process
feedback 14 for developers production is
mostly a black box right they ship it
and then it I don't know so there to
also bring self-service to bring them
the insight into what is actually
happening in what they've been doing all
day there's two things we we do actively
want is them to collect all the locks
especially application logs but also web
server logs while flogs so that the
developers can actually see what's
happening and that of course helps them
to search for a production error root
causes and giving them in this case a
web GUI where they can search for stuff
and do their stuff they usually would do
on some single server SS Aging in and
then looking at lock files or I don't
know that's much easier and much easy
and you can or we sell them that by the
benefit of not needing to use go to the
servers especially if multiple servers
it's a pain and once they use it we can
take away the the root access to the
production so they or any axis SSH
access to the production which again
helps to the no changes in production
policy right nor manual changes in
production policy and the other value is
it's all merge from servers and indexed
and you can search and filter and stuff
so that's pretty pretty cool yo que les
fue la cubana is one product it's a open
source product there is also a Splunk
for example a commercial product it's
very similar so that's like the the
output right and then for the debugging
output maybe and then for the whole
what's happening in a more quantitative
way you can either get from the logs or
collect separately servant application
metrics like New Relic does for example
it's a software as a service that does
that but you can also have it hosts
yourself for some influx TB time series
data base for example where you can both
collect server metrics like CPU
ramdisk and so on and so forth but also
correlate them with application metrics
number of locking users number of
sessions number of hits and that that
stuff that can help you debug stuff when
when you have problem right so in the
end we usually end up with a workflow
like this we have on the very left to
developers application owners older the
people that the two stuff right they
work with version management standards
of the engineering in the same version
management we have configuration
management configuration management then
provides each developer feedback loop
with a development environment where
that's docker container or vagrant
virtual machine doesn't matter from the
version management for both the code and
the Confederation management this
continuous integration contains
integration basically if it's a lot of
programming language needs to be
compiled or built or somehow aggregated
building packaging and then there's a
hopefully automated testing at least we
can provide in the infrastructure to do
automated testing that is still need to
write to test themselves and then of
course given the feedback from the cadiz
integration by a chat pod for example to
slack or hip chat or whatever they use
or to a dashboard or whatever basically
enabling them to to work faster right
and then deploying all that to some
testing production whatever servers they
are built by confession management and
then deployed the application from
continuous integration and deployment
that's basically it and then of course
there's the whole operations thing right
it was the software engineering process
and then there's whole operation stuff
so once it runs there is need some
databases and backends they need to be
created and supported of course for
disaster recovery you need some backups
then once you provision a service you
need to make sure it actually runs so
the service monitoring and alerting
logging a metrics were already talked
about it's all the it's all the standard
of operations stuff right
so when discussing with my colleagues we
were like okay so where's the security
right there's no button called security
right so that's maybe because it's all
in there right I mean the security is an
integral part of the software
development deployment and operations
processes and it's almost everywhere
that security is involved on different
layers and levels of course so let's go
through them and and discuss and if you
have input or or opinions to share
please speak developer stuff that's
probably the most white box testers do
right I talk to developers they look at
code they look at what libraries they
use where they're from what versions
they're using did they think anything
about what they're doing do they use a
libraries or do they implement crypto or
some allure you know something by
themselves which they shouldn't so
that's a record education education
education training help support that's
what I need right because it doesn't
matter how secured a deployment and
operations process if the software shit
it doesn't matter right and that's my
you know were to you please do anyway to
developers so that their software gets
better and that it's a it's an
incremental process that it gets better
and better okay that was developers part
let's go to you no more technical and
tools engineering stuff configuration
management was one of the issues and the
infrastructure donation we discussed
earlier the conversion management is
pretty coolant in terms of the system
security we any of the tools i mentioned
earlier basically you have a declarative
way of saying how you want the system to
be and then the tool make sure that the
state is a is what you defined earlier
so baseline system security is like a
typical example um
services system services to enable or
disable telnet Dolph SSH da of course
the whole system users management users
groups Keys hashes sudoers can all make
sure that you declare what which users
are supposed to be there then which
users are supposed to be absent and this
is to make sure that in 50 minutes at
his latest the system will converge to
that state and of course you should
monitor what it does and have its feet
to the logging system and when you
detect that it does changes that you
didn't you know you didn't change
something in the code but it does
changes maybe something happened on the
server and you should have a closer look
at it you can sit up for example the
triple A's or educational theorization
an accounting for example with a cute
factory or LDAP or whatever the tool the
customer uses for the rest of the users
right it should have for example SSH
access or some other access of course
that axis doesn't work if the system is
offline and that's why we still need to
have some system users to do log in and
fix stuff if the system is offline and
then there's you know host fireball for
example iptables on linux systems or PF
for whatever your software choices you
can make sure that it's pretty tight and
locked down and that it will be and stay
like that another topic is logging i
mentioned the e lk stack before audit
logging is a is a big thing right i mean
the devops mentality of enabling the
developers to change stuff of course
doesn't mean that they have like a free
game of doing anything right they have
some certain processes they can do for
example a deployment process or Quality
Assurance process or whatever they you
know are allowed to do and accounting
make sure that it's it's a valid
developer and so on so forth but of
course needs to be locked it needs to be
times them who did what when what was
changed exactly so that it's a it's in
there Nordic trail
figure out what happened actually we
feed application requests logs basically
the many logs as we can find or as the
customer should have access to and we
make it as as right once read many as
possible or as feasible for the
customers or basically it's read only 44
normal users so that we have some kind
of yeah and I'm not going to call it
tamper proof right but at least some
sort of tamper evidence see here that
it's only for restricted admin access to
change the logs and of course we can
also export them to some real right ones
medium if the customer requires that
ideal case they introduced earlier
already here also just for reference
service monitoring I mean typical
operations problem also well there's a
security aspect in that I mean older but
the services are available yeah okay
availability it's a security thing but
of course there are so many layers to to
monitor on right I started at the top
layer application layer but of course
there's all the transport layer stuff
that automated monitoring can can take
care of like checking the ssl
certificates and protocols and ciphers
and poodle attacks and so and so forth
so we can from a monitoring perspective
make sure that the systems are up to
date the system parameters like
utilization or stuff isn't exceeding
some limits and we also do check for
updates and backup in through the
monitoring you have a complete picture
of a system and also to give the
customer access to that monitoring and
see what the state is actually of his
application
back up typical disaster recovery
problem right again as right once read
many as possible the that's also you
know if if there was a compromise to of
course be able to roll back to a known
good state but also to figure out what
actually was changed and have their some
tamper evidence of the application or
application server if something happens
we don't want to add the backup to be
changed later except of course it needs
to be perched or or something if the
customer decides to do that it doesn't
need it anymore we do the back up so
that the servers are enrolled
automatically by confirmation management
that helps by there they all the servers
are by default backed up there are no
orphans servers that are oh I don't know
where it went and of course we can when
it's automated we can make sure that a
backup target is not in the same data
center or cloud provider or
infrastructure it needs to be so we can
you know cross up to off-site backups
automatically and then we want to have
to data encrypted both that address that
and at in motion and as I mentioned
before we monitor that as well version
management we talked about it earlier
software engineering basic principles
right we use get nowadays you'll
probably know a subversion or CVS before
that both customer code and fold con
fresh management code and config config
is parameters like credentials stuff
like that it's all in a repository of
course with probably with more tighter
restrictions on who can access that
audit lock mentioned before there's a
different services you can use for
example for get their shared ones we can
buy a software-as-a-service github is
the most known bit bucket and get laptop
calm or others there's a ton of services
for that and of course if you want to
have it internal for either political
company political reasons or if you
don't want to be down when get up is
down there's different products you can
buy so
and actually get love is free you don't
have to buy it that you can use yourself
on premise or wherever your replication
is is sitting again authentication
authorization through some central
database and since all the developers
have offline copies and no credentials
in code please or you will show up in
heck my github com but what is it called
the side anyway continuous integration
um if you didn't know what that was its
trigger build package doesn't deploy on
each commit we usually have to target
off the commit and as our target of to
deploy selectable by branch repository
and tag so you can say okay everybody
can commit to certain brunch but of
course it's not a production branch that
only certain or closed group of people
have access to manual protiv production
releases is a standard continuous
deployment feature like Jenkins has that
all the other tools ever as well and the
only thing that we may need to take care
of is where to put the completed build
and package artifacts right because if
you can if you can upload your own
ready-made code to the artifactory
doctor registry or debian or RPM
registry of course you can own the
application just by uploading your own
valid looking package there so that one
needs to be pretty tight of course it's
much easier when it's automated from the
from the code part under assuming the
code port is secure that one doesn't
need any manual access so it can be
pretty locked down feedback to status
and authentication of course central
again okay so what kind of automated
testing and what is the sector a
security relevant right it's both a
security as in availability problem of
course if developer uploads code that's
not syntax confirm conformant you gonna
have a bad
time especially for interpreted
languages so of course when you do that
you can also check for a coding style
and do some static code analysis to find
some obvious box that is pretty well I
call it low maintenance right because
it's it's you set it up once and you can
you have some low-hanging fruit get from
there but then of course unit tests
assuming that software developers are
good at that rate they have some unit
tests that actually fire if and only if
there's a problem with with changing the
code and then if available and if
there's budget in time functional tests
so basically do a test deployment of the
whole application with each commit or at
least of each tax reliefs and check that
and that can go just checking whether
whether it runs or go deeper like make
test requests and check that the answer
actually matches what you what you have
in your test data database there we were
thinking about maybe also implementing
some security checks on the functional
level so for example for each tech
release automatically run common
scanners nein ich to our SQL map against
the deployed application and then of
course there's going to be huge you know
list of output but I mean what could be
feasible there is to have a to have a of
course when you do a regular pen test or
at least inspection of the software you
know declare an output of one of those
tools as ok or acceptable and then when
there's changes to that so if there's
new stuff popping up then alert the
developers that ok now you change
something that actually is very visible
to scanners outside maybe you should
have a look at that and ok if it's
really ok
databases and back ends now we're going
maybe a little bit away from the from
the software engineering problems
there's a ton of different backends and
and other ready-made software standard
software that that the applications need
and depend on there's a lot a lot of
open unsecured unpatched versions of
those up out in internet showdown is
your friend Brett is I think was the
last one to be pretty wide open and
honest Takeda taxes and stuff but of
course all the others have had their had
their problems as well so it's really
really important to have an up-to-date
confirmation management template for
them that basically provides them with
the same config which usually is not a
default config and then you can add all
the clustering credential management
fireable complete backup convict
monitoring config to that template and
so each time you need a whatever mysql
service or whatever it's set up the
right way and if you change the template
once you can actually update all the
instances that you're using if there's a
problem or you need to deactivate or
activate some sort of attribute for them
and moving up the sack from the back
ends to the theory application service
it's it's basically the same thing right
there's a ton of different environments
of course we as a more service provider
oriented people we have a lot of
different ones if you only have one
application and usually you only need to
focus on one of those but then again
we've been seeing that when when
companies moved to micro servers
architectures that means that each team
has their own small code base of
whatever part of the applications are
implementing some of them actually are
allowed to choose their own programming
language for example or framework for
example and so then again yo where you
start having multiple different
environments of whatever java and bitin
and Ruby and whatnot there's going to be
around so there again the templating can
make sense to hide some of that
complexity and security relevancy
in there and also for completeness the
12 fact rap manifesto who knows it who
has heard about it about fifteen percent
twenty percent max so that's a that's
the well microservice that's the
operations experience system
architecture manifesto that that's been
very popular please have a look at it
it's it's very it's there's different
stuff you know make sure that you don't
have side effects make sure that your
application is deployable atomically all
that kind of stuff on one of the pretty
cool things that it proposes is that
instead of hard-coding credentials in
code instead of providing them in a
config file that you need to put
somewhere or in application when you
start it from the command line in some
sort of argument where you can see it
when you run PS forex provide them as
environment variables like for example
docker does because then there you can
start with each invocation of an
application you can start it with
different endpoints for the for the
backhands and that of course helps you a
lot if you have to deploy multiple times
for testing and development and
production and whatnot have a look at
that if you haven't already and then of
course in addition to all the
application servers is a ton of stuff
around that web servers cache servers
not security thanks Christian for talk
this morning H a proxy then all kinds of
VPN stuff open with them being maybe the
most popular I've mentioned iptables
before and then all the failover stuff
that's needed to if something goes down
like pacemaker keep alive d that's what
girls call our components that you
usually need in once or twice or thrice
somewhere and that's so much easier if
it's automated so let me make you know I
have an example for you so that's
something to look at
customer case one is a me we call it a
big hosting right it's basically PHP
MySQL with multiple different PHP
version and they have cache server
Barnidge and then they have a ton of
backends that in in addition to mysql
memcache tea ready solar and elastic
search for for all the indexing then
they use a application deployment with
ansible and actually they only use it at
does that is the Jenkins user that then
deploy uses ansible as a better cluster
SSH to deploy into all the application
service the same codebase the the other
stuff is managed by pop but in that case
basically so that puppet maintains the
state and ansibles used to do updates or
changes or anything that's an interrupt
basically in addition to all of that
then there's a a docker image for local
testing probably at some point it's
feasible that it might be used for
production as well but a docker image is
much more lightweight than to pull a
whole image of vagrant VirtualBox down
to each developers disk so they've opted
to to use that and so let me show you a
small system diagram I have no idea
whether you guys in the back you can
actually read that but well there
there's empty seats in the front so that
case is a multi tory architecture we
have some front-end web server for SSL
and varnish for caching and then the
varnish just load balancing over some
application servers I think the biggest
cluster they have it's about five
application service at the time and then
that each application server has an
engine X web server again which in feeds
their requests to the php-fpm which the
customer then can choose themselves in a
yellow file but it's version five six or
seven they have some standard libraries
like gip near a lake and stuff and then
feed both
the web server logs from from the
observer of course from fronting as well
plus than the old application logs to a
central lk is a log stash server so that
they can give Jeffers axis access to
that and then for all the back ends
there's a MySQL Maria DB cluster which
is low plans we are max scale DB proxy
the nav some ready is some solar and
then for files they use a redundant NFS
set up basically so that they have at
least a failover and so this this setup
is then deployed all over the world in
that case they have stuff in Switzerland
South Africa China and the US so that's
a pretty pretty standard setup that they
can now instantiate as many times as
they actually need another case that's
has been taking a lot of our time is an
open shift platform-as-a-service open
shift as you might know is a open source
project from brad head of course there's
an enterprise version of it that
internally uses kooban a days the Google
open source to that again manages the
different docker containers and it's on
a present open source so you can
download it yourself and run it on your
laptop if you want to but you can also
have a enterprise support if you want to
have that as a production backup we do
it for a pool at CH that's a switch so
its platform as a service and we're also
building it in the EU and the u.s. on
AWS actually enterprising premise is
probably something that's going to be
happening as well so that's that's the
whole point of automating this setup
right just a short intro what is open
shift in how does it work or what does
he do open shift as I mentioned is the
wrapper around two coordinators and
darker thingy so basically it Maps part
of the workflow that we saw earlier into
whole into the whole
thing so basically you have a git
repository with with your code the good
news is you can notify openshift API for
each commit and then the open shift
basically takes the code takes an empty
container and makes a release out of
that that put it in a maybe you won't
able it's a forklift there you can zoom
in and then you have to PDF and then
chips the the container give sequent the
container to coupon a days and then
kubin a days manages the docker
containers as in deploys a new version
deploys the new version those rolling
deployments so deploys a one new version
kills one old version deploys the second
new version kills another new version
and so you can have upgrades and updates
without without any downtime if it all
works if it doesn't then it rolls back
so that's just a short intro what is
open shift and how it all fits together
in this in this pipeline any questions
that's the marketing slide that's
basically it so I'm very open to discuss
further
testing yay so you brought up an
interesting problem which is secrets
management and one of the solutions
being the environmental variables and
wondering you comment about some other
alternatives such as secrets management
servers such as Walt yep etc for for
DevOps yeah we were thinking oh we were
thinking about using bold as the backend
to manage the secrets actually so Walt
is a soft piece of software if you don't
know it that basically is a very locked
down small application there's a RESTful
API where you can request a credential
and then if your certificate matches and
if you're allowed to and so on so forth
gives you back a credential and for
certain services you can even generate
credentials on the fly so that you have
you know key roll over and all those
kind of process integrated to that the
problem with with vault as an example or
other existences it needs a changes in
the applications that application needs
to go and request a credential for the
mask you service or whatever so if you
were able to do that then it's no
problem that involved it's just yet
another back-end basically for your
application and then it's just as secure
as possible or as lockdown as possible
another another back and basically if
that doesn't work or two to do a service
discovery where is the walt service API
you need to input that by some means
there the environment variable is a very
very quick and painless way does it
answer your question so you concern is
security you showed a lot of measures
you've integrated in the whole lifecycle
prevention measures other measures like
backups logs for afterwards if something
happens but what kind of measures you
have to get alarmed of a security breach
or something there's just
well excellent questions and I mean
that's the that's the pain of being in
the in the defense side right I mean we
have lots of logs we have lots of stuff
that we try to filter out of the logs if
something changes but nobody committed
something that's that's a sign there is
a lot of host IPS tripwire all those
kind of stuff there's stuff that we can
try to do like duty application code if
it's in interpreted language read-only
like darker does for example that again
if somebody charged still tries to
access or write stuff then we can be
alerted there is there's all those kinds
of stuff when we try to feed them into
either the logging or the metric side
and then configure your monitoring to
alert alert stuff thank you have you had
a look at tools that you can plug into
the continuous integration cycle to make
it easier to test for security
vulnerabilities for example i'm thinking
like most dependency check to check for
library dependencies or i'm thinking
about continuous security frameworks
like gauntlet or PDT security do you
have any comments on these kinds of
tools I've personally not use them
thinking about them I wouldn't remember
any of our customers requesting
integration of such a tool into the
continuous integration process where we
manage the process for them if they
mention themselves it might be that I
don't know that's why I'm speaking here
to get to discussion rolling in what are
their what tools and measures do you use
for both black box and white pocket
texting it would be suitable for
continuously applying over and over
again to detect changing stuff as early
as possible
what is your strategy for instant
response assuming your machines were
breached for forensics let's say that's
an old whole lotta talk I've got the 10
minute warning already let's discuss
this ought to be okay thank you are know
for a very comprehensive talk what I
like about your talk was not only
mentioning modsecurity of course I think
vision is a company which is really
walking the talk so you're really doing
DevOps and we've seen this in a very
nice way in your talk all the different
aspects which you have covered the
question I have is being a death of
company we've seen your ELQ stack and we
know if I manage to inject anything into
your system it will certainly end up in
a lock and if i can make sure that the
value of your operation people or
anybody do as everybody's a dev up guy
at your company if i get you to look at
this request i have a perv a perfect log
injection attack vector into your
browser absolutely so if you access s
you get if you get an XSS through the
logging into into the buff into the
logging to the logging framework front
end and it gets executed you're gonna
have a bad time that's why you cannot
have a better yeah we all gonna have a
bad time I'll have fun time well that's
true yeah that's that's a real problem
and that's why kabana the he calls like
JavaScript application that that queries
the log stash I sorry the elastic search
api was recently acquired by elastic
search the company also to be able to
you know in source that kind of
responsibility and knowing a few people
from elasticsearch accompany i hope they
have their application security in check
and since it's open source you're all
very very well
come to have a look at the code and
proposed changes should they be
necessary you mentioned automated unit
tests do you didn't mention tools so
you've mentioned several other tools or
like orchestration on occasion do you
use any and do prefer knee we as well as
we mostly use a for example
configuration management tools there is
specific tools for the different
languages there is for example server
spec and respec respec below something
spec but basically where you can test
for for is the file there does it
contain the string and that kind of you
know service stuff is support open those
kind of stuff to do continuation for the
configuration management and systems
Stacy I marmont automated security
software honestly so there's two tools
that we recommend a lot one of them
they're they're both free gauntlet is on
github it's GA UN TLT it's a bevy of an
automated free open-source security
tests yeah but but more importantly you
can call any tests that you want for
unit tests and number two is break man
that twitter mate it's mostly for Ruby
environments but it's autumn testing in
third I guess is do you know about
rugged software and rugged DevOps
because we're growing a tribe of
speakers and your content would be very
good for that about what soybeans called
rugged so if we're our rugged DevOps
there's basically one day tracks that
developer conferences versus security
conference where we're giving them good
tool chains like yours yep ok cool
thanks for the input
I think we have time for one last
question we don't apparently or there is
no no other question any other questions
time for one more well thank you very
much
you