hello everyone I feel like a rock star I
mean they have a backstage with a super
big bathroom with shower for people are
singing I'm all miked up I mean I really
feel like singing and dancing but we're
not here for that and that's probably
best for you no I'm sorry I'm sorry
those days are gone anyway so I'm the
only thing that stands between you and
lunch so let's make it tidy and and in
short hopefully so Amanda Berry's ani
I'm the founder of a company called
inverse puff and I'm here to present
about our little project called the USB
armory so how many of you don't know
anything about the USB armory raise your
hand ok so I hope that this would be
interesting for you and for the other
half i still hope you would be
interesting for you than i can give you
more insights into our project so just
to tell you a little bit of background
about what we do so we're company has
been doing software as well as hardware
security for more than 10 years we
specialize in exotic sectors such as
automotive avionics and every two years
we try to do a public research where we
present some exotic stuff in 2007 we
went where one of the first ones to
present to talk about car hacking with
injecting traffic information signals on
a car two years after that we did a
tempest attack sniffing keystroke using
either lasers or on the power line in
2011 we broke Chip and PIN in 2014 we
did packing impacted to in pocketing
packet over Ethernet attacks and then in
2015 we decided that we wanted to build
something for a change rather than break
the things that we were being handed to
and so we decided to build a hardware
project called the USB armory which is
this device over here which as you can
see it's very very very tiny so what is
the USB armory and why did we decide to
do it so it's a advice which is designed
for personal security applications and
the main idea the first idea which
prompted the creation of such a device
was to simply have secure encrypted
storage with something that we could
trust in a week of control I mean
you can get a lot of USB drives which or
have military-grade encryption whatever
that means and you have no idea what
they do and hopefully you would think
that they would implement good security
but every time we test the harder of
those things they're very successful
they're very vulnerable to trivial
hardware attacks so we wanted a device
which would present itself as a hannah's
mass storage and then we could just copy
a file to it then you will encrypt the
file with ir g PG or whatever algar in
which we would deem acceptable and that
the user would would feel safe about it
but then we thought why using mass
storage why don't we make a device which
is tcp/ip connected so that we can
expose a more rich functionality to the
host rather than a simple of mass
storage device rather than a simple USB
Drive with tcp/ip we could just have a
web server and we could ever reach your
interface to do more actions for
encrypting the files and also sharing
the files and maybe scanning the files
from our or whatever on the device on
the USB device itself so not on the host
and then we fought but we have TCP IP
connectivity then we could also do
things like having the device
authenticating the host and then maybe
having the device doing the data
self-destruction if we don't do a
certain action if we don't present a
valid certificate or if we trigger a
fail-safe war for some reason we we're
thinking about expanding with more and
more and more functionality ah and then
we thought that if you have which we put
a standard computer rather than having a
single purpose device on such a USB
device then we could also have an SSH
proxy so if I want to connect to
whatever service I have I can hold the
keys on the device itself I can ssh to
the device itself with some disposable
password and then i can ssh out of the
device itself to the internet so slowly
and slowly and we can have a passer
imagine and so on so slowly and slowly
the idea came that rather than having a
single purpose device there would be a
great security benefit in having a
generic purpose device in such a compact
form factor because it would enable not
only a
single application so it wouldn't just
be an authentication token or a wallet
or an SSH proxy it could be more and
more applications into one device um and
if we would allow to have a familiar
development environment and a standard
environment on the device that the user
and developers could develop on we could
enable advanced functionality such as
this one like the USB device ID
authenticate the host or data
self-destruction and and so on which
where features that you couldn't have on
such a small device at the time so the
design goals were set very clearly it
must be a compact USB power device or
something that you can carry in your
pocket it must have fast cpu in a
generous amount of RAM to enable all the
richer applications that we wanted to a
mass support secure boot so that you can
ensure that only the code that is signed
by you gets executed on the device it
must provide standard connectivity means
over USB so not too many complex driver
required and very important you must
have a familiar developing an execution
environment so not something which
requires a high learning curve to
develop on and the design should be open
so we built this device selecting
freescale IMX 53 system-on-a-chip which
is fairly powerful given the size of the
device this device is more powerful than
the first Prospero pie for instance it's
an arm cortex a8 which can be clocked
between 800 megahertz and and 1.2 gig
Earth's almost all data sheets are
public and there's no NDA require which
is a very good thing the data sheets are
ok far better than any other vendors on
the device has Trustin and secure boot
secure storage insecure arm support and
this excellent native support for this
system on a chip and this good stock and
production support guarantee so you
don't want to commit to a design and
then you realize oh now i want to make
3,000 of these and sorry we don't have
enough system on the chips in the world
for having your device being built so
that would suck so that was also one of
the requirements so the trust and
support of this device so this system on
a chip is much more complex than what it
needs to be for the sake of this
specific
device so what we do in our design is a
lot of things that we just don't power
on in order to keep power consumption
and minimum and only focus on the
interface that we care about which is
mainly USB and then some other
peripheral connections that we have
trust and support for this system on a
chip is has a fairly good implementation
we tested a lot of trust and
implementation and we found this one to
be to be fully adequate for for being
used so what trusted is if you don't
know about it think about it like kind
of like virtualization ah but it's a
much simpler scheme which only allows
you to have two domains running in your
execution context and these domains are
handled at a very low level by the CPU
and the hardware peripherals and what
this allows you to do is to have a
non-secure domain where you can add your
user mode applications and your your
kernel and then you can have a
completely separate context which is
called the secure domain when you have a
separate user mode and a separate
privileged mode but the idea of Trustin
is that you can also use it as a
hardware firewall so you can decide to
assign a specific Hardware sub component
of the system on a chip only to the
secure mode and this allows you to
segregate let's say the microsd
interface or the USB interface only to a
trust the driver that you put in secure
mode and you can define a very clear set
of api is very minimal and very
restricted to the task for exchanging
data between the non-secure and the
secure world so this is the mana cheap
as the capability of assigning each
hardware peripheral that's embedded in
the system on a chip to only one of the
two domains um so for instance you can
have the LED which is which is present
on the device only confined to the
secure domain which means that you can
do things like if the LED turns on you
know by definition that the secure code
is running at that very moment and then
maybe you can ask for a password or
something like that making sure that the
non-secure domain
not fishing for that password and other
time it was a lack of of a good
playground environment and research and
training environment for for Trustin and
this was also one of the drivers for
developing this board with this specific
system-on-a-chip the project is
completely open source is that open
source does it get the full software is
open source and also the hard word the
schematics the PCB layout everything is
open source and has been done also with
an open source tool so anyone can open
the design files can easily modify the
design files without requiring any
license and and it can also send the
output of the fabrication output of the
tool to a factory and if you make a
hundred of these it gets economical to
do so yourself as well um it is very
tiny we have a micro SD card slot where
all the codes come from there's no
persistence on the device except for a
few fuses which I'm going to talk about
we have a five-pin breakout adder where
you can attach sbir i square c gpio and
serial port and so on and we have this
led which can also be used for secure
mode detection we're now supported we
have official support for debian ubuntu
arch linux and also if you want to play
with Trustin there's a very nice project
called GNote OS which implements a
domain separation are on the USB armory
and allows you to have a microkernel
into the secure domain handling drivers
such as the micro SD card and then you
can put a Linux system in the non-secure
domain so kind of virtualizing it but
not really with this domain separation
that the image and with this device we
can emulate arbitrary USB devices we can
emulate on ethernet device and mass
storage device a keyboard or whatever
you like and I'm going to talk about
this so of course the primary use of
this device is device mode as just
mention but it turns out that we can
also use it in host mode so we can
invert the role of the device because
the USB controller allows us to have a
great freedom in configuring it and so
we can have so this is an example of the
device running in host mode this was
actually one of our first test
so we just change with a breadboard very
crudely we change the gender of the plug
and then we plug we attach a USB hub
with a mouse a keyboard a USB display
and also a Wi-Fi chip and it will just
add the device running standalone you
know with X Windows and just using it so
we made this in a much prettier form
factor so now we also have this host
adapter which merely changes the gender
of the of the USB ports you feed power
back in and then you can attach so here
we have a Wi-Fi dongle but you can
attach whatever you want so it can also
work as a standalone device and we
realized this only after building the
device but it was a it was a nice it was
a nice thing it was a nice feature
because the USB controller really allows
you to do whatever you like so uh some
pictures for the development process so
this was a development board that we
made for accessing the BGA chip so bgaa
means that you have a ball grid array so
you have a this matrix of little walls
that it's very difficult to solder and
desoler on your own you can do it but
it's a messy process and prone to errors
and we thought that for prototyping the
device we could just get this very
expensive socket that allows us to have
a solderless connection with the BGA and
then we would break out each ball and
and and and develop on this thing but
the problem was that the power regulator
tolerance requirements are so tight that
you really need to put all the power
components on a proper PCB and with the
proper distances you cannot solder this
on your own you're on and if you and
also the system on a chip needs to be on
a PCB as well so if you put the power on
a PCB and sock on a PCB you might also
as well put a USB plug the micro SD and
then you have the final board so at the
end this effort was kind of useless and
I was like being like Darth Vader
telling to my colleagues you fail me for
the last time because they tried for ten
times to build a power up that would
power the device externally but at the
end we said okay let's just build this
thing and let's hope that reward so this
this was kind of like a super
stardestroyer a big thing which costs a
log but at the end it just crashes down
into useless but it's pretty so this is
the layout of the board this is a key
card or tie cut depending how you
pronounce it the open-source software
which we use for the layout the biggest
problem here was to route the RAM memory
to the sock because when you're out
memory to a cpu all of these traces they
need to be exactly of the same length to
the decimal point of the millimeter and
this open-source tool doesn't really
help you in doing that unlike
professional tools so all of these were
length match with much loved by hand
which was a very painful process but
this is the price you pay for having
everything open source on the other hand
the 3d graphics capability of key card
are excellent when they are useless but
you know if you want to see your board
in 3d before having it produced you can
you can do so so that was cool so this
is the Alpha boy that we made the very
first one it is of course bigger than
the final product because we wanted to
have a jtag header easily accessible to
understand if the board would not boot
up on what the problem was and we made
it so that we could also cut the excess
PCB compared to the original form factor
so that then we could also test the
original form factor even if it wouldn't
make much of a difference but maybe for
heat dissipation it could mean a
difference so it was designed in that
way so this is an almond tech jtag
controller attached to the device likely
the device booted for at the very first
version he booted up so this actually
wasn't necessary but it was a precaution
that we needed to take and I think it's
pretty amazing that we'd completely open
source technology we can build such a
standalone USB connected computer which
is more powerful than a pension too but
dark later prefers this because it's
black so for this reason we made it
black and not and not green so these
were the different provisions this was
the Alpha board then we made a beta
actually we made more than one beta so
what we decided to do too
optimize the design and and and cut the
cost of building the device we when you
build PCBs you generally have a sheet
where you can fit in one tooling in one
manufacturing process more than one
revision of the board and we could do I
think sex six or eight of them so with
just one production we tested different
beta revisions where we try to power up
the RAM in different ways by converting
the five volts directly with the voltage
required for the rum or we use in by
using a buck converter by using a
different power regulator in order to
try and cut down the cost eventually we
found what was the best compromise
between price and end performance and
then the final mark one design was
selected from one of these we also try
to change the number of layers
originally the board was eight layers
and we were able to drop to six layers
by you know just keeping certain
recommendations that they give to you
but sometimes they just work you gotta
try it so we when you make a device
which is this small you cannot be
conservative in the terms of the
recommendation and guard lies that the
part vendors tell to you so we did a lot
of things that were not by the book but
in the end they work just fine so let me
talk about secure boot because it's an
important feature of this board and and
when testing so we do a lot of hardware
testing and secure boot is often an
overlooked feature which eventually
allows jailbreaking on their own of a
device because it's other not correctly
implemented or because it's not
implemented at all because its
difficulty so this specific
system-on-a-chip supports something
called high assurance boot which is the
freescale and XP terminology for secure
boot and the idea is that you fuse your
own keys so we're not talking about
secure boot such as the one on a PC
where you might have an OEM key phone
from Microsoft here the only content is
content that you flash on the device so
you fuse for public keys into the system
on a chip and this is a one-time
permanent irreversible operation and
once that is done in secure boot is
activated the system ownership will
refuse to boot any boot loader which is
not sign with one of those keys and you
can revoke up to three keys out of four
if you want to this also makes for some
interesting scenarios where you can have
free valid case the fourth one is junk
and then if you revoke all of the free
keys the device it becomes a brick
because it can never put any code
because the four feet key is random so
you're going to do things like that and
this unlike a modern PC this feature
cannot be reset so once you do it it's
done instant in a pc with a password you
can go into the bios and and remove the
secure boot functionality so this is a
feature of this device not a bug um so
you have certain parameters in the
register of the system on a chip which
over i square C so these are the
commands that you can invoke from the
bootloader you confuse the hashes of the
public keys that you want to and then
you can enable and lock them um in order
then to sign an image for a secure boot
for this I assurance boot um there's a
tool from freescale now and XP called
the code signing tool which however at
several issues so first of all it's
close its source and under and user
license agreement the end-user license
agreement is not a bad one because it
actually would allow resellers such as
as or people that integrate the system
on a chip to also distribute the tool to
its users so it's not I mean it's
restrictive but it also allows a lot of
freedom but saying that the tool is ugly
is a severe understatement the tool is
fairly horrible and also on the latest
version of the tool which is the only
one that now can be downloaded brace
compatibility with the specific system
on a chip due to a trivial bug which yet
that we identified but after more than
eight months and several inquiries at
all support levels uh they didn't fix
the issue and they don't allow download
of the previous version which you know
kind of sucks so this is a problem when
you're a very very small plane in the
hardware market is not that you don't
get support from the vendor is that the
support is kind of offensive I'm
they tell you that are going to look
into something and then it's really a
process that goes nowhere and you waste
a lot of time so we decide to just
reimplement the tool as open source
software which was the right thing to do
so now the AMX 50 free the secure boot
feature can be completely used and code
can be signed for it with completely
open source tools and this of course
apply to any board that uses this is the
motion on a check not specifically to
this one and we have two guides one
where you can still we still have
instructions for using the nxp tool ah
and we have the same guide converted
also for the open source tool so that
you can compare the two and you can
decide which one to use so this was also
uh this was a considerable effort on our
part and we were very pleased with the
results because in the end we make it
easy to use this kind of functionality
and and we often see in all the hardware
designs that we test for our customers
is that sometime features such as secure
boot are not used at all because the
tools or the support or the lack of
support given to the vendor to customers
doesn't really allow you to use these
functionalities with confidence also
because if you make a mistake or if you
don't have a full control and overview
of the process you risk ending up with a
lot of bricks which of course when you
when you manufacture or mass manufacture
an electronic device is not something
that you want so there was a lot of
engineering to make this procedure
reliable and and fairly easy to use and
also by open sourcing the tools it also
very clear to anybody that uses the
tools exactly what's what goes on in the
process of signing the images and
infusing the key ashes into into the
system on a chip and we also make it
easy to create these certificates which
are required for for this process so and
the idea with this functionality is that
so the system on a chip verifies the
bootloader so this is called secure boot
and then to further maintain the chain
of trust
the bootloader which in our case is you
boot verifies the kernel image and that
that's called verified boot so you put
supports embedding a key into his binary
blog the resulting compiled binary blob
and this key can be done used to verify
the colonel so the chain of trust is
maintained we fuse a key into the system
on a chip we embed a key in the image in
the you boot image the you would image
is a verified by the system on a chip
and the Linux kernel is verified by the
bootloader so we fully maintained the
chain of trust from the very moment that
device powers up until the end now of
course in the system on a chip there is
an embedded binary blob which performs
this operation and one of the issues
that is always raised is that you cannot
inspect or read this memory blob you
don't know what's the microcode which is
inside the system on a chip on this
specific system on a chip the binary
this binary blob is memory mapped so
unlike other shapes it can be freely
read by memory and there's also one
effort or some people that reverse
engineer to understand if if there's
anything funny going on so of course it
is not open source i mean III challenge
you to find any system on a chip that
would give you sources for the microcode
but at least we can read it in this case
which was a nice feature it's much
better than just not being able to
access that code at all so it's a nice
feature of that so in our documentation
page we do have hashes for this binary
blob so you can also verify that when
you receive your device you you get the
same revision the same binary blob in
the system on a chip and if you if you
like reverse engineering it can be it
can be inspected and it's all it's not
long so you can understand what it does
for ensuring that the operation of this
Buddha process so this is an example of
a successfully sign you good image ah
you got secure boot enable no events a
and this is an example of a failed
attempt where we have assurance boot
failures now this is done in
a verification mode which means you put
the device in a state where a secure
boot is only it's not truly enforced ah
because otherwise you wouldn't see any
debugging output when secure boot fails
of course you will not see the you boot
code at all because the system ownership
will refuse to boot the boot loader so
this screenshot here is done in
verification mode which is an
intermediate step which allows you to
verify that you're able to sign images
that you're you're fusing was correct
and then you can lock down the device as
a as a last step and this is verified
boot so verified boot this is comes from
you good from the bootloader we just
verifies the fit image that's the
terminology for the image study boots
which contains the colonel and the
so-called device tree which is a
external file which is pars by the boot
loader and Colonel to configure the
hardware of the device so if you want to
assign a GPIO to an LED or change
configuration of certain paths that's
what you do on into the device tree so
when we set the device in host mode
that's where that configuration is into
the device tree file ok so this cover
the hardware of the device as much as we
could and the software which enables you
to use the hardware functionality but
then of course we also needed an
application to show the potential for
this device the potential use for the
device and and to unleash the
functionalities and the use case
scenarios I wanted to so for this reason
we develop an application which is
called interlock all uppercase to as a
reference to the NSA code names for
internal projects that's why interlock
is always referred to all uppercase so
interlock is an open source file
encryption front end which is developed
for the USB armory but it's not limited
to being used on the USB armory if you
have a raspberry pi or whatever other
arm board or even on your laptop you can
you can use interlock freely there is
nothing specific in interlock a no code
which is specific for the USB are more
um and this project provides a
web-accessible file manager which is
tied to the linux unified key system
framework for encrypting and decrypting
our partitions and also we implemented
additional encryption features on stored
files we take advantage of disposable
passwords and you can options of the
linux unified key system to have more
than one password and i'm gonna i'm
going to show you a demo of this of this
application so first of all here see if
you see it maybe i can set the font a
little larger text looks looks looks no
okay anyway it's not it's not an
important i just want to show you that
here i'm in windows because i'm
presenting a presentation to you and the
biggest problem in IT nowadays is
presenting from a linux OS which is why
we use windows for this but if I feel
uncomfortable for whatever reason and I
want to jump into a Linux environment
here I just SSH into my USB device where
I feel warm and fuzzy that I have this
real linux environment running and not a
virtualized one so as you can see it's
very spawn civ it's just you know
connected to my Windows machine it just
acts as a standard Linux box with half a
gig of a gigabyte of RAM available so
simple so now so this is the interlock
application so i plug the device into my
laptop windows assigns or actually d USB
device assigns an IP address to windows
because if you have a dhcp server
running on the USB device the windows OS
will ask for an IP address to the device
which also enables some offensive usage
which i'm going to mention later but the
first thing that happens is that when i
connect the interlock server asks for a
client certificate if I don't have a
valid client certificate in my browser
then I can never talk to this service
which is also you know a very very nice
feature
when as soon as I pass this step igan
prompted with the volume name and a
password now this password can also be
disposed off after use so I can have
more than one password associated to my
encrypted volume so if I'm using this
device on a computer which I don't fully
trust and I don't want a loss of the
device to cause compromise of the
encrypted contents because someone might
have sniffed this password I can just
tick that box and as soon as this
password is being used for unlocking the
contents it is wiped so it's not valid
anymore and of course you can have more
than one password in the system so this
is a feature which is provided by the
Linux unified key system so now these
credentials are the credentials which
unlock the encrypted partition we don't
have an external database we don't have
a password file so as soon as I log in
those credential unlock the encrypted
partition and this is what this
interface that we have is showing to me
so it's a sort of kind of google drive
interface where I can see my files so
let's say that I want to upload a file
to it it is as easy as just dragging and
dropping the files here and the file now
has been uploaded onto the encrypted
partition every file that you see here
is uh is encrypted on it stays on the
encrypted partition and once the file is
on the encrypted partition I can also
decide to encrypt it with either a
symmetric cipher a yes or with openpgp
ah for instance so now I've encrypted
this fight with PGP these operation all
of these operations are running on the
USB armor itself and there are no
external dependencies for doing this so
we don't pipe to the gpg binary all of
this is used by all of this is done by
using standard go libraries this is a go
application which makes it i would say i
would argue more auditable and it's also
nice because we get one single static
binary without any external dependencies
so the environment for running in
turlock can be very very minimal
I can view files from this interface of
course I can download a file I can also
download a directory it will just be
compressed and given to me or I can
compress the directory I can encrypt the
direct line and just download it making
sure that no clear text content get
downloaded to to the host we have a full
log here of what's going on which also
store on the device we can generate gpg
key we can import a key if we want to
and we also have functionality 41 times
totp keys so the Google Authenticator
keys that you use so this is the key for
my kid up like the second factor
authentication and you can refresh it
and so on so you can also have a backup
of those here so on top of these
features are we also added integration
with signal for messaging so this device
now has an associated number which you
can register by using this function so
you can register a number either via SMS
or voice so have a sim or have a number
it could be my landline or whatever
which I decided to associate to this
device and now if I want to and if the
network works here because it's a little
going back and forth I can just decide
to text my use vrr me from my phone
using signal let's see if that word
demo gods I should have sacrificed more
goats to the demo gods let's see if we
have connectivity yes we do okay so I
have a contact here this is my contact
and I can just decide to to open a chat
so I received hello here on my phone I
can do it again so that you can see
hello and then I got another one and I
can also decide to send files directly
from here to my phone so what I can do I
have a file here I copy the file I go
into my chat and I send the attachment
and as you can see I just really receive
the picture of a lovely cat so you can
also and this of course also works from
one USB armory to the other so what's
the takeaway here the takeaway is that
if I want to share a file with a trusted
party using the USB armory I could
encrypt the file with gpg download the
file give it to my mail client which
must have some kind of ugly gbg plugging
and then send an email to my colleague
but with the signal plugging
connectivity what can I do if he's also
has a USB armory which is registered to
signal or maybe wants it to his mobile
phone we don't care I can just share the
fire directly from the domain of the USD
be armory with end-to-end encryption
twin bypassing all of this I can just
select a file and share it over signal
going from the USB device itself which
we think it's a pretty cool
functionality and of course we can also
receive files that will just be placed
directly into the context the contacts
folder so i can decide to send a picture
back if i want to so i can just select a
picture and then send it
let's see if it works
no network is really slow so when the
Wi-Fi goes up and down this causes
problem with windows okay there we go
you see the notification over there we
receive a message another message and
then here you see that a file up here so
this is the father we just sent to my
phone to to the device so we think this
integration is is very interesting and
it makes chatting and sharing files from
the device very very easy um as soon as
I log out from the device uh the
contents are locked or I can also decide
if I want to to power off the device
from here I'm not going to do that I'm
just going to log out as soon as I log
out the partition is encrypted again and
again this software can also be used not
only on the USB armory but on also on
whatever embedded system that you might
like we also made an embedded
distribution for interlock meaning
there's a framework called build route
which allows you to compile just by
using configuration files which are in
the form of the with the same standard
of the Linux kernel where you can define
what you want in the resulting image you
want geely BCE you want SSH you want
Python whatever you like and then you
can compile a kernel image with a new
method run disk to run another vice such
as the USB armory so we develop
configuration that allows easy creation
of these kind of images for the USB
armory so with just two commands it's
just easy this framework with just
download and compile everything you need
to create a linux kernel which has an
embedded ram disk with interlock and why
do we do this we do this because we want
the system on a chip to verify the
bootloader and we want the bootloader to
verify the kernel image but not only the
Linux kernel but also the file system
which is associated to it and the
interlock application with all of its
dependencies can fit in in LA
than seven megabytes of a file system so
what we do we put everything in one
kernel image we load that into rom and
what we have on the microSD card I
either than this single image which is
verified by the hardware it's our
encrypted partition so this is a very
minimal setup where we maintain the full
chain of trust from the hardware up to
the resulting encrypted partition
because this can only be in luck with
your credentials so this allows us to
create very compact and very efficient
images that they just put in less than
half a second on the armory and they're
very fast and they only expose the code
surface of interlocked itself and
nothing more so you can even not have
any SSH connection to this if you if you
if you want now let's talk about your
fancy fuses for the USB armory so is a
security tools any security tool can be
used both for protection but also for
attacks and being in the business of
doing security auditing and penetration
testing we also benefit from devices
such as this one in our job so the
obvious application of this device is
that it provides an easy and powerful
mean to emulate arbitrary USB devices
and not only emulating them at a
descriptor level which is something
which can be easily done with something
like the face Leinster board but you can
also expose a fool driver which might be
already there in the linux kernel or
that you might want to develop and and
and and also the speed which you can
achieve in executing this code is is
much faster than with our
microcontroller baseboards because you
have a full linux system running on this
you can do passive sniffing you can do
of course as I mentioned DNS hijacking
and traffic diversion because if you
expose a different driver from this
device the host will ask for an IP
address so you can present whatever DNS
you want you can present whatever route
you want and so on and in fact we also
had a few papers that were nicely done
by other groups oh one is USB armor is
an offensive attack platform or we have
USB devices phoning home which is a
paper about exploring how easily such a
device can then exfiltrate data home and
and a paper from IBM which is about
transparent defense against us be
eavesdropping attack they use a USB
armory for implementing protection but
one of the attacks that they do can also
be implemented with the USB armory
itself so in our job of exploring what
the device can do in our testing we
found a vulnerability was which was kind
of hyped because it applied to OS X and
iOS this is CVA 2016 17 34 any concerns
the emulation of a malicious ethernet
device it was found and investigated on
OS X but he also applies to I us because
the same driver code applies to both
platforms because there's a lot of code
reuse and this bug was interesting
because he worked on a locked session
without user intervention so you would
just be able to plug a device on a
locked 06 laptop and it would just
trigger the the issue and and what made
it interesting it was announced 24 hours
after the FBI confirmed the iphone
unlock which is very interesting and
also gives a lot of a lot of trouble and
a lot of inquiry speak because of it it
is we think it's likely unrelated but
you never know now there's one
interesting thing there was so much
journalistic pressure on understanding
if this bug was actually used in the FBI
case or not that a week after public
disclosure which is about four months
after initial reporting so there was a
lot of time to investigate this miss
fame but a week after public disclosure
because of the journal and very strong
journalistic pressures that was there in
inquiring whether this bug was used or
not in the FBI case apple decided to
downgrade the impact of the bug from
execute arbitrary code with Colonel
privileges to just a denial of service
and the reason why they did that is
because of the interpretation of the
panic logs that were that were sent out
so I think the impact on ground is
debatable but I'm going to leave that to
whoever wants to test this vulnerability
which is why now we're giving details
about it for the very first time so the
issue is that a high-speed USB device
advertising specific use
descriptors which match full speed
values so not high speed device but full
spin so we have a high speed device
which pretends to be a full speed
divisive and if it's not causes OS X to
panic and reboot about specific messages
which are sent by the device to the host
so this is fully controlled by the
device towards the host and this
corruption memory corruption is trigger
regardless of the user being logged in
or around and it is triggered by setting
first by setting the descriptors for the
USB end point to those values and then
to trigger a very specific payload from
the network so we narrow down a very
single a single ipv6 packet which can
trigger this panic when send from the
device to the host however this is just
a reproducer a reproducer of the bug
there are many other effects that
happens when this scenario takes place
and not always a panic has been it's
been trigger so we think that the panic
is being triggered only if we
specifically corrupt memory in a manner
which is then passes this specific
embeth check memory buffer check but in
other cases we will get other results
and sometimes we're going to not get a
panic report or not supporting the fact
that the memory corruption is more
extensive than that specific case when
OS X survives the attack if you sniff
the incoming network packets on the host
you will see that let's say that you
send a ping a continuous ping to the
device you will see that the palos for
more than one thing gets collected into
one giant packet meaning that we are
corrupting the memory buffers and
somehow the host believes that the
network packets are much larger what
they are and also I would like to point
out that memory buffer exploitation
we're rtv6 on bsd code is something that
happened in the past on openbsd so it's
a kind of interesting vulnerability and
you know I would I would I would give a
second thought on the impact here anyway
regardless of the impact this makes a
very good case for the efficiency of
using the USB armory in such such
testing because we have to be
to easily manipulate descriptors by just
by changing a few lines of of kernel
code and at the same time we can still
present a full valid driver to the host
which is exactly what happened here not
only we required to manipulate the USB
descriptors but we always had to have a
full-blown Ethernet USB driver working
which would allows us to send packets
from the device to the host and this is
something which is not easy to do with
other USB frameworks so five minutes
left for questions then there's lunch I
think we're doing very well with time
but first of all I would like to thank
you very much for your for your patience
and for your attention and if you have
any questions please raise your hand
thank
any questions yeah hi thanks for talk is
there a possibility to load the pgp key
in the secure Enclave so how do you
protect a key material right so there is
no persistence on the device other than
the diffuse secure boot keys and there's
a symmetric unique Kiefer sock which
cannot be read which is embedded in the
system on a chip the model for securing
user data is that you don't want to be
too tied on the hardware features for
doing that so you want to keep all of
this data on an encrypted partition
ideally or unencrypted few more and what
you do is that you need a combination of
two things you need to secure boot to
ensure that this specific device can
only run your code from the very
beginning and then you need if you want
encryption which is unattended
encryption okay you need to use a secret
which is store on the device if you want
to decrypt something with with a device
which is attended where you can input
data then you just care about secure
boot because at some point you will have
an encrypted partition and you can put
your credentials and you don't want
those credential to be stored on the
device itself if you want this to be
unattended let's say you have an IOT
device and you want to have the firmware
encrypted and you don't want local
attacks will be able to extract a
framework then you need to do secure
boot and then you need to read the
symmetric key from the sock itself so
not from an external memory which is
which is you know which is we where the
bus can be intercepted on on the PCB and
on this software two ways either you
fuse your key in the one-time fuses and
you make sure that your code does never
allow external debugging to access those
fuses or you use the symmetric key which
is in the system on a chip which nobody
knows I mean you can use it but you
cannot know it which means that when you
provision the device you need to use the
actual device that you're going to
deploy which could be seen as a feature
or it could be very inconvenient but
these are the two ways we've seen a lot
of embedded devices that they just have
an external component for doing that
they're like a crypto of indicator which
is external but the problem with that is
that you can always intercept the bus
want to secure that communication then
you need to use a secret which is in the
code and some people they do secure boot
but they do not encrypt the firmware and
then you can find the secret bear so
it's it's strictly interlock
intentionally doesn't leverage on this
it only leverage is on secure boot
because the use case is that you're
going to put your password anyway so we
don't want to waste time having secrets
which are not necessary thank you that's
very good question any other questions
no okay any time approached me if you
want and I can show you the device and
ask your questions in person thank you
oh thank you very much no just your
applause thanks thank you