good morning everyone thanks for thanks
for being here thanks Stefan and
everyone at area 41 for inviting me I'm
really excited to be here my name is my
name is Mark benziger I'm going to talk
a little bit about my bias going into
this because it affects what I'm hoping
to get out of it from you and bl so it
affects sort of the why I'm approaching
it from this so I come from and I from
an incident handling it is a response
background I was a pen tester and a more
traditional security operations guy
before that but for the last 10 years
I've really been focused on the belief
that it's the in the detect and respond
cycle that we we can have the greatest
effect and it's where most of my
interest has been I've been doing a lot
of sock design or exposed to sock design
i use the word sock with a question mark
because it's a stupid word and it's been
around for 10 years and we use it to
sort of interchangeably to talk about
organizations that worry about finding
and responding to evil on their network
and I'm really focused on the detection
response i'm not thinking about
vulnerability management or security
operations like firewall provisioning
i'm thinking about the tech can respond
and that's what this is focused on I
like agile solutions I want thing I I
definitely the idea of process over
people is important and it informs why I
did this because I feel like we we built
some really really Byzantine complex
solutions to solve problems and they
don't always work because of the
complexity that's my Twitter handle I
sadly I don't use it that much but
please feel free to ping me there or you
know I don't like said I don't do it
tweet much but maybe I'll try more I
hope that's my email address i work for
fire i obviously this talk is not
condone or sanctioned by them this is
just about my experiences both there and
it some previous companies so this this
talk isn't about products it's not about
tools that you use necessary like that
so as i'll get through you'll see that
i'm going to talk about tools several
times but it's more about process and
ideas the and so this is the last thing
it's been really intimidating to see the
quality of the talks I've seen here and
talking to many of you because there's
some really insanely smart people in
here
and their doings they have their part of
some pretty advanced programs to find
find evil and respond to it and so my
experience has been that the vast
majority of organizations do not have
multiple malware reverse engineers on
staff but some of you are part of
organizations that do that do have that
flexibility this is about this is for
the organization that doesn't have
multiple more reverse engineers on staff
they have one guy who's made is what
made it halfway through practical mall
learn analysis and keeps promising
himself he's going to go through the
whole thing and figure it out one of
these days where the sock team is 10
people and they don't have a lot of
depth or skill and they have very narrow
narrow abilities so what what led to
this talk I'm so tired of the phrase
threat intelligence and i'm going to use
the word cyber all over just because it
is the language that people at least
industry is speaking in they say cyber
threat intelligence or threat
intelligence interchangeably and I hate
the fray I hate the word it I don't know
it feels overloaded I'll talk a little
bit about my frustration with the word
intelligence for this but it is what it
is we have to we have to live with it a
lot of too many organizations are
spending a ton of money on these things
they're focusing on the the CEO they'll
pay a half million or a million dollars
a year for a threat Intel feed they'll
pay you know quarter million dollars for
a strategic intelligence service to
assess their business and give them
periodic reporting they'll build or buy
crits or big data tools and spend a lot
of money and maintaining and using them
tons of money is going into this and
it's not always having a lot of value
out in the field and so I say this is
someone who works for a company with a
threat Intel offering it's a useful
thing I mean and I've seen it help at
companies i'm not saying threatened
tells bad I'm just saying it's it's
underutilized and this is a little bit
of talk about maybe we don't need to
focus on the big the big adversary quite
as much but look a little bit in words
as well and it's and it's for all those
overwhelm sake analysts who don't know
where to start so some word some
thoughts about the word threat
intelligence or just intelligence in
general it's a horribly overloaded word
when I when I'm using it in this
presentation I'm not talking about
really really smart people I'm not
talking about nation states or scary
oligarchy is spying on us I'm not
talking about secret services trying or
or people spying on their own companies
I trying to come a better word and this
is this problem comes up frequently in
Germany I so I come I'm obviously an
American by the accent but I have been
in Germany for roughly the fast the past
four years and I come from Europe
European parents so I've I picked up
enough of the language to start spotting
like where the breakdowns happen and so
I was trying to think of a word that's
better to describe in German
intelligence and it's beautiful mouth
full of a German word alpha sins
familjen maybe that's it i don't know so
i tried summarizing in English roughly
what I mean how can I going to use data
efficiently to make the right decision
and the keywords are the right decision
and efficiently like how can we do this
quickly so please be patient with me I'm
you know almost five minutes in and i'm
still I'm still on the introduction so
I'm getting there I'm painting a picture
for a reason the there's no demo I'm
sorry I know this is my first talk at a
con and and I thought that the demo gods
would laugh at me if I even tried
spinning up a crits instance and a elk
instance and a ziam and tried linking
together on the stage it would be bad so
please maybe next time and so at the end
I'm going to ask some questions because
this is this is based on personal
experience and a couple of different
attempts in the field but I'm a data
point with I've got maybe ten different
socks I've been exposed to in the last
five years so if there's if others of
you have experienced that that conflicts
with this or supports this I'd love to
hear it afterwards or during the Q&A
session so still still in the background
we have is the word framework here
loosely frameworks aren't necessarily
framework can be a document it can be a
regulatory thing it can be an idea so
some of these things are not like the
others obviously some of them are
framework
for measuring things sums are I think
sums are organizational that enforce
things but they all end up creating or
all end up almost mandating some sort of
process for how how do we take in
something from detection to response and
and so I tried distilling like the
absolute minimalist beginning of that
detection response cycle where its most
most important you find something
probably as IAM rule most likely
unfortunately sometimes a phone call
from the FBI or from BSI or some other
organization then you take a look at it
and say how big how you know do i
understand this is it really an incident
how big is it is it scary do I have
enough information and then if it's big
and bad you analyze it maybe you do
something about it and if it's if it's
just if it's if it's a garden-variety
malware you say yeah reimage the Box
closed the ticket move on and if it's a
false positive you say hey our rules are
broken do something about it so there's
there's a group of intelligence
frameworks and methodologies again and
I'm clumping them all together because
some of these some of these are purely
technology solutions but they drive
towards ways of how we look at data and
so the ones i'm going to use i apologize
in advance for using the kill chain i
know you're tired of it everyone is but
it's still a really effective way to
model to model threats and and make and
in particularly look at targeted threats
where you're worried about the where you
can afford to worry about the
infrastructure or the capabilities to
the adversary i'm going to talk about
the diamond model so most of you
probably seen that as well it's a pretty
useful way to look at again attacker and
victim and I'm going to lock talk a
little about technology-based solutions
and so there's all of these it's been
great actually I think five years ago I
was I was I was dying for something that
allow me to keep track of all of the
thousands of indicators I was trying to
deal with and had no central way to say
yes this showed up on this threat feed
this day and went away on that day and
this IP address belongs to this threat
group but not that threat group and oh
by the way it's the all of those little
pieces of information there's tools now
to manage that and I'm
and they're very good at drawing links
between different pieces of discrete
pieces of data the ones I'm so lots of
link diagrams crits an avalanche are the
ones that throw out there but there's
like three other ones and and those are
the two ones i'm most familiar with so
that's the ones i'll refer to and then
there's a big data based approaches
where people has to or ridiculous truly
ridiculous amounts of data to and try
and build analytics to find things and
and I'm kind of amazed sometimes by the
the size of some of these efforts
there's been a few one company he was in
the US about six years ago they had
three years of you know for 100 for a
hundred thousand people all their net
flow all their email headers all their
dns all their HTTP GET get requests
everett you know every all the proxy
logs and they maintain them for three
years and they were committed to me
caning indefinitely and just keep
building that because they treat it as a
giant data analytics problem to find
badness and of course the last which is
white papers things to help you make
decisions where someone else takes all
of these different things and and
distills it down to something that
actually people can make a decision on
so kill chain really really simple the
idea that there's lots of steps in an
intrusion and that it's it's not about
and this is the most common common
misconception it's not about defense in
depth it's not about being able to break
it early on the kill chain it's a way
for modeling how the adversary is
dependent on infrastructure to attack
you every step here you can find things
about about their their method of attack
whether it's a specific you know some
metadata from a document and IP address
a mutex from these different phases of
the attack and every single one of those
pieces represents a piece of work that
the attacker had to take to build
something he had to you had to go ahead
and own someone's box and confirm it was
a safe place to put a c2 controller he
had to do the research for some sort of
exploit and ensure that no one else was
using it and that it was that that was
likely to get past whatever it was every
little piece of this represents someone
someone some piece of work so by by
treating it as discrete columns of
information you can
art drawing connections because
replacing any of these chunks takes work
for the attacker so they're they're not
inclined to replace pieces so if you can
find ways to draw connections you can
draw conclusions about the attacker so
you have your first alert and the reason
I'm going through this is because I'm
going to use this data and some of the
later presentations I know you most of
you know this you have something your
email e-mail fires on a system says hey
I stopped something that was bad that's
it that's all you got some summer
memory-based exploit and so you do the
research and say oh it looks like an
email came in and he clicked on this
Excel document and and there's something
in it that maybe was bad and actually
this is a this is a poor example I mixed
in when I was drawing this i mixed two
two alerts obviously an excel macro
based exploits probably not going to
give you an email log but bear with
maybe ideas that there's some connection
between the two and you and you have no
idea how they how the recons tied to it
you you know you can't guess about web
blogs or something that that might have
been connected to that in the beginning
and so then you do a little research and
you reverse engineer the actual mahler
and say okay if this thing actually ran
its you know or maybe put in a sandbox
probably not reverse engineering at this
point figure out you know oh it's going
to leave this registry entry and you
have this service and it'll connect to
these things and I can build a signature
on it so you build a a picture of it in
this entire each chunk here represents
some part of the adversaries
infrastructure so then you start doing
you start building up a long picture of
a different attacks and you start
getting you know you say hey I triggered
on this signature here i found an IP in
a URL and then I walked back couldn't
figure out the exploit because I don't
actually keep track of my I don't have
full packet capture so I have no idea it
was actually in that but I found a
little bit of information from this may
be a different flash attack here I found
something in the registry perhaps and
based on some other signature and so you
start building this picture of different
chunks of adversary activity and then
the day comes when you when you spot the
link when you say hey this IP address
here that you know that looks like the
forwarding you know some IP address that
was forwarded from happens to be the
same that was an exfil IP use
a year later or six months later and
sometimes they're completely unrelated
but sometimes you start drawing the tie
because as I said attackers are cheap if
they don't have to read their cheap and
lazy if they don't have to rebuild
infrastructure or rebuild code they
won't so we get here and n we and we
dumped it into crits or something else
and we model it and say look these this
two IPS it'll actually show up as one IP
but I've left him with both colors to
represent hey there's two different
discrete events and they're tied to
these different things there's some sort
of linkage between all of these
different things that tells us hey
there's there's a chance the next time I
look at you know I spot this thing that
maybe it's tied to these and we use
these beautiful link diagrams and these
big repositories of historical
information to find where what the tie
is does something happened previously
another way of looking at this is the
diamond model and so this is and I've
saved if there's any one piece of
information that informs talk most was
thinking about the diamond model and how
how we r we don't seem to focus on that
part of it very much and so this is a
work of Sergio caltagirone and
Christopher bets and Andrew Pendergrast
and it's it's really helped me a lot
it's really some great mechanism it
basically says that every piece of it to
every attacker every attack has these
four things associated with it that you
can't avoid the fact that somehow
there's there's a tie between all of
those things and so you can look at that
sort of the technology access the idea
of the infrastructure hey they have to
own boxes in order to upload things they
have to have to have something that can
write the craft their emails and send
their emails and they have some
capability they have some ability to to
write code right exploits embed exploits
package them in some way and send them
to you and send them to you so all of
these pieces are associated with the
capability piece and then we have this
access now in the in the paint in the
original paper it was described as
socio-political and it's I like and they
also refer to as motivation i prefer
looking at that way like what is the
motivation why
is this happening to me and and you can
you can make some conclusions here about
the adversary you can say hey this this
guy seems to reconstitute ip's when we
block them really fast and his locale
you know there's little hints of locale
information linguistically or time zone
or something that's embedded in some of
the documents hey this is really good
this is really good coat you know I
wasn't able to figure out anything all
of the headers are obscured and was
really tough and it seemed to be sandbox
aware and you can guess maybe there's
there's a pattern you know all of the
attacks come in UTC plus a tour plus 10
or whatever it is that makes you go okay
maybe that thing that's tied to
something so you draw some conclusions
about the attacker and hopefully that
lets you tell you something about
motivation but if you don't know about
the victim you don't necessarily know
what the motivation is like what is that
so with all of these tools why do socks
have trouble because they do they're
horribly overloaded part of it is
because we we all like the puzzle we
love the art of having to figure out why
this small where came in this time and
how it exploited why we didn't see it
and all of those doesn't puzzle pieces
so Josh on the in the keynote speech
talked about motivation the motivations
of hackers or white hats and the puzzler
and so a lot of us I think most of us
have that to a certain extent it like
focusing on the internal stuff is boring
it really is you want to focus on the
third post on the outside we're unsure
of how to prioritize there is every
every sock design have been a part of
the hardest part is getting someone to
commit to know what's really important
to you what do you want me to focus on
and and we don't have rules that help
analysts do that it just doesn't make
sense to many of the analysts it doesn't
make sense and I a part of it is work
we're our own worst enemies sock
managers are part of the problem
sometimes because they're so scared of
getting of missing something that they
can't decide that there's a priority I
literally had a sock director of a
hundred and forty thousand person
organization worldwide tell me that that
when I was trying to force the
discussion of
of of priorities that every piece of
malware and would be treated equally no
matter where it ran or for who we had to
treat them all equally we had to all
investigate them and and deal with them
and clean them up equally we would not
treat people differently would not treat
malware differently period and you can
imagine what the at you know we all sort
of went okay we'll try that you can
imagine what the the sock you looked
like after the first month and after the
third month because of that it's really
if you can't if you can't prioritize you
can't drop things we struggle with
indicator over lowered the first the
first time we buy one of our
half-million-dollar indicator feeds and
turn it on and you get 50,000 things to
worry about per week it's really hard to
figure out what to do with that we don't
know when to give up when you have an
incident that you're trying to track and
and you're not able to make a decision
because you don't have the right
information sometimes it's better just
to say I accept this I'm reimaging and
moving on even though I think it smells
horrible and it could be something big
because you don't have time we don't
have we don't have exit criteria for
analysts and we spend a lot of time
getting to root cause I know it's
necessary you got to figure out why you
got at you why you got hacked so you can
build better prevention mechanisms and
better detection mechanisms so and kill
chain analysis helps you with root cause
a lot too but sometimes you spent way
too much time on it it's better just to
not did not do it and of course the last
piece is they don't understand their
internal network every sock I've been a
part of the ratio has been roughly on
the order you know of anywhere between
one to ten thousand internal devices
maybe at best one to four smaller Sox 1
to 1,000 internal devices but the bigger
socks are always going to be maybe 125
thousand one to ten thousand internal
devices so you'll have a sock covering
250 thousand users worldwide and in
literally nine thousand individual
business units within that and they'll
have 30 people trying to manage it
there's no way they can know about the
different parts of the organization so I
know it sounds like I'm admiring the
problem i'm not i'm just trying to to
talk about what the limitations are
all of the all of these actually go back
to store a second all of all of these
have something in common which is that
we we have too much too there's there's
a we're overlooked we're overwhelmed
with the amount of choices we have to
make and we're trying to narrow these
things down so some initial steps to
start including targeting information
into your sock processes are pretty
straightforward and some of you I'd have
to say probably most socks do a couple
of these things already and it but
sometimes not sometimes it's accidental
sometimes it's deliberate build into
your process the idea that you have to
collect information about target
identity and not just not just during
the incident but in perpetuity the idea
of keeping all of your DHCP logs forever
and all of your ad and every ad group
change forever and all of the all of
your VPN you know external users VPN in
ever forever is it seems like an
expensive pain in the ass but compared
to maintaining net flow and external
browsing logs it's actually not that bad
it's actually it's often less data and
this this is the data that starts giving
you your allowing you to make decisions
about internal context so you have to
commit to gathering data about your
internal environment so there's some
really simple approaches that are just
that you can most most socks do early on
anyhow because it helps them use use
these existing repositories of data this
is just existing systems of record and
and get them into your device integrate
it into alerting at the simplest you
know if you just have a list of
directors and above and didn't Bend
domain admins and unix admins and make
sure you get put a little flag next to
the mountain your ziam your step ahead
of the rest that's at the very basic
this is this is the one that's that's
really troubling to a lot of people I
think which is the idea of knowing your
knowing who your internal targets aren't
advanced I say targets there it sounds
external I'm saying about us about that
you you the defender there's two really
radically different perspectives here
the what the outsider sees of you and
what you know about yourself and you
have to treat
differently because the depending on who
the adversary is they may really not
have any good idea of internal they
might not have internal knowledge yet
and so they are going to have a very
similar view of you to what a pen test
would have you so when you have a pen
test done you should make sure that
statement of work includes the idea that
all of the recon ng and multi go
information and perspective of what do I
look like from the outside is part of
the deliverable to the sock into the
sock database whatever that is because
that's the data that lets you say hey
the outside world thinks I'm exposed
here so all of the the the pen testers
view of you needs to be part of the sock
data set it shouldn't be part of the
extent be part of the pen testing group
or the compliance group I mean it's both
but you need to use it and then there's
also the internal knowledge perspective
from the outside that looks like your
R&D group is in Detroit Michigan and in
the reality is all the folks doing
through the really interesting
scientific work and doing all the
engineering is in Indonesia but from the
perspective of the papers that are
written and the the descriptions on your
website it's all Detroit so it may make
more sense to focus on the Detroit it
may make sense to focus on the Detroit
target as the place to maybe look a
little closer the route is though as as
an adversary gets to know you better
they're going to know soon enough that
actually all of the cool IP that they
want to steal is actually living on some
engineers desktop in Indonesia it's not
living in the research scientists desk
in Detroit and the last is is obviously
changes the instant healing process like
that's the fundamental part of this is
that you can't do this unless you change
the decisions you make along the way for
each incident so I had my my simplified
version of an incident response process
there and and so that this I talked a
little bit about that in that detect
phase the simplest thing you can do is
making sure you're incorporating target
information into whatever your alerting
mechanism is it's a probably going to be
a rule in as IAM but it might be
something else
right here if you can change how you
prioritize events based on target
information you'll make your life so
much easier when you have a hundred
events that come in within an hour every
hour and you only have enough analysts
to do 50 if you if all else is equal
choose something to prioritize it and
and if you're going to have to drop 50
drop 50 that aren't on the target list
it's a lot easier that way it gives you
a tool to shed work and focus which as
an analyst at krave I crave the ability
to know hey I need to focus on this I
cannot worry about that during your
analysis phase you need to be analyzing
the target as well as all of them all
where an exploit stuff and and more
importantly that the data about that
analysis it can't be lost it has to be
part of your big data solution that
you're using to record all your
beautiful DNS HTTP Netflix or whatever
it is when you make a note saying oh
this guy's actually a research scientist
you know whatever his name is in
Indonesia or in Detroit that that data
needs to go in into your permanent data
storage so that next time an incident
comes up it's flagged somewhere that
there's when you do that little
beautiful link analysis someone says hey
fred was targeted by this attack two
years ago and here's the notes we had on
it or even better this organizational
unit is you know we've had multiple
other incidents in this organizational
unit and here's the notes about that you
need you need to basically include that
in your analytic storage and that's
actually perhaps more hear about the
feedback here the idea of the feedback
loop that all of that data that you're
getting for for your target makes it
back into whatever magic threat Intel
system you're using to make decisions
about how we analyze the adversary so
all the difference is that all of a
sudden when you look at your at your
crew instance or whatever there's all of
a sudden something that says hey there's
something else in common between these
two IP addresses or this single IP
address and these people perhaps they
they're both part of the same business
unit maybe it's you know cuz sometimes
same IP might be a different person
penny you know if it's a shared if it's
a lab pc for example and being able to
say hey these are these are
people or working in the same
organization that tells you something
and then there's the other pieces all of
a sudden you get added you know the
who's the actual user specific beatsie
and other things so tying in those
pieces of of target information in your
incident handling process and database
it make allows you to narrow down what
you're having to look at and allows you
to make decisions about that that
motivation path right here so the idea
is here all of a sudden we have this
other information about the specific
business unit or PC or user that was
associated with these pair of attacks
and for the first time we maybe have a
chance at drawing a conclusion about
motivation and the value and
understanding the motivation is that it
finally gives it both it sheds a little
bit of light potentially on this you
know it's it's a bit of a risky it's a
risky thing because you're using the
business unit to draw conclusions about
up here but sometimes sometimes
sometimes that's valid and and then that
then can inform more effectively the the
sorts of decisions you make going
forward hey I'm going to really bump up
the alerting on these three business
units because that really seems to be
the primary motivation of this adversary
that's been targeting us every summer so
the advanced options are fairly are
probably not going to be too surprising
to all of you which is basically
actively analyzing your internal groups
treat your internal network as an
intelligence problem hey I'm noticing a
pattern of increasing 00 day activity
over here I'm going to draw some
conclusions about my internal network
i'm going to say these guys over here
are less secure treat those and those
pieces and analytic deductive insight
put it back into whatever system you're
using to analyze events because you
don't your company's too big to
understand you'll never understand it
you have to draw those little bits of
analytic conclusion back into the
instant handling process think about on
the tech centric approaches and those
are what those are the link diagram
tools I was talking about make sure you
put in the not just the you know the
business organizations but talk a little
bit about the
talk a little bit about perhaps there
there are even internal groupings so
like use group information to to create
some of those links and so the risk here
is that when you do this it can get
pretty you can get pretty fuzzy fast and
it's not something that's necessarily
yields immediate results but in the long
term it helps you draw that picture hey
these are shared business units you have
to include the internal units some some
groups do a good job of that but it
seems a little foreign to use the
threatened tool tool to track your
internal data spaces this is kind of
controversial this works more in the in
a highly regulated non privacy conscious
country the idea of tracking a internal
users connections as a way as part of
those connection diagrams because I
don't know how many of you have jive or
some other similar social networking
tool that's internally built and you
build connections side of company I
think most companies of a like a
thousand or more start having those
sorts of things mine your internal
network for those connections between
people because if they're not be able to
find things or an active directory but
you may find it in the social
connections and this of course is the
fundamental thing all of that data don't
don't don't necessarily treat the
attacker data separate from the target
data now you have to tag it you have to
make it closer you don't get yourself
confused that your think one's an attack
and ones that and target but the idea is
that they should be part of a common
data set that you can query and pivot on
together that you can make a query for
something that includes both of some
sort of selection based on target and
some sorts of selection based on victim
so this is the this is the feed but when
you've tried doing this when you tried
pushing socks in this direction and
again these these are basic like the
these are these are socks that were just
sort of nascent and we're trying to give
them the tools to do this it's amazing
how comfortable people were with
ambiguity on about about attacker
information well we know the CHC to IP
might be bad or might not be we can
accept that we're going to treat it 5050
it's bad
they're people are incredibly confident
about or comfortable dealing with
ambiguity outside the organization but
they resist accepting it internally I
had like knock-down drag-out arguments
with a with a sock architect about
including their cmdb data in there as
part of the filter you know add context
to alerts in their ziam because you said
well it's out of date I'm like yeah I
know it's out of date you know is it is
a hundred percent on a date is
everything inaccurate yeah clearly don't
use it but is it fifty percent out of
date ten percent help me understand and
the reality is it wasn't that out of
date you know there's there's like
twenty percent of the internal network
that wasn't covered maybe twenty percent
of it was wrong but he couldn't he could
not stomach the idea of using known
flawed data in his model in his modeling
of priority internally and I think maybe
a cultural thing too I definitely have
found more resistant to more resistance
to using known flawed sources using
allowing ambiguity in Germany they want
yes or no they want a clear criteria to
make a decision least that was my
perception with with the companies there
that wasn't always there in the Middle
East there's a little bit more comfort
with the idea of ambiguity saying yeah
we can get a little bit boost of our
ability to make decisions that's good
enough even if it's not perfect this is
this is that sock that sock manager who
demanded that we treat all malware
equally and his fundamental there's two
things driving and one was
egalitarianism we can't treat VIPs and
administrators different from internal
users and the second was they could
attack anywhere and we can't assume that
just because it's on a high value system
it's you know or a high value person or
or not that one is more important than
the other and that's absolutely true you
know that the first point of entry may
just may be a random person and then
they move laterally which is good
argument for making sure you have
instrumentation deeper in your network
so you can pick up the lateral movement
because the target of lateral movement
is also a target and so if you do have
the triggers on those high-value targets
when you see it see their name pop up in
something that is a you know a SMB share
some
or an attempt to move to new system or a
specific use of a password when that
happens if you happen to have
instrumentation deep in your network
you'll pick up that new connection that
that hey this is one of my high-value
targets and something bad happened you
may not care about weird weird SMB
traffic for regular users but these
eight scientists you'll actually take a
little look at whatever it is this is a
some people say well why would we want
to include our old cmdb data in our old
CMD data in the database I don't I don't
get it why don't we just wipe it clean
every time we get updates and so the
temptation is again we crave the
knowledge about our internal systems why
would I want to include old active
directory information because a being
able to do retrospective analysis is
pretty fundamental to figuring out why
something happened I can't tell you how
many alerts where we found something bad
we found a found a new piece of malware
and a new see to Hydra IP address and
then we go back and say oh wow these
four systems over here a beacon to their
six months ago and if you don't know
what things looked like at that point
it's harder to draw a conclusion so
don't throw away your old data just make
sure you tag it hey actor directly
looked like this on this date and look
like this on that date and this so this
is the last one this is one I struggle
with the most is because no particularly
in the works council centric you privacy
rules regulations German datenschutz
pressures all of those things drive a
good desire to protect the internal
people within a company and so this
looks an awful lot like you're targeting
your internal users and that you're
trying to do something to them not for
them and so if there's a way that you
can if there's a way that you can reduce
that reduce you know reduce that you may
have to make compromises on it this this
is honestly the one I struggle with the
most on a few a few occasions we haven't
been able to do target centric tracking
because of this and in some cases
we had a works council that was really
willing to have that discussion and
willing to allow us to do a little bit
more once they understood and understood
that it was fully auditable and
reviewable by them as well as us so I
probably finished too early with
apologies which is good because I would
love feedback and so so my questions to
you that I would really appreciate you
being able to talk to me about it did
this help you at all do you do any of
you shared a perception of these gaps
like do you have you seen similar
problems in your own organizations have
you seen people using some of these
techniques in your environments because
I have a limited data set I've seen you
know like said maybe 10 or 20 Sox where
I've seen it haven't seen too many
papers about using internal threat
intelligence tools I mean look external
threat intelligent tools internally but
I suspect that there's probably someone
who's doing similar things already what
other problems do you see that I'm
missing here because i'm sure the these
are the problems i saw i didn't have a
long list is that the resistance usually
wasn't too high because it's an it's an
easy step to take and what would if
there was a follow-on work to this what
should it be should it be practical
demonstrations of the actual ties
between crits plus 0 m + + elk what does
that look like how those three tools
work together if there's a if you're if
you're doing a internally eternally
focused detection mechanisms i don't
know i need please please tell me and
again you can contact me here business
cards i'm happy to happy to chat about
this any time and again thank you very
much i appreciate it i'm open for
questions also please
so did it help yes do you I share you a
perception right I mean I'm having a
hard time hearing you let's get a little
bit louder I share your perception what
are other problems you see I see the
problem use you mentioned we are doing
penetration tests and we have no
standard where you can automatically dig
into the results of the penetration test
for a third for example so we can export
it to a third and they can somehow
consider it yeah so there is a standard
missing which is above all technologies
vendor-independent where any penetration
tester can put its results into a
database I think I think that's true i
think i would i would i think i would
start maybe if I had to guess would be
would say that both recon ng and multi
go do a pretty good job of giving
formatted output if you want that and
that's just a piece of the attacker
perspective admittedly it's just a small
chunk but it but it's it's good at if
you can figure out it can consume both
of you both of those and literally recon
ng can be just a list of email addresses
and a list of domain names as much as
anything else and so you can it doesn't
necessarily have to be a lot of work to
import that but so but i but i hear your
point there is no standard way of doing
it you have to take a shortcut and do it
because from my experience there is the
results of any penetration tests are in
a doc document and there's simply not
possible so it needs something like an
xml HTML output you can import you can
parse i agree that's why i was one of
the things i mentioned is that you have
to push for like a lot of a lot of pen
testing groups will be willing to give
you working papers and presumably they
have as part of it those recon ng
results or something else in some some
form of output so hopefully that that
can do it but that that's that has a lot
to do with a company's relationship with
a pen testing team and that the signed
agreement the willingness to give up
data the raw data
thanks for the great talk I see that a
lot of this introspection would rely on
logging essentially but new attack
methods move to towards in-memory
attacks which are quite difficult to log
and forensically analyzed and I wonder
if you have some comments on those
developments like PowerShell so I think
that I agree it's getting tougher to
pick up indicators on the endpoints in
particular because the NMM reissue the
fact that folks are willing to give up
persistence because they know they have
a good drive by download that they'll
get they'll get a the pop a new shell
and the next week if they just wait or
VD is are forcing people to just accept
the fact that persistence is useless I I
come long ago from the network
background so ultimately if you can't if
you can't find it on the endpoint easily
you have to go back to the network and a
lot of our indicators are network
centric and and the network centricity
of indicators works also for further the
victims like the victims are often they
have there's characters network-based
characteristics of the victims IP
addresses where they're located you know
system is tied to a person for a given
time period so you can if you if you're
forced away from the endpoint log data
you have to rely on the ties of the
network indicators and then it's then
you end up with a harder problem though
you're absolutely right about it
anything else there are several
companies now shifting into the silk as
a service business and recapping your
talk you're basically telling me they
are totally inefficient oh god no i'm
hopefully i'm not i'm not saying that
because that's that's because i work for
a company that sells managed security
service and and i'm actually on the team
that does that so one of the things
about and this isn't a sales pitch for
fire I because that we have flaws just
like any other any other company one of
the things I loved about fire I is the
fact that they've built such a good such
good model
of the attackers that they can afford to
give up little knowledge on the target
and so but but with that said the
there's lots of ms it's SPS that that
aggressively seek and incorporate
customer data that say hey give me I
know you know hey it's January could you
give me your active directory listing
and your and your you know and your cmdb
and XXX and they can also track like
track the historical patterns of
compromise well again this isn't just
about knowing being able to know it's
being about being able to analyze so for
example there was a MSSP not fire I that
had a really great really great sock
workflow engine that anytime they you
know an internal IP came up in there and
they're in there they're highly
customized version of RT you could get a
nice mouse over and it would show you
that you know context about that I key
or network based on previous incidents
hey this looks like this is their
internal their turn Adele you this is
their data of their data VLAN or this is
their their their web their web app VLAN
or something so that like the idea that
Eva's nemesis p I can also build context
about the customer without the customer
telling me anything Jase based on the
pattern of log events and historical
analysis so I agree with you that as a
nemesis p you have a challenge in that
you are one step away from the customer
but a lot of these things are not
dependent on actually having access to
the customer it's about having access to
the data feeds and as a nemesis p you
probably have those anyway anybody is
thank you very much really appreciate it