medications and control flow guard so
you can expect something about code
reuse text and give you a quick
refresher then I will talk about in its
growth educational techniques and
there's a third bullet point talk about
Microsoft control Hobart the compiler
feature my name is Monty estas I'm CTO
and co-founder oh it's for lab we were
late espino rebuilding a software
product detect fire based software
exploits you probably heard of this
year's a pond to own competition it
happened in march this year and all of
the most current browsers namely chrome
edge safari and with most current
security mitigations have been owned and
system or root privilege has been
achieved so attackers could execute
arbitrary code as an attacker you do
some before you do the attacking you do
some basic math according to Microsoft
you your attacker return so the money
you actually get you calculate it by by
the gains peruse so how much money can
you steal with an attack times the
number of thefts but of course you have
some costs so you have initial costs to
acquire maybe a vulnerability so either
you do some may be fuzzy or you do
static or dynamic analysis of your
software you want to exploit and of
course you need to subtract the cost of
weaponizing the vulnerability then this
is exactly the point where v as the
defenders try to to raise the cost of an
attack so such mitigations to raise
costs it's a as already mentioned is a
ms rope mitigations which are runtime
mitigation
make mitigations so you deploy these
mitigations into arbitrary windows
processes and the second mitigation is
control flow guard this is a
compile-time mitigation which is
compiled into your program and then
checked at runtime this requires some
more or less recent Windows versions but
before we start I give you a quick
refresher on the data execution
prevention and address space layout
randomization and how an attacker can
bypass this so quick refresher so data
execution prevention what is it this is
a you mark areas of your virtual memory
you give it permission flags so
typically you have a your code section
in your virtual memory is typically
readable and executable your hip and
stack is typically readable rideable
sono so attackers who place code like on
the stack like this has been done some
time ago this doesn't work when you have
data execution prevention enabled but
instead of placing code on a stack you
do where so-called code reuse attacks so
there is various techniques you can do
return to leap attacks or the more
generic form of this is a return
oriented programming I will get to this
and a similar form but a form which
doesn't rely return instructions is a
jump or call oriented programming and
the basic idea is to use like existing
code until you can as an attacker until
you can make a call to some functions
like memory functions which change the
protection flags of your memory so
typically your do you do return oriented
programming until you find a call to
maybe virtual protect and then you can
mark any piece of memory you want
executable
so return oriented programming how does
it work you have a so-called Rope
catches these are arbitrary sequences of
instructions which end with a return
instructions so for instance these three
guys and return oriented programming
just puts the start addresses of these
gadgets to a memory locations and like
an attacker can craft like a puzzle
craft its own functionality by using
already loaded code so how does a SLR
work how to bypass our seller so address
space layout randomization this is where
we randomly place stuff at different
locations so by passing it you may think
of if there is a weak implementation of
ISIL are you can just try to brute-force
it or you try to construct construct a
memory leak leak some addresses of some
useful functions or depending on the
application you want to attack you can
force the application into some
predictable memory state by for instance
applying memory pressure and other
techniques is it's like pointer in
feirense or you can try to not use the
randomized parts of your addresses in
your gadgets so this would be you avoid
using exact addresses and these both
techniques data execution prevention and
address space layout randomization
station these are rather generic defense
techniques and are widely adopted in x86
world so this is exploit exploit riding
has become harder through these
techniques for like most classes of
attacks and together if implemented
right the this is quite an effective
defense mechanism but as we've seen in
the pond to own slider it's not
effective enough so how how do we
measure the security of an egg exploit
mitigation or how much of how much do we
increase the cost of an attack when we
enable specific security features so
quantifying this stuff is is rather
difficult and academia as well seems to
somehow struggle with this question for
this talk we tried a different more
practical approach we constructed a
program an exploitable program and try
it out how hard it gets when we enable
specific security features like emit
rope mitigations or control flow guard
so we hope to understand these
mitigations better so let's start with
code reuse attacks first the example we
created a an example program we call it
mainframe inventory this is a vulnerable
C++ program it's exploitable by design
but still as an attacker you need still
need to bypass address space layout
randomization and data execution
prevention so we created this mainframe
inventory program as a 64-bit program we
compiled it with with visual studio try
to the 2015 on Windows 10 and what it
basically does we keep a link linked
list of of programs of arbitrary object
and maintain this list and expose a HTTP
interface to clients so this HTTP
interface with this you can do you can
create new programs or list them or
start programs so for instance this HTTP
request would create a new program with
some specific ID
so this is how the the program class
looks like so we have a few attributes
like status ID the length of ID
indicates the number of bytes which are
rallied in this idea ray then we have a
pointer to a state buffer and again a
state size which indicates this number
of valid bytes in state buffer and the
pointer to the next enter in our linked
list and of course we have some fancy
method which is by by accident virtual
in-memory this looks like this we have a
the the object p 1 we have a pointer to
the v table of the program and then the
attributes follow so an example request
like this would this would create a new
program object with a good creedon
approaching program object with some
specific ID and some specific state we
can define as a client so in memory this
looks like this we have the attributes
here we have a pointer to the v table of
program what an importance i know this v
table is located in the read-only data
section of the executable and here the
first entry of the v table is the
program's main method so we have some
pointer to state buffer so there is some
some more data which we can control as a
client so but you already think this may
look fishy so why the heck can we set
the ID length so the programmer forget
to forgot to check ID length so as an
attacker we can we have control over the
length of this ID field which is which
indicates a number of bytes in your ID
buffer which has a fixed size of eight
in this example
so if if an attacker provides an ideal
length bigger than eight we can read and
write after this ID memory section so
what do we get out of this we can leak
memory we can construct an arbitrary
read we can deliver some payload week
and eventually we can hijack control
flow so how do we do this how do we leak
the memory so we could set ID length to
32 so this would allow us to read and
write the read stuff which is indicated
in blue writing stuff would do the other
thing so arbitrary an arbiter read would
to have an arbitrary read we would set
ID length to 24 assign the number of
bytes we want to read assign it to
straight size and the point driven to
read we will design two state buffer and
reading the state would then like read
our desired memory address delivering
payload also is easy we just used this
state buffer to deliver arbitrary
payload and we can use the memory leak
to read the address of the state buffer
so how do we do the control flow
hijacking we use if we could create a
fake object which would look like this
we could give it a fake V table and the
first V table entry would point to our
escape location so let's try to
construct this fake fake object we have
a a same object p one in the state
buffer we place our fake vtable we
create another buffer with our fake
object which not now knows the address
to the v table we previously leaked so
we have constructed the fake object when
we update the next pointer we can
successfully insert the this new fake
object into the list of programs objects
so hijacking control flow is just
calling the virtual method of this fake
object so this would then be some auto
type a request in this example so but
still we need to bypass data execution
prevention and address space layout
randomization this needs the following
steps at first we need to leak some base
addresses of some libraries we want to
use code from we need to deliver our
shellcode we need to level the rope
chain we need two hijacked control flow
to our first rope gadget do some stack
pivoting and then our rope chain will
call virtual pro txt and marks the
payload executable and then we can
return to our shellcode so how do we
leak the base addresses of our libraries
so if you have two objects next pointer
points to the next object which at the
offset 0 has the V table so we just
follow this V table pointer and we will
find the address of the main function in
the executable since we know the
executable we can calculate the offset
we know the offset of this main function
in the executable because this is static
we can derive the randomized we can
derive the randomized base address and
this gives us the image base address
with this base address we we can read
the import address table of the dis
executable and in our example we have
like imports as we use functions this
executable users functions from in this
example kernel32 and some CPP rest
library so we can leak more addresses so
with this we can say address space
layout randomization is bypassed exploit
delivery is in an example example quite
easy we just use this state buffer and
lick the address of the state
offer for this inventory example we
created the shellcode with metasploit we
use a Windows xik shellcode with which
pops a conch yeah so this is standard
generated code then the rope chain is
also pretty straightforward we do some
we use some basic gadgets to prepare our
arguments like this prepares argument 0
argument 1 etc here you for instance you
see the third argument to virtual
protect and eventually we call virtual
protect and return to the shellcode so
how do we actually then hijack control
flow you have the this is the call site
which we want to hijack so if you look
closely this is the these points then to
our fake object the fake object the
pointer is dereferenced and now Rex
points to the V table and eventually we
call the first entry in the V table and
so controls all gets hijacked our first
target after hijacking is a so-called
stack pivoting gadget we try to get
control over the stack pointer so the
first gadget looks like this when you
remain as you remember from the previous
slide racks contained the V table
address so this would load the second
entry of your retail and put it into the
stack pointer so if we put our the
address of our rope chain into the
second entry of our fake v table we can
like we can people the stack pointer to
our rope chain so this will happen so
the exploitation in pictures we have a
normal cold normal stack we deliver the
shellcode
the heap this is non executable code
then we deliver the rope chain also
non-executable then we hijack control
flow p vote the stack to point to the
rope chain the rope chain gets executed
and eventually we end up in a virtual
protect call which marks the code the
shellcode executable and then execute
our shellcode so data execution
prevention is also bypassed this is some
screenshot of our demo program we could
pop cog so next next topic let's enable
let's enable Rob mitigations for our
exploit so what is what is Emmett before
we start like Emmett was introduced in
2009 and the most current version is a
5.5 and then was released the end of
January this year so Emmett implements
various security related features and
hardening techniques which you can apply
to arbitrary processes on your Windows
desktop machine but for this top we will
focus only on Rob related mitigations
this is the m8 config we if you don't
know it so you can you can configure
processes processes to be guarded and
you can enable specific security checks
for your processes so we wrote
mitigations are these stuff in the boxes
we will focus on this the rock
mitigations were introduced it
introduced to through Rob card rock
guard was the Microsoft blue hat one
microsoft blue hat price and this Rob
card was integrated into Emmett firstly
integrated to Emmett 3.5 if you know
Amit there is some rope mitigations
which are only available for 32-bit so
so
of the Rope mitigations namely the
caller checks and simulated execution
flow is not available for 64-bit but
before we continue how does omit the
hooking so Emmett inject a dll into
every process you want to have secured
so it injects a dll and then hooks into
sensitive api calls so this sensitive
api calls our virtual protec load
library createprocess etc there are
about I think 50 functions which are
protected by a mint so if we talk about
Rob mitigations there is rather a rope
detection than rope prevention because
the Rope checks are only done when you
call these critical API functions so how
does an m8 look look like if you call
for instance virtual protect and you if
you follow the debugger you will notice
a weird jump at this symbol so this is a
ma took this jumps to some dynamically
generated code if you do some more
debugging you will see that the m8 code
eventually jumps back to the code you
wanna have called and this next location
has another m8 hook and there is like on
every level of API call there is this
Emma talk even for the right before the
system call so even system calls are
guarded by Amit so this is a mhd poking
and it prevents an attacker from just
skipping over some hook and like call
the next lower function this should
prevent this so these Rob mitigations
let's start with the first mitigation
term memory protection mitigation this
is fairly easy you just MHS this allows
the program for marking the thread stack
executable
so placing your shellcode on a stack and
market executable will not work anymore
and the next mitigation color checks
during an ongoing a rope attack
functions are not called but they're
rather returned in two so Emmett checks
the call site if there is actually a
call instruction so when Emma does the
check it checks the stack pointer like
it checks the top of stack reads the
return address follows the return
address and checks the previous function
whether this is a a valid call to the
hooked function so it checks is this
really virtual protect call then the
next step mitigation is a simulated
execution flow and according to
documentation this should detect a rope
gadget following a call to a protected
API so this we're not hundred percent
sure what it really does but it seems to
simulate instructions affecting the
stack and the base pointer and does some
sanity checks on them so next mitigation
is tag pivoting m8 just checks if the
stack pointer is within the bounds of
the stack which is a of the expected
stack so ma detects any deviation like
stack pivoting attack attempts the next
mitigation is a export address table
access filtering this is not really an n
rob mitigation but it makes lot a lot of
off-the-shelf code like metasploit the
exploits makes a it prevents them
because are the export address table
access fielding it checks read accesses
to
the export address table of the three
critical system libraries so it checks
access to kernel32 and the dlm colonel
base so whenever someone wants to read a
few bites of this export address table
of the three functions it ma triggers so
Emma tosses by inserting hardware
breakpoints and then there is a a I've
closed which is some black listing of
specific module modules to further
prevent reading of this export address
table and recently there are and being
been a lot of talks and publications
about Emmett bypasses so you can read up
on this if you're interested in too but
basically bypassing Emmett is a you have
two options either you try to disable
Emmett this was a this has been shown
for m8 version 5.2 I think we're an
attacker could just call dll unload of
my Emmett and then emitted some nice and
nice unloading of of itself and the in
solid hooks basically so you could
disable it by calling disable basically
and this I think they fixed it in
version 5.5 and the other option you
have to bypass Emmett is too hard on you
exploit and make it emit aware so it
will dance this runtime checks so how do
we bypass amet memory protection this is
the feature very prevent the stack from
being marked as executable so we just
delivered the shellcode not on a stack
but on the heap or rich we just use
return oriented programming and code
reuse attacks and not rely on marking
any memory as executable out yeah and
there is another way we be found out
about
we constructed a sample program which
which allocates some stuff on the heap
with some meaningful non meaningful but
valid x86 code and then we called it and
you see Emmett is enabled so the m8
library is loaded into the memory the m8
checks are enabled but we still can
could call the function located on a
stack without m8 complaining so if we
cannot voice key we can talk about it
yet because we are still discussing with
Microsoft but if you're interested come
by after the talk and yeah let's see so
how do we bypass caller checks to bypass
color checks we just use gadgets that
begin after a call instruction this can
maybe this is tricky I didn't actually
try it but this may be tricky and so
you'll get your op gadget may become
larger and may be more complex and we
also found some issue on these color
checks which we also cannot talk about
it yeah whatever szostak pivoting
bypassing stack pivoting is a you just
make sure if you enter one of these
critical functions which M it protects
you just make sure that your stack
pointer points to the stack actually and
not to your fancy rope chain somewhere
on the heap another option would be just
delivered the rope chain to the stack or
copy the rope chain from the heap to the
stack you could do this with rope code
so
yeah how to bypass eif and since the AF
was this is checked with some hardware
feature there was some guy on the
internet which explains how to disable
this harder feature I'm not quite sure
whether this works in most current
version of a mint but it should I guess
yeah so let's harden our our sample
program the which we which I introduced
before let's harden it with with a met
because the sample program is a 64-bit
we have to there is less mitigations 46
64-bit so let's enable it and then we
see that our exploit doesn't work
anymore and we get a animate violation
about stack pivoting so m8 detected that
the stack pointer was out of bounds for
this virtual well virtual protect call
so having our rope chain on a stack
doesn't work anymore so what we do
instead what do we do instead we copy we
used the first drop chain to copy a
second rope chain to the stack and then
we pivot again we people to stack
pointer again back to the original stack
but to a different location and now we
can call the virtual protect function
and Amit will not complain about stack
pivoting yeah
yeah we you for this example we use the
mem copy but you could do simple roping
to copy by stuff byte by byte so we try
this and with the next m8 violation so
this was a export addressed filtering
violation because our a shellcode scans
through the export address again we have
some detailed information more or less
detail so instead of using the
metasploit payload we constructed our
own payload and try it again and this
time it works so no Amit complaining so
for our constructed example bypassing m8
was somewhat easy because there are no
color checks and no simulated execution
flow checks in 64-bit this memory
protection issue was not didn't really
matter for our case and stack pivoting
checks could be bypassed by copying the
rough chain another up chained to the
stack the AF check was bypassed with a
with some custom shellcode and with some
more engineering you could make this
like the cosmic shellcode now relies on
specific library versions but with some
engineering you could make this more
reliable so let's enable microsoft
control flow guard for our example
control flow integrity is a not too new
so the original publication was in 2005
and there has been many implemented cfi
implementations proposed since then so
somewhere compiler based that there was
some binary only implementations and so
forth and debate the basic idea about
control flow Integrity's to restrict
control flow transfers to some limited
set of allowed targets
so the first adoption the practical
adoption of control so integrity was
control flow guard and it yeah it's
available with visual studio 2015 on
current windows versions and it
restricts indirect calls and indirect
jumps to a static global set of valid
functions valid targets which are
functions so how does this look in code
we have a 32-bit code so this is a
function call an indirect function call
in without guard and this is a function
call with guard so you see some
additional overhead code you see this
check function which checks the indirect
call target whether this is in the set
of valid targets 64bit is basically the
same so this dysfunction checks whether
the target is in this global set of
valid functions and this introduces some
some runtime overhead of course and some
memory overhead because implementation
look like this in pictures so we have
the compiler the compiler generates a
list of valid functions and put it into
the binary and during runtime this list
of functions is like compressed into a
bitmap and put into memory so we have a
bitmap of i get to this later and also
we have the guard track like this check
function which guards every indirect
call or indirect jump so what about this
bitmap how does it work so this control
flow guard bitmap so one bit of this
bitmap covers 8 bytes of
dresses in your virtual address space so
here we lose some precision so actually
so I get this is now so when we
transition from this set of valid
function to the to the bitmap we lose
some precision by by that the
implementation gets rid of the least
significant three bits basically so if
you have a one in this bitmap the this
means the the address you you've been
checking is a valid indirect control
sole target so this pic map may become
large so for for instance for 64-bit I
had a look at this bitmap so I use this
internal vm map and you will find the
two terabyte chunk of memory which is
reserved but not yet allocated so it's
reserved and so this is how this bitmap
looks like and some parts of it are like
allocated and this is where your control
for integrity information is encoded so
this this bitmap is shared across all
your processes on your Windows machine
so you have some shared memory and some
of some parts of this bitmap is is for
private use only so if you load the
library which is shared among all
processes you may your zeros and ones
end up in some blue parts with which you
share for all and if you have like
private cold you don't share this how do
I'll do you bypass control flow guard
there has been last year there's been
some black guy talks about bypassing
control flow guard and the essence
basically was you use search for
unprotected in direct calls or indirect
jumps some guys found some in
in dynamic code so just in time compiled
code this was the case in some old flash
version excuse me so you search for
unprotected calls or jumps or you search
for an CFG disabled modules so like old
libraries which have control flow guard
which are not have not enabled control
flow guard so when the loader loads a
legacy module which doesn't support is
it needs to fill the CFG bitmap with
with one's and basically needs to allow
any indirect control flow transfer to
this legacy module or another way to
bypass control flow guard is just don't
use calls and jumps and use returns so
if you can control the stack or part of
the stack you can just hijack a return
instruction because we turns are not
protected by CFG
that's what I mentioned before so legacy
modules have a the CFG bitmap
initialized to 1 so you're allowed to
jump and call anywhere you want and
another problem of th e f g is this
imprecision because you have a trade-off
between memory consumption of your
bitmap and precision so if you if CFG
allows a function at address 420 for
instance to be a valid call target you
imp you allow by implementations all
these addresses like seven more
addresses to be jumped or calls to so
you have some imprecision there and
another bypass possibilities just call
functions like critical functions like
v-neck sec or not you can still call
them they're not protected they're
protected by CFG but you're allowed to
call them so let's assume we have no
control over the stack as an attacker
and we can control we can hijack some
indirect call which is on the CFG
protection so we will try we try to look
for gadgets which are still reachable
because of this imprecision so how many
gadgets so we still have to work with so
for this we use some rope captured
finders in this case we use we added
some features to a rope or maybe you
notice this is some python module and we
made it CFG aware and looked for CFG
aware gadgets so and we noticed that for
Windows 10 64 bit dll the number of
gadgets reduced from about 20,000 to
factor I could use by a factor of about
eight to two and a half thousand so we
have still two and a half thousand
gadgets which are which you are allowed
to jump or call to despite of the CFG
checks and for a very small program we
observed that the gadget count reduced
to in this case two three and we also
notice that if you enable incremental
linking this is a visual studio linker
flag the gadget count reduced to zero
what so what is this a what is this
incremental linking so this is a linker
flag and it should this is a for
programmers to have a foster linking
time with small code changes so you
don't need to wait for your compiler the
whole day and this incur some some run
time and memory overhead and it
obviously helps CFG reducing number of
valid targets so why is this so so this
is a incremental linking table you have
at the start of your code section you
have a table a jump table which contains
jumps to module in turn so if you do a
module in turn call or a jump you use
this linking table and do a detour over
this table so if you enable incremental
linking ends efg this table looks like
this and visual studio pads this stuff
with a with a breakpoint instructions
with inter optics instructions and now
CFG Valley targets are only under CFG
you're only allowed to call these
functions and you can imagine on your
own if you look for a rope gadget this
is pretty hard to find any useful Rob
gadgets here so this is why incremental
linking reduces the number of CFG
Aware's aware gadgets
another thing to have in mind for
control flow guard is a dynamic code so
most modern browsers and your java
hotspot does it it generates code at
runtime so when you do this you allocate
some executable memory to be backward
compatible your CFG bitmap needs to be
initialized to 1 so we you want to allow
any indirect control so transfer to this
chunk of memory ok so Microsoft
introduced some new memory protection
flag too hard and cheat and proposed and
gave the programmers some new
functionality to like specifically take
control over the CFG bitmap but the
take-home message is your tip compiler
or your cheat code needs to be aware of
CFG so this is again how do we bypass
CFG are we try to so we applied to our
sample program we are applied control
sogard and now our indirect call to the
program main function is now guarded our
exploit obviously fails because our
first stack pivoting gadget is not CFG
valid so we fail yeah so is this the end
of code reuse attacks probably not but
but these rock mitigations and control
flow guard they definitely raise the
cost of weaponizing your vulnerability
so take on message install Emmet and the
CFG stuff disney is still is time to
reach end-users and reach the end users
and as a programmer
if you generate dynamic code as a
programmer do use the CFG it it's a nice
thing and if you generate generate cheat
code take care there's a lot of pitfalls
you need to be aware what you do when
you generate dynamic code and in the
future you may or may not see your shift
you do towards data only attacks and
less code reuse attacks thanks
you