okay thanks all for waking up this early
and going to see this talk and so the
talk is about well it's mostly the
research that I did at my university so
I'm a PhD student at the University of
Louisville in Belgium and there I do
research on security and privacy on the
web which is like a broad thing but
mainly my current focus is on side
channel text in the web and in the
browser as I will be talking about today
so the concept of Dianetics is that
they're a type of psychoanalytic which
means that it's not a direct attack like
a sequel injection or something but you
try to infer information based on
observations that you make from the
environment and all these attacks are
definitely not new they've been known
for decades but it's it was mainly
applied in cryptography and there it was
used to retrieve a cryptographic keys or
retrieve the message that was sent like
while the encrypted message that was
sent or to exploit secure connections so
for instance I think most of you have
heard about this lucky 13 attack it's
also a type of timing attack so the
concept of diuretics is pretty simple
first you perform an action which can be
pretty much anything but of course based
well the action that you do or make is
of course based on the system that
you're going to attack and then you
measure the time from a starting point
until the end so that's something that
you observe and then you
compare or analyze this timing
measurement with some other time your
measurements or just its absolute value
and then well you can exploit it so some
time ago I came up with this new type of
timing attic called the drunkenness
timing attack so in the drunkenness time
in tech you try to determine whether
certain person is drunk or not so to do
this you first perform an action so you
slept the person in the face and then
you measure the time it takes from the
starting point so the slap in the face
until that person slaps you back and
well if he slips you back quite quickly
or you can assume that he's not drunk
and if it's it's a long time the person
is drunk of course I well in my research
I like to do experiments so that's what
I did so I have this test subject who
wanted to remain anonymous but that
didn't happen so it's much as balance so
I went to him and I was wondering well
it was like in the middle of the day and
I was wondering whether he was drunk so
I performed the drunkenness timing
attack I went to them and I slapped him
in the face and so that's when I start
my timer so you see falls down and quite
quickly he slaps me back and so it takes
about three seconds before he slaps me
back so is he drunk well probably not
but of course that's just one
measurement that we took so yeah in
order to make sure that this time a tech
actually works we need to do another
timing measurement and they're
preferably not just would be drunk so
then I gave him some nice Belgian beers
and after a few minutes or because he
can't really hold this liquor he was
drunk so I knew he was drunk so I
performed the timing attack again so I
go to him and I slap him in the face and
then again i start my timer and now you
see he has trouble getting up so it
takes quite a while till the end yeah it
slaps me back so it's like eight seconds
so again the question is much as drunk
well yes and that's because the second
timing measurement was significantly
higher than the first timing measurement
so basically that's how timing attacks
work and so with the drunkenness timing
attack the response time of the user or
the victim relates to its well the
person's drunkenness and the same goes
for while recovering a cryptographic key
so there you measure the time it takes
to execute something and the time it
takes is related to whether a certain
bit of the key or the message it's one
or zero and the same thing goes for the
lucky 13 attack so there you measure the
time it takes until you receive a TLS
error and that gives you some
information about whether the padding of
the encrypted thing was correct and
knowing that allows you to retrieve the
message that was sent and then there are
the web-based Dianetics which will be
the main focus of today so these
web-based I'm ethics they're also not
new they've been known for a very long
time so since 2002 give you an ID how
long this is
so in 1995 cookies were first introduced
so five years after cookies were
introduced and all they weren't widely
used for some years after that timing
attacks had already been discovered and
then a bit later on there were some more
advanced text like this nice thing by
paul stone very good read out of well
the value of a certain pixel in an
iframe by adding a sweetie and CSS
things to make the well to make the GPU
render rendering time take a different
time based on the color of the pixel and
in the same year Eduardo Vela wrote this
nice blog post about a well timing
attack value where input of the attacker
is compared with a certain secret and
the time it takes to compare this well
so it's the JavaScript execution time
it's related to the secret so that
allows you to extract information but a
secret and then you have in the wall
they were I think first introduced in
the academic world and by boards and
bowling and so you they introduced the
concept of direct timing attack and
cross-eyed timing attack so a direct
timing attack well I will show an
example of this so here you have your
attacker and your server that's going to
be attacked and the attacker will try to
brute force the password of the Batman
user and to do this he will send a post
request and measure how long it takes
until he receives an error but well that
the user name is puts battle
which matches here but for the past 40
well type well under something like AAA
but because the first letter doesn't
match the first letter of the password
the well the tech well the server will
very early respond with an error so that
allows the attacker to know that most
likely a is not the first character of
the password so then it tries again with
be AAA now you see that the first letter
matched so the server compared the
second character which didn't match so
then an error was still returned but now
the attacker learned that be was most
likely a correct guess because the
timing was higher than before so well by
repeating this process that Decker can
try to brute-force the password of the
user of course these things only work in
well a very optimal setup which is most
of the times not the case for the
attacker so there's many limitations
regarding these direct die matrix so one
of the major issues is that you have to
deal with irregular irregularities on
the network so any chatter or congestion
will mess up the timing measurements and
will require the attacker to either make
more measurements or just don't let him
succeed in its attack also the well the
concurrent users that are using the
service may influence the timing
measurements because thus the load on
the server will fare I because of well
if there's more users it the load will
be higher and so on
but some smart people came up with
solutions for these attackers so the
main thing is that attack well the
closer you get to the victim server well
the more precise your timing
measurements can be and well in the in
the cloud architecture this can go to
quite extreme forms so you can try to
make sure that your vm gets hosted on
the same physical machine and that
allows you to do some cash attacks and
well it also allows you to use very
precise timing methods like in the order
of microseconds or even less and if you
then use some additional statistical
tests many attacks will succeed but
unfortunately it it would take very long
time to explain all this it's not really
the focus of this presentation so i will
just recommend that you read about these
things because they're really
interesting and i'll move on to the main
topic of this talk namely cross sites
timing attacks so these type of time
matrix are quite different from the
director timing attacks because with the
cross-site timing attacks the request is
no longer sent by the attacker but here
the attacker makes this the victim send
the request and because the web was
developed in such a wonderful way all
well request to third party content will
have cookie attached to them so this
means that the response that the user
will get
based on the request that was sent will
be based on the state of that user so
for instance if a user is logged in you
will see a dashboard if you Rick if you
request the root of the domain and
otherwise it will say that you're not
logged in and you need to log in to see
something so then when you're logged in
the response will be large and when
you're not logged in at the response
will be small and then the attacker can
measure at the response time and so the
time it takes to download the resource
with JavaScript so basically you can
load an image set the source and then
start this timer and when the image
sends this on error event the attacker
can stop this timer because well
typically the attacker is not interested
in images with rather HTML pages and
these are not valid images so that's why
you listen on the on error event and so
these attacks the main goal of them is
to violate the same origin policy and
just because it's so important I will
briefly zoom into the same origin policy
so it's one of the main security
principles that exists on the web and
basically it says and that's well so
well a certain origin so for instance
attacker com cannot read anything from
example that comes from an other origin
so well it's not just the content that
should be secrets but also the length of
resources should be secret because well
because the responses are based on the
state of the user and if the length is
impacted by this the attacker can learn
things about the state
of the user well and this contains a lot
of private information as I will show
later on so I'll give a brief well
overview of how this attack would work
so here you have a social network
consisting of two groups so you have the
Batman group and the Joker group and
here you have the victim and this victim
is browsing to a non malicious website
for instance google com and google com
has this malicious advertiser well it
wouldn't make sense that it's google.com
because school is an advertising but
anyway let's say this is New York Times
and New York Times has a malicious
advertiser and all this malicious
advertiser he can execute JavaScript
with only in the malicious advertisers
calm domain so he can treat out any
information from this social network and
this advertiser will try to determine
whether this user belongs to the Batman
group or the Joker group because of
obviously the advertisements that would
be shown to the user will depend on
which group he belongs to so what
advertiser does is he makes the user
initiates a request to the Batman
resource and because the user is part of
the Batman group because he's robbing
the response will be a lot of rather big
and so it will take around four seconds
then he does the same thing but with a
joker group so he requests the Joker
resource but as you can see and the
responses returned its robber small so
that all the time it will take to the
download this resource is also much
smaller so
the attacker measures that it's around
two seconds so that that's a lot less
than the four seconds that II saw before
so that allows this malicious advertiser
to determine that the user is from the
Batman group but of course these things
only work in ideal situations which
never occur in the wild because well in
the wild a request might look like this
so it moves over the internets has some
congestion so as you can see the timing
measurement of the attacker now for the
Joker group it's at six seconds which
was larger than it was for the Batman
group so yeah this prevents the attacker
from learning anything because he can't
know for sure that this response time
was for the Joker group and it would
always be smaller than for the Batman
group so there's well these Dianetics
have several limitations so there's
first the network irregularities which
were just role similar as with direct
time in ticks but in this case there's
they are worse because the attacker can
control on which network the user is so
if he's on a bad wireless network than
the Well network timings will be well
contain a lot of jitter and then there's
gzip compression so it makes that the
difference in response size is a lot
smaller which makes it much harder to
detect that there's a difference and so
one of the things that an attacker can
do if the timing measurements aren't
always correct or there's jitter on the
timing measurements is to take a lot of
time your measurements and then do
something like take the average
but in this case the attacker will need
a round trip for every measurement at
that he takes and if there's some kind
of rate limiting on service his attack
simply won't work so that's where the
browser-based time a text comment so
these are a new type of timing attack
which will try to overcome all of the
limitations or at least most of the
limitations of the classic grow sites
timing attacks so the goal here is to
start your timing measurements only
after a resource has been downloaded and
by doing so well you don't have any
cheddar or any irregularities of the
network that could impact your timing
measurement and another thing is that
these browser-based Dianetics are much
more accurate which allows you to
determine with more certainty which of
two resources is the bigger one and for
some of the dianetics that I will
explain later a resource only needs to
be downloaded at once and once it's
downloaded you can obtain a lot of
measurements in a very short time
interval so this is what an
browser-based time in Texas would look
like so again you made a request with
the response could you see that only
after the response has been received you
start your timing measurements and you
measure the time it takes to process
this resource instead of download this
resource so there's three types of
processing that you can measure in a
browser so first is to try to parse a
certain resource as of in a specific
format
so for instance by trying to parse an
HTML document as a video and if you
manage to measure the time it takes to
process this so the processing time of
the CPU you will well learn the well
learn an estimate of the size of the
resource and the same goes for storing
or retrieving certain response from the
cache or putting in it into the cash so
I will show a very basic time it well
the most basic one where you measure the
time it takes to parse a certain
resource as a video so first you create
a video element and you add to event
listeners so the first event listener is
on the suspend event and interestingly
this event will fire as soon as the
download of the video is complete so
that's when you start your timing and
measurement and because while the time
it takes to parse this element as a
resource as a video it's rather small
it's best to use the high performance
resource timing so the window the
performance up now and you all know that
a resource has stopped parsing as soon
as the error event fires so that's when
you stop your measurements and then you
can simply set the source of you too
well the thing you want to know the size
of and you measure the time and then
well that's all you need so there's also
another trick that you can do and let's
to use application cache and that's
so there you can first put this resource
that you want to know the size of in the
application cache so then it gets stored
on on the disk and so then every time
you set the source of a video element it
will take it from the cash instead of
making a request to the network so that
allows you to I'll do these timing
measurements very quickly so another
type of time a tech and the browser is
the cash storing time in tech so there
you will measure the time it takes to
have this response object and put it
into the cache so you make the request
object so these things are using the
service worker related ap ice so you
have your request objects with the URL
you want to know the size of some
options which make sure that the cookies
are attached to this request and then
some bogus requests so first you fetch
the resource and once it's downloaded
you know that you can stop start your
timer and then you simply put it into
the cache with a cache API so this
allows you to put any resource into the
cache which i think is a pretty strange
thing security wise but anyway and so
once it's put into the cash you can stop
your timer and so the difference here
will allow you to infer some information
about the size of the resource because a
large resource will take a longer time
to put into the cache so how well do do
this attack work at X work so appears
that they were pretty
nice so we did some measurements very
try to determine how long it would take
on average two to differentiate between
two resources where the difference of
the resource size is on the x-axis so as
you can see for a classic Diamond Tech's
it takes well like nine seconds to
determine a difference between file size
for files that are 1015 kilobytes
different so it still works but these
attacks were executed on our university
Network which is relatively stable so
the measurements that we hear obtained
were in the favor of these classic
timing attacks but it's also interesting
to point out that's here for where the
difference in file size was 540
kilobytes you can see that the attacker
didn't manage to perform his time in
tech and most likely that was due to
some kind of network irregularity that
well that happens when we executed that
experiment now when we look at the
browser-based time ethics so the green
blue and purple you can see that they
perform much better than the classic die
matrix so even when the difference in
file size is just five kilobytes well
the worst dometic still manages to
differentiate differentiates between
file sizes in less than five seconds and
when you look at the best performing
timing attacks or the cash plus video
portion so when you
put the resource in the into the
application cache and then do this video
parsing attack you can see that in yeah
less than 0 seconds you can
differentiate between files it's our
only five kilobytes different in file
size so i will be showing a short
demonstration now and here i will focus
mainly on facebook so facebook has this
functionality where as a facebook page
you can create a post and you can limit
the visibility of this post so you can
make sure that the people that can see
your post or from a certain location or
are all men or women or are of a certain
age so for instance people that are 26
can see this post and when you are not
36 you can see this post and you get
well the ball so when you try to request
it and you're not allowed to view it
then you get this short error message
saying that you can't view it because
you're not in well the scope of the post
so in the demonstration I will try to
discover the age of a user so this is
any user visiting any website so it
could go to New York Times com where
there's a malicious advertiser or a good
good girl hit he could go to cute
kittens calm and gets his age exposed to
the administrators of cute kittens and
so on so the attack requires some
preparation by the attacker so the
attacker first creates a number of
facebook posts which are each targeted
to users of a certain age so
as you saw before you get well you could
limit the posts to a certain range of
Ages so you well the attacker first
creates a post that's visible to people
of the age 13 to 20 to 23 to 32 and so
on and then we will try to determine the
range of the age the user is in and
that's because otherwise that occur
would need to do a lot more requests so
here you do some kind of not really
binary search but something similar and
then well when attacking the victim the
attacker makes the victim facial
corresponding resources so the posts
were made and then obtained timing
measurements for them and then try to
determine the range of H the user is in
regarding the value of the timing
measurements and then in the third step
you will try to determine the exact age
of the user by just repeating all this
process again so here you will see a lot
of boxes and the boxes or just box plots
with the timing measurements and so here
you can see that here it says start
downloading resources so that's the
first step so the attacker downloads the
resources corresponding to these things
so these this is a post targeted to
people of the age 13 to 22 and 23 to 32
and so on so it takes a while to
download the resources and then it will
start obtaining timing measurements so
after
actually less than 10 seconds or well
with some certainty around 11 seconds
you can see that the diamond
measurements for the resource of users
in the age of 23 to 32 is significantly
higher than the rest of the timing
measurements so that allows the attacker
to know that the victim is of the H
between 23 and 32 so that's all ten
different ages that he can be so then
again he does the same attack but then
for the specific age and you can see
already that for the age 26 the timing
measurements are again significantly
higher than for all the other ages so in
less than 30 seconds the attacker is
able to determine the age of the user of
course that was just an attack that we
launched against facebook actually
there's a lot of well many many more
attacks that can be done by using these
browser-based Dianetics so on linkedin
for instance it's possible to add all to
retrieve information about the
connections of a certain user that's on
a website with twitter it's possible to
determine which users the user is
following or in xfig case even try to
determine the identity of the user for
google we found that it was possible to
well to browse into your search history
so any search term that you enter in
google gets saved by google and then
later on you can search it
of course if you have searches search it
and Decker can also search it so it
allows them to know things about what
you searched for on Amazon it's the same
thing but with your shopping history and
I lantech discovered by someone else
yeah allows you to search well so in on
gmail you have this search box where you
can put something in and as an attacker
you can make the same request and then
figure out how many responses were
returned and that allows the attacker to
basically search into your inbox so I
well these are just things that we
looked at so i think i spent like 15
minutes for each one to figure out to
come up with one of these attacks and so
there's many more because there's many
more web service web services and all
because the ether Tex they exist by
design of the web most of them are
vulnerable so because these attacks are
quite frightening I think it's best to
try to come up with some kind of
mitigation unfortunately these are not
as easy on the wall neither on the
client side as on the server side but
especially on the client side it's very
hard to mitigate these attacks and
that's because the techs are there by
the design of the browser and the web in
general a very simplistic way of trying
to mitigate these attacks would be to
reduce the resolution of the timer but
unfortunately that
don't work because if you make the text
a bit more intelligence the resolution
of one millisecond is already sufficient
so for instance for the video parsing
you could simply pass a video multiple
times after in a row and then a
resolution of one millisecond would
already suffice a promising solution
might be to disable third party cookies
so when well when you're on New York
Times calm and you make a request to
facebook com if the cookies are not not
attached to that request well the
responses will be returned will not be
based on the state of the user so that
way the attacker will not be able to
learn anything about knowing the size of
that response so that's something that
you can do on the client side so there's
also a same well the same side attribute
on cookies which need to be implemented
by the server side so the main goal of
these same side cookies is to prevent
things like cross-site request forgery
and think law the way it works is that
it's sort of also and it disables all
third-party cookies but again it
requires an implementation effort by the
by the website that is going to be
attacked and because there's so many
websites it's unlikely that all of them
will implement this so I've mentioned
before that the cause of these attacks
is related to cross-site request forgery
because in cross-site request forgery
the cookies are also attached to the
request
and that allows the attacker to make
some states changes at the well at the
well website for the user so if you can
prevent a religion letter to a legend
timid across origin requests so for
instance with csrf token these attacks
would be prevented as well but here it's
not only the post requests but also the
get requests and putting a CSF token on
every request it might just be a lot of
overkill so basically the security of
browsers regarding these domestics it's
not ideal and it will likely remain that
so we even discovered some new type of
attacks which will we will be disclosing
so me and a colleague will be disclosing
these attacks and this summer and these
attacks allow you to determine the exact
response size instead of estimate but
the good thing is that it's possible for
browsers to mitigate at least one of
these two attacks but unfortunately
browsers done to or browser vendors or
standards people than to take quite a
long time at least in my experience to
try to fix these issues so to conclude
so I've presented this this node type of
browser based time antics where we
measure the time it takes to process a
resource so that's that happens after
the resource has been downloaded which
makes it the attacks are much faster and
more robust than the classic timing
ethics
and one of the major issues is that
these side channel side channels so
these timing side channels may exist by
the design of the web and the browser so
it's unlikely that these diamond texts
will go away and well another issue is
that many major popular web applications
are vulnerable so we're well definitely
not there yet regarding a mitigation so
it will be interesting to see what the
future will bring and letter or
attackers or malicious people will start
using these attacks or not we will see
so if you have any questions feel free
to ask
ok
there's no questions and thank you for
listening
you