and encryption uh the first talk in our
session this afternoon will be from
Erica Portnoy who is a senior staff
technologist at the eff
[Music]
ort hey
hello everyone here welcome from lunch
uh hopefully you'll be able to stay
awake for this talk I'll try to keep it
exciting so today I'm going to be
talking about encryption policy and how
it fits into the broader policy
landscape and how that affects what we
as engineers and cryptographers do and
how we need to think about our work
so we'll start by talking about
authoritarianism and what that looks
like when it's made into policy
explaining how authoritarians create
social control by restricting and
criminalizing what they see as social
deviants and how this is all done in the
name of protecting children
more explicitly limit access to the
internet for kids and thereby control
their access to their social life
then we'll see where encryption comes in
and how for those set on controlling
things private messages have to be
controlled as well
and then we'll conclude with talking
about why this all matters directly to
us here in this room and what we can do
about it
now before we get into it uh you know
this is a little different from some of
the other talks we've heard these past
couple of days in that I'm going to be
talking about some hard topics and I'm
not going to be offended if anybody
needs to leave the room at the beginning
or later or for any reason because I
know this can be some hard things to
hear about certainly I felt that while I
was making the talk
so we like I said we're going to start
with talking about authoritarianism and
what that looks like in practice when
it's made into policy
basically the thesis of the
authoritarians is that deviants is the
enemy of societal function
therefore if you see any deviants out in
the world you have to try to limit it
and control it to keep your Society
functioning
in much of what we're seeing with
authoritarianism today there's this
belief that Society has gone mad and we
have to protect the future by restoring
control otherwise everything is going to
be lost
to be authoritarian fundamentally means
believing that the authorities in charge
are the ones who know that's best
so as a consequence this can mean that
law enforcement needs to have access to
absolutely everything in all cases so
that they can handle everything because
they're the ones in charge
even if it treads on other rights like
privacy
it can also apply in the more closed
context in the sense of a family where
the parents are the one who should have
control over every aspect of their kids
lives but they derive from the same
fundamental underlying principles
so what does this look like in practice
when it turns into public policy and law
I'm going to use some examples of
anti-trans laws in the U.S because
that's where I'm based so it's the ones
that I know best
and in the US we have seen things lately
like Banning gender affirming care and
criminalizing the doctors who provide it
but also things like Banning drag in
public and investigating parents who
provide trans care to their kids as
child abusers
and it's not just a few States it's a
widespread and growing problem
I in fact had to update this slide
between when I started making the talk
and now because it changed so much just
in that short time now a couple of the
states did get better going into the
more blue category but uh unfortunately
three of them got redder thank you to
Texas for being some of the worst ones
out there but actually thank you to
Minnesota for having great laws
providing refugees that happen pretty
recently as well
so we can start to see how this is
relevant to encryption by looking at how
the proponents of these laws defend them
physically it's often the classic
protect the children line which in this
case here this quote becomes the phrase
gender-confused vulnerable children
it would be humorously absurd if it
weren't so effective as rhetoric
and it is in fact just rhetoric that
they're using it's not like they
actually believe that they're protecting
these confused children or anything this
is a quote from someone who used to be
involved in the movement but then got
out of it talking about how protecting
the children is very explicitly within
the community known to be a front for
damaging the trans Community when in
fact really they just want to do as much
damage to the community as they can
and different authoritarian movements
are directly connected so just when
you're talking about anti-trans
movements you can see that they're
connected to things like the
anti-abortionment movement as well by
looking at the people behind them it's
literally the same exact groups who are
forefronting these movements some of the
classic ones are the alliance defending
freedom and the misleadingly named
American College of Pediatricians which
is nothing to do with the best practices
for pediatricians
uh and the anti-abortion laws have been
spreading rapidly as well since Roe v
Wade was just overturned last year so
all of these places that have
restrictive anti-abortion laws managed
to do this in just over a year which is
ridiculously fast
and anti-abortion is also pretty digital
too already and even in just one year
they're even further ahead of the
anti-trans laws in terms of restricting
access to information so we could start
to see how these policies impinge on the
digital sphere in practice
in Texas like I mentioned before they
have this ridiculous Bounty Hunter law
where not just having or performing
abortions but even aiding them makes you
a Target to be sued that includes
providing basic educational resources
sharing information identifying
locations of clinics arranging rides and
escorts fundraising to support
Reproductive Rights or even just
encouraging women to get abortions all
of these can get you sued in Texas even
if you didn't actually manage to help
someone get an abortion
now I've drawn these examples from the
US where I live but it's of course
happening outside as well so to pick on
Hungary we can look at this law that
they pass that lets lgbtq content be
linked directly to child abuse in the
law rather than just in the rhetoric so
in 2021 Hungary passed this law saying
that you can't show miners any content
portraying being gay or transgender and
the way they did it is they stuck it
into an amendment to a bill fighting
child abuse more generally
so when you're charged with reading a
children's book about a trans unicorn or
whatever the law that you'll be charged
under is actually a child abuse law
rather than something specific to being
queer
yeah so this is some pretty horrible
stuff happening in the world that I know
when I was looking into a lot of the
details to repair this made me pretty
stressed so just take a little breather
here take a second uh look at my very
cute bunny
wow she's great
and she's not doing anything horrible
okay so we talked about this trend of
authoritarians reigning in Social
deviants and we started to talk about
how this relates to kids in online
content
now we'll look at some pushes to more
explicitly limit access to the internet
for kids
so why is the internet dangerous from an
authoritarian perspective
basically it's because the internet is
where ideas spread it's both a social
sphere and it provides access to
information
so you can keep kids in their Suburban
home and ban books from schools and
libraries but if they have internet
access they'll still be doing things out
there beyond your direct control which
of course authoritarians hate
and Direct Control is necessary from an
authoritarian perspective and this is
because authoritarians see children as
objects of protection rather than fully
formed subjects of Rights
there's a lot of fear-mongering around
the internet for kids and social media
in particular but as with most moral
parents it's mostly unfounded and it
turns out the internet is actually
mostly great for kids here's this Pew
study from 2022 is just one example so
for most kids the internet lets them
connect to their friends show their
creative side get support and feel
accepted
and you can imagine how it's even more
important for kids who are marginalized
or otherwise unwelcome in their daily
lives to be able to have access to this
sort of community
the fear is driving the push to limit
the internet for kids have the same
underlying principles as the
anti-abortion and anti-trans movements
which is that the answer to everything
is surveillance and control
so now let's take a look at some of the
proposals out there that are trying to
implement this control
these all tend to be horrible in a whole
variety of ways beyond their underlying
principles
so the kids online safety act nearly
made it into a must pass package last
legislative session not only does it
include over broad language about what
it limits for kids using this line other
matters that pose a risk to physical and
mental health of a minor it lets
individual states decide what falls into
that category
even beyond what we saw in the last
section about how states are quickly
moving to limit trans and abortion
rights
especially worrying when you consider
that one of the sponsors of the bill has
referred to education about race
discrimination as being dangerous for
kids
then there's a bunch of State bills that
instead use the tactic of giving parents
or Guardians excessive and direct
control over their kids online
experience with the Utah one being the
worst of them now this bill is wild
first of all kids can mean anyone under
18. so you have the 17 year old who's
being subject to these laws and the
limitations that they require impose are
ridiculous so a 17 year old under this
law would not be able to use the
internet after 10 30 pm
[Laughter]
and if kids want to have an online
account on most websites the bill
requires that the parents be given the
password
and of course to implement this and it
includes an age verification requirement
so you can't just lie about your age on
the internet as people have been doing
since the dawn of time
and instead you have to trust these
companies that you say are causing harm
and have privacy problems with the kids
in identification information so you
know it's a little silly for them to be
doing this in the first place
uh these are only a couple other pulses
out there and these are the ones that
don't directly touch on encryption which
we'll look at more in the next section
in case you're exhausted by all these
laws I know somebody who relates
okay so if you want to have social
control you're restrict and criminalize
what you see as social deviants often in
the name of kids and then go on to limit
access to information for kids more
directly
but now we get to where encryption comes
in
if you're set on controlling things
surely the private messages must be
controlled as well
so how can we let messages be private on
controlled space when they might Harbor
content that's dangerous for children or
to society as large at Large
now of course attacking private messages
is not anything new
since encryption is what allows messages
to be truly private encryption is the
part of it that gets targeted
since encryption is knowledge and
knowledge is power encryption takes
power away from authorities and so
therefore encryption is inherently
anti-authoritarian
storied history of the crypto Wars
authorities usually can't just come out
and say that they want to backdoor
encryption
so instead they'll find the best excuse
that they have which today means
focusing on stopping online child abuse
as they claim
but something that anyone who works on
child abuse knows is that nearly all
cases the abuse is perpetrated by
someone the child already knows
so for it to make sense at all to come
after encryption proposals really have
to focus narrowly on the re-sharing of
child sexual abuse material otherwise
known as csam
because no logical and foreign person
looking at abuse more broadly who isn't
already starting from an
encryption-focused perspective could
possibly understand how this abuse is
perpetrated and then a decide to go
after encryption of all things
and young people themselves don't want
this surveillance as an answer
when you consider kids as fully formed
subjects of Rights
you might start to ask what kids
themselves think and that is exactly
what European digital rights did they
interviewed 8 000 teenagers in 13 U.S
countries EU countries and they found
that the kids themselves don't want
government scanning even if it's to
prevent child abuse
the kids they surveyed said they
wouldn't be comfortable being
politically active or exploring their
sexuality if authorities were monitoring
their digital Communications
so even though the law might want to
Target child abuse by adding
surveillance they're effectively
chilling political activity and sexual
exploration which again is going to make
authoritarians very happy
but don't worry they'll say these days
we're not even breaking encryption
you might trace the strength back to the
2015 speech which asks for encryption
front doors but the first major proposal
of this sort was the UK's ghost proposal
in 2019 which would basically add your
surveillor as a secret silent extra
group child member
pretty Patel was the Home Secretary at
the time but given a changeover in the
UK this is a graphics a little out of
date
um anyway so thinking that this doesn't
break encryption is a fallacy arising
from poorly defined endpoints and if
you're interested in more rigorous
treatment of it you could see the paper
on end-to-end encryption which you can
find on eprim
but for an intuitive understanding of
why this breaks encryption you can think
about user expectations
in a securely encrypted system no one
but you or your intended recipients
should be able to read or make
inferences on the messages you send
things like the ghost proposal or
today's common client-side scanning
proposals which do the scanning before
messages leave the device the device
break that expectation
foreign but lawmakers of course don't
care and are going ahead and mandating
this stuff anyway
the UK wants to scan everything and
furthermore they want to also
criminalize sending messages even
intended to cause psychological harm
even if no harm was actually caused in
the UK as long as there was a risk it
might have you still might get two years
jail time
not only do websites have to proactively
prevent harmful content they have to use
officially government-approved software
to do the scanning
now if you've heard of this bill these
are probably the parts that you've heard
of but this bill is so extensive that
while they were at it they also created
this a new offense where you might get a
year in jail for lying online which
wasn't even the top story
the EU also wants to scan everything but
in the EU they focus more on detecting
things we don't actually have the
technology to detect
in addition to requiring private content
scanning the EU child sexual abuse
regulation commonly known as chat
control would make websites proactively
try to find previously unseen abusive
content
plus it wants websites to use AI to look
at message threads and determine if the
conversation involves grooming for
future child abuse again focusing on
this stranger danger
fear instead of looking at the vast
majority of cases of grooming that are
perpetrated by someone the kid already
knows
of course the U.S won't be left out they
want to scan everything too
under this law the fact that you support
encryption at all on your service can be
used as evidence against you and they're
not even pretending to be okay with
encryption here the sponsors of this
bill have just come out and said they
don't want encryption to be a get out of
jail free card
they all want to mandate this despite
the technology barely even working for
the already narrow types of child abuse
cases it might even theoretically work
for
these reports that get made have tons of
false positives
Facebook found that three-quarters of
reports are things like bad jokes
LinkedIn found that only a third of
their reports were actually CSM and even
the confirmed reports are rarely acted
on
a 2020 report from Ireland showed that
only 10 percent are even actionable in
the first place and those don't even all
get followed up on
so it's not like getting more reports by
breaking encryption increasing the size
of the haystack is going to help things
and like a 2022 New York Times article
showed talk where they were talking
about a couple of fathers falsely
flagged as child abusers because they
sent medical pictures of their kids to
their doctors these false positives can
have a giant effect on your online
social effect life that lasts and lasts
and that's because companies cannot
afford to take this risk of being shown
not to be harsh enough against any of
the positives that they flag because the
laws are so harsh
yeah
so earlier we talked about all the
different types of social deviants that
authoritarian insert against
these anti-encryption bills often
mandate scanning only for csam in
particular but it's naive to think that
authoritarians won't see this technology
see that it's already deployed and
mandate scanning for broader varieties
of content
we know it because we've already seen it
happen
the technology that was originally
developed to scan for csam is already
today being used to scan for terrorist
content and when a place considers
wearing drag akin to terrorism or child
abuse and there's this technology
available they're not going to have any
qualms about mandating those scans as
well instead of just relying on Empower
bounty hunters to report their neighbors
even more directly the term grooming has
already been used to attack queer adults
so when laws pass that allow scanning
for grooming you can see how they'll be
interpreted to scan for queer content
online as well super easily
see I gotta be skeptical of the utility
of any of these proposals
okay
so we've talked about what the laws are
and what's driving them
now let's talk about why this matters to
us here in this room and what we're
going to do about it
so the first thing to keep in mind is
you can't assume any of these proposals
are made in good faith
therefore these proposals don't deserve
your efforts in trying to make everyone
happy split the difference and you know
let them have their surveillance and
have their encryption too
so a myth that I often hear is if we
don't offer a less bad alternative we'll
just do the worst possible thing I am
here to tell you backed up by my crack
team of legislative analysis and legal
experts
that is just not true
that is not how this works
things that are important to basic
rights can in fact be uncompromisingly
protective protected
just because policy makers don't like
hearing just don't legislate that
doesn't mean it's not the right answer
and it doesn't mean that we can't get
that result it is in fact possible to
convince a lawmaker of something and it
happens all the time so for example
there could be somebody out there who
thinks that we need to scan for csam but
at the same time understands why you
might not want to be scanning for
abortion content so when you explain
that it's the same technology that would
be used for both of these things you can
get them to back off
and if they're telling you that you have
to pick one they're taking advantage of
you not knowing how the system works so
learn how the system works and you won't
be fooled into doing that
okay now that we won't all get tricked
into thinking that we need to design
these things the next step is not
getting nerds type do not let this be
you
now I know computation over encrypted
data is very cool and very fun but when
it's a back door that does not matter
how fun it is it's still assessing
private content and Reporting it to a
third party which is breaking encryption
so if you have to work on this topic
because it's just so fun
consider using it to limit rather than
open access to data
data that used to be sent in the clear
but really needs to be computed on can
now be encrypted rather than protected
data
being computed on and releasing more
information out there
or you can go do this work in another
less sensitive field like Health Data or
something to let researchers work on it
but just don't design a system that will
automatically reveal people's private
information just because there's cool
crypto involved in building it
so for those of you building
non-backdoored encryption first of all
thank you but remember the old adage
that done is better than perfect
so it's politically easier to defend an
encryption product that's already been
shipped then try to add encryption later
and if these laws pass it'll just get
even harder
just be sure when you're doing this not
to make over broad claims about your
encryption protections that can get
yours in trouble when they rely on them
and expect higher encryption than you
actually offer
but if you can get something out the
door ASAP do that
okay so if there's one slide in this
entire talk that I want you to remember
it is this one right here
remember it is not just what you work on
it's how you talk about what you work on
so this is a room here of people who
understand subtlety and nuance and the
details of security and encryption
and the trade-offs involved in
encryption like security and usability
right that's why we're all here
unfortunately politicians do not have
that luxury
they might work on encryption one day
and standardized testing and
requirements the next and even their
technical staffers have to be more
generalist so someone might be in charge
of all of science policy they're doing
the biology work and the encryption work
at the same time
so when they hear something like it is
technically possible to build such a
system they think great that means we
can now legislate to require it
the concept of it is technically
possible but as such limitations that
it's infeasible to ship it just doesn't
exist for them you have to think about
it like another language and in this
language that they speak they don't have
time for these long phrases so if you
want to say that in their language what
you say instead is a single word it's
impossible
and I know that's not like technically
accurate but it hurts a little less if
you think about it just speaking a
little language and the words in this
other language have this other meaning
it's hard to do but it's really
necessary
and speaking this language fluently
matters because we are the ones that
they look to
to answer these questions
so it's not just that we need to say it
right we do need to be out there saying
it at all
just because they don't understand
technology it will not stop them from
legislating on it unfortunately
so unless we make it clear that there's
no way to nerd harder to make encryption
back doors they're going to pass the
laws to require them
an easy way to speak up is through the
eff Action Center whose link is on this
slide
where you can mention in your messages
to Representatives that you work on
these Technologies a harder but
potentially more impactful way is to get
your company to take a public stance
but both of these are still less hard
than being stuck in a complex regulatory
framework where nobody knows what's
illegal in the first place and so then
your general counsel just says oh no we
can't risk building this so if you want
encryption to remain legal please let
your voice be heard
that's not easy
but we haven't lost yet
by speaking up now we can and will
defend encryption
and one more bonus way to help out is to
enable eff's lawyers activists and
technologists to defend encryption every
day which you can do at this link here
again I'm Eric Portnoy thank you for
listening today and I think we have time
for some questions
[Applause]
[Music]
all right so one question to get us
started uh you mentioned that it is
easier to uh it's better sorry done is
better than perfect it's good if we have
things in now because it's harder to
remove them later
um so there are areas where you think we
are missing uh pieces of encryption
technology that we should be focusing on
first
I mean I feel like and some of them
highlighted just improve
in Prince conference uh there was a
whole talk about how encrypting cloud
backup storage is difficult right the
mega talk I believe it was and so that's
a big area of improvement that we can do
it's hard but it's not impossible right
if you look at the way that WhatsApp did
it now Apple iCloud has their backups
encrypted as well like these things are
possible to do even if they're hard but
now that there's more examples out there
you don't have to design all of your ux
from scratch so hopefully that should
make it a little easier I think that's
the next big area to look at is all
these backups in the cloud yeah
let me just go back a month slide I
think or two slides before the rabbit
probably
uh one more
I I was just going to just react to this
I mean I totally understand where you're
coming from but I just want to say that
you know encouraging scientists to lie
is very it's a very slippery slope and
it's why in the U.S half the country no
longer respects science so you just have
to be very very careful with the
messaging and and I I totally I
understand what you said speaking a
different language yeah I understand
that but does everybody you know do
non-scientists understand that and and
it causes a lot of problems also well I
mean you don't really have to think
about it as lying per se right no you
know but but with somebody listening to
you think of it as lying it's only you
know no it's only it's only lying uh if
you don't you don't stand on
all the said so it not just that you're
saying each of these things in languages
words of connotation so they have
further meaning so impossible and
infeasible
in politicians speak are equivalent so
if you're trying to say infeasible you
need to say impossible because
infeasible is just not the word that
they use for that so impossible to build
in the real world under these
constraints
that is it's just a shorter way of
saying it it's an abbreviation rather
than a lie I think I think the slide is
fine but I'm worried where it goes five
years from now uh yeah
um I think these are not quite the
dangerous there
so my question is you mentioned about uh
uh you know communicating effectively to
the legislative process and how you know
technology will be legislated like even
in advance of that uh we've seen things
like before you know Apple uh maintained
the lack of end-to-end encryption for
government uh at the at the governance
request it was reported by Reuters and
uh it's been reported widely that even
with the end-to-end encryption backups
for uh for WhatsApp that WhatsApp is
still available for law enforcement
surveillance even though it's
theoretically and encrypted and we
haven't seen any like backdoor
legislation yet we've seen proposals and
things like this but like do we really
think that the biggest threat is from
legislation versus the actual people
implementing this today to enable
surveillance inside of these companies
that run these systems
uh what do you mean by implementing it
today like so like for example like you
know iCloud has just recently announced
an encryption but uh it's not it's off
by default and the backups for
historically have been maintained is not
and encrypted to enable surveillance and
WhatsApp uh is still available for
surveillance to law enforcement even
though it's theoretically and encrypted
uh the same goes for iMessage and we've
seen this like with you know the people
that participate in prison for bulk or
for targeted collection
um these companies today are shipping
what is headline news and then encrypted
that is able to be surveilled by the
state yeah I mean so I
when you see those headlines right if
you any time you look at the details it
always ends up being like a targeted
case and I feel like everybody
understands that at the end of the day
if you really want to get into one
specific person's phone there's going to
eventually be some way to do that but
that's a very different situation from
considering Mass surveillance certainly
but like to use your example like you
could Target all the abortion providers
in in a city right like if the if the
state can compel these people to to
surveil what's quote unquote end to end
then they can surveil anyone that the
state decides that they deem undesirable
right I mean but that's certainly much
easier to do on an unencrypted service
so we're talking about abortion right
we've already seen that they requested
Facebook Handover message so I think the
danger is like from the implementers not
from the state yeah I mean it's it's the
scale of it right it's going to scale
person by person when they do it and
it's going to acquire a lot of work so
you can't just have them require all the
abortion providers to you know say hack
all the abortion providers is very
different from hack this one specific
person and watch until they leave their
laptop unintended right that requires a
lot more effort and a lot more time uh
and so I think the scale of it is really
opening or something yeah hi uh great
talk what do you say to the people who
go this is nice but that's a completely
extreme position we we can't do that you
have to do something if that is a line
of reasoning I hear frequently and I was
curious if you have a sort of explicit
yeah I mean the thing you have to
understand about we have to do something
is uh hiring in politics doesn't work
like hiring in Tech or you know Academia
or whatever the way you get hired in
politics is you get elected and
politicians to get reelected they need
to be constantly seen to be doing things
it doesn't really matter what the things
are
so you know when they're saying we have
to do something you know it it doesn't
mean we have to do something about
encryption from their perspective they
just have to keep doing things so like I
feel like that's just a line they use
you know so on the political side I
agree with you but this is a question
for the people who are working on the
technical stuff the the backdoor
encryption if you will right where it's
like well great like there is this
extremist positions of like me and you
and the eff uh and then they're like but
you know we have to deal with this stuff
so we're not going to sit at the bottom
left of that side there we're going to
go somewhere else and I don't know what
would you say to the room full of people
with that opinion I mean it really
depends why they're saying it right I
feel like you have to look at why
they're saying we must do something and
that's where you know their arguments
start to fall apart right what are what
are they saying we have to do something
about are they saying we really need
this Mass surveillance system and we
need to be able to get into everybody's
phone on a whim or whatever there
shouldn't be any if they're saying you
know I feel like I think it is a very
specific answer to the person who's
saying something
but to be a little generalist here when
they're saying that they're saying it
because you know they want access to
everything everywhere
and they think that they should be able
to access all of that but that is not
how societies are constructed right we
have the social contract there are
limits that we place on the authorities
even if it means that we don't have a
perfect policing right that's that's
when you become a police state right yes
we have the Fourth Amendment you can't
just go into somebody's home willy-nilly
in any second right there's restrictions
and limitations around this and we as a
society accept that we are going to have
these restrictions and limitations to be
able to preserve some of the Civil
Rights
so when they say oh we have to do
something we have to be able to get into
it that's you know it's that's a
rhetoric they use to like convince you
but it's not
it's not the contract that we've made as
a society thank you
I'm afraid we've run out of time so
please join me in thinking Erica again
[Applause]
[Music]
our next speakers will be Matteo
scarletta and Ken Tong trong who will be
talking about an analysis of the threema
secure messenger
[Music]
all right so hello everyone I'm Kian and
this talk is titled analysis to the
three must secure messenger this is a
joint work between Kenny Patterson
Matteo scarletta here and myself we are
from the applied cryptography group at
eth Zurich so first of all let's ask
ourselves what is trima so trima
describes itself as an end-to-end
encrypted messaging application for
Android and iOS and it was released in
2012 so to put a little bit of context
this is before signals was released and
before WhatsApp was end-to-end encrypted
and they take a lot of pride in means
with indeed in their website they say
that trim is 100 Swiss made unlike U.S
Services it is fully gdpr compliant and
we all know nothing Shady related to
cryptography ever came out of
Switzerland so
that's it why is this an interesting
Target so the question is who uses
streamer well 11 million private users
worldwide as well as various
organizations and political entities for
example the Swiss government and the
Swiss Army mandate the usage of streamer
as the as the messages of choice for
internal Communications and allegedly
all of Schultz the current chancellor of
Germany also uses streamer
well this makes it an interesting Target
for the analysis and I'm just going to
give you like a birthday view a high
level view of the threema protocol so we
have the clients we use this in the
server and the clients in the server
communicate using this protocol which
you call the client to server protocol
or c2s for short
and on top and this is for the client to
communicate with the server and on top
of that we have an end-to-end protocol
which allows users to communicate
communicate with each other
you have to these two layers of
encryption which is a very standard
thing to have for secure messaging
applications
so we're gonna go take a deep dive on
this protocols so let's start with the
end-to-end protocol well now each user
has their own keeper which you can
imagine being this elliptic curve
default and now assume that for example
Alice has Bob's public key and vice
versa then messages between Alice and
Bob are encrypted under this key K which
is just a different helmet between the
long-term key and I mean you can
immediately see that this has a problem
it doesn't have any forward secrecy but
and we will show how stream actually
handles this somewhat and but first
let's take a look at how messages are
sent in three months whenever you send a
message you have to first serialize it
and then encrypt it and then after that
you send it but let's see how it's
serialized well first of all we get a
byte which is the message type and for
example for text messages this is simply
a one in the example that you see above
them and then you have the message
content in this case you have hello and
there you have a random amount of pkcs7
padding in this example it's just a0202
and the the reason behind this is that
this tries to hide the length of the
message
then this whole thing gets encrypted
using excess of 20 poly 1305 with a
random nose and the key K that we
described before so again diffie-hellman
of long-term key of both users
and before all of this the metadata is
prepended so for example the source and
the receiver of the message like clearly
just doing this is not enough because
this metadata is not Integrity protected
what Rima does is it is it creates this
value called the metadata box
and it is created by taking a selection
of the metadata and then encrypting it
again with the same nonce and a key
derived from from the keycape and this
is a pretty strange design where Keys
used both for encryption on on the right
and also for key derivation
right but this is not the strangest
thing about this protocol this the
strangest thing is that this metadata
box is actually not even mandatory
indeed an attacker could just strip away
this metadata box and other metadata is
just not Integrity protected anymore
which means that a metadata can be
overwritten and this enables some some
of the attacks in our paper
and now let's take a look at the client
to server protocol
so as we were saying before the client
of server protocol is used to as the
name implies from the client to connect
to the server and this sort of fixes the
issue that of the end-to-end protocol
the end-to-end protocol is not forward
secure and this by injecting some
ephemeral Randomness in the
authenticated key exchanger this creates
an ephemeral session key
and maybe this is not satisfying because
it's just forward secrecy at the client
to server level rather than the n2l
level but Prima says it's harder to do
it at the end to end level
so oh yeah and also note that the key
pair used for the client to server
protocol are exactly the same though as
the as the one that the users use for
the end-to-end protocol
um right so let's I'll go you through
the situous protocol but I'm just going
to skip over a lot of the details
because they're not relevant so now
Alice uses her key which is the same
again as the end-to-end protocol and the
server has its own keeper and this
public key of the server PKS is stored
on analysis device because it's embedded
within the application now let's now as
the server will will create uh we create
their ephemeral keys and they will send
it to each other and that is not too
relevant but what is relevant is this
message here where Alice at some point
will need to authenticate to the server
so what she does is she derives this key
case session which is just a different
helmet between the ephemeral keys and
she will also derive another key called
K vouch which is just a Diffie helmet
within the long-term keys
and finally she creates this value
voucher or vouch box which is the
encryption under kvouch over a femoral
key
what this does intuitively is that it
creates a binding between her ephemeral
key and her long-term key which is
containing a vouch right so FML key is
what is being encrypted and key vouch is
is what contains the her long-term key
and this value is then sent to the
server and the server will check it and
then if the handshaker goes well then
they have established this key session
which they will use as the session key
to communicate between the client and
the server
now let's take a look at the issue with
this protocol well first of all let's
focus on the watch box so on the top you
see that the there's a key derivation
which is just a different helmet between
the long-term care valleys and the
longer key of the server right so this
is just different element long-term long
term
below you have the encryption under this
key of an ephemeral value or or actually
some value right
but this is exactly the same pattern
that you that we've seen on the
end-to-end protocol we have a
diffie-hellman and then the encryption
using the result of that diffie-hellman
in some sense you can see that the
structure of the messages at the
end-to-end level and then at the c2s
protocol they sort of have some
similarities and you know one can one
can but wonder what could go wrong and
what could go wrong is exactly this so
imagine that we can find a special
keeper esk EPK such that EPK has this
shape so it starts with a one
and zero one and in the middle we have
Sigma which is just 30 bytes of utf-8
valid string so something that you can
just copy and paste somewhere else right
as a message
and now consider this run of the
end-to-end protocol between Alice and
the attacker right so this is the
end-to-end protocol
yeah assume first that the attacker
manages to somehow claim that his
end-to-end the public key is PKS npks
again is the situous key of the server
this of course looks like an insane
assumption because normally you should
never be allowed to claim an arbitrary
public key especially if you don't don't
know the private key corresponding to
that
but bear with me for just a second
now assume that the adversary also
convinces Alice to send Sigma the 30
bytes of utf-8 before to send Sigma as a
text message to the attacker and this
could be for example the result of
social engineering or perhaps you could
you could think of
um you know a Spam campaign where they
say send me this uh this discount code
and you know we'll give you something
and then if Alicia hey sorry if Alice
obliges
then what she does is she derives this
key for the end-to-end protocol which is
the diffie-hellman between her Lantern
key and what she believes to be the
long-term key of the attacker in this
case PKS
and then she sends them possibly the the
encryption under this key off well I won
because it's a message type again this
is a text message which is which implies
this one byte then the content of the
message which by definition is like the
sigma and possibly because the the pkcs7
padding is randomized in its length this
also could be a one and the probability
of this happening is one over 254.
now because of the first assumption that
the servers sorry the the attacker's
public key is PKS then this key that
Alice has just derived is exactly the
same as K vouch in the client to server
protocol
and the message that she just sent to
the attacker is the encryption using
k-vouch of exactly the the APK the key
that we that has this string shaper from
before and this means that this is a
valid Boucher for a key to which the
attacker knows the corresponding private
key
this means this is basically a c2s and
end-to-end cross protocol attack so
we're using a message from the
end-to-end protocol in order to break
the client to server protocol
the implication of this attack is that
sending a text message compromises
client authentication forever
indeed what happens is that the attacker
now authenticates as Alice just sending
the the vouch box to the server and say
hey I'm Alice are there any new messages
for me and then the the server would
just reply oh yeah these are the
messages which are of course still
end-to-end encrypted but this completely
leaks all the metadata for inbound
messages to Alice
we call this attack watch box forgery
because basically we're just forging a
large box
we have some loose ends some issues that
we still have with that I promised that
I would discuss and the first one would
be how to find a suitable ephemeral key
EPK which a problem which we call
getting that key and the second problem
is how do we claim the service public
key as ours right so how do we claim PKS
as our public key which we call the
bamboozling
well
first of all
had the key so we again we have this
shape for the for EPK and this is not
very easy to do this actually
empirically we we discovered that this
requires about 2 to 51 keys to be to be
explored and because these These are
public key operations this is actually
pretty expensive and what we did is we
ran some quick estimates and this will
cost around 180 000 on AWS and uh well
Kenny replied with yikes
which is the only correct response to
such a message
however we did manage to find some
optimizations which means that some
optimization and 8 000 course days later
we actually found this key so you can
see the secret key on the top and at the
bottom we have a public key which has
exactly the shape that we want so it
starts with a one it ends with a one and
in the middle we have this very strange
uh string that you can copy there's a
nice QR code that you can use you can
send it to our account and maybe you get
hacked you know
um
so
um next problem the bamboozling well
it's very hard to claim our an arbitrary
public key as yours but trima much like
a good swiss cheese it has holes and the
whole that we could have found is called
the trima gateway and trima Gateway is
this sort of paid API which is used in
order for companies to programmatically
send and receive messages from their
client and somehow there you have this
web API which allows you to register on
your account and you put your your
public key but it does not require you
to prove that you have the corresponding
private key this is a nice oversight
which allowed us to create an account
called lytaas
and up there you see that the public key
of lytas is that one and on the bottom
you see a screenshot from the code of
srima and you can see that actually
corresponding so that the server Pub Key
is actually the key that we claimed to
be from our account you might ask what
does lytas stand for it stands for lose
your Stream Account as a service
and yeah now we have all the ingredients
to run this attack
so for the second part of this talk let
me take over and go through some of the
backup methods that trima uses
in particular I will cover trim a safe
when you stream a safe your identity
your private key and a list of your
contacts including their nickname gets
encoded in Json dipped encrypt with a
password of your choosing and sent to
the trima server for safe keeping and
then you can retrieve them for the from
the trima servers if you lose your
device for instance
and I'm sure that this audience can spot
something wrong with this picture
and we'll reveal it now it's compressed
and encrypt so if crime on TLS taught us
anything is that if we first compress
and then encrypt something we are
leaking
information about the plaintext
especially if the plaintext changes then
the length of the encryption licks
something about it and in this case
we're lucky because the attacker has a
way to make the plaintext change
because the nickname of an account that
could be controlled by the attacker is
included in the backup
so now yeah we have like this very nice
uh crime style setting and we can
explosive in practice by creating this
Loop so we can connect our Target device
to a computer with ADB with the Android
debug tools start streamer
trima will automatically start a backup
which we can observe the sides we will
then drop the collection the connection
in order to make the backup fail
otherwise the the three map would not
attempt another backup for seven days
change the nickname of the attacker
controlled account kill trima and repeat
and we observe that if we do this 16 000
times and observe all the backup sizes
then we have enough information to
recover most of the private key and then
we can use polar slow to recover the
remaining bits
so this gives us uh
the product key
through a comparison side Channel which
is wonderful if you ask me
so this is the full list of the attacks
that we found on trima we only covered
two today for the others please check
out our paper
they've all been fixed by trima with a
set of changes ranging from changes in
the watch box derivation through better
key separation and of course for for the
backups disabling compression
no so now this has been
um very fun exercise in crypto analysis
but what I want to discuss now is the
wider lessons that we can learn from
something like trima I think the the
first lesson concerns rolling your own
protocol we have uh crypto Mantra that
is don't roll your own crypto we believe
that this should be extended to no
rolling of protocols allowed
we can see that trima used mostly
standard crypto a crypto that we know to
be safe so the knuckle Library
but knuckle using knuckle didn't save
trema or first for instance the metadata
box is uh good perfectly safe
authenticated encryption of the metadata
but at a protocol level it could just be
stripped
and the same for the batch box again we
have
secure authenticated encryption
but this value does not contain
freshness therefore can be replied
so the guarantees that these Primitives
give
are practically void at the protocol
level
much worse not only you should not roll
your own protocol even modifying solid
protocols in unintended ways can lead to
bad consequences this is the case for
bridgeify for instance the richify is an
offline messaging app they use the
signal protocol so we could expect them
to be secure but because of the way they
implement the signal protocol they
integrated in their system there are
still an attack against spiritual defy
that allows many in the middle and
therefore recover of plain text
foreign
concerns cross protocol interactions
so for trima we saw two of this one was
the one that Ken just presented we can
take an end-to-end protocol message and
play it in the c2s protocol to obtain a
permanent authentication break
another that we didn't talk about is a
cross protocol attack between the
registration protocol and the end-to-end
protocol in this case malicious streamer
server can use the registration
protocols to produce compromising
material that then can be played inside
the into a protocol
but we are not the only ones finding
this kind of attacks in crypto in the
wild so for instance metrics is another
messenger a Federated double ratchet
based messenger and it suffered a
devastating blowing its security
through an attack that also
exploits
the interactions between old and magon
and these are two sub protocols inside
metrics
okay
and finally I want to stress the
importance of proactive security so if
yesterday is talk about breaking Cloud
encryption and mobile networks and
wireless were not enough
um
trima starts with this very simple and
traditional layering of protocol so
secure transport protocol and an
end-to-end messaging protocol on top of
that
but then it makes it much more
complicated to formally analyzing by
having forward secrecy only at the
transport level
the end-to-end protocol was patched
several times to add things like the
metadata box and replay prevention for
nonsense for repeated nonsense
and when trima announced that they were
releasing a forward secure protocol as
an update after our findings we were
very surprised to see that they were not
releasing a new Fresh end-to-end
protocol
but they were stacking a new protocol on
top of the existing ones so here we are
entering the uncanny valley of
formal verification and I'm very glad I
I won't be the one trying to make a
formal model out of this and I am
sincerely uh afraid to imagine what will
happen if they try to add post
compromise security to their system
so to recap
don't roll your own protocols and if you
really have to be aware of cross
protocol interactions and please please
prove your protocol secure before some
PhD students comes and breaks it
naturally this backs the question of who
should take this heavy and expensive
load of Designing proving secure and
maintaining cryptographic protocols I
don't have an answer for this but maybe
you have opinions and with this I want
to close it all you can drop us an email
or visit our website for the full paper
uh thank you for your attention and we
will be happy to take your questions
foreign
[Music]
so we will have to move on to the next
speaker but I encourage you to follow up
afterwards so our next speaker is uh
Julia Len who will be speaking about
interoperability in end-to-end encrypted
messaging
thank you
foreign
sorry okay
uh thank you for the introduction I'm
excited to present to you today on
interoperability and n10 encrypted
messaging and this is Joint work with
Usher gosh Paul grabs and Paul wrestler
and so antenna encrypted messaging has
become arguably one of the most widely
used privacy Technologies today
it's used across many messaging apps
including WhatsApp signal and iMessage
among others
and most popular messaging apps follow a
centralized model so generally generally
this means that users of a particular
messaging app can only message users of
that same app so for example here a
signal user cannot message somebody on
WhatsApp
but a recent ruling from the EU will
mean major changes to this model for
secure messaging
so in particular last September the EU
signed into law the digital markets act
or dma
now the goal of this regulation is to
reduce the effect of large gatekeeper
companies essentially those that control
a majority of the market share for
messaging from locking in users into
their messaging ecosystem due to network
effects
and so one important provision of the
dma
is a mandate that these large gatekeeper
apps must make their services
interoperable with non-gatekeeper apps
upon request
and so some of you may be thinking that
this doesn't affect you if you're
outside of the EU but I will add that
this has the potential to affect those
outside of the EU as well for one thing
we've seen historically that laws in the
EU tend to send precedence for
regulation outside the EU which we've
seen with the gdpr
and for example the US has already
proposed a similar similar regulation
requiring interoperability through the
access Act of 2021.
so really this is a regulation that has
the potential for affecting all future
and 10 encrypted messaging
so going back to our model here where
WhatsApp is very likely to be designated
a gatekeeper app
as an illustrative example here if a
non-gatekeeper like signal request to
interoperate with WhatsApp
then signal users would be able to
message WhatsApp users without making a
WhatsApp account
and this represents a fundamental change
to the basic centralized architecture of
today's n10 encrypted messaging
and very naturally this raises a lot of
questions for instance how will this
interoperability look like what's the
design space here and how exactly how
exactly will this affect security and
privacy
and complicating this further is the
fact that the dma sets out an initial
deadline of March 2024 in just about a
year from now to have all of this
figured out
so to better understand this I want to
address some of the challenges that
arise in this interoperability setting
in today's ecosystem
two service providers will have made
completely different design choices so
for instance
one service provider could use phone
numbers for user IDs while another could
use email
one could use a signals double ratchet
algorithm for the n10 encrypted protocol
while another could use Mt Proto
and furthermore if some senders
malicious and sends an abusive message
then different providers might have
different policies in place for how to
handle this
so both recipients here might report the
same message but one provider does not
view this as a violation while another
does and therefore blocks the user from
their platform
and currently these different design
choices don't complicate messaging
but now with interoperability the
barrier between service providers are
going to be porous
and so unlike other interoperable
communication systems like SMS aside
from not being n10 encrypted we're
having to retrofit systems and protocols
together that were not originally
designed to be interoperable
and so one way to make this work is just
to completely give up on n10 encryption
in favor of interoperability but we
strongly Advocate against this and think
we can do better
so given the dma and its mandate
um and the timeline given here the goal
of our work and this talk is to
understand how can the existing
components of widely used n-10 encrypted
messaging apps be extended to be
interoperable
so to do this I'll first give a quick
overview of the dma's interoperability
requirements and I'll add a quick
disclaimer here that we're not legal
experts but our interpretation here is
Guided by legal discussions where
possible
next we'll look more closely at Three
core components of messaging affected by
the dma which are identity systems and
10 encrypted protocols and Abuse
Prevention and we'll describe some of
the solutions possible here
and next I'll describe some of the open
questions remaining in the setting
and also while at first glance this all
may seem like a major security and
privacy disaster I'll try to convince
you of the somewhat counter-intuitive
conclusion here that we came across in
this work that interoperability could be
a huge opportunity to actually improve
the privacy of end-to-end encrypted
messaging
so with that in mind let's take a look
at the Timeline set by the dma
this may the dma rules will begin to
apply then by this July potential
Gatekeepers will need to notify the
European commission that their service
meets a threshold at which point by
September the European commission will
need to designate service providers as a
Gatekeepers and so they'll use metrics
like market capitalization number of
users and annual revenue to determine
this
and then that brings us to March 2024 in
just about a year when designated
gatekeeper absolutely to enable
interoperability which is a fairly
ambitious timeline
now the dma's interoperability
requirements are mainly spelled out in
article 7 which says that these
so-called gatekeeper apps must provide
the necessary technical interface or
equivalent to enable interoperability
with another provider upon request and
free of charge
so the article also does make explicit
some of the basic requirements here
after designation a gatekeeper will need
to make text messaging and sharing of
media files interoperable between two
users
after two years they'll need to extend
this functionality to group messaging
and then after four years they'll need
to extend interoperability to voice and
video calls and while I don't have time
to get into all of the um
all of the rules set by article 7 there
are a couple of paragraphs that are
important here to understand
the first is paragraph three which
states that the level of security
including end-to-end encryption that the
gatekeeper provides to its own end users
should be preserved for cross-platform
messages
also only the personal data of end users
that is strictly necessary should be
collected and exchanged by
inter-operating providers
and finally paragraph 9 states that the
gatekeeper is allowed to take measures
to stop risk to Integrity security and
privacy of its services as long as these
measures are strictly necessary and so
we interpret this specific paragraph As
saying that Gatekeepers are allowed to
implement Abuse Prevention measures
but of course this raises questions
about what data should be kept private
from interoperating service providers
and what data are they allowed to demand
about end users in order to implement
Abuse Prevention measures what exactly
here is strictly necessary
so to address these questions and
challenges we're going to take a closer
look at these three core components of
messaging here
before we directly get into that I want
to First describe the design choices for
the system architecture which affect
these components so let's consider the
example here where we have Allison Bob
who want to communicate and Alice is on
the service provider Alice chat while
Bob is on a different service provider
bobchat
so there are two major ways that the
communication flows can happen here the
first is that Alice directly sends
communication to bobchat who then
forwards to Bob
and so
um we call this the client to server
model one benefit is that Alice chat
does not learn that Alice is
communicating with somebody on Bob chat
however has some drawbacks including
that Alice would need some way to
authenticate herself to bobchat as an
authorized user and also that Abuse
Prevention techniques like server-side
spam filtering might be more challenging
here
and so the other option is to have Alice
continue to send messages to Alice chat
which will then forward communication to
bobchat on Alice's behalf we call this
the server the server model and we use
this in our design
so there is the drawback here that it
leaks to Alice chat that Alice is
talking to someone on bobchat and to
bobchat that Bob is talking to someone
on Alice trap
however we feel that the benefits of
this model outweigh these drawbacks
including that Network level metadata
like IP address of users is not leaked
in cross-provider communication to other
providers
and additionally this will make
implementing certain Abuse Prevention
measures easier
so with that in mind let's take a look
at identity Discovery and
interoperability
let's continue with our example where
Alice wants to initiate communication
with Bob
the first step would be that Alice needs
some way to learn which app Bob is on
and so this would be called service
Discovery we won't cover this in our
talk but we do cover this in our paper
I'll also add that this is not required
by the dma but we think that this will
be important
so then to initiate communication Alice
will need to know we'll need some way to
retrieve Bob's keying material from
bobchat
and one really trivial option here is
just to have all users register with
every provider
so each provider knows everybody else's
identity including those on other
providers in this example then Alice can
just query her own provider Alice chat
for Bob's key dresses in the centralized
setting
of course this is a complete privacy
disaster since now each provider also
knows the user base of every other
provider so this also violates at least
the spirit of the dma if not the letter
of the law and we Advocate against this
so instead in our solution we have
senders make encrypted queries to the
other provider's identity system
here Alice encrypts a query for Bob's
key to Bob chat and sends this to Alice
trap who won't be able to decrypt and
therefore won't know what else is
querying for
Alice track can forward this query to
Bob chat who can decrypt retrieve Bob's
King material and encrypt that for Alice
which is then forward back to Alice via
Alice chat
so finally Alice can do Crypt to recover
Bob's King material and so the security
goals we want to Target here are that
Alice chat should not learn that Alice
is querying for Bob and also Bob chat
should not learn that Alice is the one
querying for Bob's keying material
next for the protocol layer
interoperability now that Alice has
Bob's King material Alice needs to know
how to encrypt the message in order to
deliver this to Bob
so what protocol does Alice use here
well one option that we've seen proposed
is to use a server-side bridge to
translate between protocols so Alice
would continue using the protocol as
specified by Alice chat but then Alice
chat would Implement a server-side
bridge to decrypt this communication and
re-encrypt it using bobchat's protocol
however this solution asks us to
completely give up on n10 encryption
since obviously now the providers can
learn the communication so obviously
this is not a solution that we want to
Target
another solution that's been that's been
proposed is that everybody uses a
standardized protocol
and while this might work in the long
term standardization can be a really
time-consuming process and we're working
with a very short deadline here of just
about a year
so we also don't see this as a solution
in the short term
the solution that we do see likely at
least in the short term is that
gatekeeper apps will fix a protocol that
other providers will need to speak
then non-non gatekeeper apps will
include the gatekeeper implementation in
their app through client Bridges
there are of course also some drawbacks
here namely that if an app has to
include an implementation of every
gatekeeper that they're interoperating
with this could get very expensive also
if some gatekeeper implementation has a
vulnerability suddenly this is spread to
lots of other apps potentially
but in the short term we still believe
that this is more likely the solution
here
I also want to add that our design
includes a sender Anonymous wrapper over
the base encryption protocol to hide
Alice's identity from Bob chat we
specifically use an extension of signal
sealed sender protocol so this means
that bobchat does not learn Alice's
identity except for when Alice is
initiating conversations with a new
message partner
and so our security goal here security
goals here are the more typical
messaging goals of confidentiality and
authenticity we also have some unique
privacy goals here as well which are
that Bob chat whenever possible should
not learn that Alice is the one
messaging Bob and also Alice chat
wherever possible should not learn Bob
is Alice's recipient
so finally we'll take a quick look at
the flows for Abuse Prevention and
obviously this is a fairly complex topic
and there are a variety of mechanisms
that could be deployed but we
specifically Focus here on more widely
deployed mechanisms so those are spam
filtering user reporting and block
listing
well so generally one option for Abuse
Prevention is don't do anything and
don't address it but we think Abuse
Prevention is valuable and should be
integrated with any designs that are
proposed as part of a holistic protocol
and while the other trivial option that
we've seen proposed is just to give Bob
chat all the metadata about senders from
Alice chat but this would be hugely bad
for privacy since now bobchat learns
about users on other providers so
instead we offer some designs that
involve Abuse Prevention mechanisms
while also trying to minimize this
metadata leakage
now they're specifically concerned that
this that with this interoperability
mandate there'll be an increase in spam
so having spam filtering in place will
be really important here
and many apps use server-side spam
filters to have the provider identify
traffic that is likely to be spam based
on metadata and block it
so benefit of our model is that we could
have Alice chat run the spam filter on
the sender's traffic before forwarding
it to bobchat Alice chat already knows
the metadata about users on its platform
and so
um it can use this to filter spam
without leaking extra metadata to
bobchat who might be concerned about an
increase of spam incoming to its
platform and for example based on The
dma Gatekeepers could require other
providers to run spam filters on their
end as a condition for interoperating
next for user reporting we use an
asymmetric message ranking scheme to
enable secure metadata private content
moderation
in our design Alice as part of the
ciphertext includes a message ranking
tag to authenticate the message so that
bobchat can act as a moderator
then if Alice's message is deemed
abusive by Bob and Bob wants to report
it he would send the contents of the
message the message franking tag and
that Alice was Ascender to bobchat who
could then choose to act on this and can
verify the franking tag so for example
bobchat could ask Alice chat to block
any messages coming from Alice to its
platform
and finally for Block listing the
overall flow would work similar to
reporting in our design we have Bob
reveal Alice's user ID to Bob chat so
that Bob chat can block the future
communication from Alice to Bob
overall security goals here that we want
to Target user reporting that's
verifiable
but we also want to minimize metadata
leakage here
so now that we've given some highlights
of the core areas in our design let's
look at some of the open directions left
here to explore
so the first question is how do we
improve the privacy of interoperable n10
encryption by reducing metadata leakage
in the setting
also how do we extend other protocols
used in n10 encrypted messaging like key
transparency for instance into this
interoperability setting and finally how
do we extend our framework analyzes to
group chats and encrypted calls which
will also be required by the dma
and so to conclude here interoperability
clearly presents lots of challenges and
open questions in the space
but rather than being a burden we can
actually use interoperability as an
opportunity to design encrypted
messaging with more privacy so what do I
mean here in particular interoperability
by Design forces surface providers who
we believe are non-concluding to split
up their view of communication and with
some work here we can make it so that
neither server has a full view of the
communication flow or user metadata
and so one idea here for instance is
that we could even make centralized
messaging more private by building
inexpensive anonymizing proxies using
interoperability
so if you want more details about our
work I have the link to our paper on the
slide thank you for listening I'm happy
to take any questions
[Applause]
hi so um so your proposal is that the
non-gatekeeper app has to kind of in
some sense embed the protocol of the
gatekeeper app within it in some sense
yeah so um so I saw this as this there's
like a promo code to this is that on one
hand the non-gatekeeper app has to now
be much more protocol agile in the sense
that the gatekeeper app can change uh
the protocol and the non-gatekeeper app
has to kind of update which could be
good because that means the
non-gatekeeper app has to be
crypto agile in a way that they have
been before so it's like a good thing on
the other hand the gatekeeper app could
just keep changing the protocol
which kind of could act like a denial of
service
so you see that's a you know the pro
what what have you thought about that
kind of agility issue in in your work at
all
so I think
um there is some
stipulation in the dma saying that
um like making it inaccessible for
non-gatekeepers to allow for this would
be violent in violation of the dma but I
mean that's an interesting question also
like how do you deal with this sort of
crypto agility where we could have the
gatekeeper app sort of implement these
kinds of measures so that it makes it
really hard for non-gatekeepers to
yeah exactly so
um
so that's an it's an interesting
question how do we deal with this I
think that this would be sort of in
violation of the dma and I think they
could sort of like bow it out in courts
most likely
um but
I mean I think the future long term
would be that we would have to sort of
standardize something so to sort of
prevent this but there are interesting
questions like this in the space
I'm afraid we have to move on so please
join me in thanking Julia again
[Applause]
the next speaker in this session is uh
Shu katsumota who will be talking about
meditative metadata protection for MLS
and its variants
uh thank you for the intro my name is
Shu this is a joint work with keita
Hashimoto and Thomas press so Yep this
is the title
so as everybody knows uh everybody's
using message apps lately and uh you can
see from the picture that
there's a lot of users now and the weird
thing in Japan everybody uses this uh
obscure app called line I think outside
of Japan not a lot of people uses it and
WhatsApp is more of the more popular
ones and within this community I think
signal is one of the favorite apps
um so this is just a recap on that
everybody uses messenger apps
so the thing is uh when we think about
messaging apps it provides a lot of
unique security threats
and one of the reason is that messaging
apps are mostly run on our smartphones
and that means that it's really deeply
tied to our everyday lives so once these
contents and metadata that are you know
run on our messaging apps leak then it
will leak a lot of our information
and not only our information but also
our you know friends colleagues uh
anybody's you know like relation to
these social relationships will kind of
uh leak too so in that sense it's a very
unique uh app
and also uh compared to other TLS based
Communications like just web browsing uh
messaging apps tend to last much longer
so it means from the Hacker's point of
view there's going to be a higher risk
of a security breach and also when there
is a security breach
um then this insecurity is going to
persist longer
and there's a lot of ways to kind of you
know collect data from these messaging
apps and one way is to do from a legal
means so this is a meta's transparency
report from last year for half a year
and as you can see uh it's really
growing the number of reports that the
government asks of meta is very uh
increasing and you can see that at least
75 percent of the time uh some data are
provided back to the government
so what this means is that well it is
well I mean it's not like they're trying
to like you know give all these
information to the government but we
have to be mindful that it's we're
always you know they can always leak our
information if needed
and also legal means are not the end of
the story because as some people may
know spyware are sold off the shelf by
companies and hackers so this Pegasus
spyware I think some people know uh was
a big incident
so this brings me to uh today's talk
which is about secure group messaging
and in particular a scalable one
so first I'll talk about a systematic
View and what I mean by a secure
messaging app
and then I'm going to compare signal and
MLS and show that MLS lacks some
features that signal has
and finally I'll show how to bootstrap
MLS to have this metadata hiding
property which makes it as secure a
signal
so let me first take a closer look at
messaging protocols
so Alice wants to securely send a
message to Bob and here we have to be
mindful that there has to be a server in
you know sitting in the middle and the
reason for this is that when you're
thinking about messaging apps nobody's
online all the time on their phone so
maybe Bob is offline
in that case well when Alice sends a
message there has to be some entity that
kind of stores it and relays it to Bob
when it comes online again
so you could think of two adversaries
here you know uh the network adversary
and the server adversary and what I mean
you know server adversary I'm not saying
that they're you know really trying to
uh look into your data but maybe they're
just looking at it and they're storing
in their server and maybe governments
can tell them to hand them over or there
could be a security breach so it's just
better to view them as a adversary in a
theoretical sense
so first of all removing Outsider
threats are really easy we just use
end-to-end encryption between the user
and the server so now nobody from the
outside world can see you know what the
communication channels are up to
also removing this Insider threat is
well it's actually easy too so we can
just assume that Alice and Bob shares a
secret key then um they can just uh
encrypt this message with this Orange
Box and send it and the server can't
decrypt it anywhere
and you can use like an authenticated
key exchange to share this uh establish
this key for instance in Signal we use
the x3dh protocol to do that
so at this point you know when I first
started doing uh and uh secure messaging
I thought end 10 encryption was all that
really matters
but this is actually not the case
because in practice as I think people
been talking a lot metadatas are also
used
and at least for this talk I Define this
metadata to be the identity and social
relationships of group of users
so in this diagram to be a bit more
specific let's say this MD stands for
this bit string Alice to Bob
and the reason why we require this
metadata is because when the server just
receives this you know orange blob of
ciphertext it doesn't know what to do
with it so when Bob comes online it
can't do anything with it without this
you know explicit metadata lying around
so Alice will specify in this bit string
that you know it's from it's for Bob and
this is how the server will be able to
relay these messages to Bob
but now what happens is that you know
the server learns who's trying to
communicate with whom
so we might believe that you know
metadata maybe that's not really
important but it reveals more than you
think so this was in a very nice uh news
article uh and a former NSA general
counsel mentions that if you have enough
metadata you don't really need content
and when you think of it in the very
extreme let's say you're a journalist
and you're talking to an activist then
that already explains a lot of the
content so maybe sometimes it might
undermine uh the fact that you're using
end-to-end encryption because those
relationships already defines what kind
of content you're talking about
and what's more scary is that metadata
collection can be done systematically
so there are these um services that
provide surveillance in technology for
tracking metadata so metadata are a
really important information that well
we want to hide
so as a conceptual contribution what we
did was that we tried to categorize
sensitive data that we want to hide into
three layers so here the first layer is
very very obvious so you know it's
supposed to be hidden from for any
end-to-end encryption secure messaging
service so the message has to be
encrypted we call that the first layer
the second layer is the explicit
metadata that I was talking about so
this has to well we believe that this is
required to you know like uh make the
server relay these messages
and the third layer is a bit more subtle
but when you think about it is as
equally as important as a second layer
but the third layer is this user server
authenticated Channel
and this implicitly leaks metadata
because when the user connects to the
server well the server gets to know
who's connecting so even if this you
know second layer information wasn't
there when this Alice uploads this
orange blob and Bob at a later Point
authenticate itself to the server and
retrieve this orange Bob then it will
learn that this blob was you know moved
from Alice to Bob so it will actually
learn the second layer information even
though
uh it's not explicitly there
and one might think that you can use
anonymous channels like Tor or VPN to do
this authentication on the bottom line
but you really can't do that because
um with Anonymous channels you can
perform a Dos attack so anybody can just
send garbage elements to Bob without the
server being able to catch who it was
doing
so when I when we talk about hiding or
sensitive data we want to really hide
all these one first two like third
layers and have a secure scheme
so in that line I want to kind of go
into the current state of secure
messaging
so signal protocol this is something
that everybody I think knows very well
is a gold standard for two user
messaging
and it's protocol and a variation of its
protocol are used within signal WhatsApp
Skype the list goes on
and you can also use the signal protocol
in the group setting
and here sending a message scales with
order n where n is the number of users
so this kind of uh sparked some interest
in the community that can we make this
more efficient because we don't want to
pay this order and cost
and this was the beginning of the
messaging layer security uh protocol MLS
so it is a scalable solution to secure
messaging
and there is an ITF that was driven by
academics and Industry and we're in the
final stage of being of standardization
and the draft versions of MLS has
already been used in Cisco's WebEx and
RingCentral
the main key feature of MLS is that it's
supposed to be secure as the signal
protocol and in Superior
and let me kind of like focus on what I
mean by in spirit
so let's take a closer look
and see what they do on these like first
second and third layers
so for Signal it covers all these layers
so you have this vanilla signal protocol
that only cover this first layer but
after a while we had sealed sender
private groups that eventually covered
all these third layers
so it's also secure against Network
adversaries
but for MLS
what we have right now is that we have
MLS plain text and MLS ciphertext so MLS
has two modes and MLS plain text
covers the first layer and this is where
most of the academic words on security
proofs have been
so we also have MLS ciphertext that
secures the second layer but when we go
up the third layer there's really no
protection there and this is completely
fine because it was out of the scope for
MLS but we have to really think about
this when we're going to deploy this MLS
uh and claim that it's going to be
secure as signal
so this is our main contribution what we
did is that we made MLS as secure as
signal by providing the first uh
protocol to secure up onto the third
layer and we also provided the First
Security uh definition security model
and a security proof to kind of
complement these constructions
and this work was done at CCS last year
so if anybody is interested in the like
the nitty-gritty details I recommend
reading the ePrint paper uh but let me
try to give a taste of our Construction
in the last three or four minutes
so this is our metadata hiding MLS and
the core idea is very simple we just use
this unique continuously evolving group
secret key shared among the group of
users so this is something non-existing
in signal
and this bootstraps any MLS like
protocol to be metadata hiding and when
I mean MLS like protocol so it doesn't
have to be MLS it could be all these
other variants that tries to optimize
mls in different aspects so it's not as
long as there is this unique group
Seeker key shared among the groups then
you can apply this idea it's generic
simple efficient and you can also have
post Quantum on top of that
and the overhead is really small so it's
only one signature per message so it
adds a lot of security with efficient
like with no overhand
so the idea is very simple at a high
level so let me share that with you so
we have a group secret key that's shared
among all the users what we do is that
we derive a signing key from this group
secret and we're going to give this
verification key to the server and all
these users on the left side when they
want to contact the server what they do
is that they just sign with this signing
key which is shared among all the group
of users
and they're going to do this over
Anonymous Channel
so the authentication part comes from
the signature and it provides like a
group membership proof
and this is how they uh prove that
they're a group member but nothing more
about their identity
and the good thing about this is that
since we're using this group secret key
that's based on this MLS layer we have
four secrecy post compromised security
we have all these nice guarantees we can
also rotate this group secret key and
hence rotating this uh signature keys to
and for those uh who knows about uh this
topic very well we there's a lot of
variants of MLS that offers better
efficiency
and one of the important one is using
selective downloading and our idea can
be applied to theirs by further deriving
secret permutation of group members from
this group secret key
and when I mentioned uh that this works
for any MLS like protocol we tried to
formulate that into the security model
too to make it modular so what we do is
that we provide an idealized MLs like
protocol and we view our group
membership proof as a wrapper protocol
so we can kind of slap on this wrapper
protocol on any idealized protocol and
we prove security of that so if somebody
wants to use our model then you could
just slap on your favorite MLS like
protocol into this idealized model and
you get a security out of that
so as a summary what we did is that we
tried to make MLS like protocol metadata
hiding by kind of making it more aligned
with what signal offers
and this is just the food for thought
but for the next step um I think once
MLS is finished with the standardization
there's going to be a lot of more
interest in using it in the real world
um however as you know everybody's been
talking there's always a tension between
regulation and end-to-end encryption
nowadays so right now this work really
focuses on how secure can we make it for
the users
but maybe we really have to think about
these content moderation to some extent
I'm not you know trying to Forfeit
end-to-end encryption but there has to
be some moderation maybe and in that
case we really have to think about
what's the right balance and all that
until then I don't think I will be able
to deploy this uh for everybody but um
I'm optimistic that there has to be some
nice balancing uh thank you
yes
do you mind going back to your slide
about your solution
yeah so um so I see once the group is
constructed that it would be metadata
hiding but isn't metadata leaked when
you actually create this group so
negotiation right so you can actually
use other protocols to hide that part so
when you're adding group of users in
this MLS like protocol you have this
welcome message which is actually a two
user communication and for that we can
use like some other protocols to perform
that part
what other protocols uh so Orca could be
one uh famous like a recent protocol for
Mucinex that does these metadata hidings
or you can also use signals protocol
like the two user protocol to hide this
you could use sealed sender for instance
so you could use those for the two user
communication and after that with the
group version you can use this group
secret key to perform more efficient
metadata hiding protocols
thank you
all right thank you very much
[Applause]
the final talk in this session is on
real world deniability in messaging and
will be given by Daniel Collins
uh okay hello everyone I'm Daniel and
this is uh joint work with Simone and
Lois at epfl
so this is about deniability so firstly
what is deniability so in essence uh to
quote Moxie Mallon Spike if someone
receives basically If you're receiving a
message you can be sure that's sort of
the person who sent it to you sent it
that is to say you have some
authenticity but crucially uh you cannot
prove to anyone else that it was
something you wrote
um so concretely take two parties Alice
and Bob who are communicating so let's
say Alice says something to Bob that Bob
not really doesn't approve of but maybe
wants to give this as evidence or
something to some kind of Judge to
basically frame house
so Bob sends the let's say his phone or
gives his phone to the judge so this
conversation would then be deniable uh
for Alice if um
essentially from the perspective of the
judge this uh this sort of conversation
transcript or whatever is given to the
judge could have been sort of simulated
by Bob or basically forged by Bob
um so this is kind of the broad
framework that we'll kind of consider
deniability in hereafter
um so in the cryptographic literature
it's claimed by sort of various
different types of Primitives and
protocols usually key exchange since the
90s
there's many flavors of deniability
depending say on the power of the judge
so I think perhaps since it's sort of
inception that there's sort of been some
debate about exactly how relevant
deniability is
so in this talk uh we'll basically sort
of uh look at a few little case studies
bothly from both from a technical
perspective but also a legal and sort of
social perspective to basically conclude
that sometimes there are problems with
deniability
and then we sort of propose a little
solution that maybe could be could help
to sort of improve practical deniability
but then again we ask is this even
desirable
good so we first zoom in on Signal so
we've heard a bit about signal recently
so this uses sort of xdh from the double
ratchet for messaging
um so indeed it's claimed that sort of
the key exchange protocol x3h provides
some deniability
so there's many recent works that
consider this uh so both the deniability
of signal itself are sort of exudates
itself but also sort of to construct say
more deniable or post Quantum secure xdh
like protocols
so in a recent work several authors show
that sort of indeed in some model that
xdh is deniable
um and that if x30h is deniable they
then have some kind of little
composition theorem that shows that sort
of double ratchet the messaging protocol
is also deniable so somehow therefore
the entire communication is denial
which is good
because that's what we want
but in practice there are several things
going on on top of the x3h and double
ratchet so things like multiple groups
sort of Multi-Device and one particular
thing is sort of the authentication
that's done with the server on top
so we basically we claim here that sort
of this use of authentication sort of
harms deniability and practice and this
would also apply to sort of basically
independent of the crypto somehow so if
you plug in these other schemes that
somehow deniability is also lost
so maybe let's see why
so we consider the regular
authentication first so let's suppose
Alice is trying to communicate with Bob
basically Alice will uh authenticate
with the server send a ciphertext to Bob
and also send the identity of the
receiver bulb to the server the server
then forwards that onto Bob
so the crucial thing here is sort of the
server assuming it's honest is
authenticating Alice and Bob
so let's now assume that sort of Bob is
trying to frame ours so if a judge takes
the phone from Bob basically the judge
can reasonably conclude one of two
things either that sort of if Bob
basically sort of acted honest honestly
and received this message from the judge
from Alice
um and so basically Alice communicated
or else Bob somehow modified his phone
and was able to make basically try and
frame Alice
so in some sense the deniability that
Alice attains is sort of dependent on
Bob's technical expertise which is a bit
sort of backwards but
and and of course this is worse if the
server's sort of colluding even more
with the judge in Signal's case this is
relatively good
and now with we then moved to sealed
sender so of course the idea of sold
Center is to try and hide the identity
of the sender that is to say Alice here
from the server so in this mode two
things are done uh firstly in order to
authenticate with the server without
actually directly authenticating with
the server Alice will get a token from
Bob somehow
um Alice will also get sort of a token a
sort of a certificate that Bob can then
check later that sort of certifies that
Alison did can communicate with Bob
um so when sending a message Alice will
send a token
um and alongside a ciphertext and the
ciphertext encrypts the certificate that
I just mentioned so the server will
check make sure the token's okay if
everything's good the ciphertext
forwarded to Bob
and then Bob can check that the
certificate looks okay
um so as a remark this is enabled by in
by default by between neutral contacts
so I suppose quite a lot of
communication on Signal
um and as we've seen this depends on the
network adversary so like the the sealed
sender functionality is somehow depends
uh it's security depends on the network
adversary's power
um but of course
um so again we have this sort of problem
where like if Bob gives that sort of the
phone to the judge let's say this like
if this mode of authentication is used
then if Bob sort of either provides the
certificate or sort of is honest and
used this mode of authentication then
the the only work like the certificate
basically binds Alice to this
communication or some kind of recent
communication because the certificate is
sort of attempt like sort of uh
periodically obtained from the server so
somehow this certainly limits Alice's
deniability
so in this sort of in this sort of
intuitive sense of deniability at least
it uh it's not the ideal situation
um but but even notwithstanding maybe we
should ask in practice like to what
extent is deniability sort of used
um so maybe this you know is okay so one
little case study that we look at is
um for uh court cases so very natural
sort of application of deniability and
so we look at some openly accessible
case data in particular in sort of some
cantons in French speaking Switzerland
so in the in the sort of uh in the in
the literature I guess uh there was no
mention of signal but we found several
mentions of WhatsApp
and in these cases we're only able to
find one sort of failed challenge to a
transcript communication transcripts
validity so in general communication
transcripts the consisted of screenshots
were also will often admitted and so on
so in terms of signal I think we've seen
a relatively recently that signals
appeared in some cases and high profile
cases um and as far as I know could be
wrong like it seems like the the
evidence has sort of been seemingly
successfully uncontested
so somehow this is a microcosm of sort
of deniability maybe not being used
everywhere in practice sort of in
practice at least in a legal sense
um so maybe why so
a lack of awareness about sort of the
notion of cryptographic deniability so
perhaps it's quite it's this somehow a
technical notion
um so in some cases in many cases
evidences doesn't really consider sort
of phone transcripts so trivially this
somehow doesn't apply
um and in the in a legal system somehow
sort of if someone's trying to forge
evidence then it's more of sort of the
sort of social barriers or sort of legal
barriers to sort of being able to to
pass off evidences sort of forged like
in particular due to like being illegal
so in some situations this is the case
um but we can then ask is can we maybe
sort of improve the State of Affairs so
can we make deniability sort of catch on
so indeed in some cases phones reveal a
lot to a judge
um and as we've seen sort of parties can
try to claim that they can sort of Tamp
the evidence has been tampered with or
that basically
um you know that the phone has been
tampered with uh but somehow this is
kind of a stranger a difficult argument
to mount because somehow you need to be
able to sort of modify your signal app
or whatever
so one solution is essentially to
potentially to basically you take the
sort of an app like signal and basically
you provide users with the ability to
sort of edit send and receive messages
so basically whenever a phone is handed
over for example this would basically
somehow deniability sort of evident from
this
uh so in a recent concurrent work
several authors actually perform sort of
a study where they basically try to work
out sort of perceptions of deniability
and practice and they basically in
particular gave some participants a tool
to basically do this and it seems like
it basically improves sort of
deniability in practice so so somehow
this complements sort of the suggestion
um
but one may ask do we even want
deniability so I guess firstly it could
be used to protect people so people that
we want to protect but of course it
could be also used to sort of to use by
like say powerful people to basically
you know protect them so somehow there's
always this trade-off and in proportion
to how much practical deniability you
have I guess both of both of these
things are kind of Amplified which
certainly it's problematic from you know
the side of the cons
so to conclude
um if we're if you're interested in
making a deniable system I guess there's
a few different things we can consider
so the first is sort of exactly what
kind of adversary we're defending
against so as we've seen perhaps a
cryptographic adversary and sort of a
restricted restricted sense is not
enough and even Within These maybe some
models are a bit too sort of
um strong
so notwithstanding for adoption purposes
phone numbers are useful but uh in in
the sense that you're registering sort
of with a with a service provider using
something like a phone number
um somehow this limits deniability
inherently
um it it seems that sort of a more
practical or explainable notion of
deniability is a much more sort of
useful thing than sort of a not to say
technical reliability is not useful but
then this
and of course the less information that
a judge gets the better so to minimize
metadata or metadata hiding as we've
seen is very important
and to take that one step further maybe
there are some applications where
anonymity itself may be more desirable
so maybe a deniability can be avoided
um and just to just to wrap up finally I
in we have an ePrint paper where
basically we propose a model sort of on
top of this kind of a not quite a
cryptographic model but something a
little less
um but I'd be very interested to hear
sort of and encourage some sort of
discussion or debate on this topic it
seems like it's cropped up a lot and
yeah it'd be useful to clarify so thank
you for listening
[Applause]
all right yeah thank you for um looking
at all the aspects regarding the
annihabilities there are really so many
facets to it for context I'm one of the
authors of the MLS protocol and we
discussed it a lot in length I've seen
the uh on the mailing list yeah
um so
and so I've always been on the side of
leaning towards you know saying that
deniability is a a good property to have
but it's actually incredibly complex
um it's it's certainly not black and
white and um
what you pointed out is that you you can
have it at the protocol level
and and that's true for the signal
protocol there is even an academic proof
now
um
but in practice
um it maybe doesn't give you
what you think it does you already
mentioned that on a layer above you can
sort of invalidate that already but even
on the protocol level
um there are two aspects to that so one
is that
for protocols who are not in Iowa like
pgp or you have a signature or MLS where
you also have a signature
um in most messaging systems the
ciphertext and the signatures are thrown
away after you receive a message
so they're not kept so in that sense
only in the plain text is kept and that
is completely deniable again
so you would have to assume that
um if somebody one and attacker wants to
frame a user they would have to use a
different client like a modified app
essentially yeah so I can I just to
interoperate so I guess sort of in
practice it seems like a lot of the time
sort of basically screenshots of what
appears to be plain text is admitted as
evidence to somehow
right that that anyway but but say for
example if um you wanted to frame
someone with a signature then you would
have to have a modified app that keeps
the signature after receiving the
message yeah so if if you
um start from that vantage point and you
assume that someone you know makes the
effort of downloading a modified app
um and then you can actually also attack
the single protocol on that level
because you can run it uh I think inside
an sgx enclave and then you have sort of
a proof that a message was received so
even though academically speaking the
protocol is perfect in terms of
deniability you can still attack it at
that level as well so um
at yeah after a few years of looking
into that my question is
um can we ever really achieve
deniability at you know all levels and I
don't know yeah I mean I've worked a bit
on the topic sort of more from a
theoretical perspective but I would
agree that it seems like there are
several sort of attacks that sort of
seem to crop up over time that basically
like for example yeah using a trusted
execution environment or sort of having
some kind of proof of like
non-participation or something like that
these things are always seem to be
possible so I guess in some restricted
circumstances it seems deniability is
sort of possible particularly kind of in
this offline versus online deniability
but obviously in the worst case I guess
not so I think it depends though
cool thank you that's all so I guess my
question is do you think we are over
indexing on um overly paranoid threat
models either uh court of law or the
judge or the like super secret I'm
running something in sgx because we've
seen these problems with say the U.S
presidential election Elite emails being
authentic or vcam with the French
presidential election
um
is it maybe a broader context of people
posting messages online or later
forensically data being found is that
does that change how you'd
view this
um
so
could you could you clarify the question
birthday again sorry so I mean the model
you put up in this talk is like you're
going to a judge oh yes it tends to be
the starting point I mean we used it as
the the survey in the paper too yeah uh
but the real motivation for these things
these days is people like hack and leak
operations information being posted
online yeah and you don't want it to be
trivial to verify yeah yeah so I guess
yeah sometimes it's not even relevant to
have cryptographic deniability so I
guess something like maybe Wikileaks it
seems like you know they sort of take
just like text and they have some kind
of internal sort of verification
protocol but then they'll post a bunch
of sort of dumps and even though there's
not signatures attached to it people
will still like it people still take it
as sort of true so maybe like
I get I guess it I guess it depends on
sort of exactly which cases you're
considering but I mean yeah I think I
think certainly there there is sort of a
a big mismatch between sort of the
theory and the practice on the sale
yeah I mean specifically we'll need to
wrap up here right but thank you very
much
[Music]
all right now it's time for a coffee
break and we'll resume at 3 50.
thank you