organization is is fun
so so this is going to be fun
hi everyone
all right so
um give a few people a few seconds to uh
settle down and the lights to come down
low
and uh all right so please welcome
stanislav
hi everyone my name is Dennis love and
my talk is about the current walk of
cfrg which we are sharing together with
Nick Sullivan and Alexa melnikov
so
um so Refugee goals are described in the
charter and the most important one is
about serving as a bridge between server
and practice providing good cryptography
to the item and taking all the best from
the Academia
broadly speaking our goals in
iitf and iftf Community are educating
iitf participants how to use and how to
build and security protocols with good
crypto provide cryptographic expertise
for iitf working groups and defy North
standardize existing crypto Primitives
for usage by iitf or other fdos
I have some history we have had some
changes of chairs and we've had two
selections one for elliptic curves and
one reason for pack
protocols both of them were quite
interesting and I will try to give a
hint about
the results a bit later
we published many documents some of them
are really white known and widely used
including elliptic curve documents
including some pod Quantum mechanisms
and some recommendations for security
usage of Randomness in security
protocols which is quite important for
everyone
but I'll try to focus on our current
work and our future work
uh so first of all we have a tight
connection with the iitf community
because most of our output directly fits
into iitf work most of all it's about
security area working groups and all of
our mechanisms are inclined involved
into the process of other working groups
and we develop their more standard size
existing based on requirements from as
working groups for example such words
like the operf hpk Apex are the things
that we develop for usage in the iitf
protocols
sometimes you have some specific
requests like
how much some key can be used in such
mode or how to use it or with elliptic
curve or pack should we use somewhere so
we try our best to give our
recommendations there
we have established a crypto review
panel it's a set of experts selected
experts who provide some security
expertise based on existing security
assessment of mechanisms
provide us Security reviews and provide
security reviews for working groups that
need them moreover as they are deeply
involved into the process of selecting
something like packs currently we have
11 members but
our area of expertise should be even
wider so we need experts at least in
multiparty computations and if you are
ready to volunteer please let us know
and we'll be happy to consider including
you in the panel because we have a lot
of important and difficult documents to
make in the future
we have also quite a tight connection
with Academia
all of our model mechanisms have
undergone a very deep security analysis
even if you just search safer G in a day
print you'll find a lot of security
papers dedicated to the mechanisms that
were developed or sanitized inside
several G like pegs hpkey usage limits a
demote Etc and every time when some new
item is proposed we require the also to
present the results about security
assessment and when is a document is
developed inside separency your security
results are always presented as Effigy
meetings
uh and when we have crypto European
expertise uh going on they always assess
the current state of security proof
security assessment of all mechanisms
there is a pain point an obvious pain
point that we are not as quick as
someone may want because cryptography is
hard and we try to assess mechanisms as
good as we
can so we try to have enough opinions uh
some deep research so some things could
be recommended from our group a little
slower than maybe
would be happy for the ITF
now we have some differences and
similarities between cfrg and other sdos
an example of iso working group 2 of
subcommittee 27 I would like to
underline some of them so I would say
that one of the most important audience
for ISO drafts ISO standard sorry
is a regulatory bodies seeking for
guidance for their areas some industry
specific bodies that seek for mechanisms
that are standardized all over the world
and the most important audience for us
for safer G are the protocol designers
who try to choose the best possible
mechanisms for the protocols for example
TLS and implementers of that crypto now
who want to make it as secure as
possible in the end implementations
because all of us want their crypto to
be properly implemented including all
stuff with prng
Etc
we have
we don't have any strict requirements
about maturity of mechanisms and like
ISO you can bring something new to this
FRG if it is
well studied if it is if it has some
deep research and we'll be happy to
discuss it and we don't need you to be
sanitized for three years or more on the
national level like in ISO and
um
is the main focus of our documents is uh
absence of any ambiguity so the
documents must be ready for implementers
to do everything right
and of course we have one main
similarity with any other sdo
making use of
Samsung with security all make a news
must be thoroughly assessed and the
security proofs must be reviewed by at
least someone
uh we have a lot of plans we have an
a set of upcoming documents all
documents on these slides the slide has
already
[Music]
and so some and now they are as a later
stages of publication so we hope to have
all of them this year uh to Primitives
uh one pack which was not selected in
the back selection process but was still
needed by uh some working groups uh to
specific signature schemes or save line
signature which was mentioned yesterday
for example threshold signatures and two
protocols via ref and the operfs again
which was mentioned yesterday
in one of the presentations
and we have some medium term work a lot
of documents to be made I have four
documents
under heavy assessment and in the active
phase of work with primitive modes of
parameters for example parent family
curves which is needed by everyone in in
iitf in several G so we really need this
document to be done uh
post Quantum mechanisms two
um short signature schemes based on
parents that's why we need verified
Liquors and two packs which are the
finalists the winners of our black
contest Juan opaque which was again
mentioned yesterday is an augmented pack
and the CPS which is a balanced pack
and the last slide uh
two important privacy preserving
protocols documents uh key blinding
which is more or less ready to be
published now as I think and vdfs we
have two important drafts about
recommendations of usage a of aeds one
of them is about a d limits so how much
data we should encrypt with your
favorite AED mode and about the overall
properties of AED algorithms so if you
don't know what is kick meeting AED or
something you should refer to this
document
and to drafts which is indicated are
indicated to making the implementation
of crypto even more secure using some
determinization or some including some
additional Randomness in the process and
we hope to finish them this year or the
next year
if you want to know more you can visit
our wiki page and you can always send us
an email using this address
and we have a meeting on Friday it is as
always it is the same time as the IDF
meeting so I will be will be in Yokohama
about one hour and a half with the train
so please feel free to come and just
register to the meeting of IDF meeting
and we always have a lot of work to do
and a lot of documents to review and we
also we always need new experts thank
you very much
[Applause]
all right thanks stanislav any questions
if not
um
let's see give people a second yes no
okay uh well thanks again and let's
invite the next speaker up
[Applause]
Louis burn down Louise hello um let's uh
Luis is here to talk about nist uh
specifically
multi-party threshold schemes which is
something that a lot of folks in this
room are interested in so uh please
welcome Louise
[Applause]
hello everyone a pleasure to be here uh
thank you Nick and the organizers for
inviting thank you everyone for sticking
around uh till the last talk
um I'm a magnetist as a contractor from
certifia and I'm here to talk about
um
a call on threshold schemes
uh let me start with a little bit of an
intro about some nist uh projects so uh
everyone here will know about pqc for
example that has been driven the process
for standardization of post Quantum
signatures and key encapsulation most of
you probably also know about the
lightweight crypto project which has
been driving the process to uh figure
out uh how to standardize some new uh
Primitives for authenticated encryption
with Associated data and hashing and
these two projects have been having a
standardization perspective a little bit
in contrast we have other projects such
as the Privacy enhancing crypto which we
can call
um to have a more exploratory nature it
looks uh particularly the Privacy
enhancing crypto project looks at
Primitives with some Advanced features
and functionality such as for example
morphic encryption NPC zero knowledge
proofs and then we have the multi-party
threshold crypto project that is has a
focus on how to implement diverse
cryptographic Primitives when the key
Secrets shared and that's what we call a
threshold scheme of course there are
very other projects in the nist crypto
group but here I want to make this
contrast between direct standardization
approach and a more exploratory nature
uh the topic of today's talk here is the
threshold call for short which is an
output of the pack and the multi-party
threshold crypto projects and in short
the goal of this call is to start a
process to gather reference material for
public analysis which aims at least in a
first phase to issue recommendations
these recommendations can be of a
technical nature like best practices and
other things like that it can also be a
recommendations in terms of processes
that will ensue in the future
the organizers also has to to give a few
updates on on this standardization so
before delving into the call let me just
mention in terms of pqc there's a name
to have draft standards on the selected
schemes by the summer of 2023 and
there's also a Current public call for
more post Quantum signatures the
submission deadline is in June 1st
there's Ray and Dustin here to whom you
can ask questions if you have any during
this Workshop there's also the
lightweight crypto project that in
February as selected ascon as a set of
as a candidate so it was the selected
candidate for uh to be from which to
standardize some authenticated
encryption with Associated data and
possibly hashing as well for constrained
environments there will be a workshop to
discuss that in June 21st and 22nd you
can submit by May 1st if you want to
present there and ref standards are
aimed for late 2023. as I already
mentioned the threshold call uh is is
already in a draft mode uh comments are
due in April 10th one of the the main
message I want to leave in this talk is
that please submit comments if you are
interested in this topic because they
can affect the final version of the call
and we aim to have a call finalized by
the end of 2023 and the submissions
deadline will be set hopefully uh around
the first semester of 2024. just a few
extra notes a nist currently has a
cryptographic public a publication
review board that has aim to review all
standards that are older than five years
review can mean just basically live as
is if they're still good or possibly
make technical changes or editorial
changes as another example we have fips
186-5 which was just published in in
February it's kind of the final version
of the standard net that specifies
various signatures including at the
essay and if you have curiosity about
other projects you can check online
okay so let's focus on the threshold
call for the rest of the presentation so
this is basically a call that is calling
for threshold schemes for diverse
Primitives and the call is organized in
two main categories the first one is for
selected standardized Primitives where
we have The Usual Suspects of signatures
public key encryption uh some Primitives
for key exchange also some block ciphers
and then perhaps more interestingly uh
mainly in terms of having a much wider
scope we are also interested in
threshold schemes for Primitives that
have that are that belong to schemes not
standardized by nist here we have a
particular interest in threshold
friendliness basically meaning you know
schemes that can actually be
thresholdized and possibly with Advanced
features as I already mentioned like
philiomorphic encryption for example ibe
identity based encryption I had not
mentioned it yet zero knowledge proofs
Etc okay let me show you a little bit in
more detail uh some of the scope of the
of this category so for category one as
I mentioned there are various types of
Primitives you organize them in five
subcategories signing public encryption
pairwise key agreement
symmetric Primitives like block ciphers
and hashes in terms of how they're using
their use for key derivation and key
generation as an example in the case of
signing you would have three families of
specifications from which to choose in
terms of submitting a threshold scheme
like at the essay cdsa and RSA and then
for because we are in category one we
already have the nist references from
where where the confessional schemes are
specified for example for public
encryption the obvious candidate
primitive would be RSA decryption
because that's where we have a secret
key but actually it also makes sense to
have a threshold scheme for RSA
encryption if we're talking about
encrypting a secret value I want to go
through all the table but just wanted to
leave it here and you can of course
consult the the actual document a little
more interested in talking about
category two so we have within it a
subcategory mapping each of the previous
subcategories in category one so again
signing PPE key agreement symmetric
Primitives in key generation but here
we're looking at Primitives not
standardized by this so for example if
we focus a little bit on signing things
that would be in scope would be let's
say in the second line a threshold
friendly Quantum resistance signature so
it has a a somewhat of an overlapping
um scope with the pqc project but here
we're looking to for to the actual
threshold schemes uh that would
thresholdize this Quantum resistance
signatures we can also consider
signatures that are not Quantum
resistant but that would have features
not present in in this standard so for
example threshold signature that would
be succinct and verify verifiably
deterministic and even if they're not
Quantum resistant you could still set a
good reference for what we might want
later on as Quantum resistant features
um
some interesting components here on
subcategories that are not Beyond those
first five so uh one on it's a category
on Primitives with Advanced features so
for example here we are actually
interested in receiving submissions for
threshold friendly Quantum resistant
philiomorphic encryption uh we're also
interested in hearing about threshold
schemes for identity based and
attributes based encryption of course
because these Primitives are not
specified in this standards a submission
also needs to specify the conventional
scheme a special category a subcategory
is on zero knowledge proofs of knowledge
this one is interesting uh in in two
ways one is that uh we accept
submissions for conventional zero
knowledge proofs they don't need to be
thresholdized as long as they are
motivated in terms of helping
um other threshold schemes or somehow
relate to The Primitives in other
subcategories but of course we're also
interested in threshold versions of it I
think for example of a secret uh secret
that is secret shared across across
parties and then now all the parties
want to get together and collaborate to
produce
as your knowledge proof about something
about that key let's say that the public
key is correct for example
we also have a subcategory for gadgets
which basically means building blocks
that can be helpful across a number of
the other threshold schemes here is an
example garbled circuit but there are
many others including commitment schemes
oblivious transfer etc etc
um it's a big table you can consult it
later on as well uh now I really want to
take the opportunity here to mention
what is the kind of interaction that
we're looking for to have from the
community in particular because the only
way that this project can go move
forward successfully is with interaction
from the community so we have three
particular phases one of them is about
feedback and the first opportunity for
feedback is within two weeks and just as
a few examples we welcome comments about
the structure and the scope of the call
for example you can let us know if it
makes sense for some some Primitives to
be in scope or are there any missing or
something along those lines it would be
interesting to hear about your ideas on
compatibility or incompatibility between
Quantum resistance thresholdness and
other Advanced features and of course
you're also welcome to make a number of
technical comments on security
properties that we should be looking at
questionnaire recommendations and other
suggested requirements that we could
possibly add or remove from the call
then eventually we will have a second
phase for concrete submissions
submissions are specific fighting the
call you know they have a structure in
particular they have a structured
specification with a number of sections
including security analysis the
submission requires an open source
implementation evaluation
Etc and then we'll ensue a third phase
of public scrutiny of submitted schemes
where you know a bid that you submitted
or not submit we will welcome evaluation
comments from the community and of
course this as well as in the in the
previous phases can of course impact the
subsequent recommendations that we're
looking for
some assorted notes about the threshold
call uh really assorted
um in terms of submission focuses
um a submission can have can cover a
family of threshold schemes so you can
submit actually something
that covers various subcategories uh one
particular aspect on Securities that
we're looking for active security so
we're explicitly not interested in
schemes that are only passively secure
if you think otherwise also feel free to
submit comments about this in terms of
synergies we welcome very much
submissions of schemes that might be
under development in other
standardization bodies or being
developed by Community efforts again the
aspect of reference material is that
this is not a competition it's important
to emphasize that it's not a competition
with the aim of selecting a winner after
a first period of analysis but of course
the fact that some schemes are submitted
will create a good public exposure and
can of course influence future processes
and in terms of of clarification
we're really expecting that the process
overall will actually clarify a number
of interesting aspects about system
models what is what are the right
security formulations that we should be
looking at for threshold schemes Etc I
have this kind of written out as well
but I'll leave that for offline review
uh just want to emphasize again public
feedback within two weeks by April 10th
this will help improve uh the final call
um there's this is last slide just to
mention there are a number of online
resources so of course the the
publication is online public comments
should be sent by email
and you have the websites of the two
projects including forums in particular
the form has not been very active namely
if we compare it with other projects but
we hope that once this period of public
feedback uh ends and we publish the the
all the comments that we received we
really hope that this will lead to some
constructive and healthy discussion
online
um thank you very much for your
attention and I'll be glad to answer
questions
all right anybody brave enough to ask a
question before the end of the day
if not another thanks for Luis and
thank you to
thanks to all the other speakers today
and we'll see you tomorrow real world
crypto
[Music]