all right you can say something action
ok action let's start building burp
extensions I'm actually gonna talk a
little bit more than just building Burke
extensions
there's a little bit more to this than
that so first of all who my senior
security consultant with secure ideas
and for some reason my presentation is
let's keep going I've done a lot I have
a fairly extensive background in
software development and then I got into
security several years ago and I can't
say I haven't looked back since I
haven't really wanted to go back into
pure security software development but I
now use those skills to build out tools
scripts so on and so forth to make
things better for us and that's
yeah open source contributor so this is
part of the reason why I have this talk
is having to write burp extensions co2
is one correlator is my latest one which
is I think it's pretty cool i also have
contributions into laudanum mobis sack
samurai web testing framework 33 was
just released it was earlier this week
or last week so I've done a lot of that
sort of thing and other than that run
our musician and probably the most
important point point on the slide is
that I am a home brewer as well that's
what I do for fun so this site has no
title tools what I want to do is
actually i'm talking about tools think
about first of all i think it actually
recognize most of people in this room
why the aren't there more people at
our sweet talk that's what I'm saying I
don't know people realize what the
you can do with this tool I don't know I
mean that's what that's what we're
talking about we can go get more people
I will dude burp suite is hot yes maybe
I should have in your title what the
can you use maybe then would have
filled through a little better yeah so
tools what I wanted to do is start off
with just think about all of the tools
that you use when you're conducting pen
tests and where those tools come from
and probably some of the tools that
you're thinking about are on this slide
here somewhere so the next question is
what do all of these tools other than
the fact that they are used for pen
testing what do they all have in common
and the answer is they're all free or
more people coming in okay let me just
back up one side what we're talking
about is the stuff that we do for pen
testing here's some of it right seeing
some of these tools before they're all
free or they have free versions or
community versions and that's really
what I the crux of this this talk is
about is a lot of what we rely on to do
our jobs is free stuff we like free
stuff right no you don't like free stuff
okay so we like free stuff and but it's
not really free i mean it's it's free to
everyone who's using it it's free as in
beer but somebody has to put in all the
effort right we have to actually get
down we have to figure out how we're
going to write that code that's going to
automate this test or how do we write
this script and so on and so forth in
the case of this talk how how we're
going to write a burp extension that's
going to solve some problem for us so
that's basically what I wanted to get to
so let's start off with birth as anybody
everybody know what purpose yeah
everyone's on their head good so I don't
really have to talk about this slide too
much there is a free version of birth
which is good we like free it's an
interception proxy does a bunch of
things the one that we're going to talk
about is the one at the very end the
last arrow there an extender right
not co2 new extender is part of her so
what I'm saying you can build you can
you can build extensions in burp on the
free version camp and they have this
thing in there and i'll show it
afterwards the app store which is
basically a marketplace although
everything on there is free for
extensions and it will tell you on the
extension which one's only work with the
pro version and which work with both the
free and the pro version okay so burp
extensions if you're going to write a
bit extension fortunately you have
options you don't have to only know Java
you can write them into Ruby if you
really want to I don't know if we have
any Ruby people in the room I don't I
really dislike Ruby so ya know I hate
dealing with gems every time I install
anything with Ruby I don't know if you
run into this is always yeah you got the
wrong gems installed or some point 1 1 2
3 2 a yeah so now I got to figure out
how to fix this thing and yeah I hate
Dillon threw me python is an option you
can it has a jivonne wrapped around it
you do have to actually download jai
thumb it's a java version of python
basically because earth itself is
written in java so that's the reason why
these other things they work in sort of
a container inside of java and then
there's Java itself and I'm going to
focus on Java for a couple of reasons
one is burp itself is written in Java it
inherently the it works better with
extensions than it does with these other
languages there are some issues with
them and you'll you'll actually see if
you look at the port swagger website
home of burp you'll see there's
instructions on there for making this
work better with Python or Ruby which
involves actually increasing your memory
heap because they tend to actually use a
extra memory and not release it ever so
it can be if you're just running one or
two and it's not not usually a problem
but if you're running a lot of Python or
Ruby based extensions it can
actually exhausts all of the memory on
your in your burp instance and make it
crash so that's not good so all right so
what we're going to be talking about is
is Java and to do that hang on second we
need to use I just realized one of my
slides is out of order it's free Java is
free that's good I have I built a test
case here so this is a scenario it's a
mechanism that's similar to something
I've run into a couple of times recently
on Penn tests and is the mechanism isn't
username harvestin I just made it into a
familiar form the mechanism is actually
a nonce type of mechanism where you
can't simply send requests through a
fuzzer like burp intruder it just won't
work right out of the box so we have to
come up with a way to solve that problem
so Emily actually this would probably be
easier if I just show it so hopefully
everything just works on here so yeah
can everyone see that
so I have this this login screen here
and if you type you type in a username
and a password
they're okay there we go it woke up so I
typed in a user that doesn't exist in
the system and it comes back with this
message no user session no session you
use your session with that user okay if
i type in i have a test user account
that i've created in here so this user
is in the system and if you put that one
in you actually get a different message
so this looks like a very classic
username harvesting type of flaw right
so let's pop over to burp i'm running
everything through burke and we'll take
a look and see what's happening there's
the problem okay for some reason I don't
know why but hope seems to think that
the JSON stuff has tits it's a script
response I'm not sure why so what's
actually happening when I did these two
logins we see that the first request
let's go back to ya so here's the first
request that I sent with user equals
user and what it's doing is it's making
its making a request for a nonce and
then on a second request when it logs in
I don't know if you can see this but the
what's being submitted is the username
again the password and the nonce so on
the nonce recently there's the nonce
around the response comes back as a JSON
some kind of strength question
I rent work I don't know very much about
it but I flavor with recently yeah I
always do intercept and I'm really noisy
websites it's linked as I put forward
yeah been able to just grab what you're
grabbing we're not having to interact
and it slows it down you know
yeah so it's a great question so when
you're using burp suite want to see
right click copy is girl can replay and
right in which case you're actually
using the wrong tool inside a burp
there's a there's a different way to do
that and I'm actually going to show that
right now so first of all when the first
thing you do anybody does when they get
into burb once they know what they're
doing is they turn off the intercept
over here there's intercept you'll
notice that it's off and if you go over
to options and scroll all the way down
to the bottom there's a enable
interception on startup and you can
change that to always disabled for some
reason that's the default that the
developer put in there and has never
changed despite everybody telling them
that that's not the way that you should
be using this tool so so what you want
to do instead is capture your history
like I just did here okay and you notice
that I mean there's this target tab
that's the other thing too so this gives
you a site map of what's going on it has
its use but most of the time i use just
the history tab because everything
happens in order that here it's a lot
easier concert without me having to
forward and drop yeah it captures it
here in this history lot bug so now you
have everything yep everything that
every requests that proxies through i
have these actually filtered right now
so I'm not showing CSS or images or
anything else so it's a filtered version
of that list but it captures every
single request and response that goes
through the proxy and then what you can
do is you can right click and send one
over to repeater ok and the repeater
that's where you can modify request and
send it and get a response sent to get a
response the browser is no longer part
of the equation right you can just
modify the raw request so that's what
you probably want to be doing so in this
case here
if I hit go on this it responds back
with the knots if I go again it responds
back with a different knots so we can
see there in the response rate so
question is we have a username
harvesting fall let's say that we have a
list of users and we want to run this
list through and see how many these
users are actually in the system so how
are we going to do this there's a couple
of ways one is you could pull up Python
which is probably what I would normally
do in this situation it's just write a
quick python script to do it but I
wanted to show something with a birth
extension so we'll do that so and
actually before I get into that let me
just for completeness I'll show the
login same thing I'm running it through
repeater but I haven't changed the nun
so it's going to say no user session
with that user and even if i put in test
for the user which we already tested on
the actual interface and i hit go there
i'm still going to get new user session
with that user so unless we get the
knots correct it's going to always
respond the same way and that's not what
about what we're looking for we want
something is going to tell us whether or
not the users in system so
to do that
so to do that we're going to write a
burp extension how do you do that first
you need to pick your language Ruby
Python or Java is what we're going to do
so for Java best to let their to use is
intelligent IntelliJ the reason there's
a couple reasons for this first of all
this is the tool that ports burger uses
to build burp I asked them about this
this is this is their integrated
development environment so we know that
it works it provides an easy
drag-and-drop way to make interfaces for
those of you who have seen co2 before
that entire interface was built
drag-and-drop I didn't have to write any
custom code for that it was actually the
interface Park was pretty
straightforward hooking up all the logic
took a little bit more effort but the
interface wasn't too bad so we want to
do it that's that's one reason sep one
is they have a free community version
and we like free so it's a commercial
tool the community version works just
fine it's not disabled in any way that
prevents us from writing burp extensions
so works well so the first thing we want
to do is we create a new project in
there and then once you create the
project so I'm actually calling this one
a nonce payload processor and I'll get
to why we're calling it that shortly but
what we need to do is we need actually
include the Rope libraries now if you're
writing this if you're writing it as a
Python or I don't know about the Ruby
actually but I know for Python you don't
have to go through this type of step you
can just start writing your Python
script and you just subclass the same
classes that are in the API the API
doesn't change no matter what language
you're using so but anyway what we'll do
in this case so we create a project and
then we what we need to do is add an
additional module because in order for
everything to compile it needs to be
able to see the burp api's
alright so what you'll do is you'll
create this other module call it burp
epi or whatever you want and then hook
that up so that it basically your your
structure looks like this window down
here afterwards so you have two modules
one is the interfaces and then the
second one is the your actual code in a
rate which is right now is empty now
where do we get the baby is from there
actually insider that's the easiest way
to get to them so you just go to the
burp extender epi stab and then you'll
see down at the bottom I don't know if I
could yeah there we go down at the
bottom you have two buttons one is for
the javadoc files so you can save those
locally and the other one is safe
interface files so what you'll do is
take those save them into that burp API
folder and it's best practice to do this
each time because the API is changed
with the version so you want to make
sure that you have the latest version
once that's in there you open up your
module settings I know this is kind of
technical but if you're looking to do
this later on you can go back to this
video and figure out how so open the
module settings and what you want to do
is go into the the adds a little bit
hard to see here the nonce payload
processor module inside of intelligent
and make sure that your burp ap is our
our dependency of building your your
actual extension
okay so the reason we do this is that
way everything compiles that means your
extension can actually see all of the
interfaces that you're using from birth
so one more step in the configuration
then it gets on to the actual fun stuff
so the last thing that you want to do is
go into the artifacts tab this is still
under the module settings and and
basically set it up so that it creates
down here you have this build on make
you want what you want to do is you want
to create a jar file that's the artifact
that the jar file is what you're going
to upload to burp so that it has the
extension so that's how it's packaged so
you can once you set all of this up
inside of IntelliJ it basically run make
it automatically compiled everything
creates the jar file and it's ready to
import into birth so okay so taking a
step back let's think about the problem
that we're trying to solve now that we
have our project structure in place and
the problem is we want to be able to
capture a nonce so that we can submit
that into a login form so we can
determine whether or not the user exists
so to do that we're going to need some
help from we need to have some way to
plug into it so they have these
interfaces that have been set up in the
API and that the the main one that we're
going to use is this one here I burp
extender so if you're building a burp
extension it's weird that is called I
burp extender not I burp extension but
that's what it is so every every
extension implements this interface here
in all it all it has is one method on
their register extender callbacks
and I'll get to what that looks like in
just a second some other important ones
to consider the actual callbacks
interface so this is what lets you
interact with burp itself get into
calling all the tools so on and so forth
also if you want to write anything to
standard out or or to the output with in
berk that's what you're going to call
you also have your helpers so that's for
actually creating manipulating requests
or requests and responses inside a burp
as well so there's also some decoding
and encoding routines setting scanner
insertion points and things like that so
miscellaneous functional have
functionality in there so those those
are basically that's all there is for
the main support classes so you have
extender you have callbacks and you have
helpers then the types of things that
you can actually do with an extension so
you might be thinking okay well what
kinds of problems can i solve you can
plug into everything that's there so all
of the tools that are available inside
of there's ways to interact with those
programmatically so we can interact with
with the actual proxy itself so
basically we can get every single
request and response that goes through
the proxy we can get a handle on that
and do something to it change it
manipulate it analyzed it may be log new
issues we can generate payloads okay so
I've done some of that before you won
co2 has a generator in there where you
can pass it a a list of user information
and then it'll start fuzzing off that
list and create like passwords it'll do
leet speak type of insertions and places
and stuff like that so it's pretty cool
and then there's a cable processor which
is taking an existing payload and making
some changes to it and that's actually
what we're going to use for this problem
a few other things you can do you can
interact you can add issues so that's a
pro version only right so it has the the
scan issues on there so you can actually
create new issues you can also add
editor tabs change some of the behavior
of the tabs that are there you can
manipulate session handling logic as
well so can do a bunch of things so
payable processor so we have it has two
functions on there this is directly
snapshot off of the API dots and get the
name of the processor and then it's pay
process payload and it takes three
values here and it returns a byte array
so basically what we're the only parts
of this we're going to use is we're
going to take the current payload so
that's going to be the username that
we're passing into the function and then
what we're going to return is the knots
so we need some way to fetch that knots
and the easiest way to do that is to
make an HTTP request and just so happens
that there is a function inside of the
callbacks for making HTTP requests using
Burke's own HTTP sack so you can just
use that directly
and I think what we'll do is take a look
at what that looks like so here is
intelligent and I know it's probably
very tiny on that screen it is I don't
know if there's any way to make this
larger now if it just zooms the whole
window what's that he doesn't give out
all this I don't want to give up all the
secrets hey yellow alright so i will
briefly explain what's on here and I
well I think what I'll do is I'll just
make this available afterwards so you
guys can take a look at the actual
source code so what I what I did is is I
took a request one of the requests that
we're sending to the nonce basically
pasted it in here as a template and this
is the request to get the nonce okay
then i did in register callbacks just
basically said hey I want to register a
intruder payload processor and this is
it here and then down here is that
process payload function and all I'm
doing with that is it's taking the
username so that current payload
parameter that first parameter that i
showed in the function and it's actually
making constructing that request for the
nonce sending it out getting the
response taking the non set of the
response and then returning that as the
new payload so it's basically swapping
out a user name for a nonce
and that's all it's doing so how does
this look inside of burp I actually have
one set up so for those of looked at
burp before sometimes you're wondering
you know the attack type there's all
these different types of attack types
remember this so the first one on their
sniper is the default that's what we
almost always use this is one of those
situations we need to submit the user
current username a password and the
knots which is actually the username
using our payload processors that's been
changed into a nonce so we have a
situation now where we need to initially
submit the user name twice in two
different positions to do that we use
pitchfork right so now here's a use case
for using pitchfork is the first one
I've ever found it might mean how the
first one but they can use pitchfork so
on the on the first payload set I have I
just put together a list of usernames on
the second payload set it's the same
list the user names because that's how
pitchfork works as you want to have
pairs of things submitted in this case
here I want the same ones because the
second one I'm going to change into the
nonce
sighs no have you they're huge yeah I
love tools but eventually something's
going into more purples in their
processes well yeah and here's the thing
if you run into a case where let's say
you're you're pulling payloads off of
some other tool or something so it could
be an infinite list that's when you want
a payload generator because you can make
that memory efficient so that it doesn't
generate an entire list first it just
generate some as you need them I know I
have it's got 10,000 items on this list
so and now let me go and I'll just
remove this and add it back in so you
can see it so the payment processor for
the second one all you do is is you add
the payload processing and then there
are a bunch of different options here so
if you enter ever it out the situation
where you need to do some type of
encoding or something to a list this is
where you do it and at the very last one
here is invoked Burt burp extension and
oat mine's not there actually hand it's
not there because we actually need to
add it in so on the burp extensions I
need to go find my file which is Ayano
find in a second
it's buried
building burp extensions every are
there's the jar so I went and found the
jar that I I created and hit go and
there it is so it's loaded alright and
so now it shows up on my list here at
the bottom and then it also shows up
inside of intruder so i can go i can add
the payload processor vocal rip
extension knots payloaders what i called
it because in burp everything ends in ER
i don't know if you have a ghost so i
try to stick with it so now we have that
so now if i start the attack you'll see
that i have to pay loads one the first
one else going slowly because having to
make these extra requests the first one
is the from the first part of the
pitchfork you know how I putting in two
lists the second one is after the pay
Lisbon process and so that's why we have
the nonce on there
and of course we have a couple with the
length coming up differently and I don't
know if you can read those but the user
names are Kevin and Jason's those are
the users in this system completely
random yes so right so that's that any
questions other than you know you can
actually see the code or anything like
that so much too small i will post this
afterwards along with the code samples
you take a look at that actually how
that actually really worked one other
thing i want to show because we have a
little bit extra time which i was hoping
we would is correlator I know probably
something you've seen the co2 stuff
before correlator i think is actually
extremely valuable tool at making us
more efficient at what we do oh wait I
think I actually have some slides on
this let me let me switch over to that
is the pro version worth the money you
spend yeah absolutely if I get for your
mom well yeah if you actually do pen
testing absolutely right off one client
yeah exactly so it I think it is the one
of the biggest comparisons you see out
there is zap versus burp zep so awesome
free tool and it is very good as well so
a lot of it is personal preference i
find verb to be a little bit more
intuitive it's easier to kind of switch
between the tools so you can take
payload or not POS you take requests and
responses from one tool and get them
into other tools very quickly and easily
so i find i work with it more
efficiently than i do is out
yeah yeah true it doesn't crash as
frequency so the others are all good
reasons and I mean if you don't if you
don't do actual pen testing very off and
if you're just playing around with it
obvious whatever then immediate isn't
worth it but for 300 bucks if you do any
pen testing it is in life that so yeah
right some extensions to do the stuff
that it doesn't have it's possible I
guess so correlator basically what it
does is it's automatically automatic
analysis of the parameters and and when
am I say parameters I mean everything so
post parameters get parameters cookies
basically everything that burp
understands as a parameter and the types
of things that it recognizes is anything
as URL encoded it will decode it
automatically for you base64 encoding
it'll recognize if something looks like
a path and say hey yeah it looks like
this this is a path HTML XML fragments
email addresses Social Security numbers
if you see something that looks like
that one that's not on here is credit
cards although I seem to be currently
having an issue with the it's supposed
to run the LUN algorithm on there to
actually determine if it's a valid
credit card number and I'm not one
hundred percent sure it's working and
it'll currently also decode big eye peas
cookies so if it runs across the big IP
cookie it'll decode that into the IP
addresses so all of this stuff it
basically does automatically and I
eventually want it to do more now the
purpose of this isn't okay I'm doing a
quick little test let me just run it
through this question what's the big
so big-ip is basically does the load
balancing yes that's the word I'm
looking for load balancing so it does it
through this cooking mechanism but
there's a a known flaw in most
configurations of big-ip that I've seen
anyway where the the internal IP address
i think is the internal IP address is
exposed inside the cookie it's in an
encoded format but being encoded not
encrypted there's a way to decode it and
then you can actually see the IP
addresses so just it's just an
information disclosure vulnerability
it's not a huge deal but it does give
somebody an idea if okay this is what
the load balancer is on the internal
network mm-hmm yep so normally well you
would use correlator is if you're
testing a whole bunch of websites or if
you're testing like a very large complex
website that has a whole lot of stuff on
it and I'm going to change my scope here
and I just ran some demo stuff through
it earlier so that we could kind of get
an idea of what it looks like some of
the output and that's basically all I
did so all you do all it does is it kind
of goes through everything that you've
marked as in scope for your test and
that's why you saw me pop over to the
target tab for a second I changed the
scope so everything is marked in scope
it goes through all of those requests
looks at all the parameters and then it
starts figuring out what's what and then
it gives puts all in a nice table for
you now in this case here you can still
see that all of this over here still
looks in its it all in its original form
so that may not be helpful it does have
the format down here of what it's
figured out it is but then I actually
just figured recently hey why don't we
just go ahead and do the decoding right
there in the table so so now it will
actually decode those values right there
on the table if you click on one of
these like let's say foo for example
this one here says 75% of the instances
that it ran across
we're md5 so it's probably an md5 and if
you go down onto the details here it'll
actually lift them off all the unique
values you can list every single one if
you want but it'll list off all the
unique values you just click on one of
those and you can see it'll walk through
how did it figure out that this is md5
and it says but basically it looks like
a hex string and so length 32 which is
commonly md5 some of the other ones this
one here you see the starting value on
that it's this huge string and I've
actually run into stuff like this before
it's this huge string of gobbly gook and
it figured out on its own hey this this
needs to be base64 decoded then you were
all decoded than URL decode it again and
then finally it looks like something
that's a printable string alright so the
n values may be interesting in this case
also I paths it would it would determine
if something looks like a path or in
this case here we have something that
started off as base64 encoded block of
stuff and it figured out hey this is
actually XML or HTML I mean it looks
that's what it looks like to me so and
then it decoded it for us too so and it
is turns out this is in HTML fragment so
this type of information if you're
looking at a huge test being able to
break it down like this very quickly you
can separate the interesting bits of
information from the probably not so
interesting bits of information very
quickly it's a table it's all sortable
all the tabs you can you know so if you
have a really long list you can say ok
let me just look at everything that
looks like an md5 let's look at all the
shell ones let's look at everything that
looks like an XML fragment because
that's a good spot for injection
possibly right if you have XML fragments
going in let's see if I can put a script
tag in there
so that's it has a couple of other
features too you can highlight where
something is on the request you can
right click on things to say hey I want
to send this request over to repeater
you can if you have a one case where
this works like let's say you have a
bunch of md5 s in there that you think
are useful hashes you can right click on
that and copy that to the clipboard and
then paste it into some other tool where
you're doing like cash lookups you can
do that sort of thing that they're
pretty quickly changed so that's
basically it so that's that's correlator
that's the latest extension that I've
built along with an interface and
everything so I do want to kind of put
in a plug for that I don't think it's on
the bap store yet although I asked for
it to be on that decision you just email
them yeah for what ya know it's it's a
folk it's a company they I've actually
interacted with two different people so
I know for sure that there's more than
one here know what well yeah it could be
I was gonna say one is male the others
female but three's company
so that's that's my spiel and I mean
really what this is is hopefully getting
people somewhat interested if you see
any issues with plugins or tools as
you're using them try to be I mean first
of all let the author know hey
something's not working right i'm not
sure why I'm latest version seems to be
broken but be polite about it too and
realize that most of the time most of us
are actually doing this on our own time
in addition to the whatever 60 80 hour
weeks that we're pulling so question
I'll give you recognition so yeah I'll
give you a big big thanks on Twitter or
something but yeah yeah any questions
and good so you see
honestly collaborate what do you think
you're going to expand in my or do you
feel like that it's constantly well I
would like to do that's a good question
so how can I where I want to go with
collaborator next I think I want to
improve on what's there one of the
things I'm really looking for feedback
if anybody is doing a pen test and you
run into some kind of encoding that it
doesn't handle do let me know and and
let me know what the decoding is that
you need it to to figure out because
that's the sort of thing that I I'm only
adding functionality as I run into any
pen tests so exactly the submission
function yeah no I don't need that but
yeah that's that's a great day so yeah
if you do if you if you use it and you
find anything there's any the same thing
with co2 to Thanks