alright so the title of my talk here is
software vulnerability discovery and
exploitation during Red Team assessments
I just kind of realized that this is
actually the longest least sexy name for
a title ever so I'll have to bear with
me hopefully it'll know please approve
me worth it see give a little background
about myself I work here in Charleston
and I'm a Red Team operator our job is
pretty much to you know simulate
real-world act you know attacks against
our customers networks so that hopefully
we can find vulnerabilities and tell
those to our customers so that they can
patch these I've been doing this
probably for about three or four years
now so our job continues to get a whole
lot harder as our defenders our blue
team is getting a whole lot better
because of that we started looking to
other possible ways that we can have
success on our team and actually be able
to find some of the harder avenues that
maybe some of the more advanced
attackers are starting to use nowadays
and one of these areas that I've been
looking into a lot now is actually
vulnerability research so we're you know
looking for actual bugs in some of the
software running on the systems that
we're running across and one of the main
reasons we're doing this is because a
lot of our assessments are actually a
long-term persistent red team
assessments so we might actually have
you know access inside a network
anywhere from six months to a year and
once we're inside the reason we're in
there is we're also trying to test them
for you know your internal
vulnerabilities and so we usually have
to set up persistence instead the
network and then our biggest goal next
is usually try to move laterally
throughout the network unless so that's
kind of where this all comes into is
we're starting to look for services and
these types of things that might have
vulnerabilities that we could use to
propagate throughout the network
all right so I guess the the where to
start on this is kind of I just want to
present just a lot of the tools and the
ways that we start looking for these
targets and a lot of these you guys are
probably pretty used to and so a lot of
this talk is really just going to be
collecting those all together so that
you can package it up and kind of have a
process our first step typically when we
get on the box the first thing we want
to do if we were looking for remote
access opportunities is first thing we
do is we run that netstat if it's a
Windows box and we start identifying
what sockets are open what processes
those are running on those sockets as
you can see from our example here this
is just a you know quick example we'll
see if something's running on port 902
and we see that that's processed
23:52 from this point we probably won't
identify okay well what does that
process what is that process where is it
so I can identify what the application
is well your next step in that one just
to be run task list we passed it in that
process ID and we can see from this
example that that's actually VMware the
same process applies the Linux is just a
little bit different commands net stats
the same but then once you figure out
that process ID you move on and you just
search your process list and grab for
that process this particular example we
were just on Callie and we had a
listener running and it so it shows us
that that was actually Metasploit
running
once you've identified that application
and you've found it on the system keep
in mind like I said this is assuming
that you're already on a system you've
compromised so more than likely you're
gonna have a rat or some kind of way
into that network so so once it's a look
like I was saying originally you're
gonna get that binary you're gonna
download it back to your system and
you're gonna start doing analysis on
that application and some of your
typical tools that you can use or for
your reverse engineering would be idea
ID a pro or hex raise for those of you
that have you know mac bot boxes or
Linux you can use hopper pretty much
open that up and from this point you
would actually start doing your stack
analysis looking for these entry points
for where that data is coming in so you
can start trying to trace through the
code when you start that process like I
said a lot of the the ways you're the
places you're gonna want to look is
where that input comes in some of those
examples would be you know command line
parameters your sockets as we mentioned
before any kind of file reads
environmental variables some of those
those functions that do that kind of
thing that kind of stand out as you
probably have seen things like read gets
every and receive or see from from here
this is a this is pretty much how it
comes in and at that point you're gonna
move directly after that because
typically once that data gets in it
immediately starts getting processed in
parsed and a lot of times those bugs
that we end up finding are right in
those parsing routines pretty close to
where that data comes in
all right so as I mentioned the the
parsing functions you typically come
next
a lot of the vulnerable functions that
you guys probably heard about before
when dealing with memory are some of
these examples here these are things to
kind of keep your eye out for if you
know you run across these these are
definitely hot areas to just make sure
that whatever they're doing with memory
using these are secure because a lot of
times it's just not recommended to use
these so if you see them that's
definitely something to research further
make sure especially if you see anything
like custom memory operations and
they're written their own string copy or
their own memory copy those are
definitely places you want to look
closer to make sure they did everything
correctly bounds checking all those
types of things
another definitely good place to look
when you see data being moved around is
a lot of times when you have data coming
in from the outside a lot of those
protocols will allow you to specify
indexes into memory so say you know this
is my first record this is my second
record and a lot of people will actually
use those to directly memory access so
if you see any kind of operations coming
in from the outside and they're using
indexes and you control that that's
always a very interesting thing to look
at all right so once you've kind of done
the most static analysis you can you
typically want to move forward and get
into more of a dynamic analysis kind of
phase in order to do that it takes a lot
more time stack analysis is definitely
easier because all you really need is
the binary with then I dynamic analysis
you actually have to model your
environment so you have to set up your
system as closely as possible as the one
you found the application on that means
getting whatever libraries the needs
whatever files did it might use for info
files
registry keys is windows a lot of those
fun things to actually make this
application run if you were to just kick
it off
luckily sysinternals gives you tons of
tools that actually help this out a lot
so once again if you're on a system that
you've compromised and you're pretty far
under the radar a lot of times you can
actually put these tools on there and
actually find out what you need to
actually create your modeled environment
another option and this usually comes a
little bit further in your analysis but
if say you're trying to run your
application on your modeled environment
and for some reason or another it's just
not working one option you could have
and it's definitely easier on things
like Linux because GB comes packaged in
you can actually attach yourself to
those processes and and dump that memory
at which point then you can take that
dump and whatever you have in your
modeled environment and you can actually
analyze the two and make sure that that
they're the same this is this is
definitely one of those things where
I've run into the problem where you have
one that you you feel like you've
modeled perfectly but for some reason or
another it just won't run so you can
dump that memory analyze it too and see
if you missed a library if the memory
addresses are just slightly different or
something like that another thing that
you'll also notice when you're doing
this if you're on a system say it's a
secure system you might actually see
other HIDs application running like hvss
or Emad or something like that and
that's a good thing to know if once you
take this further and you're actually
trying to write an exploit or something
like that so I guess once you get past
that point let's say that you've already
found your bug you've already moved
forward and you've already written an
exploit and once again like I just
mentioned it it's not working for some
reason or another
and say it's crashing
so you've you've done your memory dumb
and you still can't figure it out if
you're on Windows you're on Linux there
are actually a abilities to actually
turn on the collection of memory and
dumps from a crash and you can actually
bring those back and analyze those
further you can see in Windows it's just
a simple registry key if you have the
ability to write to the registry Linux
same idea it's just quick command and
then those will dump your course and you
can bring them up in gdb and see what
might have gone wrong
all right from here I kind of move into
a case study is something that we found
when we were doing one of our red team
assessments on a system and we went
through the same process that I just
described and I kind of want to show you
what this might look like and you know
real world environment this particular
application is called medicine serve
it's a medical application you can
actually get on the internet a lot of
EMR systems use it for storing medical
data and these types of things and so
when we found it we found it running we
thought this might be a pretty good
target to start looking at as you see we
started on the same process as I
originally said where we ran that stat
we found that it was running on port
8080 we saw the process it was running
and kind of went from there once we saw
like I said what the the process ID was
we identified it as the med serve a
plication we saw was running as a
service so our next step was to try to
figure out where on this system it was
so we're in SC query which actually will
list you know information about any kind
of services running on Windows we were
able to figure out where it was on disk
tracked it down and we're able to
download it and bring it back
all right so once we brought it back we
opened it up into I do a pro which is
one of our favorite dissemblers we were
lucky enough to actually have hex race
decompiler so it makes the code look
pretty much like C allows you to you
know pretty much risking all of your
variables to what you think they are
doing so by the time you get done
it looks really close to probably what
the code looked like when they first
wrote in as I mentioned the very first
thing I did since I saw that it was
running on port 8080 I knew that it was
listening in on some sockets so I looked
for any receive functions and I was
lucky enough to find that there are only
two so all data coming in was coming in
through this one function and then it
was probably being processed immediately
after so as you can see it pretty much
takes in a header and then after I took
in the header took in the data going
from here we assumed once again that the
function calling this we were hoping
that immediately after ours it would
probably process that data and we got
lucky and that was exactly what it was
so pretty much it took in the data and
then immediately took one field out of
that data which we assumed was the
command ID and began switching over all
the different types of commands and
processing them accordingly so when we
were looking at us code as you see here
was literally like 300 different
commands and then just how they were
processing them unfortunately at this
point this is where it gets really
tedious because we now had 300 commands
and we didn't know which ones could be
good bad or indifferent which ones might
have bugs which ones might not so pretty
much at this point there was a lot of
reversing there was a lot of just
fuzzing just seeing okay maybe we can
pick the needle out of the haystack
because we didn't want to actually have
to go through every single one of these
functions
because we were hoping to have a pretty
quick turnaround so we can actually use
this in our assessments so much
reversing later we came across this one
function it was a message type it was
like 239 something like that and it took
in our data and as you might be able
tell here we had a location on the the
stack that was expecting a hundred
integers at which point it would go
through the data that came in and it was
assuming that data that we gave it was
literally an array of integers followed
by commas we don't actually know what
they were doing with it at our point it
really doesn't matter to us the big
thing that stood out to us was in our
loop right here we have absolutely no
bounds checking so we know it's taking
100 integers and the way that it breaks
out of this loop is basically when it
gets to the end of our array which is
absolutely horrible
so from here anything over 100 integers
it's going to override our stack and we
could immediately gain control of this
application at least this was our
assumption at this point
all right so going forward now we think
we found a button so we've done our sac
analysis we want to verify this and this
is kind of where you step into your
dynamic analysis it's like can I
actually validate that'll I think I saw
is actually real so this is where we
were started bringing up the tools that
I mentioned earlier for dynamic analysis
to start identifying what like what
files that application needs what
library needs so that I can actually run
this on my virtual environment first
thing we did was run lists dll's that
should show us any kind of libraries
that it needs to run as you can tell
there was absolutely nothing proprietary
all the other libraries that used for
Windows libraries so this was actually
really convenient going forward we did
handle the exe which is another
sysinternals tools that just lists any
open handles to any files that it might
have open at the time this is a good
thing if your application opened a bunch
of files and left them open
unfortunately this isn't going to show
anything that it might open is a
configuration file and then close it
subsequently I'm lucky for us though we
got a good amount of files that are kept
open and it looks like we had a lock
file because anytime you see a document
or a text file or something like that
that's probably a log so our next step
was to just go ahead and open up that
log file and see what that was from the
log file we actually can glean there was
a few other files as needed but the kind
of overarching thing we saw was pretty
much everything it relied on was in the
directory that the binary was in so we
were hoping we just copied that install
directory and that would be pretty much
everything
so we got just about everything so we we
got all the files over that were
libraries got all the files over there
were input files we still weren't having
much luck getting it running and we
remembered the one last thing we didn't
check was the registry for the actual
service and it's pretty rare but
sometimes you will actually see them put
data in there for their their startup
stuff and so we checked it out looked at
the registry and noticed that they
actually had the path to where their
data was so that wasn't hard-coded and
so once we got that out and put that in
our in our system we were able to start
the application up and begin our dynamic
analysis as I kind of mentioned the when
you're setting up your dynamic analysis
modeling virtualized whatever you
actually want to get to where everything
is as close as possible to what you're
looking at so you want to get the same
operating system same patch level you
know you want to make sure your registry
looks the same you want to have
debugging tools so that you can actually
step through things if you need to you
want to have some way of writing scripts
because more than likely you're gonna
have a proof of concept that you need to
work on to to quickly send data this
thing without much room
and once you've done that and you're
gonna want to try to match what you
found in your stack analysis over to a
debugger because you're pretty much
gonna start switching tools at this
point unless you do use a debugger
immediately from your disassembler for
example idea Pro has a debugger but a
lot of times I actually tend to move
over to immunity debugger because they
have a lot of built-in tools that are
really nice so from this point we pretty
much found the idea or the address of
the function that we thought was
vulnerable copy that thing down and then
move it over to our debugger and put in
a breakpoint at this point now we have
our system set up the way we want it we
have our binary on it we've loaded it up
in our debugger and we're ready to see
we're ready to develop them for proof of
concept to exercise what we think might
have been a bug and see what happens
so once we can leave us to get to this
point we kind of start thinking about
the design for our proof of concept from
what we've seen in our disassembly
there's a header there's data and
there's the data length so we should be
able to go ahead and start getting a
proof of concept for a lot of the
boilerplate stuff we don't really know
like I said what that function might be
doing otherwise or what we might have to
do to make it you know a reliable X way
or anything like that that's gonna come
much later but we should be able to go
ahead and set up the necessary things
like opening our socket
sending and receiving closing that
socket just the really easy stuff that
will get us to the next step of being
able to develop a proof of concept and
you can choose you know whatever
scripting language you you feel better
about doing this kind of stuff and I
usually pick Python just because I'm
used to it here's here was our first
stab at our little proof of concept
skeleton you can see it just takes in
the host the for creates a socket
creates a string down here it's
literally just an array of ones followed
by commas
and then it just sends it and then it
closes it we did exit I had a little
helper function over here that will set
up that initial header it would just
tell basically say hey this is the type
this is of the the function that we're
gonna want to exercise and this is the
length of all of our data so that just
kind of made it a little easier for us
whenever we send data to this this
service
all right so we got really lucky and
even with that very simple proof of
concept you can see that when we ran it
we immediately got access over a IP
which is your instruction pointer which
is pretty much the one register that
determines where your next execution is
going to be and as y'all could see
earlier there was that array of ones and
we have a one sitting in EIP
so we are really happy at this point
because it's this is ideal from this
point you probably want to start
thinking about okay now I have the IP I
would like to actually you know put some
shell code in there I want to take over
the system I want to use this exploit
and when you start thinking about those
types of things you want to know
again more about your environment you
want to know you know what protections
does this binary have in place what am I
gonna have to get around to make this
work in our case we already know because
we control a IP that there were no stack
Canaries which is typically it's a
protection that allowed that keeps you
from being able to get to your
instruction pointer because if it
overwrites that stack canary and then it
checks it before the end of the function
and it will kill the whole program
before you even get to the situation we
just saw so we know it doesn't have that
for next protection from our list here
this is actually a command that you can
run from a mona script which is
developed by core LAN that will tell you
all the protections for every
application every library that you have
loaded into memory at the time and as
you can tell from ours it actually shows
that our binary right there in the
middle has absolutely no protections
this is like once again ideal for us
horrible for them
so at this point we literally could have
just written one instruction to our VIP
register and jump straight to our shell
code and we did try that at first but we
assumed that more than likely the
systems we were dealing with which were
actually very secure systems probably at
least had DDP turned on at the operating
system level and so we determined that
probably to make this as reliably as
possible we would go ahead and pretend
like all the protections were enabled
and write an exploit for that so going
with that assumption in mind we're
assuming that we have to get around DP
which means that I can't execute
anything directly on the stack so
typically the first thing you want to do
is you want to put gel coat on the stack
if you want to execute it so we can't do
that and we also can see that other than
our binary a SLR is enabled as
protection too and they SL are basically
all that means is whenever you load up
your binary it gets loaded in a
different place in memory and so when we
are actually writing these exploits your
exploits gonna be static unless you have
the ability to leak addresses back to
you in our case we we don't we don't
even need that so we want to actually be
able to just have static addresses in
our exploit which we can jump to and
will actually start executing down till
we get to our shellcode
so in this particular case as I said
we're gonna try to pretend as if all
these protections are in place so with
them in place we're actually gonna have
to make calls to re-enable execution on
our stack
lucky for us windows provides lots of
different ways to do that you can use
write process memory you can use virtual
Alec and and the great thing about this
Mona script as well as it will actually
look for those gadgets for you and it'll
just construct that whole chain for you
so on this slide right here you can
actually see what happened when I ran
the rap chain command it went ahead it
found every gadget I need which is when
I say gadget this is actually an address
in a static library that you can use to
do something you need in this case what
we need to do is set up our stack and a
way to call that function so this
particular chain is set up to call
virtual Alec and basically sets up all
the parameters need needed for virtual
Alec and then once we call virtual Alec
it will change our stack from
non-executable back to executable at
which point we can jump straight to our
shellcode and start executing the only
problem I found in our particular
example was that script found gadgets to
every single thing we needed except the
address to virtual Alec it's kind of a
big problem because that's you know what
we're all hinged on here so going
forward we realized we're gonna have to
resolve virtual ourselves using two
additional function calls the first
being get module handle which would give
us the addresses at kernel32 and then
once we get the address at kernel32 we
need to find the address of get process
address so that we can then resolve
virtual Alec and then of course once we
get the virtual Alec address which are
off straight into this drop chain that
was generated for us and then our
shellcode
so since all this gets a little
confusing it really comes down to you
know just software design in the end and
so you start designing out what this is
gonna need to look like and then you can
start plugging in the pieces as you get
to them and so right now in the process
we pretty much have our packet header
set up we have all of our ones which is
basically our garbage there and then
we'll start setting up our Rob gadgets
for the three stages that we needed at
first being getting that module handle
to kernel32 then getting the address to
virtual Alec and then calling virtual
Alec and then calling our shell code we
add one extra little helper function
since we since we were actually passing
in that data it's looking for Strings
that are numbers and when we end up
having our shell code it'll typically
just be raw so we're just going to have
a bunch of raw bytes and we need to
format that in such a way that they just
look like an array of numbers so all
this function does is take in all of our
shell code and it converts them into an
array of numbers and adds them to the
end of our data set segment there
all right so let's have a demo
all right so
before I run this I'm going to show you
kind of what did I ended up looking like
so this is our code this is our proof of
concepts see if I can go where I can't
see this at all can you okay just bear
with me all right so this is this part
up top is all of our shell code and this
is basically just shell code for a
reverse TCP form interpreter and as you
go down this is our sin function that
basically just sets up our header and
then sends our data as we were talking
about this is our little helper function
that turns our shell code into the array
of numbers this is a similar helper
function just for Strings and then this
is actually our Rob chain so that first
one as I mentioned before that's gonna
get that's gonna call get module handle
it's gonna get kernel32 she scrolled
down we'll have our next call which will
be get process address and then as you
keep going we're finally gonna get down
to our actual Rob chain to call virtual
Alec I think that's right here and then
once we call virtual Alec the last thing
we do which would be right here is add
our shell code all right so
yes
all right so if you look over here when
you just have simples multi handler
waiting for a callback on four four four
four four a reverse TCP payload and my
mouth
and if we look at our box here let's
make sure we have this service running
didn't you
all right so let's check that port
so we can see we have a service listen
here up for 8080 is that medicine serve
that we just we've been talking about
and if we run our scripts
I couldn't look up here looks like we
got a show back
at which point we can make sure y'all
definitely can't see this I mean really
can we see that's a we are system and
remember system info we say this is our
win7 box so this point this would be
exactly what we wanted this is we found
a service we were able to write exploit
and now we're hoping that this service
would be installed all over the network
and we'd be able to allow Li propagate
and start setting up our persistence on
other boxes that we may or may not could
have gotten through in our red teen
assessment
so one of the fun things about stepping
into this new type of work in the stuff
what we do as we just described all
these these things that we're finding or
considered O'Day's so a lot of these
people don't know what we found they
don't even know that this stuff is
running on their systems so you know
it's it's it's a gray area and you
definitely have to make sure that the
the customers that you're working with
are completely okay with you doing these
types of things in lucky for us our
customers they want to know about
anything impossible that can be done to
their network so they're completely okay
with this but you have to make sure that
you're not gonna be doing anything that
could bring down their networks so when
you start doing things like writing
exploits you need to test a lot and you
need to make sure that what you're doing
isn't going to be adding anything
negative to their performance or
anything like that in this particular
case it was pretty simple because once
we got on we immediately restarted our
service and they didn't even know that
we had done anything make sure you get
permission and then of course once you
get permission then you just get lots of
shells the next step of course knowing
the ramifications of what you've just
done you pretty much have to realize all
right well now I got to start telling
people what happened here and a lot of
times it's a lot further up the chain
than what you think because a lot of
times your customer can't do anything
about this so what we've noticed is
depending on the customer and how
widespread it is if it's commercial
based you can pretty easily just go to
us-cert and say hey I found this thing
with this vendor we think it's bad news
could you reach out to them for us and
start this process because I'm
experienced so far - like a lot of these
vendors they don't want to talk to you
and you can try pretty hard but we've
we've been ignored pretty much every
time we try to talk to vendors so far
but luckily us cert somehow gets them to
talk back and
started actually moving forward which is
great if you can't let's say for example
that this isn't commercial this is
actually just got software you can also
have other avenues like Cybercom for
example and they will push through
similar things and they will keep it
more close to the chest since a lot of
that stuff might be sensitive
there's also miter and this I think they
all pretty much work together with us
cert as the main reporting group at
which point they will then replicate
those disclosures to you know all the
others all right does anybody have any
questions anyone anyone all right well
that's all I got