yes okay amir please join me here on the
stage so everybody please help me by
welcoming
amir shakir yeah
and i want to tell you a couple of fun
facts about emil so amir
is the vp senior vp of research and
development
at perimeter x and he's here to talk
about
hacking and fixing the csp standard the
content security
policy standard but what you didn't know
about amir is that other than
being a security pro he also has a
degree in physics amir quickly what is
pi
after five points after the five numbers
after the point of pi
three point i really don't know
oh okay well i wanted to tell you he got
his degree at tel aviv university
but since he didn't know it you got it
in another university
so he has a degree in physics and an mba
both from here from tel aviv university
and his i asked him for his hobby he
says he likes
python 2.7 so there you have it please
welcome amir to our stage
all right let's see if it works
it works excellent hi everyone
uh great being here so much fun doing a
live event
after such a year with only zoom and
seeing on myself
we're going to talk a bit about csp how
we might try to fix it
and part of the purpose of this talk is
to invite everybody here
to try and dive in find more problems
and try to contribute to the csp3
standard to make it better secured and
improve
everyone's security along the way we'll
just demystify a few things
that you might have already known or not
like karen said my name is amir shaked
i lead the research and development at
perimeterix i've been around
security for many years
i avoid warranties i am a lifelong
hacker
aspiring father trying to teach them to
break stuff as well and
will that will dive in straight um
to i think hypothetical story but if
somebody had such a case in his own
work it would be very interesting to see
so
i wanted to enable csp on my website on
our own website
we read and understood the spec
completely it's very well and easily
understood
we added the header with report only
mode and then
a day later we marked all the resources
all the
all the notifications that we got all
the violations supposedly violations
we cleaned everything we rolled it out
we had zero issues with the website
and everything worked fluently i think
no one said
ever anybody here tried to use csp
as a technology one
two okay that's pretty much the stats
that we see also in the internet so it
works long now
it really is a very complicated standard
and it has a lot of problems along the
way on trying to implement it and use it
uh what is uh really frustrating is that
a real story that we did encounter and
helped with
was something a bit differently
so we got a call from the company um
um we got a call from the credit card
company
telling us uh they see a lot of credit
cards being used on some
website uh being uh circulated in some
forums being used and they correlated
all those credit cards
to a specific website and they're
talking with that
company trying to understand what
happened reviewing all the security
possibilities along there and then
what we see is they configured
everything properly everything was
well defined but there was a fundamental
flaw which they have no control over and
that's
the supply chain some third-party vendor
that got hacked
that specific case was a chatbot they
were using
they got hacked their social code was
replaced with an additional code
and that code worked and
basically exfiltrated data from the
website
digital scheming if you want to an
external entity
now it was whitelisted and everything
was supposed to work
properly but why this doesn't mean that
you will not be able to accelerate
information
and let's go here
and from there i want to talk a little
bit about csp what does it mean
how is it used and then we can see a few
of the cases where it breaks down and
has
issues so csp is a standard
um it's actually been around for a lot a
long time
it was first conceived in 2004 by robert
hansen
he um gave the name content security
policy
only around 2012 it actually became a
standard by
w3c that websites started to use and
implement in their own infrastructure
and the common version version 2 which
is the official one
latest version 2016 that's the one that
most browsers
support if you want to see which kind of
features specifically it actually varies
so nobody
really implements the entire standard
like any security standard
can i use is actually a great resource
to see which specific
[Music]
component of the standard is actually
being supported
and the version 3 which started around
2015 is still a work in progress so it's
not finalized yet
and that's being worked on now before i
continue um if anybody has any question
you can just shout
and i'll stop and let you ask it now we
don't have to wait for the end of the
talk okay
so very briefly how does the policy work
what's the standard
it combines two headers one is um
content security policy and the other is
content security policy report only
basically implementing this exact same
standard but not blocking anything just
reporting the violation
if there is a report destination url
where you can send information to
so if we look at this we can see a
pretty simple
description of a policy saying
the default source is to allow any
content to come
from the website source code javascript
code can come from the website
itself and a specific domain cdnjs in
this case
and the report uri on any violation will
be to the website slash csp logging
and then in this case this is a two
examples the image and the script will
work
because they're coming from an allowed
destination
and if everything works properly the
last one will not work because it's
trying to download the script
from an unauthorized destination
basically
not within the policy so the entire
concept of csp
is a whitelist method where you define
what is allowed
if something is not allowed it will not
work
which is great in theory somebody here
tried to manage iptables policies
yeah yes to both you have a question
louder please
i get your question so actually this is
a server protection because this is a
csp can define will be defined in two
ways actually didn't thought of
mentioning that one way which is not
recommended would be within the html
tags you can define the policy
the other would be the http header
itself so the server is the one you need
to protect
defining the and releasing that header
so
that's the that's the place where you
need to make sure that sends the right
header
the server
yes if somebody changes if somebody has
control over it's not just the servers
but you need to change specifically
what's configuring the http headers
because in big websites you have a chain
of
elements say the headers come from the
front edge on the cdn
then it will not be able to manipulate
that even if somebody defines something
down the stream so it really depends on
where you control and how the website is
specifically defined there was another
question here
shout because it's hard to see okay
so that's around that um it's most
commonly practiced is to define it with
http headers
i really don't recommend defining it
within the html
it's really hard to maintain okay
so um
i don't know about you guys but being a
hacker seeing a specification just calls
out to let's try and see where it breaks
and what
you can do with it and different methods
we can
play with it first of all it's not fully
defined even with all the
uh well um rich documentation
that i invite everybody to read it's not
fully defined
there are items um that varies
what the reports hold when to report and
i'm going to show some example of that
and that leads to inconsistency when
you're trying to analyze what it is that
you're viewing
the implementation itself may be lacking
um
just char researching csp and the cv
database and see where
where there are gaps in browsers
themselves and it's very usage dependent
and can be abused and i'm going to give
examples on any of
all of these uh how they're actually
being
exploited so let's start with numbers
we've seen this as a security technology
it's been around for
a long time if you actually try to see
what kind of security
methods are being used by websites
we can see the numbers do people know
http archive
the amazing database it's an amazing
resource
i'm glad to see only a few hands so i
invite you all to try and dive in it's
an amazing resource
they scan in the past three four years
they've been scanning four million
websites
every month storing a lot of information
about that
if you're trying to do analysis on web
usage uh
over history that's a very rich
information where you can try and see a
lot of things
what i was specifically looking at was
how the different http headers
were being reported by websites and what
we can see here
the top three are actually
the one with the dashes they're actually
deprecated
but still growing with numbers so csp is
replacing that but still people use
deprecated security headers within their
infrastructure
and then the bottom
three it's uh csp see i don't have a way
to
shine on this um i'm also colorblind so
i'm not sure which colors i'm gonna say
so the lower one that's report only and
two one two after that that
the content security policy itself now
it's only the mentioning of the
header it doesn't say what's actually
being defined and we're going to see a
bit more numbers around that
what is i was happy to see that over
time and i've been handling these
this in the past few years the numbers
did grow so we're around 10
now of csp usage uh when it was much
lower
in the past so
it seems like a positive trend but when
uh
looking at those comes down to about
seven hundred thousand websites
uh as of last june uh last month
what are they actually using we're gonna
see the following directives
so what is the policy we saw before
several examples of directives these are
the actual directives being used
by websites and what do they mean the
first one the frame ancestors
that basically mean if you can embed a
page within a frame or an iframe
and it's just replacing a previous
security header that we saw which was
the one of the most common
the second one to upgrade insecure
request again
means moving all http traffic to be
https
um and that as well is replacing a
defecated security header that we saw in
the previous slide
so if you look at that we see that most
of the websites implementing csp are
just replacing
uh the different security headers with
the new version they're not implementing
the full scope of what you can do with
this
technology and the following ones
pretty low numbers those are the ones
that are actually interesting the fetch
directives
which tells us where we can get content
from and where we can send it to
these are the interesting ones we can
really use to secure our website
they're not being used that much and i
believe part of the reason is the
complexity of using the technology
within the website and that is
pretty low numbers so it is still sad to
see but will
with those actually trying to use that
we're still going to see a few
fundamental gaps within the technology
um i took the example of several
websites
um and this is frustrating so even
those trying to implement csp they're
using the top one the top one basically
says
you can bring source but it can be
unsafe evil and unsafe inline meaning
we don't check anything everybody can
add code to the page and run it
and we're not going to validate anything
the bottom one
which i've seen a very few websites use
dictates
that if there is an inline javascript
code within the page it has to match the
specific hash
so you can't just add any type of code
you want to add into the page it has
to match the exact hash harder to manage
but
actually brings the security into in
default
and like any system um looking at the
directives we said okay there should be
around 30
why do we see 700 and that's because
people
don't check anything
[Music]
all kinds of mistakes i really don't
understand the last one the go for it
it's interesting um it's been around
on more than one website i'm not sure
what they wanted to do with it
but all kinds of examples and when the
directive is wrong
the policy just breaks and doesn't work
so it's as if we have nothing
so even out of those websites not
everything is actually working
the google csp validator is the best one
i've seen to date so if you're trying to
write a policy please use that
all right it's jump no cool okay
so we defined the policy we defined the
report uri
it's json so it's pretty simple
supposedly to just read the reports and
trying to understand what are we seeing
and um and that's the next phase of the
madness
data is not normalized at all it's full
of stuff
coming from extensions and ads and it's
also unmanageable because if you have an
extension
running within the browser by design
they bypass the csp but if they're
injecting code
into the page the page will still report
csp violations so now you're trying to
read your own violations and they're not
actually coming from the website they're
coming from one specific user
and within the standard there is nothing
that tells you it's a user
you need to add a bit of hackings into
the reporting information itself to
understand
which user was it that reported that
violation so it's really not helping you
to analyze the information
at all and i'm not going to jump into
the link but i invite you to go to the
last one
it's full of really fun examples
that's the explained one you should look
at the unexplained one
it has a lot of examples of csp reports
websites see and they really don't
understand where they come from
the last one when we went into high
scale of looking at the actual
information was browser misalignments
when the report is actually being sent
and what are we seeing
and the few of the examples which are
still relevant chrome
um works differently if the report
is uh to be blocked they will send one
report per page
fine that's gone that's easy firefox
will report it multiple times per page
so now you have the differences between
how many reports you see and how you're
trying to analyze them
and then safari behaves completely
differently if you have a repetitive
call blocked
and and it will send it it just sends
the
top level domain so you don't even get
the full page of the reporting
[Music]
of where it originated from
and then of course like any reporting
service there could be log spamming we
actually saw some
interesting cases where lockspain was
trying to be used to manipulate systems
but this is still i would say next phase
of attacks
because some vendors are trying to build
systems which will automatically
configure
and uh define from reporting policies
what is a uh something that should be
whitelisted you can actually spam
the system and trying to abuse the
machine learning
to to learn a specific domain as should
be whitelisted
i haven't seen an example yet but i
anticipate it will happen as it's
becoming more
abundant so we went over
that part the next part we wanted to
look at
was actually cves and how do browsers
behave
so this is the cvs report over the years
specifically in total in firefox and in
chrome
i'm going to dive a bit to one that we
found
a while back it's pretty straightforward
the following code if you look at the
directive it says that object source uh
shouldn't come from anywhere and skip
source will only come from the page
itself
and then this code uh should not work it
should be blocked by the browser
basically trying to
create an element with a script and
fetch it from
a non-white listed domain but then
if we add a tiny bit of hack this is
already
by the way mitigated so we don't have to
worry
just opening an iframe and adding it
into the iframe
that worked now i'm not blaming browser
developers it's really hard to build a
fully protected browser and to match all
the different possibilities you can have
with all the different variations
but these kinds of cvs happen all the
time and i've actually reviewed a few of
the latest 2021 cves
they've seen um breaches reappear
after they were closed three and four
years ago because
code was refactored again
any questions so far
okay so let's assume we have a
well-defined policy and let's assume the
browsers
work well what can possibly go wrong
with this concept of policy
[Music]
i asked the simple questions again going
back to http archive
let's see which are the most commonly
white listed uh domains
that websites use let's not assume
anything let's just see what they're
using and let's see
what we can do with it so going back to
march 2020 and then looking at
last month we see these domains here is
a question for you
if we look only on the top one does it
bring you an idea what you can do with
it
malaysia's advertisement okay any other
idea
yes so um
thank you um first of all it's not that
the top one it happens again and again
when you're going down the list so it's
more than just the top one it's actually
more common
and the simplest idea here was okay
i'm looking at this information i'm
saying sounds pretty simple let's just
try and use the top
domain which is white listed to
expectate data
will it work will it be that simple and
the answer is
it is because any uh jsonp uh
endpoint that is whitelisted can be used
for data explication
and it's just just google analytics this
is just the simplest one to try to
implement
this bypass it can be with anything it
could be with trying to send tweets
or a facebook message if it's
whitelisted
new relic you can open an account for a
few dollars if that is whitelisted and
use that
any service that is shared and is
commonly whitelisted because websites
are actually using it
can be used for the data exfiltration so
even if we did all the work
of defining a well-protected policy uh
somebody can
try and bypass it and it's pretty simple
to write the code so
we just added a few bits of lines
as you can see
this isn't even a complicated scenario
we just doing all the information
on the query string itself not even
trying to do it as an ajax
request and obviously it worked we have
the information
we can export it from google analytics
and then we have
a user password that we expected uh
from a website even though uh it was
tricked
just because google analytics was
whitelisted
now we went back to the um
to the standard and said okay
interesting let's dive in and see
if somebody tried already to resolve it
so let's at least
with the questioning itself can we do
some kind of limitation
to protect it and as you can see by this
by definition
it doesn't this is a quote from the
standard itself
we do not go into the query string we
don't try to validate anything beyond
top level domains that is the only level
of protection
we can efficiently implement within the
standard itself so that can be supported
unfortunately then we said fine
so far still an interesting story let's
publish that we didn't think it would be
that um
biggest bigger story as itself we
published the
method um it got a lot more exposure
than we expected because it seems pretty
straightforward
and then just a few days later other
security companies
started to report on actually seeing
this being used in the wild
from kaspersky from sunsec and a few
other companies reporting that they
actually see this being abused
so it's not even just story and a theory
it's just a matter of looking at the
data
and trying to underst on playing the
game of if we would have been the
attackers
what we would have done looking at uh
websites and seeing that
yeah somebody is already trying to do
that it's just
a matter of exposing the method and
bringing it into lights
so today by the way if you're going to
add google analytics
as a destination domain and go to the
csp validator tools
they will point it as a potential risk
they don't have any suggestion on how to
solve it
but at least they will tell you that
there is a potential risk so that is an
addition
which is an important one
okay
so if you look at the story from where
it went wrong the ma with the
fundamental problem here is we're trying
to protect
a modern website with a lot of different
elements and tools
with a policy and like i asked before
who tried to configure an iptables
policy
these things are really hard to
configure well and there are a lot of
not a lot of best practices i'm going to
mention a few
but it is really problematic and
when we're defining a policy the most
common vector of attacks today that we
see
on modern websites is coming from some
kind of a
whitelisted target i don't know if
you've seen
just earlier this week cdnjs reported
they had the major
potential breach have you seen it
nobody so cloud4 reported that
they had a major potential breach where
somebody could basically
change the source code on any javascript
placed on cdnjs that's a pretty high
risk item they fixed it after they
discovered it
but that happens all the time that means
that
code we bring into our website which is
running on multiple platforms we didn't
build it we didn't own it
we're using a lot of different tools
when we're building our system or the
marketing team adding
all kinds of tags when they're just
trying to improve uh
some aspect in their website we don't
have actual full control over what's
joining
and we have no control over the security
of those elements
and they're being whitelisted and they
expose us to data exploration
from both angles from where source is
coming and where data can go to
because we're using all these tools
so what can you do to make the best of
it uh it's still a good standard i'm
still recommending everybody to use it
i'm not recommending anybody to just
avoid it it's
still raising the bar and make requiring
a potential attacker to try and work
harder to try and breach
and expert rate information first of all
pretty basic but still not that common
is just to add an identifier
on the report uri at one some kind of an
identifier telling you
this is a user a or user b so you can
look at the logs later on when you're
trying to understand what you're looking
at
obviously filter the reports my go to
here is just look at the most
common newest
browsers if you're trying to understand
if your website is working well enough
ignore all the minor cases just focus on
those which are the most common
if there is a problem that will tell you
where it is you don't need to focus on
anything else on
all the long tail of noise and the last
one which is a pretty nice hack that you
can do
i haven't seen any open source system
yet to do it but it's a pretty
nice method is to a b the policy the way
you can start
is with the report only policy which is
the strictest
allow nothing get all the reports and
then
just starting to add elements one by one
to be still as strict as possible and
see with the report only what kind of
reports you're using once you get to a
position
when you don't see any reports that you
don't think you should get
then switch the policy from report only
to mitigation mode basically changing
the header from report only to
to block and that will give you all the
information
that you need and then you can play with
it as you go along you can keep on
iterating
on the policy uh back and forth on
uh portions of the users on actual part
of the sites
and then see what how you can
verify that both domains that you have
there
should be should be there and that
they're not obsolete this is something
that i didn't mention before
we've seen cases where the csp whitelist
has domains
that were obsolete because somebody did
it fast it didn't work
they added a domain and they they forgot
about it because
you never change it there is never a
report on something is not needed
and the domains got obsolete and are out
there to be bought so
somebody can actually buy domains that
are whitelisted on websites
um not very popular one but
assume you're using startups sometimes
they close
and if you don't remove them from the
policy somebody else can try and buy
that domain and reuse that
as a as a target
so like i said clean up after once in a
while that's the idea behind this
and complicated but i definitely
recommend you use the nuances and hashes
to make sure the actual inline code is
also the one you intended
requires a lot more work but still
something that should
should be relevant and and the last one
still not common enough is to be context
aware you don't need to use the same
policy for the entire website you can be
strict on different pages according to
what's being run there on the login page
be very strict on the front page you can
allow google analytics you can also
decide
that there is no google analytics on the
login page and just
remove that risk you don't need to
assume you need it on every single page
so this is something you can take into
account when you're trying to protect it
and the last one is really to me the
most important one
try to contribute to w3c
to the csp3 with comments and ideas it's
still a very important standard
and a lot of browsers are still
implementing it and it's still open
for reviews so try and hack it trying to
find new ways to bracket
to break the the standard and try to
find ways and ideas in order to
push everything to be better because
it's protecting all of us as users in
the internet
with browsing those websites
any questions
yeah so
welcome yeah so the attack vector the
csp is trying to prevent
is if someone several client side manage
to inject malicious
javascript code and you want to block
exfiltration office for example that's
the whole point
the server sends the http header and the
browser
itself enforces the policy that the
server
defines that's the basic idea behind it
csp is mostly intended to prevent xss so
cross-site scripting those kind of
attacks
they can come from different places but
that's the main idea behind
the the method it's not only that
because
one thing that we see is that the
standards are trying to move
all the security uh headers the
different headers that
we have as directives into csp so it's
also adding of
more layers of protection i would say
but it's just a matter of
making more convenient for the security
person
to manage one context and not and learn
less about less and less
methods that you can try to protect like
the upgrade insecure request for example
that has nothing to do with access
it's mostly about making sure the
website is only https
but it's most but that with that said
it's mostly around access yeah
thank you
how are you answer that
ask a question get a prize
any other questions
over there all right somebody over here
hi can you kindly please comment about
the age of xss in view of
csp can you repeat that
eh what is the status of xss attacks in
view of
css csp implementations
interesting so i haven't seen them
myself i read a few reports and from the
reports i've read
xss is first of all still very common as
an attack vector
but it is very csp is very effective in
blocking that on websites that
published information on how xss is
actually being trying to be abused and
being blocked with csp so
i've seen very few reports of those but
from what they're reporting they report
on very effective
mitigation on various access
other questions someone back there
i'm going to need the mic
do you think we could use the
do you think we could that a new version
of csp
could possibly defend against csrf
attacks
or is it that just not going to work
ever
i don't think so because csp is mostly
intended to be the client side
part of the protection and csrf tries to
manage
both ends so i don't see it
going into that they're mostly focusing
on the xss part and the client side
protection and i think that's where they
should focus it's coming to protect
the user using the websites
hi do you think csp should also support
by this thing of urls full urls on just
domains
because currently um you can just
find a url inside the domains that are
already
whitelisted that you can just do
whatever you want with it
yeah it's a good question it's one of
the items we actually we looked at
interior would say yes but it adds a
very
complicated layer to the browser
themselves trying to be effective when
they're trying to analyze and mitigate
so from the security perspective i would
say yes but as a user this might affect
us in a negative way
so i'm not sure it's something that they
will be able to do there is a reason
so far it's being explicitly said it's
outside of the standard
with that i think it's a combination
the big services that are a potential
leaking endpoint they should also do
their part
in trying to prevent uh themselves being
part of that attack factor
and uh and and protecting uh basically
the businesses that using them as
services so it should be part of the
story it can be
something that is just one way and
one-sided
in practice you know google analytics
should also do something on their end to
try and protect the users
it can be something that only the
browser does because they're on
potential risk
it's not only them but also them
any other questions
going once going twice
all right thank you
[Applause]