[Applause]
okay hello people so this is our tool
it's called xrdp and its main focus is
on exploiting unauthenticated x11
sessions so my name is Thomas this is my
colleague Darren we both work at st.
spells as security analysts and just a
little bit about myself so before I was
doing the security stuff I was a civil
engineer one day I was sitting in a
meeting looking around me seeing all
these old people and I decided well
that's not me I want to be a rock star
so then I joined st. first okay so
Darren everyone i joined Sun Space
Shuttle diversity studied computer
science I was originally planning to
become a coder but then I found security
and so much more interesting so I joined
sensitized as well ok cool so xrdp added
this thought so in the beginning of this
year we did since post-training about
after three or four months we got the
time to do some research since we were
both new to the field we didn't really
know what to do so we asked the analyst
some ideas and the one guy Dane is the
most of all today and they and make some
noise you didn't hear anything ok so
Dane told us he had this problem on
assessments ok basically he got this
vulnerability and he didn't really feel
that exploiting this manually was really
working for him so we decided to take on
this problem we were really excited
about this so we got started so the
first thing if you you might know what X
is but for those who don't I'll simply
give you a short description basically
if you are using a unique selinux type
of system then you are making use of X
so X is currently in
the 11th version so it's called x11
mainly you might note by that name and
basically it just plays a central role
in displaying graphics on your screen it
originated from MIT we're back in the
days computers were really expensive so
they had this one main computer and they
needed a way to for students just to
connect to this computer and just share
the resources for instance if they want
to write a report I can connect to this
machine have like it takes editor
whatever display on data screen and they
could do their work ok so looking at the
basic architecture they on the top left
you can see there's keyboard and mouse
so that's basically your inputs and the
top right that's the screen that's where
X will display the windows and here
looking if you're on the top of the
dotted line that's basically your local
machine if you go below the dotted line
that can be some remote client ok so X
is basically a mediator between the user
and clients for example a browser on
your machine may be X term on a remote
machine anything like that ok so you can
imagine when there's lots of users using
one resource authentication let's play
role somewhere ok so we're yeah we can
imagine we have our remote server there
for the resources on the first method of
the authentication is just by host so
the administrator you can type in a
command he says exhales plus and give it
a IP so if you connect from that IP you
can authenticate ok the next method is a
cookie MIT generated MIT cookie if your
computer or terminal wherever usage can
prove that you have knowledge of this
cookie then you can authenticate as well
last method a little bit more difficult
this is where the server and the user
both need to put a trust in a third
party machine I through something like
Kerberos that's just another thing
Cashin method okay so for one other
method you can commit connect with it's
also authenticated is simply through ssh
so it will update now okay so what you
do you can just type SSH include the
dash X option the target machine and
when you connect it you can type X term
and then you can see your little
terminal that will actually pop up on
your local machine okay so that's all
good and fine everything is secure
looking at an unauthenticated station
like one of them is there's quite a few
ways to mess this up one of the ways is
where the administrator allows the TCP
traffic on port 6000 also you can maybe
mistype something or if here is like
just not I'm info struggling with
authentication you can run XO spliced so
anyhow on that network can simply just
connect to that server okay so the main
problem here or the what we have now is
an unauthenticated session we are
hackers what do we love most okay second
most we love shells okay so our aim for
this was we needed some other reverse
shell maybe a graphical shell anything
like that okay so just one more thing on
this unauthenticated station the you can
export your expert display run that
command and that IP will typically be
the IP of the remote server and at the
end you can just type your command okay
so we have our remote server we want to
exploit it what do we do ok so this
process is not just straightforward
there's a lot of different tools
can use every tool just give you some
output you have to chain that into the
another tool and you go forth like that
there's no like fluency throughout the
process so it's really frustrating just
rating okay so the first two we looked
at was excellent info that you just
targets display or window on the remote
machine and it displays some information
so looking at the command so it's just X
watch one screen will update now dash
routes simply says that you want to look
at the root window that will typically
be exactly what the user on the remote
machine will see so display that just
says you targeting display 10 dot 213
whatever is running on there ok so
another important piece of information
is the window ID you need that for some
of the other tools ok so like we had
some information about two remotes a
window we needed some like we needed see
what's on that a machine can we get any
output anything like that so the first
tool we came across was xwd it stands
for X Window dump so you can run the
command its xwd dash display that's a
remote display you're targeting the root
window again and you put that out to
some file now you can't just read this
file you need to convert it into the say
for example the JPEG and then you can
see what's going on so this process is
not very like this it's very kind of
blocky you do one thing at a time so we
did some more research and we came
across X watch when so this is a little
gift this is typically what you'll see
when looking at X watchman so you can
see what's happening on that server it
updates as quickly as possible with it's
basically a bunch of screenshots that
steichen and they is where you include
include your window ID so at this point
in time you can see what's happening on
the remote machine you can just see what
the user is doing and we want to take
this further either just a reverse shell
remote and like a reverse shell or some
graphical shell since we really do love
shells as occurs okay and the last thing
we looked at was X 22 so what this
enabled us to do is you can send some
commands you can for example open a
terminal you can open a file browser but
this is not it looks easier than it is
because if you say for instance you
export display and you run your ex 22 if
you after that type something like X
term in your terminal then your terminal
will actually be displayed on the remote
machine so that's rule one no backing
like never hack yourself that's just
stupid okay so in the second command you
can for instance send a mouse movements
but say you opened this second then you
need to find a way to select your first
screen types of if you want to just type
like echo other world or whatever then
it's got to be like a character space
character space characters face so it
makes the whole process really tedious
so basically we were looking at a some
form to like it a graphical shell remote
shall something very easy to use and
that's not frustrating ok so I'll give
over to Darren and you'll tell you more
about our implementation cool so we know
what tools are available and so what we
need to do is take those tools and wrap
them up in a nice bow so that they all
work together and give us something
awesome so what we did was we decided to
write a Python script
and we started off by running excellent
info using Python grabbing the window ID
and passing that 2x watch win creative
creating the screens that updating gift
that you saw earlier now we had the
output so now we needed to figure out
how to get how to take input from the
user and send it to the remote machine
we did some research and we'd had to
brainstorm a bit like how we're going to
do this and really finally sort of just
using transparent overlay so creating
another window with that's completely
transparent allowing you to click and
with like text inputs and buttons and
making it all look pretty and so we
looked online how can we do this we
decide we found pi gtk and we decided to
use that the main reason for that there
was with excellent info x1 and x2 a tool
there's already a lot of dependencies to
this tool so pi gtk ships with python so
we didn't want so that simplifies the
installation process and whatnot but in
hindsight there was a terrible idea pi
gtk is horrible never use it it like
getting the buttons and oh there was
just making a transparent took us ages
it was it was horrible but we eventually
got it to work and then PI gtk allows
for you takes the user input and then
you use X through tool to send those
inputs to the remote machine doing
obviously doing some processing like
taking a sentence since splitting it up
into characters and whatnot but once we
had the tool we decided we needed a fast
and easy way to find a vulnerable hosts
that was that would be fun to tack so we
created an nmap script using the N map
scripting engine obviously and they
already exists the x11 access script
that ships default with nmap but all
that does is it checks whether
the host is vulnerable to
unauthenticated x11 which tells you okay
it's vulnerable but it doesn't give you
a good enough idea of whether it's worth
even looking at and if you come across
like if you come across an internal
network or something and every box is
vulnerable which one you go for so we
realize that there are four main options
option one the box is invulnerable
either port the port is closed the port
is open nothing is running or it's
authenticated but that's not very
interesting or important the second
option is there's no active display so
the the box is running x11 it's
unauthenticated but it doesn't respond
to any of the X commands we only
actually found out about this after
writing the tool and writing the script
and using the script when the script
would keep failing and we were like
what's going on so we run x.x win info
against that box and it just bombs but
according to the but according to the
output from the auth check it's
unauthenticated we did some research
into this and we really still have no
idea why that's why that happens so
that's some further work for us later
the third option is it's vulnerable but
there's no desktop environment there's
no desktop environment so this happens
generally when you run an xserve but
without an operating system or anything
like that when you when you get a
screenshot back it's literally just a
black a black image with the default
resolution so that's not very
interesting either and the final option
is jackpot you find a vulnerable box
that's the one you're looking for what
this the script actually generates a
screenshot and saves it to the direct
your directory so you can once you've
run the script you can just look at all
the pic
and the pictures are named nicely with
IP addresses and whatnot so you can see
you oh no this from sections from sex
this one sucks that one let's go for
that one once we created the scripts it
was time to take it for a test drive
okay so as you can see this is South
Africa now imagine that you are the two
interns like oh just finish the training
you have this opportunity to write a
nice script do you think this will be
your main target well this was not our
main target but we just started here we
were we thought we going to take over
like probably the whole internet with
our new too okay so we got some IPS from
our scanning team and these are the
results so just in South Africa we
scanned about 27 million IPS we did that
with masks and since we were just
checking for port 6000 x11 ports and
then after that we ran it through our in
my script okay so looking at the whole
of South Africa we found for vulnerable
hosts now not vulnerable like in every
case you could see a desktop we could
see only one desktop okay so this was
really pretty disappointing so we
scanned the whole of South Africa found
one desktop environment and we just
thought that was really just lame so we
also internally like that people see any
of these x11 vulnerabilities on Eternals
and they confirmed it they said they are
quite not that common but they do see
them on internals so the soul if it was
not in vain okay so the conclusion is
that our scanning stop right there we
did not scan the whole internet or
whatever but that's okay so this picture
will always remind us about this whole
exercise this is the one guy in South
Africa that was vulnerable
okay so Darren will quickly show you a
demo of our two and I'll try to speak
you through it or he'll speak you
through it as it goes along sorry I'm
talk very loud or october so i'm
currently on private network and i know
that there's a horrible host so first
thing you have to do is find it we're
going to run an nmap scan let me do that
is that big enough everyone first let me
get the subnet
I'm going to ms down my current network
looking for ports 6,000 i'm going to
have make sure Ernie finding open ports
and just to be double sure and use the
default x11 imprint the script what I
our stands can i refined a horrible loss
yes I did
and
mr.
just that I did
with our custom stress
and it produces a screenshot it saves it
to my cam truck because I didn't provide
it with this is a this is a little teen
years later we want to change the
sawdust as saves the current working
directory right I'm the grossest
suppliers with a the directory of your
choosing if you check out the
screenshots
streets is great look at just
yeah that's why the game
hand against Pedro
once you have this you go well that's
horrible now we can run up to providing
a Chris I big mess
and the display this is generally
reports class everyone said this is 0
for 6,000 the run as a reference tool on
my other screen the Greater Los
considering we may collect little easy
regards your mind to change settings
they're so now we're going to grab
yourself basically the devil it's as
close to more definite you can obviously
you can see this text box and follow the
buttons so it doesn't want to capture
your keyboard but it still allows you to
do things like this I can hit to control
all pendants to talk on type T is enter
since it's a booty it will eventually
when exports for updates Michelle I can
then type grammar I answer this enter
again itself in turkey drumstick man and
Gia it also allows for lasting quest it
doesn't do much trapped in Omaha but
wherever you click + where it sends the
clip man so I get the X goes away with
the menu eventually
in Tibet slur but it's better than
dinner with one of those multiple
multiple tools giving gear shall I am
one of the other patients we added in
the bottom right corner you can see my
if I can show my box set up a net
Katniss now every poor 44.4 I reckon my
teachers and my idea dress
I put that in attack I'm address the
port number and i hit the archelvin if
you're getting annoyed with the laggy
deaths or laptop what this will do is it
will open a shop neuroimaging run where
we can pre pre call pash magic sporting
a reverse shell to your book reports and
in minimizing the shell to try and hide
the evidence and then happen easily can
I see the time like this there you go a
professional you're under a high and
just to prove that this isn't the actual
wish I just magically I got a box behind
some for overlay there's no paradox
that's the term
and
you can see this is cutting through the
overnight
I move the front of the happiest and
roots of this to me originally when you
click the exit button on my other tool X
watch we would stay and it would when
you click excellent at urbana some areas
in my heart yeah that's that's the tool
and then there's be bitter and sour hola
we took with Tina's horrible task you
think and every time you want to do that
you have to search long large figure out
on usual tools because XD to open the
light music and drumming ramen shop
regression how long did take in total
about three to three days to recover
very old and then on top of that like
coding here and there over like a month
to make it pretty they could add to that
some teachers but the myth the main bulk
of it was two or three days first aid
figuring out at that point we were new
to acting room and like I had some
knowledge on c1 X so the first day was
just figuring out what X was and how to
use it all that stuff and then the
piping game quite
project Russians comments what's the
battery usage of Armenians doesn't
really use the patient as i am not as
far as I wear but Graham Nash eternity n
Carter i but the screenshots do you take
you take a screen done it's usually not
very long the xbox persons
little access
so you can so you can know you can't
export the remote display to your
machine so you are a few runs for
example X term on the right there and
have the title of here indoor ones the
only way to do that would be through ssh
or the proper means but they make
themselves vulnerable like this it's
generally the vocal box is generally the
one that the admin BOTS trying to get
connections from other machines so that
they're trying to run next play right
next next time on another box and
several years from now on a machinist
Olivia
is it it's what the thickness alarm
cotton and we still really confused
about which way which way the
communications happening yeah so when we
do export display we're exporting we are
exporting the remotes and then rerun the
next virtual or I'm not done and it does
that sevens keyboard it works to the
river and the new exports the remote
display terminal and you run ga ga we're
running launching a display over room so
that box it hit it could be serving on
the same box theoretically it could be
next running a separate machine
yes I'm one machine can run multiple
Exeter if the growing x-overs within
x-overs it gets complicated but it is if
this scenario this this is generally
will be fine although there is one
cabinet to r2 and that is our we saw
I've tried to create a large this
because we come across vulnerable
windows machines a windows box running
XO unauthenticated and I have no idea
how they got that to the first place
making a sauce vulnerable using the unix
based widow
this is bleh
but i found it when I come to use that
one for the tools i found was paid for
one thing but this tool doesn't work
against Renee's party so if you come
across a vulnerable readers box this to
export all the default tools like X LED
x1 x2 alerts d west xbox-green point
also that's another to karaoke later as
Christmas egg which is to probably
manually do X bar instead of life which
seems
brussels
you
[Applause]