so first and foremost thank each and
every one of you for joining me if I do
a lot of these talks my name is Greg
pepper I'm the head of engineering for
our data center cloud and virtualization
teams here at checkpoint is the audio
okay in the back excellent all right I
was saying I have an opportunity to a
lot of these conferences and speaking at
different conventions user group
meetings industry sessions and I got to
say the session after lunch is the
hardest so thank you all for joining me
today
and thank you to the time we're going to
spend here in the next 45 15 minutes
talking a little about how we help our
customers secure their migration to the
cloud
who in here is and somehow got a company
organization is working on a cloud
project cloud initiative cloud and right
you can't sneeze let's step it on clouds
so we're going to try and keep the
buzzword bingo to a minimum I promise
but there may be a couple of TAS and CFO
lays that may be used today right the
three-letter acronyms and the complex
four letter acronyms all right we'll try
and avoid the really complicated five
letter acronyms themselves but when we
look at cloud I mean is here this is not
a new technology Amazon had their cloud
for over a decade now
Microsoft little over five years
Google's in the mix too and if it's not
public cloud that our customers are
migrating to many of you are thinking
well how do we continue to enhance our
physical environments how do we move
from traditional virtualization and
static networks to this new
software-defined network as well and as
many drivers that people are moving
forward some of us just want to quite
simply reduce the amount of capital
dollars that we're spending on servers
storage networking software licenses
from security vendors like checkpoint
for a lot of us though our computing
needs are growing faster than we can
source the technology let's be honest
there's a lot of layer 8 9 and 10 and
all of our organizations and those are
the people the politics of the money
around how you buy deploy manage and
maintain IT services so as one of my
customers said this was a large Bank
he's like look we've got the money but
it takes me six months to buy a server
six months
can do it in six minutes in Amazon and
he said that's exactly why we're moving
to the cloud because we can do things
faster that was not always cheaper in
some cases sometimes you pay for the
agility you pay for the right to leave
someone else's software however
regardless of this cloud is on this
massive growth and it is on a single
organization that I talk with and I have
the opportunity to talk to our largest
customers our smallest customers our
public sector our private sector all of
our industries and every one of them
seems to have some level of initiative
and desire to move into cloud however
every single one that we talk to
security is concerned now who thinks out
of the box cloud secure right the cloud
has security built-in I don't need to
bring security with me to the cloud I
hear that a lot
and I would like to think that that's
the case but at the end of the day the
cloud is really no different than your
own data center it's just somebody
else's computer somebody else's network
somebody else's infrastructure and
you're just in tenant living in the
shared services multi-tenant environment
now as we look to move the cloud the two
key things that we constantly hear from
people is the ability to move faster
right like that bank that I talked about
it took six months to deploy a server
the DevOps guys they want to do in six
minutes and they want to build it
destroy it build destroy it ten times
within an hour - but equally is the
activity and let's be honest every one
of our organizations have those
impactful events in our year maybe it's
one of my department stores that has the
biannual sale what happens twice a year
they bought computing resources to
support that peak workload well the
other 50 weeks a year they were running
about 10 to 20 percent utilization who
wants to pay for a lot of money for
stuff to sit there idle for the once or
twice a year that we needed and this
continues to be one of the primary
drivers for cloud so I want to move
faster I want to scale up when I need it
but more importantly I want to scale
down right now our computing and our
server and our infrastructure and our
software guys get this
I'll be brutally honest our security
guys are the last ones to embrace this
level of agility automation and
elasticity however new demands are being
put in IT let's be honest whether we
want to or not we have to support this
application migration a cloud our
companies are saying we want to automate
and orchestrate and enable self-service
portals and provisioning systems that
allow our user population to have that
Amazon like experience but due to my own
private environment use the tool that
I've already invested in and that is
awesome but let's be honest who in this
room has the resources of Google
Microsoft and Amazon none of us
absolutely none of us so it's very
attracted to build upon their technology
history take advantage of all that they
have to offer us however in order for us
to truly embrace the cloud and move into
this new software-defined world we have
to embrace what it offers us now I'm not
trying to sit here and say that the
software-defined network is the answer
to all of our data center problems as a
matter of fact it creates new challenges
and problems and opportunities but it
also provides tremendous amount of power
and one of the things that we'll look
about is how do we use this Sdn
capability and whether we're talking
about in the private cloud maybe you're
using OpenStack or in a sector a CI or
new eyes or juniper contrail maybe
you're moving in the public cloud and
looking these Amazon ads or Google
Rackspace SoftLayer Olly cloud is so
many options out there but in each one
of these situations one of the biggest
differences is that we've moved from the
traditional static to the highly dynamic
now in the world of cloud there's a lot
of as solutions out there right we have
our infrastructure as a solution our
traditional computing storage and
virtualized network in from Amazon as
your Google and others all right we also
have our platform services in the middle
where people are saying you know what I
don't even want to manage the operating
system anymore I don't want to have to
patch a hundred instances of sent OS
soap unto Apache Tomcat you do that for
me I just want to use those sir
those microservices themselves and in
the far end from a responsibility
perspective are those who say you know
what I don't want to manage any of that
I just want to be responsible for my
users and the data itself now in each
one of these buckets the key takeaway is
there is a shared responsibility right
what are they not securing in each one
of these situations
traditionally your own IIM tools and the
data that resides within it now as I
mention the beginning I work at
checkpoint I've been here a little bit
over a decade now and I where checkpoint
glasses so though there's a lot that we
can talk about around Kaz B's and while
we talk about API level integration
where I'm going to really focus our time
is around the infrastructure side and
it's not to say that there are other
security considerations for platform
services and software's of service great
topics great conversations but I only
have an hour
technically 50 minutes so we're going to
focus on a little bit of what we really
do well now for those of you know us we
were the adventures of the fire we'll be
doing this thing for 25 years but let's
be brutally honest you can bring your
firewall with you to the cloud where can
you so when we talk about the cloud we
talk about the shared responsibility
most of us we have a very similar
environment we've got this hard crunchy
outside and the real soft chewy
underbelly I'm not going to embarrass
you in the room and say whose
organization looks like this but I can
tell you most of the banks government's
healthcare commercial organizations that
we talk to this is them they bought
every security technology from vendors
like myself and they've thrown about the
perimeter and we're still vulnerable
we're still exposed we're still at risk
we are still getting compromised and
worse yet since we've only protects the
perimeter and not done any internal
segmentation a very small infection
becomes a very big problem rather fast
look at target a couple years ago not to
pick on them they're a great customer of
ours but they have every security tool
known to mankind and a compromised of an
HVAC vendor moved into a purchasing
system and moved into a PC
I system then the actual trading
millions of our credit cards and many
people like you and me probably got a
new debit card in the process maybe
twelve months of free credit monitoring
service Thank You target but we want to
be able to do things faster and is this
Evan flow between agility and our DevOps
guys wanting to move as fast as humanly
possible
and those server networking and security
guys that have been holding us back and
what we see in many cases if some of the
application guys they lift and shift and
move to the cloud and they say you know
what guys
networking a security service storage
folks see you later I'm going to the
cloud I can do this by myself maybe you
can but let's be honest that you're a
DevOps folks and application guys really
security specialists do you think they
care about the security applications I
would hope so I mean they're they're the
ones responsible for it but the other
major change that we see here back to
the reason people go to cloud is for
automation and elasticity so if I'm
going to build as highly elastic
application that can handle that twice a
year sale or I'm a tax provider on April
15th coming around the corner and I need
to scale up my application or I'm going
online florists and we're now going to
take a whole year's worth of orders in
two weeks right around Valentine's Day
well my solution has to be able to scale
up now it does no good to have your
application scale and the infrastructure
not scale it would be no good to have a
thousand web servers in an auto scaling
group going through a single firewall
that sounds like a lot of packet loss
and latency to me who here one security
with significant amounts of packet loss
and latency nobody now every one of you
in this room are faced with many choices
right now do we continue to invest in
our traditional data center environment
in maybe VMware it could be OpenStack
with KVM you might have juniper switches
or brocade and not Cisco but the point
is you've got servers store
networking and software that you've
invested millions of dollars in over the
last decade and do we continue to invest
in it to enhance it with automation and
orchestration maybe bring forth and Sdn
controller would say many people in this
room they're going to continue to invest
in this dedicated infrastructure and
especially in a highly regulated
industries like financial services and
healthcare the more sensitive to data
right data is the new oil as we learned
this morning the more sensitive the data
the more we need to invest in the
security protected now for some of our
customers the question is which
applications are we going to move into
these public cloud providers Amazon
Google and Microsoft or other there's
many people out there but those are some
of the leading providers that we see or
on the opposite side how do we figure
out maybe how to use more open source
technologies within my cloud computing
to drive down some of the cost that it's
not an editorial statement that I think
OpenStack is better than VMware and
effects that better than ACI or vice
versa a matter of fact in many of our
customers you wind up with all of these
and what I find is the bigger the
organization the more likely that you're
going to have every one of these cloud
computing platforms on the screen itself
just to have a little fun right here
who's got at least two of these in their
environment right now all right keep
your hands if they got three got three
different or anyone for Ionis e1 or two
maybe we'd have a lucky five all right
sometimes I get a six for six in the
room I don't have giveaway prizes I'm
sorry now regardless of where we invest
the technology there's been this
tremendous shift from static
configuration management to be more
dynamic and agile now depending upon the
environment that you have the VM toolkit
the OpenStack toolkit the Cisco toolkit
Amazon and ash or there's three players
I really want to introduce now in the
right corner is the cloud manager this
is your traditional vCenter your
OpenStack management systems the
traditional native consoles and portals
these cloud computing providers we can
provision virtual machines I can give it
networks I can give it storage I can
attach the virtual machines themselves
and in the private cloud you potentially
have a couple of different options am i
using hyper-v or KVM or using vmware
it's example now when we go to Amazon or
as you're you don't have the option to
bring forward the cloud manager with you
now similarly on the left corner over
here we have this new guy
this new up-and-coming Walter rate
champion of the world this is the Sdn
controller so you may be augmenting your
private cloud your VMware adding NSX you
may have Cisco and be adding ACI you may
be looking at Juniper you're looking at
nuage or a plum grater that there's so
many people in this space as well
however when we move to the public cloud
so there are some options to bring forth
software-defined routers and things with
you you have to use the Sdn that Amazon
Google and or Microsoft offer to you and
is actually one of the things that we're
going to talk about which is
understanding the capabilities of their
Sdn and how it works but also
understanding some of the limitations
because if it's not possible for me to
get into Amazon and not use the Amazon
software-defined network it is not
possible for me to go into a drawer and
not use the rest and controller now
where we do have tremendous amount of
flexibility and options here is in this
guy in the middle the orchestrator now
there's many vendors out there that make
orchestration engines we are not one of
them but there are orchestration engines
to focus on the computing side some of
them focus on the security side some of
them are trying to do a bit of both the
key though is that this Orchestrator now
becomes a central place to automate an
orchestrate configuration management in
both the Sdn controller the cloud
computing manager and even vendor tools
like myself or a 5 or Citrix er Palo
Alto or for dinner cisco look we all
have a very similar management
architecture but the key is on this
Orchestrator is responsible for kicking
off these workflows these automation
tasks there's many things that happen as
part of these automation
maybe we're just changing around the
networking a little bit right we're
modifying the load balances the routing
or the VLAN or something within the
network fabric itself automation could
be used to scale up the application
alright we've gone from dev to staging
from staging of production and now I
want to go from a small environment of a
couple of the ends to a large-scale
production environment of dozens and
hundreds of virtual machines so tools
like puppet chef ansible BMC a tree on
VR Oh Cisco clicker I mean so many tools
out there can be doing these jobs for
you but they're going to cause changes
in the network and the security tools in
the past have been perceived to be the
bottleneck anybody gets this complaint
from your peers oh we've done stuff but
we're waiting for the firewall guys to
make the change
maybe I'm the firewall guy I hear more
than most but the key is that the
security tools have to change and adapt
along with the changing nature of the
infrastructure I talked about in the
DevOps world we are rolling out in
destroying entire application stacks in
minutes with automation they live for a
test case we destroying we delete them
and we redeployment of itself or even we
talked about IOT this morning as you
bring forth all of these connected
devices on the network how to enable the
security system to real-time learn about
them so let's look at a couple of very
simple automation tasks and what that
potentially does for our security model
right so maybe we've got a simple VM IP
address change although this IP address
now potentially moves into a different
VLAN or place in the network well it may
or may not have the access necessary to
go live so even though the virtual teams
are finished with their work the
security teams now have to log in the
firewalls maybe make a change push rule
base or if the person put the virtual
machine in the wrong security zone maybe
doesn't have access for the rest of the
tool that it actually needs to I get
this question about ten times a day how
do we reduce the amount of time having
reduced the amount of times I have to
log into the firewall and make a change
who likes making fire oil changes nobody
I'm the firewall guy I don't want to
make firewall changes right but the
point is is that is going to change
and if we don't start to do it in a more
agile and automated way it just means an
endless supply of tickets in the
ServiceNow helpdesk you that we have to
go ahead and manage and maintain now I
talked about the scaling up this is
another perfect example this is not just
a change to the firewalls you might have
load balancers sitting around your
webform so not only are we adding 20
more web servers now we not only need to
update the file on the IP as a rule set
but maybe the load balancer needs a
configuration change as well
and this could be a third party load
balancer like f5 Citrix obby networks or
other this can be the native load
balancers built into the public cloud
the elastic load balancers in Amazon or
Azure or Google as an example similarly
there's a cause and effect we've changed
the computing environment the security
model has to change to match it as well
and the key here is this automation
orchestration started to change
shouldn't it be able to complete the
change all the way through the stack
itself same idea with an entirely new
application stack especially in a cloud
is not uncommon for our customers to
build and destroy a v-net or VPC the
logical containers of compute storage
networking in the public cloud multiple
times a day they spin up the web servers
the App servers a database they do all
the automated connectors they set up the
security groups well couldn't ensure
that the firewalls and security controls
come alongside with it and this is not a
specific to checkpoint thing this is
every one of our security vendors should
be offering these automated ways the
zero touch wait employee security as a
service at the same time that our DevOps
folks are deploying the infrastructure
as a service and this is the
evolutionary journey that I like to help
our customers with most all of us we're
definitely here right we've got VMware
we've got virtualization and I get to
meet a customer that doesn't have some
small private cloud environment now
whether or not they're actually
augmenting that by bringing forth an SDN
controller that varies you know flip a
coin some are all in some is not the
right thing however every one of our
customers
trying to move into this automated and
orchestrated way clearly our largest of
customers when I'm talking to that very
large bank in America or that very large
bank that has thousands of devices you
can imagine they need to automate an
Orchestrator they cannot manage
thousands of security controls without
automation orchestration on the flip
side when I talk to my school districts
that have one or two people managing
everything they need to automate an
orchestra too they have very large
networks with very large infrastructure
and only a handful of people to help
them deploy things so it doesn't matter
if I'm talking with the local school
district K through 12 community college
regional health care providers and every
one of our customers are trying to move
in this direction and the challenge for
us as security professionals let's be
honest is that we have not always
embraced all the levels of automation
and orchestration that's out there this
is not new technology however automating
your securities for firewall and IPS and
proxy and DLP and encryption this is
where I think many of our customers are
moving into new frontier so let's pause
from it in and take a look at some of
the leading cloud providers and I
mentioned we're going to focus on the
infrastructure side in this conversation
again one I only have 15 minutes until
we gotta really focus in on things that
we can help with so first and foremost
the deployment of security and today's
software-defined world takes on a whole
new mechanism no longer is it just about
buying a pluck a box from a vendor
racking it up plugging into a couple of
ports and going along with configuration
management as a matter of fact in
today's Sdn world there are no boxes
there are no 1u appliances with console
ports and a management port
everything is software-defined now we
use very different terminology to
describe the same exact thing and first
step is how do we give birth to these
security instances the day zero
deployment as a lot of my telcos like to
talk about now in Amazon they use cloud
formation templates which is really
fancy JSON file in Azure they use arm
templates same idea only knock you if
your Microsoft drill bit more PowerShell
centric and some your deployments if
we're using VMware we can create the
apps and if we're using OpenStack
controllers we can use heat and llamó
templates we're girls of what name we
want to attach is the automated
deployment of the security it's a giving
birth of the instance but also it is the
day one configuration management now in
some cases we can bootstrap this
information and feed it into the
deployment of itself this way when it
comes out born it's got all the
characteristics that it needs
triple-a information for authentication
accounting and authorization my highly
accident P information or the role based
access control information or the syslog
and the net flow information all of
these things however are post-deployment
fix ups right we deploy them in the
basic configuration and then we feed
into it our own level of configuration
however as well see in a moment
in today's Sdn world even if you've
deployed the security and this is not a
checkpoint thing package will never hit
our devices unless the Sdn controller
sends the packets our way and this is
both the challenge in the opportunity
that Sdn presents for us is that it's
very easy to deploy in the cloud however
you have to determine what is the
traffic I would like to be able to sit
into these cloud instances now in the
public cloud layer to behaves a little
bit differently than it does in the
private cloud world but equally based
upon the compute instance size that we
purchased it's not just cores and RAM we
also notice these little network
bandwidth columns it's funny I love when
I get the question from my customers you
know what's what's the 10 gig cloud
firewall well there really is it a 10
gig cloud farther wall so you can take
many firewalls and put them together
however in our largest instance type in
Amazon if I put my fire one a 36 core
instance they're going to put a network
around that at 4 gig and this is a good
thing because they're protecting
themselves and are protecting you and
protecting me they don't want a small
instance to exceed that rate right they
don't want that for focus in the highway
trying to 120 miles per hour up and down
295 and I've seen some of you drive I
know who you are out there ok but in the
public cloud we have to understand that
performance is going to be dependent
upon the instance that we put on it and
it's nothing to do with how fast my
firewall is and weather pans faster than
me or if I'm faster than Ford Annette
because on a 2 core four core eight core
16 core instance this is Amazon on top
and Microsoft down below they need to
determine how fast I can get there but
you're probably sitting here saying well
everything's in the cloud is all tango
connected I need everything to be 10 gig
well how do I get that 10 gig firewall
well remember 10 times 1 equal 10 and 1
times 10 equals 10 and 5 times 2 equals
10 there's many ways to get there and we
utilize a lot of these load balancing
capabilities in these auto scaling
capabilities to provide the incremental
performance remember this is not like
your physical data center where you go
from router to firewall and firewall the
course which everything is
software-defined and stitched together
so we use the load balancers we use
network address translation we use
different routing mechanisms to send
packets in and out of the security
devices in the public cloud and again it
doesn't matter if it's a v6 firewall a
forward in that firewall app and
firewall we're all using the same set of
infrastructure within the Sdn controller
to insert not just for north to south
the basic perimeter because again let's
be honest that's table stakes that's
minimum entry point
it's securing the perimeter but where we
really need to be going is securing
inside of those applications as well it
is very easy to protect on the outside
but what about on the inside of the
organization too often a very small
compromise of a server can lead to a
very big problem I'm going to tell a
quick little story here that happen to
one of my Amazon customers so
so in the counseling department notice
an anomaly in the AWS bill they were
around $5,000 a month and all sudden the
next month they were on $10,000 now mind
you this wasn't the InfoSec folks that
sort of the anomalous behaviors that was
being counting so they did a little bit
of research what they found was there
was this rogue auto scaling group that
was created well started with one small
instance and much like we saw this
morning with that MongoDB admin
interface I'm going to pick up my
developers here but they want to work
from home they just open up these ports
to anywhere in the internet they don't
patch their systems and all of a sudden
now one of these Apache Labs admin tools
is compromised well next thing you know
people had root level access to the
subscription because the keys were there
and they created these auto scaling
groups to do Bitcoin mining which
considering bitcoins are what 2,000
bitcoins or 2,000 bucks a Bitcoin not a
bad deal especially if someone else was
paying for it so what happened was they
compromised the AWS environment they set
up an auto scaling group they're mining
bitcoins in the next month someone had a
ten thousand dollar Amazon bill and
figured out what was going on now that
was good they're not 5,000 bucks
although the question is how did they
get in well at the end of the day they
got in because there was a very small
vulnerability on an exposed admin tool
but the developers thought that no one's
going to hit this yes because nobody
randomly port scans the Amazon address
ranges trying to look for vulnerable
hosts come on of course then we see it
all the timing look we put our firewater
IPS in the cloud and within minutes we
see hundreds if not thousands of attacks
coming in people think oh I've got the
Amazon firewall it blocks everything but
port 80 and 443 however on 80 and 443
every single thing can get through it
all right
these are access control lists who would
deploy an application the internet put
ACLs in the router high-five and go home
and call it a day
nobody is comma buzz laughs but this is
what people are doing in the cloud today
they're just deploying basic Ackles
and expecting it to be adequate
so I talked about routing in the public
cloud everything is done through some
type of a layer three service insertion
even if you were IR to VLAN or two VMs
on the same VLAN there's a layer 3
controller that's allowing us to talk to
one another
now I will say this is one of the major
differences between Amazon and Azure
itself and we'll see in a moment from
the north to south they're kind of
exactly the same
we service chain the internet gateway we
route packets through a firewall we
maybe used some load balancers as an
example however when we look at the east
to west one of the big differences
you'll notice in the Amazon routing
table the subnet of the V PC cannot be
overridden so what that means is if we
roll different VMs within the same
virtual private cloud in Amazon even if
we're in different subnets we are all
one hop away from one another different
availability zones doesn't make a
difference we're all one hop away and
unfortunately we cannot override this
local routing table within AWS now there
are ways to do east to west insertion
but it is not as easy as it is to be
brutally honest in AWS AWS allows us to
override the local routing table through
the use of multiple route tables with
different route prefixes allowing us to
override things such as the local v-net
itself so if we look at the basic
deployment envy net is one of those are
virtualized Network firewalls you may
hear virtualized network gateways
there's many different terms that we out
there and I happen to have my little
icon in there but again you can put in
your own firewall vendor of choice we're
not the only ones in the marketplace
maybe the best ones but we're not the
only ones now from when York to South
perspective this is pretty
straightforward right we've got some
type of a network address translation
happening of the public web servers
maybe there's some load balancers as
well that we're using that handle the
flows and we route the package south
down through the firewall on egress we
do the exact same thing we basically go
into the route table of the
particular subnets and we modify the
default route to point at the E and I
the elastic network interface of the
firewall and checkpoint four to knit pan
Cisco we're all going to do the same
exact thing here now I mentioned from an
east-to-west perspective Amazon does
this challenging thing that makes every
VM one hop away from one another and by
default it is not possible to route east
to west it's overriding a local routing
table there are a couple of workarounds
that one has one of which is quite
simply using simple network address
translation so let's play the very
simple game I've got a web tier which is
10 10 1 I've got a database tier which
is 10 10 2 and by default they're going
to talk to one another however if we set
up some bogus network address
translation let's call this the 10 10 11
subnet and call this the 10 10 12 subnet
now these subnets are external to the V
PC the local routing table says I don't
know this IP address and I have a
default route send it to the firewall
now these firewalls would do a variety
of NAT trickery source snotting the
flows destination you added them back to
the original allowing this type of an
east-to-west insertion to happen inside
of Amazon now this is a good strategy
for a single V PC however for some of
our customers that have dozens of V pcs
and now have to have the application
guys use new address spaces to talk to
Wes this can be a little bit of a
cumbersome problem now within that I
mention that there's a bunch of network
address translation and a bunch of NAT
rules and for those of you that are kind
of in the network engineering world and
are curious well what might it look like
for me right so we've got some public IP
address these elastic IP addresses and
they get massive some type of a private
address itself all right one of which
might be the gateway in the manager some
of it might be the load balancers or the
jump host or the terminal servers or
however you want to get in and out of
the environment itself but it's
important to understand these elastic IP
addresses these are actually NAT
addresses that happen one hop north of
the far
our walls again doesn't matter
checkpoint forward in that pan Cisco
we're all the same Amazon is providing
this public network address translation
at the internet gateway itself so
technically all your firewalls will know
about is the private addresses on the
inside and/or the outside but you'll
notice on the internal route table we
make the next table default gateway or
the firewall again depending upon some
of the public address translation that's
taking place anybody's going to route
these packets in another gateway and
this works very well for a simple
architecture one gateway one VPC well
what happens you've got dozens of V pcs
or dozens of gateways out there a little
more complicated to do I mention a door
we kind of do the same exact thing again
we modify the routing table to send
southbound traffic or we utilize the
Microsoft load balancers to handle flow
and anatta through the Gateway to send
it on to the web tier itself and
similarly from an egress perspective
we're able to go in and modify the local
route table and say the next hop default
gateway is some type of a virtualized
Network appliance checkpoint or some
other vendor out there now where they're
different is around the ability to
override this local routing table and
this is not me saying that address
better than AWS or AWS is not as
sophisticated as what I'm just saying
from a network security perspective
Adger is a little bit easier to work
with refine because these locally define
user-defined routes allow it to very
easily not only provide east to west
insertion between subnets
but even micro segmentation within the
same exact subnet itself so if I was to
apply some type of a user-defined route
within the web subnet for the web subnet
it is going to now send every host to
host communication up to the virtual
network firewalls
get nothing to do with checkpoint
everything to do with the ash or stack
itself all right now similarly I mention
that we utilize those user-defined
routes in order to send north to south
or east to US traffic in and around the
firewalls right so it doesn't matter
whose power you're using we have to use
the Sdn
troller we cannot turn off the Amazon in
Microsoft routing engine we have to use
it so let's use it to our advantage now
I mention the beginning that many people
move to the cloud for the purposes of
scalability an auto scaling or VM scale
sets is a very common solution that our
application folks are using rather than
having a single instance is a group of
instances and these groups can both
scale up and scale down right now it
doesn't matter whose firewall you're
using in these scaling groups we have to
utilize the load balancers to terminate
the flows so if you imagine dub-dub-dub
my website comm it terminates on a load
balancer and in this particular case it
allows you to round-robin scale across
multiple devices so just like you'll
have a scale set or an auto scale group
of web servers you might have the same
thing as a firewall now what's nice here
is that these firewalls automatically
deploy themselves they automatically
scale up we need more and most
importantly they scale down when you
need less now this is not a checkpoint
magic solution this is using Auto scale
groups that she's just in cloud watch
this is using lambda if you're using a
lot of native capabilities built into
the cloud solution itself now this works
great on ingress however on egress these
auto scaling groups cannot become the
default route for a particular subnet
so from an egress perspective you can do
egrants proxy controls in a similar auto
scaling fashion however for non eighty
and non 443 traffic for egress controls
you have to deploy some type of a
standalone gateway device all right now
this might be used for VPN tunnel this
might be used for outbound SSH
monitoring this might be used on an
express route or a Direct Connect or
some other mobile access solution but
the key here is finding the right tool
for the right job and what I always tell
customers is ask what are your
application guys doing and if your
application folks are using auto-scaling
in the application what your security
controls whether they're checkpoints
somebody else should also utilize the
auto scaling functionality if you ask
you developers are using Auto scale they
say what's that
well let me go back to the more
traditional static models all right
they're not building an elastic
application
you don't need elastic firewalls if they
are building an elastic application well
you need an elastic security solution to
go along with it
I mentioned that we've got the term of
an auto scale group within AWS Microsoft
kind of does the same exact thing
different icons different names remember
the different TAS they call it a VM
scale set but the same exact idea
happens we terminate dub dub dub dub my
website comm on some external load
balancer this now handles the session
round-robin
to the firewall or the load balancer or
the lap or some other security device
you may choose to bring with us and then
on the inside we stitch it back to
another load balancer and that's the
introduction the one that's sitting in
front of the webform right the scale set
that represents the webserver group
which is potentially different than the
scale set here which represents the
firewall group now the key for all the
security folks in the room were saying
man this sounds like a lot of work for
me the truth of matter is that when we
deploy the solution it is zero work for
the people in this room it is
automatically deployed we're going to
use those templates we're going to use
those CloudFormation those arm templates
and the dev ops team that's rolling out
the automation orchestration should be
responsible for rolling this out as well
and I think that's one of the key
takeaways and that many vendors like
myself and others we have api's we can
automate an orchestrated version of the
configuration management however I will
tell you having worked with many of our
customers and we have over 160,000
globally I haven't talked to all hundred
sixty thousand but everyone I talked to
is saying Greg how do we automate an
Orchestrator how do i D couple myself
from these manual security processes
that we have in place and enable this
DevOps mentality to push into the
InfoSec world as well and I'm telling
the people in this room is that the
technology is there we have to embrace
it we have to use it and understand this
mentality for automation orchestration
well there are others inside your
organization that are already doing this
today bring them into your projects
bring them into your teams you may not
have the Python in the automation expert
in the InfoSec side someone in the
application side understands it because
when you set up the automation now if I
was a hacker this would be my primary
area of focus I don't need to compromise
the network if I can compromise the
controller because if I can now
compromise the automation engine I can
wreak havoc and inject major change into
your infrastructure which is why things
like the I am roles the delegated
permission the role based controls it is
so important this is not a place where
you can have one user root root log in
and do everything and for those of you
who still have those privileged accounts
out there with these simple username and
passwords we saw earlier on change those
passwords all right let's not make it
easy for the bad guys to do their job
all right so let me try and wrap it up
we got about five or ten minutes left
here what is a very simple plan that we
provide customers what do they want to
know from us and again this is not a
plan that the checkpoint proprietary
plan or the way they implemented this
with our customers dozens and hundreds
of times
first and foremost like any data center
we have to secure the perimeter so we
discuss no one's going to have basic
Ackles out there we need next-generation
security whether it's myself or a
different vendor if a question sir
there's complications
what you
well I don't know if it's superior
actually it's a lot of race to west and
the question was I'm the layer 3 routing
certian has his own challenges you're
absolutely right and let me back up
most of our DevOps guys who are full
route access within the VP C that has to
change yes yes
sure sure but this is also as far as we
separate in different VP C's as an
example to create additional role based
boundaries the question of comment was
more in these shared environments it is
possible if you give the wrong delegated
permissions for people to bypass the
security controls I mean to summarize
and put words but that's kind of what
I'm hearing and that's absolutely
correct yeah potentially potentially
absolutely but again this is where it's
not just about getting the security guys
into the cloud is understanding one of
the swimlanes
right what I want to give the server
guys what I want to give the networking
guys and how do I use those cloud tools
to create those lease privilege rights
today the application guys instead of
the VPC they've got full route level
access for everything and it's a
challenge because they're not let me say
different they went to the cloud to get
away from guys like you and me big burly
arms a lot of these cloud migrations are
people want to divorce themselves from
their internal IT groups but there are
ways for us to go ahead and create
different swimlanes use iam roles remove
some of those permissions but you're
absolutely right depending upon the role
based permissions that are allocated
that user they may or may not be able to
choose a route table as an example
well let's talk offline because we're
doing some project with Starbucks for
that very thing and I'm sorry Coffee
Company I'm to do very similar things
now I talked about the perimeter right
at minimum we start with edge firewalls
and hopefully you somehow securely
connect your arm premise data center
into the cloud and whether you is the
Amazon vgw
the azure of EPM gateway a third party
gateway of Cisco Gateway I don't care
just remember MPLS is encapsulated is
not encrypted so for all of my
fancy-pants out there are things that my
Express route and Direct Connect
protects my data it doesn't it
encapsulated through the carrier network
to get it into the cloud itself but at
minimum we have to protect the perimeter
and do more than just basic ackles more
than just basic firewall step number two
and again it varies based upon whose
cloud and whose Sdn is looking inside
the network yes I know we need to
protect and harden port 4 4 3 in the web
tier what about the web to the app or
the app to the database what about the
Pradhan vironment from the nonprofit
environment what about the student
information system is carrying all my
grades and admissions versus my reg life
which is dealing with the cafeteria in
the bookstore right there are two
different customers with two different
requirements they should not be able to
talk freely amongst one another here is
those internal controls and the future
will help protect us from the lateral
movement of an infection because let's
be honest we will get infected there
will be a breach there will be a system
a good compromise
there will be an unpatched IOT device in
your network sometime soon and at some
point is going to access the environment
alright step number three that we talked
about is the consistency of security for
some of our customers and entire
application moves out to the cloud for
some of our customers the web tier moves
out but we still hang on to those M
efforts in the network you know the
mainframes right those M efforts in the
network that are never going to the
cloud right that big iron database that
AI
that Oracle Sun server that's still in
the data center and probably is talking
to some of the most important systems
you have out there right so we need to
understand what's the difference how do
we protect on-premise and how to protect
off premises as well and provide some
consistency for you guys because let's
be honest there's a lot of great
technology and most of my customers have
bought two of everything and I've
struggled to maintain and manage it over
time all right we get an armory with the
shiny new toys syndrome or the resume
enhancing syndrome lastly fourth we
talked about it automated we have to be
able to automate and there's a lot of
great vendors out there that focus on
security automation to confirm on August
X anthem and others right there's many
cloud automation and orchestration
engines we talked a little bit about
puppet Chef ansible VR OVR a cisco
clicker BMC axiom on and on and on but
our servant or infrastructure folks are
embracing this concept of automation
orchestration we need to harness their
power their capabilities and their
ability to automatically deploy systems
and make changes and ride their wave I
really appreciate you joining us today
we talked a little about how do we
enable service chaining in the cloud
whether it's private cloud whether it's
public cloud but the key here is that
the Sdn controller is your friend this
is not just a networking tool this is a
technology that allows the automated
service chaining of not just firewalls
by the SI PS DLP dDOT's ssl offload
their x' many great technology out there
and Sdn makes it easier to insert these
security controls in the network we
talked a little about automation
orchestration and one of the key things
that I didn't want to get too much to do
it here is how do we enable the security
controls to automatically use things
like tags and groups in Amazon and as
your again the server folks are already
using these tags your security solution
should be able to consume and enforce
based upon the tagged information that
already exists in the cloud providers
and Lancias visibility this is not to
sit here and say that the native
firewall the native laughs that the
cloud providers have is no good but if
you can effectively see what's going on
we'll shoot get access to the logs or
the packet captures login and be able to
do a TCP dump and see what's going on
you don't have the right security and we
deploy the security to both protect the
assets and see what's going on so I
encourage you to talk to all the vendors
in the room ask them questions about
their cloud platforms see how portable
and dynamic and agile that they can be
because the truth in matter is that we
are moving to cloud whether we want to
or not and we can either get in the
train and go along with our DevOps guy
for the cloud we can get left behind
really appreciate you joining for my
session you guys have been a great
audience I'll be around throughout the
rest of the day both here and the
pavilion if you want to ask more
questions
thank you again thanks to our host our
sponsors and have a great day