you can download the slides at this link
if you'd like or take a picture right
now so that you can get them I recommend
doing that especially now since we
transfer slides and I don't know how
it's going to render but also when
you're on your phone or your laptop I
can pretend you're paying attention to
be instead of slack and it gives me a
ecoboost I so desperately need all right
so the clicker works while I'm waiting
on that yeah I'm going to go my way
today all right okay before we actually
get into the meat of the presentation
the technical pieces we're going to go
through a few things that's happened
recently so the first one is one login
anybody heard about this whole one login
breach cool so as you can see from the
quote stolen access keys or somehow
otherwise obtained AWS access keys
resulted in a breach and then somebody
decided to put some confidential stuff
out there on the internet on AWS without
doing any due diligence and that's
that's another recent one this is a Q or
a thread I always like to point to it
the title of $50,000 lost but somebody
lost two hundred and eighty five
thousand dollars and again through
compromised through a breach somebody
got access to the account started
spitting stuff up spent a bunch of money
and this one I laugh at but I had an NDA
he still disclosed my code with access
keys in it so that's just sort of a few
examples of things that have happened
and I think make this talk a bit more
relevant so I'm Ken Johnson the chief
technology officer and busying were
actually in Herndon Virginia
outside of DC as the chief technology
officer I do a lot of engineering and
work today to go that's quite a bit so
my concerns are that we're a security
company
it runs on eight of us and if we get
hacked that's really bad for us right
reputation loss of confidence things
like that so I actually give you a story
real quick so I was driving through West
Virginia on a Sunday the best thing I
could say about West Virginia's not
Maryland so I'm driving through West
Virginia on my way to Ohio and I'm
supposed to be taking a couple days off
of my family and I get this panicked
call from the CEO and I guess somebody
on Twitter in a language we don't speak
said something I think was Portuguese
that's something about I have something
to report to envision or something along
those lines roughly translated we use
Google Translate as best we could so it
is what it is I'm winding down 25 miles
an hour in the back Hills West Virginia
trying to be out of there as fast as
possible and also trying to sort of work
with this Incident Response process I
guess you would call it and I came to
the realization once the day was over
and by the way how this ended was it was
somebody in Brazil who wanted us to hack
a web site they felt was some I don't
know they had some something against the
site so that's what whole Twitter thing
ended up being about we weren't hacked
but at the end of the day when we did a
recap one thing I realized was I don't
have a lot of visibility to AWS and I
really don't know much about it in terms
of how to harden it and how to how to
really go back through it well first of
all get real-time events on things when
they occur and then also go back through
if something has occurred and actually
figure out you know what's going on this
talk is primarily about preventing super
preventable things things that like
stolen access keys or somebody posted
them to AWS or to github that's the
actual like a key being leaked is
not a big deal if you follow some of
these these things that we're going to
walk through in my experience account
exploitation or AWS account exploitation
occurs through primarily three ways and
also like not just my experience the
news right so vulnerable systems that
means an application with command
injection hosted on some ec2 instance or
unpatched and has some security groups
open or somebody like I said leaking
credentials more than being retrieved
otherwise or just misconfigured services
someone taking a stab at the dark stab
in the dark it you know doing a show dan
search which will show looking for
something along those lines
the misconfigured service still
networking all right I've given up on
the clicker expose credentials so when
you operate with the AWS API this is
where credentials are typically stored
on your machine as developer and for
those of you are like red teamers and
pop a box this is where you want to go
another bunch of animals for developers
so doing a little search on that note on
github just for like one of these files
god hey let's look for it oh oh no
access keys right and I by the way I
have so many screenshots of this I'm
actually just limited but here's another
one worshipped in source code alright so
you can use github z' advanced search to
to find these things or you can just use
code search which goes through github
and a ghost or bitbucket and wherever
else it searches to find those keys for
misconfigured services so good buddy of
mine Chris guedes Carnall ownage on
Twitter giving him some credit here
we've actually been working through some
attack tool sets for a bit as well some
defense
and one of the things he started doing
was let me enumerate buckets that exist
out there on s3 pretty simple and it's
not really like a super novel idea but
what's interesting is if you find and
you can see here it's like you only you
know it doesn't it doesn't exist or you
don't have access you know it's either
there it's not and what's interesting is
when you go to list one of those buckets
that you you shouldn't have access to
right what we see here when we're
running this AWS LS command on the
bucket is that we're just providing our
AWS account credentials not and this is
this is the pivotal part of this is that
there is a permission on AWS s3 that if
you say hey allow authenticated users to
access this bucket it's not
authenticated users for your AWS
environment it's for any AWS environment
yeah a lot of people actually one of the
so and we reported it to this company by
the way but like I said we were doing
some research and we found that hey if I
just yeah this is called a list but then
you can go into the web console and you
can actually upload as well so we just I
just navigate to the bucket upload it a
text file let them know what was going
on and luckily the only reason that the
only reason we knew who the company was
because of the way the folder was named
so this is just probably as a joke ball
doesn't matter to show Dan search for
elasticsearch basically you can search
on show Dan for any of these AWS
services and find them open xposed not
right it's it's somebody who just
misconfigured and didn't lock down the
security groups or didn't lock down that
service in some way but this isn't the
only example right I've got plenty of
examples for open RDS but we have I have
screenshots those and I didn't put it on
here we had a lot of material to run
through but we've got screenshots of RDS
which is a you know database service
within eight of us where people were
using default credentials weak
credentials and then just leaving it
exposed to the Internet
but yeah the list goes on of bad things
that people do in terms of vulnerable
services or vulnerable systems the way
that this works is both systems
vulnerable pool we've gotten on the
machine now this is where it gets
interesting because on the machine there
is a place I can navigate to to get
credentials and then based off the
access of those credentials I can pivot
throughout the network and if you're
ever curious about you know how often do
ec2 instances be compromised just Google
you'll find you'll find your answer so
this is the URL on these machines that
you would navigate to and this isn't
just ec2 instances these are just any
instances that actually use STS or
security token service or a role
attached to the instance so you obtain
your credentials here you pivot through
the network and there's a talk on this
from 2014 and there there's also a tool
nimbostratus if you'd like to mess with
that so the summary is of all this stuff
is there's like plenty of ways to get in
people are making these mistakes but
it's all really preventable all right so
we're going to show monitoring we're
going to show hardening and if we have
time open it up for Q&A so monitoring
there's three services within AWS that
allow you to monitor you get a cloud
watch config and cloud trail we're going
to cover cloud watch and cloud trail in
this presentation but I have a link to
the config to it to a talk where I show
how to set up config and how to use it
in this flight deck so cloud trail this
is sort of what it looks like there's a
web console there's a PA whatever way to
you're interacting with AWS if you're on
the web site if you're doing whatever
you trigger an event and you access
something and then we've got what is
this i am i think dynamic dynamo just
any service on AWS and then that gets
put into cloud trail and those logs can
then be parsed by config cloud watch or
anything else that you'd like
used to parse and analyze and use
something on those logs and it's really
easy just turn it on super simple
go to cloud shell turn it on and you
configure a log group and it's going to
ask you can I create this iam role of
course you can either be that's creepy I
am world
now that was cloud trail and it is
really that simple so it's not something
you don't need we don't need to spend a
ton of time beating that into the ground
cloud watch on the other hand I think
this is part of the interesting the
interesting section on monitoring
because cloud watch has two different
features alarms and events if you use
cloud watch alarms this is what you get
it's the information you know something
bad is happening but you don't know much
else this is where we want to get to
using cloud watch events and walkthrough
how to get like the event ID so you can
go back to your logs and do something in
response you get two source IP in fact
you can go a bit further and maybe have
a group of source IPS that are trusted
and if something happens and it's not
within that list you can react in some
way this was a pain and this is why I'm
sharing this information because - has
anyone ended up with like 30 tabs in
Chrome or Safari just trying to figure
out AWS documents yeah all right cool
not just me so you won't have to do it
for this so first I'm going to show you
setting up a generic alarm for an author
unauthorized activity and then we're
going to go into some showing a little
bit more granular depth on on how to get
more information from from cloud watch
so one thing I'm going to point out
though is you don't it's not at like oh
I'll use alarms over events or it's used
both because alarms will trigger every
time and because of the way that AWS has
parsing set up and their event structure
set up so it's JSON but depending on the
source event depending on the version of
the event JSON blob coming to you
it could look a little bit different and
that means that whatever you're using to
parse is can fit so it's a 90 percent
solution on events and I would say that
when it comes to the alarms it's a
hundred percent you never see any issues
it is what it is
so in creating the alarm you go to the
logger that you would like to log pull
logs from and analyze and you create a
metric and then you define the pattern
that you'd like to drop for is whatever
you think in this case it's an error
code of you know access denied and
unauthorized activity and so if that
pops up in an event you get notified and
you give it a naming convention and sort
some of those sort of standard stuff
that you do and you go to create an
alarm because once that's set up you
will once that metric is set up you will
create an alarm on that metric give it
some information in this case we we say
hey if this happens once within like a
five minute period do something so one
of the links I have shows taking this
alarm where it triggers and pushing it
to SNS and you get an email and all that
good stuff and I'll point out which link
that is so it works really well very
effective but again the data is not very
useful this is what an email so using
that alarm and pushing to simple
notification service within AWS which
allows you to like email text whatever
the case is you'd like to have SNS do in
this case an email this is just the
information we've got which is like you
set a metric of 1.0 and I'm a robot in a
machine and you exceeded that and that's
not helpful
we know something bad happen we just
don't know what so then rules apologize
that renders a little weird on this
laptop but the basic gist is if
something happens what we're going to do
the steps that we're going to we're
going to take here if an event happens
we're going to send it to we're going to
send an event matches a pattern we're
looking for it and send it to lamda
lamda is going to parse out the
the data that it needs and it's going to
push a slack notification out 14 so it's
how it works shoot a cloud watch and you
go to events on the left side and then
you this is by the way the JSON blobs
that I was talking about and it can look
different like I said before and this is
going to be parsed and caught what this
all kind of was based off of is this
link or said hey look if we detect an
event where someone's trying to do
something like add a user and they don't
have access we're going to check and see
if they're an admin and if they're not
an abbot we're going to revoke revoke
access and that's pretty cool it's just
not really what we want not what we're
looking for we're just trying to to
monitor not revoke access so this is the
part where we actually walk through the
meat of this the lambda and slack
integration there's three parts to it
we're going to configure a web hook
within slack we're going to have we're
going to use kms which is key management
service to actually store the sensitive
web hook value and then we're going to
create a lambda function that can
basically decrypt that kms value to get
the web hook URL and then send
information out from lander to slag so
you'll configure the web hook and slack
pretty easy add the configuration
there's some other stuff you can do here
like a cool picture or give a nice name
and then tell what tella what channel
you'd like this information to be posted
to retrieve that URL and then go into
kms and create a key really at this
point what you're doing is you're saying
I'm kind of creating a repository inside
of kms or that key value pair is going
to be stored so you're not putting the
value in right now you're going to do
that in the command line so you give it
a name in this case flak alerts that's
the alias and that's important because
in this in this screenshot this is this
is the basic breakdown of what's
happening we're giving it
basically the web clip which is well
it's blurred out and I'm going to give
you my web hook fair enough right so
we're telling it that it's the the STS
probe I wanted to point out that I'm
telling it's the STS profile so I
actually am using security token service
and we're going to talk about that when
I get to the API and multi-factor
authentication but just I'm doing my due
diligence here and then the alias part
which is really important they're
passing on that it's these black alert
so that's what it this is what's going
to happen we're going to provide it this
Web hook we're going to tell it the
repository the key on KMS we want to to
use it's going to give us back this big
blob and what that blob is it's base64
encoded and what's if you were to decode
that it's actually encrypted value we're
not relying on like base64 to encrypt
all right so that is normalized and you
can pop this into lambda and be on your
way so the lambda function you can just
create a blank function and with no
template and then go in and follow the
next step just don't worry about the
trigger just hit next and then use this
code so I'm giving you the code on how
to parse events and actually send a this
this is just for the unauthorized
activity somebody's doing something as
an on permissions for but still it's
something you can you can use right so
modify and tweak so there's where the
codes that plop it into that that lambda
function and you're going to choose you
know give it a name and all that that
good stuff and this is the role is where
you choose the role and you have a role
that basically allows that lambda
function to decrypt that KMS key and if
i showed it but the important part here
inside the code and again very blurry
but there's two pieces here one is that
big ciphertext blob that I told you
about you're going to put that in there
and then the other piece is the
you just put the channel in flack that
you wanted to go to and then again
choose the choose to the service role so
when it comes to going back to cloud
watch an event and actually setting this
up one thing that I beat my head against
the wall for like way too long was
figuring out how to change this event
source because my problem was the events
like I wanted a vent for everything I
don't want an event for just I am
somebody doing something in I am or
somebody just doing something in ec2 or
whatever the case is and I'm embarrassed
to say that I missed the directly edit
the file link there at the bottom but
I'm going to point it out so you don't
do the same thing because when you click
on that edit link you're allowed to go
in there and actually just modify the
raw JSON so in our case we gave it a an
error code and then we said if it's we
gave it two items inside of an array and
basically we said hey if it's any one of
these error codes this is your this is
which you're going to trigger on and
then we told it on the right side we
said targets and we said hey if that if
you get an event that matches that send
it to that lambda function okay so and
then just finish it sit so when we go to
test and we have a user that doesn't
have shouldn't have access to actually
create users we get this notification in
flag so we're really happy and
everything works and life is good
awesome so I think hope that has helped
folks in this room in some way I'm going
to move on to the link that I mentioned
earlier so this link that I mentioned
earlier this has basically the things
that I tell everybody to set up at a
minimum which is hey if you're billing
usage increases overnight like you
should have a threshold and get a lot on
an alarm if that threshold is exceeded
and failed login attempts definitely
want to know about that and then root
account usage so we are going to talk
about root account usage share shortly
but yeah I definitely recommend checking
that out for a little bit and also
config is talked about
in that video so for hardening it's
crazy because AWS provides all this
information but I just don't see it used
very often there's a whole framework on
doing these things with security
fundamentals and there's a CBT a free
CBT on the kind of the high level of AWS
security so our checklist is don't use
the root account audit your policies
enable multi-factor authentication and
I'll enable multi-factor authentication
on the API and we got the mess blind
stuff in here depending on how much time
we have there might be some add-ons so
AWS root account every AWS account has
one it is the king the King account on
there right and you should only use it
when you absolutely have to do not use
an operational account we see this uses
and operational account far too often
and there's a reason for that so in the
video I reference and we talked about
setting up the root account usage alarm
on my team I can tell you how it works
if somebody has not told one of us that
they're going to use the root account
for some specific reason and we get this
alert we freak out and it sucks and
everybody is kind of like it doesn't
matter what time of the day or night it
is you're going to hear about it right
so you should have an alarm for it and
you should have a limited use case for
it auditing I am so this is the craziest
part of AWS in my opinion a single user
can have in line policies manage
policies belong to groups who then have
in line policies and managed policies
painful very painful manage policies are
just policies that can be attached to
multiple like multiple users groups etc
inline policies are just something
specific to that user role whatever the
cases
and I've seen you to conflict with one
another too which is fairly interesting
so I gave a tool here is the little
script and it creates a CSV file and
allows you to see what these policies
give a user access to and it dumps out
their username and all that fun stuff
and here's sort of what it looks like
and I can zoom in there that's a lot of
information this is only like six or
seven accounts and these accounts are
basically real this is these it's
scrubbed but this is real data and also
limited to just seven people here but it
gets insane especially when you have
like a hundred users so that tool should
hopefully in theory help you but one
thing that happened since I actually
wrote that script was AWS and this is by
the way anybody works on a TBS knows if
you build something for AWS wait six
months because they're going to build it
for you it's a painful thing but anyway
so if you go to this link they have many
more pretty screenshots and directions
on how to get basically a beautiful
breakdown of what a policy gives access
to what type of access what resource
excetera
so it's pretty nice why is this
important so I'm going to give one use
case of why this is important that I saw
before which was pretty interesting so
we had a client and they were like oh
yeah you know we've locked everything
down and only specific people have SSH
keys to these machines and yada yada
yada so these machines actually stored
thi and PII and all of these machines
used unencrypted volumes if you're not
familiar with unencrypted volume the
volume is essentially the virtual hard
drive if it's unencrypted and means
anybody with access to spin-up piece and
eighty-two box can attach that volume to
that newly created ec2 box that they
gave themselves SSH access to now
they've got to access all that data so
this is one example of why this can be a
little bit confusing but you really have
to audit really have to audit access
continually because the environments
elastic and it changes and I don't know
about you but I'm sorry if I'm offending
any developers but it really scares me
that we've got developers basically
pushing infrastructure with code and all
that hard work from the neckbeard it's
just admins are kind of going by the
wayside
so anyways elastic environment audit the
policies and figure out where your your
data is flowing and who might have
access for multi-factor authentication
is pretty simple everybody here knows
about two-factor authentication that's
all it is only thing to mention here is
you can do this through a virtual device
which is like an app and you can use a
hardware which is just a new gemalto
piece of hardware but what most people
fail to remember is that while you can
do this on the web console it's most
important to do it on the API and this
goes back to the original first few
slides in this talk which was this isn't
happening because people are obtaining
credentials to the web console it just
isn't it's happening because somebody's
posting keys somewhere and those keys
are used to access the API so while
we're sitting here protecting the that's
a good thing protecting the web console
via two factor cost I'd argue it's more
important for the or just as important
if not more important to the API I'm
good just for a second strap it up okay
so to enable it easy on account you go
to security grant roles you're going to
manage MFA device and you choose
whatever virtual or hardware that you'd
like to choose in this case it's an app
and we take a screenshot and I think
it's important to to mention here
there's an issue with this though and
this is what we usually so let me talk
about the issue real briefly and then
talk about the solution that people are
using the scene so the issue is you have
to have access to actually manage I am
and so in some small way and obviously
if unless you're an admin you shouldn't
have that access so the solution that
I've seen people
you is to take a picture of that and
email it to their administrator or I'm
sorry the administrator email it to the
person and then the person sets it up
that way
awesome there's another way to do this
not so easy to read so here's a link
basically what it is is you create this
policy tweaked a couple things put it on
the attach of somebody's account and
they can manage their own MFA device
alright so if you need to share that
root account for any reason I do
recommend one password they use totp
20-degree excuse so widely use standard
and I like the service on the API I'm
going to briefly I'm going to kind of
skip passing things here so this right
here this policy on I am you attach that
to a user in this condition right here
this one line says for both the web
console and for the API you have to use
two-factor authentication this really
sucks at first painful not going to lie
I've seen give you here's some code set
to actually do this I've heard a lot
about people using hashing cobalt I've
never used it myself but apparently this
is one solution for this problem but the
code that I gave you a link to this is
sort of an example it's Ruby code and
all it is is you see that you give it
your MFA device you give it your access
code or sorry your access key in secret
and you give it the MFA code that you
have right now you send that request off
and assuming the MFA code is still valid
you get a new set of credentials which
means a new access key ID a new access
secret key and a SPS or sorry a session
token so this is running it this is what
I said three different pieces of
credentials you get back and then to run
anything you just pass it in like here's
an example using the ec2 describe
instance and we pass in that this
credential but that - key is that added
token and in case you don't like Ruby
which I get a lot of hate for being a
ruby coder here's another bit of code
that can help you out there elastic
Beanstalk is awesome it likes use it but
it doesn't use SPS so a workaround for
that is Co pipeline code convey
and github what you can do is cook hook
code pipeline into that into that repo
to point that repo and then when a
change occurs it can be automated and
pushed into the elastic Beanstalk
environment
so remember MFA only protects you
against the web unless you explicitly
enable it for the API all right roles
roles are awesome they are not an iam
user they give you permissions to access
things inside of a of us like a user but
unlike a user you don't need to like
hard code credentials inside a source
code for your applications the basic
gist here and by the way referring back
to that URL where you went to that URL
and you like exploited a box by grabbing
the credentials from that URL the
double-edged sword here because this is
how STS works but what I'd like to point
out is there's a few I gave a few
examples here like the AWS SDK chin and
egg for you Python folks what it will do
is if you've got that STS roll attached
to that instance that easy to allow
something stuck whatever it'll actually
automatically grab the credentials off
that box for you and you don't have to
put it in your source code and if you
are a ruby person use fog don't use
paperclip all right this is an example
of policy it's hard to see it doesn't
matter it just means that you can be
very granular and what you give that
role access to and once you've created a
role under the I am with an AWS you just
attach it literally just drag-and-drop
attach it to whatever you need to attach
it to in this case elastic being stock
instance so miscellaneous stuff gave you
some code here this allows you to flag
on any volumes that are not encrypted
and it also lists the ones that are
encrypted this is just a review of s3
bucket policies so it just dumps out all
of your policies and I'm going to go
ahead and play a dangerous game here and
go real quickly over some extra added
bonus content so if you've got splutters
anybody its plonk awesome so for you
well
first thing here for you that are using
Splunk don't put it in the environment
that you want to monitor I think that's
pretty much common sense same thing is
like when I talk about disaster recovery
don't upload your 80s backups to the AWS
environment that's how code spaces went
out of business but anyways first lunk
the plugin that I like is the Splunk app
for AWS plugins the first one listed
there and it gives you all this
information and you can alert on all
this cool stuff topology changes billing
etc pretty screenshots very cool this is
an automated topology builder it gives
you that's pretty cool and basically all
it needs is an account that they give
you at this link the exact policy to
give that account to you and it and
it'll be able to pull in most of this
information all right so I'm going to go
back and summary Hardin monitor do some
of the basic hygiene for your AWS
environment and really I do hope this
was helpful helpful for folks the links
to the slides are at the bottom here and
I guess we have time for maybe a few
questions if there are any none okay
awesome thanks everyone
appreciate it