thank you for em thank you for heckling
me for many years because I'm really
happy to be here really happy to be
surrounded by people who work in
security like I do our work matters and
I'll speak about that a little bit so
yeah my name is Nick cook I live in
Helsinki Finland and I've been working
with computer security forever basically
forever and and I think we're all very
lucky to be getting feedback better here
maybe it is okay cool they're all very
lucky because we've seen massive shifts
in the world around us good ships the
internet came about during our lifetime
during our lifetime every single
computer has gone online and that's easy
to say but it's it's hard to actually
understand what it means but let me
illustrate this to you indeed I've
worked with f-secure in since 1991 I was
hired as employee number six back then
and I was hired as a programmer and when
I would go to the office in the morning
it was very similar to go into the
office in the morning today I mean we
have of course much more people today
but basically everybody's sitting at
their desk
banging at the keyboard all day long all
the disks have PCs and Macs exactly the
same thing in 1991 we had PCs and Macs
but in 1991 our PCs and Macs were not
online and when I say they are not
online I don't just mean that they were
not on the internet but obviously they
were not on the internet in 1991 they
were not even connected to each other we
did not have a local area network so
when you were working with your files on
one computer and you needed to move them
to another computer you would use these
remember these some of you have never
seen these
this is the USB thumb drive of 1990s it
is a dual density two-sided so it's one
to two megabytes it's a big one and it's
actually infected is a real infected
floppy from our archives because we've
been collecting and saving malware for
well more than a quarter of a century so
during our lifetime we've seen this
change where all computers are connected
to each other and now we're starting to
see the next revolution which is
everything else getting connected to the
Internet if it uses electricity it will
be online that's the way it's going to
be it is the IOT revolution and it's
scary as hell but then again the
internet revolution was scary as hell
anyway obviously internet exposed us to
completely new kinds of risks because
before the Internet you didn't have to
worry about thieves and criminals from
far away you didn't have to worry about
you know criminals from Ukraine or
criminals from Brazil because they were
too far away they wouldn't fly over to
Richmond to break into your houses or to
steal your cars but of course today you
have to worry about them because they
are as close to you as they are to any
other victim internet took away
geography it took away distances it took
away the borders but I think we would
all agree that the internet borders more
good things than bad things clearly
there's been so much business so much
communication so much entertainment that
we have received from the internet that
we would take the the downside anytime
we could get such big upsides and I
would like to think I would like to wish
that the same thing will apply to the
next revolution do the IOT revolution
because it's quite clear that we will
see new risks we've already seen great
examples of the kinds of risks that IOT
brings well I hope when we're having our
VA tech 2027 in ten years or something
like that then we can look
back to the history of IOT and we can
say the same thing that IOT brought us
lots of risks but clearly the upsides
are much bigger than the downsides but
we do have to know that that's just a
wish we don't actually know if that's
going to happen or not so we're lucky
we've seen one revolution that we will
get to see another one in fact if we are
really lucky we get to see the next
revolution after the IOT revolution
that's going to be the AI revolution
artificial intelligence general AI and
of course AI is a buzzword and you can
use it for many different things in fact
at our labs at f-secure we've been
running AI or machine learning for
almost eight years now our systems which
collect malware and bring them in and
then run them in virtual machines make
the decisions on their own and it's a
learning system it looks at hundreds of
thousands of malware samples every
single day and tries to make the
decision if it is a good one or a bad
one
like should we block this or should we
not block this and that's a learning
system so you can use machine learning
for good obviously we use it to bring
better security but when we get to
discussions about general AI then things
of course get really scary and I'm a
believer in the notion that when we
reach general AI it's either going to be
really great or really awful general AI
if it's good it can you know solve all
of our problems so problems of pollution
or hunger or poverty it's going to be
trivial for a superior intelligence to
solve those but if it's it goes bad then
it goes really bad so it's going to be a
pretty big thing probably the biggest
thing in mankind's history and with any
luck we'll get to see that and the first
implications that will come out of like
general AI I believe will be things like
programming programs I actually spoke to
a start-up I think on Monday yeah on
Monday which was building this
programming program in fact years ago I
wrote
programming program a program which
wrote in this case C programs and those
programs would compile but they really
sucked of course but you can think about
it let's say I would drop everything I
would do anything else I could try to
make my programming program better all
right I put all my effort into making it
better it's going to get better pretty
quickly and if I spend years at it it's
going to be pretty good so at some stage
it's going to become as good as I am if
we imagine how good I am as a programmer
my program would start to reach that
level and then maybe that's I don't know
30 years 40 years of work it would be as
good at me and that's best day I would
ever have to write a program in fact
it's the last day anybody would have to
write a program every single programmer
would immediately be out of a job why
because the program would write a better
version of itself which would write a
better version of itself it would write
a better version of itself in ten
seconds it would have skyrocketed in ten
minutes it would be beyond our
capability to understand what it does
this is what this AI explosion means and
by the way if that would really happen
and like I said their company is working
on this if that would really happen we
would get rid of vulnerabilities right
now all the problems we fight with are
either humans doing stupid stuff or
technical problems and we will get rid
of those technical problems
vulnerabilities will go away because
when programs are no longer written by
human beings human beings won't be there
to make mistakes which means there won't
be any bugs which means there won't be
any vulnerabilities which means there
won't be any exploits or if there will
be bugs they will be so goddamn complex
and we will never be able to exploit
them so there are very clear
implications to our line of work from
these machine learning and AI systems so
great revolutions in the work exciting
times after 26 years of working at the
same company
I've never had a boring day and that's a
pretty remarkable thing to say quarter
of a century I've never had a boring day
at work
why because this keeps changing our
enemy keeps on changing and it's work
that matters when I was a young boy I
always told my mother that I wanted to
be a doctor I want it to be a doctor
why because I wanted to help people then
later turns out I didn't like to look at
blood and if you don't like looking at
blood you want the common doctor so I
didn't become a doctor I became a geek
and a nerd instead but in a way I'm as
close as you can get to being a doctor
in our field I mean I enjoy what I do
because what we're doing is that we are
helping people our work matters people
come to us with the kind of problems
they would have no hope in hell solving
by themselves and we can solve those
problems we can help them that feels
good
and that's very it's a remarkable thing
and that's one thing that keeps me
getting out of bed in the morning so
like I said we've seen internet change
the world it has brought us great things
but of course it has brought us bad
things and we get reminded about the bad
things regularily we got reminded about
the worst things on the internet three
weeks ago with the one I cry episode and
this was quite remarkable not because it
was a ransom Trojan ransom Trojans are
not a new phenomenon the very first
ransomware we ever found was in 1989
1989 not 1999 1989 this is almost 30
years old in 1989 we found a ransom
Trojan which was being shipped in the
mail two victims in a letter with a
flopping which had a useful application
which you would install and then when
you would install the application after
three days if they encrypt your files
and ask you to pay to get your files
back and since bitcoin didn't exist in
1989 they were asking you to pay by
wiring a money order to Panama so this
phenomenon isn't here
what really changed the landscape of
course is cryptocurrencies and Bitcoin
in particular but one a core I was such
a special case because it was a
combination of a ransomware with a word
and we never see worms anymore
worms replicate on their own which means
they typically get out of control and
wanna cry got out of control this is the
Friday three weeks ago and those of you
who've been around we'll remember how
similar this looks to the spreading
patterns of slammer or blaster or Sasser
and by the way it's slammer from 2003
still has the world record in spreading
speed it scans every single ipv4 address
for two billion addresses in 17 minutes
so from the moment when it was launched
in 70 minutes it was finished it had
already infected every system it could
infect we had already scanned the whole
internet will the whole Internet as far
as you can and we're also the headlines
after one a crime one occur I was
especially bad in Europe and this was a
timezone thing what I cry spread for
five hours those were very early morning
hours here in the United States and
South America it was very late in the
evening in most of Asia but it's
business hours in Europe and that's why
most of the affected companies and
parties and organizations for European
like the UK health care system the NHS
which had remarkable problems however if
you want to look at the bright side for
once our medical data was strongly
encrypted
sorry
but speaking spirit seriously about
things like these when you have
healthcare systems and hospitals shut
down I mean you have ambulance cars
queuing outside of the hospital because
they can't get in because the computers
are down of course it is is serious and
I actually asked our our people at our
UK office to try to collect the try to
see if the death statistics are public
information in UK to see it tell us a
peek three weeks ago but did more people
die during one a cry
turns out the statistics are public but
you get them six months afterwards so we
will see in couple of months if this
actually created a peak in death it's
perfectly possible people died because
of this now ransomware is unique in the
sense that every victim sees that they
are infected when you get hit by a
keylogger you don't see anything when
you get hit by a credit card stealer you
loan receipt from your credit card bill
afterwards
same thing with button it's the same
thing with banking Trojans but ransom
Trojans show you the ransom note and
this also means that when computers
which are public get hit then the public
will see that they are it so we saw
things like this this is a closed shop
in Spain and their door is infected I
want to cry this is a fuel pump infected
by one a crime this is a moral
information system infected by one a
crime this is from the Frankfurt train
station this is the timetable
information displayed that peopie wanna
cry and i know what you're thinking
you're thinking that yeah that's pretty
bad but that's just the time display
thing it's pretty bad but it's not the
end of the world because surely this
thing here is not connected to the train
control system here's the train
controllers
now I told you wanna cry only spread for
five hours and you might have heard
about the kill switch that was used to
stop the spreading of one a cry after
five hours so it's starting around I was
in Spain when it started it started
around one o'clock and I was finished by
by five by five or 6 p.m. so let me
explain this this kill switch thing to
you because turns out that there is no
kill switch the way ransom Trojans are
basically all trojans and malware today
work is that they try to avoid automated
analysis I just told you
we're running machine learning systems
in our labs and these systems collect
samples automatically we're right now
right now have around 750 servers
surfing the internet trying to get
infected running I don't know Windows XP
service pack 1 surfing the internet with
is 6 with flash and Java enabled and
then surfing porn and pirate sites and
clicking on every link and as you might
imagine they get infected all the time
in reality they are not running Windows
XP in reality they are running hardened
versions of CentOS Linux but they
pretend to be old windows computers so
they would get infected so we can
collect the samples and throw them into
our analyzes systems where we then
execute them and simulate an internet
environment for them so they would work
and then we make the automated decisions
now
Mulder orders notice and quite a few
malware samples we find are trying to
detect am I being analyzed and if it
figures out that it's being analyzed
then it won't do anything bad and our
learning system think it's good because
it didn't do anything bad so how do they
figure out whether it's being analyzed
or not well it depends some of them
actually look for virtual machine names
some of them look for specific
wallpapers into virtual machines because
they figured out what wallpapers are in
the background of some Mulder analysis
labs some try to detect emulation
environment or root VMware or what
the way one occur I tried to detect if
it's on the real internet or in a
simulated Internet if they tried
connecting to this DNS name it tried
resolving this DNS name this domain and
this domain doesn't exist so it should
not resolve to any IP but for example
our analyzes systems when you try
resolving any domain name we always
resolve we always give you an IP address
and there actually is always a webserver
there because we've learned that is the
best way for malware to work if not if
it doesn't get online it typically
wouldn't do much but to get online and
believes it's on the Internet it
actually executes further and for
example if a piece of malware tries
connecting to google.com and makes a
search it actually gets results it's not
the real google.com
it's a simulated Google of code but
things like that are built into our
systems so for example in our system if
you would try resolving that domain we
would answer with an IP and in the real
world this domain doesn't exist it
should not resolve to an IP so this is
how it knows it that domain resolves an
IP I am being analyzed so I won't do
anything bad this was what the code in
one hour I did around 3 p.m. on that
Friday UK researcher guy called Marcus
you might know him as malware tech he
was looking at the coat and he saw a
reference to this domain he didn't know
what it was he assumed it's a C&C server
but he realized it's available for
registration so he bought it for 9
dollars then maybe half an hour later we
realize that holy hell this thing isn't
spreading anymore it just stopped
spreading what changed and then we
realized you know somebody's registered
this domain which is representing the
code and you no longer know it has zooms
that every real computer is an analyzes
computer and it won't do anything that
this is the kill switch there was no
kill switch there was an T emulation
feature in one a cry which was used by
him and he Marcos
he would deserve a medal and I'm not
joking about he saved the world singing
he stopped the outbreak in its tracks
after just a couple of hours
he didn't realize at the time what he
was doing but this is what he does he
looks at malware and he sees available
domains he always registers them just in
case it's useful in this case it was
very useful so yeah I don't know if
you're a president gives out medals to
foreigners but
so researchers at Google went looking
for earlier samples of one occur I did
it is what we often do we try to find
like alpha or beta versions of malware
when it's a big case and they they have
the biggest model very forces during the
world
it's called virustotal and they've been
searching for all earlier samples and
they found the sample here on the left
and that was interesting because it had
a decryption loop which was identical to
the sample on the right and the sample
on the right is two years old which
links one a cried this sample and this
sample was involved with the swift
attack which happened two years ago the
attack against international banking
networks in which the attacker tried
stealing almost a billion dollars
billion with the be lot of money they
succeeded in stealing around hundred
million in four different heists
targeting different international banks
and we can link this attack the earlier
attack which happened in 2014 because
this attack was connecting to a server
and logging in with a user credentials
and a password is password which was
used the same account with the same
password was used in completely
unrelated attack in 2014 and that attack
was an attack against a movie studio in
Hollywood that was the Sony Pictures
attack which happened because they were
just about to release a movie in which
spoiler alert Kim Jung hoon gets killed
this is the interview moving that skinny
moon he's in a chopper which is about to
be shut down by a tank and he dies in a
theory death North Korea whose dictator
Kim Jung hoon is protested violent very
vocally about this that they don't like
a movie in which their dictator is
killed and then Sony Pictures got hacked
and I do realize Sony is a sponsor of
ours so greetings to Sony but they did
Sony Pictures it's completely different
this is the movie studio so then this
thing happens when the Sony Pictures
hack happened US intelligence agencies
very quickly made a public statement I
was the NFL the statement was I believe
done by the CIA but later on as the
statement was being discussed was quite
clear that the information was actually
coming from the NSA and when this
statement was made that you know Sony
Pictures was hacked by the government of
North Korea I was really skeptical like
really like this can this really be real
life I mean seriously
and if this really is true how on earth
can you know how can you know because we
all know that cyberattacks have this
deniability problem we never have the
smoking gun this is why governments like
cyberattacks cyberattacks
cyber attack I still remember with
Cybermen cyber sex
what a cyber that's that's why it's so
funny when general speak about cyber
ring like yeah nevertheless governments
are interested in cyber because cyber
attacks are effective affordable and
deniable affordable effective deniable
that's a great combination in a weapon
especially the deniability part and then
two weeks later we learned how during
collisions agencies were able to make
the call
because New York Times broke the story
turns out your guys had hacked the North
Koreans were and we're watching them do
it and this change is the story a change
is the story from those goddamn North
Koreans packing countries here in USA -
those goddamn North Koreans are hacking
companies here in USA and we know
because we acted however if we believe
that Sony Pictures was hacked by North
Korea then we have fairly strong
evidence linking that to Swift and if we
believe Swift was the work of North
Korea then we have fairly strong
evidence linking that the one o'clock
and I know that is incredible like do we
really have government on this planet
which are willing to first of all steal
money from other governments like they
did with Swift
second of all distribute ransomware to
steal money from people all over the
world sounds incredible doesn't sound
something that would really happen I
actually went to Wikipedia to take a
look at the annual budget of North Korea
the budget for the whole country is four
billion all right
four billion so when they were trying to
steal a billion with the Swift attack
that would be a quarter of their annual
budget so if they are trying to fix
their budget deficit by hacking I don't
know but it's pretty creative if this is
what we're talking about and I don't
think there would be any other
government on the planet which would be
willing to do this but North Korea is
not a normal government in fact we know
from public sources they've been
involved with other kinds of crime to
fund their country including drug trade
including printing fake money printing
fake dollars have you heard of super
dollars you can google them up there are
hundred dollar bills being printed
national printing press of the North
Korea I don't know of any other
government which would print fake money
of another government if the previous
case where I know this happened was
during Second World War where the Brits
were printing fake German marks and then
dropping them from bomber planes to
Germany to try to quote and actually did
cause an inflation because everybody
became a millionaire because there was
money coming from raining from the sky
so if we believe they're able to do this
then it's maybe easier to believe they
might have been doing things like sweets
than wanna cry as well now 1 a crime was
a failure they managed to collect
payments from 300 victims which is a
very small number
most of those didn't even pay the full
amount of 300 or 600 dollars that was
asked and most of the victims who paid
did not get their files back it was a
very poorly written ransom program was
hard to maintain hard to configure hard
to use it was a failure even with the
rise in Bitcoin valuation which is
unrelated I believe they only still made
less than two hundred thousand dollars
which is a failure and it's a massive
amount of damage for very little gain
and also what they did was that they
made a lot of the old school ransom
Trojan gangs really angry because ransom
Trojan gangs and we track right now
quite a few gangs they had a reputation
that they deliver like if you pay you
get your files back and want to cry
destroyed their good reputation now
people know they only remember one a cry
and one
didn't deliver in fact we've been
tracking ransom Trojan families for six
years now the map of the different
families actually I can only fit two
it's live half of them out here's the
whole map there's quite a few gangs out
there making these the only one coming
from North Korea is one a crime rate
basically almost all of the rest of them
are coming from Russia so how do people
get hit by one a crime well they didn't
do anything to get hit typically we can
blame the users when something bad
happens like stupid users following
links stupid users giving their
passwords to every field that asks for
it stupid users executing attachment
we'd won a crime it was a remote exploit
you did nothing you could be away from
your computer and it would still get
infected so whatever we do we can't
blame the users for the wanna cry
incident and that make also makes it
unusual because the typical ransomware
cases we look at look like it's somebody
in your human resources department
receives a job application job
application from Cameron or Chandler in
this case very nice resume it even has
active contents this resume has active
contact please click enable content
let's click enable content and you get
it education history and you can infect
it because this button enable content
button is the button you should never
click I have friends who work at
Microsoft and I've told them that they
should rename this button they should
rename it from enable content to infect
my sister
so if there's one thing I want you to
remember out of our va6 2017 I want that
to be don't click enable content
clicking enable content will execute
macros which means running a binary with
your user rights well it runs a macro
which can create a binary and execute it
with your user rights and that's unique
about brands on Trojan France on Trojans
don't need to elevate rights the
keylogger or a button it needs to stay
persistent on your system for example it
needs to survive a reboot which means
they can survive a reboot if they only
have end-user privileges they have to
elevate their rights either by tricking
the user into allowing it or having some
kind of an exploit Ransome Trojans don't
ransom Trojans only require access to
your files defines that you can access
with your rights so it's going to
encrypt your files and they don't need
to survive reboot they can encrypt the
files and leave a message behind you
reboot the machine you're clean but your
files are encrypted then you have a text
file explaining to you how to get your
files back so over the years we've
investigated many of these ransom Trojan
gangs and we've communicated with them
well I think we've infected our or test
systems and we've pretended to be
victims ourselves and one thing we've
learned is that if you decide to pay a
ransom and we don't recommend anybody to
pay a ransom but if you decide to pay
the ransom the thing you should do is to
haggle they almost always are willing to
negotiate the prices we've actually paid
we have a paper out of this we
negotiated with 18 different gangs
pretending to be victims 15 of them are
relative but no negotiate a good price
they're businessmen in some cases
they're even willing to let your files
back for free some of you might have
seen discussion with the victim who got
hit by thunder crypt in taiwan and then
complains to the attacker that he don't
have the money and the attack are
actually nice guys ok
this content has been a total failure we
can't get any money out of your country
so why don't you just have the files
buffering it's okay they actually give
the files back for free but you know why
don't you could have put good work for
us if you can it's hard to be angry at
these guys when they're so nice so
what's the mega Drent megatrend annada
look is possible well it's this one
crypto currencies and bitcoins of course
bitcoin isn't bad
bitcoin is just a tool it comes just
like cash in the real world by the way I
had an interesting episode on Monday on
Monday I was in London this photo you
see here of physical bitcoins as you
know you can convert virtual because
it's a physical bitcoins by printing the
private key of one virtual coin on a
hologram this is a hologram here that's
the beginning of a private key printed
in the center of it so it converts
virtual because it's a physical which is
the only reason to do it is really is
that if you're like investing in the
Bitcoin and you worried about them
getting hacked and stolen you can buy
physical because and put them in a safe
which means they can't be hacked from
you because now they're physically in a
safe place so Monday I was in London for
BBC they were shooting a show called
horizon and they they were asking me to
explain stuff including Bitcoin and they
told me could could I bring some Bitcoin
with me so they could actually shoot
them on the show and this photo here
these are my bitcoins I bought the stack
of physical bitcoins four years ago when
Bitcoin was valued at 40 $40 so I have a
25 Bitcoin coin anybody wants to buy my
I'm not going to tell you where it is
but it's valuable it's like anybody do
the math 2,800 by twenty five sixty
seventy so it's a lot of money that was
a good investment right so I didn't
bring my 25 bit coin coin to UK for the
two but I did bring that that's a five
Bitcoin cord and then a one Bitcoin coin
and some stuff like that and it wasn't
the interesting experience because when
I arrived to Heathrow I realized I have
to take the red line at the customs so I
walked through the red line hello hello
um I'm carrying monetary instruments
worth more than ten thousand dollars on
me what should I do and they're like
okay sure look like what do you have
well I have Bitcoin yeah what let me get
a guy and he gets a guy and I explained
again like really
we have Bitcoin on you and you're
walking through the red line let me get
a guy and he gets another guy I'd do the
same
swing it sing and dance three times then
they ask me okay okay let's let's figure
this out did you fill in any paperwork
about this when you left the country
before arriving to UK when you were in
the countries you left
so no I did it Oh excellent you may go
please go
[Laughter]
just for the record I don't have them on
me anymore I've left them home so don't
steal my bag
but these cryptocurrencies have created
the market for ransomware they've also
created the market for targeted hackings
like cases where organizations are
hacked their lets say customer database
is stolen and then they get a
threatening message that you know we're
going to leak this unless you pay us and
of course the payment is always done in
in Bitcoin the one thing we've learned
of this targeted case it is that these
guys have no idea how much money they
should be asking like in this case
they're asking for zero to fifteen
Bitcoin and got you know a thousand
thousand dollars or something like that
in other cases they're asking for
millions of dollars so clearly they have
no idea how valuable this data is and
this is going to change
it's going to change next May
it's going to change on May 24th 2018
because on May 24 2008 een European
Union general data protection regulation
will come into effect and I know it's an
EU law so it only applies to companies
operating in EU and companies operating
outside au if they handle personal
information of EU citizens which means
every company on the planet every US
company is under GDP or as well and GDP
our regulation sets lots of rules about
how to handle information and it takes
fines so if you lose customer
information and you didn't take proper
care of it you can be fine your company
can be fined up to four percent of your
global revenue that's a lot of money
imagine Google getting hit by this or
something like that so this creates a
price level right next May
a company attacked the customer database
is stolen then their CFO gets an email
from the hackers hello we hacked your
customer database we have it right here
it wasn't protected very well at all now
we are going to leak it on taste bin
unless you pay us I don't know two
percent of your global revenue right am
i right it's going to happen I mean
these create and now they know how
valuable the data is because there's a
price point the price point created by
GDP on so let's think about the next
revolution a little bit I told you
anything that we will connect to the
electricity grid we will be connecting
to the internet great and when I speak
with people about the problems we've
seen with IOT devices a very typical
reaction I get is that yeah that sucks
I'm not going to play park I don't want
to be part of the IOT revolution I will
not be buying any IOT appliances to my
house and that's something you will not
be able to do you will not get it get a
chance to avoid it nobody is going to
ask you in 10 15 years the only kind of
devices you can buy your home will be
IOT devices whether you know it or not
this is going to happen because data is
the new oil you've heard this data is
the new oil so have heard I mean the
companies that make appliances have
heard it as well so today when we think
about IOT we think about washing
machines which will send you a popup
message to your phone that the clothes
are clean you know there's a feature for
the end user some benefit for the end
user from the fact that it is online but
very quickly we will see things like IOT
toasters and clearly toasters don't need
the internet I mean you don't need a
pop-up notification but the toast is
done what you don't
but they will I claimed they will still
be online but they won't be going online
to give benefits to the consumer they
will be going online to give benefits to
the manufacturer because the price of
putting that thing online is going to be
so cheap that the benefits don't have to
be very big and the benefits will be
analytics because the toaster
manufacturer wants to know who are the
customers where are their customers
where in the world are they how often do
they toast what kind of a bread do they
toes what kind of day how often do we
have failures do we have customers in
Richmond do we have more customers on
the west side of Richmond or on the east
side of Richmond if you have less
customers on the east side maybe you
should advertise more on the east side
this is valuable information it's not
very valuable for one user but it's
probably more valuable than the price of
that chip which is going to be two cents
as time passes so you won't even know
that your toaster is an IOT toaster and
it might not be going online through
your Wi-Fi it might be going online
using low RA or fudging or LTE M or any
of these upcoming technologies
everything will be online and that means
anything one thing it will mean is that
in the future whenever we take new
appliances into use we have to start
lying every time because the biggest lie
on the Internet is that I have read and
I agree with the end-user logical and
you will have to accept an inducer
License Agreement in the future with
every appliance because they will all be
computers and they will all collect and
send out data and we know that people
lie when they click yes because we
tested this we set up a free Wi-Fi
hotspot called f-secure free Wi-Fi and
you've got free internet access all you
have to do is to accept our Terms of
Service in which we ask for your
firstborn child
you
and if you don't have a child we'll take
your pick and everybody clicked okay so
these I out these things I mean that the
revolution really started from factories
it started from ICS industrial control
systems they were the first ones to go
online now everything in our homes are
getting online and the risks we see
there's two different kinds of risks one
is exposed admin interfaces what that
means is that you set up some kind of
automation gear or IOT gear and only you
are supposed to be able to configure it
but you mangle it so that anybody is
able to configure it and we find these
regularly when you scan the internet
which show them or with riddler which is
our search engine for things like this
especially with VNC you'll regularly
find factories which are exposing their
interfaces with no username and password
so here's a steel mill software in
Germany now actually some very poor
struggling with twenty four thousand
kilos of steel at the temperature of
1215 degrees Celsius and I know these
are European but that's a lot of steel
at the very high temperature and you can
go and start clicking at the buttons
that there's no password and that's a
bad idea or we find pump stations or we
find home automation systems and here's
a tip for you if you are running an IOT
security camera to monitor the state of
your plan
put a password on it that's the people
free team is it legal in Virginia no
okay
put a password if you find these
interesting or funny you totally should
follow Dan Templar on Twitter this VI SS
he keeps finding these regular rulings
smart yacht hmm I'll actually coined a
low around this smart thing the law is
that if something is smart its
vulnerable so here is a smart phone a
vulnerable phone smart watch whatever
watch smart car smart city smart grid oh
you get the point and this is of course
a very general statement a very
pessimistic statement but we do keep
finding vulnerabilities from AI all
these things at the worst of it
vulnerabilities which actually will let
Outsiders in through the IOT devices so
you have a secure network and the
weakest link in the network is a goddamn
light bulb so your firewalls are okay
your routers are okay your workstations
are okay but then a light bulb is
connected to your internal Wi-Fi and it
leaks the credentials to anybody on the
street I mean this this is the perfect
example of the weakest link and the
worst part is that in many organizations
the IT department doesn't even know that
somebody brought in an IOT coffee
machine to the office and hooked it up
to the corporate Wi-Fi this is one of
the headaches we see so anything we plug
into the electricity grid we will plug
into the Internet in some cases we will
be plugging things to the internet which
we traditionally didn't even plug into
the electricity grid and to demonstrate
this I will show you the smart matters
you heard me right this is a smart
mattress manufactured by a company in
Spain and I hear you wonder why on earth
would you need to put your mattress on
the inn
well they put in sensors in the mattress
so when you are out of your home you
have an app and they will send you a
warning to your mobile phone if your
mattress is being used in an
inappropriate way I know it looks like
it's from the onion but it's real it is
not a joke it is a real pregnant of
course it's being mass manufactured in
Spain of all countries I'm surprised
it's not made in Italy it's made in
Spain it's a prime example of Engineers
over too busy thinking how can we do
this to stop and think about it they
should do this another example of
vulnerabilities in IOT devices cities
from a dishwasher
this particular dishwasher had this was
found just last month it has a web
server directory traversal vulnerability
which means when you connect to the web
server the dishwasher and you throw this
get statement you can still the password
let me repeat the beginning of my last
sentence when you connect to the web
server on your dishwasher
what the hell but this is the world that
we've come to so the question really is
that I mean is this going to apply to
everything is everything going to be
running all this and totally seems so so
for example if you look at the manual of
new cars with a Mercedes they actually
have the GP of statements in the
Mercedes car and you can see you know
they're running drug beer on his class
they are running for beer when is class
Mercedes I have no idea and this means
our cars our computers we've become data
centers on four wheels I was chatting
with Charlie Miller a couple of weeks
ago we were both in Oslo Norway and he
was thinking about it was a conference
and he got a keynote about car hacking
and later on we were chatting and he
said that he read from somewhere that
Chrysler recall that they had to do
because of the work of Charlie and Chris
Wallace ik-hee so quote somewhere that
it cost Chrysler 14 billion dollars and
then Charlie said that you know they
could have just paid me increased ten
billion and we would have shut up and
they would have saved four billion when
people think about car hacking they
typically think about things like evil
hackers hacking my car disabling my
brakes and driving me off the road and
killing me which is not going to happen
because hackers don't want to kill
people it's also illegal to kill people
the kind of attack that we should worry
about other things that makes sense the
things where the attacker benefits
somehow so for example turning
self-driving cars into self stealing
cars how's that but you wake up in the
morning and your self-driving car has
disappeared clearly that's going to
happen of course because that's that
that makes perfect sense why wouldn't
the existing car theft gangs migrate
into hacking that's much more beneficial
for them and they don't have to break
windows to steal your cars
the fact that cars our data centers also
means our cars have to be patched and
updated sometimes it's a little bit
worrying when you realize if you're
driving somewhere and your car is
updating its its systems but it also
makes me wonder how long will the cloud
backends for all of these connected
things be there like when you buy a car
you expect it to work for quite a while
I'm driving an eighteen year old car
right now I expect the garbha for at
least 10 more years so when you buy a
car which requires a cloud service will
the cloud service be there in 30 years
and if somebody's still paying the bills
for Amazon AWS
for that particular instance in 30 years
that's great question isn't it will it
be getting security updates will be
getting patches we can't obviously we
can't maintain Windows XP anymore
Windows XP is from 2001 16 years old my
car is older than XP XP is out of
support for 3 years how are we going to
solve it an even better question how
will these things fail when the cloud
backends go away but will they fail open
or will they fail closed and we saw a
great example of that in March when
Amazon s3 storage platform was down for
couple of hours I was on Twitter just
monitoring like what people were
complaining like what didn't work
because Amazon was down typically was
like mobile apps or some websites which
didn't work but then this guy was
complaining because he couldn't turn off
his oh one
but you can't turn off your oven because
Amazon is gone what and these problems
remind me of this VCR playing weird VHS
tapes because we all used to have these
in our living rooms in your living room
you have to have a big TV and then
underneath a VCR and you would go to any
of your friend's house they would have a
big TV and a VCR and the display of the
VCR at your home and that every home was
always displaying the same thing
it was always blinking 12:00 o'clock am
i right I'm right why what is blinking
12:00 o'clock because when you plug it
in it doesn't know what time it is and
now it expects you to go and read the
manual the manual explains to you how to
set the time and we never did it and
this is what we're doing with our IOT
devices we go and buy an IOT security
camera and we bring it home and we unbox
it and we put it on the wall and then we
go and install the app to our smartphone
and we pair the phone to the camera and
they configure it and we get the video
feed it works it works don't touch it
don't touch it
so we never eat the manual page 80 on
the manual of the camera I would explain
to you how to change the default
credentials page 85 would explain to you
how to segment your network so you have
to feed on one part of the network and
the admin interface on the other part
but we never do that doing this is part
of the problem so is anybody doing this
right a friend of mine a hacker friend
of mine was maybe two months ago he was
shopping at IKEA and he bought himself a
couple of new light bulbs light path
cold throat cream and as all IKEA
products the names are Swedish throat
cream means free of cables and this is
an ILD light bulb system from Ikea it
comes with a mobile app and you can turn
up your lights from your phone and this
friend of mine when he was driving home
with the system he was sort of chuckling
to himself as oh my god IKEA ilt system
it is going to be horrible like I'll go
and check what what's inside it's going
to be really bad isn't it and he
installed it and looked at it and it
wasn't bad it was actually very good
first of all it wasn't running some
three verses old Linux kernel it was
running a limited real-time operating
system which wasn't running any services
which had no open TCP ports which was
listening to one UDP port but would only
listen to order to gated traffic
everything else would be dropped on the
floor
cold updates were signed with a long key
I mean it was well done it's almost
surprising isn't it I mean you wouldn't
think that IKEA IKEA is the company
leading the way to secure IOT
because he would think ikx 2 plays very
buddy's cheap stuff like especially the
meatballs
I've actually been in touch with IKEA
since I've spoke with their guys there's
a line nukem of the guys they had hired
they built a really top-notch
world-class security team which has
built this and that's a bit surprising
and I don't really know why they've
decided to do this but I have a theory
because the business model of Ikea is
that everything is really cheap so
margins are really thin but they still
make a lot of money because they sell
millions and millions of the same
product all over the world the margins
are very thin but they sell the same
product all over the world and they sell
them for a decade that's how they make
their money and if that's your business
model the worst thing that can happen to
you
is a product recall now if you at any
time in the future have to take the
product back that's going to kill all of
your profits for a decade to come so
whatever you do make sure you never have
to recall the product and if that's your
business model then this makes perfect
sense it makes perfect sense to invest
money in the beginning to build the
secure platform which you can then use
in multiple different products for a
long long time to come and you never
have to do a recall because it's secure
from the beginning and that makes sense
but it is the exception to the rule most
IOT gear most home appliance is
connected the internet right now are
awful and the reason why they are awful
is that cyber security is not a selling
point for washing machines cybersecurity
is not a selling point for washing
machines when you go buying a washing
machine you don't ask questions about
what kind of host intrusion prevention
system you have
you ask questions like how much is it or
you know how many pounds of clothes can
it was that's what we ask and if that's
the reality
then the vendors in general would be
stupid if they would invest money into
security because that's going to just
make the product more expensive and
nobody's asking for the security the
only logical reason to do it is the
business one of decisions like we have
here with IKEA and we've been looking at
this ourselves for quite a while for the
last two and a half years we've been
building something we believe will bring
better IOT security into our homes we
actually shipped it two weeks ago this
is our product the small box you bring
in your home which will then create a
secure restricted Wi-Fi network just for
your IOT devices so if your existing
Wi-Fi network for your computers and
phones and then you have this separated
network for your TVs and Playstations
and stuff like that so let me finish by
saying a few words about yes about the
cyber arms race I think it's quite
remarkable that Russia tried affecting
the outcome of the presidential
elections in the biggest superpower on
the planet but this is what happened
we've seen this reported many times we
saw this reported in the media just a
couple of days ago especially in the
inter set and just to be clear I'm not
going to show you any classified
material so they're people with
clearances in the audience no need to
leave
so these reports that we saw are quite
remarkable but I think it's even more
remarkable when you see how President
Putin has been commenting on these cases
in particular last October bloomberg
interviewed President Putin and in that
intagram it it was before the elections
in that interview they asked a key
question mr. Putin who hacked the
Democrats
and he answers he's answer he's got
really important doesn't even matter who
the important thing is the content of
the emails there's no need to distract
the public about who did it there's no
need to distract the public about who
did it and then last week he gave an
interview on the same topic as really
disabled him have listened to the food
of media we should restrain I cannot
like paint release very easy matter
hackers are in good mood if I kill him
any personal issue it pritchett Alistair
Tom stood for equality ministers
machining is the not mastered by the
latest games night of the hits elliptic
initiative driving by boost in Victor
look at the right arrested three mothers
not kidding she was moving yes
theoretically it's possible
hackers are like artists and Russia has
no control over what these artists might
be willing to do regarding elections in
superpowers across the ocean but like I
said earlier we can trace back almost
all of the problems we have today to the
fact that yes data is the new oil this
comparison isn't new but I think it's a
great comparison if you look at the
largest all companies on the planet
their revenue is typically smaller than
revenue Google and Google make all of
their money from data so in that sense
data is absolutely the new oil also when
you think about oil when when you pump
crude oil out of the out of the land
that crude oil is obviously valuable but
you can't do anything without it until
you refine it and exactly the same thing
applies to raw data raw data is
obviously valuable but you can't do
anything with it until you refine and
oil has brought the mankind huge amounts
of prosperity and huge amounts of
problems exactly in the same way data
will
as prosperity and it will bring us
problems if you work with oil you have
to worry about oil leaks if you work
with data you have to worry about data
leaks our work matters your work matters
people come to us with problems that
they can't solve and we can solve it
because it is our area and of course
it's a job we all go and do this because
we get paid to do it but it's a little
bit more than a job we all could do
anything we could go on you know write
programs for write games or whatever CRM
systems and we've decided to work in
security working in securing in some
ways it's a service if we help others so
thank you for your work and if there's
one thing you're going to remember out
of our VA SEC 2017 that's going to be
please don't click enable content thank
you very much
[Applause]
you