all right everyone good morning good
morning so thank you all for coming we
are here today to do a little bit of a
post-mortem style of a little bit of a
hellish or a story that I went through
at my my current role and have seen in
consulting for a while and it's
basically how the the apparent knocking
of heads between people who are
responsible for maintaining systems or
keeping systems up keeping systems
efficient and those of us who are
responsible for securing systems how
when those things are at odds things can
things can actually end up worse as a
result of general atrophy than better
and so first things first my name is
Robert wood I currently run trust in
security for a little healthcare
analytics company called nuna based out
of San Francisco as of about two weeks
ago I moved back to the DC Maryland area
so East goes to once again and nuna just
at a high level
when I say healthcare analytics
basically what that means is we are a an
ETL company solely based on AWS we are
what Gardner and other marketing
companies would label as cloud natives
so everything we do is some form or
fashion of infrastructure or services
that we don't actually own and operate
we configure and manage and utilize them
and apply them but we don't own them
it's either sass or stuff that we're
rolling ourselves or deploying
open-source stuff on AWS or Google cloud
platform etc etc and prior to that I was
I was consulting for a good many years
so setting the stage for this for this
little crap show that I was on to use
proper language pg language so when I
initially came into Doudna I was
security
higher number one there and at the
beginning of my tenure at nuna there was
a lot of hand-rolled systems it was an
early-stage company but not even at just
early-stage companies like many big
enterprises you end up with new projects
that are getting started and people are
experimenting people are building things
they're trying to do the right thing and
they end up just rapidly putting stuff
together experimenting and those things
kind of end up in production so we had a
lot of stuff that was hand rolled or
snowflakes in some some form or fashion
we had a lot of people who were you know
they knew how a particular system was
configured their personal keys were the
ones that was that were on those they
weren't necessarily backed up anywhere
things like that for those that are that
have lived this nightmare scenario
before you would call our bus factor
very very high that is if one of those
critical folks got hit by a bus or won
the lottery if you prefer the less
dramatic scenario we would have been
screwed and so initially we started off
or I started off with with a small team
that I was building very much focused on
putting in initial security controls so
because we were a healthcare company we
of course were subject to your typical
regulatory requirements like HIPAA high
tech high trust and that includes the
security and privacy rules and so you
know like any good company operating in
that space we invest we build these
security controls into these systems and
we launch it into production and so at
the end of the journey
what will kind of work our way to is
moving away from hand-rolled system into
gaining a few it ease or a few abilities
or properties of our systems and that is
consistency observability security and
then ultimately I think one of the
biggest takeaways here is how doing some
of these things are focusing on some of
these things at least in my experience
ended up leading to cost savings and
ended up making friends for the security
team around the company
friends help you get things done friends
help you grease wheels and so starting
off we have to first clarify why this is
a problem so a lot of a lot of security
security frameworks or security mantra
and security conferences security papers
security blogs etc the general operating
knowledge is that we start by building
security into our systems and we you
know we operate and we follow the secure
SDL system where we you know we start
off we design things really securely and
that we we move in and we have you know
requirements and we have static analysis
and we have penetration testing we have
ongoing operation and maintenance tasks
and we you know we have this this nice
little feedback loop that includes
incident response should crap inevitably
hit the fan and so we have all of this
stuff focusing on building security into
a system but our security frameworks and
our security operating knowledge does
not actually focus on maintenance and if
we don't focus on maintenance what we
end up with is the situation we're in
now where the world is releasing more
and more code more and more systems
faster than ever and if we're not
focused on maintainability then our
systems in evitable atrophy I don't know
if if we could do a quick show of hands
how many people in their places of work
er in the past have ever come across
some kind of legacy IT system that they
had to patch but they could not patch
alright yeah so we've all been there so
and those legacy IT systems the reason
you can't patch them is because you know
somebody tells you that they're serving
some kind of critical mission critical
function of the business or nobody knows
if you bring it back if you bring it
down to bring it back up if it'll even
come back up we have no idea if that'll
if that'll work you know you you kind of
pray to the patching gods every time
that you go through a maintenance window
or anytime Patch Tuesday rolls around
and you know cross your fingers that
nobody
Otto like auto-updates uh on anything
anything critical where you know
security patch gets rolled out and then
you know
blam your you know everything is
everything is lights out or a system
just restarts as part of its patching
process and so over time if we're not
focused on maintenance we end up with
this increasingly widening gap of
vulnerabilities because we were
ultimately finding more issues in our
code and if we can't patch them if we
can't maintain our systems then we can't
we can't address the stuff that's
already there and we're releasing more
stuff that in the future you know we've
roll it out it's all nice and shiny but
over time it gets it gets dirty it gets
you know we start to find things
researchers poke holes in a net cetera
et cetera and so it's this increasing
pile of technical debt that we're
accumulating and that's exactly what we
ended up in and so so day one this was
this was as the company was getting
started and this is not necessarily
unique to to my organization or to
anybody's organization because we've all
been there at some form or fashion and
it's not necessarily just for your
flagship products but it could be for
you know some oddball system that's just
hanging out in the organization that
somebody rolled out to serve a purpose
one day and then and then voila it just
existed and it lived on and so the first
thing that oftentimes popped into the
product managers the executives heads is
we have to give the customers the
features that they want we have to get
it done now you know we've got business
development folks out there trying to
make sales they're trying to you know
bring business in bring dollars in
that's what funds the security team
anyways so we have to support that
initiative great the not so high
priority things the non sexy
capabilities of a system or properties
of a system are how do we constantly
redeploy it how do we maintain it once
it's out I II apply patches to it
ie as a system or at the system level or
at the application level how do we make
security group changes or firewall
changes that
if you're not operating in the cloud how
do we how do we scale it a lot of folks
believe that if they're operating in a
cloud a lot of these things are just
taken care of for you because isn't that
what the cloud does it just magically
solves all of our problems and is
another kind of misnomer and what
inevitably ends up happening is a lot of
time goes on I don't know if this is
actually 730 days later but it's a long
time later in in my particular case and
we roll out and what we were building
gets out the door it's shiny it's secure
at the moment and it is a success and so
then we start having this condition
where more people want that tool so it's
only ever built for a small set of
customers to get it out the door but
then what if we what if our customer
account jumps by 50 jumps by a hundred
jumps by 200 what if you're a you know
if you're a B to C style customer you
probably plan for this but in a b2b
environment where you're working mostly
with enterprises sometimes you don't
consider it sometimes your company may
have agreed to two special one-off
features with a particular customer and
those are baked into one instance of the
product but not another those things can
really come back to bite you in the ass
and at that 730 day mark you then have
to start asking yourself as the security
team is the things still secure you know
oftentimes regulatory requirements don't
change rapidly enough to keep up with
these things but you probably have seen
some amount of CVS come out on the
underlying technology that you're using
whether it's the development frameworks
you're using whether it's nginx Apache
you know whatever whatever the case is
you probably seen some vulnerabilities
come out you know we see it like our
stack is pretty basic
we're running django on edge and x
servers we've got Splunk forwarders
we've got a few like particular agents
we've got SSD to like log in to to like
use a be managed ssh logins and like
Ubuntu just added crazy
issue the other day with SSS D and like
for for half a day we could not login to
any of our servers which is a lot of fun
and then of course after a while you
have to start asking yourselves can we
can we still redeploy these things
because sometimes in the early days you
might not have to it's up that's making
a customer happy they're smiling and
then of course the inevitable scale
issue so we ran into this pretty
frequently where we just thought we
could throw on an auto scaling or drop
an instance in an auto scaling group in
AWS and it would automatically you know
to scale out to billions of instances
and it would work but we we found that
we weren't actually engineering for
longer-term distributed scale you know
we were doing processing on like very
inefficient processing of data and most
of our business is ETL focused which as
you can imagine is probably you know
we're going to run into a lot of like
really expensive computations very very
quickly and you know the bigger threat
to us would just be running ourselves
out of business because the very ws
costs and so after after this instance
this you know this seven hundred and
thirty day point where you know we start
rolling things out and we start asking
ourselves these reflective questions is
around the time when I got hired and so
coming from the consulting world I came
in very much like this I'm a huge Batman
fan I have a sleeve to everything which
there are no pictures here but if you
want to see them ask me so I came in
very much like this you know crashing
through the through the windows and was
like you know we have a lot of issues
we've got to start fixing stuff you know
we need to like I found secrets
hard-coded into in the source I found
you know old databases that haven't been
patched I found all of this stuff and
there was a lot of drastic
recommendations made as a part of that
and I and I've seen a lot of security
folks fall victim to this to this trap
and it was just that it was a trap for
me so
that did not actually work out and so I
ran into three sets of problems and I
want to cover the challenges that I will
kind of the minefields that I walked
into with each of these problems and and
how we solved it that's how I want to
kind of structure the rest of this talk
and so first of those was political
problems as you might imagine so just
the organizational politics the inter
interagency politics with regards to how
we are dealing and interfacing with
customers with upstream and downstream
providers etc there was of course
technical challenges which are in some
ways more interesting and more
challenging and then there were
procedural challenges so the first thing
on the political front so a lot of the a
lot of the engineering a lot of the ite
a lot of the the folks who have been
there for a while or you know that they
grow they grew up on this project this
project grew up with them and it was
their their special baby there was a lot
of questions that were very much
centered on we've always done it this
way it's always worked why do we have to
change it and Billy Bob over there knows
how this thing works why do we have to
pester anybody else but by him over
there to do this particular thing and
why do we have to write it down because
he's there to take care of it for us and
because there because these things have
always worked in the way that and you
know in the way that these that these
folks have operated there is very
there's a lot of fear around any any
potential change and they do that that
change was partially attributable to the
technical fragility of the systems but
it was also due to the fact that
customers were happy for the most part
the customers that they had were were
pleased they kept paying us and so why
are we going to fix what is not broken
it's like you know consistently using a
credit card and just paying the minimum
payment and saying well you know I'm not
bankrupt yet but you inevitably will be
or especially if you keep using that
credit card and your minimum payment
continues to to pile up and let's say
you lose your job one day all of a
sudden your ability to pay down that
debt instantly evaporates you also
tunner we also ran into a lot of the
questions of you know these things are
no longer priority so because we passed
some initial audits why do we still care
about security you know we probably all
heard this working in and around the
security field why once we get past
those check marks do we want to invest
more money into this we need to invest
more money into features we need to
invest more money into more customers
business development things like that
the things that are going to make the
business money not prevent you know
prevent money from going out the door
which is a dangerous dangerous way of
talking as you guys probably are all
well aware so a couple of solutions that
we had here this was more about how we
framed the kind of work that we did so
instead of instead of you know sitting
there and poking holes and everything we
really tried to focus our efforts on
enabling and this was like ripped out of
the whole Phoenix project style meant as
any we've had folks who have read the
Phoenix project yeah we have some hands
raised for anyone who has not read it
highly recommended it is it is like the
DevOps manifesto of sorts fantastic book
but basically our entire our entire
mantra was all themed around enabling
and so to do that we had to we had to
really focus in on a very small and
targeted set of things we couldn't focus
on this big grandiose set of
capabilities you know if we probably all
seen the like the size o mind maps and
stuff where you know in order to have
this robust security program you have to
be doing a million in one thing
you have to have threat intelligence
capabilities and you have to have
artificial intelligence sprinkled all
over your security program and you have
to you know basically have like the
terminators running around protecting
your organization and and it's not
really realistic you know a lot of the
vendors speak that you'll get is that
you have to be sprinting like a full-on
Olympian before you can even crawl which
is not really effective because you're
then just taking on more kind of debt
for your own team and they're looking at
more things and trying to do stuff that
they can't really do and act on they're
ingesting information that they can't
that they can't act on and it's just
it's more money flying out the window
for for you and it's more debt and load
placed on their shoulders
the other big thing for us here and this
and that enablement that enablement
mindset was us interfacing with
engineers for what it's worth with
regards to upper management this was
also really really important and I think
the most important thing here was
instead of operating in the the mindset
of ordinal R it scales where we're going
to go in and tell the board the exec
team the engineering team etc that we've
got you know 30 high-risk findings and
50 medium risk findings and 100 low-risk
findings if somebody wants to shout out
and give me a definition of what is high
risk mean anybody alright so we had big
impact on the business anybody else okay
so yeah pick a number more than 50k in
damage potentially it could also
potentially mean that something is
really likely to happen but maybe has a
little bit less of an impact I don't
know it depends on a lot of it just
depends on that organization's threshold
of risk but ultimately what we what we
tried to do here and this was based on a
study a study that the CIA did a while
ago it was called the psychology of
intelligence analysis
in that in that study what they ended up
doing was they they took ordinal risk
scales like high medium low and they
they went through and they experimented
with they did like a be testing with
with those high medium and low risk
scales and they presented them to
different people who were experts in the
field of the things that they were
presenting on and they presented them in
different orders at different times of
the day that different people present
them and what they found was that based
on all of the ways that they could
present and order these risks even
though they are the exact same risks the
exact same numbers that people's
interpretations of them very really
really significantly and so if I go and
tell somebody that you know I found hard
coded secrets in your source code like
in your source code and this is a big
problem and it's a high risk issue you
know if I tell that to ten different
engineers they're going to interpret in
10 different ways and that's a really
really big issue if you're trying to get
things done and if I go tell that to an
executive who is non-technical that's an
even bigger issue because they're you
know it's like how do I weigh that
against you know the this might be be
people who are telling me if I can
deliver these 10 new features that are
going to dedicate the same amount of
engineering time potentially how do I
weigh which one is more important that
one's going to make me X billions of
dollars this one I don't know what this
is going to do you're just telling me at
high risk and so what we ended up doing
is instead of saying anything is high
medium or low risk we gathered a few
different information points about each
vulnerability and this led to a lot of
just arguing and bickering among our
security team which you know arguably
you should be doing when you whenever a
vulnerability comes in you shouldn't
trust things at face value that you know
tool spits out at you etcetera but we
would say what is the actual likelihood
you know throw a percentage on it that
this thing is going to happen in the
next six months twelve months whatever
let's say if it's a publicly accessible
server and it's unpatched it's 80%
chance that it's going to get
it's going to get tipped over you know
bump that up to like damn near a hundred
percent if there's a public exploit for
it or something to that effect and then
based on what that thing is we would put
it in place a range a lower bound and an
upper bound of what that is going to
cost us impact wise dollar wise and that
could be in terms of productivity it
could be money flying out the door Judah
finds it could be customer confidence or
revenues lost things to that effect but
then this allowed us to have a much more
informed conversation with upper
management and product teams who are
influencing the scheduling of certain
maintenance tasks and specifically
security tasks in our case to say you've
got an eighty eighty five percent chance
that this risk event is going to get
actualized and when it gets actualized
or if it's slashed when it gets
actualized it will cost you anywhere
from this to this or it will cost the
organization anywhere from this to this
only X percentage of which is coverable
by cyber liability insurance I don't
know if anyone has ever successfully
seen a cyber liability insurance claim
get paid out I I saw like a tenth of one
get paid out and that was it
yeah you pay like tens and tens of
thousands of dollars to these things
every year it's like worse than auto
insurance terrible so so that really
helped us with with the folks who are
driving the the scheduling and then we
also went to a lot of the other
stakeholders not just engineering and
product teams and we started getting
them on our team and so in talking with
sales and marketing and the folks who
are actually doing business development
if we can if we can tell a story around
why a security issue or why this this
accumulating debt was going to
potentially impact the work that they
were trying to do then they're much more
compelled to say all right well you know
we know that we know that we're trying
to we're trying to push features that
are nice-to-haves not necessarily
must-haves but if our customers care
about the security of their health care
data and we know that they do
and that becomes a must-have versus a
nice-to-have then they can also make
requests on our behalf into the product
and engineering organization to help
push our agenda and so we did this a lot
with with completely non-technical
stakeholders and we went after them we
told them our stories you know we would
help them you know help them make their
case we promised to help them on things
we you know we would we would grease
wheels a little bit that way and you
know one hand helps the other kind of
thing and we found that to be very very
successful so the next bucket of
challenges that we went through we're of
course the technical issues and in this
case as I mentioned we had a lot of hand
rolled things and to everyone's credit
we did actually attempt to codify some
bit of infrastructure we're using
ansible for some some deployments and we
have a little slack bot that we do
deploy so you know do like slash deploy
bought and you know tell it what you
want to deploy and it was all good some
ants will screw should run it would
provision a system and it would boot up
load the code on and it was all good to
go but what we ended up happening is
because there was a lot of missing tests
and missing production ready monitoring
things would inevitably go wrong if they
were if they were up for too long for
example if we were not deploying on like
a monthly basis a weekly basis a daily
basis they were just kind of sit there
things would atrophy things would go
wrong you have memory leaks you have any
number of issues and then somebody would
ssh into the thing when they SH into the
box they would inevitably start changing
things they would leave it running and
you can you know you can probably guess
as that thing is running if we've got a
hundred production hosts each of which
has been SS aged into at any number or
any point in time and had unique changes
made to that particular production host
you basically have a hundred different
you know it is effectively different in
unknown ways running instances
there that you then have to maintain but
you really kind of your mental model
tells you you have one instance out
there because you're expecting them to
all be deployed and extrapolated from
the same golden image the same the same
packaged up code running the same
versions
maybe there's dev test instances
what-have-you but they should be roughly
equivalent and this was not the case and
because there was very little monitoring
there was very little ability for us to
make any kind of assertions so for
instance how many how many instances in
our fleets were running this particular
type of software this particular
operating system version you know
consider when when vulnerabilities like
Hartley got released how quick everyone
was trying to scramble to figure out if
they were running the particular
vulnerable libraries that Hartley
defected and there are some people who
can recover very very quickly as soon as
the patch got released or if they got
really access to said patch they could
really quickly check deploy and and you
know they knew exactly what their what
their exposure was for those that didn't
it was a much much different story and
so we ended up relying on a lot of tools
in this case and if anyone is if folks
are familiar with these set of tools
what a lot of these and these are not
like exhaustive or any means this is
just a sampling of the things that we
ended up using but what you'll notice
the theme here is that all of these are
codified in some form or fashion they
can all be instrumented or controlled
through some form of configurations some
form of scriptable thing that we can put
in source control except for except for
Splunk oakley i mean we would just
deploy Splunk ages and then that would
that would get us get us logs but
everything else was was geared around
the the idea that we could have some
kind of configuration or some kind of
state that we've put in source control
it was versioned in that state that was
in source control is what existed on the
box or what in the case of cloud
formation what represented the ongoing
active AWS infrastructure for example
and so as you might imagine from that
from that list of tools one of our big
focuses here was trying to make as much
of our infrastructure codified as we
possibly could and what we found when we
first started having this conversation
is that a lot of people were very much
focused on they were very much focused
on like one aspect of the infrastructure
as code process you know they had seen
like a presentation from chef or puppet
or something like that or they you know
they already had familiarity with
ansible and so they were familiar with
that one slice of the overall stack that
was codified and that was that was kind
of enough for them but if you really
start to break it down there's there's
this whole pipeline of things that that
need to be codified there's the initial
you know get git commit that somebody's
going to make you want security checks
running on that code when it when it
enters your repos or potentially before
like a pre-commit hook or pre receipt
book you don't want people making manual
changes to your AWS or Google cloud
infrastructure or Roku or whatever you
happen to be running on or your your own
manually provisioned infrastructure
you want you want all of that
infrastructure and you want that entire
workflow from git commit to packaged up
deploy on a on a server to be codified
in some some structured fashion and so
you can point to exactly what represents
your pipeline and so so the first step
here was really enumerated the entire
set of things that represented are our
deployment pipeline or our development
and deployment pipeline and then we had
to start small because you can't just
you know Rome was not built in a night
or in a day and so we had to start very
very small we focused on the things that
were the most expensive or that were
there was where there was the most
sprawl and so for us that happened to be
AWS infrastructure so at the time all
engineers at AWS access you know it
wasn't all route super admin access but
they all had AWS access
in some form or fashion they were in the
console clicking buttons I don't know if
anyone has familiarity with AWS console
but it's not the prettiest console in
the world there's a lot of buttons that
are hidden in a lot of different places
and so it's very easy to experiment
around in the AWS console and try to
find what in the worlds you're looking
for and click a lot of buttons along the
way and there's not really a good
rollback mechanism or if any rollback
mechanism that exists other than
snapshotting something which you must
intentionally do and then roll it back
which you also must have a capability to
do so it's not it's not as easy as just
the you know the commands the undo like
if you you know are typing a document or
something like that so so we had to
start building guard rails around AWS
infrastructure and that's where cloud
formation came in for anyone who has
used cloud formation as well I would I
would advise folks to not use the raw
CloudFormation cooling itself it's a
little bit like a bull in a china shop
with a hammer attached to it it is it is
not very nice about telling you where
you're going to potentially destroy
something it has no knowledge of the
state in which it's about to burst onto
like that Batman scene that I that I had
flashed up here earlier that is
basically cloud formation coming in to
your AWS environment and just like
kool-aid manning in and just and just
wrecking whatever is in its path and
doing whatever i mean you're telling it
to do stuff but you're don't you don't
know what it's actually going to do in
reality and so I would recommend one of
those abstraction layers around it that
has some sense of state for what it's
worth and we can talk tooling and stuff
after this if you guys want but start
with the start with the guard rolled the
guardrails and so we we set up templates
to for people to like create create s3
buckets that had encrypted like that
enforce the SSE flag as policy you
couldn't do any at three buckets unless
you had you had them set up in this way
you ran this CloudFormation template
wham-bam
you're done and you have a compliant
secure s3 bucket then we started
creating some process and some controls
around how people created security
groups and so we didn't have all of
these security groups that were just
blatantly wide open to the world and
attached to every instance and then we
started creating ones for EBS volumes
for RDS instances for redshift clusters
and we we slowly but surely started to
codify our AWS infrastructure and that
will then what we ended up having to do
was then go back and build in monitoring
or checks to find stuff that was not
that was not created by that automated
infrastructure and the stuff that you
know persisted in that manual snowflake
fashion and for that what we ended up
finding was that tags applied by some
kind of CI server or you know some kind
of automated process was super super
helpful we could tag things with a
release we could tag things with a
certain um with a tool that created it
with the person that created it with the
timestamp it was created thing things
like that if an instance got SS aged
into we could have a lambda function
that went in and mark that as dirty or
something like that and then you know
market for redeploy after the fact
there's a whole bunch of things that we
could do to to slowly start to remove or
reduce that that snowflake
infrastructure and then at the end of it
we end up with much more stable stable
infrastructure that we actually you know
we can provide CloudFormation templates
to an auditor even which we've had
success doing and say here is and you
know instead of giving us giving you
access to the console which you know
you're not going to be able to find your
way around anyways because it's an AWS
console here is here are some templates
and you can go through and see exactly
what ports are open you can see exactly
what settings it's all commented for you
it cetera et cetera and you know and
it's much easier to to understand and
make assertions about and the same thing
went for same thing went for
applications so we used we're a heavy
Python shop we just started
experimenting a go so we started off
with bandit if anyone's familiar with
the tool we built a bunch of custom
checks then we started off using gas
which is another Python like Len
thing tool integrated those into the get
flow process things like that and one
big thing that I want to emphasize here
is that we tried to use the some of the
concepts from test-driven development to
improve our process and so we would
start by writing a test for a thing
whether it's some some crappy AWS state
like s3 buckets not using the SSE flag
or not being clouds warmed or etc etc we
would describe a compliance where ideal
state in the form of a test we would run
it we would keep running it we would
keep posting the results in the slack
until we were able to make the changes
and those tests came back green after a
certain point and so eventually what
they ended up giving us is that we of
course during the during the improvement
process we could see how we're doing and
we could we can make assertions about
things but one of the other really nice
benefits that came from that is that
over time if anyone does make a
snowflake change in the future
we've got tests automatically running
that will tend that will catch those
things faster and so we can respond to
them sooner or we can just you know set
something up to automatically kill it
and have it be a vendor of and based off
as a result of our test and so we found
taking that test driven approach was
really really effective for us highly
recommend and so the last bucket of
things was on the process people tech
and process so how many folks have ever
worked an environment where you have
somebody experimenting with things
they're tinkering and then that
experiment all of a sudden becomes
mission-critical business business
software yes so when you're
experimenting with something those
things are oftentimes they're oftentimes
not done with production rigor because
that would slow the experiment down
exponentially you know you don't want to
have to go through and apply the entire
set of like ISO 27000 controls to a
little bit of experimental code because
you know what's the point of
experimenting if you have to you know
spend several months doing it they want
you know engineers want really quick
fast
experiment but if they run a run an
experiment after doing so people love it
and they automatically escalate it up to
production status you're going to be in
trouble because then you have more of
this snowflake
one-off code kind of running everywhere
and then as part of that if you know if
you're if people are not doing pairing
if they're not writing things down
things like that you have a lot of this
knowledge silo followed by attrition or
bus factor incidents as we had I've
heard horror stories and some
organizations in the in the valley where
you would have you would have somebody
had set up a system they leave the
company their key was the only one on
that box they don't know how to redeploy
it and you've got people literally like
tweeting at the person seeing if they
you know happen to like steal like take
their keys with them if you will and
you're almost like welcoming the fact
that or you know hoping for the fact
that they did steal company property or
you know take things with them after
after they left so that way you can
maintain your system instead of being a
big issue it's a it's a sigh of relief
and like unfortunately like these
stories are real to happen and then of
course you know we talked about this
stuff a little bit earlier but if things
can't be maintained then they're left
running forever if they're left running
forever then they inevitably atrophy and
then of course if they at some point
they become too critical in the
organization then and their and their
atrophied too far then they become too
fragile to make any changes and if
they're too expensive then the risk
you're trying to mitigate by making
changes to it then the business is going
to win and just shut you down and so and
what we ended up finding is that we had
this whole set of just organizational
debt through process and so we ended up
creating new things to solve these
problems and so we just have more stuff
kind of compounding on itself
it's like continuously it was like
paying your bills with your credit card
and so similar to the technology debt
consolidation we ended up doing a very
similar thing for the process
consolidation and so
here we started off we identified all of
the mission-critical processes that were
helping us serve these strategic
objectives for the organization in our
case it was keep our customers happy
keep systems up and keep systems secure
those were like the three things that we
focused on and so we had processes like
how do we redeploy the VPN how do we
check code in and how do we maintain the
how do we maintain the git server how do
we maintain Jenkins how do we maintain
like who maintain the Confirmation
abstraction tooling that we that we were
using things like that and this took a
lot of doing but we would we we did like
hack days just to figure out something
like reverse engineer something because
people left you know people forgot etc
and we would just go through and reverse
engineer everything and then document
the hell out of it once you document
everything even if it's a 30 step list
you have a you have a run book with
which to work you have a starting point
and then for us we just really focused
on writing code in very small batches to
say if you can take a run book and turn
it from 30 steps to 25 steps with a
script great the next iteration UNIX
tabbed you get it it you can do you can
take it from 25 steps down to 15 and
eventually you can get that process or
that run book down to a single button
and one of the big cultural things that
we really had to push on people with
documentation was that most people write
Docs they write them once they never
touch the docs again they're like well
documentation is written it's like we've
all seen it when we go to use an
open-source project it's like dammit if
this thing didn't run on the dev system
it doesn't run on mind that the readme
hasn't been updated since the project
first started I screw it I'm going to go
write my own and so you know whenever we
found bugs in the dock very much like
bugs and code we had to make it a
culture thing to go back and fix the
bugs in the dock we call it we tracked
and and handle those very much like we
would
technical bugs
so one of the things to consider here is
my my particular situation here is very
much focused on a small set of focused
prod products when you're thinking about
this stuff at scale if you're working in
a large enterprise or alongside a large
enterprise is there going to have tons
of legacy IT systems that have just kind
of accumulated over the years or things
that are serving some some business
process and there's a lot of bloap that
just gets distributed everywhere and so
executives are then forced to make the
decision between paying down that
organizational and technical debt across
an entire portfolio of things versus
bringing in new projects that are going
to make the make the enterprise money
and so one thing that I wanted to call
out here is that I've seen this work
very nicely in large organizations in my
consulting days is that taking the
taking a portfolio management approach
where you map out everything like all
the applications you're maintaining or
all the servers that are up or something
like all of the basic inventory stuff
that we're going to want to see anyways
if you have that and you can attach some
kind of number even if it's not entirely
accurate that represents the total cost
of ownership or the total cost of
downtime for that thing and you can map
it to a to some kind of business process
or like some kind of what in the hell
does this thing do question and answer
then then you can start to just work
your way from the bottom up if you have
like this outdated thing that serves a
process that only one person in the
company cares about yet it represents
you know a fairly significant chunk on
your on your budget list or your your
application inventory list and it's and
it's expensive to maintain nobody wants
to touch it it's you know it gets
included in in audit scopes things like
that see if you can just remove it see
if you can just kill it and if you
slowly start to just work your way like
small targeted projects not doing this
stuff at a big grin
scale you'll slowly but surely chip away
at it so wrapping things up
I've got wrap up and then some like
actionable things that I would like to
leave like a couple of to do's for
everyone homework if you will so this
pretty much this problem almost always
starts with misaligned priorities which
in my opinion isn't always a bad thing
engineering teams are going to be
focused on building features business
people are focused on stirring up you
know building the brand you know
bringing money into the organization
things like that and those are not
always a terrible thing but over time
you have to start to bring people back
together and figure out where the
mutually aligned benefits exist and then
don't believe the vendor snake-oil here
this is this is going to be a really big
one almost all folks will tell you that
they've got the silver bullets solve
your problem and it is absolutely not
true
you know you could even look at like the
like the Gardiners like maps and the
fact that there are so many different
segments out there tell you that each
one plays in a different space and so so
as nice and steak dinners are don't fall
victim to to the snake oil and and I
don't say this to say that vendors are
necessarily bad they can help you get a
lot of things done but don't believe for
a second that they're going to solve all
your problems you have to figure out
where to apply them in an intelligent
useful fashion you have to think about
your program systematically and you have
to use them as tools in a much larger
picture and then one thing that I think
is really important here is don't design
just for security upfront don't just
focus on like building security into
your system and focusing on the SDL and
everything's going to be alright because
if a system starts secure but you can't
make changes to it it will over time not
be secure and I think that's a really
important thing that is oftentimes
neglected in our in our industry jargon
and talking and so three things that I
think are worthwhile taking on taking
away from this first thing is within
your organization's find these systems
are
sizes that exist around your
organization who in the world owns them
what the cost of those things are even
if you just ballpark it even if you just
put a label on it like a lot not a lot
that's still going to help you just
start to visualize where the most amount
of debt lies around your organization
and then try to find that 80/20 type of
improvement area so sometimes you know
you don't want to take on the big 80
percent amount of your effort to have a
very small marginal improvement you want
to make small marginal improvements or
you want to make small investments in
your time and resources to have big
returns on investment sometimes it
doesn't always work but my bet is that
if you really start to map these things
out and figure out where all of your
time is going and this might even go for
like unplanned like interrupts work on
your own team for instance on our
security team we found that we were
handling a lot of access control
requests and they were constantly just
burdening us and we're doing a lot of
interfacing and our purple team was like
constantly bogged down with like nagging
people any time security alerts came in
and so we just made some investments in
like little slack bots to handle like we
can type slash request access and you
know we handle all we have a slack bot
just manage all of the manager middleman
communication and just log something for
us we could veto things if we want we
can you know we write little tests in
there about the things that we want to
improve but we automate away the things
that are taking up the most of our time
and then with regards of critical
processes this is all about not letting
yourself fall victim to the bus factor
and so I I think that process is
oftentimes tightly coupled with with
technology solutions or like you know a
bit of a piece of technology that might
need to be maintained at some point but
always make sure that you define
documentation for a process for a for a
piece of technology as part of the
condition that is done so don't call a
project done if it's not documented if
multiple people haven't run through it
if it's not tested things like that like
if you bake those things into
the circumstances that are going to let
that thing proceed from experiment to
production ready system and production
ready infrastructure and you
consistently like you know every every
couple of months or so like run through
the run books see if it's still accurate
and if it's not fix it you know treat it
like bugs and I think you'll be I think
you'll find yourself in a good place and
so with that thank you and does anyone
have any questions