hi thank you so much for shake up
hangover II coming out a little bit
earlier so I'm super excited or burning
you know so several months ago when we
were first under CFP standing that sends
in his proposal and be portrayed like I
was like okay this sounds like a regular
[Music]
description
what's that
so without further ado sandy camp
everyone
and I watch your project I've been
working on so this is the first time
I'll be talking about opens great
instance that are supposed to be fun so
this is called NASA tank and it's a it's
a update from earlier urgent from 2002
written proof of concept effective first
let's just talk about that in general
that is network address translation
so we're old when most of us are gonna
be familiar with that we have a router
at home that is on a network that can to
multiple devices come around your
network to Letarte like this now what is
the neck so an app is a device so when
that's basically device that allows to
have multiple devices on network use a
single public IP drums so you may have
heard that we're running out of ipv4
space and that I totally but until then
we used to have all of our devices
public IP address space so when you
would connect your DSL or cable modem
really that's just a public IP address
that is accessible from anyone else
across the internet then router
manufacturers basic
progress came out when they had network
address translation firewalls have just
above where they will have eternal
subnet so even have a devices on top and
those elect me from IDs like ten dogs
you're about 0.1 or 190 ones it's a
viewer done whatever and those are only
accessible within your and then they'll
need your router and your router will
then translate that to the public IP
that's the router and in many cases a
router will also beautifier wall so in
reality the rat watching protects you
from hook ingress so if someone is
trying to
- device under machine they will be able
to be survivors and walk it unless we
explicitly set up port forwarding DMC
etc and another thing - uh what know
what that thing is the goal of Nappanee
is to bypass your net
so as an attacker I've moved higher
English it's a lot of fun people to
attack things and I want to bypass
someone else's net so you haven't had an
open you have some devices on your
network
why can't you be able to access through
devices as if they want behind a
networking party and why is this
interesting
well this is a fella so a valve above my
computer I have something like 28 or 30
services they're just listening and
anything most of these are actually on
the public in space so that means if
you're on the same network as me
you can talk to all these device oldest
obligation so some of us I'm going to
eat your sucks I don't even have Soto's
but I have a son was happily 18 that's
running on my computer
24/7 I didn't even know that until I did
this until I reported this Cosmo output
I hit like fun bunch of random note
clients these aren't no J's things right
running parallels parallels is just
listening or whatever because the
Spotify so you to Spotify but that means
it's listening public so anyone can even
connect to Spotify on two different
words it's listening so who knows what
those are that breaks there are going to
be so many vulnerabilities there are
action over both execution stuff that
key not just this year now normally you
are protected from the public by your
neck
but we nothing works this they also make
gold if we want the victim let's say you
picked a machine to visit a website
because that's pretty easy to do and
that's maybe it looks like that maybe
not malicious website but we have
malicious Allen right you just
facebooking and get some JavaScript
running that is just as good as getting
them to if it was malicious website so
let's see how we can do that but let's
understand let's learn a little bit more
about that and how it actually tracks
connections so that Excel will look at
this is an IP header in the TCP header
of a TCP back let's say you're
connecting to a web server on port or
4-3 or maybe you're going to send these
IP packets out and you're gonna have a
source address which will be your
internal IP address like and not fear of
drug to a destination which is where the
Google comm that have the source and
destination party and those will be
tracked by the net
let's see the video here you might it
might be difficult to see food I eat but
essentially on the top I'm sticking from
my local machine and from the bottom I'm
sipping from the remote machine and here
basically we can see that my internal IP
and off by about what's up my name is
connecting out if you are one of four
public I repeat but on the blog machine
it doesn't see the ten dot it's either
207 not which is a public enemy so
that's the conversion of the current now
if there's something in that that we see
that's pretty interesting as the
progress came out we started to do
things like which I could use things
like that Kiki and FTP to stop working
as those people install it in that and
the reason is FTP
uses multiple reports so if you're
having some where you'll connect of
course when you want hopefully your on
everything but if you were if you were
you connected a 20-watt
on some machine and you would say this
is a real example something like that
and you say important you said important
command and the port command says eight
connect back to me on this IP important
and we are empty be client opens the
second important and it's now waiting
for a connection to come back so when
you say a list I want to list all the
files that's on happening over that
she's over that it can be special
second connection and what's really cool
is that this is a non-conventional not
out of contention
so your computer your machine is now
hoping they'll to support once you agree
and it says hey if you P server just
back back to one two three
now as soon as you're going to nap that
phrase just software so what didn't that
vendors do it without our vendors do is
they invented something called
application level gateway for Al cheeks
and what these do is they write
basically inspection so they were
actually now looking at maybe oh you
know what I know were 21 TCP is actually
typically used for FTP so if I'm going
to watch the commands and I scale or
command gets sent out and it says hey
like that mean on or what you read I
think owes report forward one two three
back to this person when I see that
circumvent so we can use this to
actually to actually connect through
someone's land even if they're not maybe
doing enough to be now what I'm trying
to learn I mean a lot of this stuff may
be basically to some people but I'm just
going to go over something that I used
to learn so time with reading guard sees
our how something works if it's a
protocol well-defined protocol that
nobody in part C on it so you can always
to check those out you can see how the
port command up to P for example now you
know the 10 I started playing with this
idea I found that they sort of groups of
restricting points I basically had a
curtain thank you for deep and then
there was an update to do like these
Firefox or Chrome ladies but the editor
for the description list because I was
thinking of getting you get to use the
web browser to do an HTTP POST and send
FTP commands on quickly we want and
until those commands being the positive
the problem was the browser's then
started walking port so here's actually
source code from prom who needs to dip
watch important anyone around that time
isn't playing around and listen thinking
okay we'll see some keyboards or sixteen
minutes so this is a five thousand five
ninety different possibilities what is
gonna give important that is larger than
sixteen minutes
what'll happen and essentially what will
happen is in many cases it will overflow
we only 11 16 bits so what if you create
a form an HTTP form and you send it to
not a 16-bit address but a 17th of
engines and that 17 bits is the port you
want in this example six six six seven
which is IRC +65536 which is just a one
date in the 17th well what happens is
that you're going to see example like if
we take port in step 2 6 5 5 3 6 + 137
and then we printed we did 1 through 7
and assuming we only have 16 bits of
space so that extra bit of data gets
dropped so when the here browser is
looking at the screen in your form and
says oh this huge about her large and 16
bits isn't in my restricted port list
and then this says it'll block the TCP
stack which is in live scene and not
only has 16 bits of space he now drops
that extra bit and you just bypass the
restriction within the browser now I'm
connected so that's pretty cool
here's an example of IRC I received she
what I ended up using really like I
receive so here is I just selected any
green what I will send to an IRC server
of our connect name you have your
username you have your nickname I said
my dick name and I said they're quite a
message not a big deal now what's
interesting about I receive my selected
IRC as an example is because it's very
similar to HTTP when the fact that it's
a new line are mutable right many
protocols are binary but HTTP is
coordinating oculus an IRC of a new line
based text based protocols so when
you're making committee should be
serving for 80 and you say you can get
/h would be 1.0 of us whatever that will
give every command phone me long and
what's cool about that is a new book
post you say post and then some headers
and then you can scroll the content of
that David so if your application level
gateway is now looking at this and says
oh I hear there's your mail guitars and
I see ok I see oh I get the great a
forum we can create a forum in
JavaScript generated added
Paige lue Linden and that to our report
which again is overflowed by our IP
staff in terms of two six six and seven
this is one ecstasy to the seventh your
ALG on your router to the season higher
state measures even though your browser
is so now you confuse the router
but isn't no there's no idea that your
browsers to be getting x86 and so in
this instance IRC and you now control
this post either within the content of
the track which is really gold or
whatever you want
and please looking why my line and your
brother's like okay po / I don't want
that means I don't know that my reseach
remember thinking I'm going to ignore it
post post polling whatever
I don't know that line I'm going to
ignore it and then it gets to go to the
content and it's like okay I have this
post effects data that's like IRC
driving little cool thing about IRC is
using the DCC chat or a t65 and TCC
words just like community where you're
opening a port on your computer and
you're really great power is very
beneficial and very helpful in here it
says oh they're trying to open port 22
and therefore that back to the user
now I was trying to do this the only
thing is the very first line you'll see
the way DCC works as you see by a
message you turn a DCC chat my name I
addressed before now what what's goals
we've defined important which means we
can select any port we want a corkboard
but we had to know by now when I was
writing this I was just using that users
public ID trips because I can get that
problem but that wasn't working and
that's I realize because the routers
doesn't be looking from an internal Anki
so how did the each my IP address from a
browser in 2010 there was something
called my limits
is anyone heard of body connected in
JavaScript
well this it was in Firefox for like two
months before they realized this was a
good idea but during that time I got to
use it
so here's my deck code so essentially
direct people to actually use Java
classes factories whatever they are and
then to get them blind leads because
then you can pull you can actually get a
local address you can find the socket
and then ask there's two table factory
using my little eye business you now
have the internal IP address of the user
right browsers normally don't reveal
that information now you can take that
and you know you can take that update
the five FS of the GCC chat and now the
rounds like oh this is a totally
legitimate DCC chat I better put forward
reports me to or whatever another port
and in your post day that you don't need
to do one courtly and inside multiple
VCC chimes because then sixty five
thousand fifty CC times if you want will
be every single quarter back to the
victim just by them visiting a website
now unfortunately no that was 2010 so
life connection no longer exists it was
with their God and they fix the overflow
teaching guide to me whoever loathing so
I was kind of playing with this recently
Montgomery
are there other other look mechanisms
that we need use so I went through the
clinic's netfilter infiltrated Linux is
my key snack and it was great because
the open source you can see politics
and the first thing I did doesn't I made
it to this spreadsheet and this protein
is all the application of gateways
including supports so it has sip FTP IRC
so stuff I never heard of like sustain I
think it's a backup service Amanda and
some other white stuff like HTTP three
and then I went to to chrome source code
and I saw okay what are those reports
that our students you can't get out port
evasion technique there are many ones
that aren't blocked we're saying again
never the ER that sit which is to be
tzitzit and BabyTV only one of these
three three recall such as voice over IP
so we're looking at what rome doesn't
block so and thats it was pretty good to
this if it isn't pretty common that's a
voice over IP protocol virtually every
IP Constance it and sieve is they say
like FTP
so it would sit a nice thing about SIF
and Doris pendant to st. is because the
SIP is also a B you like basic vertical
the benefit here is that the router can
ignore the life of you don't know and
we'll look at the line that doesn't for
example in the middle of your post so I
attempted to do the same thing I ran
into decision and the zip also be nine
pages you need to include your ideas so
this wasn't working so late okay maybe
we can use them they a night to
discovery some other way
I started looking at little features in
the browser we'll go over some of that
in a bit but basically I'm going in
chrome either like prone colon slash
slash actually learn whole instrumental
features although the w3 use website and
look into some new standard they're
coming out rather simpler the words and
do things that are available and I'm on
web RTC are these pretty cool sort of
peer-to-peer audio and video and in
order to do peers of your audio and
video is pretty easy it's over we've
been participating some public IP but if
you're doing Intermountain Atlantic we
need to know the IP address the internal
business so for that mechanism
they'd introduce ice and I support stun
and turn and technically it support some
other stuff but some intern is actually
determine what type of NAT you're behind
so you will your browser can now has
stability with WebRTC to connect to
acidotic turn server and it says hey
you're on this type of event and also
here is your public IP address to me to
make one versus work in Charlie on the
network you will actually connect
directly to look like idiots so the
browser now gives you a local IP address
so this is pretty exciting that
basically makes its attack work all over
it
this was super exciting until I was
making a presentation last night and it
was working that's why I refreshed and
I'm like I took a screenshot and
apparently they just fixed this so now
the browsers don't give you an internal
IP address instead they use font or a
DNS and they generate they've got a
local address which only works on your
network so why don't you don't know the
looks like your dress anymore
it's tell you goodness like weird
hex hexadecimal but if you uie legate
they docto and that's only accessible
within your network
this sucks so here something on the top
I am just doing a speed up of two
different ways why he wants to take
throughout two and yet it's not like you
creepy doc to exists dollars you free
does not exist and I couldn't happen so
I do netcat I'm got to to a word that
isn't open and that's 79 and immediately
it says connection with the way the
ability connection is refused is that
TCP lets you have all the artists to go
reset and that's how I can connect
somewhere and sent immediately know
there's nothing open Thomas however what
that means is they were supposed to do
now what the court is hoping like on
port 80 which I also did then you get
into guitars team gets in that and that
is to start this up to a three week
engine what is interesting about those
two is that they reach my feet but when
you hit a dog one two three what was
happening is you send a bunch of our
requests for a host and nothing gets
responded so isn't times I've heard
whatever your local fine artists so what
I'm going to get abused that from the
browser what if we create an image and
we sent an image to just a random IP
address for now exists let's say fine
your network it will return essentially
and you add event handlers all on air
and on success it will either area
because that where it's not okay but the
height she teams up or it will succeed
because or is open from the machine is
up or it won't air until and seconds
later but to garrison heatedly that
means it exists so literally just take
the top one the top most common gateway
of IP addresses like kind of zeros
Monty was about block and then do that
for the there is a 256 movies that are
common there for everyone and he's say
in this code right here we generate an
image of dog script it's just plain HTTP
colon slash slash in this case when I to
ones dignity requirements and then
extend it to a kitten kitten so you
don't see this image it's not a real
good and we have too many others on air
and unload and all those do if they time
they say how long did it take to either
succeed or every it's less than one
second you know this post exists so it
wants for 250 and 300 coasts and in one
second you now know oh this kid wait
exists why not to wants figure out one
10.00 I want does noises so now I know
what the Kingman's
didn't repeat this for all 250 States
biotic ease on that something and you're
gonna get a bunch of posts but was
really nice if you have microsecond
precision in JavaScript you see what
what respond communities that's going to
be your computer your computer is really
fast so here's the example where it was
trying to create web RTC which fails and
then I have the local subnet code and
basically it's easy thought 107 as a
spawn of the fastest and now you see
seven is my goodness so we now have
modern so here's the actual sit back and
updated right so we kind of go through
that you determine the local I hid right
and now you did some the correct IP
address a little I take you to the syn
packet and let the router alg to all
runs
said it's not working and okay I don't
know why
so next was a figure out well daily I
would switch back to IRC which is
succeeded for me ten years ago long as
higher states block right we need to
find something that from and Firefox and
Safari ie met lump and 5060 was
basically what we wanted a little
further impossible so how do we
understand our router works
or unless you're not really actually
works so we'll go quickly I'm just going
to go through some of those tools that
they like to use there's lots of other
talks and you know we only have so much
time so one thing I use a lot is it
actually my phone and so the nice thing
about the phone is it allows you to see
things really well because you can soon
bring in the nightmare time and that
this is super useful especially when
you're trying to look in circuits
nothing is super useful like your phone
is that it has a light so if you would
enable your flashlight include a very
start recording you can then see traces
it's very useful for seeing where traces
go and when you look at a piece to eat
if you know nothing if I need enough
about circuits or electronics couple
years ago so it's just just by like
opening things up and starting to look
at them today learning more and more
because they're trying to understand how
and when you start looking at chips than
you look at the names you can google
those names and often with my
motivations so you can download all the
data changes and legend works micro
roads
these are super useful so these are the
little tiny probes that you grab onto a
million tiny hitch and on chips
this is usable for kind of primary and
wanting grab on to a couple of minutes
on some ships this should be vehicles
five images so this watch you can change
the firmware for a router for example
logic analyzer LEDs use a logic analyzer
just I want to give you guys the basic
tools that I use that will allow you to
extract your America from devices like
products and for glitching I will be
doing the talking a month or two on
glitching using really low cost FPGA so
that's pretty cool but there is another
fool called a chick whisperer which is
meeting an amazing device you can
project is the second source working
hardware device for
glitching attacks you can do all sorts
and click extract ideas these devices by
doing some color analysis protection so
there's a really cool stuff when you
have a you have
microcontroller and it's booting up
often vendors will enable to deserve
protection or debug protection that
prevents some people like us from going
in saying hey I want to enable to bugger
and access to expect reverse engineer so
they and when in development they don't
have that name let me go to production
maintain well the way that works is when
the chip is booting up a bootloader runs
and says okay I'm gonna execute this
instruction and check the value of this
use is this fuse set it says don't a lot
of debugger now the thing is all these
instructions that are running on the
microcontroller
they take time right it takes some time
to do that and time it's a controlled by
a clock so if you can do take something
like the clock even glitch it you can
say okay it takes 10 nanoseconds to run
this command so normally the clock
query you say you know what normally
takes 10 nanoseconds but for this one
cycle we're gonna make that one annual
cycle so the transistors don't even have
enough time to check and it gets to the
next segment you just skip that check
before that no computer the bug means
because we're not gonna we're not gonna
lose clock cycle it is use the bottom
and it seems they don't get virtually
from the clock cycle English and then
that doesn't I'll have to be voter
protection we can choose five seconds
automated leaves it there half an hour
later get full access code ship that
memory and then you can dump a bunch and
now you can find another way to get
drivers depending on the type of router
right in many cases mind reserved and
permits go home on many kinds of
encrypted
correctly problema Jenny was that mean
cryptid but here's the example I found I
got the zip file online and downloaded
it unzipped it makes big wok which
wasn't littler than count Mac OS like or
did just imported some stuff made didn't
watch extract this type of file this was
a squash a test pilot and I just watched
a pheasant pulse wouldn't work my Mac so
I never get hype and I put links in all
of us so I'll make these slides
available so I need a quarter of the
siwash FS cool so you can run on that it
runs fine on those and this will unpack
the firmware for this rally monkey
starting
so cool but which is and that gives us a
reasonable inclination that there are
other functions right if we really want
to Center why using the SIP had a pretty
and it looks a further and going to eat
here so specific encode function alright
cool so if we look further in city code
and you're looking breath and graphic
you there's something interesting here
I'm loading this screen called invite
invite is a Pacific Command so the
registers and other stuff commands
justice if commands that are at the
beginning of only sipping and we're
doing this sprinkling case compare and
we're company to somewhere if it's zero
and not an otherwise daily you did not
that's what I'm saying is is the
beginning of this packet start with
register for a bike and if it doesn't a
big morning it's the entire packet which
normally even our b2b example is HTTP is
post right but news on HP both the first
word in the teeth in the data portion of
your packet is the post and of course we
don't control out or every casual post
we can make it and get we might be a
little trigger
your offense but we can't just
arbitrarily control the data attention
in fact we can only arbitrarily to
control the middle burning in the most
content so the problem is mongers and
routers look pathetic
thus if command they don't just ignore
line by line like these they're actually
looking at the very beginning of impact
so this is kind of a problem if I can't
I don't control that coordinator so as I
was saying like there's some other
techniques that we can use maybe there's
other verticals I can use other than a
sneaky to try to find out to this so I
started looking through chrome Flags
features go to the cross for us to start
different sockets there I started going
to get w3.org and looking through their
standards in this protocol I think I
could protocol and everybody just like
was hopping explained the explanation is
what I said and there's like what does
Apogee support explanation probably what
it says on the website but there's
excellence in transport natural the RFC
well document so I started going through
thanks to the HTTP HTTP FTP WebSocket
EMS some of the things that modern
browsers support and I was looking at
now stun is something we solved with
what you see earlier yeah it sounds
pretty cool because it is I started
playing around with it seeing what we
could do in stock is already and as I
was playing with some of the that you
can click the user name and the username
is in plain text though Scott's Elvis on
Krypton
there is term and there's a return there
actually is encrypted stuff but it's not
so some it's always pop encrypted and
you can set a user and that user name I
just like playing around and accept the
user mainly to hello is it me you're
looking for I can see it in your eyes I
can see in your file with new lines and
we just included everything so there's
actually a character limit to use
maintenance on it so I was wondering
what they might send a lot more tape at
some point something's gonna break or
overflow or something
unfortunately the penny buffer overflows
but the packets didn't have to break
that this long because your Ethernet
controller your Wi-Fi can only have a
maximum transmission its IP so IP is
unplayable pregnant you will get back
your fabulous kitchen now singing well
is there a way that it may be tackling
that and figure out where doesn't play
if I send this really long use me right
you have this stone packet it's all the
snot you can be stuff and then the
username and then it overflows well you
can over closed well that's have another
packet and this is the beginning of a
packet that I potentially have purpose
very controllable so if I can measure it
where it's going to fragment they can't
buy just intentionally insert something
doesn't have a beginning of a secondary
package and I have arbitrary beauty
medium so the answer is yes what but
I've got a general stun stun server
that's listening on my server and it
says okay at what point does this
private and at that point I didn't send
back to the user basically the client
has a lot of talking open to me as well
secondarily and through that website if
we step back to gate this is the size or
an IP packet this is the size of your
banking options to the size of your UK
packet this is the total size of a
packet before a river flow and so now
what you want to do is you want to send
a single arbitrary packet would be using
long enough that Duke is exactly to this
single byte that then overflows and then
you said you're still packing
now that is pretty cool and what that
allows you to do is open any UVB work up
all your DB ports and then port or the
with the victim may be nothing but
visiting website now this was pretty
cool except that that's PGP and TVs
pretty boring we want to see his all the
rules whoever service authorities rates
I think so TCP can we do the same thing
what if we send our post and we just
send in that post data there's a ton of
stuff
there's some dead pixels on my screen so
if we sent a bunch of TCP post data we
only control that that bottom portion
and enemy send our synthetic can we do
this again you can have any TCP server
listening on TCP 5060 and that's a nice
thing about said is that it works for
both TCP a so that you send an HTTP POST
massively large you can also get a
little bit of control by by massaging
the TCP message sides essentially when
you connect to something the server can
say it makes that packet whistle of size
so that makes it even easier so you can
you can have a good connection connect
to you you then respond hey I only
accept packets of this size and then you
already know where it's been pretty at
that point you then you get these
perfect precision controllable in the
second packet the second type of the
beginning of the post well if on the
third packet where it's hard to see but
you have a man and that was our original
system and we met in college he address
including the port number that you want
to open and you can perform this in a
loop and do this for 65,000 ports you
literally just enable DMZ got some up
router just by them visiting a website
this is named this is essentially what
happens right victim this is a website
Rudy and then through the router through
the internet is the Muslim web site
could just load your JavaScript with
your evil doctrine so it can be a normal
site and you can be a malicious
advertiser
then it sends this data back in your
browser does all this automatically
doesn't request anything for you
and you get a laboratory this defective
injection through their theology just
which is pretty cool this is a simple
example it's gonna be hard to see any of
this stuff but essentially it because
begins running first to determine what
every five men and then on that some
that determines what is whether it be
upwards
he'd send a bunch of large packets it
measures the size of the packet that
returns though those sizes are then in
generates a post on the back on the back
the background began it generate the SIP
packet example is a packet and we go in
malady on the server side that this is a
packet with receipt probably we fizzle
what happens is the router will change
occasional on key Dresden of guidance so
they can validate new Christmas Eve did
properly and the cipa server the server
that's running response in both HTTP and
sent back to the clients of the browser
actually closes the connection properly
and of the system and then the router
thinks it's totally legit and we're to
network
[Applause]
also I saw your clothes so the second is
107 and 16 is my way you write to five
is broadcast so that is myself so we're
going to milliseconds but you get
microseconds
yeah my god oh I will imagine that I
think I probably just make that a
separate project it's a useful caustic
library
I don't looking everything's happening
so I do do inverse so I could fly by
piece of the time you don't have your
browser do too much if they might
actually exist I found that when I try
to hold them you know they could web RTC
change but it wasn't a process I am
Brian made up like I want to beat it
wrong so I don't know and Safari doesn't
do it at all yes it is started yeah at
some point they did that and actually I
do be curious
I came a little late but I noticed a lot
perfect so a lot of the exploits
regarding ship and so forth so if you're
on the other side of the of the offense
there you're trying to keep trying to
make ship defensible in a in a company
or whatever yeah that's a good question
so about not looking sick or really
exploiting the router potentially in
maybe the browser
oh I mean what I was suggesting in this
scenario is disable sit a little cheap
so your router allows you to do that
definitely commercial stuff will do that
okay not all the consumer surplus can do
that however that means it will stop
working so it also he became as quiz
right people unless you then
attention important forward but then you
can only have like a single voice or you
could make the next part and you could
say you know what let me not leagues but
that this was like the TCP segment but
that's not guaranteed because you can
like it's eating with IP fragmentation
is from this is the records that I that
I don't think but there's some other
cool stuff so for exactly press mention
that in the turn stuff I was doing when
I was trying to be political in these
other sock these other all those reports
those who only apply to PhDs making your
accent right so kind of in stores or
something is you need to go to turn or
cidade they don't do not have access to
all because their only motivation so you
can actually buy cash anyways I also
know that Firefox actually made this is
a little bit more challenging using
Firefox when you have your HTTP POST
this is a kid content why that is the
essentially the delimiter for your post
but basically the fun is that string
will change lengths so even though if I
use the link for the first post as soon
as I determine what the length of it
would then change fortunately it was
only in a few fights so they just if it
detects Firefox and it seemed that thing
this changes it just has it a couple
more times and after about four bus it
will Instagram her for a router
obviously this for one specific router
do you find me I saw absolutely
impossible routers so I was coming back
something Robert so it's exactly pine
trees from other others definitely
hiring some others so it smells a nice
about it that's pretty
great idea probably you'll probably just
hit the children by and then it doesn't
response that you know you're not on
slash 24 right and then the next week we
technically not just needs but I suppose
that you can do is actually you could
just keep keep doing this until you hit
something that it's similar Chris this
gateway voice Aria broadcast books
similar become faster and your own IP
address changes little minute maybe
that's group and then after that if you
get no responses than you know that your
mother you know that's yours right
master and then you know your net mask
but I never played without W cool I mean
there should be we should definitely
iterator off this is a hello lose in
court for date
that's a big question I don't know I
don't think it's a long time though
there's those hand I don't need to long
time but you know what's happening
because they get your server right baby
asleep your server and then you can
probably do it over WebSockets like
technically about is a drug
companies do you end up having HT socket
and you can generate and then you send I
think is a great request an upgrade
request that says they upgraded
WebSockets
and then they'd arrive like I don't know
if I don't know