[Applause]
everybody itself that was great
I really have to travel for like 10
minutes anybody pays attention so yeah
if you're standing out mahallae
if you can come in
important stuff to say everybody today
so first of all but the fun doesn't stop
here so I wanted to look at some stuff
that we were really proud of this year
so some statistics from wrench so we had
203 Sadie's attending tickets that's a
65 percent increase from last year we
had a 176 tickets between the speaker
your sponsors are going to be tables
workshop presenters and raised me so
that's basically the number of people
that it took to pull this off over the
weekend so because the bank so that
brings us up to a total of 22 and that
doesn't count all the people that count
fitted their badges so I want to thank
our sponsors so this complex would be
horrible without them and we've had a
really good relationship with several
responses from the beginning and she'll
come they supported us they put time and
energy into finding ways that they can
inject an energy into the community they
sponsor specific events they work with
me to figure out how best we can use
their resources so let's give all the
sponsors at
a bead said did you and your company
think that there's a spot for you at
Showtime we love to talk to you so come
up with find me afterwards okay
so if I could have you come up third
year at UC 5 6 q is there with a bar
seen from the CTF competition I think it
was a pretty good year overall every
year we have something else we have to
do this year as well but I think in the
end it was pretty enjoyable for
everybody so first place aside because
the prices that we have somewhere up
here awesome
so first place we have them at the peep
you're gonna get the
because as a an original MFP I was very
proud of my team but also I wanted to
heckle I was kind of torn on this was
the closest here I think we've ever had
I think the first place they're going to
get the raspberry pie
at least we had in third yeah awesome so
thank you for everyone who competed we
hopefully will be back again next year
from Chelsea and event is something that
where you are we learn from every year
as well so we hopefully configure better
here if you are interested in helping us
we are always open to challenge creation
this up and if you're in the LA area be
sure to check out our partners RC they
do a lot of local community work and
efforts
[Applause]
so next contest we have is ET skier
every day period so the cannibal will go
ahead come on up this is a brand new
contest for this year it has never been
done anywhere else so I won't give him a
chance to talk a little bit about it
so you see engineer is when we were
carrying all these tools and not using
any of this gave us a chance to you know
come up with different ideas on how to
get past certain challenges so it's the
challenges are points and then you take
the points and you subtract the weight
of the tools and that's so a lot of
people that and it was a lot of fun and
I got a lot of really good feedback on
how next time so first place and the
last entry for today mr. Bhatt
[Applause]
[Music]
[Laughter]
[Applause]
who has hit this was amazing he came up
he looked at the challenges oh I'm sorry
third place is fine
[Applause]
a pair of scissors he went to the gift
shop and got a pair of scissors and did
so many things and still managed to get
about 113 points with a pair of scissors
like what was the maximum points maximum
point use about a hundred pieces
included like and that was he also did
amazing and really analyzed the tools
and the puzzles and came up with this
entire strategy when it was her turn to
do the puzzle to do the challenges
earplugs which house each of you are
getting a little token price L guitar
you're getting a titanium snap ring
because it's ultra light and
[Applause]
okay I'll see you later then he shows up
makan with the coolest things I've ever
seen okay so I know this I'm going to
throw this in here it's a little bit of
a shape for closing remarks but I heard
some rumors that we might have some
people from rather far away so I want to
do to see who is the longest distance
from Elmo right now so let's start with
is so everybody put your hands up put
your hands down the u.s. is really just
a - ok we know more
so all right put your arms down if you
call North America your home comedians
so is that does that last thing that's
in here there any hands out in the hall
okay well El Faro wins
[Applause]
that contingency is still here but
thanks guys for coming out
I know that it wasn't really an option
for outfitter oh okay a train well I'm
certainly glad that he got stuck here
because it meant that he graced us with
his presence this weekend so okay um I
want to do some thank yous because I
have an incredible team and this comm
ran really smoothly this weekend because
I have an incredible team because they
put in and then Norma's amount of effort
so these are arranged I'm not in any
particular order because it's me and I'm
sorry but he's going to go through so
Carrie thank you for organizing to see
Athena's here and for anybody goes on
the CFP review order if you have never
done a CFP review it's a lot of work
it's extraordinarily difficult to pick
between really good presentations and we
ended up having a huge number of
submission sister which is awesome I
love that but it came with the negative
of having to reject some people and that
was really hard it was incredibly
challenging to figure out we wanted to
see it all we just we can't do it so
thank you for submitting thank you for
and then thank you for the review we're
also on top of that that's not like so
that's that's good stuff the Jared takes
character here and then at calm the poor
man wrangle speaker speakers
and I don't know if you guys but the the
speakers are hard to track down and
they're sober okay so either really
crucial thing that we had that's been
going on all year is get to the crown
process what did you guys think of the
Crown Plaza so we really like the Crown
Plaza I think we may end up here again
so I'm glad to hear that you guys liked
it if you have any suggestions for us on
anything please let me know send us an
email but also if you have a suggestion
specifically for how you'd like to see
book then you can figure a little bit
differently maybe soft pain point with
proudful let us know I was pretty busy
putting my hair out whole weekend so one
of the ways that the primary reason that
the crown has been such a great venue is
because you have Sonia and Marie who
have spent countless hours negotiating
with the hotel organizing things about a
month ago there was a change of
leadership and so even though the
overall contract was in place all of the
details and all of the fine precision
work was just gone and we started over
from scratch to the fact that things
went as smoothly as they did is a
tribute to how hard they work so
laureen's I mean who is me stand up
[Applause]
there's tusky so you're pushing stuff to
essentially what we consider our
production website and normally and that
goes through some sort of middle the
process but II switch that happen you
switch over to telepathy so I would
think about a change and I would log in
there already
so for all of the purchase signage and
the t-shirts around the conference our
lovely back designer Barbie clips in an
enormous amount of time and we often
said that she's the soul of conference
because it's the image that everybody
sees so we did some incredibly cool art
this year she also got this cool so they
made a photo photo closer and abouts
been more fun than it was pathetic cost
so it was
okay so police is our lead and this year
we normally we rent the equipment this
year we decided that we wanted to focus
on some of the expansion it's we ended
up purchasing some portion of our
audio-visual equipment which meant that
lease had to end it with partially
rented systems and partially own systems
and somehow make that work he did an
amazing job with very little help
and basically no health before calm it
was all Elise so thanks to Lisa
and then the team team they are high
school students that are affiliates of
the table and they monitored their time
today and yesterday become health and so
not only are they incredibly
hard-working and fun to hang out with by
hopefully they're getting some
real-world skills that they can apply so
the chopped and I'm totally springing
this honor but does Gloria want to come
up and say a couple of words about
[Music]
okay Hector is our veteran or salute
keenly he is he's a better service and
he's also a wonderful guy so he
organized so we were able to sponsor
tender business you're actually I'm
sorry girls sponsored photo evidence
this year because we had the sponsor who
was able to purchase two tickets for
veterans so that's really awesome we
were able to have basically in the final
race be there was a track that talks all
salute where it focused on our service
members were moving to the extra duty as
well yes okay so it's exactly to the
Emperor service but it focuses primarily
on transmission in the civilian tech so
that's that's not something that I see
at any other conference and I think
that's amazing
so thank you so much detector for
putting that together
okay so first security physical security
and the code of conduct Brett or static
was amazing this year super helpful and
very guy came in he meant somewhat
last-minute because because we asked him
to please and and he saved us from the
vine so thank you so much
okay so for your leads in amongst those
made about 65 to 70 toll volunteers
between raisiny hacker village and
general volunteers and the people
leading those were ana Ana and Victor so
they put an enormous amount of effort in
and dealt with the hundreds of emails
that I didn't want to do so we've got we
had a big party last night out of the
pool and we're gonna have another big
party tonight for bonfire so hopefully
we'll see you there
the only reason that that happened is
because Sonia came in she told me and
she said I'm organizing these events and
I said okay and she's done an amazing
job she has pulled together on a
shoestring budget beautiful decorations
and all kinds of fun things to be there
we're going to completion food showing
up and it's very exciting so thank you
again to Sonia for organizing all the
first
if you were a volunteer a raking
volunteer or a fabulous monster thank
you so much
it's it's wonderful to see the number of
red shirts groomed and you guys did an
amazing job holding him this comment
would not function without staff and 12
or 13 of us that are on core I couldn't
do it alone so thank you for being
willing to donate your time thank you so
much it's hard it's a lot of work and
effort to do that and coordinate all of
that before con so to come up with new
ideas and fresh ideas so robic just just
shout out from the audience everybody
who went to talks what were some of the
favorites mainframes there was a the
silence comes people like there was so
many amazing talks
I don't know if you have never spoken
before
she'll come is the perfect venue for you
to do that so you know we are not
terribly huge as you can see from the
attendance in this room and so we also
have really passionate really interested
and really intelligent individuals who
are willing to help you with your talk I
understand about the community this is
not like a shell calm specific thing for
people in this room want to help me make
your talk better and this is new place
to practice so if you have never spoken
before so then next year
[Applause]
so we started doing workshops last year
so the workshops are a four hour
hands-on environment format that are
held in these tools over here and we
double the number of workshops that we
had this year so that's that's crazy it
was an enormous amount of work that was
another jarred thing and so thank you so
much for handling all of that if you
were a presenter I know how much work it
takes to put together of a cohesive
horror map so thank you for a sacrifice
and weeks of your life for this
conference
okay so for the sepia johansson play the
TGIF so thank you for participating the
team that put it together this year has
been with us with us from the beginning
[Applause]
work through some really tough
challenges and we're willing to bring it
back so despite the fact that some of
them have moved some of had you know
traumatic life situation changes they
pulled through and put together what I
heard was a amazing casting back
so thank you guys
Sonic's work for me okay so for IOT
villages air in here okay so Aaron and
Janie put in some awesome who played IOT
village okay awesome
yeah it's you know something that's new
he actually started that here
[Music]
I can't promoter we started in the layer
one over she'll calm it's the same team
so you know we're all on the same family
so we have been some of the earliest
villages for Internet of Things and the
hacking of said things so it's growing
we're still trying to figure out the
best way to do it and Aaron and Jamie
did an awesome job this year
so thank you very much to them for
pushing through and get next worth so
long
okay so for lock-picking village and a
seat thank you so much to the wonderful
team of Pat
and guys were just inhaling it the whole
time I had we took the team team over to
show them lock-picking and so that is an
incredibly high compliment and so animal
and Holly are old friends and then I
just met here and he was wonderful so
thank you very much for coming down and
donating your time and then first L and
Natalie thank you so much um they got
someone randomly assigned to a
lock-picking village I needed some extra
help and I thought well you know these
people will rapidly learn how a lockpick
and they both already had instructed a
topic abilities so I can't make that up
folks that's awesome
so a call for art coordinator on the
shelf constant was Barbie and then she
worked really closely with
Pinguino so all of the tables in hacker
village was amazing all of the lighting
was amazing and then if there was all of
the centerpieces on the tables I thought
that that really brightened up a
privilege and it was amazing so that was
it we know coordinated with us for all
the decorations and then should also
help put together the call for art and
go to wall so thank you very much - we
know and pile and then find was there
pretty much the whole time almost look
around and helping out with whatever
need be
and then thank you very much - moose and
our guitarist Matt thank you for being a
last minute of call so that was awesome
[Applause]
okay so for those of you who enjoyed the
music in hacker village I strayed that
was an amazing DJ he he brought his own
the stuff he hauled her through San
Diego PD I'm sure there's no big deal no
problem and he's fun just an amazing set
it was just the right amount of chilled
and quiet so that people were on CDF
didn't get overwhelming believe that
still talk so thank you for making an
accurate village a wonderful place to be
and then Tania put together the
jellyfish this one and did an amazing
job and then pretty much
so thank you for Everett for those of
you who know my history with Gahan I was
mostly looking over accurate village so
that's certainly where I'm the most
excited to be and it's my favorite part
of the con and this year it all my mind
it was awesome because it was colorful
it was hopping people look like they
were having fun so if that's the kind of
environment you want to see please let
us know please provide some feedback for
our community tables we had a bunch of
local groups come in and we really
enjoyed working with them we really
enjoyed collaborating with those teams
so thank you so much for the people that
were willing to staff those tables and
interact with shall come members because
I think that at the end of the day it
doesn't matter what comp you go to as
long as you're working together people
in your community and build each other
up right
[Applause]
the final link that I have is I just
want to thank all the attendees came out
and made this time possible you know if
if nobody came to the Crom it wouldn't
be any fun right I got stuck here in the
empty halls with all the cool toys and
all the cool stuff and I would be bored
silly so thank you for being a part of
our wonderful community and for making
it a great place I really had fun this
weekend
you are like glazed over
or maybe hungover so just if you want to
stay in contact with us follow us on
Instagram or Twitter isn't this a
wonderful photo the whole reason for
this 5 is so that I can put this photo
it ok so what are we doing for the
bottom fire into the deep set so the
place that we go is 302 beach bonfire
pits and it is just down the street
according to this highly effective a map
screenshot it's nine minutes away so you
have no excuses
7 minutes if you take the weird bendy
place
[Applause]
the parking is where you pull in and
then you can walk a really short
distance and that is for some reason
forget all the things that I just said
mr. hungover or bored of you talking
it's all on the website there's a button
called
bonfire babies probably not gonna get
now and then it's already up so you
don't have to worry about it makes you
changing one final note the parking lot
is locked at 10:00 so you probably want
to enter vehicle how does the parking
lot before that occurs so in the
background this year again some pretty
major organizational changes Shawn who
was a co-founder with Laurie and I moved
and he still really wanted to be
involved but light kinda got away and so
it wasn't able to be as heavily involved
this year and I needed help so I reached
out to Steve whose birth the courts did
last year primarily in an operational
role and asked them you willing to come
be my co-director so he's been pretty
much documenting all of our processes
which had been a nightmare he's slowly
ramping up and stepping up in his role
at shell pop so I just want to both of
him and let you guys know that
any questions that you would direct to
me that now you can direct them to speak
no wait that that Stephen are people
working together to make sure that this
table continues to grow and continues to
have a level of quality to be sought
this year thanks everyone core team feel
welcome as one of the team members I
just wanted to make kind of a pre
comment on the stack of dead so I've
been an entrepreneur and a project
manager my entire life and so I go team
like I it's what I love to do I enjoy it
and to this I believe giving the most of
the AZT I've ever seen in my entire life
like I cannot get over how it's just I
mean each individual piece of this
puzzle the person who's running it is
perfect is perfect for their position so
I didn't want to be a part of this and I
don't know I mean you guys are more
perfect community I've got an actual
part of the other now this but this
seems and feels a lot different than a
lot of other cons and conferences I've
been to in other realms and I think what
we're building here is really really
special and really really important so
thank you all thank you all who attend
and it's been an amazing experience and
I look forward to helping just grow this
thing of that make it as best
into lotion sponsored us this year and
they also donated a bunch of t-shirts
and so I've got me arranged bite size
because I was I just wanted to throw
stuff that you guys so you raise your
hand if you're small any smells on that
side sorry I just like that those last
two shirts are actually a cheap options
so those were all they had left over
from last year so those are those are
rare commodity exposure medium
[Applause]
[Music]
so as you guys know everybody works
really hard and we feel that our you
know people are charged don't always get
things well enough so I'd like to have
Jared are we Louise Laurie come on up
[Applause]
three of us a secret team market acrylic
she was getting one of these we
encourage everyone to come up to them to
try to sign note to keep it as a memory
for this year and thank you to all of
you that come here you guys make this
really amazing we're really really hard
year round and we just love to see if it
works basically minute thank you the
particular to Zach and Steven from
heading this up force this year for
Barbie for her music design is for
Laurie wine convinced does not sleep
this woman does look at memory
connection she really doesn't
charity week say no to something things
and I wanted to 3d print I made that
like 3 a.m. 72 which link links maybe
was printing off stuff so that's amazing
it all of you this was great
I'll see you at the beach it's BYOB and
keep it a little undercover
[Applause]
for