hi there
hey uh my name is larry pesci and i'm
the director of research
just a few other hats uh at uh in
guardians
and i'm here to talk a little bit today
about um
some rfid type
cards from uh hid global and we're doing
some
hit card hacking uh here at crango con
so first up uh a big thanks
uh to santa for inviting me
um you know it took a little bit of time
uh to get here a couple flights
um you know masks secret locations
um but uh you know many of my uh my
other presenters are saying it's uh it's
it's pretty cold but um i'm
i'm from new england and and we get a
fair bit of snow and it's not as cold as
some
other places uh but uh certainly
uh it's still you know jeans and t-shirt
weather
uh here at the north pole even though it
is a little blustery
now you don't want to stay outside for
very long but certainly
it's uh it's still quite reasonable so a
big thanks to uh to santa for the invite
uh and for uh the hospitality
all right without further ado let's uh
start looking
at the hidden prox 2 from hid
corporation
so the hit prox2 is based on
some low frequency rfid
based technology they are fairly simple
they don't have any security mechanism
uh to them
you read the card and they typically
spit out a unique number of some sort
they're incredibly uh popular for
physical access control uh for gaining
access into various organizations
uh typically door access whether that be
uh you know potentially into the front
door of a multi-tenant facility
into office suites and you know
potentially even
into some secure
data centers and i'm using air quotes
here for secure
to restrict access into specific
locations
uh where there may be some more uh
sensitive
types of things that we need to restrict
access to
okay they are in fact typically low cost
there are a couple of different
um solutions within his
prox uh product line but we're
specifically going to be focusing on
the uh hidden procs 2. specifically
um from some quotes from stephanie r
dilley
the product manager uh at hid global uh
who states that
legacy 125 kilohertz that's the low
frequency
uh proximity technology is still in
place at around 70 to 80 percent of all
physical access control deployments in
the us and it will be a long time before
that changes
and and absolutely i can i can see
that figure based on the number of times
i've gone into facilities and seen
uh the hid prox2 solutions as well as
the being for a long time typically
these installs going into organizations
are those that
are a fixed asset and there's no push to
replace them
given that they're installed they're
working and it will be fairly expensive
to to make that happen oh
hey so what's uh what does it all look
like well
we've got a couple of components uh to
uh to the system uh on the left we've
got our
uh hidden prox2 uh reader uh where we
present
uh the card to the reader and the uh 125
kilohertz uh rf
energy uh transpires the card is
activated by the presence of rf energy
uh through some capacitive inductance
and the card activates spits out a
number
uh and in this case access to santa's
sentence workshop
now the unique number from the card is
translated
uh via uh wire to some sort of
uh controller that is the part that is
uh
checking for which numbers are allowed
into uh
into uh which doors and then triggers
the unlock events uh for those
uh those doors now on the wired side
of on the back of the the the
kid prox2 reader uh it gets translated
to
uh the wigan protocol uh which is a
a well-known well-documented standard
that is unencrypted
uh on the back end so you know
potentially in some of these systems we
have a couple of other opportunities for
us to interact with them
and not just on the rf side we could
potentially
intercept that wigan protocol on the
wire
or we could potentially find somewhere
on the network uh
the systems that are potentially uh
integrating with the door controllers
uh for the read of the batches and the
unlock codes
uh you know typical windows
or linux space system that would be
subject to various network
uh traditional type of pen test attacks
on the network
all right so let's take a look at the
the cards themselves well the cards
themselves
do provide us a little bit of uh
information
when presented to a reader when
activated they do spit out a unique
number
uh to the reader which is then
interpreted and sent wigan protocol to
the controller which verifies hey this
card number
is allowed uh into this door
or not on the card itself there are some
numbers printed
there are uh the two numbers being the
unique
card identifier and the sales order
tracking number
now for the most part that sales order
tracking number is not particularly
useful
uh to us but that card
id number is that card unique id number
is intended to be unique per card
but if we can read that physically
that doesn't make a whole lot of sense
for us to have that be a secure
mechanism
but what really happens is that card id
number is combined
with a facility number or a unique
you know purchaser or a unique location
of facility number which is not printed
on the card and it's only inspected
uh and transferred in the air uh when
read
so a combination of a hidden facility
number
and a unique card id number that is
printed
on the outside of the cart one of the
things that i think that's pretty neat
about what hit did and potentially comes
back to to bite them a little bit
is hit didn't develop their own rfid
based technologies
they actually uh used some uh
some rfid technology that was already
out there from atmel specifically
uh the t5557 and
also i think the new one is the t55
77 which to the best of my knowledge is
uh backwards uh compatible now the thing
that makes this interesting
is that the atmel t5557 chipset
is publicly available and it's usable
for
other purposes and is readily available
uh
in the market and hid global just
decided to
adopt this chipset for for their
application
what that means is that we could
potentially purchase
uh other cards from other systems that
are leveraging this chipset to be able
to use
uh within our kid prox card to supported
systems
all right so looking at that data format
we
for what is spit into the air
comprised of that facility code
and the unique card id
the facility code is between uh 1
and 255. zero is reserved for internal
hidden corporation development and so
forth
uh and then the unique card id is
between one and sixty five thousand five
hundred and thirty five
uh where zero is reserved or uh hid's
internal
uh stuff as well so
we have a facility code between 1 and
255 and for each one of those facility
codes we can have a unique card
identifier
so i can walk up to a facility and
see two different cards
out in front of the building maybe
someone's wearing them and note that
they have the same card id uh in fact in
likely in this case uh the facility code
is different
uh and we'll talk a little bit about you
know some of those facility codes and
the card ids
so once that the data is on the card we
print the card id unique
uh on the outside we've got our facility
code
that data is then encoded and then
happens to be encoded to a length of a
26-bit
data format and then at the reader it
fits
conveniently within a single
wiegand protocol 26-bit data format so
it fits nicely for one one packet
now some of his
later adaptations the hit corporate 1000
has the ability to have longer facility
code and card ids
uh resulting in longer output of between
34 to 37 bits
but it doesn't have any additional
security protections it is
specifically related to the availability
of the quote key space those unique
identifiers
so how would i interact uh with
uh some of these hidde cards and and
readers
now there's a bunch of tools out there
but arguably my favorite
and even my favorite out of the proxmark
versions
the proxmark 3 the rdv2 uh
version so specifically the prox mark
iii uh is a tool for
interacting with uh rfid both high
frequency
uh and low frequency for doing some
really deep analysis
as well as some utility type of
uh application for interacting with
various rfid tags
and in this case we're specifically
focused uh on the hidden prox2
uh hardware was uh the original prox
mark iii designed by jonathan west
hughes
uh and software by gerhard uh decoding
gans
and a few others as well as part of the
project
and uh the software and hardware has
seen
some evolution uh over time
uh the thing that i think that is
fantastic about the proxmark
uh while it's complex potentially in its
usage through
the tethered software attaching it to
our computer
it gives us the ability to read tags
interrogate them find out all the values
find out its feature set capabilities
and even determine its types
it has also the ability to become a card
a tag itself meaning
it can receive the data and then
transmit
that data back as if it was an actual
card okay
uh it's typically usb based when we're
interacting with it with the prox mark
iii software it does also work in
standalone mode we'll cover that
uh but uh typically we're interacting
with it uh
over usb uh to manipulate the device
with the prox mark iii software
and that proxmark3 software has multiple
different options
and some of that evolution over over
time
and one of the more a prevalent is the
uh
iceman version of the prox mark iii uh
software
uh we've seen some uh from brad and
hanowitz
introducing the ability to do uh brute
forcing
on head cards with prox brute uh and
even some potential
interesting custom versions for the
holiday hack challenge
all right so with the proxmark 3
attached to our computer over usb using
the prox mark 3 software we can in fact
read the cards get their unique values
and then get the prox mark iii to replay
those values into the air
acting as if we had the physical card
this allows us to effectively perform
cloning
type of attacks now we can do capture
and effectively replay and we can do
capture
and push that data to a brand new card
so we can actually have
physical card medium as opposed to this
piece of
electronics now there's no prevention
for anyone for reading
these tags we just need to present it to
the reader
and in this case uh we're connected to
the prox mark 3 software we've got our
product mark
iii connected via usb and we issue the
low frequency hid read command
it reads a card present uh to the
antenna
in very close proximity and it tells us
that
uh it's a 26 bit uh hid
gives us our facility code of 149 and
our card number of six
four eight nine nine okay and then some
uh some raw data uh down on the bottom
with lots of
zero leading zeros and if you take a
look the card that we read
uh over here on the right uh we do have
some values
printed on the card is 64899
and then the 1126-1137-1
being that unique purchase order
tracking number so the unique number for
this card was 64899 which we recovered
as the cn
with our low frequency hit reap and we
also recovered that
facility code the fc of 149 the part
that's only inspected
in rf once we have that data
we can use the low frequency hid
simulate or sim
command and use some raw data to spit
those same
card values back out into the air from
our prox mark iii
and then present our prox mark iii to
the reader
uh which the reader thinks a valid card
has been presented
uh in this case we are using uh the raw
data
with the tr uh the leading zeros uh
trimmed off
so you note on our lf he had read we
have that raw data at the bottom with a
bunch of zeros
uh starting two four oh one uh we just
use that two four oh one
uh for uh the replay
um for the raw data with the low
frequency hid
simulate so super easy
read and effectively replay
we can also clone to a
a new card now the standard hid prox 2
tags are uh not writable that
facility and id code cannot be changed
they're read
only cards but as you remember they are
commodity atmel t5557 or t557s
and there are some enterprising firms
that have purchased
these atmel chipsets and provide them to
the consumer
in a quote magic version and i'm using
air quotes here
to make them writeable now
they're they're questionable in uh
you know how hid wants folks to sell
these
um but they can't do a ton of
restriction because they
are a publicly available chipset from
amazon from
uh from atmel uh and i've had really
great luck
in being able to to find some of these
both through
ebay and amazon and amazon
prime today uh by searching for
uh writable t5557 uh and sometimes
you'll get
the models that come back of the t5577
okay so how would we actually write this
to uh a new card
uh well first one uh instead of doing uh
the
uh lf hid read we can just do lf search
and it tries to find all the possible
low frequency card present to the
antenna and in this case
uh it did find that we had that same
head card with the facility code of 149
and the
64899 for the unique card identifier
and its raw data so it attempts to read
all the low frequency tags
and until it discovers one
once we have that that raw data we can
write that to a new card with the
low frequency lf hid clone
and the clone is not simulating that
data into the air it's actually
pushing it to a a new blank card
with the t5557 chipset and writing that
raw data to it
uh it says it's preparing to clone you
present the card it writes the data
and then you have a new physical cart
all right it is possible to do
standalone
cloning or capture and replay
because well if we're going to do a
capture and replay
that device you know it's really small
fits in the palm of your hand
but it's now attached to your laptop
with a usb cable when you're issuing
some commands and so forth
and that's not very stealthy that's
quite obvious to surreptitiously bump
into someone on the bus
or outside of the building uh and
that's you're gonna get caught doing
that type of stuff so
uh the prox mark iii can also perform
untethered
cloning meaning if you provide it with
some power like a
portable usb phone charger type thing or
the optional internal battery for the
rdv2
we can power it and then use that one
button
uh on the prox mark iii with the various
sets of key presses to read hid tags
and once it reads a tag it will
automatically start simulating just like
issuing that
lf hidden simulate command for the most
recent
tag that was read so and we can do that
with that small device battery powered
in the palm
of our hand the challenge becomes
what happens if we read a tag with the
unique identifier
and a facility code and typically that
facility code is going to be the same
for every that that run of cards that we
order
uh so let's say santa's workshop
facility code 149
every card that has access to santa's
workshop will typically have
uh the facility code of 149 and the
unique card identifiers are the part
uh that change now it is possible to
buy cards that are randomized
but you definitely pay a premium
for that uh and i've only ever
encountered uh one organization that
has ever uh had fully admitted that
they randomized all of their facility
codes and
their card numbers and they said they
paid you know
exorbitant amounts of money to be able
to make that happen
now part of the reason why they did so
is if you think about how you're buying
your cards you're getting them in say a
chunk of
100 or five hundred cards and they're
all shrink wrap you un
you open the shrink wrap and then uh
you start programming the cards and you
know the first
your first card out you program the
system and that's the the security team
uh meaning the physical security team
they have access to everything so they
can do their inspections
uh and then maybe you uh end up with the
c-level
executives and they have access to
everything
and then you start moving down uh down
the chain you have your
computer administrators that need access
to the computer room uh and then you get
down to your administrative assistants
and your interns that just need access
to the front door
but let's say uh you uh recover a card
and uh it's for the administrative
assistant you can get into the front
door of the multi-tenant facility
you can get into the office suite but
you present that card to the data center
door and it doesn't allow you in
because now you have the card of a lower
privileged user and you need to elevate
your rights
now if we think about that you know
that's that administrative assistant
that has likely gotten that card
towards the end of the run meaning they
have the higher number
so if we think about those cards that
were delivered they're typically
sequentially numbered so if we look at
this one here
up in the top middle we've got uh one
five five seven three
and then we go over to the left uh 574
575 second third one in go back
one 576 578
579 580 581
there's no 577 but i'd argue that it's
probably the card that's
turned over in the front here uh where
we can't see the number
so they're sequentially numbered maybe
they're a little bit out of order uh you
know
maybe we dropped them uh as we were
taking a couple of them out uh so
they're they're close so if we can read
one card
and recover the facility code maybe we
need to start guessing
other card numbers because the card
number that we read
doesn't provide us access but those with
lower numbers and some case higher
numbers
usually lower numbers uh will allow us
to get into places where uh the card
number that we read
uh doesn't allow us to but read using
that same
facility code okay so
with that thinking um about uh some of
those facility codes and those card
numbers
uh i do very much encourage you to
have fun during the holiday hack
challenge and
explore the use of a approx mark
iii uh within uh within the challenge
and a huge thanks to uh the holiday hack
challenge
team that puts all this on and spends
so much time crafting this game
and you know giving this to uh
to the community during the holidays so
and again a big thanks
uh to santa uh and uh everyone involved
and please uh go enjoy and uh we'll talk
to you soon