oh my
God's injection breaking all micro
security layers with a single film
ability
if you have started the xcode since
updating to version 4D you may have seen
this new function in the template
application supports secure restorable
state which by default returns true
in this talk I'm going to talk about the
vulnerability that's
necessitated this change and what what
this actually means and then yeah how
does vulnerability could be applied in
different ways
and here together with my colleague Dan
Cooper we are the security research team
at computest we are the research
Department of course our sector seven
competency security company in the
Netherlands doing stuff like pen testing
it's in response so but we don't work
for customers we just do research to
help make the world better and to talk
about it and to publish about it
at places like this
all the work that you may have seen from
us over the past couple of years is uh
zero click RC and zoom equivalence over
loss here you know when it comes to
Miami this year with five
vulnerabilities and ICS systems
but my quest has always been a bit of a
background research project for me if
I'm stuck with the the main focus of my
research and I want to do something else
for a change than what I just end up
doing is looking at what's running on my
system so looking at some processes so I
can get some files and most of the time
that it doesn't turn out to be anything
there but sometimes I do find stuff so
yeah over the years I've you know found
a couple of things word of those to
Apple and today I'm going to talk about
one of the yeah most interesting
probabilities I find
uh to describe it I'm going to go
quickly over the micro security model
it's probably well known to most of you
here but I just want to make sure that
the context is clear
and then you start this process
injection permeability I found and then
in the third part I will apply it for
sandbox escape from this escalation and
then finally buy Personal ship
so the security model in Macos
current Macos Monterey
first I want to compare it to like the
old sort of Unix Linux security model
and that's basically means that the
users are basically privileged
boundaries with processes are not
you can see this if you look at files
files always have an owner and a group
and a number of flags that determine who
is allowed to read or write or execute
that file
the same thing for processes if the
process wants to attach to another
process as a debugger and then read this
memory or affect this execution then you
need to be running as the same user
and the exception of course is roots
rules can always read all files they can
attach to any process read all memory so
basically root has access to all of the
data on the system whether on disk
whether in Ram anything
and this was the security model of Mac
OS up until the introduction of system
Integrity protection
so this was induced introduced in 2015
with El Capitan
uh this screenshots from the WWDC
presentation where this was announced
and the basic motivation at that time
was like two things
so
adding a privileged boundary between the
root user and the kernel
and protecting the system itself from
being Modified by other software so the
operating system itself
should not be modified by malicious
software even if it has root privileges
so you see that there's now no longer
just Roots can do anything but in order
for roots to do certain stuff that it
needs to also have something else
and that's what entitlements are for
so if an application wants to load a
kernel extension that it needs to have a
specific entitlement if it wants to
modify system files then it needs to
have another entitlement
if you want to debug processes then
there also need to be
entitlements on probably in both
processes
and this is so that those privileges
that can then be given back to certain
processes we still need to be able to
update your system you still need to be
able to load a kernel extension
and after the introduction of sip
originally there have been more and more
restrictions added over the years
so debugging any application is now
requires Privileges and
probably need to turn up off zip if you
want to attach to some other process
and one interesting feature is I will
refer to as data faults I'm not
completely sure if that's the official
name for it
um but this basically means that there
are certain locations on the file system
that even root cannot read from without
an entitlement
so for example your Mill folder Apple
considers your email to be very
sensitive so if you try to list that in
your terminal then you will get a
permission denied error even if you do
it with sudo
and there's also no TCC prompt for this
this is just it's always blocked
unless you have full disk access
and then of course your mail application
does need to be able to access those
files so there's a specific specific
entitlement for mail to be able to
access those files and only applications
with an entitlement like this can then
access those locations
now this is a pretty big shift in the
security model of Mac OS and I don't
think many people have realized how much
that that model has changed things
this also means that there's now
different classes of vulnerabilities
that are certainly become very important
like a process injection vulnerability
so process injection basically means
that one process is executing code as if
it is another process so it may be
launching that process and then adding
some a shared Library like project was
shown yesterday maybe replacing certain
parts of the application
there's there's various ways that you
might be able to do that
now Apple has blocked a lot of these
things already with zip so from your
original presentation there was already
stuff like
blocking tasks for bits and stuff like
that and and
dynamic Linker environment variables
and also third party applications can
also prevent a lot of those features in
applications if they enable it so like
the environment variables in library
validation which means that you can no
longer load a dynamic Library unless it
is signed by either apple or by the same
developer
but Macos is pretty old it's pretty
large it's it's been
waiting for a long time and the other
security model
so there's still a lot of places where
process injection vulnerabilities may
exist
now it's pretty common to find a process
injection probability in a third-party
application
especially by third party developers
don't often know about these these
different kinds of permissions
so it's you often have to explain the
entire security model and then why what
they are doing is an issue
um and then often it's an issue like we
can modify the application and then
abuse its DCC permissions so you don't
need to ask for webcam permission and
stuff like that
and often it's also possible to just
downgrade an application even if it's
currently secure you can download great
to an older version that may not have
the hardened run time and then you can
inject into that application and get the
webcam or something like that
those are often just single instances of
vulnerability
of course it's way more fun for me as an
attacker is a process injection
vulnerability everywhere
so that's what this talk is going to be
about
so this cve was a process injection
probability in apkit so basically it
affected all Macos
user interface applications
so anything that's yeah following the
normal Mac OS UI
and
the feature where this vulnerability was
in was in What's called the saved state
or internally I think it's called
persistence UI
and one of the ways you can see it as a
user is if you shut down your Mac you
get this prompt
with the checkbox for reopen Windows
when logging back in so this is part of
that safe State feature
but it's used for a lot of other
features as well
so for example there's appnap which is
basically a feature where the system can
see well you haven't switched to this
application in a while it's not playing
any music
I don't think you're using it and what
it then says is it asks the application
to save its state it terminates the
process but it keeps just drawing a
bitmap picture of the application so the
user still thinks that application is
running
but then when they switch back the
application is quickly reopened again
and it restores its state
so yeah the system can save some memory
about the user still still thinks the
application is open
and it's also one of the other things it
can do is it can restore your unsafe
documents if you reboot while you have a
document open even if you didn't save it
anywhere on your disk it can still be
there if it's implemented correctly
now a large part of this
already works if you just create a new
application you don't need to opt in as
a developer it already does a lot of
this for you but you can extend it if
you need to so for example if you have a
document based application then you may
have your own States for the documents
and then you might might want to store
that state in the safe State as well for
each document
now those safe states are stored in this
directory in your safe application State
directory in your library folder
there's basically two files here that
are important for this there's a couple
more I don't really know what they do
that's the windows.plist file this is
basically an array of all of the windows
of the application and a couple of other
things like a doc menu but
every window has one entry here
and they'll see very recently named
data.data file
and this is a custom format and it's not
used anywhere else as far as I know
and it contains a list of records and
each record has an ID that refers to one
of the entries in the windows.plist file
and it's in the windows or PLS
Foundation encryption key and every
records in the data.data file is
encrypted with AES CBC
and it's an encrypted serialized object
now I don't know why this is encrypted
because the the encryption key is right
next to it there are no different
permissions there's no
um
yeah there's no entitlements here for
accessing those files
my best guess is that they wanted to
store this in the keychain but that
turned out to be complicated or
something like that maybe the keychain
is locked and then your stage is gone
or maybe to prevent these files from
being indexed I I don't know
um
because there's no Integrity check as
well you can just any application can
modify it as long as they can just grab
the key and modify the state
but what this really is about is this
serialized object
now insecure deserialization is a type
of vulnerability that's very well known
in many programming languages but mainly
C sharp and Java are well known for this
being able to lead to code execution
so there's these projects that you can
just use to generate your c-sharp
serialized object and that will then
bring some sales kit for you if it's
deserialized same for Java I think for
python it's pretty trivial to do as well
uh I think Ruby as well
um and apple also has a serialization
format called nscoding
but Apple also realized this risk of
insecure deserialization and he realized
this back in 2012
so the edits are secure for variant the
NS secure coding
and and that's back in Mountain line
but the older version of the protocol is
still in use it still exists and um
yeah still used in in certain places
so to compare those two different uh
variants
so the insecure version what this does
is it first decodes an object
and then it checks is this of the class
that I expect here
and this is a risk because at the time
you check its type the object already
exists it may already have done stuff
maybe it's Constructors doing stuff or
it's destructors doing stuff
but the secure version
for that to decode an object you need to
specify init fonts that it needs to be
of a specific class
if it's not of that class it's not
created
so this is much safer because you now
can no longer just create arbitrary
objects it really needs to be that class
or a subclass of it
doesn't mean it's impossible to attack
this there still have been attacks
against each secure coders but it's much
harder than an insecure version
so
um I had this idea for an attack
I create a safe state with a malicious
serialized object
invited to the safe State directly with
another application
I launched your application
it deserializes that object and if code
execution in that other app
this sounded really easy but then I
started looking into this
well did somebody else already find such
a serialization
chain of objects that I can use here
so this is why so serial projects
watching serial uh for c-sharp as well
that you can use for Java serialization
or for c-sharp serialization
but nothing like that for objective c
seem to exist
I looked into a couple of project zero
white tips about security serialization
but those all use very specific filter
abilities in the these in the secure
serialization that has since been fixed
so those weren't really techniques that
it could apply anymore
so I could not find any prior work on
this
um it might exist but uh eventually I
just concluded I had to do all of this
from scratch
so
finding a chain of objects that I can
pass through that uh
into that format to eventually evaluate
applescripts within another process
so how did I do that well I disassembled
a lot of those initial coder methods
those are the methods that are used for
creating a d sharedized object
and what I noticed is that especially in
appkits many of them do not support
secure coding
kind of surprised me but it's also many
of them aren't really objects that you
want to send to somebody else so they're
not just xpc or something like that so
also really no need for secure coding
and also many of those were not very
interesting so they just recursively
decode some instance variables and then
they're done so took a while to find any
of them that had anything actually
useful
then the first step I found was the NS
rule editor
and when this object is deserialized
what it will do is it will create a
binding to another object
using a key path also from the archive
so bindings if you're not familiar with
Mac OS
development they're basically like a
reactive programming technique where you
can just directly connect a model to a
view without having a controller full of
boilerplate code in between
so for example you can have your model
as a person an indicate a few with a
text field and you can bind that field
to the name of the person
and then the key part that you have is
the name
property of that person and then if you
modify the text field then the model is
automatically updated or if the model is
updated then the
view is also automatically updated
now how this works internally
is that if you create a binding then you
should
select a property of the object but
there's really no check for that so what
you can just do is you can pull any
methods as long as it has no arguments
um on an object
and whenever you make that binding it
needs to create an initial value so that
method is invoked immediately as you
deserialize this object
so for example if you have a
NS process clause which has a launch
method it has no arguments so you can
okay The Binding to the launch method
and then at the moment that binding is
created that method is invoked so you're
not supposed to do this it's not a
property that you should be binding to
but by doing this I was able to call
arbitrary methods during deserialization
as long as they have no arguments
and then as a second step I use this NS
Custom Image wrap
and when this object is deserialized it
decodes two things from the archive
a draw method
which is a selector it's like a function
pointer for a object Objective C method
and an object
but it wouldn't use those yet at this
point
but it has a draw function
uh and we call this draw function it
will perform the selector that is
decoded from the archive on the object
is also decoded from the archive
passing itself as the first argument
so by combining this with the previous
one by creating a binding to that draw
method
I was then able to call arbitrary
methods although I did not have any
control over the arguments yet
I could
call these arbitrary methods or objects
that are deserialized
now sadly for the next step I have to
skip a little bit because it involves a
vulnerability that's not yet fixed
hopefully it will be in Ventura so I'm
going to step skip ahead a little bit
and summarize a bit the steps that I
just did so first of all I could call
zero arguments methods on these
serialized objects
and I could call any R methods on the
I could use this
reject this vulnerability to create
arbitrary objects so not just the
serializable objects with any objects
and then I used actually a similar trick
to call zero argument methods on those
objects
called arbitrary methods with another
rejected parts
and at that point I can basically
execute applescript
so this applescript is running inside
another process so it's running with the
entitlements and the permissions of
another process
so for example if I would attack mail I
could just tell it to copy the entire
meal database from the data fault to a
location where I can read it and then
upload it do stuff with it
applescript also music and spawn a shell
with virtual stuff like that so at this
point I had pretty well compromised the
application
but then it turned out that this was not
quite enough for everything that I
wanted to do every the second one of the
exploits that I was here later
uh this was not enough for
I wanted to be able to execute something
equivalent to Native codes
and it was not yet possible with this
and then what I had to deal with is the
hardened drone time that was really the
main issue here
so at this point I could interact with
the objective c runtime I could call
methods I could create arbitrary objects
but stuff that I could not do is called
C functions could not create any structs
I could not create C strings no pointer
D reference nothing like that
but due to the heart and dream time
versus not allowed to create jet memory
Pages or inside memory at all so I can
just not just
yeah create some some
memory write my payload into there and
you jump to it so memory corruption that
would be possible with the methods that
I had but it would be
pretty tricky
and Library validation also means that I
was not able to load a malicious Library
into the process
but I could load libraries signed by
Apple
now that's very interesting because
Apple includes quite a few scripting
languages within Mac OS
so I looked at all of those scripting
languages see which of those has a
foreign function interface that
interacts with c
and I notice all of these were included
in Macos at the time so python has been
removed since then in
12.43 I think but this although affected
big serve so it was still there
so I evaluated all of these things and
what I could do with them
uh for Apple scripts I just concluded
this was not powerful enough didn't give
me The Primitives to do what I wanted to
do
JavaScript had no ffi that they could
use
you had to expose the new stuff to the
JavaScript world and I could not access
that
Pearl and Ruby were interesting but the
ffi uh modules are not included
so if I wanted to install those they
would create new binaries which would
not be signed by Apple
and I would not be able to load them
TCL might work but I I think I'm too
young to know what this is
but python python was interesting for me
because python on Mac OS did include the
C types module
so I didn't need to compile anything I
could just load the C types module
with C types you can do a lot that you
can also do in C you can call C
functions the reference pointer C string
structs anything
and most of it works with the art engine
time on there's there's a few things so
um
C types as a feature where you can pass
a python function as a function pointer
so C function pointer and to do that you
need to have Js memory so you need to
have writable executable memory
and the hardens runtime wasn't allowing
me to do that but it could just delete
all of those parts from the C types
module because I wasn't interesting
interested in using them anyway if I
just deleted all of those I could load
the module file
so in practice this is
equivalent to native code execution
within a process
but now I'm still back at the same
problem because python doesn't have an
objective-c interface I wanted to load a
different language to call C functions
and now I need to call C function to
execute python so it's back at the same
problem again
but then I noticed that one of the steps
that I previously saw was The
applescript Objective C Bridge
so this is basically applescript
with access to the objective-c runtime
and it's a framework that's been
included in Macos for a couple of years
in The applescript Objective C framework
and what you can do is if you load it
and you can then load the scripts from a
bundle so instead of loading the bundle
itself you can just load the scripts
from the bundle and even if that's not
signed by Apple even if there's no code
signature on that at all you can just
load it and add new Apple scripts into
the runtime
now this was able to interact with the
objective-c runtime
but one interesting thing here is that
it can cause C functions so it did give
me that extra thing of being able to
call C function
but it cannot create those non-object
pointers structs C strings stuff like
that
so this gives me just this little step
further
but then there was still the issue of
how do I execute python
because for python all of the C
functions
that I was interested in take a string
argument
for example file path or the actual
python code to evaluate there
and it took me a while to see what I
could do there
but if you call Pi main with
zero arguments and nil as a second
pointer
what it will actually do is it will act
like a rebel just like if you enter
python in your terminal just the the
actual Rebel stuff would start within
the process that I was attacking
so I could create a new pointer and I
could pass it to this function
and then at that point I could execute
python on standard input in the process
that I was attacking
now if you think applescript or
objective c is a little bit for Boost
you should see how code in The aposcript
Objective C Bridge looks like
so all of this you need to prefix stuff
with like tell current application or
current applications anus bundles Alex
and then pass the the method name and
it's
pretty terrible to read this
but with it by main line at the end I
could start a spiral Rebel within that
process
so to go back to that summary of the
different steps I could go any methods
on arbitrary Objective C objects
evaluate applescript to the Apple script
Objective C Bridge
evaluate python
import C types and then I had code
execution basically equivalent to Native
codes
so I could apply this vulnerability on
any application
but of course I was very interested in
seeing what is the maximum input Maximum
Impact I can have with this
vulnerability so if you report something
to Apple you really want to make sure
that you have understood the full impact
and that you can demonstrate it because
they're not going to figure that out for
you if you want the full boundary you
really need to demonstrate it yourself
is my experience
so first of all that's sandbox Escape
for that I used uh what's known as an
open Panel
it may look quite boring if your Mac OS
user you probably see this one 10 times
a day and you don't think much about it
but it's actually technically quite
complicated
so what you have here is that
the application may be sandboxed so the
application has no access to your list
of files with the open Panel can see
your full disk
so the way this works
is that the window itself is actually
part of your application
but the contents are being drawn by a
different service
so you can kind of see this like an
iframe on the website but we need an
application
and that content or that open and panel
save service
is not sandboxed because yeah it needs
to see all of your files
now as it turned out
for some reason
is open a safe panel was loading its
safe state from the same directory as
the application itself
I'm guessing because you might want to
resize the panel and then the state
needs to be saved per different
application differently or something
like that
not completely clear to me
so what I could do is just write a saved
state in my own applications directory
open that panel and then I had escaped
the sandbox
now this one was actually fixed a little
bit earlier by Apple in 11.3 by no
longer sharing the directory with the
open a safe panel service
so I could just use the aposcript
evaluation and then execute the sales
script and I reach first shell or
something like that at that point that
was outside of the sandbox
now privileged escalation to Ruth and
this one requires all of that extra
python evaluation stuff
so for this I used a technique I
borrowed from Elias Moritz in in of d
so I looked for an application with the
entitlements
com.apple.private dot authorization
Services containing
system.install.apple-software
for example install command line
developer tools
and what this basically means
is that this application is allowed to
install packages signed by Apple without
authorization from the user so normally
if you install package the user need to
answer needs to enter their passwords or
something similar to that
but if you have this entitlement you can
just install any Apple sign package
without authorization
and any installation of the Packers wins
US Route
so then from the right up of Ilias
there's also this macros public beta
access utility package
this is basically if you want to enroll
into the Macos data you need to install
this package
and what this package does is that it's
in its post install script
it runs a command from the disk you
install it to
but as a normal user you can just attach
a new disk image or you could create a
ram disk
and then use this
service to install to that disk
and at that point you are winning a
commands that the user specified as root
so just mount a disk put that file on
the same path there and there's no check
if it's a Mac OS disk just go to the
installation on that disk and you're
executing code as root
now I think Apple has fixed this in the
newest version of this package but
because it's still Apple signed and I'm
not sure if they even have a way to
revoke package signatures
if as long as you have this package you
can just keep doing this attack
now if you want to see what that uh
uh c-types python code looks like to do
this it's a
yeah it's pretty similar to how you
would do is this from C
you can create an authorization
reference uh grab that uh
right for the install Apple software and
then pass it to the PK install client
that can then use it to install the
package
so it's very
for Boost writing something like that
but yeah in the end this works and I got
it to elevate privileges to root
foreign
ly I also wanted to bypass sip of course
so to do that I just looked at all of
the applications that were available to
me I try to
find them everywhere that I could and
one of the places I looked is on the
install disk for the Macos Big Sur beta
and on the disk I found a application
I'm really not sure what it's supposed
to do
but it has the entitlement
com.apple.rootlist.install.heritable
and what this entitlement basically
means
is that it can access any sub projected
files
and it's also heritable which is a nice
bonus because then you can just spawn
the shell or something like that you
don't need to work within the process
itself
and even though this was included on the
data disk image I could just copy it
into a Mac OS environment and there the
application would still
open as normally
so what can you do if you bypass ship
well as I mentioned you can read user's
email also the messages database Safari
history also protects it in the same way
I can modify the TCC database so I can
just give myself permission to access
the webcam the microphone anything like
that
I can also persist in locations that are
sip protected normally
so if I buy to some protected uh
place your antivirus would not be able
to remove me probably
and maybe useful this is not completely
sure could also probably delete all my
removal tools so Apple would really need
to push the software update to delete
this
and also as a final step I could load a
kernel extension without user approval
so there's a database for kernel
extensions that the user has approved
and normally the user needs to see a
prompt like this where they need to
click OK and go to system preferences
and also approve a kernel extension
specifically
but because I could modify the database
I could just load any kernel extension
without the user ever seeing anything
happen
so that's not yet kernel code execution
because uh you still need a apple kernel
extension certificate to sign those
but if you would for example find the
vulnerability in any kernel extension
then you would be able to load that
exploit the film ability and then
execute code or get a certificate from
somewhere maybe
now I have a demo of the attack so first
of all it will demonstrate the sandbox
application is actually sandboxed
and then start the attack the first one
should be really quick
the Second Step takes a little bit
longer because it needs to create a disk
image to perform the entire installation
stuff like that
it's it's also not trying to be stealthy
in any way so you can see the ram disk
bearing but might be some way to hide it
from the user
Amanda said bypass is also really quick
because it doesn't need to do anything
other than
the serialize the object
as you can see we now have a root shell
and to demonstrate also the Sip bypass
go to the system policy configuration
directory this is where your approved
kernel extensions are stored
and I create a new file just to
demonstrate that I can write here which
should normally not be possible with
just a root user
thank you
so a little bit about how Apple fixed
this
so to go back to the very first slide in
Monterey apps can now indicate that they
only accept secure serialized objects so
they can just set that secure flag to
true
and for all of Apple's apps this is
already automatically enabled
but existing applications may want to
store insecure deserialized objects if
they have like a document format that
they need to serialize their
so for those applications that methods
might be needed to return false there
it's not completely clear to me if it's
exploitable if the method is not
implemented but the application doesn't
store their own objects
I'm not completely sure I haven't
controlled well enough to say for sure
I reported this to Apple on December 4th
in 2020 and the effects of sandbox
Escape pretty early in 11.3 in April
last year
and then the complete fix was included
in Macos Monterey October 25th in last
year
and supposedly it's backboarded to Big
Sur and Catalina now I didn't know about
that
so it was not in the patch notes for Big
Sur or Catalina at the time it was
released
so as you can see here it was released
on October the 25th and then they added
it to the security to secure the
security advisories page on May the 25th
in 2022.
I don't check that page very often so if
they updated seven months later then I'm
not going to see that so I was assuming
they didn't backboard it because it's
it's quite an involved change
um it's also not in the Big Sur patch
notes anywhere as far as I can tell so
it's a bit weird that they skip a
version
I also have not verified if it's
correctly fixed or if they use the same
approach
uh yeah it's been so long that even
getting it to work again to make this
demonstration already took some time so
find all of those old versions I didn't
have the time for that
to conclude
security boundary between processors now
it's not just users and there's all of
these different permissions and
entitlements
that separates processes
and process injection vulnerabilities
can break those security boundaries by
allowing malware to get actual
permissions and abuse them
this was a process injection
vulnerability affecting all applicant
applications and could be used to escape
the sandbox Elevate privileges to roots
and bypasses it it was fixed in October
last year
I find some finally some takeaways
you see that Mac OS keeps adding more
and more defensive security layers
but adding security layers to an
established system with such a large
history is Mac OS that's really
difficult there's all of these places in
code that was written like more than 10
years ago
at the Assumption of a completely
different security model and a
completely different security
requirements and suddenly all of that
code is now a tech service so
application can now suddenly attack each
other
and there's still a lot of gold in the
system that is not really
making that assumption
and also what I think is a important
point to make here is that effort of
attackers may not increase if you add
more security layers because sometimes
you can just have one vulnerability and
bypass all of those layers at once
I have a few references that are used so
the Google project serial y tips for the
insecurity serialization
the and of the bug from Ilias and a few
other things about secure coding
and finally we have a write-up on our
website
it's still just the first part of the
exploit chain they're still part missing
I hope to be able to publish that soon
after Venture is released
um you can will also be able to find
that on our website
now do you have any questions
and can you repeat the question for the
live stream please
so the question is did I consider Swift
for the Apple scripts in the python
parts so
uh
I could not compile Swift and then try
to load it because the dynamic or the
art engine time would not allow me to do
that
I think there's this Swift playgrounds
like stuff but I'm not really sure I
haven't looked into it if I would be
able to load that and execute Swift like
that I haven't looked
into that it might work
yep
have the same limitations
and instructors
but the basic code is
using the objectives
going over
so I think there's a couple of different
ways that you can execute Apple
JavaScript so there's these
direct methods and there's also this
JavaScript for automation I'm not
completely sure how to call that from
Objective C so it it may be that this
was not possible I I don't fully I'm not
completely sure
uh but I think I did try it and then if
I eventually just gave up because I
already had python working for this
yeah this affects all versions of Mac OS
right like it goes back
yeah
or at least uh yeah probably back to the
introduction of sip uh probably affect
all of those yes cool and apple
backboarded just a few versions you said
only to Catalina and Big Sur they said
although the release notes don't really
make that clear
okay thank you
[Applause]