all right hello so you're all back from
lunch later on today we have at three
o'clock and hardware hacking is the
InfoSec career panel at five o'clock
your programs say chill-out room but the
demo party will probably be moved to the
hardware hacking village since there's
good
I assume gonna be a lot of you there at
six o'clock you for doing ham testing
that's in the lock-picking village and
later tonight at eight o'clock in this
room will be the big banquet dinner and
party so without further ado we have a
meet surfer with adware is just malware
with the legal department hey everyone
can you hear me okay
[Music]
yeah the first step bomb okay so before
I start I have to say two things one
this is kind of cool because two years
ago in layer one I go I gave the part a
talk about this whole story is there
anybody here
show of hands it was in my talk two
years ago rad three people also and it
was also the first time I gave a talk in
a security conference outside of my home
country which is Israel another cool
thing is I live in Boston now and
yesterday at TSA I just forgot my laptop
there this laptop so my wife actually
went to the airport when two TSA managed
to find my laptop and overnighted it
here so round of applause to my wife who
saved me from such a insane public
shaming anyways let's talk about some
adware so the obligatory Who am I this
is me
my name is a meat as I said originally
I'm from Israel I live in Boston now as
of a few weeks ago I'm the head of
security research at side reason
alternates which is our new research lab
that we are building right now before
that I used to act for a nation state
actor agency whatever
I do a lot of low-level research malware
research vulnerability research on like
shitty IOT stuff because it's always fun
and I should post a lot on Twitter and
this is my handle so you're all invited
in and yeah and sometimes my shitposting
actually causes trouble so as I said I
am originally from Israel and about a
month ago I went to visit my family and
I used those kiosks that you put your
hand on the thing and it lets you go
through the border the moment I put my
hand on the thing the fucking thing
crashed and I took a picture and then I
noticed that it's running Windows XP
this is a thing that makes people enter
a country and it runs Windows XP yay
so I I took those two pictures and I
post it on Twitter about ten minutes
later I got some really weird phone
calls from people from the government
tell me what the fuck did you do and a
day after that was in the papers so I
should probably shit post a little bit
less or a little bit more anyways a
quick history lesson because this story
is literally for me the gift that keeps
on giving because this whole thing has
been going on pretty much since the
layer one two years ago
so back in 2016 I discovered an adware
for for Mac really really aggressive
adware for from active with and when I
started looking through it I actually
realized it was a port for OSX for Mac
of the windows pirate adware the story
was that this guy I was in an OSX
reverse engineering IRC Channel and this
guy popped in and he said my machine is
acting really weird and he started
asking questions I told him well ok I
told him hey send me some files I'll
look at it
we'll see what's going on and that's how
I discovered the whole thing throughout
my research I was still living in Israel
back then and throughout my research I
noticed that all the signing
certificates had Israeli names on them
and a lot of things in
in in in when I looked at the scripts
and they look at the way that the
comments were written and the the
grammar that was used inside the
comments this whole thing felt very
Israeli to me again being Israeli III I
can figure those things out about I want
to say a month after my my talk in layer
one
they actually whoever did this adware
thing which behaves completely like
malware and will see it they pushed out
an update because I created a script
that removes the adware from your
machine and they pushed out an update
with a new version of their malware that
makes my script not to work anymore
pretty much and when I started
researching the new version that they
released I was too lazy to fire up my
Mac VM and I didn't want to extract the
files on my own machine so what I did is
I was lazy and I listed the father was a
tar.gz archive that they were pushing
out and I listed the file inside that
archive without extracting it now the
tar.gz format and again we'll see it
the tar.gz format is a POSIX format
which means that it saves the permission
tables inside the archive as they were
on the original machine that the archive
was created on and those guys their
username that created the the tar.gz
archive their username was their full
name like first name last name
so a quick LinkedIn search revealed the
fact that this was actually the VP Rd of
a company called targeting edge and they
are in fact in Israel and they are in
fact about I want to say a quarter of a
mile from the office I was sitting at at
the time so that was funny and there
were there were a bunch of articles they
did this talk in conferences and
basically all of their infrastructure
went down they had lots of servers and
they had a pretty substantial
infrastructure and all of it went down
and they were quiet for a while now
every time I find something interesting
and malware them working on iOS I always
have euro rules for it Iran virus Allah
or other
threat Intel services and our own
product cyber reason the company I work
for so I always look for stuff and in
November of 2017 all of a sudden all of
my alerts started lighting up like a
Christmas tree so I said okay I'll play
again that sounds fun so as I said I I
always have it looks kind of weird maybe
I should change the resolution is this
does this look fine like I don't know if
you guys think you can see it okay Brad
okay so as I said I have the are rules
for pretty much everything I find just
so that I could track it and once I
found some new samples as I said I
should post a lot so I went to Twitter
and I said hey are you fine I found this
thing and they're back at it again it's
time for another write up the next
morning we started getting threat
letters like legal cease and desist
letters from targeting edge and here are
some of the best the best things that
their attorneys could come up with so as
you can see this is really personal in
addition mr. surfer has been referring
to our client to our clients product on
social media as malware please note that
our client father is not malware no does
it include any components which may be
considered as malware and bla bla bla
bla it complies with laws and
regulations which is absolutely bullshit
because there is no end user License
Agreement anywhere in fact I double dare
all of you to open your phones and
Google targeting edge e ula or end-user
License Agreement you're probably going
to find links to my talk they kept
saying that as the cybersecurity expert
I am or side reason consider itself to
be an expert company it is well known
that adware is explicitly not malware
and a whole bunch of other preposterous
things against me again very personal
and they said that they said that my
previa
articles and talks were a direct attack
against them which is actually true
because I found their names and yeah I
mean I don't know they also said that
their product or their client which is
targeting edge does not spy or takes
over the browser the Prada product does
not collect nor store any personal
aggregated or sensitive information of
the user rather solely technical data
which is used in real time we are all
going to see that this is actually
bullshit they also said that so part of
the thing as you'll see as I go through
the talk excuse me
they showed several examples both here
in this current talk and two years ago
on how they're trying to distance
themselves from from this malware so you
won't find I mean if they wouldn't have
fucked up and left their names inside
the archives it would have been pretty
much impossible
again back then for me to tie it back to
targeting edge to that company into
those people because they use a lot of
methods to distance themselves they use
randomly generated like DGA domains
which we will talk about and they have a
whole anonymous infrastructure all of
their domains are registered with
privacy guards and all of that so it's
very hard to unless you know what you're
doing and where to look for it's very
hard to tie it back to them and they
said I mean they said we're not trying
to distance ourselves because the
product is not the OS X period malware
it has nothing to do with us and then
they added you said you know they said
that I called it malware here is how
ESET the AV company describes what
malware is their product literally
answers each one of those criterias and
all of those definitions which is pretty
funny as well so after I got like I
think 14 different letters because for
two weeks they used to send us between 1
and 1 or 2 letters each day and each
letter has had a completely different
narrative so they started with we have
nothing to do with this and they ended
like their last letter say
this is us but we're not malicious so
I'm like okay Wow
you should really up your you should
really get better lawyers in their last
letter they actually told us listen if
you want to release your report because
they realize that the report is going to
be published because and I need to tech
to thank the legal department inside
reason for that and our CEO which
basically said oh no fuck them like
we're not we're not gonna we're not
afraid from their legal department like
we don't give a shit our legal
department is bigger so fuck them so
they said if you are going to release
the report hey if you are going to
release a report include this sort of
disclaimer in it now we don't owe them
shit and we don't have to do that but
their disclaimer was so funny and so
ridiculous that we ended up including it
in the report and in this talk as you
can see anyway
just for the lols so it's basically them
saying that this is all fine and cyber
reasons mere purpose is to exploit our
products reputation google them there is
no reputation in order to create media
buzz and fulfill cyber ease and foreign
side reasons for an interest which I
don't even know what it means but ok so
if they keep saying that everything is
kosher where is the end user License
Agreement I literally went through like
I don't know hundreds of different
samples if not dozens I think it Borton
dozens it's hundreds of samples no
end-user license agreement anywhere and
their website has a contact form where
you can you know you can go to go to
their website and I don't know talk to
them and like ask them for a quote for
their product or whatever so that
contact form doesn't work so this is a
screenshot was sent to me by Zach
Whitaker from Zenith he's a journalist
and he sent him an email hey they're
reaching out for a comment regarding to
the report written by some reason blah
blah blah
the answer was at
a dress not found this is the email on
their website in for targeting edge comm
so like oh okay that's fine so this was
pretty much my reaction to like every
single letter they sent us because every
day they realized that the news is
pretty much like tightening around their
neck and after that quick history lesson
let's talk about the actual stuff so a
quick a quick introduction to Mac adware
so Mac adware is kind of kind of the
same of what you know from Windows like
you get ads and pop-ups and all sorts of
shit but the way that you get infected
with that wear is by downloading
software not from the vendors website so
let's say you want to download VLC media
player what you should do is go to VLC's
website and get it from there you should
not go to download calm or softonic or
all of those third-party downloads
website as if it's like 1995 because
what goes on in there is that they give
you an installer and the installer will
eventually install VLC media player but
it will also give you what I called in
layer 1 2016 I called it you'll get
herpes with that so yeah or chlamydia or
whatever and and the way that it used to
work back in 2006 is that they used to
create installer packages using Apple's
own package installer system and in
Apple's package installer system there's
a feature that's called a preflight
script a preflight script means it's a
script that runs as the Installer opens
so actually even before you saw the end
user License Agreement which is in the
Installer there's already a script
running in the background and they use
this mechanism back then in 2016 that's
the mechanism they used to they used to
in order to install themselves on your
machine so you would go to a website
think that you're downloading a media
player or whatever it is and you'll
double click it and even before you saw
the end-user License Agreement that
allegedly tells you that you are going
to install herpes on your machine it's
already too late and you're now infected
so
this stung around they kind of shook
things up and what I what I saw were
installers that and what I saw was
installers and they weren't using the
pre-fight stripped they were just
straight-up they were they wrote their
own installer that straight up calls
system like the system C API call and it
would do a bunch of things in the
background and in the end of those
things in the background they would
reach out to their server to get all
sorts of payloads now if you're familiar
with the concept of the Russian
matryoshka doll which is the doll that
opens and inside of it there's another
doll and you open it up and there's
another doll so that's pretty much the
whole fucking thing that you're gonna
see here it's like one payload
downloading another payload in another
payload in another payload and every
payload has a watchdog that watches over
the previous payload to see if it's the
running and to keep its auto runs
working so it was a pain in the ass to
analyze because it was it was a lot of
shitty codes and shitty scripts to read
so anyways that's the link that I saw
when I started looking at samples now
the thing is that every one of those
links has a unique identifier that is
right here and that identifier is only
valid for the same installation now the
thing is that I I'm always getting
things after the fact so when I see the
link and I try to and I try to request
that link it doesn't work because that
ID is invalid anymore so I'm like I can
see that there is new there's news
things happening and I really want to
look into it but I can't because the
fucking link won't work so this is a
this is a concept that applies to pretty
much every everything in my life which
is when everything fails apply fuckery
so I literally took the link and I I
trimmed all the crap and where it says
where it says ID I just put in an HTTP
encoded an HTTP encoded quote like a
single double quote that was literally
my first attempt and I said well I send
it what could possibly happen
so I send it and their server sent me
another link like interesting what
happens if I request that link I got a
huge installation script now this link
is like full it's it's 326 lines if I
remember correctly it's a really
terrible bash script and it's full of
things that are like running as root
it's basically just a bunch of Kanab
unch of commands like this command
semicolon and other command semicolon
another command and they're like
installing crap all over your system and
like right here you can see launch
agents so they're installing like auto
runs and all sorts of hooks and shit on
your Mac so that when you restart your
machine you'll already boot with with
herpes now you can see where was it you
can see here that they have the ability
to run stuff as routes because you're
calling they're calling they're calling
sudo on a whole bunch of commands which
means that they run is route now here's
the kicker
a lot of people when they saw this
thought they said oh wow they have route
like are they using exploits like holy
shit and no because if you ever
installed something on a Mac you know
that the first thing that happens when
an installer is opening up it asks for
it asks for the password of your user so
that it could do all sorts of things now
on on Mac by default your user is in the
sudoers list so your password is also
the password that gets you root so the
installer asks for your password they
have your password they run stuff as
root it's that easy so as I said that
script was huge and that's what's being
downloaded at the first stage of the
infection now yeah it's 329 lines not 26
it's a huge bass crypt it's very similar
and actually almost identical to the
script I analyzed and again displayed
here two years ago so that's that's one
thing that ties this new infection back
to them and they said that they had
nothing to do with this that stripped
also has
url's in it on different servers and
like the URLs are DGA addresses show of
hands do we know what DGA addresses are
okay so those who don't know DGA stands
for domain generation algorithm very
popular in malware and nefarious shit it
basically it basically means that there
is an algorithm that the people who made
this malware have and they have the
ability to basically generate domains so
the de mal where has the same algorithm
and it just tries to access all sorts of
different domains and the attackers can
register those domains whenever they
want because they don't have to have the
domains registered they know which
domains the malware is eventually going
to hit so if one of their domains get
blacklisted they can also register the
next one on the list and the malware
will attempt to access this domain so
again like you don't see DG a outside of
malware like there's no legitimate
reason to register a really long weird
domain it looks like a sha-1 hash for
example now those scripts that giant
installation scripts just it does a
bunch of work downloads another strip
that strip does a bunch of work
downloads another strip and that's what
we're going to see here now all of the
payloads that are being downloaded are
saved to a random directory directory
with a randomly generated name sorry and
the way that they're generating the
domain that they name will see that it's
also the same method that they use two
years ago so as I said it's it's very
it's very generic it's very easy very
easy to understand as we can see here
they have in their script they have a
function that's called our MD I'm
guessing that it stands for random and
it simply cats a file in slash USR slash
air slash dict slash words which is just
a file with a bunch of dictionary words
in it so it casts that file gets a
random word cleans it from any other
shit it has in there and just saves it
into a variable and this is how the this
is how the random name is being chosen
so on
reinstallation of the malware on every
on every computer this thing is being
installed on the path is not the same so
it's also very hard to figure out if you
were infected or not because if I was
infected there will be a certain word
but someone else was infected it would
be a different word than that does the
path will change values and all sorts of
other files that it's dropped that it's
dropping will change so it's another way
of basically helping them to bury
themselves deeper in in your machine and
they used that same method actually the
same function with the same syntax in
their stripped from two years ago so
that's another thing that ties it back
to them as they said they don't spy on
the users they don't gather any
sensitive information they don't trap
the users but there is a line in their
code that simply and it's just a script
it just gets the unique identifier of
the machine and it sends it back to
their server so you can see that it gets
the i/o platform UID and then it just
parses it and to the point that it has
the UID and then it just like uses curl
to send it to their server and you can
see the domain here like 0 9 a II d5 mck
3 it doesn't make any sense right
there's no legitimate reason to have
that domain and as you can see there's
like a web app of some sort that takes
this UUID and puts it into their data
database and that's how they know that
oh this this machine with this UID is
infected and it also sends them this
this value my path is also the randomly
generated name that was created for this
specific infection so they actually have
a way of knowing which machine to the
point of the unique identifier has the
malware installed with which fake name
so again they say everything is fine
right once the UID was submitted then
there's another payload that's that's
being downloaded and and it creates a
launch agent now a launch agent in Mac
speak if you don't know it's basically
an auto run so there are all sorts of
way of ways both documented and
undocumented to create Auto runs on on
max the two most familiar ones are
launch agents and launch Damons which
will see both of them here the
difference between the two is that a
launch agent will launch when the user
is logging in so if you have multiple
users in your machine and like my user
has a launch agent this launch agent
will start as soon as my user is logging
in a launch daemon is launching as soon
as the system boots
so it's user agnostic so they are
planting both launch agents and launch
Damons and as you can see again they're
downloading more payloads you can see
like the URLs are weird and like all
sorts of variables are weird and and and
the purpose of that is to make it very
very very difficult for detection
because most detection programs and
software for Mac just sucks so it's very
easy to avoid them so I started to look
at the payloads that were being
downloaded very very basically just I
just looked at the names of the
functions there so like when you look at
the functions the function names of the
binary that was downloaded you can see
like functions that the names are like
did receive response did receive data
will cache response connection did
finish loading like everything looks
fine and then there was this function
that's called run external application
and I was like oh we run external
application that's kind of weird so it's
at a time and when I looked at it in Ida
so here's the function here run external
application and here is a pseudo code
for your enjoyment wow it's like really
hard to see so I'll just tell you what's
going on here so it's calling an
objective-c function that's called NS
tasks and as fast as the objective-c
equivalent of C's system so it simply
just execute a command through a shell
and you can see here that one of the one
of the parameters actually called slash
bin slash SH so they actually have the
ability to run stuff as route from that
payload that
runs on your machine so they know your
computer through the UUID and usernames
and whatever it is that they're
collecting and now they have the ability
to run code on your machine I don't know
yeah right this is fine so as I said
when you look at it just when you look
at this artifact alone I know it kind of
looks like a rat right now unlike their
old payloads from two years ago which
were code signed because in Apple's
world if you want to run something on
your machine without getting weird error
messages that this is not safe you have
to have your code code signed now unlike
the windows world where you can buy
certificates from all sorts of vendors
with Apple being Apple you can only buy
certificates from Apple and the the
process the procedure to obtain such a
code signing certificate is very very
very complicated you need to have
ninety-nine dollars in your bank account
and an excuse and that's it
so you basically send them you fill in
this form on Apple's website you sign up
to their development program and and you
you sign up for that and they and you
request a certificate and you tell them
well I am working on an app on an app
for a Mac or for an iPhone that I don't
know makes fart sounds or something and
I need a developer certificate here is
99 bucks Apple will say thank you very
much here's your receipt here is your
code signing certificate and that's it
yeah okay we can debate that but two
years ago they had hundreds of certs and
I had a contact in Apple I told him hey
this certificate is like bullshit and
it's spreading malware they would revoke
the certificate they would have they
would in like two hours they would have
pushed a new version through their
server with a new signing certificate in
like that was like a like a really bad
Kevin Mouse key
that I was always losing with that was
always losing in sorry this time it was
code sign but with something different
that's called an ad hoc signature which
is actually completely meaningless from
Mac OS that hawk signatures are used for
when you're developing iOS apps and you
want to test them on your phone and your
phone your iPhone can only run only run
code signed code sign binaries so an ad
hoc signature is just as it's called
it's an ad hoc signature it's it's a
signature that was meant to to test your
software on your phone so they would
sign their Mac OS binary with ad hoc
signatures which was which for me looked
really weird and I thought that it's
like a some sort of way for them to
throw off antiviruses because oh this is
sign so that's fine but actually the
component that verifies this code
signature doesn't exist in the Mac OS
kernel so okay
and actually I gave this talk a few
weeks ago in Chicago and and do that
works for an AV company walked up to me
and says oh your your theory is actually
correct it does throw off antiviruses so
there you go another thing that they're
doing which is completely kosher right
now this payload also enumerates a list
of running processes on on your machine
and and the reason that it does that it
looks for what browsers are running on
your machine because you need to
remember the whole purpose of this thing
is not is to spy on you but it's to spy
on you in order to give you ads and the
ads have to be targeted to you I mean
hey the name of the company is targeting
edge and what it does it looks at what
browsers you have and then it it
downloads what's called in the code it's
called ad packages so if you're running
Safari it will you know download an ad
package for Safari if you're running
Chrome it'll download something Chrome
and it also makes sure that everything
is up-to-date
now this this service that downloads the
ad packages also creates a launch agent
with with the same method so it's it's
it's generating a random
from the dictionary and then it creates
it creates a listing that runs that
launch agent as you can see here and on
on my VM it was called roadless so okay
that's a word I guess and then when I
started looking at it more and more and
more and more I saw that I have more and
more payloads to look at so that was fun
so welcome to my world so once this
thing is done once it creates at launch
agents that's this launch agent it
downloads yet another tar.gz archive and
in this tar GT archive we can see that
we have scripts we have like text files
and we have some binaries along the
binaries and you can see by the way they
names you can see a browser enhancer
updater and protector and when I saw the
name protector I was like okay protector
that's interesting what is it protector
ring so protector is a binary file in
this and this is by the way you can see
in this slide that how much sleep that
provided I am so see if you can spot it
protector is a binary file with one
purpose to check that all the payloads
are running and that all the launch age
and all the launch agents and launch
demons are still there if they are
removed protector will bring them back
protector also sets up a launch to - so
there's two purposes protector also sets
up a launch daemon with a random name
generated the same generated in a
different way this time so instead of
going to the to the dictionary word file
in like written randomizing a word from
there it comes attached with a file
called with a file called name names DB
which has some just words in it and then
it takes like words and it creates those
words and then it creates a random word
from them so another thing another cool
thing about protector which I find which
I found really interesting is that
protectors and updaters insulation
script is also removing a browser plugin
that's called omni key and i was like
what is omni key so i went to look at
what i'll make he is an omni key is Amna
key is actually a plug-in
allows you do you know how in chrome you
can go to the address tab and you write
something you just write random thing
hit enter and it Google's it or if
you'll sometimes if you'll type eBay and
hit tab and then like search something
it will search it or eBay so it's
basically a plugin that allows you to do
the same thing and allows you to create
custom search providers for your browser
and apparently that plug-in causes
issues with this malware so it kind of
makes it hard for them to see in what
websites you're and what - what website
you're going to so they're just straight
up remove it without asking you because
this is fine now as you can see they're
like OPSEC masters and you haven't seen
shit yet and they they have lots of
debugging shit in their scripts so like
when they I guess that when they test
their code they test it in production so
you can see like echo searching
extension checking removing now for for
like free literally years for two years
I was really I was wondering like how do
they call that project in house because
they don't call it OSX spirit that's
like an AV name and and yeah so there is
one there is one block and discreet that
in the script that just installs the
thing and it just says installing the
vinci i was like cool i have a name a
cool name for my where am i right up
that the vinci code because that's not a
cliche right so let's look at browser
enhancer for a sec which is the binary i
told you about so let's enhance i
fucking love this gift yeah the first
time i saw this i stared at it for three
minutes like oh motherfucker
yeah so another thing that ties this
whole thing back to targeting edge as
they said because this has nothing to do
with us right
another thing is their constant use of Q
T so Q T is a programming framework some
of you may know it and QT allows you to
write software and it's basically right
once compile anywhere or run anywhere
whatever you want to call it so you
write your code and then you can compile
your code to work on Linux Windows Mac
whatever but you know that one of the
disadvantages is you get all of the Qt
crap bundled into your software so when
you look at it and I know you can see
like all sorts of QT types like the Q
string which is the string type in QT if
I recall correctly so that's another
thing that ties it back to them because
the binaries I looked at two years ago
we're full of QT crap now brows are an
answer which is another QT application
looks for the browsers that you have
running on your machine it looks for
Firefox and look for Safari it looks for
Chrome but it also looks for Microsoft
Internet Explorer on a Mac so two years
ago when I when I gave this talk I I
showed I show people like there's there
was a lot of windows related crap in
this OSX compiled binary and this was
also here in this binary so as you can
see it's kind of hard this is a fucking
Windows registry key HD current user
software Microsoft whatever that like
myself endurance for and it checks for
this for this registry key that
obviously shouldn't exist on Mac OS now
as I said I have no I have no idea of
what kind of wizardry was pulled in
order to make this thing compile at all
but hey so yeah that's actually another
thing now I gave this talk a few weeks
ago and I said well I have no idea why
intercept or should run on Mac OS and
then someone from the audience yelled
yeah but you can use
no not wine natively like I know what
wine is come on so oh and yeah and there
was ages ago
um Internet's core version for Mac but I
think that died a decade ago so like
this is this is a fuckup like this is
not intended
now once browser enhancer is executed
the browser's will restart themselves so
people like people would see like oh
they're like browsing the internet and
all of a sudden boom their browsers like
all of a sudden restarting and the
reasons the reasons that the browser is
restarting because you have a whole
bunch of weird shit loaded into your
browser so you you have like new
tracking cookies that that follow you
everywhere you go and you have like a
new search page that you never asked for
but you have it because herpes and and
they also learn to use Apple script
which is really funny because two years
ago I teased them on Twitter and with
every bit of information I released I
said oh well they could have used this
API call why didn't they do that oh they
could have used Apple script to do that
and like every new version I saw did
they actually implemented what I told
them to do which is kind of cool and
like I'll show you you'll be able to see
it it's very important to stay hydrated
so in here you can see they're starting
to use Apple script Oso script is the
command-line tool this is like the
interpreter for Apple Strip and Apple
script is kind of cool because it's
basically English like the syntax is
like tell application Firefox to launch
and that will cause Firefox to run I
heard and I think it's true that if your
Mac is like in French for example then
you will be able to write Apple script
in French so if we have any foreign
languages if any foreign language
speakers here in the audience that would
be awesome to check because I only speak
Hebrew other than English and no one
cares enough about Hebrew so
look now this is your hijacked search
page so if you'll search if you'll if
you'll use the search function in your
browser it won't go to Google or Bing
anymore it will go to a very reputable
search provider called tikka search now
when you go to the about to the about
page and take a search com
you can see that their address is in
Israel which is my home country all and
not only its in Israel its Babylon
Limited which is like the biggest
fucking spyler crap that ever came out
of my country not including all of the
nation state shit so rad but just when
you think that it's done there is more
it's a long gif
yeah okay they also have a post install
strip that runs after everything is done
installing so once browser enhancer
enhancer is done with installing itself
it will execute a post installation
script that is called post install data
staging
now this strip you guessed it right hit
tell there's another payload this time
it's actually it's not a strip because
most of the payloads are scripts scripts
and this time it downloads a binary
executable called Mac there now I don't
know what Mac ver means someone
suggested Mac verifier I don't know but
again it's generating a list of random
words using the same method as you can
see here and it will create a new file
called complication dot P list and it
creates it in your home directory slash
library slash preferences so that
directory slash like till the library
slash preferences you have it in your
home directory and and this file
actually contains lots of preferences
that have lots of preferences for your
user for example how far are the icons
from each other where are the icons
arranged on your desktop like all sorts
of shit so if you go to that directory
and you'll see a file that's called
complication dog plist you won't suspect
it because it kind of makes sense that
the file with that name will be there
but when you when you look at that file
you can actually see that there's a
random word in here it's another plist
with around the word and it's actually
contains the name of the plug-in that
should be loaded into your Safari
browser when you're starting it so again
like it's it's all sorts of weird dumb
tricks to make to make it hard for you
to find them you can also you can also
see in this image what it means it was
what I'm showing here is how they take
existing configurations and just change
them so they changed oh no what happened
okay so yeah so they take the files they
file that they just created with that
with that key the random word here is
sailcloth which is also a word I guess
and then they change it and they add
some more shit to it so this is another
tracking thing so what they do here is
they actually they hijack your Google
search page you can see here so if you
if you go to Google it will actually
take you to loading pages info / jo / is
and it will send the server this gooood
which identifies you and that's how they
can track your Google searches as well
so let's break let's break apart Mac for
it this is binary how are we doing with
time okay
hyperspace Modi matter is a 64-bit mock
Oh executable now mock o is the
executable format on OS X naught P
that's Windows not else that's Linux
mock fucking Oh
unlike other executables it doesn't
import any QT resources but it has many
interesting things in it now I am very
very good at my job so when I look at
the strings I saw a whole bunch of
base64 crap now as you know base64 is
the best way of encrypting and since I
am very good at what I do
I decrypt at that shit and so yeah
always like sensitive stuff always
base64 and and when I D base64 it I saw
a bunch of Apple script code which is
fucking rad right now Apple script is a
scripting language that was created by
Apple and it was created in order for
Apple to make it easier for their users
to automate stuff so if you have for
example if you have an application that
converts video from one format to
another and you want to convert a whole
bunch of files and your software your
video conversion software doesn't allow
getting multiple files and work on them
you can very easily in plain English
write a script in Apple strip that will
tell this application hey take this file
convert it like take this value put it
in this text field hit this button and
so on and so forth so they actually used
Apple strip which is what I told them to
do on fucking Twitter and and move their
entire malware to use Apple strip now
almost any application on OS X has an
apple script API so you'd be surprised
you can use that with script in almost
anything
so Apple script is actually code
injection as a service without doing
code injection and I'll show you that oh
ya mean yo dawg i heard you like code
injection so we used Apple script to
inject coded inject JavaScript yeah okay
you need to run so this is a you to get
on with the show so this is part of the
part of the base64 encrypted stop so as
you can see it's an English tailor
plication Safari to set page source to
do JavaScript and then a whole bunch of
JavaScript and that
the JavaScript atraxi would displays the
ads you know you want to go to one side
they will say fuck you and we'll take
you to another website and this is
basically the code that does it the way
did they put it inside your browser is
through Apple Script so when you think
that you're using Google Chrome or
Safari or Firefox or fucking Microsoft
Internet Explorer on a Mac and you think
that you're safe because of that no one
can inject code and everyone cares about
security and this is this is a Mac and
you can't inject code on Mac because
there's there's there's not a CPU in
there it's a bunch of unicorns and
courage Apple actually gives you a very
easy way of injecting code without
really injecting code so think about it
like every page that you load actually
has JavaScript code that wasn't intended
on being there and it doesn't break as
to sell it doesn't it won't get error
messages you don't even know that it
happens here's another example for
Chrome no one cares so basically what
happens is you have this binary Mac fur
it runs
ohso script through simply calling anis
task or system right and it it asks the
browser what tell me what is the current
URL that you're visiting the browser
will say hey I'm in I don't know Twitter
and it will go back to Mac fur mattre
will do like this bidding ad bidding war
on their servers on targeting edge there
so okay this guy with this UUID so let's
say like oh this is a meat we know that
this is some meat we know that the meat
is from Boston
let's give him ads that are suitable for
what he is looking for on Twitter or
whatever and then those ads would
actually be planted on the top of the
page it - you're visiting
so they're actually stealing ad revenue
from other website which is also illegal
but who gives a fuck no one now in older
versions of OS X spirits what they
actually did so if you'll watch my talk
from two years ago they were actually
installing a proxy a straight-up proxy
server on your machine and they would
reconfigure the firewall that's running
it's like the it's a PF it's like the
acquit the Mac equivalent of IP tables
on Linux so they would actually install
this proxy server and
reconfigure the the firewall to route
every packet that goes through port 80
through their fucking proxy server and
this is how they would inject at this
time because they listen to me they're
actually using javascript to inject code
directly to your browser so they're not
installing anything on your machine
other than those scripts right but since
I said that they're masters in OPSEC
they also have debug strings like if you
run there if you run their binary in a
console you'll get all of the debug shit
that they didn't remove so you can
actually see oh yeah and he's good he's
going to Google so I went to Google and
I looked for error right I sent I simply
went to Gulen wrote the error hit enter
and then you can see the bidding war so
it goes to loading page it sends them it
sends them you can see here the my
gooood so they know it's me and then I
say okay Google Chrome is running and
then okay open this URL and this URL
hasn't has an ADD so as you can see here
I look for error and then I've got
another tab you can see it here and when
I went to that tab it was an ad for like
an anti-virus if you know it's fucking
Mac what with me shit
Mac keeper yes Mac keeper which is like
this fake AV which is also bullshit so
they're probably going to sue me as well
that's gonna be fun
and as you can see after the after the
whole first last name in the archive
they actually listened to me and now
everything is Batman like it's no longer
their name it's it's it says Batman so
they thought that by doing that they can
make it hard for me to tie this thing
back to them but oh boy they were wrong
because here's the thing when I write a
report in when I write malware reports
if you've never written and if
everything anything I wrote including
this report that this talk is based on
it's like 30 pages long it's like super
detailed and I just dump everything onto
the paper or the PDF or whatever you
want to call it but I don't reveal
everything because unlike them I'm not
an idiot
well I am but to a certain extent so I
didn't reveal all this stuff I know
about them because I want to have a way
of finding them again the next time
they're doing something stupid
now they
they were convinced that because they
removed her because they removed their
names from the from the by from the
archive I won't be able to tie it back
to them but boy were they wrong because
I already did it so let's look at the
proof that I've showed that I've shown
you now right so we have code that looks
almost identical to the code that they
that they wrote two years ago all of
their methods are the same other than
the Apple script stuff and we have
frantic letters from their attorneys to
us saying don't publish that this is
like infringing our intellectual
property but while this is all super
interesting and funny and this is like a
funny story I can I can tell on stage
this is not really proof then I'm asking
you what is proof proof is this thing
for example so when they're buying their
cnc domains those DGA looking things
they're always buying them in batches of
eight or ten and there was this one time
they forgot to put on the privacy thing
on on a certain batch of domains they
bought so when I looked at at this
domain I saw that it's related to a
bunch of other IP addresses that are
tied to other domains and those domains
were registered by the name of the CEO
at targeting edge com wait no no no
seriously so we have that now if you go
to the Whois record you can see very
clearly the name of the dude and the
company and their address but after my
talking layer one two years ago I got a
resume into email that not me cyber
reason and the recruiter send me a
frantic email you got to see this one of
the one of the guys so I found two names
there one of the guy who wasn't the BPRD
was so excited that he sent us his
resume and his resume he literally said
my work appeared inside reasons lab
report linking it to my report
yeah and there was another article that
he linked to that actually wasn't
related to me now this is actually even
funnier because if you remember in in
their letters they say we don't use any
exploits
we don't use any vulnerability we're
legit omit software company but the
article that he was linking to was on
another ad was about another ad word
that they did which was exploding which
was exploiting the back then back then
the exploit it was called root pipe
which allows you to get arbitrary root
access
so this idiot literally just framed them
he framed them he framed he framed
himself and he actually made their
attorneys their attorneys claim
basically like worthless because here
they are using exploits and with that
dumpster fire I will thank you
so do we have time for questions or do I
need to get the fuck off the stage
someone yes funny you should say that in
their letters to us they said that they
are fully gdpr compliant so yes but yes
just not at our company yeah so I think
I need to get off the stage if you're
really interested in that thing there's
it's a huge report it's on cyber reasons
what one minute or do I need to get off
oh yeah okay
Oh personally so I can go back in a
personal way against them I mean I find
it funny and yes in they're idiots and
they're breaking the law in multiple
countries they're threatening people
personally hi me and they're actually
not really good at their job so yeah in
my book they're idiots
[Applause]
Wow I just I just I this is a completely
asshole answer it's like totally not
like me but so I'm sorry if I'm rude but
like that's what I think anyways if you
guys have any questions feel free to
heckle me in person because I have to
clear the stage
[Applause]