talk in the hardware hacking village
there is the info set career panel so if
you're interested in that that is after
this also after this in lockpick
knowledge is another intro to
lock-picking there's of course another
talk after this but that's just other
stuff going on at 5:00 p.m. the demo
party has been moved to the hardware
hacking village not the chill-out room
but that's at 5:00 o'clock hardware
hacking village if you're doing ham
testing that's at 6 o'clock in the
lock-picking village and then at 8 p.m.
tonight is dinner and then board game
night after that and with a bit of luck
you won't ruin the experience for the
kid having his high school graduation
next door to us you are dorks confirmed
dorks no comment other than that we have
RIT's key with git for hackers god
that's loud it's nice to know that this
is a this is a sound amplifier and if I
touch anything on this podium it's going
to be really noisy so I'm going to try
not to set this fine root beer down and
do that
alright so get for hackers of course
we'll get into the question of what this
has to do with hacking in general in a
moment but thanks for taking some time
out of the middle of your conference day
to come to my talk I am Jason risky or
RIT's go or our tzq zero and today what
we're going to be talking about is
deleting things or the rather
frustrating experience of attempting to
delete things from the git version
control system a system where record
retention is in fact one of the only
qualifying functional requirements
a tiny beetle blag I think my laptop is
so old but it's saying 1020 yeah 19
sorry
1080p okay now some of you may be right
software and maybe some of you will
never ever write a line of code but if
you know somewhere who writes software
or if you do write software the chances
are that you are at least aware of git
and aware of the fact that over the last
decade it's kind of become the major de
facto public repository standard I
remember when I started out doing
software stuff the field was a lot more
cluttered as far as who was running what
but seeing a lot more centralization of
get there's still a fair bit of SVM but
I think people are no longer seeing
mercurial as maybe the serious contender
that it once was and so we're seeing so
much pressure around get and and it's
you know whether you're using github or
get lab or Garret or get T or fabricator
or redmine or something else I have
never heard of most of these platforms
are are centralizing on the get service
back end and while git is a fairly good
distributed version control system in my
opinion one of the best things about git
is that many many of its users have no
idea how it works
and since bugs and bones by extension
are essentially defined between the
Delta of expectation and reality right
this is how I think things work versus
this is what's actually going on
hopefully you can see where I'm going
with this the more you understand about
git and unless someone else understands
about get the more things you're going
to take away from them so prove this
point let's talk about the fact that
people leave horrible things lying
around and let's go on a little bit of a
very very short and simple Safari to
github
this this is in red so this private key
has been deleted which means I can't see
it so one of my favorite ways to depress
myself at night is to go on github and
enter the search is a search term delete
private key and then looking commits for
people who have made a git commit the
title of which is delete private key
they could have called their commit
anything they could have called their
commit add important feature and I would
never see it I would never know it was
there because I'm not searching for you
know IDRs a dot M I'm searching for the
words I'm searching for an admission of
guilt there are 77 thousand 821
admissions of guilt that's a lot of
guilt this guy's my hero
he's done this twice and he still
doesn't know that it doesn't work if you
if you actually start looking into some
of these repos and again there's there's
seventy seven thousand eight hundred and
twenty one of them so there's a lot of
commits there to depress yourself with
you'll find a lot of personal
repositories with people playing around
and then you'll start to occasionally
every one to two hundred repos or so
bump into something where you're like
that's probably somewhere important or
like a piece of software that was
admittedly by its developer volunteer
software were written for a Veterans
Hospital or like various things really
like did they stop using that key I hope
they're replaced and I'm not sure but
but yeah definitely um definitely some
stuff lying around this is the lowest
hanging fruit this is I went on the
internet and typed some words into a
search engine and hit enter and now I
have creds right this is a slick this is
this is barely hacking this is just
advanced googling and there's more fruit
up that fruit tree and fruits delicious
so let's talk about the anatomy of git
first of all and we're gonna be dealing
with like the world's smallest repo I
think we're gonna have at max at one
point we're going to have a grand total
of five commits in this repository that
we're talking about
I'm keeping it small because I'd like to
be able to hopefully have all of you
keep what's going on in your head we're
gonna try and follow through it but I
want to make sure that as much as
possible people can track what's going
on so some of you may have worked with
get at the command line the basic get
commit to create a new local
repositories get in it so we're going to
create a new repo move into that
repository we're going to put the word
foo in a file food on txt I'm gonna add
that to the index and commit it so now
I've created a new git commit right in
our repository in a moment we'll go to a
graph and I'll represent this visually
but for those of you who are
command-line learners this is how you
add something to report this is the
basic I have created a one commit rip
posit or II didn't get and that creates
something that looks kind of like this
okay we have at the top head which is a
reference in your git repository there's
a folder called Dopp kit and in that
folder there is a file called head all
caps and that file contains a path that
points to another file called master
under a directory called slash refs
slash heads and that file contains a
hash contains a sha-1 hash which points
into a folder in your gift directory
called objects and in that directory the
first two characters of that hash or a
folder and the rest are a file and
that's where your commit is your commit
contains another hash that points to a
tree which is another word for a folder
and that commit it contains another hash
which points to another object which is
a blob we'll go into this more but this
is generally what you have in our brand
new repository we have a single commit
which contains a single tree which is
the base folder and a single blob which
is our food ext file another way to say
this is like I said there's a file in a
folder called refs heads master that
points to a commit that commits has a
sha-1 sum that starts with EE 65 afbf
that points to a tree that has a sha-1
sign that starts with FCX
0b e 4d when it's do a blob that starts
with 2 5 7 c c 5 6 and the content of
that blob is the word who will discuss
the anatomy of each of these objects
it's not important that you understand
exactly where they are they're all in
the dot get slash objects directory
they're all pointed to by these sha-1
sums get indexes everything I'll I get
indexes some things by sha-1 sums until
you get into pack louse which is about
2/3 of the way through this talk this
begins to lead us to what I call the
original recipe failure to delete or
what we find when we do those fun Google
searches for deleted private keys
if I remove my food txt file and then I
make a new get commit with the message
remove food txt because I didn't want to
type the words delete private key
because it makes me sad we create this
so what's important to understand about
git is that it does not delete things it
merely creates new things so previously
we had a tree that pointed to a blob and
when we removed that blob from our
director who and removed the food on txt
file
what git does is it leaves that tree and
it leaves that blob and it creates a new
tree it creates a new commit that points
to the new tree and not the old one and
so the old tree and the old blob in the
old commit are left behind this is good
this is it doing what it's designed to
do it's a version control system and it
says that commit points to the old
version this commit points to the new
version and if you look inside they get
objects directory at the hash value of
your old friend Fuu dot txt you'll find
that checksum right 2 5 7 CC
2 6 4 right that whole thing it is
compressed with the Z Lib deflate
algorithm so you can use there's a
number of tools you can use here I'm
using Zeeland flate uncompressed and I
just type the object into that and I get
blob for foo but it's there it's still
there in the repository even though it's
not my local directory anymore because I
removed him in a hex editor we can
actually see what's going on here we
have the type of the file it's a blob
so 6266 f6 - then we have a space then
we have the size in ASCII then we have a
null byte and then we have
the content of the blog right this is a
blob object
this is how it's represented in game
this is this is the manifest of it after
it's been deflated as for the tree
object it's kind of a similar
composition it says that it's a treat it
is a space that tells you how big it is
then it has a no bite then it actually
gives a mode which is similar to the
unix mode but not exactly the same it's
fun to read up on it's got all of these
bytes for the mode but most of the
values are invalid and then it has a it
has the the path of the file right so it
says foo dot txt is the path of the file
and then it has a it has that path so
that when it when you do a git checkout
it can restore the file to the correct
location and then it has a checksum that
the hash of the object not in ASCII ok
this it's important to remember that
because in a moment we're gonna look in
commits that hash is going to be an
ASCII that this hash is just in binary
so if you're ever looking at this and
you're like why is the house in this
half as many bytes long when you go to a
commit it's twice it because it's it's
an ASCII this time so commit object it's
similar it says it's a commit it has a
space it tells you the size then it
references a tree it says here's a tree
here's the hash of that tree here's also
the author here's the committer and
here's a unix timestamp and a UTC offset
which is fantastic if you're trying to
find out where somebody lives by the way
if you ever want to find out what
timezone someone's in unless they're
changing their local time before they do
their get commits that can always be fun
oh I've been going through these fairly
fast I don't know how many of you may
have noticed but the the tree ID just
changed and the reason the tree ID just
changed is because when I started doing
this demonstration to harvest all these
values for you I accidentally put in
I had left my kid repository turned on
to my to my work email address
what a fantastic teachable opportunity
to show you about how to delete things
out of a git repository how providential
this brings us to the second way of
failing to delete something from get
pardon my terrible coffee puns github
has a lovely page on changing the author
info they offer a script to change offer
info there's also a commonly used tool
called BFG repo cleaner cleaner both of
these are wrappers around a get internal
tool called filter branch filter branch
is designed to allow you to rewrite git
history in this case let's pretend I
don't really know what I'm doing very
well because that's as we saw from doing
our google search most people I look at
my git log I see that I have these
commit values d21 80926
1865 AFB those are the check sums of my
commits because they're shot won hashes
everything and give us a challenge
except for pack lines so I run the
change name dot sh-sh file it rewrites
the commits now they have new hash Sons
they have news check sums because
something's been changed in them what's
been changed my email address has been
changed if you go back here you know you
can see that that commit address that
that commit right there is gonna match
the one that I had originally so we've
run the filter branch we've changed the
values that's fantastic and if I look at
my git log it tells me oh we have we
have the right name here that's not my
work email address you you guys all
don't get to see my work email address
now if I pushed this already if I push
this to github I'm a variable degree of
host now I would me by to say a variable
degree posed if you have a small
repository that's private and only you
use you can do a rewrite and you can
force push and you're good
if you've successfully submitted a patch
to the Linux kernel you're never
uncorking that Genie and you're just
gonna have to get new SSH keys or
whatever yeah so we're Horst case big
public repository best case small tiny
repository or a corporate repo sometimes
in the corporate repo you can tell
everyone okay you guys have to delete
all of your local beta you guys have to
delete all your local data and reclone
will take you five minutes as long as
you've been managing your repos properly
or it'll take you six hours if
everyone's communic committing large
binaries into your git repo like bad
children but let's return to the filter
branch we just did because obviously it
solved our problem that object is still
there
my commit object from previous to my
filter branch is still there I've
rewritten the history but once again the
object is still in the objects folder
and it's still there for anyone to see
I've replaced my name in my email for
safety reasons why doesn't this help
filter branch doesn't delete anything it
writes new commits it changes reference
pointers it doesn't delete anything if
you look at the documentation for vfg
BFG repo cleaner is going to tell you
that afterwards you need to use the
standard get GC command to strip out all
of the unwanted data right it's gonna go
in and it's gonna garbage collect it's
gonna remove all of those dangling
objects all right good good we can fix
this we can fix this this is going to go
well so we do a git GC okay good it's
done the get GC
and it says that I can't access the
object fantastic we've done it we've
removed the object why are there seven
objects I have made one commit that
contains one file and one tree and I've
made another commit that has one tree
and no object I should have five objects
why do I have seven let's talk about PAC
files the reason that I can't see that
object anymore is because when I run get
GC get happily takes all of the objects
and packs them up into pack files pack
files are basically lists they're
basically binary files that contain
pointers into various values inside the
pack file indicating where objects can
be unpacked and they're also Delta fide
so most of get does not do Delta dipping
but PAC files do this is a concession
from the git developers from the very
early versions that allows you to
transport data more efficiently right so
when you're doing get pushes and pulls
and you have lots of files that are very
similar files move faster gzip
compression is already pretty good
storage space saving but PAC files are
better right PAC files do do better
storage best explanation of PAC files
you're gonna find is from the recurse
Center they explain how these actually
work I'm not going to go into it but
they're very impressive from an
architecture perspective if you wanted
to be able to do successful binary
search over Delta diffs
spread over multiple arbitrary files
there's a good explanation in here of
how to do it but you don't need to know
how to do this if you want to unpack
these files right very simple recipe for
dealing with this problem is you take
the PAC file out of the get objects
directory I just didn't have enough room
on the slide for the full hack
one and then you cat it in to get unpack
objects get unpacked the objects and yay
we've found the odd I mean boo
we found the object again but what
happened right
we removed the object that didn't work
we did a filter branch that didn't work
we did a garbage collection the commits
aren't in the log and they aren't
referenced anywhere why do we still have
them right if I do get logged these
commits aren't here I do get log -
that's all they aren't here where are
they let's talk about the get rest log
but get ref log
well the get ref log command is a
command which looks at various logs
inside of dock gets slashed logs and the
logs are in plain text you can just read
them you can use this command or you can
read them with any text file editor or
what the ref logs actually contain is
they contain a pointer to a commit and
they contain a timestamp and they
contain a brief message of what was
happened but the ref log are as they are
a local log of branches and references
updated in the local repository in the
headrests log actually stores branch
switches so if you want to see when
someone on their local repository is
switching back and forth looking various
branches if you want to see if your
employees are actually you know looking
between different berries maybe you can
look at their head ref log and see you
didn't look at anyone else's branch
today you're lying to me because it
would be in their local ref log and so
if you look at the ref log you'll see
there's a pointer there's a pointer to
refs original refs heads master there's
a pointer to this old commit this d-21 a
nine to six
and there's there's the data that it's
actually there UNIX timestamp you can
you can do this in text or you can
actually just use the date raw and it
will actually give you the full UNIX
timestamp just like it just like it's in
the get commit this is the important
thing to remember get garbage collect is
very friendly it's not going to delete
objects for you that it thinks you might
still want it's not going to delete
objects that are still in the ref log
and the ref log by default is going to
store things for three months which
means if someone deletes something in
the git repository and you get a hold of
that get repository even if they've done
a filter branch even if they've cleaned
things up you still have some time
don't just delete things from the ref
log that will go badly for you we expire
the ref log we say get ref log expire
expire now all we say get GC prune now
delete all the stuff I don't care about
your expiration date prune it now hooray
you run the commands it still says seven
why does it still say seven this is the
fourth way you can fail when we look at
the ref log there's nothing we
successfully expired the ref log why are
there still seven objects when we look
at get info refs there's references to
these two different refs here master
which is our main branch and refs
original refs heads master which is d-21
a nine to six that's our old commit
right you remember that
there's nothing in get refs what are
they pointing to
get packed refs so if you run get GC
before you run your expire kit will
happily pack everything and it will also
pack your reps into pack reps it
generates the single pack rafts file
because it's easier to transmit over the
network get rough log according to my
testing at this time doesn't expire
anything impact refs so everyone's
documentation about how to fix this
problem and about how to delete
something for your repository doesn't
work if a GC has already haven't because
the objects aren't going to get deleted
because they're still impact reps this
is easy to notice right now because I
have seven objects in my repository but
if your repository is thirteen thousand
objects long you are not going to notice
that your git GC command has the wrong
number and you are probably not going to
check inside pack refs to see if the
object is still there I would bet that
there especially since get GC gets run
periodically automatically I bet there
are a fair number of things lurking
inside of people's repos that they think
that they've successfully GC that has
been caught by this because if you just
run these commands out of order of pack
graphs gets run automatically you're
never going to see this so now we have
to go in and we have to delete this ref
manually so we do get update ref - D
this will delete the ref for us and now
we do a prune now aggressive it's gone
it's finally gone finally successfully
removed an object from our git
repository and we only had to fail to do
it four different times that's four
different ways any person can trip up
and not delete something so if you get a
hold of the git repository when you're
doing some kind of pen test or site
evaluation or breaking into some naughty
actor remember that just because it's
not there doesn't mean it's not there
but I said at the start of this talk
that I was going to tell you five ways
to lose things in a git repo and these
are the four ways you can lose things in
to get repo normally and you say to me
surely this is all the ways we can fail
to delete something you'd get and I say
to you my sweet summer child have I told
you about getting notes who here knows
about getting notes
yeah it's widely used isn't it get notes
is a fantastic feature that get hats to
allow you to add text to get commits
without altering the commit hash this is
a fantastic feature they added because
you might legitimately want to go back
in time and add notes to a commit that
you've already made and certainly get
repository import of fact
Gerrit to get review software actually
stores or may have at some point stores
code reviews this way they pen notes to
commit most other repo management
software that I've seen doesn't show
these if you put in get notes github
used to show them but doesn't anymore
get lab doesn't show them they're
effectively invisible one of the reasons
they're invisible is because they're not
in a branch and they're not part of the
commit they have their own space and
they have their own references they're
stored in refs notes by default refs
notes commits and you can push them you
know I can go back I can make this note
I can add some classic PII some classic
creds right there I can have them added
and I can push those notes to my
upstream right
and then I look in my log for that
branch that I'm on the notes branch and
there they are I can see that get added
notes which is a commit that's
interesting notes or commits okay so how
are notes stored well if I check out
notes commits there's a file with the
name of a git commit and the contents of
that file is the note so the notes
commits branch quote-unquote it's not
referenced as a branch but it functions
as a branch just contains a series of
files with names that are commit hash
it's and when get wants to present notes
to you it just looks in notes commits
and says oh this commit has a note so I
will display it when I display get lock
well that's interesting that has some
interesting ramifications it brings us
to wave five the dangling note so
we're gonna create a new branch get
checkout - be dangling no we're gonna
switch to that new branch we're going to
create a text file and commit it just
very basic right and then we're gonna
add a note very simple make a branch
make a commit add a note I'm gonna
delete the branch we're gonna totally
delete the branch the right way the
first time so we delete the branch you
know create something that looks kind of
like this right we have our master
branch has two commits spray our first
commit where we add the files like
whoever deleted it you have the dangling
note branch dang we note branch has a
commit that commits has a parent that is
that our second commit on master but
it's deleted that's why it's great at
and then we have our notes commits
branch right which has the most recent
commit is pointed has files in it one of
them pointed at the most recent commit
and one of them pointed at the first
minute right now when I ask get notes to
show me the note for that file it says
the kitchen no that's not a valid
reference but if I check out notes
commits it's still there the finals
still there it doesn't get removed even
though I've removed the branch file
still there the notes still there get
notes as far as I can tell is completely
independent from all of the gigs basic
GC ref log dangling object handling
infrastructure none of it points to it
in any way
and remember you can push them you can
push notes attached to deleted branches
and if you never clean up your notes you
can always clone them pull down the
notes - deleted branches and read their
contents no matter how long ago the
entire branches expired or been deleted
there is a get notes prune command right
you can delete get notes the way it does
that as it just looks at all the notes
and then it looks the hashes and then it
goes through commits and sees if there
are matching hashes and if they're on it
deletes the note and that generates a
new command but the way that get notes
stores data is completely different from
the way the rest of git stores data it
actually stores these separate files in
there so none of the existing
infrastructure for tracking things works
so that is the fifth way that I know of
that you can fail to delete something
from get look like let's reflect on this
for a moment get notes realistically
isn't that big a deal as you already
discuss there's one person in here who
raised their hand like nobody uses
getting notes I'm not too worried about
the credentials that have been stored in
there I'm much more worried about the
credentials that have been stored in
Dropbox but the rest of the ways are
probably pretty illegitimate it's
probably very likely that people are
going to delete things using a set of
commands and not necessarily go and
manually unpack their objects and verify
expressly that the objects that they
think are deleted are purged from their
repository so if you run across a git
repo in the wild what you do right first
thing take it
unpack all the pack files and it's
fairly trivially to go through
everything and see Lib deflate every
object in search for credentials through
its Zeeland deflate is a very fast
algorithm you can uncompress every
single object in the repo
matter of seconds there are tools that
do this and I don't want to talk about
them not because they aren't good there
general step up from what exists but the
whole reason for giving this talk is for
hopefully people who may not be familiar
with getting Turtles to walk into those
tools with ID while eyes wide open about
the nature of the different objects what
it is these tools should be looking for
and how to validate whether or not
they're actually finding what they're
looking for there's a talk earlier on
today about validating the performance
of your security posture and so when we
get these get scanning tools we need to
take a good hard look about whether or
not they're actually picking things out
of our git repositories when they're
left there in the various myriad ways
that they can be left there so thanks
all for your time I'm Jason risky or
Ezio I work DEFCON 562 down in Long
Beach and if you're in the LA South Bay
good love to have you come out and visit
we'd love to tell you it's up and if
you're not from the La Salle thing or
just driving through town we'd love to
see you to come down have some talks do
some hacks maybe go out for alcoholic or
non-alcoholic beverages as is your
choice no pressure but thanks for
watching and if anyone has any questions
I've tried to leave some time for those
and the next person any takers
any takers 3 - oh ok what
what's up
so I can't give you recommendations on
how to not commit them I can give you
recommendations on how not to push them
right so so the first one's actually
really hard there's not any real there
are local pre-commit hooks there were
there ways to do local pre-commit hooks
but that's actually kind of a hard
problem and it's really not it's hard to
manage because if you're trying to
manage that across an infrastructure of
staff you're dealing with the problem of
I have to make sure that no one's
tampered with their local configuration
on something that's specifically
designed to be owned by that user right
so the right place to control it if
you're talking about enterprise space is
control at the repository with a code
management system that actually supports
investigating you're pushed commits for
various kinds of information fabricator
does this really well get lab does this
fairly well but but the way to do it is
is to look at your you know to look at
your post commit hooks there to look at
your code review tools like I think
there's a lot of problems that what so
called github flow ameliorates if you're
forcing everyone to do their work on
their own Fork because your repo
management tool supports that and then
they have to pull request all of their
code in the master the worst thing that
can happen is that they have to delete
their Fork and then they can just
reclone and start doing work and you
never have to delete all of master
because you had someone reviewing all of
their commits that's that the human
involved way but but automated code
review tools can definitely help here
but they can't do everything right
because you set up a rule to block SSH
private keys and then someone commits
their Google Cloud JSON credential file
and you're like oh well that's great
that's easy to change we don't have any
automation that uses that that's going
to fall over when we rotate that key
so so yeah recommend a good hygiene with
regards to how people get code into your
repos is good but that's on the
enterprise space
that doesn't address the question of
what do we do for the seventy seven
thousand eight hundred and sixty one
deleted private keys on github those are
personal repos or community repos I
don't I don't have a good answer to that
like github has included tools to try
and warn people about this but AWS is
also included tools to try and warn
people about public s3 buckets and
that's doing lots of good so I mean that
every time I go into a client I see the
big yellow box every time I pop open
their AWS infrastructure so it doesn't
seem to be helping either that or they
just never open their AWS console ever
which is probably more likely this is
not alcoholic enough for that part of
the conversation
yeah yeah
yeah yeah baby would they would do that
so yeah good good hygiene is important
and I will honestly say like I think I I
think I echo a number of security
professionals when I say there's nothing
that is a replacement for good practices
no level of automation will replace good
isolation and no level of no level of
tooling roller place you know a culture
of attentiveness over speed because most
of these things happen because people
don't have the time to do the other way
like I people make accidents happen
right and sometimes that has to be fixed
but the number of actual accidents of
people committing their private Keys
versus the number of I need to put this
private key in the codebase because it
needs to go out there with the software
because I don't have a password vaulting
system and then six months later we need
to get private keys out of the repo that
seems to be far more common like the far
more realistic solution these
organizations don't have an
infrastructure in place to support good
credential management and then they
realize they have a problem and then
once retroactively we fixed that problem
and they go on the internet and they try
and fix their problem and then they
still have at least for 90 days
all of those credentials in their
repository and they're wondering how did
someone get them while they were still
in your repo unless you're still there
so that's my best answer that anything
else from anybody anything I explained
poorly yeah
no they exist but I'm not going to
recommend any what she asked if there if
I could recommend any tools just that
would scan github for
right so I think there there are two
points to that one of them is there are
tools and my experience has been that
they are good at there are some tools
that are fairly good at manipulating the
github API and there are some tools that
are fairly good at pulling down repos
and scanning them at the surface level
most of them do not deal with every
single way they don't deal frankly most
of them don't unpack all of the objects
maybe some of them are going to go
through and look at various dips of the
objects but most of them aren't going to
check out every version of every foe
there are a couple tools that do but for
enterprise purposes I don't use public
github like that's that's honestly the
best answer is don't do it it is not I
understand that core driver is we
shouldn't do things that aren't our core
business but there are a lot of
companies that are more than happy to
take on that problem for you that are
not github.com and and you know I I
really think that's the best solution
for keeping your credentials on
github.com is to not put them there not
to depend on on their ACL layer or their
security team right they can't be
responsible for all of that
there are definitely are definitely
well-known tools I I'm hesitant hesitant
to talk about other people's tools
generally unless I'm really confident
that they do what they do very well or
really confident that they don't do what
they do very poorly through sheer
negligence that middle ground is
somewhere I like to keep out of and so I
I'm I'm going to say there they
definitely exist and they will do a
fairly good job but but look at them
audit your security tools
Ravine thanks for calling me by name
good doctor is it your most recent
commit if your most recent commit you
can just delete the most recent commit
you can do it get reset hard delete the
objects you know and and you'll be fine
if it's further back you're gonna have
to have recourse to filter branch
because you're gonna have to rewrite the
history of more because your most recent
commit is only going to have a reference
pointing to it and it's pointing to its
parent but nothing else is pointing to
it but if you're further back you're
gonna have to use filter branch because
all of the other commits down the change
has to be rewritten to point to the new
things so you're lucky if you just did
it because you're gonna be able to
change that commit between the old
objects and move forward but yeah it's
basically a three step process first
step replaced the commit second step you
know second step is to to expire the
reference and get you see and then check
to make sure that you did it right
because you have the commit hash you've
had it there right there in front of you
all along and now you know how to look
you just look and get objects see if
that hash is still there or you you know
pop out the pack file or you just just
use git checkout just check out the
commit directly if you can check it out
and you end up in detached head it's
still there
if it says it's not there then then
there's no git commit so perfect timing
this is what I'm supposed to end
what plastic is fine okay thank you
everyone appreciate it
[Applause]