get it out of your system because I'm
gonna need you to shut up for the next
hour so yes you are so I know not all of
you are here for this some of you are
but we have an info set career panel
this is the panel to tell you all about
themselves in a second for the rest of
you I need you to be quiet or go
somewhere else just for an hour then you
can come back and yell at me it's not
fair
alright if you want to ask a question
this is the panel question asking spot
so line up and after they're done
introducing themselves you can ask them
anything you want InfoSec related yeah
okay thanks David Graham well welcome to
the InfoSec career panel the goal today
is to provide some advice for you
aspiring hackers security enthusiasts
that are looking to get started and
advance your careers in the industry so
to do that we've assembled a group of
experienced professionals yeah
to share their thoughts and experiences
on how they got here and what you two
can do to succeed in this business so on
my right let me introduce a panelists
we've got Jeffrey jantuah
from exuberance group he's a former US
DoD civilian with 12 years in the field
experience next we've got Mathieu Stitz
security architect with Adobe 20 years
experience we've got Sam Brown teaching
at the City College in San Francisco
computer networking and security since
2000 he's been a speaker at many cons
and training sessions then of course
there's Jack Baker pentester
extraordinaire bug bounty hacker reverse
engineer and finder of OU days and last
but not least patrick albert director of
security engineering AppDynamics
experience guy and DevOps and security
yeah
and I'm mark Lippert I've been a
director security done executive
positions in the industry and currently
involved in computer forensics
investigations so so where do we start
well there's no real true path to
getting into this industry people come
at it from all different disciplines
everything from technical computer
science philosophy history could be any
but what they all share is a deep
interest in how the technology works and
that's the thing you need to know you
need to know exactly what you're
protecting and the reasons things are
insecure so to that end a lot of people
start out with getting into general IT
positions and they kind of work their
way through then they learn what the
basics are and they try to create a path
from that so that's a good start we're
going to talk about that a little bit
and what you want to be doing if you're
really looking towards a career in this
industry is thinking like five 10 years
out kind of decide for yourself what
areas you're interested in and that will
help you forge a path and pick the right
jobs to take you on that way so to start
out the first question for anybody can
answer this year what suggestions can
you offer for starter jobs they're good
for moving towards an InfoSec job and
and maybe why I think so I've seen a
couple of folks a couple different
career paths people traverse on some
into kind of at least from pen testing
which is what I do on a day-to-day basis
they come from kind of tend to come from
three areas one is one is such an
administration right so folks come from
system administration side they know how
the system's worked and are built that's
like Network admin - so Cisco side that
kind of thing but I also see folks come
from software dev right so that's like
you know your traditional developers and
those kind of things and then folks who
are doing maybe more low-level stuff in
the in the embedded universe so that's
what I've seen I don't know about you
guys but those are the three kind of
areas I see comic folks come into
pentesting which is a kind of a
specialized discipline it's very so
broadly it's fundamentally like do you
ask questions what do you observe what
do you report back like just having that
fundamental mindset maybe not even
initially as a start I mean there's
there's so many amazing people InfoSec
that started in like the Social Sciences
or something of that nature but in terms
of where to start with an initial role I
mean you can't you can't beat a sock in
my mind like just see it all or even
working in a consultancy and maybe not
even the technical role initially in
transitioning into that and just seeing
a lot of companies and how they approach
security like from a fundamental
philosophical perspective I think
there's huge value in that like
initially not even assessing the
technology but just assessing how people
view technology do you think it's a
business problem I think I see a lot of
lately a lot of folks talk about
technical but from doing consulting and
doing a lot of work it is really a yeah
it's a business it's fundamentally it's
it's that operational debt it's the
technical debt it's understanding the
risk of the businesses faced with how
it's being communicated how it's being
understood I think we're supposed to
encourage them that is encouragement I
promise that yeah sincerely that is
encouragement but in terms of where to
start with initial if you get back to
the question sorry for a slight
digression there if you're if you're
gonna start I I would really sincerely
have I would say started to saw starting
a consultancy I think those two agree in
any level will get you so much exposure
like a year in a consultancy is five
years at a corporation in my mind well I
have something very different to say but
I have to warn you that I don't know
anything see these guys are actually
professionals in the field but I know
what happens to my students and none of
them can make a five year plan or a ten
year plan because it changes so fast and
they don't have the luxury of choosing
where to go they take what they can get
and five years ago they couldn't get in
security they would have to do something
else like network operations for a few
years before they trust you to move you
up but in the last two or three years
many of them are starting right out in
security and companies have told us they
would though hire you if you've done the
embedded device CTF or if you pat the OS
CP or any kind of reasonable evidence
that you know something they'll hire you
they just want you to I don't so I don't
tell them this kind of advice I just say
make sure you love what you're doing and
learn something well and if you impress
people there's room for you because this
is a
very chaotic field and I think there are
no rules really you just have to be
great at something anyway no I I concur
on the host CPU I think it's a it's a
sum of those are really valuable in
terms of demonstrating that you actually
know something doesn't guarantee it but
it's helpful to as a as a initial filter
exactly certificate in general or
watermarks they're not necessarily a
gauge of your talent or your skill but
it's something that we accept you know
now even I'll even give this yeah SSP a
shout out here I mean I will I will grow
like everyone's go oscy P because it's
hardcore and it's long and deep but CSS
peas and inch deep and a mile wide I'll
give you something for persistence right
because it's like this is not an easy
gig right you're gonna have to be
persistent so if you've got the kind of
persistence to go work through some of
that stuff on your own I'll give you a
lot of credit even if it doesn't really
mean you know a ton of stuff it's just
you work really hard to do it and I'll
give you there I give you credit for
that and the Sam Jeff Patrick's point to
even even just participating an open
source project and getting that exposure
putting that on a resume
is a fast track for most HR departments
that's definitely something to consider
so so those are a lot of great ideas
let's say what what would you describe
as maybe some of the ideal
characteristics of a cybersecurity
candidate somebody coming in looking for
a job what types of things would you be
looking to see from them transparency
I'll tell you what they don't know 100
percent say I don't know if you don't
know please don't lie to me good guy I'm
interviewing someone and they actually
say I don't know what that is I'm so
happy things so I spend a good portion
of every week of my life either
screening or on-site people trying to
place them either in my order my company
but the things that I care about are not
necessarily your technical proficiencies
or how you can answer the questions but
how much you care about them and how
hungry you are to actually figure it out
so if I see you at
a problem in front of me even if you hit
a wall ten times if you persist that's
when I start caring that's when things
feel better for me because we can't
where we sit now as an industry I mean
how many open jobs do we have with how
many qualified candidates we can't sit
around and wait for that person with 20
years of experience Lana or lap
eventually it does yeah there's layer
build and grow and every technology
change the technology changes so often
you can't be an expert in absolutely
everything there's no way to get that
perfect PhD candidate who knows the
technology all the sudden it's just
never gonna happen so you gotta make a
gratitude yeah you look you're scouting
for aptitude but it's not yeah it's not
always about who can answer the security
questions it's about who cares the most
I would also say in a consultancy which
is something you know that is really
important is that is the people skills
people forget this so you're gonna have
to communicate you're gonna have to
commute very but communicating very bad
news to very important people all the
time all the time every day
exactly respectfully like this is why
this has happened this is bad
we know it's bad can we not do this
anymore I need your help right I need
your help nothing exactly help me help
you yeah so you got to be able to
communicate those soft skills it's
tremendously valuable I think that's
actually one thing most candidates miss
completely for me especially when they
attack things from a technical
perspective is actually being able to
sit down and discuss or converse a
period soft skills immensely yeah you
know I got to agree with you there
that's the one thing that often seems to
be overlooked when we focus on the
technical aspects and I can write
perfect code and do all this crazy stuff
the communications is really a key thing
and in this job in any job actually
because if you can't communicate your
ideas or the situation you're not gonna
get very far nobody will know how smart
and brilliant you are and you know from
a career standpoint as you move up the
ladder so to speak and take on positions
with more responsibility and/or
management communications is really
vital to being able to convey what
you're what you're doing what your team
is doing and why so I think that's
really a big thing that sometimes
overlooked
it the team-player aspect I have seen
people hired because not necessarily
that they were the uber greatest but
that they were a better team player they
people wanted to work with them rather
than the other person because you can
always level up your skills but if
you're a total dick it's not gonna play
out yeah you can't fix a personality
don't be a dick personalities it's
really tough and also you know you want
to look for somebody that has
problem-solving skills because you're
gonna get thrown at things that you
don't know and you've got to really be
able to to dig into those things figure
stuff out put the pieces together and
come up with solutions so I think
problem-solving skills any anyone that
can demonstrate that in the different
ways that that might be done is going to
be a plus in an interview situation
absolutely outside of the the soft
skills what I think are super important
I would say that a interest and desire
to understand how computers
fundamentally work and how the code
works how the systems work and the you
may not know it but being able to
understand the technical information
presented to you is very very valuable
because you're gonna have to go slog
through Doc's you're gonna have to go
look at source code you're gonna have to
potentially go work with tools that are
very low level kind of diagnostic tools
to go figure out how does this actually
do the thing it's supposed to do and
does it does it do the thing I expect it
to do or does it do the thing the
developer expects it to do does it
function the way it's intended and and
that is not an easy thing to do and you
need to be prepared to kind of self
teach to some degree in those technical
skills but I would say software any
software development skills you have are
very valuable any because they translate
language to language any system
administration skills you have that are
very valuable any any kind of
infrastructure building experience in
big infrastructure projects so that's
like you know you work in an ISP you
know how routing works you know what you
know you know what signaling is you know
how that stuff works you've done
computer forensics you know what bits
are on the file system
how file systems are constructed those
are very valuable in a genuine technical
situation because it means you can
problem solve and work out something new
well there's something I heard go by
here but I want to say it more
explicitly the the most important thing
is that you really love technology you
can't be just trying to make a paycheck
and do the minimum or you'll never make
it because you have it I hope that's why
everybody's here because you're a
hobbyist there is something you love
that you really want to build or
understand or change because you can't
get paid enough to do this you have to
spend your whole life digging through
things and they have to be really
interesting to you I have a few students
who clearly don't really want to do this
they're hoping to make money and they're
never gonna make it because I mean I
remember every when I develop my first
set of Linux classes it really took me
36 hours to make every one of those work
because I didn't know any of it I had to
dig and dig and go down blind alleys if
that's something you're forcing yourself
to do it's never going to work you have
to really love the technology some part
of it there got to be some part of it
that is yours that you really understand
because you care and if you don't have
that please go work in something else
good you're never gonna make it if
you're just like trying to put check the
boxes you know I think the inverse of
that is just you have to hate yourself
enough to maybe that's what Sam saying
yeah I think what I think what Sam
saying is you have a career in internal
audit yeah you know Oh a line that I
outlined that I often have uses said
it's it's not really a career it's a
lifestyle it's not a job it's a
lifestyle it's more like art you have to
have a passion and leverage if you don't
then you'll never be happy and you'll
never be good at it because it's not a
nine-to-five job it requires more than
that and worst of all you'll make
everyone around you possibly very
miserable something to consider they
likely to do that anyway so let me ask
I'm just out of college I'm starving I'm
putting my resume together what resume
looks like hey you actually enjoy what
you're doing like what are you looking
for right yeah yeah my question is
actually the next question that's a
great question though I mean for me at
least when I get a resume especially for
someone just out of college I want to
see what projects they're working on I
want to see what other skill sets they
have what their interests are that
they're
rounded that that to me is way more
interesting especially like if it's hey
that's great you had a 3.8 or a 4.0 at
MIT that's cool
that's wonderful that you can talk to me
for two hours about compiler theory but
what projects did you work on what else
did you damage demonstrate your
capabilities yeah that's what I want to
see demonstrate you capability show me
show me you can do something and I will
definitely want to talk to you show me
the money
yes show me show me you can do something
cool right and maybe it's not pakery
right maybe it's not you don't have a
bunch of CVS or O'Day's that's cool but
if you have a bunch of debt projects or
you modded a badge here at whatever
that's cool I want to see any any
applied knowledge any applied knowledge
show me you didn't read a book and
regurgitated the answers show me you did
something different and something that
you've seen through to the end your
completion is comparing a lot of starter
projects that are 90% complete something
that you've gone a hundred percent a and
I okay so we touched on this question a
little bit earlier briefly but I want to
ask it formally
how important are certifications and are
there any particular certs that that you
recommend for whatever the heart of the
cert the more interesting it is but in
general certs are kind of 50/50 for me
yep usually if you've got certs listed
it's a talk to you yeah maybe it's a
maybe right I will say this they
completely agree with what everyone's
saying here the one value of a cert is
it gets you past that first hurdle with
an HR where yeah it might get you past
the resume filter which is valuable but
it doesn't necessarily guarantee you're
going to get a position right it's like
just cuz you gotta see is SPE or you've
got your OS CP or you've gotten your
OSCE or whatever I asked that's cool but
I don't know if I would say I would hire
anyone based upon anything other than my
personal practical examination I do we
when we hire we do a practical pen test
like hey here's you have you have 24
hours go hack some stuff show us what
you did right show us how you did it
that's what we asked you to do you say
you're a pen tester show me prove it now
speaking as someone who had no real
background or education or
really who wanted to get into pen
testing I spent about all the money I
had to get the osep and I think that's
the only reason that I now have a job
doing pen testing so if there's anyone
else in that situation that would
probably be my recommendation I think it
is valuable like I said to get you past
the HR hurdle but you still have to
apply that knowledge on the job and show
me you can do it there's two different
aspects here so we have a hacker who
wants to do things better and wants to
learn more so he goes in to get the
certificate that's a great way to go and
learn so we appreciate that as hiring
managers but there's also the other side
of this coin which is their certificate
factory's offshore that print people
certs and they have 20 of them and that
lands more often than not somebody with
OCP who just came up from nothing yeah I
mean you can see the progression I think
a lot of times you can see somebody
who's done it on their own versus
somebody who is kind of man you just
kind of trying to check the boxes it is
it's it's kind of transparent the resume
typically you can kind of see how people
do it right if it's like I did if I
worked in business logic business
management or something and then I
decided I want to be a hacker Hey and
then I went and did a bunch like
security Plus and network plus all this
other stuff that's cool I'm glad you're
going and doing the effort but the
question I have is how deeper your
technical skills and that's why I want
to see you do something more difficult
potentially like the OS DP if I saw
somebody go from business management and
go take the osep and pass it in a year
like this person is pretty serious about
what they're doing right actually I want
to ask you guys what certs do you think
are valuable because we want to say that
they're not valuable no define that well
yeah I guess that's what I'm asking what
are you looking for in a certain I mean
there's the become and ones we all know
of liase PSPs ch whatever CH security
plush what do you think that stuff I I
will tell you the only I think off sex
stuff is okay right it doesn't guarantee
any knowledge I've seen folks passed the
osep and I'm question how they did it
because I mean I don't know how that
happened but I would say that's anything
that where you don't do a practical
examination I've really no interest in
right like if you don't do a project or
do something real in real life and
demonstrate the capability in real life
if you're regurgitating answers if it's
checked the Box a Lancer ABC or film
like multiple choice not interested real
quick since we're using the term a lot
if you don't know what the OS CP is it's
the offensive security certified
professional yeah it's a it's a
practical exam the exam takes three days
or thirty six hours and you have to hack
into six boxes it's 24 hours five
systems yeah 24 hours five systems you
have 24 hours to write a report okay so
let me ask this question then so you're
new you're trying to get in the thing
you don't have a security consulting job
you're not working in a sock you know
maybe you're a database administrator or
whatever but you want to get into
security so what other sorts of training
or things can you do self self training
that would be helpful and move you in
that direction
for a pentester there's lots of
vulnerable stuff on the internet right
so there's like voom hub there's a bunch
of other junk out that that's free it
sucks to work with because it's really
clunky but it is free right if you have
an internet connection and a desire to
go learn this man if you search for
hacking tutorial on Google I bet you
will have a lot of hits right there's a
lot of stuff but there's a million books
if you hit Amazon not all of them are
gonna be good not all them are gonna be
valuable but come here do CTFs do that
kind of stuff you'll get good I
guarantee you if you do you did CTF 365
every weekend right
you'd be pretty damn good at doing some
reverse engineering and code writing
code and stuff at the end of the year I
guarantee if there's no way you just
work on it every day you're gonna be
good anything you practice every day
you'll be good all right I want to
contradict all of that DUI that's
awesome of cause this is what I do all
the vulnerable stuff on the internet
none of it is training material it's all
just final exams you give you a
vulnerable scene they say they're hack
into what you say but but I don't know
what to do they say well you should know
what to do and any well what good is
that there's only a few that actually
guides you through I found a place
called pen tester lab that's like 30
bucks a month that's pretty good there's
Vivek Ramachandran sting security what
is it security tube and pen test or
something or other
pentester academy or something where you
pay a fee and they guide you through and
there's picot CTF from Carnegie Mellon
which is very good for beginners because
there's a lot of challenges and it's
about a year old so there's a bunch of
blogs they'll show you how to get
through but a beginner needs
instructions and for some reason almost
all the training material on the web
forgets to give you any instructions so
it's really not helpful but once you get
going then you can start doing the CTF
stuff but but really you need some
training not just exams I don't know
there's a I mean like if you go on I
mean I don't want to like bicker about
it but I'm just saying that I think that
like if I have looked it's there's so
much material out there I think the
problem is not so much that there's no
material is that there's so much garbage
there's too much it's almost impossible
to figure out what's quality and what's
not well I this is just what I do
I figure stuff out in right classes and
what I've found is the books and the
training videos and the blogs are very
little use none of them actually work
they worked on that person system five
years ago with old versions of
everything if you do the six the half of
the steps they don't tell you about that
they assume you already know but if you
actually try to get from zero to where
they got by following their steps it
usually is very difficult so in in the
long run that's what you want if you
were an expert you could work from out
of date material for the wrong operating
system and figure it out but when you're
a beginner you really need something
that doesn't present you with too many
baffling frustrating hurdles on the way
up and you pretty much have to have real
training materials for that and there
are some but you know the vulnerable
machines are not that anyway how about
how about some tools that you can play
with may be things like Kali Linux or
something that people can get for free
and can get started using something just
in my mind just fundamentally coming to
an event like this and bring your laptop
and having Kali or parrot on it and just
having conversations and people hey what
can I do with this tool what have you
seen with this what else can i
accomplish with this oh how do I use TCP
replay in this scenario and having those
kinds of conversations and just building
from there I think that's that's a huge
part of it just getting the tools and
playing with them and written
this is gonna sound funny but RTFM like
it really does go a long ways I don't
like who knows what that means
[Laughter]
yeah I think a lot of the CTX have
write-ups and some of the stuff and you
will find a ton of people who are
willing to be helpful especially at cons
like this be like hey how do how did you
solve that dude right how did you figure
that out and I'll show you this thing
that thing and you can get some actual
help there I think part of it is
building your network of technical
people you can lean on right and coming
to events like this is really valuable
especially smaller cons I will say
shoutouts to like torque on and layer
one and all these other like kind of
smaller stuff if you get a like a big
con like blackhat do nobody gives a
about you they unless you have a budget
no one's interested here you're actually
gonna meet people know people these
people are in the local area you know I
mean you can go you can go hang out with
these dudes on the weekends but talk to
people here and be like hey dude I was
working on this problem you you want to
help me out I do not know how to solve
this half of it is leveraging your
network you know at cons like this
you're more likely to have a chance to
really relate and talk to somebody and
then kind it's almost like an important
informal interview and you might get
might get farther with love no space
loves so just to touch on what they're
saying I think I wouldn't have a job or
a career if it wasn't for a couple
people in this room and probably this
conference at Def Con like period so
that's what's up like no network no
friends no learning experiences I didn't
get college I didn't have a lot of fun
when did military crap and then came
back and try to figure it out which is
having a strong network and actually
people who think like you and want to
help you build champions and make
friends I mean I think everybody on this
I would argue that everybody on this
panel probably came non-traditionally
into their career right you did not
follow the prescribed career path and
we're sensitive to that right I don't
care if you don't have a degree I don't
care about any of that stuff I'm gonna
try to work for you make it work if
you're good and squared away and want to
do the job
i'ma try to do what I can to help you
right so I think everybody in this on
this panel would probably say the same
thing I don't know if you anybody would
disagree with that
yeah I still don't know how I got here
I just want to mention Sheldon a wire
here about the connections people make I
had a student that went to a con and
volunteered to help and all he did was
get drunk and hand out t-shirts and I
gave him extra credit for that because
that's important for friends you make
are very valuable anyway extra points
extra point for layer 1 hey so you know
there are some paid training things out
there that are fairly decent I want to
mention I don't know if it's con first I
want a bitchin sans sans does some good
I know they do some good forensics and
some other charges too much money well
they're extremely Expedia if you got
that they are expensive but it's either
that if you can get your job cut the
training it later want to upgrade your
skills though you know that's worthwhile
doing you should definitely come to
training at layer one we did it Friday
[Laughter]
okay next well hey let's open it up to
some questions from the audience has
anybody got any questions to stumped the
panel go ahead take the microphone there
Sarah going back to the concept of soft
skills working with other people there's
a big difference between software QA
working with developers and working with
outside clients and I'd like to get a
little bit more feedback for that
because in the past I'm mainly an
engineer worked with other engineers and
sometimes you know when I did a stint in
software QA going over and talking to
the developers was one way of getting
things across some of the developers
were easy to work with other guys I
would never call him on the phone
because there was no way for
communicating with him on the phone and
without sitting there out there down
there and their cubicle so I'd like a
little bit more about the soft skills
working with outside clients because pen
testing is mainly going to be with
somebody else outside not working with
somebody in your organization that you
have a chance to know I mean I would say
if you can communicate bad news to
someone that's what you're gonna do
you're so your constant salesman yeah
you're you so if you're selling
imagine your
you got a sandwich and you want
this got to take a bite and then tell
you how great it tastes afterwards
that's the job you've got to basically
do you've got to get that down and be
like hey look I know it sucks right now
but we're gonna work this out right so
that's the soft skills I'm talking about
and it's not necessarily just it's not
like a sales gig but I would say that
the ability to communicate bad news in a
non-confrontational non-emotional manner
and get to the solution because the
objective is a business solution right
the answer that the bottom line is we
are here to help our clients and
sometimes that means communicating bad
news and sometimes it means helping them
understand what the problem is in a way
that gets them to the answer if you tell
them the bad news and they go screw you
I don't want to hear from you you have
screwed them over you have done that
disservice to your client because they
cannot get it fixed cuz they're gonna
ignore your advice right so I would say
the soft skills you need are to talk to
people and tell them bad news in a very
non-confrontational manner in a very
soft way if you're talking specifically
about internal communications
essentially it sounds like I want to
walk downstairs to talk to Bob and Bob I
need your help
yeah and Bob's like I really don't have
time for you right now like there's
there's it's actually a different set of
skills right so it's making sure that
you can build those relationships and
kind of what I do and I'm kind of a jerk
about it those I put money in the bank
with my teams and my developers and I
make sure that we're always doing each
other favors so if you have a chance to
build relationships like that I
encourage it yeah be nice to the people
on your way up the ladder because
they're the same ones you'll meet on the
way back down I don't think I think if
anything it's the network you build as
in your career that helps you get that
done right so I think communicating to
the technical people is sometimes a lot
easier than computing to communicating
to leadership because you're commuting
you can communicate fast you talk to an
engineer you'd be like you know waters
wet electricity hurts when you touch it
you know these are not confrontational
discussions right you guys have a bad
product and your your bonuses on the
line is not a fun conversation to have
with a CTO right you know so I think
it's a different discussion sometimes
yeah I mean when you're dealing with
like a scenario like you've described
where you're working in QA and you're
going back and reporting a bug just some
those can sometimes be major fundamental
conversations that go back to
architectures that could be like a
decade old hey why is but I have a
deserialized object here
well our foundational texts act etc etc
it's not your fault it's yeah it's not
your fault right but but we need someone
that we need to work on how to fix it
and it might take three years so okay
we're going to triage this we're going
to document it we're gonna acknowledge
it and we're gonna do what we can to add
additional processes for integration
testing what-have-you and yeah exactly
and that's the thing like you don't come
with like a critical even if it's
critically say this is critical we
understand it's critical we also
understand this is gonna take four
engineers five quarters to resolve if
you phrase it if you if you frame it as
though I need your help you can be the
hero that's a much better conversation
to have than it is like you guys screwed
up you need to fix this and they'll
thank you for it they'll really say
thank you that's not a yeah if you can
do things in if you can present your
ideas in a non Advan serial method that
makes it a lot more acceptable and you
want to get other people to buy in on
your ideas when we were doing large
projects you never want to be the only
guy waving the flag you want to get you
and your buddies and the other people
and say that we all feel this way okay
or when you go to somebody with a
problem situation ask them well how do
you feel about that what do you think
about that rather than telling them what
they should be thinking you can get
around to that eventually but you can
elicit that pathway by starting with
getting their take on the situation
seeing how they view things that way
you're less likely to get into a
conflict and you can more likely get
through on the path of least resistance
well how much you finish in a minute I
think it's actually complement what
you're saying what we are as advisors we
are not dictators or your job role
bringers we're there to help absolutely
I am a consultant right that is you pay
me for my opinion right I don't tell you
what to do I'm here to help right and
you're there to advise if there's this
client decides that the customer decides
I'm not gonna do that
I don't care that's okay that's fine
it's not a big deal right that's their
decision your job is to inform make your
recommendation do the thing
and if they decide they don't want to do
it you can't stop them right that's okay
so you know everybody knows about the
seven-layer Network model right yeah I
know that
well good burrito yeah it's it's it's a
big burrito right well actually actually
that's a little short-sighted because
there's actually nine layers the other
two our management and politics so you
always have to keep that in play
politics seems like an ugly word but you
can learn to make it work for you and it
can be very powerful in your career so
be patient use the tactics and the
techniques of good communications
listening well to other people asking
them for their thoughts and ideas get as
much information as possible before you
open your mouth and say but and now this
is what I think and it'll be taken a lot
clearer I just want to say something
explicit which is perhaps was not
obvious to me um you have to deal with
an attitude problem technical people
think they're smart and they think other
people are dumb for not knowing
technical things and you have to realize
that you have an emotional problem and
fix it it's like a disease and until you
can for you and begin by trying to
pretend to be nice and that's better
than nothing but people will still sense
that you hold them in contempt like a
dog knows you don't like dogs you have
to really get over thinking you're
better than other people and the
fundamental issue here is they hire the
technical person because they don't know
that stuff so when you cuddle them why
are you're needy you don't even know
this stuff they say well you're an idiot
because like you shouldn't respect me to
know this stuff I hired you to figure it
out and explain it to me in terms I can
understand but at first I was the same
guy I got no wire in my job because I
kept disrespecting the boss and then one
day the boss came in and I said you know
I calculated that we lost $200,000 last
year because everyone got the flu and
they did all those ends up for a month I
mean hired a bunch of temps to do the
work and the temps did it all wrong and
we had to do it over and the next day he
brought in a nurse to give everybody flu
shots that was the one time I did my job
right I took the problem and turned it
into his language and it's not wrong
that he wanted that although I thought
it was he's just got
different job he's steering the ship the
gobbledygook about the details are not
what he wants he wants actionable
business decisions I have analyzed all
this complicated junk and you can either
do this or that and here's what I
recommend that's what he wanted and I
didn't understand that I wanna make one
quick comment on something that I wanna
get to a next question a lot of we're
talking about a strategy here but then
you wonder well how do I apply that well
a tactic that I use sometimes in dealing
with people is if you have a group of
people somebody you got to get across to
you got to get a message to but it's
like oil and water the two of you just
don't get along but you might have
another person on your team that you
have a relationship with use them as a
go-between to forward your ideas they're
seen as a friendly you'll accomplish
your objective by using those other
people and get the message out to the
people that need to have it so do that
another yeah building champions that's
it yeah anyway let's get to our next
question here sure sure
questions along the lines of Builder
versus breaker for your core team member
is there a percentage that you would
like to see 90 percent breaker a 90
percent builder 50/50 described that for
me so you have someone that comes from
software they build databases they build
networks and they also in their free
time go and rip apart servers and look
for O'Day's and code and they can go
5050 they can go 90 percent on one well
the only thing I look for is if you can
break it at least tell me how to fix it
yeah you got to be able to don't know
just walk up to me with a problem yeah
please do not walk like I mean really
we're in the solutions business we
happen to generate problem as a
byproduct but the reality is you're in
the solutions business so if you can't
deliver a solution a problem is not a
you know that's not an exciting
discussion yeah we have problems
legitimately by say 50/50 because the if
you cannot fix it I don't care if it's
broken what what are you saying you want
to go into it start there that's
actually good question I'm already in
security I come what do you want to be
when you grow up yeah fire truck what
what you know what their role are you
are you referencing to the
so either like a prime pentester
security engineer core internal security
audit team got just so like audit I
would it's not scary yeah I wasn't gonna
go there I was gonna be nice and just
say whatever but yeah yeah pen tests are
definitely 50/50 engineer probably 70/30
yeah the engineers are forward-looking
right because they bring up the crap
that every yeah literally like a solid a
solid security engineer especially like
this is gonna be a bit of a digression
you can argue with me but a lot of times
on a project they'll start with a
waterfall model for like the first three
or four quarters and do foundational
tooling and then go to agile it varies
but they're really kind of you know if
they're really good at it they're
looking at white papers for technologies
that are being released in the next 24
months and how they can adapt that and
how they can feature through fit design
and there's a lot of work that goes into
that I would say that you
hundred-percent on your right if you
don't know the how the developers work
how they have they operate you're gonna
have a really hard time convincing them
right because you've got to sell them
that this is the way we're gonna fix the
thing or get their support in it if you
come to them and say hey you need to
stand on your head for the next six
months they're gonna go nothing and you
should be doing security agile security
as much as you can absolutely wait
what's a jalisa curity guys we have
another question here sir about tools
he said Kali and something else oh
parrot what is that
parrots are just I don't even call it
competing it's a complimentary distro
it's got a lot of trying to think how to
phrase that they've got a lot of
complementary tools it's just your
choice do you want to do like Red Hat or
did sorry and pin test toolkit for the
access you know you can get a boot disk
with the tank so you can just pop it in
run and play with it right away
well one thing I would say those like
either Kali your parrot like there's
some cool tools that they no longer
package well like Dee sniffs a great
example D sniff like if you want a mess
with layer 2d stuff is amazing to see if
you're even if your layer 2 stacks is
going to break
an insecure state and become a hub or
something like that like you can flood
thousands of mac addresses a minute and
let's say like Wireless like old school
Aruba you could use D sniff and just
start slamming away on the interface and
then all of a sudden the controller
would fail and all the wireless would
drop and become a hub for about two
minutes while things were rebooting and
anyway cool yeah and so if I could give
some advice just if you want to get into
pen testing stuff like that take some
time take your laptop uninstall windows
put Linux on there force yourself to use
it for a while
no because Windows is bad you need to
know that too but you already know
Windows I know you do you have steam
Linux still has theme it's fine try it
out for a while you're gonna get a ton
out of it I would 100% agree with that
that was the advice I got I was like a
junior tech and I was like working with
this crusty old UNIX guy and he was I
was like how do I learn Unix he's like
just yeah he's like destroy your laptop
or your computer put put Linux on it and
it was beat actually FreeBSD at the time
so it was there's no Linux Linux was
terrible time so he was like put FreeBSD
on it and then that was it and I did
that for like two months and I was like
I know a lot about you so I have one
more question
umm so I'm a student right now at
Moorpark College coming for computer
networking and trying to get into
security I'm taking the summer off to do
OS CP and I go to every conference I can
afford what else could I be doing or
should I be doing to get into being a
pen tester you won't be a full-time pen
testers what you want to do yeah I how
far when you graduate
I've been going at my JC for two years
because I fit a that was a business
major okay I took a computer class loved
it
pivoted so I'm actually really new I'll
probably have my associates and the next
year and then I'll transfer to a
bachelor's program online I think I mean
competitions
yeah you should get in CCAC and see PTC
and things like that yeah I mean I would
go with like
you know there's a bunch of kind of
college targeted cyber stuff I know
Moorpark has some stuff I know some
folks out there and I do know there's a
lot of stuff local I would say I guess
what more can you do is keep doing what
you're doing right I would stay on the
path I'd look at maybe some software dev
kind of experience that's gonna be very
valuable when you do source review and
some of those type of things learn some
languages so like CTF style it's not
gonna be like pure re that's not really
the same thing but it can be very
valuable right so doing that stuff and
then I would say the other thing that's
a big need for and a desire for not a
lot of folks really good at is like
modern web exploitation stuff I'd say I
don't see very many people very good the
system stuff the that kind of
traditional stuff is more is more around
yeah more more around but there's
there's very few folks who are really
really good modern web folks bounty the
bug bounties are valuable I think if you
if you put on your resume you have but
you have a CVE
you're coming out of college it'd be
like I definitely want talk to you
alright
I definitely want to know what's going
on with you cool thank you guys thank
you yeah I was gonna say bug bounties if
for no other reason because if you get
it done then you got money for Spring
Break exactly if you get you gettin paid
to hack so what's wrong with that
right
hi just a good question I'm thinking
about going into forensics and I know
there's it can be very just burdensome
by having to document everything and I
was just wondering how likely is it that
you run into the requirements of having
the having forensics as well what do you
mean I have to document everything I
understand that a little better
well in the sense of having to just the
the order of having to document who the
procedure of who's had the laptop hard
drive whatever so chain of custody
changer custody is called right okay
that's not that burdensome I can tell
you it's so usually a form that we fill
out and identifies the item that we're
taking
and who handed it to us and serial
numbers in mom cipher man it's more of
the actual evident cherry oh yeah I wait
to research that how often do you run
into using that into Red Team Blue team
or almost almost never so red team you
hope to God as a blue team it does I
don't want students a blue team it
definitely does come up really where
there's like some legitimate need to
pull something off the network and do a
full-on investigation I'm thinking in
the sense of using the same skillset oh
oh okay like if I apply this if I were
to learn forensics how is it applicable
to using the same skillset to red or
blue absolutely sorry that reversing
that process absolutely you because
you're incredible communicator like hey
look at this somebody dropped put
dropper on this box it then downloaded
like pony you can see this child process
that's occurred okay you can see where
this executed in Excel because they
enabled macros or whatever and you can
you can have that whole chain of
communication and show a complete kill
chain with egress or what have you
that's very
yeah you know it's kind of like we're
saying what the job is the job is kind
of like it's almost we combine some
reverse engineering in some situations
but it's really very internals based
okay you got to understand the the lower
level of how they operate system and how
the applications are working because
what you're what you're doing and
looking besides just metadata what
you're really looking at is you know
what happened in what and timelines are
important okay and you know how this
occurred how it moved along and you've
got to basically document and dissect
each of those things often yeah and
certainly in my situation we're involved
in litigation and it's usually
multi-million dollar problems so when
you go into court and you're against the
other side or whatever you're doing you
know you've got a you got to be right on
on all those things and prove what
you've done and have tested this in some
situations say that yes that's the way
it happens and I know why because I
tested that in the lab and these are the
results and that's what I see happening
here stuff like so it's it's extremely
detail-oriented as opposed to you know
stop this or fix that it really breaks
things down into a great level of detail
so well you can apply those skills to
red team and blue team thing you know
it's only one way to get there you can
certainly don't need to go always into
that level of detail you know to to play
on a red team or blue team but that's
kind of what forensics is so if that's
what you're looking for you know you're
gonna study the internals how things
work and document processes and discover
what the timeline is of events so I hope
that answers your question on the
flipside out to the cells point is well
a lot of law firms now have an umbrella
part of their organization that's purely
IR so that's something to think of - I
don't know if that's something you're
interested in but that's why it's trying
to yeah like there's definitely there's
hold conferences dedicate to that but
but but literally like talk talk to some
of the larger law firms as well if
you're really if or if you have a
connection there this gentleman might be
able to have some introductions for you
that that's a huge and growing part of
of our business as a general rule of
thumb yeah some of them have their own
departments now for electronic discovery
which is you know which is you know a
simple way possibly to get into the firm
and then to roll into doing more
forensics aspects of those
investigations and responses is there
any tools that you would recommend I
know that there's Swift and ftk okay if
you're talking about forensic
investigative tools well the big names
out there that people will talk about
our end case okay for yeah yeah they're
just down the street in case is good
another tool that we use is black light
by a company called black bag they're
particularly good for Macintosh things
okay
there's ftk by access data forensics
tool kit then there's a variety of
things on like the linux like the the
kali disk that are useful we use some of
the imaging tools that they have to
capture images as well as other things
there's a couple different you know
forensics kind of goes a couple
different ways you can do forensics
that's incident response where okay who
hacked my network and can i find the
virus malware type of thing but another
aspect of forensics is in business and
civil litigation its intellectual
property theft and trade secrets and
activities that are going on
business fraud other types of things so
you know there's different types of
investigative stuff there depending on
whether it's a civil or criminal cyber
type of thing so they use similar skills
but sometimes there's a few tools that
lend themselves more to the network
response guy then you know looking at
McIntosh for something-something in
civil thank you thank you do we have
another question hello thanks for all
the advice for getting into inside info
SEC career my question is so once you're
in can I give some more advice how to
advance yourself like for 10 years
you've been in a pen tester how can you
become a city chief security officer for
example oh it's give you the politic you
want to see sweet job you better be good
at communication and politics I would
echo that I mean the soft skills become
way more valuable the higher you go up
the ladder so if you can organize a team
get stuff done convince people it's the
right thing get things accomplished
demonstrate results that's how I see
people do it I don't know people
demonstrate that level of leadership
they understand finances very well good
money
they understand risk really well right
absolutely and the risk is money in
another form though true very true yeah
but I'm dead serious about that like if
you see a CTO that's like pure tech it's
not my nature people are going to
usually take a double take so so yeah
you gotta understand you got to
understand the business not just the
technology to get to the sea level
because now you're playing at that level
now you're the communicator and the
leader of the technical people
underneath you but you're sitting there
communicating with the non-technical
types running the business making
decisions for business reasons not
because the tech was cool or they wanted
this new or no thing so how do I get
good at those skills I understand that I
need those interpersonal skills how do I
train that I can't Google that yes you
can there are books there are plenty of
books like social engineering people
talk about social engineering social
engineering is weaponized soft skills ok
so like that that's exactly what social
engineering is
have you ever gotten a who's gotten
pulled over and convinced a cop not to
give him a ticket that's soft skills
okay have you ever have you ever been in
the DMV and like they're not gonna do
the thing for you and you want them to
do it
that's soft skills right that's what
we're talking about and there's a
million books out there called like
things like emotional communication and
how to have difficult conversations a
million books out there and these are
all great things that the classics are
like you know the Carnegie stuff right
the del Kearney high fret win friends
and influence people all these there's a
million soft go look at sales books that
pretty much every sales book ever is
that you want to do but exactly what you
just brought up there was actually
something that's interesting because
typically people who want to be yes
Toastmasters hundred percent typically
people who want to be ICS stay I sees
usually or they become architects which
is a grown up I see they don't usually
jump over to so it's typically a you'll
divergent of management before you'll
become a grazie great pentester very
rarely do I see mature penned esters
jump in a management like I can list
them on this hand and to be fair this is
gonna sound weird but I like when you
start talking to executives they're like
this is hard the techno like yeah
managing up managing down like it
becomes all about people and less about
technology that's when you just start
talking bout risk the c-suite is not a
technology although it's a it's a people
for office you have to you have to this
hurts to say give up you have to give up
some of your tech you have to let other
people become better at it than you
you'll never touch and follow you yeah
you have to move you have to move to the
next level and that requires that you
need to focus on that and the only way
to do that is to leave summit you can't
right perfect code ivory night anymore
you have to let other people do that
find those people have them you know
it's great minions but you need to move
to the next level and that's the people
in the soft tech side yeah I know like
two three okay well a lot of the
experience is good though
but you need to move past that to get to
be next level here's another option
don't get promoted this is what I did
because I made this observation at my
college the normal path did you become a
part-time teacher then you become a
full-time teacher and you actually know
far less and you begin to go out of date
and then you move into management where
you know nothing and I was reluctant to
be promoted and I'm glad I got old
enough because when I was young I would
have to climb the ladder and the fact is
the common ladder is to give up being
technical and for a lot of us I would
rather just take less money and stay
technical so it is possible but you have
to beat off people trying to promote you
wait are you trying to get motive wait
you don't know Vince now you'll never go
for C level management it's over and
stay at pentester for life yeah I mean
well one point is like what can you do
to get it promoted but like even if you
want to get promoted so like every CV
for a CSO says please demonstrated
trackable record of being a good CSO so
how do you have that like the chicken
and egg broke that best advice I could
give you is cross-training seriously
like actually go to a p.m. and say hey
why are you passionate about project
management yes yes I'm not joking well
yeah just start cross stream may and age
money if you manage money and make money
work for the company they will be
interested in what else you can do
because like mild shock like PMS or
sometimes just as passionate about
project management as we are it's a peat
project management is hard right you
think that's easy that is not easy that
is that is really hard right being a
good PM and managing a lot of money is
really really hard
hi I'm trying to transition out of
accounting into IT and I feel like I'm
18 again so my question for you is can
you suggest some security related roles
that might leverage my accounting and
business back so like audit IA those are
just those are definitely awesome
opportunities for you another one and
this is gonna sound weird is actually
going the forensics route yeah like for
it on the forensic side accounting
background is this is not an
exaggeration like people will fall over
backwards to want to hire you that I'm
not a CPA I don't like accounting no no
but if you have a CPA if you have like a
forensic accounting background or any of
that and you leverage that my company
that can be very valuable
I have studied an introductory and
advanced forensic accounting and so but
I really didn't want to have to do the
CPE for accounting because I really like
technical not talking about forensic
accounting he's talking about doing a
computer forensics but how many skills
we'll talk because literally you're
gonna be talking about how these people
effectively either stole by time or
resources hundreds of thousands of
dollars from the company that's that's
really valuable to be able to say here's
a timeline here's what's occurred here's
why it occurred but but maybe to answer
your question more directly you've
already got this one silo that you've
built up you don't need to necessarily
rely on that you want to build up the
other one III would probably start with
training at smaller conferences like
this simply around probably macro level
security then been something really
granular okay so to that point like an
introduction to read sort of like red
teaming something like that would
probably really valuable to you what
kind of security role do you want well
that's like saying it's like saying I
want to get into medicine that's a lot
there's a lot of things there are you
are you interested more in defense or
offense I thought that
maybe leveraging my accounting skills on
a red team would be kind of fun because
I could tell them some parts to attack
and so like for instance if I saw
someone going and looking through the
accounting policy or the the org charts
come for the controller's department I
would probably be somewhat alarmed
tracking where people are the Internal
Auditors do a lot of things that are
probably similar to what you do and it
would be an easy transition yeah because
they'll have they'll have software that
they're monitoring data loss data
protection software and things like that
this DLP stuff where you can see who in
the office opened this fall or touched
that so so it sounds like you're
accounting for things and feeding the
other group from a procedural some
procedural standpoint like when you're
gonna deal with compliance issues and
procedures of that sort it sounds to me
that that's probably your easiest venue
is to is to pursue something in audit
that also get you near people who are in
security so you can be electro yeah and
you can be like hey how did you do that
that's really interesting or whatever
gets you some Network effect right and
on the flip sorry are you willing to
travel for work things of that nature
yeah can I say just as a as a heads up
like consultants right like I'm a pen
tester the same place doesn't need pen
testing every day right so i'm on the
road 50% of the time okay so that's a
real life you know that somewhere
between 30 and 50% of your time it's
gonna be in hotel rooms which is not
like on vacation travel it's like like
imagine being jet-lagged you know 50 or
60 percent of time with your life it's
pretty crappy sometimes so yeah it's -
it's yeah that's right you you know you
get parachuted into someplace you have a
week to make it work right you don't
know what the deal is everything you
were told is wrong so be ready to figure
it out thank you okay well it looks like
it looks like we're running out of time
all right all right all right let's do
any more so I have a question because I
want to try to help the accountants out
there the physical therapists the
musicians try to find forays into the
security profession and it's in my
experience if you have a Java programmer
standing in front of you depending pump
what their background is and what their
personality is you might tell them you'd
be great for the Hollywood industry you
should go work for a government
contractor or I mean there's you should
be look for a small start-up you should
look for a giant company right depending
upon the person in front of you with
this particular skill set you might send
them to different industries for the
same role but in completely different
interest rates because they'll do better
if they if they find a career path that
works so my question to you is based on
your experience you're seasoning in the
security world what what what are what
are the what are the different how do we
give people advice that are coming from
other careers trying to get into
security what would be the right person
to look for a security job in the
healthcare industry or biomedical
industry who should look for startups
who should look for the big three-letter
agencies typically the three letters are
ex-military anyways yeah it's muddled in
immediately after they get out exactly
beyond that I don't think you should
focus on any of that you should focus on
if you want to do something go do it and
find a place that needs that you don't
have to be in an industry to be in
security I guess I would say that like
in what I've seen I worked with small
companies and big companies and shout
out to your resume workshop by the way
what's up Lori yeah the I was seeing
that the smaller smaller the company you
work for the more jobs you get to do and
the more exposure you'll get the more
willing they are pepper to take a risk
on you a big company wants to a very
defined role with some security at
you'll be able to do that specific role
very discreetly so if I was starting out
and like I started out I started out
very small firms right because someone
needed to take a risk on me personally
right needed to say okay Jeff I'm
willing to let you try this thing out
because I trust you
right and that that growth and my career
came from personal mentor ships and
relationships I built with my boss and
but with the other parts of the company
and smaller companies is much easier to
do that the bosses to people away maybe
down this down the down the hall as
opposed to in another city or another
state right so it's a different
organization I'd say I would say smaller
companies are better for starting out if
you're looking to expand what you're
doing gives you some gives you some
flexibility I'm gonna add something to
that I'm gonna say yeah I'm gonna I'm
gonna dispute that no actually I'm gonna
say that's a good idea but it's not an
absolute and here's the reason why you
learn certain things with a small
company you're the chief cook and bottle
washer you're doing everything ok and
that's cool you can get into those jobs
you know probably easier than some but
at the same time from a career
standpoint and eventually trying to get
into management make that you know
c-suite you need to learn how big
companies operate they've got a budget
the little guy does everything in the
company the the in the big company you
know you're you're learning a lot more
they can put training money behind you
which can accelerate your development a
lot faster you're going to not have to
figure it all out on yourself but you're
going to be learning from people that
aren't that are doing some of that so
you're gonna be able to leverage that
experience on top of what you bring to
the party and you know you want to get
as I was told early in life is make sure
you get that corporate staff time in
somewhere along to your career so I used
to bounce in and out of doing my own
thing then an opportunity to come to
work for AT&T I'd go hang out with them
for a while then I go do my own thing
then I go back work for McDonnell
Douglas for a while they trained me some
more stuff and then I go do my own thing
then I you know so you know you can
bounce in and out of here and try to get
the best out of each of these so
hopefully that helps all right well we
seem to wrapped up to the end of our
time here today hope you all had fun I
want to thank our esteemed group of
panelists for sharing their insights and
experience and I want to thank all of
you for participating and coming here
and wish you all the best of luck in
your new careers
[Applause]