my clip Hartsock on privacy and it will
be awesome don't worry there's no drugs
involved but it'll be amazing after this
in this room is the closing ceremony so
stick around if you'd like to see more
DG open mic and after that we're going
into the 23d shop after-party in
Fullerton
if you're looking for a ride there's
some people offering rides in the
hallway then you see it's available so
figured out the hallway asked me if Yugi
pointed in the right direction
talking does privacy really thank you
all for coming there's plenty of empty
seats up front you didn't come up we
won't be smashing watermelons or
anything too dangerous here today so
when I got the idea to do this talk I
thought you know I've got this idea and
I can probably do a talk in an hour for
it and then I thought okay well what's I
got a beginning middle and end I can I
had the beginning I thought I had some
middle I really didn't know where I was
going with it but a couple days ago I
finished all the slides so I guess I got
to do it anyway there was a lot of stuff
and I I couldn't fit it all into the
hour so I I think I kept the best and I
ate throughout all the rest and
hopefully you'll feel the same way so
anyway well let's get started
so does there's privacy really matter
anymore perception versus reality and so
the question is is privacy important to
you and why I can we can we can we put
it on a scale of 1 to 10 can we measure
in some way I mean this would seem like
an easy question to answer but it's
actually a rather complex question and
well in some cases it might appear to be
obvious in other situations it's not so
much so it's not always black and white
in fact as you'll find out often it
depends so let's start with let's start
out with people you know in the industry
here we think of well we can
differentiate between privacy and online
security yeah we think in a more gray
more detailed but you know the mere
mortals out there the average purse
they kind of don't do that they kind of
combine those two things into one so in
focus groups that were done
respondents pretty much echoed that
feeling it you know these questions
sounds like it the same looks like same
to me
so for the purpose of today's talk will
kind of follow that definition will will
be using the terms interchangeably okay
all right so let's look at this data
privacy today and and whether it's
retail stores tracking customer shopping
habits or online services and
applications that you know give you
stuff for free but then want to target
some ads to you you know it's a
Americans regularly face the choice of
is it worth handing over my personal
information for something I'm gonna get
in the back in return okay so I went
trying to look in and find some answers
this question and there's a lot of
different research being done out there
but but I came across I came across a
group that's pretty well respected you
may have heard of them it's called the
Pew Research Center and if you don't
know them they're a nonpartisan fact
tank that deals with issues and
attitudes and trends that shape America
in the world and for the past three
years they've been doing surveys and
have tried to map this landscape and the
nuanced feelings that Americans have
regarding privacy and insurance and
surveillance I mean insurance as a
freudian sleep of some sort so anyway
exploring the exploring these things
they they did a number of surveys they
did some focus groups to get some real
in-depth insight into that and I'm gonna
borrow some of the better parts of that
information present that today to give
you a feeling on you know how this is
really shaping up in the world and my
goal here at the beginning is to kind of
establish a baseline on expectations
what do people really feel about some of
these issues and then we'll work from
that to see how those things are being
met we're gonna cover a few of the
recent when he called legal events or
changes in some laws and then we're
gonna look at things things that are
happening in the world at the moment
that affect this and then we're gonna
use the crystal ball to look a little
bit in the future and see where things
might be going so
with that let's start with the first
scenario here okay so here's here's the
scenario
the office surveillance some people in
the company there were some theft issues
and so the company says well we're gonna
put up some cameras that use facial
recognition we're gonna try to see and
spot and recognize who those bad guys
are you know that sounds like a good
thing but then you know this idea works
so well that we're gonna keep those
things up there and we're going to you
know be able to monitor the workplace
see how performances on workers and
things like that and so on so is this
something that would be acceptable or
not acceptable okay and as they found a
lot of people said you know 54% here
said that's kind of acceptable to me I
can deal with that 24 percent said no
and the other thing that happened was a
number of those people when it came down
to security the ones that said yes were
kind of Pro on the security aspect to it
but on the performance review well that
was kind of a no they they felt that
that was overstepping the original
intention of this thing so yes we want
to stop crime but no I don't want you to
follow me around or we don't cameras in
the bathrooms and you know watching me
work and seeing if I'm lazier if I'm
playing solitaire and it's kind of we're
stepping the line so so those are some
of the things that came out in that
scenario now what else have we got here
let's look at this how about health
information you got HIPAA compliance all
sorts of laws to protect things but in
this case a doctor's office created a
website and the idea was to help manage
patient records and in doing that if you
participated you'd have access to your
records easily you could look at those
things you can see the lab reports
coming back and you know it would kind
of speed the process in some in some
sense well pretty much by a two-to-one
margin people found that acceptable
fifty-two to six twenty six percent of
Americans were willing to accept that
now some twenty percent say that you
know the scenario would depend on
particular circumstances and a lot of
those things would be you know related
to how this information is being used
but
the other difference was that people say
age 50 and older were more likely to say
this was acceptable than people younger
than 50 it seemed to be that people with
a higher education were more likely to
accept this than those without a high
school education so there are a few
demographic differences in that regard
but a few people thought that the
trade-off was unacceptable
some people issued some concerns that
you know hey it's another website to be
hacked and and that could be a problem
one comment was well if it is I I'd
rather lose my medical record than my
banking record which I don't know I'm
not sure if I agree with that but you
know you're getting comments all over
the place with this thing with this type
of idea so let's look at something else
next scenario here's one that we
probably already do something about no
wrong way let's go that way there we go
customer loyalty cards how many people
here use you know that car at the Ralphs
of the Vaughan show of hands if you're
one of those people ok quite a few of
you right and you know same thing here
we found that you know almost half the
people 47% said that that that was
acceptable and and that it was worth
doing for the bargains that they could
get people pretty much thought that was
a good thing although there was some
concerns with the unacceptable group
that well you know they took person they
took exception to the idea that their
data was being collected they didn't
like the idea that would be sold to
third parties and they also expressed
some concern about getting unsolicited
to telemarketing calls as a result okay
so but most people seem to be accepting
the idea and you know as shown by the
hands in this room you know I mean we we
all kind of do some of that here's an
interesting one auto insurance imagine
the following scenario if you will your
insurance company decides that they want
to offer you discount but to get the
discount they want to put a GPS type of
monitoring device in your car to you
know track your driving habits
are you doing you know reward good
behavior type of thing in fact back in
1998 progressive insurance started
offering people a chance to install this
telematics device in their in their cars
to track their driving behavior and they
offered discounts to those that you know
performed well so to speak that went
along for about 15 years then in 2013
they changed the system a little bit and
they started charging poor drivers
higher rates so that wasn't a great idea
anyway in in general people most people
found this is not acceptable
they didn't like the idea of being
tracked they didn't like the idea they
didn't like the idea of knowing where
they went in a particular time I mean
there was certainly a group that was
agreeable to this and they would make
comments to the effect that there were
good drivers they had good habits and
they deserve to be rewarded for that so
they welcomed this type of system
however others felt that you know I like
the speed sometimes and you know maybe
this isn't a great idea that's gonna
help me so much so so they were a little
divided there but most people kind of
were creeped out by the idea of tracking
where they're going and probably most
people in this room would be creeped out
at tracking where they're coming so all
right so what are the scenarios we got
here free social media well not a new
idea but in this case the scenario was
presented that high school was trying to
get together for reunions - you know
10-year reunion or something and they
wanted to create this website and you
could subscribe to that and you could
share your information up you load your
picture you could connect with you know
your old high school pals and stuff like
that
pretty much this one this one kind of
got shot down 51% said non acceptable to
33% and it was good the biggest
difference in this pertains mainly to
aged people that didn't like social
media well let's see under 50 about 40%
said yeah this would be acceptable
over 50 about 24% said this would be
acceptable and part of the problem with
this question they think was that
especially among those people that
didn't use social media much then
generally disliked social media that may
have colored the responses to the
question in general people felt that
they wanted to use existing systems
rather than get into adding their
information to one new system the
trade-offs really didn't seem to be a
great idea and you know it was
unacceptable in that regard other people
said that hey those guys in high school
haven't contacted me in ten years
they're bunch of losers I don't care to
connect with them anyway so you know
that was a note that was a no-go how
about the Internet of Things thing okay
so smart thermostats right so here's the
deal power companies got smart
thermostat technology they want to put
that in your home then doing so they
want to be able to monitor as you're
moving around the house see what's
happening there or what your energy uses
are you know maybe at night everybody's
in the bedroom they turn down the turn
down the heat in the living room in
other areas and they turn up the heat in
the bedroom make comfortable one place
do some energy savings surprisingly
enough fifty-five percent of the people
thought that's not going to be
acceptable about 17% of the it depends
we're mostly what are they going to do
with the data how long are they going to
keep it you know who's gonna have access
to it and things of that sort
other people just objected to things
being captured about their movements in
their home it was like it's my space
it's my castle you got no business being
here and if I want to manage my if I
want to manage my heating and remote
remotely managing and I can arrange that
for myself so so this was kind of a
thumbs down all right so are we finding
any themes here so far well
let's see mostly we're finding that
there's a not all information is created
equal I mean as far as the sensitivity
people have to that so the Holy Grail
Social Security numbers the identity
fraud thief's gold golden egg that's
something we universally want to protect
other things like you know my shopping
habits or what am i listening to on
Spotify things like that not such a big
deal I don't care
all right so people value people have
lots of personal information but they
obviously depending on this situation
value that information in different ways
okay and the focus groups went on to try
to dig into some of these things and see
what some of the major concerns were and
and this this this word bubble here kind
of shows that what sort of terms seemed
to come up and you know there's secret
the right to keep hidden things hidden
you know a number of areas there in the
post Snowden era when many of the many
of the citizens learned that gee there's
a whole lot of spying going on here and
collection of data that we never even
thought I just thought it was a tv-show
thing but no it's really happening well
that kind of changed the National the
national perception and the talk in
these areas most Americans close to
about eighty percent agree that citizens
should be concerned about the government
monitoring programs and particularly the
government monitoring phone calls and
Internet communications only about
eighteen percent disagreed with those
things or some reason of their own and
an overwhelming majority of Americans
sense that they have a loss of control
over their personal information how it's
being collected how it's being used and
they really feel that there should be
greater regulation on the part of
advertisers as to how they handle their
personal information now people have
their own methods for posting content
whether they're using their real name
screen name or
anonymous posting but you know that
seems to change from time to time based
on the venue and the information they're
sharing so once again different
information seems to have different
values to us okay so water break alright
so so now we got so hopefully now we got
a little bitter feel on the complexity
of this issue and some of the trends on
how people respond to those types of
choices that they're having to make on a
pretty much daily basis so now I want to
go into some of the some of the changes
recent changes in loss now there's a lot
of laws that affect privacy okay but I'm
just gonna take a couple that a couple
of the most recent things that have
happened here
one is the gdpr that just went into
effect on Friday and probably a lot of
you I know most all of us have been
receiving it a slew of emails over the
last couple weeks if you know hey you
want to keep your receiving junk from us
sure click here and so on and so forth
so show of hands is there anybody in
here working for a company that's that -
been dealing with this gdpr thing any of
you guys been involved in that few hands
in the back a little bit but you've all
gotten the emails right yeah okay so we
all got that all right
so let's talk a little bit what GDP are
and let me give you a brief overview on
what it is okay so this is a new
regulation that replaces the the data
protective director okay it's a law that
had been around in Europe for about 20
plus years and in general Europe has had
greater privacy protections than we have
in United States I don't know what I'm
not sure what to account that for but I
think that you know during those early
years the world war twos and things like
that when there was a lot of persecution
over there that they figure the less
they know about me the better and maybe
that maybe that concept is carried
forward and affected the developmental
of a lot of their laws the the GDP are
the general data protection regulation
it's a European Union law and it
idea is to deal with data protection and
privacy for all individuals in the
European Union now and this also
addresses the export of their data
outside of the EU in addition now why it
may be affecting companies in the United
States is because it also reaches out to
impact companies that are dealing with
individuals in the European Union so if
you're doing business there if you're
dealing with their data you're going to
have some requirements to this okay so
not to get into the minutiae here about
this but the gdpr is basically made up
of 100 and the main part of is this 173
recitals that make up the body of the
thing and just to give you a feel for
the one of those the first one first one
it was kind of cool first one says data
protection as a fundamental right
protection of natural persons in
relation to the processing of personal
data is a fundamental right I think it's
a pretty good idea and everyone has the
right to the protection of their
personal data concerning him or her yeah
it's gonna be good this isn't this is
not a bad idea to have here in the
United States I don't know usually we're
leading to California why didn't we
think of this huh so other things going
on with it you know in many services
you're automatically opted in under this
system you're automatically not opted in
you have to specifically choose you also
have the right to know what is being
collected and how that information is
being used furthermore you have the
right to get a copy of the data that's
held by these entities and unique new
thing the right to be forgotten so you
can just say hey lose my number forget
about it and all my data and that's kind
of cool and those are some of the
challenges that these companies are
having is being able to construct their
systems in such a way to allow them to
do this you have to you have to group
information you have to take information
in if you want to look at information
you can look at it
you know like I could say I want to know
all the orthopedic surgeons that are
male between this age that live in you
know Nevada or something but I can't
zero in on Bob in Reno per se the
information can't be stored or available
in that fashion so so this is giving
some headaches to companies that have to
rethink their software and their
database structures to try to
accommodate and allow them to do that
okay so a couple things going on there
that you may not have heard now gdpr
tries to be a very wide-ranging thing so
it deals with you know it casts a wide
net and trying to deal with privacy
issues and there's fines involved as
well in fact yeah there's some serious
fines involved and we'll talk about that
so one of the compliance problems here
as I mentioned anybody that deals with
the European Union has to comply with
these rules and if you don't potentially
you could be fined up to 20 million
million euros or four percent of your
global revenues not just your European
not just American your global revenues
which everyone's greater so I mean if
your Facebook or Google or one of these
big players that could be that could be
a lot of money okay so they've been
working on this for a while and and it's
still a problem for many of them there's
some workaround things because you have
to if you're processing the data you
also have to get permission for that now
there's a there's a element called
legitimate interests basis and the idea
behind that is if you've got something
that well you have to define a
legitimate interest you have to show
that processing is necessary to achieve
that interest for the individual and
then you have to balance it against the
individuals individual rights and
freedoms and interests so it makes
things a little bit more complicated you
just can't decide hey we're gonna
processes data this way and do this
thing with it without consent if you can
pass those tests and because this thing
is new and none of these things have
really been litigated yet you know
there's a lot of gray areas there so if
a company is trying to say hey we can
keep doing what we're doing more or less
and we're going to use the legitimate
interest basis that may come back to
bite them later so it's a still a few
confuses there all right so what else is
this cost well it's also caused as you
can imagine some casualties in fact
right here in Los Angeles the LA Times
is now blocking users from the European
Union they they can't do the things they
need to do so their solution and the
solution of a number of other companies
has been well you just can't go here
anymore okay but worse than that for
some companies it's actually putting
them out of business
there was a an app called Instapaper
that Pinterest owns that's shutting down
there was a Straits
it's called Street lend which is kind of
like it Craig's this sort of thing where
our neighbors can say hey I need to
borrow a rake or you know do you have a
drill or you know what have you and they
can mix those things now now think about
it for a second now you're exchanging
personal information about the neighbors
without explicit permission so that idea
in that model the way they had it set up
violated the thing and so they
completely decided well we're not gonna
fight it we're not gonna risk the fine
so we're I guess we're shutting down
until we think of something else so not
only can be costly for non-compliance
but it could be very costly to set this
up oh you have a question sir go ahead
you know I don't think so let's face it
if you came in on a VPN and I said I'm
living in California instead of in
London you know that that's that's gonna
be a thing often often in the law when
you're litigating things there's a
concept of making a best a good-faith or
a best effort you know if people try to
fool you and all that you can't really
be held liable to somebody that's going
out of their way so you're doing your
part they're going out of the way to
subjugate their own protections so it's
hard to hold you liable to that I would
suspect that those arguments would be
made okay so costly well how much does
it cost
well here's an idea some people it's
cheap but for others they might be
spending over a hundred thousand to a
million dollars and in some cases over
here with the this little sliver of 10%
million dollars plus I think that's the
guys with the billion dollar exposure to
fines probably so there's a lot of
changes going on with with this new law
and as I said it just went into effect
on Friday okay so that's what's
happening that's a little snapshot of
Europe and recent things what's
happening here locally well anybody here
heard a thing called the cloud act no
okay a lot of a lot of head shaking here
a lot of head shaking okay all right so
the cloud act or the Claire clarifying
lawful overseas use of data act who
comes up with these things
hey I really needed to what they needed
something that would spell out cloud
anyway so has anybody heard of the
stored Communications Act
if not I'll tell you a little bit stored
communication Act allowed federal law
forcement to compels technology
companies and you know basically the
warrants and subpoenas to get
information that's stored on their
servers the cloud Act it was actually
information and rest the cloud Act
expands that to allow them to request
information
stored on servers wherever those things
are so Google might have servers around
the world and previous to this there was
a regulatory boundary or a
jurisdictional boundary where you know
he couldn't go outside the country
because that's not your jurisdiction so
they couldn't reach that in Austin this
thing started by well actually this act
was this was this was proposed in three
different bills by senator Orrin Hatch
and they didn't get him passed and when
the Republicans took control of Congress
they combined all those bills into one
big badass bill and they crammed it
through and so what we now have is the
cloud act and with a cloud act oops
with the cloud act there was a there was
a famous case with the FBI in Microsoft
they were chasing a drug trafficking
investigation back in 2013 and the FBI
says hey we want this data and Microsoft
says hey it's in Ireland on servers
there we can't give it to you because
we'd be violating privacy rights over
there and so forth and and so it went
all the way up to the Supreme Court and
was about to be heard this year when the
cloud Act passed and made that whole
argument a moot point
so they dropped that and now they have
the ability to to go to Europe or to go
anywhere else and to get that sort of
data and now obviously the bill gives
law enforcement a tool that they wanted
and the second part of the bill allows
the President to enter into executive
agreements with foreign governments that
would allow each government to acquire
users data stored in other countries
without following each other's privacy
law so this is like a loophole around
everybody's privacy laws this is like
the secret I'm gonna pass you the data
thing okay
so as you can imagine a lot of privacy
rights groups have have said this is a
problem because depending on how they
enter into these agreements you could
have foreign governments that come in
that want to monitor dissidents or
follow their citizens and so on and they
can request this data and and get it
sent to them without any due process of
law
those unlike a warrant or a subpoena
where the party beans peanut is going to
get notified of that you wouldn't know
this was even happening okay so so
there's some real problems here with
this in in potentially and in citizens
rights okay
so so there's a couple of things
happening on the legal sphere so what's
happening here in the real world today
besides this okay that might be
affecting privacy rights well let's look
at a couple items anybody aware of the
postal covers program postal covers is
where the post office is photographing
your mail not the inside but the send
the to and from on the mail packages
letters what have you and this was
something too started a number of years
ago when there was this anthrax scare
where somebody was sending poison powder
through the mail and they wanted to find
out a way to track this and so they
started this program well the anthrax
thing is over however the program never
went away you may just decide that this
could be useful and in fact if law
enforcement wants to get access to this
all they do is fill out it's like a
two-page form they fill out and they get
their supervisor to sign off on it and
there's tons of these requests that get
processed over the years okay so that's
a little concerning license plate
cameras anybody seen the license plate
cameras on the police cars they've got
them you'll see them on the top on the
on the light bar and they'll be kind of
angled out to the side so as they're
driving they can see the cars on either
side they'll have them behind there and
that picks up all that information feeds
into a large database in fact in the Bay
Area recently they proposed that they
put these things on garbage trucks so
that every day they'd be combing through
the city and adding to that database
okay that's a little creepy I don't know
about you but seeing Ray's cell phone
intercepts we know that's being used
here in LA and other in other areas and
big data analytical services how can I
put together all the pieces you know you
watch those CIA spy movies and they got
the screens all over the walls and
there's stuff coming in from here and
yeah that kind of stuff that kind of
okay it's helpful for some things but we
want to make sure it can't be used
against us so oh and there's a thing
called the expectation expectation of
privacy doctrine so how do they get away
with taking pictures your license plates
and the postal covers and that sort of
thing isn't there a law to protect you
against invasion of privacy you know
like the Fourth Amendment illegal search
and seizure things okay
so there's this concept called the
expectation of privacy when you're
driving down the street in your car you
have no expectation of privacy that
somebody can't see you or take a picture
of you or your license plate for that
matter the same thing as mail going
through the system you really have no
expectation of privacy there so this
privacy is expectation of privacy
doctrine is something that they use
and/or abuse in a number of ways to get
around due process of law and
potentially Fourth Amendment rights okay
so okay let's drill down let's get a
little more fancy stuff going what else
cool is happening there's a thing called
the laser program now the laser program
is kind of a combination of these things
plus about 15 different database sources
so they call it lazy because it's able
to zero in on problem hotspots and
things but the civil rights people say
well it's really useful for you know
keeping a brother down because and once
they get somebody then they keep
watching them they keep arresting them
and and then while it may be helpful in
some areas you know it's it's it's it's
prone to abuse and interesting enough
interesting enough you don't forget
Kickstarter this thing was funded by the
CIA's venture capital arm you didn't
notice see I had their own VC fund did
you pretty cool huh huh so yeah if
you've got some elite tech they might be
interested so and the the laser system
isn't transparent there's no oversight
there's there's really no there's nobody
watching the Watchers okay so we're
getting a lot of these technologies
there that are floating around moving
very fast and yet nobody's really
understand in control of them nobody
stands the implications and so
consequently a lot of stuff is running
wild on its own all right well okay so
how about some other cool stuff here's
an idea here's an idea
there's a concept called a reverse
search warrant now police in Raleigh
North Carolina tried this thing they you
know they had a stalker and they had
some other they had some other cases and
the idea here was what they did was
served a warrant on the service provider
to say in this neighborhood give me all
the cell phones that were there
well the signals you had who were all
those guys okay so now normally a
warrant you have to specify you have to
have probable cause you can't just say
hey we're going to little Aires in
search of okay you've got to have a
reason to go in there and and you got to
be very focused and the warrant says
we're there and we're looking for this
and only this and if it's not on the
warrant you can't go search for it right
well this is a completely different idea
this is like let's go let's go fishing
and get a big net and see if any of
those things are of interest to us so
that's a real interesting thing and it's
certainly it's showing up on Google's
transparency report that they're getting
a lot more requests for that but
literally you get GPS tracking
information you get a lot of things that
can be putting the pieces together
you're broadcasting a wide net so you're
picking up people that shouldn't be
involved in your investigation
indiscriminately and you know this just
certainly could be a problem I don't
know anybody else feel that way
a few heads nodding okay all right so so
that's a little glimpse of some of the
things you have a question sir
oh no no no yeah yeah that's that's it
there's the the due process law that you
would normally get when you get served
with a warrant they walk up to the knock
on the door and go boom warrant you get
services if you're being compelled for
production or something with a subpoena
same thing you get a subpoena with a
subpoena you have a certain amount of
time to quash that subpoena you you have
you normally have about ten days okay
but you have to act quickly on it
there are subpoenas that we can use in
cases where you don't have that it's
called an ex parte sore subpoena to get
that you have to go before the judge
before ten o'clock in the morning you
have to present you know the names of
who's involved and you have to have a
situation where there's imminent danger
and you know and and you know they use
them in domestic violence we use them in
forensic investigations because the data
can disappear very quickly if I tell you
we're coming to get it
you're gonna hit Deline destroy it
you're gonna do a bunch of things to try
to do that okay so so there's instances
of that but in general yeah you do get
noticed on these and you do have
responses to them this you don't get any
of that they get everything you get
nothing so I don't know we're reversing
a few things there right yes sir the
laser program is a very broad-based
intelligence-gathering tool at the
street from the street level that's
applied to areas of high crime
potentially I mean that that's the plan
but in doing so they can they're getting
feeds from multiple databases you know
the cameras and a number of other things
so you can use it to track people you
can use it to do a lot of things beyond
you know just stopping crime so well
yeah in that case well you're well you
think of like um was everywhere they had
pre-crime Minority Report
or they're trying to project things so
in this is this is kind of a step in
that direction where they're going well
these are areas that we want to have
extra views on we're using predictive
algorithms to determine where likely
certain types of crimes are going to
occur in those areas and individuals
that have a high probability of being
involved in some way with those action
based on previous convictions and or
associations it's getting kind of deep
so yeah so yeah but the problem is these
are things happening now so it's science
fact
not science fiction okay Blanchard yeah
I don't know that term but it was a
plant or product so I'm sure that it
evolved out of that process over the
number of years they've been looking at
it
Interpol's been looking at some of those
things they want to spin this technology
off to their 190 different partners and
in different countries and things like
that so apparently it's it's doing
things they like
right yeah what what they disclose to
you is different based on your level
yeah it's it it's right in there somehow
whether whatever their name you're not
in it so okay all right so there's a
couple things going on right here and
the good old US of A
home of the free well let's look at some
let's look at some other parts of the
world because there's always China ok
China has got this thing going oh you're
gonna love this
China's got this plan to create an
all-encompassing social credit score to
keep tabs on its citizens and their
activities and it's due to be in place
by 2020 so even if you don't engage in
political activities it doesn't mean
you're spared last September you know
they started they started using tests of
this the idea is that once you break the
trust restrictions start to be imposed
on you the score can be based and be
influenced by financial transactions
political and social behavior general
lifestyle and you know basically
everything you do today so it's like a
it's like a grading system for your
population now you're deciding what's
the proper way to behave okay so they
want to have that in place by 2020 all
right
well now in the meantime they're not
that far off okay aside from being two
years away most of the information the
government needs for doing this score
has already been collected by companies
like Ally pay which is you know the
Chinese version of PayPal they you know
that restaurant bill you didn't pay on
time that day came to work a few minutes
late the fact your doctor said you
shouldn't smoke soon starts smoking you
didn't you know all sorts of personal
information that's in the hands of
WeChat and its competitors you know all
this stuff can be moved in to and
collected because in China they don't
there's no Constitution they don't have
the personal rights they have the right
to do whatever they think they want to
and they seem to be really good at doing
a lot of that so the score is also
influenced by your hobbies
so interaction with friends
shopping habits lifestyle it´ll higher
the score that you get the more
elimination privileges you get in in
alle pay services or you may get
fast-tracked if you need a visa or you
want to rent a car you know you'll get
privileges to that whereas if your score
gets lower you'll get more and more
restrictions so that seems like it seems
like way beyond the credit score idea
all right
way beyond the credit score idea I mean
I can live with the credit score if I
have a shitty credit score okay fine I
can't get that loan but I can still do
everything else in this case it starts
to encroach on the freedoms in your life
and tries to direct your behavior and
punish bad behavior according to the
powers that be and of course reward good
behavior for those that follow the party
line so I find these things a little bit
concerning anyway so this technology can
quickly move around the world because
technology can quickly be exported so
you have to watch that these sorts of
things don't become part of other
totalitarian or oppressive regimes to
you know further limit the movements and
the freedoms of their people so okay so
we've covered we've got an idea what
people like about privacy and how they
perceive that we talked a little bit
about some of the current laws that that
there are affecting that some for good
and some for not so good now we've
looked at a few things that are going on
in the world as far as potential threats
by activities by large corporations data
collecting and or their partners with
law enforcement and federal agencies and
we've looked at situation in China so
now this is all science fact now where
my things go in the future and what
concerns should we have about some of
that okay so let's think about that for
a second technology is moving along very
quickly Google artificial intelligence
those things are becoming more and more
useful the badges we're talking to Siri
I mean you know 10 years ago thinking
that you're talking to something and
it's giving your answers that are
somewhat meaningful it's totally science
fiction yet today
it's science fact all right so we're
some of those with some of those things
coming along where might we where might
we want to exercise some concerns about
the future well hey something popular
self-driving cars right so with
automated vehicles automated vehicles
for them to work they've got to snag all
kinds of data about the world around
them I mean pretty much they're just
little data factories they got scanners
they got sensors they got it all going
on they got they got infrared they got
lidar they're collecting information all
around to know what's happening around
them who's moving close who is moving
away what's happening wherever and
there's no real there's no real laws in
place that say how long they're supposed
to keep this data for so essentially
they can keep it forever and because all
these things are being captured you know
if you're doing some sort of if you're
doing some sort of investigation for the
federal government's doing yeah imagine
they could go hey give me the give me
the history of this car everywhere it's
been all the things it's done I mean you
could you could have a little video
showing you all that and seeing where
where these things are maybe there's an
accident an intersection we couldn't get
it because it was a not an autonomous
vehicle that had the crash but there but
there were a visa round and so we can
look at the sensors and the data plan
and the data that was collected by those
and see what was happening there as well
so and obviously things are going to go
more towards the self-driving automated
vehicles I think you know on a side note
I think that's probably one thing that
will improve traffic here in LA is if
they can automate the cars you won't
have this bumper tag and stuff they'll
all line up and go happily down the road
for a while so maybe there's a benefit
to that I joke with people saying that
you know if you have kids now by the
time they grew up to get their driver's
license
it's just going to be an app you're just
gonna get in the car and go take me to
Grandma's and it's gonna go there more
cars now it's harder than now to buy a
car with a stick shift you know if you
get a BMW or a Porsche or whatever you
can do that but that's less and less the
thing moving more and more towards you
know four-wheel tech and in more
autonomy so that you know we can be busy
snapchatting and
googling things in the backseat well
we're going to Grandma's so it's kind of
it's uh it's all changing yes sir lock
the doors
right sure I would I you know wind out
that I mean the black market rises up to
deal with injustice everywhere really
yeah but you know you bring up an
interesting point look if we were
surveilling everybody we know that you
know Johnny Chan the the triad kid is
hopped in is a V and we're and we've and
we want to get him baby locks its doors
drives into the police station I mean
it's possible it's certainly possible is
that entrapment well not in China
because they don't have those kind of
laws when it comes here he'll be an
add-on to the cloud Act somehow I'm sure
okay so all right say how about how
about this speaking of Siri voice
recognition well isn't it cool so
imagine this imagine this for a moment
a criminal his face is hidden recorded
by a security camera and he's
threatening one of his victims but we
can't see his face so or a monitored
phone conversation between a suspected
terrorist or drug trafficker or someone
between them and someone pulling the
strings the big kingpin okay 100% voice
recognition would be a game-changer okay
although it can be presented as legal
evidence there's still a lot of
skepticism about its applicability but
happily enough the EU has funded a
program called speaker identification
integrated project and they're trying to
get away around that what they've
basically done here has created a
speaker identification engine that
utilizes audio tracks from phone
intercepts legal phone intercepts social
media posts anywhere you can get
anywhere you can get the people sounds
and creates this database and then
starts to put together a way to identify
those individuals based on known thing
and there evolve z' voice patterns and
you can imagine now that this can really
accelerate because if you consider
artificial intelligence googles
artificial intelligence implementation
is is is largely not what's known as a
neural network neural networks are
really good for recognizing patterns and
things that are close to that pattern so
it's like yes that's similar must be the
same guy and they're offering this as a
service so I you know a lot of
development could easily be done
utilizing the capabilities that they
have and enhancing this whole thing to
make it extremely effective where you
could literally like a fingerprint feed
the voice into a database and come back
with a face
and back to China once more because
they're just so much fun it's not the
new Google glass it's the new police
Google glass now here you see a police
officer in a Beijing station with a with
a facial recognition glass bleh this
glass this this system is hooked into a
back-end database that contains
individual personal details name gender
address lots of other things so as
they're scanning the crowd this
information is coming up and a number of
they've made a number of arrests of
people they've done this in stadiums
they did recently in a big rock concert
in China they arrested several people
that they've been looking for that the
face recognition cameras spotted not all
of them are on the ground level like
this officer they're also installing
cameras you know up on poles in the
major cities they're usually up about
ten feet or so so they're not in your
direct line of sight yet gives them a
great view of your face and your
movements so it's kind of big
brother-ish makes it pretty tough okay
so that's exciting okay I got another
one for you here let me give you a hint
on the next one zombies love this brains
that's right brains we're talking we're
talking brain scans here yes folks brain
scans are a thing there's a technique
known as electro encephalogram set
filmography I think I got that right EEG
for short okay and the EEG stuff you
know you put a cap on it's got some
sensors around your head picking up that
stuff picking up those brain patterns
well there's a there's a well-known
thing called the p300 wave okay and so
here's the deal of p300 p300 Peter
honoree gets fired off kicks off when
when you see or hear something you
recognize okay so imagine this scenario
you got you got a suspected bank robber
and you're showing a picture of the
getaway car and P 3 P 3 huh
goes off is that incrimination okay so
you could do that with a lot of
situations now here's where it gets
interesting so the idea of your
biometric becoming a testimonial thing
well if it's testimonial there's a lot
of protections in the law that should
apply you can't be forced to testify
against yourself for example but if it's
not if it's just physical evidence well
you know you can't refuse to give your
fingerprints so it's a little bit iffy
which way is this going to go and and I
also know that there's researchers that
are doing work on trying to trying to
read your mind with brain scans okay
whether they can pull a sentence out of
that or they can pick emotions or other
sorts of things whether they'll ever get
to the point of making it a shape who
knows but certainly like I said ten
years ago talking to this seeing Siri
would seem like science fiction this
stuff moves pretty fast sometimes so
something to be aware of
you can't just fear the zombies alone
all right so I got another one for you
here okay I think this needs a there's
supposed to be a flux capacitor or here
down in the middle somewhere I believe I
don't does anyone recognize this or know
what this is yes sir
what's your guess this is a quantum
computer this is IBM's q1 it's the
quantum computer unlike our binary based
systems of today quantum computing is in
another dimension and these machines are
this is not the type of thing that
you'll be using for a surfing the web or
doing a little word processing taking
selfies that kind of thing no this this
is made to solve specific types of
complex problems but one of those things
happens to be cryptography and it is
said that this type of computer quantum
computing can break can break encryption
in in the blink of an eye it's like it
doesn't exist okay
it's a
of terrifying beauty now
that means we've got to change does that
mean that you know when this thing comes
out it was probably expensive I don't
know if I can get one for you know to
use but I would say that you know maybe
I can find those lost bitcoins with it
you know there might be there might be a
reason to do this maybe in your time
sharing on Google with it maybe it's a
web share Amazon Web Services could have
one that would be nice but anyway so so
encryption is encryption will
fundamentally change and because the
level of its protection is going to
change now what are you gonna do well
there's a new type of encryption there's
a different type of encryption it's
called lattice field that's kind of the
new hotness that's supposed to be
resilient to resistant to quantum
computing and breaking it so we might
see things going in a new direction
there as well okay all right well what
can you do after all this well it once
again it depends okay you want to do a
threat assessment you know who do you
fear is the government is it cyber
criminals and it depends who you think
your who do you think is coming after
you and what should you do now
cybercrime vulnerabilities that can be
mitigated scams ransomware espionage
things like that the government stuff
might be a little tougher so if we look
at scams and cons and cybercrime it's
the best practices in right you know you
have an antivirus have a firewall be
aware of phishing attacks you should
know that all major breaches start
probably with a phishing attack okay so
you want to be aware of those back up
back up back up that's that's super
important because it allows you to
mitigate the damages okay this is all
stuff we know right keep the software
updated lower the vulnerabilities be
careful of what you share don't click on
links from strangers and that kind of
stuff okay so if you follow some basic
sanitary computer of practices you can
really minimize those threats okay
however the government and that's a
little tougher you're seriously
outgunned here
deleting your cookies is not going to be
enough
in fact coming from a forensic
standpoint deleting your cookies never
really did that good because I can get
them back and yeah and a lot of other
artifacts that are on your machine that
you are not even aware that they exist
so you you can't get rid of them it's
it's it's really that simple so what can
you do here well using a VPN tour you
can try encrypted apps like signal you
know those those are possible you got to
be careful about things that are stored
in officers offshore servers which used
to be a great idea because you figure
hey I'm outside the jurisdiction I'm
cool
remember the cloud act not anymore not
anymore
so offshore stuff you got to make sure
they don't keep logs that's it okay so
beyond that the best defensive weapon
you possess is your brain and you want
to educate and improve user's ability
and your own ability to defend
themselves so you learn about the scams
be able to avoid fake news try to find
legitimate media sites not that the
troll sites that don't quote their
sources that don't do fact checks I mean
they might be amusing but really you're
you're fooling yourself if you were
going to rely on that for valid data
this is kind of cool fake news ww get
bad news.com okay so this is like a game
of you get to put together a fake news
campaign and influence or misinformation
campaign for people and you walk through
this thing and it's kind of fun and do a
number of number of little choices along
the way to see how you want that and
tells you this will work better than
that it's a lot of fun it's good and
it's a type of thing that you can you
can spread this to your friends and
people that should know better and it's
a helpful oh I am to create an awareness
of what how these campaigns get put
together and hopefully someone will you
know look beyond just the picture on
Facebook and find out that there's you
know nothing behind that okay now here's
another item secure drop so if you have
him for me
from a whistle-blower standpoint you can
submitted anonymously with this this
actually was something was coded by the
late hacker Aaron Schwartz so he was
involved in that and it's now being
managed by the freedom of the press
foundation okay
another little item here is the the
American Civil Liberties Union has a an
app called mobile justice and what this
does is you can use this to record civil
liberty violations or protests that are
being oppressed things like that
why use this rather than your camera the
reason is with this it goes directly to
the ACLU lawyers and so they have it so
if your gear gets you know taken or lost
or whatever that stuff is still in play
there and and lately we've seen a lot of
you know suggestion or suppression of
legitimate protest movements certainly I
guess the most recent one was the NFL
where they decided to decided to not
allow their players to kneel during the
national anthem
I suspect this will go to the Supreme
Court because you can't make rules that
infringe on the constitutional rights of
whether an individual can express their
there are First Amendment rights so
it'll be interesting to see what happens
with that
so all right one other thing here here's
an observation that's as relevant today
as it was almost two hundred and fifty
years ago
General George Washington father of our
country first president United State
reminds us that people must remain
ever-vigilant against tyrants
masquerading as public servants now our
document our democracy is supposed to be
by the people and for the people and
during our history many have fought and
suffered and died to protect those
freedoms now you don't have to pick up a
gun but you just can't sit on your butt
and let the attacks on your rights with
the government go unchallenged so if you
want to know where to start if you want
a place to you know to begin with this
you should think about the American
Civil Liberties Union the Electronic
Frontier Foundation these are two
organizations that have been working for
decades to protect those rights and if
you want to know what's going on
subscribe to their feeds you get
notified of what's
currently how you can have your voice
heard and compel the government to do
the things to do the right things the
aunt that the the takeaway here is if
you want personal privacy and you want
personal security you have to take it
personally and get involved so with that
I got one thing here you're gonna like
this oops let's see see what's gonna
play yeah come let's get a place
yeah no this is a cool video
I'm gonna play it small because it's
kind of cool you like
Oh
well that's not gonna work for me so
with that I hope you all enjoy that hope
you learned some things be involved be
the agent of change and as a wise man
once said be the change you want to see
in the world go forth and make a
difference
[Applause]