hello how are you everybody awake me
neither so later on today at 3:00 p.m.
we have the fail of things in the IOT
room we have the raise me resume
workshop in the hardware hacking village
at 4 o'clock all the contests end so
tamper-evident king of the hill capture
the flag as well as the pinball contest
you may not be aware of happening in the
chill-out room the score to beat is 584
million which sounds like a lot but it's
not don't worry
so go beat that win the prize if you
want to buy a fabulous layer 1 2018
t-shirt they're available at
registration for $20 if you like this
talk or missed a talk before or gonna
miss a talk later you can buy the thumb
drives which have all the talks from
Todd in the back after we wrap up here
for $40 and at 5 o'clock in this room
we're doing closing ceremonies after
that we kick all of you out of the rooms
and we head over to the 23b
shop in Fullerton it's a local
hackerspace which promises lots of fun
flock fire hammer Jenga maybe a Tesla
coil we'll see how it goes double check
ok so up next we have a very dear friend
of layer 1 Katy Knowles with signal
Safari investigating RF controls with
rtl-sdr
[Applause]
the goldfish are important hey so thank
you all for joining me right after lunch
I know the food comas gonna kick in in
about what like ten minutes right now
you think you're ready for it you're
like rearing to go you're ready to learn
and then I'm gonna see you all drooping
down so it's my job and my challenge
today to keep you all awake but speaking
of being awake who was here this morning
for the it was the wireless pen testing
talk who was brave enough to get out of
bed for that awesome so you might notice
well other question who had the
self-preservation to just stay in bed
this morning also an excellent choice
both really good options so you might
notice there's a little bit of content
overlap between this one and that one
for anyone who wasn't who missed it
there was a great talk on some devices
that you can use for wireless
communications and you know whatever
you're doing on the security front and
this is a little bit more about almost
the opposite instead of using devices
we're listening devices to devices we're
trying to figure out what they're like
and what they're doing and what they're
up to
there's a lot of mystery in the world
around us and a ton of signals out there
you might not have thought of so we're
gonna go basically from nothing to
surprise you'll find out so this is me
making sure that my remote works perfect
all right so a little bit about what
we'll be doing today um we're gonna go
through how RF works how signals work
how you're gonna expect devices to
communicate on a basic level and then
we're gonna go on an adventure a little
safari through a bunch of devices that I
found in you know amazing
technologically advanced world of my
apartment so there's just a bunch of
stuff that I use around my house maybe
I'm lazy I don't like turning on lights
or fans or anything I'm
ideal user for this right I've got a
bunch of things and they might not be
that secure but we'll learn how they
work we'll see what they do and we'll
take the opportunity to use different
tools whenever we can because that's
what it's all about right we got to push
ourselves to use new stuff and learn new
things which is really what it's all
about
once we get through that we'll close
with some thoughts on signal security
and how he can continue the adventure if
this has hooked anyone there's a ton of
signals out there some of them are
really simple some of them are really
complicated and today we're here to see
if we can catch them all bad Pokemon
jokes I hope you're ready um so if
you're curious about RF if you're
looking for good projects I think that
was the slide before this but that's
alright it all melds together and if
you're seeking adventure then here we go
it's the short story there so to start
things off I'm gonna go through some
introductory stuff I'll try to clip
through this pretty quick while you're
still awake before the food hits this is
like the alright go go go and then we'll
go on an adventure and because your
brain will be moving you'll be awake so
to start things off RF travels is
electromagnetic waves it's kind of like
light and there's a bunch of different
you know RF waves that some of them
you've got the higher frequency with the
shorter wavelength and the lower
frequency with a longer wavelength and
an easy way of thinking about the
relationship between the two is that an
electromagnetic wave will always be
going the same speed they all go as fast
as each other there's a speed of light
so if you multiply the frequency in the
wavelength you'll get back to that speed
of light so signal that we've got that
our higher frequency we can send a
little more data because more of those
wavelengths are gonna pass by in a given
amount of time because it's going like a
little bit faster but you know
metaphorically faster not literally
there's just more waves passing whereas
with the lower frequency we're only
going to get so many and we can only
send so much data with a given
wavelength and this this is it this is
how your phones work this is how the
Wi-Fi works this is how radios work tons
of things so today we're gonna be
looking at a bunch of those signals you
and rtl-sdr so has anybody used one of
these before
cool has anybody really wanted to use
one of these before like they've been
super curious that's great I think we've
got like mostly room at this point
you're like oh maybe yeah well hopefully
by the end of this we'll change that
so rtl-sdr s are super cheap they're a
little USB device that you can plug into
a computer and they have all the
circuitry that your computer needs to
receive radio signals and all of the
processing of that signal can be done by
software so programs on your computer
can handle it so instead of having a
giant clunky radio or you know like the
image of a radio operator in the middle
of the century with this giant wall of
things we can just have this little USB
device this one just receives signals so
if you start using devices that transmit
signals you want to be aware of FCC
regulations and the legalities of that
but for today we're just listening and
learning and finding out what's around
us so we can speculate on security
things but we don't have to worry about
the transmission side and obviously when
you add up cheap devices that do cool
things with free software on Linux you
get magic really not that no way around
it that's what happens all the tools
we're doing today is are using today our
Linux based if you like Windows flavored
things there's tools for that as well
but today it's all Linux so we're taking
our first steps at this point you know
I've gotten through the intro where I'm
like this is what a Pokemon looks like
and now we're in the starting town right
and we're ready we're ready to wander
out you know we kind of know what we're
looking for a little bit maybe you think
we're ready and we're gonna use a
program called GQ rx so this program is
one that lets you tune around for
signals very easily if you've got an RTL
SDR you can pick up like FM radio
stations maybe there'll be some really
interesting frequencies that people are
talking on for a company or police
radios things like that you can just
sort of see what's around you and
there'll be a little bit of like a demo
video coming up with this it's also got
a waterfall view so the waterfall you'll
notice coming up is the view of
different amplitudes over
time and the fruit I'll just let you see
it it's pretty cool it looks like a
waterfall which is why it's called the
waterfall the frequency range you can
look at will be limited based on the
hardware of the software-defined radio
you're using so if you've got a more
advanced one you can look at more
signals if you've got a less advanced
one you can look at less signal so this
is a video of me using it I'm just gonna
turn it on with the rtl-sdr plugged into
my computer and you can see right now
we're at eighty nine point nine
megahertz or at an FM station and this
is that water you can get a sense of why
it looks a little bit like a waterfall
now we see the changes at different
frequencies we can see over time how
it's changing and modifying we can tune
around with it really easily we can
change how we're filtering the noise out
sometimes they'll be RF noise so you
can't hear a signal great you want to
sort of focus in on one thing so you can
hear it and we can actually type in new
frequencies to look at as well so here
we can tune to a different station
maybe I didn't like that music pull the
scanner around so it's really just easy
to play with fun to look at what's
around and see what you'd expect from a
typical radio and then if you want to
you can look at AM so some more
amplitude modulated stuff as well which
is how a lot of the local signals that
you'll find for people talking back and
forth with each other will be so here
we're gonna look at I think it's like
somewhere around the 400s and there's
some local chitchat going on you know
you if there was sound for this you'd be
able to hear you know maybe someones
giving a status update or asking for
help or something like that for some
police related operations which when
they are unencrypted you can tune around
and listen to those which is how if
you've ever seen those police repeaters
online or something like that so now
we've seen we've played around with the
signals a little bit we've kind of had
our first encounter right we've been
like oh wow a signal we found it but now
we want to see more signals right this
is kind of like I showed you what you
already know
FM part of things with a slightly
different view but now we want to start
thinking about like okay so the security
side of things right how do things
operate how do you things turn on and
off how can we find the application of
this to something we'd be a little bit
more curious about and to get there
we're gonna look at sort of the the
zones and the habitats that our signals
live in so we've got you know tall grass
and icy terrains and things like that
here we just have different frequencies
so down towards the lower side of the RF
spectrum you're gonna find AM radio any
amateur radio operators in the room
awesome so I believe ten meters about
like eighty is all in that band that
I've got highlighted here it's not all
the amateur radio frequencies but it's a
lot of the ones that get used for
communication back and forth for those
of you who aren't familiar with amateur
radio you can make some amazing
long-distance communications that way
and then moving upwards we've got a
bunch of different areas where you'll
find television signals if anyone still
uses broadcast television instead of
cable FM radio and these white boxes
I've got outlined are where the control
signals we'll be looking at today live
so this is the specific terrain that
they live in this is where they end up
zooming in on those systems we've got a
few different bands so if you're looking
at control signals for close range stuff
so turning things on and off and maybe
you've got some industrial systems
things like that then they'll probably
be in these bands so when I say the
center frequency on the left here that's
how you'll hear here people sort of
colloquially refer to that band so you
could have something that operates at
maybe like 430 3.9 megahertz it would
still be called a 433 megahertz device
in that range the is M is for industrial
scientific and medical so these parts of
the spectrum were originally set aside
for industrial scientific and medical
equipment and then as time went on they
were sort of opening to other things
operating there as long as they don't
interfere so there can be some pretty
serious things that need to keep
operating there and as long
your signals don't interfere with that
then they're allowed to play too they
just need to you know be quiet calm down
if something more important is happening
and then the unlicensed band down here
is you can just create a device that
operates within the power limits of that
band so it's not too strong works out
well and without having to register that
device it operates as an unlicensed
device so when I say licensed versus
unlicensed if you've ever gone to a
restaurant and seen those buzzers or
taking your phone out of your pocket or
use the laptop you notice that FCC ID
that's the license so people have to
submit information on what the device
does why it's in those frequencies why
it needs to operate in those frequencies
in order to get approval all right
closing out on the introductory stuff
here so we've got the how do these
devices talk right so we know where they
live we know what they look like but
what are they saying how do we get to
those ones and zeros that were used to
seeing for devices that talk to each
other in a digital way and there's a
couple of pretty common ways there's a
bunch of different ones if you start
looking into this there's a ton of
different ways that are really cool that
these systems communicate but at the
very basic level we'll just talk about
amplitude and frequency shift keying so
for the amplitude shift keying or ASX
we've got some length of pulse so the
amplitude the strength of the signal is
going to change so I'm gonna send a
short pulse for a zero and maybe a long
pulse for a one and you know maybe I
could change that up if I felt you know
different in the end whoever designs the
system gets to decide how it works but
generally it'll it'll be some kind of
pulse for frequency shift keying we're
gonna change the frequency a little bit
so we might have a slightly lower
frequency for zero slightly higher
frequency for everything we're looking
at today is amplitude shift keying so
nothing super complicated this is it
this is our first mystery signal this is
our encounter we've like wandered around
trying to figure out what this is which
this is basically me walking around my
apartment like let's find some signals
what does this do and so this is
something that I just found does anyone
want to guess what it is I know it's
super hard to tell you only have a yeah
it's a remote
someone said remote yeah
you caught me it's not very complicated
so this is just like a light switch yeah
I got it on Amazon it came from China
sounds like a great recipe for security
it's very affordable for me as a user I
want a cheap device which is great great
recipe for security and I've got buttons
where I can turn switches on or off this
came with I think like four different
plugs that you put into the wall and
then you plug your device into it and
it'll receive this signal and turn on
off and you push the buttons so this is
cool I don't have to get up and turn my
lights on and off and that's great
because I'm lazy but you know I'm
picking this up and I'm looking at it
and I'm realizing just looking at it
we're not we're not understanding the
signals that it makes we don't know how
it works we've just got a plastic cheap
box that turns things on and off so how
are we gonna learn about this it's like
if only we had something like a tool
like a signal decks and you just you you
know you you go out adventuring you've
got your backpack and you've got your
running shoes and the smell of fresh
adventures on the air and you pull out
this little encyclopedia point it in a
signal and it says I got you know
exactly what that is how it works what
it does it would be really cool if that
existed maybe somewhere so and then a
little bit of research I was like
there's no way there's something that
could make it that easy for me there was
really excited about this so RTL 4:33 is
one of the tools that we'll be looking
at
it's a command-line tool you run it and
it will look around a given frequency
and decode the ones and zeros for you so
you don't need to sit there tuning
around and trying to be like go up to
they go down like what's a what's the
pulse length here it'll chop that all up
for you and show it to you it'll also do
device discovery which we'll look at in
a little bit but here we've got the -
RTL 433 with the dash Q and the - hey
the dash Q is just to make things quiet
and they it's kind of like operating and
discovery mode looking around for things
and you can see we've got here
that we don't care about this one is not
relevant to the testing but maybe it's
it's just something in the neighborhood
talking his devices do and then we've
got down here I start pushing the button
on the controller and you can see the
same signal over and over and over sort
of calling out to that switch turning
the light on again and again and again
or if you hold it for a longer time at
all it'll make the same pulse so in
video that ends up looking something
like this so here we've just run that
same command and you can see as I push
the button we get the signal back we
start seeing you know maybe there's like
a smart meter or something nearby that's
got a similar frequency but you know we
can push the buttons as I push different
buttons if you're paying close attention
you'll notice that some of the ones and
zeros are gonna change so those are four
different buttons but if I come back to
that same button it looks exactly the
same
surely that wouldn't mean something
would it like a security thing or uh
let's just forget about that it probably
doesn't matter right probably doesn't
matter so this is the part where it's
kind of like a baking show I'm like well
here look here's the signal and we can
reverse it by lining up all the bits and
bytes and sort of theorizing how it
works I could just be like dinging I
already have a tray of cookies done over
here so this is this is the done tray of
cookies this is me pushing all those
buttons and seeing what does though on
first which one look like what does the
off for switch to look like and if we
chopped it up so I've added some spaces
to kind of see where it looks like
things are similar so you see the first
10 bits or so are all the same so let's
assume just go out on a limb say that's
the device ID it's saying which remote
it is so maybe my neighbor has the same
cheap remote we don't want to turn our
lights on off at the same time that
would be kind of silly so this is like
the introduction of saying hey this is
Who I am as a remote after that it seems
to be consistent where that zero one
shows up for which switch it is and one
one if it's all on or off so maybe it's
some kind of like selector like hey turn
on just one or everything and after that
we've got some level of which switch it
is so
notice the switch numbers consistent and
then we've got the on in the off look
consistent so we can like translate
these at this point I could receive a
signal someone could push the button for
me and I could just receive it in this
way you know using RTL for 33 and be
able to translate oh this is the switch
saying its name it's saying to turn on
switch to and that's what's gonna happen
so as simple as it looks hopefully by
this point um this is the reversing
right this is like very basic signal
reversing we're pushing a bunch of
buttons and figuring out how it works
which is cool like this is our first
we've caught a signal and we've
understood that signal so that was
backwards there we go so now we've got
another mystery signal right we want to
keep challenging ourselves I'm learning
more things and adventuring around does
anyone want to guess what this is I know
it's really hard to tell whoa a remote
control that's a great guess what kind
of remote control fan yes we have very
smart people in the audience because
it's very hard to tell what this is
isn't it so this is a fan remote that
was in my apartment more me being lazy
of course I don't want to like turn a
fan on and off with my hands all the
time with a switch on it that would be
annoying and it's got some light
controls - this one looks a little more
complicated than the last one which is
cool maybe we've got an opportunity to
use new tools so for this one I tried
running our TL 433 because why not you
know with the same exact options as
before what's gonna happen there it
didn't work so this means one of two
things one is that I'm doing it wrong
which is always a possibility right I am
human I think the second is that maybe
it's at a different frequency so our CL
433 has got an option to tune it to a
different frequency to look at but it's
not gonna find that on its own every
time it's it's only gonna look at like a
little bit of slice we have to know
around where that signal is
so maybe this is a chance to look at
something new we could tune around with
GQ rx but maybe we want to make our own
tuner right maybe this has been really
just so much fun for us that we wish we
could just take all the pieces of a
radio and slap one together ourselves
and make it ourselves almost like Legos
and there's a tool for that - so the
ginyu radio companion is a great way of
putting together the little bits and
pieces that translate software signals
and then getting the display or the
output that you want from them so to
kind of put that in perspective
GQ rx is a tool that uses the new radio
libraries but the radio companion builds
tools that use that so it's kind of like
either a step up or down depending on
how you think of it you get to build
your own things but you're still not you
know left out to code everything by hand
it's very visual it looks something like
this so this is the block diagram that
we get we've got like our little toolbox
over here which is all the different
ways of translating signals and things
we can do with signals the outputs that
we can take the ways we want to display
it in the middle we have the RTL SDR
source which is the most important this
translates for us so this does all the
heavy lifting of taking those little
bits of signals and then turning them
into ones and zeros for us and we can
then feed that into some different
displays for this one I chose the fast
Fourier transform sync so it does a
bunch of math that makes it possible to
see the amplitude at nearby frequencies
so kind of like with GQ rx how we could
see what was going on around us in the
spectrum we get to do that here too and
then I also want something that shows me
the change in amplitude over time so
maybe if we've got that amplitude shift
keying we've got a pulse we want to see
that happening we want to see like what
a short look like what is long look like
so that'll give us that view we've also
got the GUI slider way over on the left
here and this is the thing that we can
grab to tune with so if I was just
making this and putting in 300 megahertz
I'll have to step away for a second
then it would just be stuck at 300
megahertz I wouldn't be able to tune it
we need something that we can use to
explore and in this case it'll be this
sort of variable the GUI slider in this
case we'll just call it fre Q so it's
like a variable if anyone's done coding
and then you just reference that
variable in the rtl-sdr source too so it
knows what frequency to tune to when we
grabbed that button drag it back and
forth which you'll see in a second it'll
make a little bit more sense then so
we've got all these together we've got
our bits and pieces and we're just gonna
press that play button and it'll make us
a radio just like this so this is when
you press play you can see we've got the
fast Fourier transform and then we've
got over time the amplitude for whatever
our set frequency is it starts out
really really like zoomed in on a
specific set of time so right now we're
at microseconds which we don't really
need we want like seconds right so we're
gonna step out a little bit maybe look
at over milliseconds instead that seems
a little more reasonable and now we can
take that button up in the top left and
drag it back and forth between where we
think the signal might be to see what's
going on and then you know in the
background you can't see the part where
I'm just like mashing a button like
crazy seeing what's gonna happen so we
start pulling it along and the range of
frequencies maybe it is we see a little
bit of jumping but nothing really coming
out yet until this right so it just pops
up it's like there it is BAM this is our
signal we found it you know if I stop
pushing the button that'll stop showing
and if I mash that button again it pops
up but we can't really tell what's going
on here right this is pretty dramatic so
maybe we want to zoom out again the fast
Fourier transform plot comes in really
useful here because you can see the peak
if you turn on the peak hold it'll show
you peak amplitudes and it'll kind of
hold on to that so even if the signal is
jumping you can get a sense of around
what frequency that happened that and
then as we zoom out we can start to see
these pulses coming in when we hit the
button and if you'll notice some of them
look a little bit longer and some of
them look a little bit shorter go figure
so we've made it to the ones and the
zeros we can see them with our eyes this
is in the air right I mean like
metaphorically you can
you can fight me on the science of that
but it's pretty cool it's around us and
we've got ones and we've got zeroes and
we're looking at them on our computer
for $30 it's pretty cool
but at the same time as excited as I am
as thrilled as I am in this moment I
don't want to take out a notepad and
start writing down like one zero one
zero for every button that this
controller has but now we know where the
signal lives we know it's at around
through anyone who can't read up in the
coordinates of like three hundred four
point one megahertz we'll call it so for
anyone who remembers with RTL for 33 our
favorite friend right now we can just
tell it where to go so just sort of a
recap on that video portion and then we
can make it do the heavy lifting for us
all over again so we can just give it a
- s flag for the frequency give it
around 300 four megahertz let it do its
thing and it will pick up those ones and
zeros that we were seeing back over here
exact same stuff great much easier
translation right so now I can go and
reverse this one without having to do
quite as much work this was a slightly
more complicated controller so if you
have or have seen anything like that it
would be a really fun exercise to go try
replicate that and see you know how do
the buttons work how does the fan speed
work it's cool stuff so awesome now
we've cut two signals and we've
understood them which i think is the
really powerful awesome part so why
don't we just keep going let's do
another let's do like one more this is
our third mystery signal and I know you
can't tell what it is it's so mysterious
the shape is not determined at all
it's very strange does anyone know what
the signal is can anyone help me
it's a car key it is also a remote
control Thank You Tacitus but it is a
car key we have people who are very
clever all across the audience so this
is a car key and a mystery signal how
does that work let's kind of so for this
one I'm gonna kind of assume that maybe
it's in the 315 megahertz band I've
heard that the signals of type car key
like to live in the 315 megahertz band
so let's try pointing our tail 433 there
so we do that and what do you know we
start pressing the unlock we're like man
maybe this will be just like the light
switch right which rewinding a little
bit does anyone remember with that light
switch I push the button and it looks
the same every time can anyone guess why
that might be a problem
nervous laughter does anyone want to
vocalize their fears about this control
that thank you yes with my light switch
so if I'm using that light switch and my
friends are in the neighborhood which
there are many of my friends in the
audience who may come by and decide to
visit and mess with my lights not a
great light switch for that so anybody
who could transmit could play the exact
same thing they could catch the signal
of me turning on the light and then play
it again whenever they want and wake me
up at 3:00 a.m. if I'm not already you
know staying up late doing radio things
maybe they could turn it off that would
be no fun um but anyway so for this one
we're thinking like a car key right
maybe this will be the same maybe I'll
have a replay attack that would be
really cool wouldn't it we've got others
he's so cool cars or Security's broken
right but we start looking at this and
we noticed there's there's some
consistencies in the beginning of the
signal for this one we've got the same
it doesn't show up perfectly but we've
got the 0 3
8840 and that looks the same for the
hexed representation of the bets but
after that it changes every time that's
no fair just then we can't replay attack
on a car hey so you know with things
like that we've got a little bit more
security going maybe we can't expect
high grade encryption like how our
computers are communicating on a regular
basis and maybe if you're holding on to
a car key for 10 years you can't
necessarily expect someone to show up
and like factory upgrade the encryption
of the controller maybe one day that
would be kind of cool actually but we
still can't do a replay attack we can't
get away with it this time we've been
foiled so in this case I did do a little
bit of research on that specific
controller and somebody had done a
survey of the insecurity and security of
different car controllers car clubs so
for me that would be like my next steps
right I've gone from the beginning town
to looking at a car key and kind of
understanding what's going on which is a
pretty cool you know stepping things
along and advancing my knowledge and
maybe it is still insecure so another
fun trick that you can do with RTL 433
you can just discover so here you'll
notice I've taken away the dash Q and
the dash a flags which means it's gonna
for taking away that I think it's the
dash a it will load all these profiles
of devices it knows so for all those
things in the neighborhood that you were
just seeing the raw signals for before
now if it recognizes something it'll
tell you so I'm just listening to
signals in the neighborhood as one does
one day and down here we've got a Toyota
TPMS is what it's called what's it's
it's a tire pressure monitor system so
for anyone who's not familiar with this
tires will report their status of their
pressure in some way but every tire has
a unique address kind of like a MAC
address thing going on and if you had a
unique set of tires that were attached
to a unique car and a unique person
owned that car and you could tell where
their tires were at certain
times of the day you know you might know
where that person is at that time of day
so TPMS stuff has actually been used for
tracking a little bit in the past so
we've got that more surprises that you
find along the way type stuff and that's
just investigating whatever's around so
at this point we've gone from what is a
signal all the way through I'm decoding
a car key which I hope is a pretty
satisfying experience for all of you it
was for me I love that adventure if you
want to continue that adventure I've got
some resources coming up but sort of as
a closing reflection yeah that light
switch controller is not secure at all
and if you think about how many
different RF controllers are out there
in the world you know you've got
industrial cranes and you've got all
kinds of different systems that talk to
each other with RF and they might not
have quite as strong motivations for
security right you think about the
computing power you're gonna have in a
remote control that's not for a light
switch that's for something a lot more
important it's gonna have a similar
level of power and its security might
not be there so even though we've just
been looking at how to mess with my life
today
there's definitely applications you can
get in surprising places by looking at
this all around the world around you
things are getting better over time as
with a lot of security things you know
we we definitely there's something
satisfying about stopping your feet and
saying everything's broken but they do
get better they really do little by
little over time so and the more people
we get looking at these things and
getting curious about this stuff and
just kind of saying I found this and it
shouldn't really be that way someone
might not have looked at it before and
said hey is this okay is this expectable
is this secure so being able to take
that security mindset and apply it to
something new not only are you
potentially going to help out an area
that doesn't have as much support and
security but you're also going to be
able to just sort of sharpen that
security mindset right look at something
new
thing you've never looked at before
learn new tools push yourself out of the
comfort zone little by little and make
it to much more greater challenges right
so I don't know if there's an elite four
of signals that would be pretty cool
line up but you get bigger badder
challenges and with more curiosity
eventually you get more solutions by
keeping that open mind thinking about
how could we improve this what is the
next step so if any of this piqued your
interest if you want to keep
investigating this stuff then there's a
lot of great ways to do that for anyone
who is interested in amateur radio I
know we had exams last night so you
could try and find someone and ask them
about it
there's also the a double RL so they're
an association that does a lot of
amateur radio stuff very welcoming
community who always loves sharing what
they know and then if maybe the OS n't
part of FCC IDs intrigues you so every
time someone registers an FCC ID they
have to submit papers on what's going on
right and some companies that are a
little less experienced with this
they'll say yeah you can know all about
my device here's the test report and
here's the circuit design and here's
that one note we sent to the
manufacturer that one time they'll just
like and that will get listed publicly
so you can learn a lot about some of
these devices if there's a bigger
company
you know like Google Apple they're
probably not gonna submit that they know
they've got they're used to this right
they've got a sense of what they're
doing but sometimes you can find some
pretty fun stuff there and you can also
see new devices that are coming out you
can see new registrations and kind of
like squint and say it's like do we need
that why did someone make that so it's
fun if you're really curious about just
playing with software-defined radios in
general I cannot recommend more Michael
Osmonds materials on this so he has a
series on using the hack RF on the great
Scot gadgets site but you can really use
it with any radio you want to it's
amazing material and he does a really
great job breaking it down and
explaining it and making it easy to
follow and if this the research side of
it is fascinating to you if you want to
think
little bit more of the car stuff or you
know it's some really fun tricks that
you can play in the world around you
Sammy camp cars got some great stuff on
both the security of cars and RF stuff
and a wireless doorbells right there's
another thing where maybe somebody wants
a wireless system but it might not be
super secure and also the paper that I
mentioned on looking at the excuse me
the security of car fobs in general
there was a great usenix
paper on that so that's all I've got and
does anyone have any questions also
slides are up at that URL just to
mention that so if you want to go back
and look at any of this then or your
phone pictures aren't good then
definitely check that out yes
um could you see again sorry
frequency
the question was when you're registering
advice at the FCC if you have to state
what frequency is used definitely so the
FCC manages basically all the different
frequencies for the US and they're gonna
tell you what power you're allowed to
use at different frequencies and how to
play nice with other devices so when you
do those registrations it's saying hey
I'm gonna make a device and it's gonna
do this at that frequency and basically
here's how I've done my homework to make
sure it doesn't mess up somebody's day
or interfere with something important or
you know transmitted really with too
much power and do something dangerous
does that answer the question I'm saying
yes so when you register with the FCC
you need to tell them what frequency
you're operating at for that device yes
sorry about that
any other questions yes
I thought about transmitting I've
definitely thought about transmitting
you can do a lot of really awesome
things with that the reason that for
this talk there's no transmitting is
it's a lot easier to talk about the
adventure when you don't have to also
talk about the FCC regulations involved
with transmitting so to give a little
more context on that if you're testing
different systems and transmitting
different systems you are also subjected
to those FCC regulations so you need to
think about very carefully about what
you're doing with what systems the other
thing is there might be unexpected
behavior if it's not your system if it's
somebody else's RF device if anybody
wants to play around with the
transmitting side without worrying as
much then definitely make sure you've
got a Faraday cage so some metal to
block the signal so you get your own
sort of this is my world of RF and
whatever I transmit won't get out of
this box so you at least know you won't
cause any trouble you'll just do damage
to yourself if something happens any
other questions
yes so there was a little bit late so to
cover this well the questions I had it
kind of dovetails with the transmission
question but talking about me boys more
capabilities of these devices and how
susceptible they are to serve the
jamming capacitance
well I guess the question I have
so you talk about the the Aryans you
have or potentially of these people so
one of the things I've seen passes its
key fobs will stop working in high noise
markets by heart
our evidence is the party'll STR capable
you know without it's simulating that in
mind poison fire
so without actually by going to a pine
marten will tell me what
answer the question that I'm hearing and
then if I got it wrong
you can ask another question if that
works out so the question that I'm going
to answer um is does you know can the
rtl-sdr handle interference you know if
something gets jammed characterized
[Music]
the noise environment so that you can
send
okay so I guess to the general situation
of the noise floor and then if you want
to keep talking about this after then
I'm definitely interested in that but
just to provide some general context on
the noise floor when you're working with
RF signals things in the world around
you also make RF noises and they might
interfere with what you're trying to do
so if you've got a car key and maybe
there's somebody else who's transmitting
very rudely on the same frequency as
that car key so your car can't hear the
the key unlocking frequency or well it's
hearing all that noise right so
somebody's going to transmit just it's
like the equivalent of shouting right if
somebody's shouting then I'm not going
to hear your question if someone just
stands up in the corner of the room and
yells so it's like the RF equivalent of
that not that there are a lot of ways
with advanced processing of signals so
you cut that noise out as much as
possible but if it is loud and
interfering a lot then you're kind of
out a lot yeah there's also ways to work
around it so if you have like what's
called a noisy environment you can do
things like a complex system might
change frequencies every once in a while
so maybe the system has a way of saying
hey I can't really hear you over here
can we step you know 5 kilohertz over
this way try again so I think that is a
little bit about the noise floor stuff
and then absolutely if you're if you
want to talk about that more if anyone
else is curious then let me know after
this yeah yeah then I'll definitely I'll
look forward to chatting about that any
other questions
awesome well thank you so much for
joining me for this I love sharing this
talk so I have to cheat you all being
here
[Applause]