so welcome it's another 3-2 presentation
three years ago it was a possible kids
again it's the one full kids this time
I'm not sick just good routine because I
can pretend the insane number of slides
that I have for you today ooh am I know
me I'm playing it makes since 2007 when
i bought my first bike I do a lot of
reverse engineering then I started a
blog which was mostly dedicated to
breaking up productions usually when I
download the new program the first thing
I do is breaking the protection just for
fun and then I testing program I'm not
the mac salad people get a lot surprised
when they asked me which from the US and
I tell them we just form but where the
world OSX reverse yes so I use whatever
words whatever I like so I'm not to make
sell it if you want to learn about food
kids I wrote a very long would kids
articles formats for frag last year
something or is it is very long you can
learn a lot of stuff I'm writing the
book or I'm still trying to write a book
me and two other guys it takes a lot of
time hopefully throughout this year or
early next year I think it will be worse
wait if you like you Stefan I have
really been a bit of creating too many
slides this one is 172 in my eyes I see
much here at least 180 or 190 usually
the guide my life yeah Venus if you go
to see the Siskin presentation you see
Thomas Wayne telling me five minutes ten
minutes then two years ago we seek one
and I took like six shots of whiskey I
can also see that because I kept talking
and a high just wait I couldn't stop and
up to do it so keep drinking and the fun
part in Portugal I'm trolling the world
with my domain the other part I Spanish
in Brazilian understand this one it's
very funny because now you have these
guys linking to my reminder your CNN you
have registered a lot of self and
really fun stuff is going down and see
the link to my to my domain video
footage the reason is their ultimate sir
I say mind I just hope to see this one
ever occur with you sky presume they
would keep wakin these guys are so what
I'm going to talk about how to load
Colonel would kill specially by passing
out protection set fos I presented least
the first time last year in Japan in
marching in sis can I'm doing another
presentation based on the if I stuff
that you probably saw on all the new
ones very happy probably parties
research breaking stuff and I releases
your that if you want to have a very
interesting to blog posts if you want to
learn about these five go to my blog and
you can learn and then again a week or
two you can see the slides about that
presentation you can tell you know Rory
gets these are big doors or not they are
mostly design and implement
implementation flaws because I hope
usually doesn't know what they are doing
they can get to be bad Colonel
vulnerabilities i'm going to show you
that the bench for his mighty that was
released this week still in these two
vulnerabilities so I'm unless my job
makes my life very easy because I don't
need to update the slides it's your work
the coats your words funny which is the
second one that I'm going to or the
third one and they put some features
that we can use to bypass all their
protections so I don't know if you can
call it back doors or not it's your
choice or decision after you see this
presentation assumptions if you know me
you know that I'm Economist economy's
fly to put the assumptions you know big
file because you have the IMF failing
with their assumptions so but we still
like to do this this is our model so
this is where we work so the
presentation assumes that you already
have put in in a machine so I'm not
trying to exploit and macros I can show
your or I'm not going to show you
because it's others did your day stuff
but it's not that difficult to get
routine in mac OS if you try to estimate
the probability of this happening I
think this with you like and very fast
because i have this your days for that i
can show you the proof but anything
below is probably wrong you cannot say
it medium or instead base like windows
everyone says bad-mouths about windows
but windows is the chances are probably
much harder than in microwave for
example I didn't take this slide this
part because once again Apple does my
job my life easy because this week they
release the patch for 10 10 dot for and
if you go to see the amount of
vulnerabilities that they bench it's
insane a few more from this guy from
ian's beer so you have a single guy from
google project european beer alike in
two or three men like 10-20
vulnerabilities your days will route
with Colonel called the execution all
kinds of stuff one game so we can
imagine how things are then we aren't
funny stuff desire finally pension but
you have the funny things like this they
patch the tumor abilities in iOS but
they don't care about OS X and I put
this like playing day it really is a
bullet in sight and she denies in micro
its baby they don't say anything when I
need this presentation for example this
vulnerability for which projects he
releases the next point of fully working
late point that works without any
problems flawless they've already things
for us mighty because they they got the
bug from google one from matrix they
didn't release any badge so you had a
fully working next point out there from
reliable working and amiable doesn't
care about that bench but also these for
example another example from a Korean
guy friend tree moon is very good and he
has a safari browser remote code
execution with full local privilege
excavation exploit so he go to page they
are mikey is over he has a full security
it's two words much easier ways to get
see you cannot discuss this with me
because I will win this fight video you
can suffice the user the stupid mac
users give me our admin password and you
got this small where I wore that in fact
it normally 17k people just wait then
please insert your admin password that
it more fun stuff a lot of these
sounders it updates going over HTTP so
if you are a guy say once and you
probably shouldn't download this stuff
over HTTP you have applications
installed with Ron permissions for
example they installed themselves with
the sweaty binary with on the on the
machine with the with information so you
can override and play some games then it
can easily resolution excavate for
example earns the backup help for a
formats carbon copy cloner that you can
exploit the first time the user execuse
and gives the permission again whatever
you want so the question is the tax
advice is really big on my knees so the
assumption that I do that getting root
is not that difficult I Mike so we can
continue on hundred good kids so my goal
since I like put kids especially the
colonel completes because it's low level
and it's way more fun intent username
stuff please i want to let to load the
bed code into the problem while Apple
introduced the new policy basically
dangerous is code signing in Mavericks
in marriage it's not mandatory meaning
if you try to load some kernel code that
is not find it will complain it will say
this this code is not fine but I will
all be genuine if you like sometimes
because it's the first time they
introduce these so they want to test to
see the effect of this finally in use my
keys mandatory if you try to load a
kernel code that is not sign it will not
load so these are three reasons why
that's Colonel that hope Blue Mountains
in the colonel first there's a good
signature so you cannot old anymore if
you
as user if physical signature is invalid
you cannot talk can't flow because it's
invalid that was a trick and you could
really hold your Colonel extension very
early in the system Apple isn't x
feature so is here for example unique a
security product this brings you some
problems so it basically will put your
bundle night competent not they
certainly getting education so you
cannot use this trick anymore what are
the solutions the first one is what the
spies are using if you are up to date
for example i Dessay or the guys that
sucks man and who and all that stuff
they are basically with me suing the
certificates final it costs you ninety
nine dollars to get a certificate then
you need to make a request and tell okay
i want to build a colonel work drinkies
tell them it's not for testing if you
say it's for testing they will be knock
to request it's just say i want to build
a security product and they will give
you the right search be they could
disable that feature i'm not sure if
eNOS mighty it's it's still available in
El Capitan if it's going to still
available if you want to get visible as
a perimeter inside disable everything
you can attack from the e-file this is
where I'm movie now this is a really fun
world and essentially if you can Bronco
that the firmware level it's game over
you can be whatever you want which
student firewalls
you can attack user this is really
stupid you are going to see how good a
please main steps you can exploit
Carlton abilities because if it's if you
can find a way to write to the kernel
memory you can do whatever you want and
they can abuse existing teachers which
is what i'm going to show you last these
are lying demons these are ever get me
security video they have no idea what
they are taking point there is no demon
in my code is called kexp what it does
it's the immune responsible for doing
the co-signatory shank so if one more
what do you want to load the trailer it
sends a request this demon this theme it
goes to purify the container such as yes
or no and that's it the funny detail
design this demon is running in pink
tree basically it's running gets to use
reliable so it's not running in the
curve so what you have is something very
fine coat that you want to load that the
lower prefers from a higher privilege
this isn't make any sense because you
can attack that process if you attack
that forces it's game over they don't
seem to learn there's a guy saying we
are going to or there is a wee quest for
using these to the car balls so they are
building new feature in El Capitan you
probably heard about it rootless if they
leave these like this it's to wherein
the better version did you like this if
doing this it's game over it just
batteries and let it what you need to do
this is the piece of combat unit patch
and there's the call that function like
static codes check validity this is the
certificate related stuff essentially it
has the codes shake the certificate see
if it's valuable value return yes or no
so until you do you attach for example
to the process petra discount the shore
in the XX or whatever you want to do
what is your way of etching stuff and
that's it you can load everything and to
the current that you want hope and with
code signature or not it's static so you
know you really just need a few bites
and we bypassed yourself
I wrote about it wasn't this specific
attack in 2013 it was a variant for
mavericks because Mavericks would love
anyway at the time I just patched the
warning because it will show a warning
to the user and this is Colonel
extension is not well so just by two
medicines the message never appears and
that's it so it's more or less the same
variant about this so I'm not showing
you guys in infinite loop then they were
like they're really nice but we really
are potheads and it's hopeless so my
presentation could essentially end here
because it is game over that it there's
nothing else to do but i like to wait
for stuff and I like to teach people or
charging people and find yourself I love
this life and because it says a lot
about the security field you have
English further we have fireballs
encryption antivirus software and is
going on ending this farmer we update
the date is the human so basically in
the human examiner's and it's part of
the game this is from always happens and
so as long the critical there will
always be vulnerable ities so we are
going to explain them what I'm
interested I'm interested in anything
and an internal tomography that allows
me to write the kernel memory for
example you can get some buffer overflow
or some primitive that allows you to
write anywhere in the colonel you can
get some custom stuff that is from the
specific to the mac which is the colonel
test part this comes from the mac design
and there is also the host rivlin work
if you have access to be sports if you
have sport and whatever you want to the
colonel in the district of microwaves in
the mac kernel which is part of it every
process is represented by the task a
task is just a container of data then
there's a there's a point to respondents
between the task and a process because
the process is
bsd process but the task is the general
container the colonel is also a task and
you can't think about that as kids you
this concept doesn't exist in other
machines if i'm not mistaken in mac OS
it exists it's the pto so more fun stuff
before snow leopard depth or there was a
feature essentially you could access the
colonel using the task for p the task
for field which is the task port gige
beans I want this Pete give me the
passport and they can access to to build
process so you just say give me the
passport for the colonel and you get a
net it you have a DC described in that
Frank article there were no steroids
because we can write to the colonel this
is the function and 2 guys I hired TT
organized the conference game in a in
Taiwan and they report this very tracing
vulnerability the processors fell tasks
and insight is also easy and when I saw
this woman really rang the bell inside
my brain and I didn't know why and
someday i was browsing this book it's
one of my books thats always it on my
desk is very stressing if you are
interested in the term in the internal
result in my class and i was browsing an
exploit the vulnerability was there
since the oak tree with nobody notice it
but it was there so insight is always
easy to after you're not saying it
everything is very clear what tomorrow
will it does is gives you access to the
colonel passport which is the same
result as the best for you this is the
function processors i passed see it
calls another function this violent as a
lot of code and essentially what it does
it goes over all tasks that are running
in into the season and returns dead part
into an array testify stuff that we're
done which is
the defines to occur I will show you
what what this means this is how you get
the passports you need to do get some
ports this is one of the reasons why you
need root access because to get the O's
part in row taxes so we feel good we can
do this and you get the colonel passport
from the first element of the array that
is returned it's dead or so it's very
easy to to get as I told you this is
your mud patch I was expecting these to
be banished at least in El comedic still
not back there knowing this page for use
my dude it's also not there I have no
idea why I hope is not patching this
they know because i was showing the
slides to them in and right there in one
infinite loop i was this is about fitted
and i presented to two times and they
say use my teens every bit as powerful
as it loads i say you've survived it is
so what is it from you because they know
what about this file because that's what
to secure Colonel define is there
because this one doesn't have any nye
ways so they had matching the bug in iOS
because they understand how powerful the
buggies in iOS because if you are then
this part it price to iOS and Joan
breaks will be much easier I try to
patch this park and there are no side
effects your Mac will work without any
problem so I don't understand why they
are not bad genes let's get to the fun
part other it spoil please what we can
do if you get the kernel corn what can
we do with this world we can allocate
internal memory we can read and we can
write and modify write whole memory i
will show you what i mean by right about
dressing in a bit we cannot change the
memory protection of kernel code and
some beta sections because they are made
in the army and we cannot execute code
because we just have access to transport
but we are from a different from a
different task so we cannot change the
pointer are directly the colonel
watch somewhere else so we need some
tricks what are some kernel protections
the level guys are really bad at
security but they implement some stuff
for slowly but they do it the kernel
code is reductive you know apples
snitches connections to bike home like
crazy and the colonel is made Reno me
but this is at page while so you can see
this is the code from the kernel that
finding the colonel is initializing it
changes the page table to reload me this
is a reason why we cannot make the code
it cannot change the deprivation because
a function and is from a higher from a
higher level and if we try to change it
cannot because the protection is
education Bible the same happens to to
battle sections they were made with only
for example before you could see the
data section is writable and you have
for example the deceased all tables and
the market are tables then you just need
to modify a pointer and you can get code
execution now they are they are real and
so you cannot detect this is called
directly these also happened in
seemingly not when I said at a sample
durability you could attack the table
because it's rideable mouse real ugly
there are also another trip they made
the table itself read-only but there was
a pointer to dead table that was
frightful so what you do is create a new
table input everything their original
you notify the pointer that you want and
then you change the pointer that points
to the table at it and the technique is
always called shadow Siskel table and it
comes from windows I think it was some
cannot remember the name but it was a
little screw tip that implemented first
piece technique most of those pointers
from the dead section is the god section
so you cannot detect any more like this
you cannot put the shadow table in his
mighty you can do the same in one every
person before they can you can
with this is the data section being very
naughty also also you have not execute
the data protection you cannot execute
code from from various the the
protection is my that page first level
is basically best practices and probably
all this stuff was introduced by white
parks and gr security because they are
the guys that did most of the innovation
and last using insecurity if you know
this low level stuff it's possible to
provide this protection because there is
a register cr0 which is the control
register which is change the back piece
wpb which is right protection if you
send that bit the tunnel will not
colonel panicky to try to write to a
rebound adventure but these rings you
can earn a problem because to build it
to change this we need to execute code
but we cannot directly execute code yet
then you are also the curb this is not
very difficult to to bypass in OS X you
have a cisco the KS an underscore info
that will give you the offset of the of
a SLR in iOS this is my this function
doesn't exist once again I don't know
why a diplomat leasing OSX you can have
infolinks which is what everyone is
paying based on to get slightly police
and you have something else there are
other techniques a reigning rope is
chapter for the book and it developed a
new technique when the book is out you
can can read about it so it's not very
difficult which easy easy things we
usually work most of the time so my goal
is to execute kernel code there already
told you about the matter problems we
can't execute code we can use the siskel
tables we cannot do that trick and the
Mavericks are older we can use the the
shadows you stable which it's very easy
to implement so for those it's not to be
problem
how much it should will like that will
attract internet the kernel extensions
you could try to attack the kernel
extensions because we have the Caroline
the kernel extensions they are also
protected they are made we normally so
it's not interesting to to attack what
is the solution and become if you come
from the good kids you know that this
means direct Colonel object manipulation
which is finding data objects in in the
term that you can't change modify that
do something that you want the goal here
is to find a writable data structure
that we can modify and then somehow it's
a code execution we can execute the
small shell tops and disable the the CR
0 protection and then we can do whatever
you want in a easy way or you can
execute more complex code which means a
full root kit from from from there I
don't have much time to think about is
the trusted vs vehicles just in future
very big introduction it is a mandatory
access control framework the ball the
project started in three BSB ever
portrait parts of it to tomorrow s and
that the project is called trust VSD
market is a subset I think we call it
recipes PSD just for for richness but
the framework that Apple part is the max
frame work of art it is the basis for OS
X and iOS sandbox for example the
gatekeeper and the code signing also use
this the latest feature ruthless in El
Capitan this is the same ruthless is
essentially global sandbox if it has an
engine a decision engine that's it I
want to write the system folder which is
protected it goes to the to the colonel
axis on the list is these authorized
write this to this place yes now and
send back the response and if you are
used to exploiting you already know that
how to exploit this because there will
be for example update
is an authorization to work the file so
attacked the update process and you
attack ruthless and / subjects but it
has many hoops available i love i really
love this framework and police posing
access to it today they say it was never
made public and now there are doing some
internal changes and they are closing
exit this is a very powerful framework
because we have many hooks in the kernel
that allow you to control a lot of
functions in the system so you can build
for example your own module 2 to control
and stop physical to mind it up for
example there's a module that if you try
to execute a swanky binary it will send
you a warning and back saying this
problem this implication wants to
execute is slightly better do you want
to allow we want to deny you want why
twist for example PS process one to
whitelist it's a warning it's some more
information I also did something to
annoy i think in guys it was the
presentation at whiskey turn I don't
like having team Excel those guys and it
was based also on this framework so it's
very powerful you should take a look I
haven't really annoying i don't really
not ample don't host this stuff because
i love this stuff so we can politics you
just in the kernel extraction beds heads
volume on it has a writable data
structures and it leads to call the
execution because it essentially a
callback system you put your whole bag
and your gold is executed under certain
conditions how can we use these to
exploit we have a new policy with a
single hook we just need 1 1 code
execution that will point to our code it
this could be the shellcode that
disables to CR 0 or it can be the food
with root contain a medley and then we
call the function that we have the hook
and that starts the root case let me
quickly go on what to do for this the
sex
we need a colonel passport because we
are writing Colonel we need to find the
slide because he will need to change
some stuff and the colonel and data
structures are somewhere so we need this
we need to compute the route concise
because we are going to copy and install
it in memory we need to move gate manner
to put the work in there or we can find
some free space for four days then we
need to copy the rootkit to kernel
memory remember we are executing from
user lines and we have you have to put
somehow the coding in the colonel then
we need to change memory protections
because if we locate the memory is not
executable pi by default then we need to
fix the simple service external signals
and this is the funniest part or the
more interesting part at least this one
because we don't we are by tracing the
colonel linker so we need to do
implement basically implement our own
liquor let me install a new recipe
policy and execute the hook to start and
you probably want to clean up so the
forensics guys don't know what's what's
happening there and I line what the
forensics guys I'm not sure if useful
agility for for a while I was playing a
little you guys because they have an
assumption they think that they can find
everything because it's a memory and I
show them a few times our few more
abilities on that stuff they think they
will not find the colonel good kids with
their software so don't trust and your
tools I did talk about that just rest
your tools always be suspicious about
that especially if you are trying to
change route kids remember I'm running
on that on a level problem lower than
your tools so i can men employed all
your tools so undress them and use them
but be very suspicious about the spoons
and this is the hope is all ready to
show you to get the colonel test port
plussing difficult and this is the code
to get a slide using that function the K
has info this is basically inline
assembly you can import the function is
not very difficult math nothing very
type of it
to compute the rookies sighs there is a
small trick usually the site is
different from the size on memory
because alignment recent so if you want
to compute the brute keys because we are
in our memory we need the memory the
memory version so it's basically used
fuel that gives you the size on memory
and hot on disk because if they are
different you are going to get round to
locate Colonel memory there is a
function the map you will see what
functions bottles functions Mac on the
colonel this is our function that is
usually the passport that deal with the
mac you can mark layer or our max traps
especially what we need we need memory
somewhere in the colonel you don't get
because we are controlling a pointer we
are not playing with offset so we have
64 bits a absolute address so we can we
just need memory somewhere you use the
function the colonel part you see then
the first parameter is the past is the
past sports you can use this function
for example to inject coffee to any
program as long you are support offense
that's the process you can do whatever
you want and then we put size and and
everything else there are some problems
with is because if you do if you use
these function like this and for example
if you try to locate 100k of memory
these you press your system what happens
is that the whole memory is not wired
why would mean that non wired memory it
can be pushed out to this even from the
colonel attempt and what I memory is
obvious they're physically for example
the colonel grunting in wider memory
because if you had a page out or a
fishing on the colonel you could risk
running the pressure running the
pressure to to the to the Beijing system
to this and then there is not no co2 to
the deck so this is the reason why
weather is fair no panic because the
colonel do not copy everything when you
copy it says it wise to each other I
copied everything
everything is not there to try to you
sometimes line into Carla parents if you
are trying to execute sudden just a
small shell code this is not for example
of page is cool enough for some stuff
for K is is too much you get it set at
64 K it was too much but for Kate and
sometimes it's more than enough shell
code so the result these thresholds what
is the solution the solution is very
easy you just need to make bets memory
wire there's a kernel function you're
telling this piece of memory that I
located is wired do not crash out ever
it has a small tree first you need to
set the memory protection so first you
say these memories going to be
executable we try to move if you need
and then you to change the wire stage
with dysfunctional if you try to do
otherwise you will get this function
giving the measure and you don't know
why I spend some time these and then I
translators just the trick to copy the
rootkit another my function right you
tell if I won't write these that these
data to this process that is address we
already of the price we know where the
good kid is because we located the
memory so it's medically hmmm copy in
the kernel using the max function same
for changing many protections you have a
function called my vm protect you
probably want to fix for example beta
areas to not be executable this is once
again to avoid forensics because if you
start saying if you are changing
something at you see for example what's
memory that is breathe printable and
executable this is very suspicious so
you want to put changes as normal as
possible once again use the beautiful
memory size field and because alignment
reasons and this is what you will locate
it to fix external signals the concern
is Colonel aslr the kernel code must be
the body positioning panel
so you don't need to change the offset
and everything in the kernel enduring
the curve accidental call them colonel
is based on upset so a function is
called without an offset so you can put
the colonel anywhere you want the
offsets say always the same so there is
no problem with this what we need to
worry about these days symbols this is
the equivalent in is rent for a library
usually you link and see if you are
doing for linux or any unique system for
example stp be able to get functions
system functions you do the same in the
kernel there are for example string
functions that you can access and memory
location function design and so on
because we are by pressing we are doing
we don't use the linker we are talking
directly to the colonel week our own
Colonel this is very complicated maybe I
was like yes this is going to take me a
lot of work and I don't want to write
linker myself but in the end it's very
easy well all information you have
rotation tables these are these are the
same tables that the linker the colonel
incurred uses it needs to know what
needs to be fix it you have the same
information in all our other formats be
as the same information else as
information you can find these
information in those two comments then I
dynamics in time it's in tap it's there
the location where it is table is all
the symbols that need to be fixed in and
so on complexity and there are 10
different types of publications and you
can start restarting okay this is why
you need a lot of work but in reality
there are only two bit that you between
into to face one is a relative
addressing this is if you know if you
are used to researching stuff this is
basically 32 bits offset to somewhere
and using the current instruction
pointer so the log says embed equate the
instruction pointer address was the
instruction
sighs end up sides minus or plus the
null set and you also have some
relocation of which are actual two
dresses these are easy because we just
need to cite point to this address and
that's it I know this because I get the
small agility to go to all kernel
extensions and get the number of symbols
and I know only those two types are used
and there are two two and two types
external which are the singles data data
linker does and local local are strings
for example that you I 1-yard code if
you f and some other local kernel
extensions symbols for example the stack
and stop functions they are theirs so
this is not very complicated to to do
this is some code there locates and the
tables then finds the symbols to which
they could respond to then try to solve
the current symbol to locate the target
signal for example I want to do Mary
copy I need to find where did my copies
in the relocation them I need to find
where the map copy function is
implemented the colonel and then you
just need to fix the offset yourself
this is what the linker does when is
thinking it's very waving this work this
is a little code I like these on purpose
it does about because offsets here is a
32 bits and interior and there is no
guarantee that these all set will be
nuts it can also flow and it will point
tool to somewhere else written for this
is that we are implicating the Tyrell
somewhere else in the colonel so we get
current memory so we are no guarantee
that's the address where it is in 32
bits away from from the colonel and this
is an interior signed integer so we have
off of the space half of log set unless
this year is just as worried what we can
do is using trampoline for example you
can put junk from death from the
characterization to some space you
locate when you kill the colonel
session we will cater sprays for for an
island that is executable you jump there
and from there you can use an absolute
address because you have enough space
and jump anywhere you want so we are
basically in directing the flow of a
problem so it's not very difficult to
implement it's a very easy way to work
around the problem these are the actual
defects these are very easy you find a
single where the similes and we put the
whole offset the whole address and
deliveries to process and these are
related to the to the local it's
essentially there the local ones are
always absent addresses so they are even
easier to an end to things so fix to
build your own linker it takes like what
200 lines of C so as you see it's very
simple it appeared a very complex
problem with inning or something that
you need to spend some time but in the
end it's really easy to build so out of
line interesa PSD ah I will not go to
how this essentially there is a very
important short the one which is a
global variable that contains the
information but first BSB as the number
of policies that executes and all the
policies that that are within the system
this is the structure for for each
policy this is an array that contains
all the policies and this is the policy
configuration for example we can see the
name and full name and this is one
contains a function pointers are the
hooks and this point to another starter
which is a really big structure with all
the hoops available in the system what
you do you register call back you say I
want to for example to to get a hook
that's every time the access its
function is executed I want to get the
call back so we put the function pointer
that to be our function that will
process please and
Yahweh go about this because it's which
is basically you do yourself the word
you install disruptors install a new
policy and inside the pointers in that
way there's a something to facilitate
your work which is the rain is already
okay so we don't need to allocate memory
they pray locator right with it i think
it's 256 or 512 entries so you just find
a slot there we put there and at it then
to start your model which is what we are
going to use to get code execution you
just increase inside a system there's
another module and then the system will
go to the least and see okay this one's
to to get a comeback ever sent a call
back that's when we start with roofies
in our example i hope this function the
task for people because it's very easy
very simple you just call a keep an on
Pete you can use the big one which is
munchie-t which is equivalent to in it
in windows so you know that process is
always there you call it and their end
you probably want to do add some kind of
fuse so your code is not executed for
example if father hole is an object if
you get your route get executed so you
just need to execute once you to fuse
there and that's it then you want to
clean up all the stuff you don't want to
leave a trace that you use the trusted
be policy so we decrease the Houston I'm
the number of loaded policies there's no
problem in doing this and runtime and
then you remove all the memory that you
located and how that stuff you just
leave the Woodley's in memory I'm sure
okay this is the one of the portions I
content voters voters the person that
uses this way of doing this version also
as the the google exploit this one at
this version of that one lithium is
still vulnerable for to this so i'm
going to execute these feral expansion
valve Allah controlling our coke quick
this is a very cheap this is the colonel
extension that I that I built for anti
anti debugging so some processes there
but involving this will do NT NT
debugging for for it so I'm going to
connect to betray my attention okay
selected and let me show you okay gtv
this this is a sample code that is anti
debug and running and the debugger is
found so I enabled the anti debugging
run again nothing but you're fine so
it's running I wanted code from from a
normal user using the google exploits
we'd be smaller and i can show you there
is not mean that in the slaves nothing
even the turtle was the colonel
accession isn't old using the system
stuff was all the directly with a strict
and let me show you the last three and
because we are living the buffer we need
to put get whatever we can for a temple
over the remote good case okay and here
it is this came from my side this is a
reason why it's funny 11 p.m. because i
don't know if you can't hide and i will
be demo and getting hacked myself so the
variable ford is
it's just as a printf view nothing
complicated came from my website so for
example you can you can have the loader
and you can have the payload on remote
website then you can clean up and
forensics cannot get probably not much
information from from the good kids so
it's the technique is variable because
it's all those allows you to do this
kind of stuff to next technique you
click on front wheels and sorry for your
references to windows I used to work
with players a lot and there is to be
the device which allows you to access
the kernel memory directly it's
something that is closed now also the
dev / man is also closed or it's
protected because essentially you could
act as kernel memory directly from that
defines these option exists in Mac OS
it's not activated by default because
it's so powerful you can enable it for
example for testing and debugging you
just need to go to that configuration or
to any fear am setting and said Kim n
equals 1 i'm going to do City metrics is
Colonel extension ample HW access
Colonel expansion it allows you to write
access physical memory this is the trade
physical memory so you can read and
write up to 64 bits of memory you don't
have a full control so you have to send
requests for 64 bits it takes a while
but it does this when I saw these i
would like a thank you yes baby
once again i saw this this the same
implemented in a keen Tosh forum which
is running mic mac OS e in normal
computer hardware and then tonight ok
yeah but because the guy was complaining
know this can crash the system and a la
la la and do you immediately so i was
developing the first technique and my
break connecting finally a lot i start
to use this one
you say because I have the core
techniques and maybe I can use this this
feature to do the same virus diseases
the reasons why they went to different
work there was a debugging framework
shot it was a canal extension they
convert it to a private framework
because these this these debugging tools
need to connect the colonel they
probably created this connection
extension because it's not missing I can
find in the system that uses this what
we can move with this corona extension
or this feature we can read and write
every single beat available the almost
understand why it's there and we can my
pants all the read-only protections that
I've shown you because we are accessing
the physical memory so vegetables
protection doesn't matter we cannot
allocate memory we cannot change memory
protections and we cannot again once
again execute code directly till there
are some restrictions once again and we
need to bypass this is how to use the
function where you bypass is very zzz
service to send their only two
structures involved that request for in
it out if you want with you say i want
to read up to 64 bits and I want to read
from this address and then you get the
contents in the pub start this by Sigma
0 is to read the function is executed
then again you can forget that you can
copy the data if you are willing to
write the more necessary just
essentially you give you copy data that
you that you want to do i get the
structure and doubt you get it went ok
or not other it's flightless what we
need again the same steps we need to
copy what kid calls me to fix of
locations that that's the easy part now
I mean we need to start the good kids
what are the problems with this we
decision we need to find memory because
we cannot allocate memory as a Tully we
can find free space on
honestly for example the colonel Heather
usually it's not guaranteed but there is
usually spice from the header to the
first place where I put where cookies
there's usually some alignment space
which is essentially 000 ever since you
that memory is executable so if you find
space there you can use it for for
executing stuff good intentions they
have also alignment spice we can try to
put there you can / white kernel
functions for example what what the
morning shelter was doing the Gator gets
a function thank you for example NFS
stuff if you are attacking a target that
you know they are not using an offense
and if s is default on my colonel so you
just write that stuff and it are you
going to locate memory via shell code
essentially you just need a few bites
for the shellcode allocate memory and
then you do whatever you want good
execution it's easier ear because TV we
can buy protections we can use the
fiscal balance you can go very complex
and use the same trusted vsb you cannot
hope the kernel function because we can
write anywhere so it can be very
creative about it sometimes find the you
want to find the amount of available
memory because we have prior to reads
from the from the colonel we need to
boot for some stuff so you don't you
don't want to go out of bounds because
if you go what other funds here it's a
kernel panic right away you need to find
where the colonel isn't useful number
and if you can do the routine size rice
and everything else and I decided to
attack at cisco table because it's the
easiest method there's no point is
complicating it's very easy to find the
table there are many places that are
free you use one of the three places you
know the system remember you called X is
calm and is it and then you call that
Cisco and start to get this is the same
stuff so easy to find the the tournament
system early there is a function for for
that and it's possible to told you it
wasn't real every bit in GMS and there
are two solutions 14 there's a smart
solution and there's a brute force
solution the smart solution is
exploiting a subway of the car when in
your system starts there's nothing in
memory so the colonel is put there in
memory and then it's sleep somewhere
depending on the offset so what you can
do you can read the dress where the
colonel is from to this that is the
original address on the system then
you're the slide so we know where the
colonel is in virtual memory what you
can do you clear the highest 32 bit
because of physical memory you have 32
bits there and you know what is very
easy trick to get the physical location
you can use the brute force solution
which is start from zero go to to the
amount of system and find where the
perilous these winter problem was right
and remember the time yeah this works on
TBN first time I were put on a physical
machine and there is a reason of course
you have machines exceptions which is
you have a lot of stuff devices and
everything that is mapped on physical
memory unusual you're very lower oil
prices so if you try to read from that
stuff Colonel back this is the reason
why you cannot do this in Kitty paw
machine these are some drinks that left
by biases and 12 to two people this is
what I told me the language space
between the text which contains also the
headers and the data segments you can
put stuff there for example in May
braids it's not enough you cannot put a
rootkit there for good kids and just
might at least have that version 2.0
there is enough funds you can come to a
good hitter so it depends usually my
solution or my best
put a small shellcode colgate memory and
put everything there just a warning that
night sessions are not wired as I told
you 32 p.m. we will get pinched folds if
you want to use a shellcode to this k
mama lupe it's for country which I'll
get to continue you can use the normal
memory allocation but probably those
function is that it's not guaranteed
that Vista memory it will be continuous
so you will need to find this piece of
man where each page will be located this
is too much work there is a function
that can tease you to give you physical
memory that is continue so why
complicate what canvassing this is a
shuttle we go there and look but in
Thailand as a stylist it's like Twitter
bite or something the shellcode battle
cage vortex memory and when yes
everything that you need to do good kids
there I'm saying find ok fun this is
called table and you just there are some
signatures for example you know where a
certain function is because you can read
the colonel from the disk you know for
the cisco f will be located at this
address you just need to go to all the
tournament fight workpiece addresses and
you know where this is table is and this
is how we start the book is just on the
cisco that you hooked and that's it and
my bestie just once singing point detail
if you want to execute code and
multi-part CPUs essentially everything
and you is multi board we have a lot of
course various dysfunction NV ren days
it was presented by nima Frank article
it guarantees you execution on 12 cores
of the machine so for example if you are
using the trick to visit cr0 register
you need to guarantee that execution is
happens on all the course because this
this is racism is per core so for
example it is about these not one car
that part is
okay but then another car price to
execute get cold kernel panic because
dead car as a protection enabled so this
is just a very small let me put another
demo very weakly so these are the mighty
that was released this week and time
plot for and this is the second portion
okay once again the same put it by Road
so it's for begging you can see takes a
lot more time because it because of the
64 bits maximum request so we need to
send a lot of requests exchanging the
colonel everything else and okay if I
it's there that was executed with using
these three so we can do the same would
keep bypassing all the protections that
there are against this compulsions
hopefully i will convince you that or FX
cuties don't tell anyone crap total brat
there's the funny thing about this as i
told you i presented this first thing in
japan and months ago or something i got
feedback and the first comment that they
sent me was from an attendee fi no web
will be broken but it's not nice to call
able to find that i love this quote
because i don't know what what was the
translation to japanese punk wasn't that
funny but because the guy was really
japanese that will be promotions I
hopefully this your you are in these
days the colonel extension code signing
as it is is useless because it's running
on on on reign three if they don't put
on rings the bell rings you it's not
Allah there is no pointing doing
don't trust it as a security measure
there are some plots people telling case
there is Colonel extension co-signing
it's a security feature dr. soon because
it's useless and my question whoever
when I was everything teacher
dead why's it was even exist because if
you are designing something to protect
at least give it requires some problems
that that I shall be awarded a shortly
there is no issue product advertised
policy for example Apple releases
patches for maple correos mighty doesn't
release the veggies except matches for
matrix so even though I still run this
laptop running kills my food on my plate
that stuff is to my friends I don't know
for example they release a fiery passion
for Lyman which is a radio version but
they don't release security patches so
we don't know at least windows you know
and Microsoft's told you windows XP it's
that unless you pay 20 million light
than 80 to the US but this is there an
ordinance to know there will be no
matches for for this essentially you
either upgrade or you more vulnerable
and even if you want bring your suit on
rule because I end up in touch for a few
Apple saw the presentation so it's it's
great this is my personal fight I tell
them this a lot your strategy is
essentially reactive and not proactive
and you know this why because I really
feel day on the e-file aight three or
four weeks ago and that will this be
very surprisingly to me they release the
patch today if I back so finally and
they released to pop top all machines
for example final five year old machines
it really is the bed and then they don't
do this while it is my personal opinion
is that they had bad publicity because
that's the point everywhere they don't
like publicity and so they react to the
issues there and they are not proactive
on that they try to be proactive for
example they kill to protest but at
least the system like these
now is a joke because we for example
you've attached to the k xt process you
patch it these two words are still work
so I don't know what they are doing if
you want to look at the gold Barry it's
a real one the pita and go there there's
tons of code blue code is very well
commented people working on the SEC and
yes it's amazing one your slides
everything is very commented what I
don't put it I don't lose comments i
like to do it because I never know what
a week before while is changing stuff so
it's good comments this is my blog it's
very easy to memorize part is good you
are makita and I feel free to email me
if you have any doubts or if you have
any issue and there is a small community
on freenode OSX r e if you have any
problem with the max or or if you are
the first hangover hanging stuff come
there you have people there whether non
guys from the mac OS machine feel free
to come there and feel free to put your
problems okay