my name is Jackson how was the evil
mastermind behind the other CD f's
how many cuts xx you okay
I don't know how many people that finish
knishes set seven
okay not that I miss and reduce the
resolution of the CPF I'm going to to
stop this because I don't have much time
so basically this is I made a storyline
behind this basically these sites is a
organization that fights sorry
so we are Liberation's
Googlebot that we're trying to sit down
I'm not going
sorry why not forever but this step was
made up of four exercises for challenges
and okay I'm going to start with really
simple but I think a lot of people that
start on here but I'm going to show you
that it's not that hard because I'm
going to start okay so everyone knows
this part right so this is basic 64 this
is really simple you could do this with
any jeweler that you you want it cure
you anything okay
so everybody got to this part right I
know that this is a very common encoding
and I'm talking on the super revolution
well it's hot encryption or anything
which is an encoding so if we see here
we have just capital letters and equals
so if we didn't know what what it was
because just search on Google
I'm coding betting people's if you see
the first results you will see that that
meant many up so the first result is
actually advice 32 article where we see
an example that uses three equals s P so
from this point we just need to decode
meed color online for base 32 I think
want to make okay so this is a little we
see that this is a decimal and we see
our positions on the numbers so when
could assume that this was just a ski or
that I tried if you can see it but I'm
crossing meet you yes
so this was the first flight okay and
I'm going to prove to you that this is
so this is our a precision
EMP cannon that we are now we are
requesting our supply to strike to
manager and we take you out and that's
it this is a this was the first
challenge second under the player I
sleep with some that even means on the
titles and you will notice that
specifically on the third the third
challenge but this this is what I get
it's just an image and we have to figure
out what's in here in this image so the
first thing that I normally do in this
kind of exercises is these staggered X
because it's a very nice tool to analyze
images and SEC the decks will tell us
that there is actually some some like
that
appended to the end of file
so one could also use a tool called
people and what will also help that
there is as if perfect encrypted zip
file at the end of the of this image so
from this point to NZ the path so I'm
hoping the file to a specific section
and then zip it it's asking us for a
password
and so we need password
I'm showing you that there's actually
better so right now we and the password
must be hidden somewhere as having being
12 because it's the only thing that that
they give you so which spits out lots of
information about the new about the
image and mr. interesting comments you
see that it's kind of strange so I'm
going to show you you can also see this
information on Windows when we do this
is really simple you should set to go to
properties on the details and it's right
there the comments again you could you
could not enter fight that this is just
a ski and an X so what I'm going to do
is to rebuild it again you're honest I
miss apart here and the password is
first strike elite speed mode so we have
not the contents of the seizure of the
deep inside image and there we have it
we have the node ID incited now we just
need to get and we get flight
pretty simple again I'm gonna just get
our subway and it's firing Indian people
eyes so we've got two dollars now and
we're going to the third challenge this
this challenge was interesting the
people were really great so basically
what I'm saying here is that we
intercepted some packages some packets
so I give you a link to a PDF file I'm
going to download it and open it on fire
sir you could also use network miner or
any other tool that over speaker I'm
using my chart this is where things get
complicated
I try to do this as simple as possible
so in my opinion it would be very
creative creative in this one so let me
just pause for a second because this
pcap well as I actually expected this
from a malware malware analysis on the
Internet
what I did was to strip out foliage
detecting and I injected my my my my
knee HTTP traffic that I did on my pants
but some other data which was not HTTP
and a lot of people were losing time on
that because it's actually real traffic
that was so we that was an Gmail account
with the best word
but the thing is is it was supposed to
be simple right so I think with me I'm
just so what we have here and we see
here that basically it's like a page
that will directs two times and give us
some hints that to follow the points
treatments
it's the encrypted key so here we see
that the body is each way to redirect
the parts of bevel as you see here is
the first part of three two part three I
think this was kind of logical so I
think the first step here is to
concatenate everything this is what I'm
doing here and everything so for some of
you would look at this and right away
you will see immediately what it was for
for those of you who don't know it but
for those of you we didn't know what
this is the title actually add even and
you'll see whether why the title is
wired language so terrible or where
language and with such are Google for
wire language and notice that google
corrects you in suggest that it's clear
language human memories we want like
digital stuff so so good
you're evil
yeah why computer languages I guess
that's what we are talking about right
here so any one of these links will show
you right away what it was
so I'm going to open the second one from
we bet which is very trustworthy source
so we're going to scroll down a bit and
there are examples for each each weird
language and so let's scroll down any
pointers and they are all too fat and
okay so right away we will see this 25
so what we need now is just to decode
this using a bring our encrypted text
and there we have it to be as in alladhi
step once again I'm going to put this on
our inspector
I think this just a lot of fun great
okay challenge was a very simple reverse
challenge not anything near remotely
like Marco do maybe for next year is a
new 32
we found the ports on a machine that
allows us to download the botnet client
so I don't love these clients and I'm
going to open it for you
of course it study run this without any
problems because it's a malware client
asking us for encryption efforts
I don't know what the password is I'm
going to put something and it says about
for a checkup so one thing that you
could do was to okay maybe it's asking
us for a password
but then aa B will be outputted by the
way so one could think that's okay let's
search for Strings and this is
executable minus n 19 which is the size
of the anomaly if you if you think its
8:03 16 plus 3 but if you there is no
nobody here that's because I have
encrypted it it's using a short version
so you will never you will never just by
strings using strings on this tiny bit
ago so we will do a little bit of
reverse engineering and I'm going to
show you a few
I'm just want to open my immunity I mean
crystal at once I can see so I'm going
to get to the entry point and then I'm
going to scroll down
okay so we'll just hold on of it's on
the to get the interesting stuff we
already know that the program is asking
as far as people encryption pepper so
here we'll we'll find the string and I
really here we see that the program is
asking us for a password and now we see
the good stuff here so if this if you
notice here is a lot between getting an
account or password accepted so a simple
way to would you check this would be to
find reference for this password
accepted line so we see that immunity
gave us that the reference is this
channel so it's just it's not 0 so if
you reach here I'm going to put a
breakpoint here and eventually the the
code will reach this parts and make the
validations of the best work some will
put something which is not a pestle
obviously so we have seen here that
immunity is telling us it's it's a
breakpoint and is having its that the
job is will not be taking so we want to
take this jump because we are we want to
go to back password
not spell buster so this is really
simple because oh yeah by the way DX is
zero miss comparing to zero so that's
why it's it's not jumping because it
will jump
only if it's not zero so what we can do
here is very busy it's just we see
switched jumping from zero we jump it
and this was one of the many solutions
because I thought that there are some
people that changed the beats of the fly
but bears on the beets or of ax Cupid go
go
lots of ways here I switch to 74 which
is to jump with people and now we see
that the immunity is telling is that the
champ will be taken so right now I'm
going to do a step over and actually see
the cub jumping to the password accepted
and I rehab it's now I'm going to run
and the program will decrypt the
password and if it's done on ID I'm
going to move to put this on a notepad
so you can see it and there you have it
we find the less flag and the main
command Apple ID
it was simple and this was the final
exercise any of you could reach here you
will see this
we have the fried servants and you will
be rewarded by the agreement okay this
is it guys I hope you enjoyed this