we have a great panel of guests today
with us to discuss these
especially within the context of the
next budget MFF also in plans for the
invest you financing structures the some
of our panelists actually directly will
help to manage in the future which
clearly will seek to leverage billions
in funds to finance projects across the
EU over the coming years so maybe I just
briefly introduce our panelists we have
Pablo Chavez who's immediately to my
left he's the vice president for global
public policy and government relations
at Google cloud he obviously has a big
stake in what happens to the Digital
Agenda in central Eastern Europe and I'm
sure can tell us about some interesting
studies and figures on what is needed
and the scale of the investment needed
in the future
we also have Shemesh Tov a sense key
who's a member of the management board
at BG k Bank in Warsaw it's a major
player in the management of the
impressed
EU fund in the future as well so he'll
have lots to talk about on that we also
have Vasily Hudak who's vice-president
of the European Investment Bank he
obviously has a great macro
understanding of not just transport and
ajeeb it just general infrastructure
financing generally and finally tomash
Bernath who works for the Hungarian
Development Bank who will also have a
big voice in how invest you funds are
mobilised in the future so gentlemen
thank you very much for joining us here
today for this discussion maybe I will
kick off by posing one simple question
to you and letting you riff on this for
a minute or two starting with you public
candid slow economy or candy digital
economy provide a new engine for growth
in central Eastern Europe and how can I
do this terrific well first of all thank
you very much for including Google on
this panel
you mentioned Big Ideas I also have very
big ears and they feel bigger with these
these things I don't know if you can
tell that they're pushing them out a
little bit self-conscious we are very
very bullish on the on the digital
economy in Central and Eastern Europe at
Google and from the specific perspective
that I that I focus on mostly which is
Google cloud
we are really looking at the region as
as a as potentially embracing new
technologies including artificial
intelligence within artificial
intelligence machine learning and and
and using that in order to bolster both
purely digital businesses but as well as
well as businesses that are in other
industries so agriculture manufacturing
and so forth all of them can really
benefit from digital transformation and
so when we've been looking at Central
and Eastern Europe we have this idea
that all of the growth that's happened
over the last several years we believe
that it will continue but we believe
also that it can be tremendously
enhanced by focusing on on digital and
in order to to maybe put a little bit of
rigor and analysis behind that that
belief we supported a study that is in
process right now by McKinsey and we
have some representatives from McKinsey
and in the room that is really focused
on the Cee region as the region of
challenging on the digital front
basically a region of digital
challengers and what we mean by that is
basically that as we see in labor color
and other factors that have that have
driven the regional economy today we
believe that that by infusing the
existing factors with digital we believe
that that can actually lead to
significant economic growth one of the
stats that came out of the McKinsey
study which by the way will be made
available later this month I think we
have a summary of an executive summary
about here in the room that one of my
colleagues can give you if you are
interested in in it
by 2025 we the the study indicates that
we could create about two hundred
billion two hundred two hundred billion
euros in GDP in the region that's the
equivalent of is essentially shakyas
economy or perhaps Portugal's economy
that's in the edition of that kind of
economic development in the region
through digital and more than happy to
talk a little bit about how we could
accomplish that but as an overview and
as a highlight that is what the report
indicates and and and it is one of the
reasons why we are
again tremendously bullish about this
region we really think that it is a
massive driver of economic growth
through digital both in Europe and
throughout the world
thanks Anne and Vasily maybe you can
also add in what exactly the eiv is
doing in his sphere if he's doing enough
I'll start as you mentioned it's more
macro macro view from the IB perspective
from European Luxembourg say they are
facing some really important gaps gaps
in terms of economic development and
structural gaps in the Indian economy I
have some numbers because I think
numbers they say quite a lot we did a
research research and we estimated that
the 27 because we are looking at 2019
you without you okay unfortunately but
that's that's the reality we estimate
that the so-called investment gap in 27
is around 400 billion euro this is 400
billion per year of investment which is
needed in different sectors of economy
just to be able to catch up with the
United States and with the growing parts
of the global economy and this includes
for example 155 billion to upgrade
energy networks 450 billion to transport
networks 50 billion for broadband data
center capacity and cyber security some
billion for climate change investments
and an additional and this is important
number 110 billion a year needs to be
invested in R&D just to again catch up
with the level of the investments in the
United States and China so the numbers
are huge also if you look at the
situation today with the technology
companies and my colleagues they have
interesting thing if you look at the
main technology companies which are
listed globally on the global stock
exchanges you have the big US group of
technology companies
so-called FAA and G's which is basically
Facebook Amazon Apple Netflix and our
Google Google friends and under half of
it and then you have in China its
so-called B 80s
Baidu Alibaba and $0.10
so these are world's largest firms and
their combined stock market
capitalization is around four trillion
US dollars which is a fifth of the u.s.
GDP and if you look at the European side
the highest valued European tech company
which is sa P is only the world's 60s
most valued tech company so you see a
huge discrepancy in terms of the
investment on the public side into
innovation into technology but also a
gap which is then reflected on the
private sector side where we see that
the technological and European
technological leaders are falling behind
now the question is what do we do about
that and how do we address this issue
also in Central Europe we believe that
one element has to be done is to push
more investments into this area
di b is one of the leaders at the
European level for example last year in
2017 where our level of investment
immunise was around 80 billion euro we
invested 14 billion into innovation type
of projects so it's quite a lot of money
which is going into the into the
European companies and European public
public sector projects which have strong
innovation element also we are managing
as you may know under the Younger plan
there is the European fund for strategic
investments which is pushing money into
more risky projects because they can
they can utilize so-called guarantee
provided by the local European budget
and AIB I'm glad that Gordon by now is
here who is actually a member of the
investment committee which is
independent of the ID and decides on the
allocation of the of the guarantees for
individual projects but I think in
Central Europe there are activities
which we are trying to promote and which
we believe bring will bring more
innovation and digitization into economy
one such area where we are working
closely for example is the Development
Bank's and we stammers and connect this
is the area of smart cities and smart
regions so basically how do you bring
technology and connect local technology
companies with local development with
local mayors with local cities and
regions
and creating this kind of bottom-up
innovation drive which I believe is very
important but also basically building on
the traditional economies which we have
in this countries like in so lucky it's
very much the car industry and yesterday
we had the launch of what we call Slovak
battery alliance which is also very how
to bring more innovation into
traditional sectors of economy but make
made them make them more very edit and
important from the region maybe lastly I
want to mention is that with all these
money all these efforts we cannot move
much further if we don't connect with
education and all our surveys show that
another important gap which is not so
much financial but of course connected
to money is the gap in skills of the
labour force and unfortunately our
schools universities are still producing
students who are to large degree not
relevant for the for the needs of the
modern digital market economy so I think
this is important issue which we also
have to address thank you maybe if I
could just an established if you've had
the top-down view if you like from
Luxembourg the the big macro if you walk
in a National Development Bank do to
foster digitalization well to start out
thanks for the question I was about to
quote the same McKinsey study for two
reasons I'm a bit partial to the firm
first of all I used to work there but
second I actually think that you know
going beyond the first layer of things
is always a good idea and the digital
economy I really think we should go
beyond the very first layer and just
call it you know digital and that's it
rather three
I would I would rather propose three
kinds of differentiation one is which I
understand comes out from your study is
that well if you compare well we always
talk about the east-west divide in these
kind of things but if you actually
compare the GDP produced by digital
economy in the top five the biggest
Western European economies windows in
the centre in Eastern European part of
the world then you find that actually
bigger share a bigger share is produced
at the GDP in the C countries than in
the top five ones actually 6.5 percent
compared to five so not a huge
difference
actually larger barn where you really
find the legging is compared to the
frontrunner compared to countries like
Denmark or the Netherlands where 1012
even more percent of the GDP is already
due to the digital economy so there is
this kind of differentiation that we
have to keep in mind this partially
comes from leapfrogging
some of our economies actually started
to develop things after some developed
countries already developed them think
of one very specific and easy example
tall boots on motorways whoever drives
on the motorway in France Italy has to
stop or at least slow down very much at
those boots is now for example in
Hungary it's totally digital you don't
even have stickers anymore
it's fully digitalized because we
actually started to build motorways of
current quality later than anybody did
and in France or Italy so there is a
reason why this is a bit differentiated
then the other thing where it's
differentiated is well across Central
and Eastern Europe and there I have to
be a bit self-critical about Hungary for
example in each government we are very
much lagging behind the best ones eyes
Estonia and this is one of the things
that we want to concentrate on now and
in the coming years and the third level
of differentiation would be across
industries and I think that there it's
really important and that's where a
development bank can come in and their
investment gaps can be identified to
realize that well when you talk about
digital mostly you have things in mind
which you personally always use like
digital banking however maybe the
biggest opportunities are in areas such
as agriculture or healthcare or actually
as I said E government and we would like
to actually find where these biggest
opportunities are in Hungary and in
Central and Eastern Europe thank you
Shammi Slava well what is the view from
Warsaw on these issues
welcome everybody thanks for letting me
present the perspective of Poland and
and educate on the initiative our
perspective
is very much focused on fostering the
cooperation in this central Eastern
European region and as far as the
direction of the investment that
president
Hudak mentioned the energy
infrastructure transportation we fully
in line with that but we think that
where the biggest gap is is in the
Central European region were during the
second half of the 20th century we had a
big slowdown in the development and now
we need to catch up and and close the
gaps especially in the transportation
and an infrastructure going from north
to south or south to north
we have firmly well-developed east-west
the infrastructure as far as the the
energy and and and transportation it
goes but we also need to enable better
cooperation between the northern
countries in our region and the southern
countries that will link the those sub
regions effectively even though this is
the beginning we already have many
initiatives that are at least named
sometimes better designed like the a
carpaccio for example or the constant
saw the ice railroad thank you
thank you very much in and that actually
perfectly brought us on to what I wanted
to talk about next which was to open up
a little bit of a more fluid debate on
where money should go exactly what kind
of projects should be invested in of
course you mentioned of course via
capaci also energy links the LNG
terminals in
Poland and Croatian connecting them with
pipelines but I wonder on the digital
side to start off Pablo where do you
think money is needed most is it in
maybe smaller municipal projects is it
in improving cellular connection in
local areas where urgently needs money
to fostered utilization and guys do feel
free to jump in and interrupt each other
and fight a little bit to make it
exciting if well I would leave to the
experts too to give a sense of where you
know government money and other sources
of financing should should go you know
perhaps the the perspective that I could
add to this would be just to highlight a
couple of points that have been
previously made certainly education is
is critical and this is an issue that we
see globally it is you know it's not
simply the idea of improving education
but rather aligning education with the
needs of businesses both digital and
non-digital focusing significantly more
on skills you know one debate that that
I've been involved in and very very
familiar with in the United States is
this question about degrees versus
skills and whether you know a bachelor's
degree in political science is worth as
much or more or less than skills in
being able to program in a particular
language so so education focused perhaps
more on skills and perhaps more on the
needs of employers that we can find out
through data and entry tools in
connecting educational institutions to
employers that is an area perhaps of
investment secondly and this has been a
common theme at this conference
entrepreneurship there the investment in
entrepreneurship which might sound a
little bit strange but there is a way to
to promote that through educational
institutions through government you know
and more broadly through through society
one it's tremendously interesting
example that the that I've become aware
of here in Slovakia is the is there's a
company called Expo neo
Expo Nia's is is a startups digital
startup it's it's based in Bratislava it
is
essentially a micro multinational it has
offices throughout the world it's
supporting companies throughout the
world and it is really a company that
that is that is founded by a couple of
individuals who decided that they did
not want to work for the large companies
they wanted to build their own company
but they were very much driven by the
fact that they had digital skills and
the fact that they were that they were
very much entrepreneurs the third area
of investment and perhaps it's on
investment in perhaps it's more a point
of cooperation as you were saying before
is is for for the governments of Central
and Eastern Europe to unite around these
themes you know really there is an
opportunity you know when you think
about scale and you think about
platforms you have scale and you have
platform a platform here and in in the
region somebody mentioned before that if
you brought all the economies of Central
and Eastern Europe together you'd have
the twelfth largest economy in the world
what that is that is scale and and for
governments in the region to really kind
of think about how to perhaps
collaborate and cooperate more perhaps
around these issues of entrepreneurship
and education as well as enhancing a
true digital single market and other
policy areas that could also be an area
for for investment and in cooperation
thank you and Russell if this is
something that I think you brought up in
your introduction was the issue of
Education and research around this of
course the e the investi you program
would also focus money towards these
kind of initiatives but what is
happening now and how easy is it
directly fund education projects from
the EIB level I think when you look at
the correlation between the European
level and the national level in the
India we have to take into account that
the EU budget is only one percent of the
total GDP so it's not only small and
it's about two percent of the of the
public spending in the European Union so
really the main focus in the EU has to
be on the on the national public finance
and national national budgets of course
the European level of financing and the
EU budget can provide some some type of
incentives in the sectors which are
really
and then but also you bring kind of
European additional value into the into
the financing I think that overall and
as I mentioned the priorities on the
national level I think the government's
are responsible for creating a pro
innovation environment in their
countries and this is where you have to
talk about the education obviously you
have to talk about helping to develop
broadband connectivity you have to talk
about issues such as support for the
startups I remember when I was Minister
of Economy here in Slovakia we did a lot
of work for example on creating a legal
and financial environment for the Slovak
startups to be able to grow to make it
as easy and simple as possible to
register to get the financing to to be
able to grow and so on so these are some
of the steps which have to be done on
the educational side for example we
introduced and is now moving forward is
the dual education vocational education
which means that students especially in
the secondary schools are able to go and
work in the industries in companies and
this also helps to to kind of bridge
this divide between the education which
may go outside of body what are the
needs of the market and the economy so I
think these are some of the measures
which which should be undertaken on the
governmental national level on the types
of financing where we see from the elbe
perspective I think this is felt
something on the national level and what
is needed in Europe is certainly the
equity financing for the innovative
companies maybe there is enough of
startup financing but what we are
lacking in Europe is financing for
scallops
so when startup grows usually what we
see in Europe is that many of these
companies innovative excellent companies
they then leave for the United States
for China for Israel etcetera because
there is no basically no access to the
type of financing which would be
available for for the scallops so what
we have developed in the Eid so-called
debt financing their equity financing
the kind of quasi equity
which which can help and support these
kind of scallops in their further
development so I think that these are
some of the initiatives which can be
done both from the European and the
national level and eventually they need
to complement to complement each other
and Thomas I want also to ask you about
an interesting initiative in in Hungary
is the inauguration of a test track for
autonomous vehicles hey I wonder how
successful do you think the country has
been so far in fostering these kind of
research hubs and of course retaining
talent then to work on self-driving car
system is lidar technology for detecting
passengers well what can your bank do
and how successful as a government being
in creating these these kind of research
hubs and centers thank you for the
question actually we have an interesting
situation where Hungary by the way a bit
similarly to Slovakia is talking very
much on the car industry 14% of the GDP
is produced by the car industry plus
some other related areas which is
obviously good from a specialization
specialization point of view but also a
risk if you look at the future of cars
so is that me okay it was a very
powerful voice yeah artificial you wants
it right unhappy that BMW is selected
[Laughter]
seriously the idea would be to look at
where cars are heading I mean literally
as well on the test drive but even more
importantly in terms of development and
it's quite quite obvious that e cars are
part of the future and part of the
self-driving development is also taking
place in Hungary especially with trucks
by the way not exactly personal cars but
rather trucks and this is one of the
things that yes we are we are we are
proud of and it's a it's an overbooked
test-drive
facility already although it hasn't
opened yet
so we think it was a good idea to build
it and this is a good example of how to
build on your strengths so to speak but
more generally I think that from a
Development Bank perspective and also
from a government perspective there is
also a question we digitized
digitization which goes back to the
point of how you basically when you
digitize usually outsource some tasks to
the customer I mean we don't like to
call it that way but I mean our bank
also introduced a landing procedure with
which is fully digital so the customer
at home basically puts in all the data
and attaches all the documents that
normally the bank adviser would do now
the problem is and I guess there are
many in the room who already tried to
digitize some of their processes let's
first of all you have to completely dumb
down simplify and really you know
streamline your processes to be able to
digitize digitize it and then you
usually find that it's still not
understandable enough it's still not
used in a foolproof way it's still a lot
of times full of full of errors and
mistakes on the customer side why is
that partially because they are just not
educated enough in using the system in
using these kind of processes and
actually they feel alienated and if you
take this to the logical conclusion then
you will end up with people who are very
much at home in a digitized word and
people who are not and then they are
going to slowly be excluded from
services be it
eegh of ermand or commercial services so
I think keeping up the balance and
actually taking care of the education in
that sense is one of the key tasks or
for a Development Bank and and for for a
country as such thank you so much divert
ponen doesn't have such a huge car
industry compared to its it's Vishu file
really great for neighbors but look
there's clearly a big role that
digitalization is playing especially in
Warsaw can you speak a little bit about
what your bank is doing on these
projects yes
the relatively our car industry is not
as big as in Hungary and Slovakia but in
absolute terms is also not negligible I
started in the first round talking about
the big projects since Banco Scholastica
Vega is a development bank that supports
the government policies in in the
investment strategies investment
programs and obviously government likes
big big projects but in parallel we
would like to couple the this this
direction with supporting the segment
that president hudak already talked
about which is startups which is micro
small and medium companies today we use
the cohesion funds to support that
segment and in the future we would like
the invest you initiative to create the
environment for supporting that segment
because in Poland we see that as the
best way to grow domestic capital which
will then support further development of
the economy that was tough and also
bringing some perfectly to what I wanted
to talk about an expert vessel you just
want to mention that I think there are
growing evidences of countries of these
regional central Zandro Europe coming
together to support innovation and I'm
just looking at Ernst my friend that who
is working very much on on the idea of
so-called Danube tech Valley basically
how do you bring best minds and best
innovative companies in this area
ranging from Germany Austria
Sakia Hungary to Romania de facto how to
how you connect them how we bring them
together and to support also the growth
of innovative companies throughout the
region because they also need a scale in
terms of for the development
and another exam example very ideas was
also participating in cooperation with
the National Development Bank's in this
region in so-called Central Europe Ando
funds which is an equity fund where
countries like Hungary Slovakia Czech
Republic Slovenia Austria put their own
money me I'd be matching the this pool
and creating the factory fund overall I
think over 200 billion euro which next
year it's fair enough next year euro
which will be used primarily for for the
support of innovative companies in this
region from on the equity level so so
these are very good I think very very
good first initiatives where these
countries are actually coming together
understanding that they can have a
bigger piece of an or a small piece of
bigger pie whatever you call it but
basically creating a better space better
conditions for innovative innovative
companies in the countries to grow
Thanks
I I just want to move on to the MFF and
watch it up in the future and this was
something I think what have you have now
alluded to just for I do that anybody
got any questions for our panelists
about the topics we've discussed so far
anybody there
not yet which means we can go straight
on to the future so we've got the the
discussions in Brussels right now are
focusing on what to do about the next FF
but then also how to how to set up a
cohesion fund in the future is an
element of the connector Europe facility
there's also a lot of talk about how you
blend funds also how you leverage
synergies between sectors and create
energy and digital projects transport
digital project I wonder if what if you
could maybe give you a thoughts on what
do you think policy makers in Brussels
need to really consider right now is
they're putting the finishing touches to
these these proposals maybe Joe McIver
if we could start with you at that end
for for once well I think there is many
challenges that the policy makers in the
you are facing and the upcoming
perspective will be way more difficult
than the previous two I actually don't
have a ready recommendation already
advise we rather look at it as sort of a
follow-on challenge for the member
countries and and Poland Poland will be
one with those that's why I mentioned
that what we have now which is
relatively large support from the
equation policy of the you may not come
in the same scale in the next
perspective so we seek many different
ways of closing this gap one of the
things that we are doing is we moving as
much as possible from grant model to
financial instruments so we already have
some success in this in the previous
perspective this perspective is even
more focused on on the financial
instruments so we expect to have
revolving money fueling the growth of
especially the SME segment but also in
the in the other parts of the economy as
well thanks Ian Thomas you of you it's
similar I would start with the idea of
centralized and decentralized funds in
to you because that's actually a key
point in in making the making any
recommendations about how how the future
should look like
the point is that now there are in the
structural funds already financial
instruments meaning money that has to be
repaid refundable loans or private
equity envelopes this is part of the
decentralized part of the funds whereas
there is a centralized part which is now
termed FC for short and which would be
replaced by investing you now our
experiences with the two sorts of funds
even though both our financial
instruments are very are very different
on the decentralized side Hungary
actually has the third highest rate of
financial instruments so repayable
refundable actually has to be repaid
kind of the fundable is a bit
technically correct but not not the
right term
so anyway of that that share is actually
8 percent compared to the total total
envelope which is higher than even the
average and the two other countries
which are even higher are also see
countries this is the funds actually
that the bank that I'm managing NFB is
managing in Hungary it is quite a
success actually we've been through more
of the sources more of the funds then
than most EU countries 90% is already
used up compared to 44 which is the
average and also especially in the
private equity space which we've been
talking about compared talking about
startups we are I mean maybe even too
dominant
I'm happy that Commissioner first target
is not in the room anymore because last
year actually our funds were 99 o % of
the total venture capital investment in
Hungary which basically means that there
is no such market yet so we have to
build this market and so these funds
were these funds actually worth
they are big share of the total and they
are well placed in you can in the
economy on the other hand these were
decentralized funds on the other hand
the centralized ones well we actually
didn't have any any FC project in
Hungary until last week
because we just signed a Thursday to be
very exact because Thursday so two days
ago we signed an agreement with AIB to
put to put 25 million euros into an SME
refinancing facility backed by FC
guarantees but until then we had zero
and more more seriously actually a total
region C as a region has a total of nine
nine percent of total FC spend so far in
this seven year budget cycle and we are
speaking about 13 countries out of the
28 so our experience with the centrally
managed FC fans is that it is mainly
spent on the big economies more than
sixty percent actually went to the top
five economies and that is a problem for
Central and Eastern Europe and we would
like to have an investor you which
actually makes these problems solvable
or actually tries to solve these
problems and at the very beginning thank
you and I so just to say that debate a
little bit this clearly been a an issue
of recent years probably for good
overall the structural funds have really
driven growth in parts of the EU
especially the newer member states how
do you think this is going to develop in
the future who could could this become a
problem as as time I said when it when
you have a situation where basically
public funding is being used for to
drive a whole industry is it
over-dependence i have a kind of mixed
feelings frankly about the structural
investment funds of the EU in these
countries as a one hand they have played
a very important role to to move this
country towards convergence and getting
closer to the levels of Western Europe
on the other hand I think there is a
negative element which is the fact that
these are certainly not market-based
through market based products and they
have created the certain mentality in in
these countries which is very much grant
based mentality so basically we take the
money we don't have to replay the money
and it's not always not always fresh and
always good so but basically looking at
this issue from the European perspective
you have
difficult situation post-2020 because as
in any budget you have to have a revenue
side and the expenditure side on the
revenue side you have less money because
of the brexit on the expenditure side
you have more needs more so-called
priorities of the of the european union
because we have in addition to the
traditional ones like cohesion and
Common Agricultural Policy you have now
also European defence migration you have
environment or climate climate change
and so on so you have more things you
want to cover so the big question for
the European policymakers is how you do
more with less and that's the I think
the biggest dilemma for the for the
future you budget now how we do it on
one hand you have to cut somewhere so
there are cuts in cohesion policy and in
Common Agricultural Policy the the two
elements have been traditionally around
two thirds of the of the EU budget of
course cohesion countries are unhappy so
we hear from ministers from the cohesion
countries and regions this unhappiness
for central Central Europe it means
decreasing the cohesion funding
somewhere around plus minus 20 to 23
percent just quite a lot obviously and
as I said in the beginning there is a
certain addiction to stop money and and
on the other hand you need to somehow
compensate for this gap and the way the
Commission is trying to compensate is by
creating the so-called invest in you
pool of money which is the fact to the
financial instruments astonish explain
the money that has to be repaid or
should be repaid the invest in you is
very much modeled on the FC on the incra
plan on the European fund for strategic
investments where actually what we have
achieved is that with the amount of
guarantees for FC s or FC 1 which is 21
billion we have achieved an investment
impact in Europe of over 300 billion
euro so it's a huge leverage this is how
we can very efficiently use public
resources to actually get a big impact
in terms of investment and this is very
much thanks
to the fact that this type of money and
proper use of financial instruments can
leverage and engage private sector so
there is certainly more and more
realization that we have this big
investment gaps which cannot be filled
by public money nor national or nor
European and you have to engage a
private sector into this cooperation and
the only way how you can engage private
sector is by creating so-called bankable
projects or at least have pieces of
projects which are bankable where you
can blend some grant from the structural
investment funds and some portion from
the soccer financial instruments which
has to be repaid and this is now what
the big thing is about you know how do
we how do we structure this future
invest you who is eligible to use these
guarantees and obviously National
Development Bank's like MFP in in
Hungary or BGK in in Poland are getting
ready for the utilization of this pool
of money the AIB has traditionally been
in Europe the manager of the financial
instruments on this centralized level
but I think in general it creates a good
opportunity especially for private
sector to be engaged in these projects
because we will need to be much more
much more skillful and creative
including in developing projects which
have this commercial bankable repayable
element Thanks so anybody have any
questions on on the point raised to
comments on the points race so far yes
sir Jordan Bernie from Hungary I sit on
the FC investment committee and I wanted
to react on what tomash said about the
FC because I and I would like to see
much more Hungarian projects there and
my grandfather always told me in the
1970s that you know my uncle if I don't
play at the lottery
I usually don't win so the problem is
the FC investment committee I've been
there for one over a year almost one and
a half years I've only three three three
projects from Hungary coming in in the
infrastructure window was three first
supported the last one on Friday this
week
which is still not public which one it
is but only three projects for Poland we
keep a proving project every month
sometimes two or three in one session we
approved one yesterday as well so there
is a very strong difference between the
countries Bulgaria is the number four on
a GDP proportional drawdown of FC and
Bulgaria is not a more developed or
larger economy than Hungary so I think
there is a difference between the
activity of the given countries and here
the local presence of AIB and the
Development Bank's matters on generating
those projects and those projects can
come from the private sector and the
public sector what is a clear difference
is what I see is that in in Western
Europe more projects come from the
private sector in in for example hungry
the three projects we have proved one is
a quasi private sector the two are
publicly owned companies who received by
the way very large support we have also
on the other windows direct there are
already signed contracts with banks on
funding SME loans in Hungary for example
that was not mentioned so the FC I don't
think is biased for the larger economies
it's but there is certainly a factor to
be taken into account that in certain
Eastern Europe there are the structural
funds which are a huge proportion of GDP
related development around 3% of the GDP
per annum so that's money for free and
that's non-recourse money as you
mentioned that's something that doesn't
need to be repaid so that free money is
also reducing projects that need
recourse funding there is a crowding out
impact of that as we expect in the new m
FF that it is widely expected or
forecasted that the structural funds the
free money the grant money will reduce I
expect that the demand for for recourse
money ie landing and equity will
increase in these countries as well but
it is worse running already for
FC projects now because you need to
learn the methodology you know you need
to learn to play the bureaucratic system
so that when the demand is there you can
use it efficiently Thanks
well as I said nine percent was the
total for Central and Eastern Europe and
that's actually IB number so we can
discuss country between country and a
lot of projects from one country and not
that many from another and the basic
point is actually right obviously if you
don't submit projects you don't get
something but the total of the 13 in
countries including Bulgaria including
Poland is nine percent so there is still
something wrong if this is the end
result and that is also true for what
you're saying about public and private
because well everything that we as a
publicly owned institution can do is to
directly leverage some incentives on the
publicly owned ones and to try to get
the private ones to actually submit
projects and there another point is and
actually that's leading to invest EU I
think a very good idea to enlarge the
technical assistance part of of this
whole program because to be frank there
is not much knowledge especially not in
the dispersed private sector to submit
the right projects and economies where
there is more knowledge already
accumulated throughout decades for that
are obviously at an advantage and that's
where we have that's what leads to the
kind of situation we are in now we have
seen show Misha if I could just ask you
very very quickly to respond to this
point
why does Poland get a new road every
week and hungry belly gets anything
what's the secret lottery
no no Poland is not covered by roads yet
we have still forests and meadows and
and beautiful nature we are really we
have very efficient system of devising
projects
which then are submitted as for they for
the EU support this is this is true we
also have a very effective mechanisms
for distributing the especially
financial instruments and I'm talking
about this because this is what I manage
on the daily basis we really well
address the the the support to our to
our companies and I think the reason is
that we really care for this I mean it
for us we coming out of communism we had
literally no private the capital and
still I don't I don't know what what's
the structure of those projects is it
are they originated from the public
companies probably if private they those
are not natively polish they they
probably are some foreign investments in
in Poland who have the capability to
apply for for for big support for big
portlets mentioned I think in Poland on
one hand I think kind of genetically
poles were always very entrepreneurial
I remember when even during the
socialist times you could see this
Malucci
and the Fiats Littlefield's driving all
over Central Europe always carrying some
big stuff on top of the of the Fiat sand
and Paul sitting inside squeezed now you
see them in inner-city assemblies and so
on but anyway so I think that there is
this very natural natural interest and
an ability on the poorest idols on the
corporate side to develop projects which
are actually bankable you know where you
can use financial instruments and where
FC can be one of the sources of
investment a second important you have
strong strongly decentralized system and
the boy roots to other regions or the
cities are very active in developing
projects which qualify for for FC
guarantee so for some of their several
projects in the Polish regions which are
financed to FC like regional hospitals
where actually the hospitals are
modernized and built with the support of
FC and their kind of balance sheet
entities or some people be structures
for for local regional infrastructure
like in Krakov the bypass by President
Clark ozone so I think Bob Pollin has
really done a lot in this area
thank you and Pablo just to pull you
back into the conversation they have
nothing to say about Big Sur yeah but
you do have something to say I would
imagine about the road of digitalization
in this because the EU now is making a
very very big push to make sure that
however it calibrates the next budgetary
period it creates lots of synergies so
it specifically asks project backers to
present them with projects that combine
transport with digitalization
initiatives and I just wonder from from
the perspective from Washington is
Europe ahead of the game on doing this
is this is this a very future interested
look at infrastructure instead of saying
we need to build a road and then later
will update it with connected car
technology and sensors is what's the
modern way of looking at funding
infrastructure you know that that is the
modern way of
looking at funding infrastructure I
think the more and more what we're
seeing is the a couple of things one
there's the the you know the physical
infrastructure piece two there's the the
aspect of preparing not just for you
know in the case of building roads for
you know the roads in the cars of today
but the roads in the cards for tomorrow
with sensors and so forth and this gets
to the internet-of-things part of it
then the third piece of it is is
leveraging the data that that's coming
out of you know both the use of these of
this infrastructure and the
infrastructure itself what we have found
is is that there is a tremendous
opportunity both in terms of of the use
of infrastructure or even in the
previous case of automobile
manufacturing I mean the the amount of
data that the factories in this region
are the amount that it's that it's
generating is really significant and it
tells you a lot about the longevity of
parts the efficiency of of manufacturing
the the you know the the value of
certain of different materials that go
into the vehicles and it does really
raise this question in terms of thinking
about kind of the digital future of
central in Eastern Europe you know how
how the region really thinks of itself
for example in the context of automobile
manufacturing is is the competitive
advantage one of labor costs as the
competitive advantage one of logistics
and perhaps the the question is also its
the can the competitive advantage be one
of Technology and of leveraging data in
a building digital infrastructure around
those factories we think that there's a
tremendous amount of promise you know
again not just for digital companies but
for again manufacturing companies and
other companies that can really leverage
these tools and just as a final thing
because I should remind everybody there
is this McKinsey report that's coming
out we have the executive summary of it
that's available hopefully we can work
together both with governments and with
private sector stakeholders to turn
those ideas into reality one point of
the that the report makes is that the
time is now and and there is a fair
amount of urgency in taking advantage of
the the digital promise so
we would love to work with you and and
we're looking forward to that thank you
and just a very quick point as well
going back to what we're talking about
earlier in terms of Education
specifically would Google cloud consider
having more staff in the Central
European region is there space for
research clusters around universities
and how do you view yes and for sure
more we already do a number of those
kinds of partnerships a lot of training
a lot of support for for entrepreneurs
and you know from a strictly the cloud
perspective one thing that we found is
that one of the challenges of cloud
adoption and this is not just for
Central and Eastern Europe its it's a
global challenge is skills the the that
that there is not enough knowledge
within companies that are in other
industries that are not yet digital in
in the you kind of in the knowledge
about like how to how to use these tools
and how to leverage them to enhance
business models so that's another area
of Education that will be that will be
focused on ok we quickly approaching the
ten seconds left time but I want to ask
you a one very very brief slightly
cheeky question to conclude with if you
had the the European Council in front of
you now the 28 was 27 to 28 EU leaders
looking ahead to how they should fund
infrastructure in the future what would
be the message that you that you think
they should get on how to calibrate the
next budgetary period for issues of
infrastructure education etc maybe if I
could ask Warsaw and Budapest then
Luxembourg and then the Washington
perspective to close I'm not prepared to
give advice I think it is important to
maintain this dual approach that is that
we have now which is cohesion so that
the Europe becomes more similar there's
the differences among the regions are
reduced and the ideas like invest in you
or younger plan were you
rob is supported in the global
competition Thank You Thomas well I
would say something like please make
sure there's a level playing field and
if there is not yet one if there is not
one yet then please work on creating one
so I think that we have to make sure
that there is more engagement of private
sector in all these projects and I think
that we have to make sure that the
European money or national money public
money creates opportunities for private
sector to be engaged that's what we have
to make them simpler easier to use and
and and and create projects which would
bring public and private together and
Pablo to conclude I agree you know say
I'm looking at a sign that says times up
all right there you go if you join me in
thanking our panelists will be great
thank you very much gentlemen thank you
everyone for coming