it's very optimistic and a bit I'm the
shrivel it's about the weather or about
the discussion I hope both the
everybody isn't a very positive mode of
thinking which is if I contrast it to
the past year it's a very dramatic
change because last year everybody was
in this various sober pessimistic mode
versus this year there is much more hope
about the future this is not to say that
we totally ignore the problems and chill
issues on the ground quite the opposite
people were able to look at the problems
with a very constructive approach and
find some solutions to the issue so I
hope on Monday everybody's gonna start
implementing they all the solutions that
we came up with during the Tatra summits