hi all my name is alenza fapico and
today i'm going to present a joint work
with color raffles that is called an
algebraic framework for updatable
universal snacks
so since the introduction of interactive
proof systems in
1989 a huge line of research has drove
us to what is nowadays most efficient
construction of a snark due to rot in
and
when i talk about efficiency i mean we
have proof system where approver wants
to convince verified that some relation
holds
and we are going to consider in in this
case the work the brewer has to do in
order
to convince the verifier the amount of
information they have to send back and
forward and the work of the verifier as
well
in this almost optimal construction
there is a drawback that is that in
order to achieve such sanctions
the
program the verifier both need to share
some information
that contains some description of the
relation and this information also has a
secret so whenever we talk about the
secret we talk about a trusted party
thinking on the applications that snarks
have nowadays this condition is highly
undesirable so the community has been
working on solutions
as multi-party computation which could
be the most natural one
but this still has its own drawbacks
so in a multi-party computation model
many parties collaborate in order to
create a secret that none of them
knows completely
so they send messages back and forward
and at the end of this interaction
they have
one srs that stands for structural
reference ring and it's this information
i mentioned before that both pro and
very high and very fire have access to
but this srs is specific for one
relation so this
quite expensive computation has to be
performed
for
for every time we we need to use it for
for a particular relation
in 2018 rothetol introduced an
alternative to this model that is the
updatable model
similar to multi-project computation
there are many parties that collaborate
in order to create
this srs but in this case they don't do
it interactively but they act one after
the other
and compute its part of
the srs in a verifiable manner
the output of this
of this computation
is an srs that we are going to call
universal why because
it will work for any relation up to some
size
and then from that universal srs we can
derivate in an untrusted
step
other relation dependent srs right so we
start from these
this universal srs this um that contains
the secrets and then
construct descriptions of relations from
that
since the the appearance of this seminal
work
uh many constructions of snarks that use
updates with universal srs
have have been done
and the nice thing is that all of them
share some common principles which
consist in breaking the construction of
the snorkeling two-step
first we work in the in an information
theoretical object through its security
and then by using
cryptographic assumptions finally
compile it into a snap
this information theoretical object is a
what we call an holographic proof and
i'm going to talk about that in a second
and the cryptographic compiler is done
using a polynomial complement
all the cons the the constructions that
we
we are aware of in
in the updated universal model follow
this blueprint i hope um we are not
forgetting anymore
so what is an holographic proof and here
i'm going to use the notion
introducing luna but with different
flavors
flavors and this come
they are calling different ways in
previous work
so we have as always the prover that is
going to be played
by the pirate today and a verifier
the vulture
but also we have a third a
a third entity which is the indexer
played by the unm and the indexer is
going to output polynomials that
describe the relation then proven
verifier will interact programmer
messages will include polynomials as
well
and the verifier rather than having to
read these polynomials will have access
a oracle access to it so it can query
them at a
arbitrary point of their choice
and perform their rejects among others
so
we want to construct a polynomial
holographic proof for proving general
relations
what is the motivation of these of this
work this work is
it's meant to break this information
theoretical object a bit more
why first of all to extract the main
ideas
of all these
very
interesting constructions
for two things first of all we want to
compare we want to see what is that they
have in common what is that they
their differences what are their
differences because
what they have in common can be a bit
more standard their difference may work
different
in a different manner for
for a specific relation so maybe we can
why not combine them and of course at
the end the final goal is to to improve
right to to get a more sufficient and
more efficient constructions
so for that let's start from the
beginning
and we want to prove general
computations that we can model as empty
problems and in this talk i'm going to
consider secret satisfiability why
because it has a very like
uh
a very nice representation
an arithmetic circuit
have three types of gates we have
multiplicative gates additive gates and
gates where the inputs gets multiplied
by constants and for the first one
we capture them in a set of quadratic
constraints
so if we can label all multiplicative
gaits from 1 to m
what we are going to require is that the
left input
of
gate i times the right input equals the
output of the gate
so we label with a the left inputs will
be
the right inputs and we see the outputs
then
to capture uh both additive and
multiplicative by
by a constant gate
we use linear constraints
so
every input
will depend
on previous outputs
and some coefficients that describe the
the circuit itself
so if you remember what to say about the
srs the intuition is that
quadratic constraints are the same
for every circuit of size and every
circuit that has a multiplicative skate
we have the same set of quality
constraints but linear constraints
include some
constants that describe the circuit
so this is
why we need to derive the universal srs
into a specific one
to generate um
[Music]
a science in the description of the
circuit
because these concerns
are not something general
so algebraically the program wants to
convince the verifier that there is an
assignment that satisfies
a specific circuit so what the prover
wants to show is that for some vectors a
b c
of size m
and given matrices f and g that
describes the circuit
two things happen the first one is that
they have a product between a and b
equals c so this entrywise
probe
includes all the quadratic constraints
and then
that summary some linear relation holds
between matrix f and g and the vector of
of the witness
basically what the prover wants to prove
is that a b and c are in the orthogonal
space to this matrix w
generated by the rows of this matrix w
why because if if you see
what this matrix this
equation is say in this
matrix vector probe is that element i of
vector a
equals a linear combination between
vector c
and the constants of rho i
of matrix f
and
similar for b and g
so let's see
this uh a bit more in detail
how can we prove that
the vector abc
is um in the subspace well we could take
every row of w and perform an inner
product with a vector of the witness and
check that all of them are zero
but this will require to prove 2m
relations
and we are pursuing sanctions so this is
far from
from optimal
but
thinking in an ad the right matter what
we can do instead of checking one vector
against every generator of a subspace we
can sample one random
element in that space by using a
random
coefficients
and then just check one in a product
so
our prover wants to promise our verifier
that the secret is satisfied
he has to prove the hadamard probe
he has to prove also the inner probe
equals zero
uh between abc and some random
so that's in the world of vectors and
matrices which is nice and intuitions
came very fast but then we have to move
to the word of polynomials so for that
we are going to define a set h
of size m where m is a
is the number of multiplicative gates
inside our field and then define the
lagrange polynomials
so lambda
is a polynomial of degree m minus 1 that
vanishes at every point in h but h i
where it takes value 1
and t x is a polynomial that vanishes at
every point in h
and there where it says rjh it's
supposed to say hj
and now we have a natural encoding we
take a vector of size m
and then we write
the linear combination between these
these
the elements of this vector
and
the lagrange polynomials
the
the output is a polynomial y
that when we evaluate it in
h i give us the i element of oi
so
um so for so good we have the intuition
of how to proceed with satisfiability in
the algebraic world we have the tool to
move to polynomials and now let's wrap
up a bit
what we need
so
we need um
to sample very proven verifier need to
sample
this vector d and then compute the it's
encoding as uh as polynomial
and then from the encodings
of the vectors
of the witness and the encodings of of
the vectors and the
generate d
two things have to be proven first of
all that the hammer plugs between a and
b equals c
and there is a pretty standard way to do
it when we work with orange polynomials
we can write it as a divisibility
problem so for example here the plural
will send
polynomials abc and h
h1
and the verifier has to check that
basically a times b minus c is divisible
by
the vanishing polynomial
and then also the prover has to convince
the verifier that the inner product
between this
random vector d and the vector of the
witness is you
we present a scheme for this inner
product relation in our paper i'm not
going to get into the details but it it
has a very similar structure to the to
the mr probed
scheme so
the proverb wants to commit the verifier
of this and we already know how to
perform hammer probes and in approach
how the prover can show to the verifier
that these two relations are satisfied
so the quadratic relations
and the inner relation the linear
relation is divided into steps one of
them we have it recover which is the
inner product so we have to focus on how
to sample this vector g and compute the
encodings
these two this the last step is what we
are going to call it check also by
sampling so the prover
has to sample this vector d because we
cannot ask verifier to do it
it will take a linear time
and then it has to prove it to the
verifier prove the correctness of the
sample
so to sample we need a vector of size 2m
and
because
the
the prover
is trying to convince the verifier the
proverb cannot choose his coefficient he
cannot choose the vector in in the row
space of w that is going to check
against
the witness
but the verifier we don't want it to
send
two
m
field elements so we we solve this
problem
by including the description of the
relation some vector of polynomials
alpha
this vector of polynomials you can think
it as um the monomial basis
or the lagrange
the lagrange polynomials for a for a set
of size 2m
then the prover is going to evaluate
this vector of polynomials
in one element
so we will get two
m
random coefficients
but the point of evaluation will be sent
by the verifier so the referral sends
just one element
and the prover use it to evaluate two m
polynomials and generate uh the
randomness that is going to use for the
linear combination and then it performs
the
the sampling itself
now
next step how do we get the encoding of
vector d we already know how to
find vector v
so for the
encoding of vector d what we want is
something like that looks like this
because d has size 3m we need the
lagrange polynomials
that interpolates and set of
of size 3m as
well and
and our encoding is
is of this form
but
what
is d what is vector d what are the
elements of vector d
well vector d is a linear combination
between the rows of w and and this
alphas
so we
patch
all these rows
in just one vector and then we'll use
the large polynomials to match the
columns
so to match the elements of
a vector d
but at the same time these alpha
coefficients
are evaluations of polynomials in some
point y
and if you think this is the natural
encoding of a matrix it's like we
compress all the rows with some set of
polynomials all the column with another
set of polynomials and then in order to
recover an element in w we basically
play some novel but
so d at the end is a partial evaluation
of a vector
sorry of a polynomial that describes
matrix w
a polynomial that naturally encodes it
this may seem as already a solution
but
here we have a
a problem here is where we need to focus
and this is the bottleneck of all
constructions
this vector w
has two variables with independent
degree m
of course the verifier cannot evaluate
it it will take quadratic and
quadratic work and we don't want it even
to be linear
and we cannot include it in the in the
relation dependent srs because we will
need from the
the universal srs to be quadratic to
include all the combination of powers
between x and y
so
the
the goal is to find a way that the
verifier can have can partially evaluate
this polynomial
and prove its correctness or maybe not
partially evaluated maybe evaluated in
two variables sent by the verifier but
then
prove the correct values
if matrix w is dense
and it has a quadratic number of
quadratic in them
a number of non-zero elements
this could get super tricky
but
there are some assumptions we can make
in the shape of w and previous work made
them and they are super fair assumptions
we are going to talk about that in a in
a way
so
to prove circuit satisfiability
we will start
from a checkable cells by sampling it
has a structure of an algebraic
holographic proof and then
recall we add the inner product relation
in order to prove the linear constraints
and then we add
the
the halamer product relation in order to
finally proceed with satisfiability so
this is how we break the information
theoretical object
but
for time constraints i'm going to focus
only in the first primitive the checkout
subspace sampling which is our main
contribution
so because it has the the structure of
an algebraic proof
polynomial algebraic proof
a primarily graphical sorry
we have the indexer that performs uh in
an offline phase some computation to
output polynomials that describe matrix
w
then in an online phase proven verifier
will interact
in two steps the first one is to sample
so the verifier will send and the
challenge
a y
and the prover will reply with encoding
of the vector d it's a sample
according to y
and then
the approver has to convince the
verifier that the sampling has been
performed correct
at the end
the verifier
accepts or rejects
depending on whether dx
has been correctly computed
so and this is a the first step to
construct
a snark and update on universal snark
and
it's implicit in all previous
constructions that's
that's the core of the work this work so
in sonic it's called it's implicit in
the signature of curry computation and
the partial evaluation of of this
b varied polynomial s is indeed a
sampling
er in the in the rows of the matrix that
describes the
the sequence
then they present two constructions in
the samsung construction they assume
that w can be written as a sum of a
permutation matrix which is a very
assumption and the complexity depends on
how many matrices we needed
how many permutation matrices we need to
compute w
and then they present an amortized table
subspace sampling
that is unrestricted makes no
assumptions on the size on the um on the
structure of w and is super efficient
in malignant lunar
er they use a very a very smart chain
calling
of sparse matrices that is uh
that is presented in malin
which is again a fair assumption because
what they assume is that the amount of
non-serious elements is actually linear
in the size of the circuit
and
the
the protocols are super efficient but
they have um quite a large srs
in our work we first
start from this algebraic intuition
and
and create a css that is um inspired in
the blender modern assembly which is not
very efficient uh by itself but it works
very well with dense
rows so because this is linear algebra
we want to sample a
a vector in the row space of a matrix
so we can use one css for example to
to work with the dense um
rows and then if the rest of the matrix
is sparse why not to use marginal rule
we also present um
a construction that is inspired by
marlin but is
generated from
simpler building blocks and
uh came out to be
to be as efficient as the best
construction in in luna
but
with a with a smaller surface
and then in an extended version of our
work while trying to include blanc in
our
in our framework we
we
combined somewhat the ideas
of lunar um and plonk and came out with
uh with our best construction
that considers and secrets with limited
fan out
again after
after assumption in the applications of
snarks
to wrap up
why to use css why to think this um
information theoretical object this
holographic proof
in in this way
because
decomposing
the construction of a scheme in many
steps
is always useful also it comes
with
with an algebraic intuition that we i
think we all feel comfortable working
with
like it
simplifies then the framework it has cut
through several constructions i would
say
all of them in the index and the version
of our work
and this css is the bottleneck it's what
all these constructions defer on
it's where the smartest idea
came
on the table
so
isolating it will allow us to again
compare combine
and then
improve we now we know where to focus
and a and as i mentioned before then we
can
mix this
this works
so that's all from me thank you for
listening i hope this was useful if it
was not please don't hesitate to contact
us or if you have
any doubts on on our of our results
you