hello everyone my name is yuyu wang i'm
from uestc
our title is fine grain secure
attribute-based encryption let's join
the work with judgement and return
for cryptographic scheme we usually
require that hanami safari can run the
scheme in polynomial time and the scheme
can be secure against polynomial time
adversaries
by now there have been a great deal of
works constructing cryptographic schemes
that are secure based on quality
functions factoring discrete logarithm
ddh lwe or even the existence of generic
groups and outbreak groups
however we do not know whether these
assumptions hold so it's desirable to
use no assumptions or mild complexity
worst case assumptions so that we can
still have cryptography even if for
example one functions do not exist
but in the long history of cryptography
it has turned out that this is quite
difficult
fine fine-grained cryptography gives us
a direction in approaching this problem
instead of considering polynomial time
on its parties and adversaries we only
require that an owner's party uses less
resources than adversaries
and the resources of an anniversary such
as the running time the memory and the
circuit dips
can be a prior bonding
under this setting it's possible to make
the underlying assumption extremely mild
and make the scheme very efficient
this field was initialized by marco and
there have been many fine green
primitives proposed such as key exchange
one-way functions pke verifiable
computation hospital systems and triple
1 functions
but notice that there are still many
important penguin primitives that are
not known to exist such as signature
in this work
we propose the first fine-grained secure
ib scheme which is secure against
adversaries with bondi circuit depth
it borrows the bkp framework by blizzard
and others which constructs ib from f5
max
and the chw framework by chang and
others
which constructs a b from predicated
encodings
we first propose a fingering version of
the filemaking the bkp paper
and generalize it by using parts of a
predicate encoding
and then we combine it with other parts
of the encoding with some new techniques
to construct a b schemes
our construction essentially implements
a dual system in the banking city
the proof for the mac and the general
construction of rab switch functional
user secret keys and functional
ciphertexts to semi-function once
respectively
similar to the work of chw by
instantiating the underlying encoding in
different ways we obtain an ibu scheme
which in turn implies a signature scheme
and abe schemes supporting various types
of boolean predicates
and also broadcast encryption and fuzzy
ib in the fragrance setting
all the instantiations are computable in
ac02 and secure against adversaries in
nc1
the assumption is that
nc1 is not equal to parity l slash body
this assumption is widely believed to
help
also we know that all the computations
are over gf2
this setting is exactly the same as the
boundary circuit setting in previous
works on penguin cryptography
here is easier to include circuits with
constant depth
polynomial size and unbounded fine using
ends or
not
and priority gates
and c1 includes circuits with
logarithmic depth polynomial size and
fine to gates note that nc1 includes
ac02
priority l poly
include log space turing machines with
priority acceptance
we now recall the definition of apk
which can be easily converted to abe by
using a symmetric encryption
an apkm consists of four algorithms the
first one is jing which takes as input
the security parameter in lambda and
outputs a public key picking and the
secret key sk
the user key generation algorithm takes
as input a secret key sk of value y and
outputs a user secret key usky
the encryption algorithm takes as input
the public key of value x and outputs
ciphertext and also a session key
the decryption algorithm takes as input
the user secret key
value x and the ciphertext city and
outputs the session key
correctness holds if the session key k
can be correctly recovered by deck which
is the decryption algorithm if p x y is
equal to one
here p is the boolean predicate
this is the security game the adversary
takes us input the public key
and makes many queries why to obtain
user secret keys and also makes one
query x to obtain the challenge
ciphertext and also the corresponding
session key in k-stock
security holds if k star is
indistinguishable from randomness when p
x y is not equal to 1 for all queries y
ib came is a special case of a became
where the predicate is restricted to be
the equality predicate
and can be easily converted into ibe
for simplicity in this presentation we
only give the high level idea on how we
construct an ibe
our construction of fine-grained ib
borrows the bkp framework recall that in
this framework the ibe is constructed
from an f5 mic which is secure under the
mdd assumption
the construction heavily relies on the
asymmetric pairing and it's necessary to
compute the inverse of matrix in the
security proof
however we have no pairing and mdd
assumption and c1
and we cannot compute the inverse of a
matrix in the nc1 world
we now need to find the counterpart of
the mde assumption
although the assumption that c1 is not
equal to parity l poly does not directly
give us to us to construct cryptographic
schemes
degree card and others showed that this
assumption implies the
indistinguishability of two
distributions which are zero sum
and one sample against nc1 adversaries
here
zero samp
outputs rank deficient matrices
and one sum outputs four rank matrices
and orchestra and others showed that
this implies a hard subset membership
problem
this problem says that it's hard to
distinguish a vector sampled from some
ps
and the vector from sub node 4i and c1
adversary
let m2 top be the inputs of some ps and
some node where m0 is from zero sample
some ps samples vectors from the span of
m0 top with some no samples vectors
outside the span of m0 top
next i will give the construction of our
fm mac
the construction of our fan mac is
similar to the one in the bkp
construction the secret key consists of
a matrix b whose transposition b top was
sampled from zero sample
a sequence of random vectors x 0 to x n
and run bit x prime
the type consists of two parts
t and u
t is vector sampled from the span of b
and u is computed by an equation of x i
top t and x prime with coefficients
derived from the message which is
denoted by id here
in the security game the anniversary
queries messages and obtains the
corresponding text
at some point
it makes a challenge query id star and
obtains a token which consists of h0 and
x prime
x prime is part of the secret key and
hu0 is also computed by an
fine equation
security holds if x prime is
indistinguishable with the random bit
when id star is not equal to all the
queried messages
the security proof follows from the fact
that when switching the distribution of
t from sun psb to signal b
x prime is information theoretically
hidden in you due to linear independence
we omit the details here and please see
our paper for more details
next i will give the construction of our
ib cam
let's record two facts given by akasha
on the other side first
the m0 biomatrix sample from zero samp
and m1 matrix sampled from one sum
the distribution of m0 top plus n
is identical to the distribution of m
one top
here in its matrix with the bottom left
entry being one and the other entry is
being 0.
another fact is that the distributions
of m0 top r0 and m0 top r1 identical
where r0 is run vector with the first
speed fixed at 0 and r1 is a random
vector with the first bit fixed size 1.
we now give the construction of our ib
cam
the key generation algorithm samples the
transposition of a matrix a from zero
sum and the secret key of our fm mac
then it commits to the vectors x i by
computing y i top x i times a
it also commits to the run beat x prime
in the secret key in the same way
the public key consists of a and the
commitments
the secret key consists of a secret key
of the underlying mac and the randomness
y i and y prime used to commit to the
values
the user key generation algorithm
generates a tag of the femac and compute
scientific equation of y i t and y prime
to generate vector v
we can be treated as a proof that the
tag was correctly computed
the encryption algorithm for samples a
random vector with the first b being 0
and vectors c0 and c1
c0 is a r and c 1 is computed by an
official equation of z i r
the session key k is equal to z prime r
the decryption algorithm is designed
similar to the bkp framework
but notice that the pairing is not
necessary now since the competitions are
not in the groups
the crucial step in the security game is
to construct a reduction break in the
security of the underlying of imac
and at the core of the proof we
developed a new technique to extract the
forgery of the affair mic from the
adversary
what specifically we switch the
distribution of the matrix a twice
and change the distribution of the
randomness r
during the switching procedure
we now give the sketch of our security
proof by using several hybrid games
game 0 is the original game where the
adversary obtains the public key and
makes id queries
at some point it makes a challenge query
id start to receive a cipher text
consisting of c0 c1 and also the
corresponding session key
game y is the same as game 0 except that
we additionally add a with the constant
matrix and we mentioned before to
generate c0 c1 and k
one can check that when the first bit of
r is zero and r is equal to zero
so this does not change the view of the
anniversary item
in the next game we switch the
distribution of a top to one sample
this does not change the view of the
adversary due to the
indistinguishability between one samp
and 0samp
we now fix the first bit of r as 1
instead of 0.
notice that a plus n top is a matrix
from 0sem now and the fact about zero
sample we mentioned before shows that
this change does not affect the
distribution of a plus and r
also notice that y zero top x 0 times
and r is equal to x 0 and y prime top x
prime times r is equal to x prime
instead of a 0 matrix now
this allows us to extract x 0 and x
prime from
c1 and k later
next we switch the distribution of atop
back to zero sum
in game 5 which is the last game we do
not use the randomness y i and the
secret x i to generate z i anymore
instead we generate z i as
0 d i r 0 top
d i is equal to y i top plus x i stop
and it reveals new information on x i
and r 0 and s are intermediate values
used by zero sample and they are
independent with y i and x i
also we can redefine z prime in the same
way
now we can prove that v reviews no
information on the secrets except for
you which is a tag of the fmac
also we can prove that c1 reviews no
information on x i except for x0 plus
the sum of idi xi
this is exactly part of the token in the
security game for the fm mac
this allows us to make use of the
security of a 5 mac to show that x prime
which is another part of the token as
indistinguishable from randomness which
means that the session decay can be
switched to randomness
by doing the steps in the reverse order
we can prove that k is indistinguishable
from randomness in the original game
which completes our proof
also notice that in a security proof we
did not compute the inverse of matrix
and all the computation signs in c1
otherwise the proof does not hold
we also show that the red parts of rib
came essentially use the encoding for
equality and can be generalized as
predicated encodings proposed by chw
in this way we can generalize ri became
eisen abk
this extension can also be used in the
standard world not only the vanguard
world
this is the conclusion of our work we
proposed a general reconstruction of
fine-grained ab scheme secure against c1
adversaries and computable in ac02
the assumption is a worst case
complexity assumption which is very mild
it has many types of instantiations
including a fine-grained ib and the
fine-grained signature scheme
also we know that our techniques can
also be used to construct an efficient
fine-grained qnisk
please see our paper for more details
thank you for your attention