hi everyone this talk will be about
improved computational extractors and
their applications
this is based on joint work with
akshayram srinivasan who is at tifr
let me begin by introducing you to our
setting
we consider the problem of randomness
extraction
randomness is actually extremely useful
for all sorts of cryptographic
applications
it is often obtained from physical
sources sources which are usually
imperfect
in many settings an adversary may be
able to obtain side information about
the randomness that was generated
and therefore be able to attack the
system
and there have been in fact instances in
the literature that have demonstrated
that cryptography instantiated with
imperfect randomness can often be broken
completely
so the question that we look at is
whether weak random sources can be
converted into stronger ones
now we study this question in various
settings included in distributed
settings where randomness is split
between many sources some of which may
be adversarial
let me begin by making more precise what
a weak source is a weak source is
represented by a distribution on n bits
that has min entropy k
where k is
smaller than n
a min entropy of k bits corresponds to
each point in the distribution being
selected with probability at most 2 to
the minus k
an example of a weak source with main
entropy k is the uniform distribution
on subset of size
2 to the k in 0 1 to the n
randomness extractors help convert weak
sources of entropy to nearly uniform
sources
say we have a weak random source with k
bits of entropy on an n bit input space
ideally we would like to have a
deterministic algorithm that converts
this into a nearly uniformly random
source on mbits where m can be as large
as k
unfortunately it turns out that this
dream deterministic extractor simply
cannot exist even for really weak
parameter settings say we just want to
extract one bit of randomness and the
source has almost full main entropy it
has main entropy and minus one and we
want the resulting distribution to have
a statistical distance of at most a
fourth from the uniform distribution on
a single bit even in these settings
deterministic extractors are impossible
what is possible is actually a variant
that takes the help of a short uniformly
random seed to convert an n-bit source
with min entropy k to an almost k bit
uniform distribution
this is pictorially represented on the
slide here as an algorithm that on input
a source and a seed outputs a
distribution that's close to uniform
in fact the size of the seed can
actually be much smaller than the main
entropy of the input source or the size
of the output source
for example guru swami at all show that
the min entropy can be as small as poly
logarithmic the size of the seed can
also be poly logarithmic and in this
setting the error can be a negligible
function of the size of the source
the definition of a seeded extractor can
be further strengthened to what is
called a strong seeded extractor where
the requirement is that the output
distribution be statistically
indistinguishable from random even given
the seed
the problem with seeded extractors is
that you need the seed which is itself a
uniform independent source of randomness
the next primitive that we look at a two
source extractor relaxes this so that
the source and the seed are both
imperfect
a two source extractor considers a
setting where there are two weak sources
of randomness that have a certain amount
of min entropy and the only assumption
is that the two sources are independent
but neither of them needs to be uniform
they also don't necessarily need to be
the same size or have the same amount of
entropy and really the assumption is
just that they should be independent
a two-source extractor is a
deterministic algorithm that given such
independent sources with sufficient
entropy outputs a distribution that is
close to uniformly random
and for a long time we only knew how to
extract randomness in this setting when
at least one of the sources had min
entropy about half of n
a recent breakthrough work of chatopathy
and zuckerman broke down this barrier
and built two source extractors in the
setting where both sources have poly
logarithmic mean entropy
these factors were further improved in
several works
in all these works that achieve
polylogarithmic main entropy in the
setting however the running time of the
extractor turned out to be inversely
proportional to the desired error
in particular this means that the error
cannot be negligible in n as that would
lead to inefficient constructions in
these settings
the dream especially from a
cryptographic point of view would be to
have information theoretic two-source
extractors where both sources can have
as low as poly logarithmic main entropy
and yet the
error would be negligible in n and the
running time of the extractor
would would still remain polynomial
alternatively this means that we'd like
the running time of the extractor to be
inversely proportional to the log of 1
over epsilon
it is unclear if this is possible
information theoretically
and at least appears to be a hard
problem
so while we work on trying to solve this
a natural question is whether two source
extractors with negligible error
with low main entropy can be achieved
under computational assumptions
prior work has indicated that if the
assumptions are sufficiently strong then
the answer is yes
in particular assuming an optimally
exponentially hard one-way permutation
kali lee and rao showed that one can in
fact obtain negligible error extractors
with forming entropy epsilon n where
epsilon is smaller than half
more recently
under the sub exponential hardness of
ddh in joint work with ankit gerg and
yail kalai we showed that one can weaken
the assumption to sub exponential ddh
but this comes at the cost of assuming
the existence of a common random string
in more detail
this involves a trusted setup phase
where a random string is sampled
uniformly and fixed once and for all
then a source distribution can be
sampled arbitrarily depending on the
string
this actually differs from the setting
of seeded extractors but crucially the
source and seed must be
independent of each other
and so what this model basically does is
reduce the need for true randomness to a
single one-time requirement
in that work the amount of entropy that
we could work with was sublinear for the
first source and poly logarithmic for
the second one
and like i said before ideally one would
like to be able to deal with polylog
arithmic men entropy for both sources
and yet achieve negligible error
subsequently agarwal at all obtained
sublinear entropy assuming
quasipolynomial ddh and obtain
extractors for poly logarithmic main
entropy sources assuming optimally hard
collision resistant hashing and these
are essentially exponential hardness
assumptions
this brings me to the first part of our
work where we perform a different
analysis of the gkk extractor to obtain
improved parameters
just like in
gkk which is the work i was just telling
you about we also focus on the crs model
in this model we perform a different
analysis of the gkk extractor
while theirs was more general in some
sense ours is more tailored to their
specific construction
in contrast with gkk we are able to
handle balanced sources meaning both
sources are allowed to have the same
length whereas gkk explicitly required
some sort of imbalance between the
sources
moreover each source only needs to have
poly logarithmic mean entropy on the
other hand the analysis in gkk
required
sublinear entropy in one of the sources
and finally
our extractors just like the our
analysis just like the one in gkk shows
that the extractor has negligible in n
error
we also obtain improved parameters
albeit in the computational setting for
new types of primitives where randomness
is required to be extracted even in the
presence of adversarial attacks
before going into the details of our
analysis let me give you a high level
overview of the gk extractor
they build their extractor in two steps
the first is to build what is called a
computational non-malleable extractor
for
relatively high entropy sources in the
crs model
this is done by repurposing a
construction due to brevard veneto
a non-valuable extractor is a
strengthened version of an extractor
that we will define in more detail on
upcoming slides
for now once they have this
non-malleable extractor in the crs model
they apply a template of benaroya at all
to compile any non-malleable extractor
for sufficiently high entropy sources
into a two source extractor for low
entropy sources
this template was originally designed
for the information theoretic setting
but gkk show how to apply it to the
computational setting in the crs model
both these steps they show can be done
while only obtained by with the error
being only negligible
we will now go ahead and define what a
non-malleable extractor is
a non-malleable extractor can be seeded
that is involve an entropic source and a
uniform seed
or b2 source
that is involve two independent entropic
sources
for the purpose of this talk we will
only consider strong seeded
non-malleable extractors for which we
have the following definition
just like a seeded extractor a
non-malleable extractor on input x
sampled from the source distribution and
a seed outputs a new output something
that's supposed to be uniformly random
but the security requirement here is
stronger this requirement is that the
output of the non-malleable extractor be
indistinguishable from uniform even
given
access to an oracle
this oracle can be queried on any string
y that is not equal to the seed and it
returns the output of the non-malleable
extractor computed on x and y
in the information theoretic setting one
typically needs to bound the number of
times the adversary can query such an
oracle in the computational setting
non-malleable extractors can be defined
similarly
like the information theoretic setting
they can be seeded or to source
again for the purposes of this talk we
will care about strong seeded
non-malleable extractors
with computational indistinguishability
from uniform in the crs model
the one key difference from the
information theoretic setting besides
the existence of a crs will be that the
adversary will be allowed to query this
oracle an arbitrary polynomial number of
times and we will have no
explicit a priori upper bound on this
polynomial
this brings me back to the gk template
for computational two source extractors
with negligible error recall that there
were two steps the first step built
computational non-malleable extractors
for high entropy sources in the crs
model
and the second one compiled any
computational non-malleable extractors
to two source extractors for low entropy
sources
now the second step actually was based
on a blueprint first introduced in the
work of ben aroya at all
and
it turns out that the proof technique of
binauroa at all crucially had an
inefficient
reduction which means that given an
efficient adversary for the two source
extractor they actually ended up
building an unbounded adversary for
against the non-malleable extractor
now while this works well in the
information theoretic setting it breaks
down completely when the non-malleable
extractor is only computationally secure
because of the lack of an efficient
reduction
to counter this barrier
gkk used the leakage lemma of generics
and jet f petrozag and chungatol to
efficiently simulate inefficient steps
in the reduction of benaroya at all
and it is this use that led to them
requiring unbalanced sources and
was one of the reasons that
they their analysis did not achieve poly
logarithmic mean entropy
in the new analysis in this current work
we give up on having step 2 be a general
compiler that compiles any computational
non-malleable extractor to a two-source
extractor
instead we
give a more specific analysis that is
specific to the non-malleable extractor
obtained in step one
this allows us to perform a monolithic
analysis of steps one and two together
first stripping off all computational
exp components until we obtain an
information theoretic
hypothetical experiment and it is only
in this experiment that we must invert
the dispersal
this allows us to sidestep the need for
inefficiencies and
in the binaural at all transformation
and make a more optimal use of our
computational resources
unfortunately i don't have time to go
into further details of this analysis in
the rest of this talk i'm going to talk
about some of the applications of these
techniques to other settings to other
extractor settings
the first setting is that of network
extractors
in a network extractor protocol there is
a set of processors that each have
independent sources
they would like to communicate with each
other potentially in several rounds such
that at the end of this
communication they each end up with what
is supposedly a uniformly random string
in this setting
an adversary is allowed to corrupt some
subset of the players and the guarantee
that is typically desired is that the
outputs of honest parties be close to
uniform even conditioned on the view of
these adversaries
that is given the transcript and the
adversarial source distributions the
output of honest players is required to
still be indistinguishable from uniform
let me now describe some prior work on
network extractable network extractors
this concept was uh introduced dating
back to the works of doris and oliveira
and goldwater at all but was explicitly
studied in the works of kalai starting
with the work of kalai at all
who obtained network extractors for
sources with min entropy 2 to the log n
to the epsilon but where only a fraction
of honest parties obtained uniformly
random bits
in contrast we would like all honest
parties to obtain uniform randomness
the recent work of goya lethal
tackled exactly this problem where they
were able to have all honest parties
obtain uniform randomness but needed
relatively high min entropy
in the computational setting the work of
kalai
lee and rao showed how to obtain
network extractors where all parties
obtain uniform randomness but assuming
omega n min entropy and assuming
exponential hardness of one-way
permutations
in this work using techniques that are
very similar to our construct to the
construction of two source extractors we
obtain a one-round network extractor
protocol with negligible error
for up to polynomially many parties
that tolerates up to all but two
corruptions
meaning that we require only two parties
to be honest this is optimal because
recall that
in the setting of a single honest party
this boils down to the problem of
deterministic extractors which cannot
exist
moreover we require each source to only
have polylog arrhythmic min entropy and
assume the sub exponential hardness of
ddh
our second application is to the setting
of extractors for adversarial sources
here one considers many sources some of
which may be adversarial but the
guarantee is that there are at least
some k honest sources again k must be at
least two and the remaining sources can
be adversarially chosen depending on the
honest sources in particular each
adversarial source is allowed to depend
on up to d honest sources and the
resulting extractor is called a kd
extractor
the guarantee that is required in this
setting is that the output of the
extractor applied to all these sources
where some of the sources may be
adversarial be close to uniform
in the information theoretic setting
this problem was introduced and studied
in the work of chatopathy at all who
obtained
adversarial source extractors for a
setting of at least
p to the one minus r on a sources out of
a total of p sources where r is a
constant
and where each corrupted source was
allowed to depend on at most k to the r
sources
and they were able to obtain such
extractors for the setting of
polylogarithmic min entropy
on the other hand in the computational
setting our work assuming
sub-exponential hardness of ddh
achieves adversarial source extractors
where there are two honest sources out
of a total of p sources
each corrupted source depends on at most
one of the two sources
and we achieve poly logarithmic main
entropy with negligible error
let me conclude with some open problems
that i find exciting
the first is whether we can eliminate
the crs and
still rely on nice assumptions like ddh
the second is whether we can eliminate
the need for sub-exponential hardness
and only rely on polynomial hardness
assumptions
and finally can we explore relationships
of these objects with other primitives
like leakage resilient codes
non-malleable codes
in the computational setting as well as
other cryptographic primitives such as
non-malleable commitments
that brings me to the end
my talk thank you