hi i'm sarah wrote and i'll be
presenting moss the modular security
specifications framework
this is joint work with professor amir
harrisburg from the university of
connecticut
hemi leibovite from barline university
and professor evacetta from trinity
college
we know that proofs are critical to
ensure security and improving the
security of well-defined cryptographic
primitives like set random functions and
encryption schemes for a long time for
example probabilistic encryption by
goldwester and ricali was published
already in 1984.
so probable security is well established
and we also know that bringing the
security of a primitive is not enough to
guarantee the security of a whole system
or protocol using the primitive and
there have been many failures of systems
which were not proven secure
so ideally we would like provably secure
protocols as well
but unfortunately many applied protocols
are not proven secure
and admittedly proving the security of
applied protocols is not easy we can
make subtle mistakes and the protocols
themselves and the specifications which
include assumptions and goals
can be quite complex and in addition
defining specifications which accurately
reflect real world environment
assumptions for example about
communication and synchronization
is not trivial so altogether this can
discourage people from
trying to prove the security of
protocols
in order to prove the security of
protocols though we need to define
um what we're proving so we need to
define the protocol specifications
and there are a few existing approaches
um to protocol specifications
the first one is the informal approach
in which we list the
specifications as descriptions
and words
and your specifications include the
assumptions and goals
and we use models to refer to the
assumptions so we have adversary models
like men in the middle communication
models like reliable communication
synchronization models like boundary
drive clocks
initialization models like shared keys
and so on and we use requirements to
refer to the goals so you can have
generic requirements which can apply to
multiple protocols
like indistinguishability
um and you can have more specific
requirements like authenticated
broadcast for a broadcasting protocol
so going back to how we can define
specifications the first way is to write
a list of descriptions of the
assumptions in words and then a list of
the goals
and this separates the assumptions from
but it doesn't facilitate probable
security but this is the approach that
we're used to and which is used in
systems papers where the models and
requirements are informally defined
properties in english
which is natural and easy to understand
for people
but informal arguments can be misleading
can overlook things and it can be
difficult to tell if they're correct and
if each paper defines their own
specifications it can be hard to tell if
they're comparable
second is the game based approach in
which we define a game for each goal are
for multiple goals and the game includes
the assumptions as well
so the assumptions and goals are
combined and the game is kind of
monolithic in the sense that all the
assumptions and the goal are defined
together
and or even all the assumptions all the
goals are defined together in one game
but it does approval security although
we don't have general compositions
the third approach is a simulation based
approach
where we show the pro that the protocol
is indistinguishable from an ideal
system or an id functionality and you
see
an ideal functionality is a description
of what the protocol should do
as a an ideal machine
so it specifies what what outputs it
should ideally have
and this is also monolithic because all
the assumptions
and even all the goals too is are
defined together in one ideal
functionality
but it does have approval security and
you can also
have secure compositions which is an
important feature of uc
both for applied and theoretical
protocols
um because we often build protocols out
of smaller pieces or we design a
cryptographic primitive using another
cryptographic primitive so we want to be
able to prove
based on the security of the smaller
pieces that the bigger system or
protocol is secure
and uc has secure compositions
and finally uh in this work we present
moss
which is game based and it uses
predicate so we have model predicates
and requirement predicates
and in contrast to the typical game
based approach moss
has
separate models and requirements so it
separates the models and requirements
and notice that this is similar to the
informal approach where we can list the
models and requirements
but now these are formal models and
requirements which are well defined
using predicates
are not descriptions in english
and we can prove security
and currently we do not have
composability but we have some intuition
and are optimistic that it can be done
so what is moss moss stands for modular
security specifications framework and
it's a game-based framework with
well-defined formal modular
specifications
um and it's in game based because we
found it more convenient to use
game-based definitions
but there is an interesting question for
the future of whether we can have
modular simulation-based specifications
as well
but moss is game-based modular and
separates the execution process models
and requirements so these three
components are independent
and models and requirements themselves
are modular also so we can for example
combine models together easily
and it'll be more clear what i mean by
combine
after
i believe after i
define models and requirements in moss
but notice that this modularity has
several benefits
we can have gradual development of
specifications
which can be useful because oftentimes
we first simplify a complex problem and
then gradually make it more realistic so
we can for example start with a stronger
model
and prove a weaker requirement and then
work towards a
weaker model and prove a stronger
requirement
and
maybe it was intentionally simplified or
or the assumptions and goals changed
over time so it can be convenient to
reuse previous definitions and only
change what's needed
and we can reuse models and requirements
across works to save time and space
and make the results easier to compare
which might not be so easy with
even monolithic games idm
functionalities in uc and even more with
the informal approach
so now you know what moss is let me tell
you a bit more about how moss works
starting with the execution process
and then
models and requirements
so this is a high level diagram of the
most execution process
and the great the succession process in
the gray box interacts with the
adversary
at the bottom and the protocol at the
top
which are both represented as stateless
functions
and the execution process maintains
their state and then gives them their
state when they're invoked
and we give the parameters params on on
the left to the execution process
which can include security parameters
the key length and other parameters
and then the execution um is run and
it's controlled almost entirely by the
adversary so the adversary can choose
the number of entities inputs operation
clock values
in each round
and
then can see the outputs
the execution is
basically
a sequence of events and in each event
the adversary interacts with the
protocol
and chooses the input operation clock
values and then the protocol is run with
these inputs in the entity state and
returns an output and a new state and
the output is given to the adversary
and this can repeat for as many events
as the adversary wants and then at the
end
the execution process outputs a
transcript t which contains values from
the execution
so the adversary can do a lot and this
is intentional because we don't enforce
models as part of the execution process
instead we define models using
predicates over
the transcript so we can limit what is
allowed in the transcript
and we can this way we use the execution
process in different works which makes
writing and understanding works easier
in contrast to for example
the typical game-based approach where
the execution process is also defined as
part of the game
so and also the execution process is
simpler which is one of our goals that
we want it to be understandable
and we also have a formal description of
the execution process with pseudocode
and it's not that complex but you can
see it in the paper i just want to draw
your attention to lines 12 and 13
where you can see that values are saved
to the transcript t and then the
transcript is returned which includes
the entities operations inputs clock
values
entities
states and other values
and then you can look at these and place
well-defined restrictions on them and
models and requirements
so we talked a lot about models but they
may be abstract so let's look more
closely at what we mean by models in
moss
so first
on the left we have examples of models
which we can define and it's kind of
like a menu where you can pick and
choose the ones that you need
and each model is a clearly
independently defined piece or item on
the menu
and then they're defined using
predicates so you can have adversary
models
um like man in the middle byzantine
threshold you can have communication
models like authenticated communication
reliable communication and others you
can have clock models like boundary
drift or synchronize clocks
you can have secure key initialization
models
and then we enforce a model by looking
at the transcript
of the execution and checking if the
adversary satisfies the model based on
the transcript
and so i'll go over definitions more in
a moment but basically when we assume a
model
we consider only adversaries that
satisfy the model so
only adverse series for which
the transcript satisfies the model with
a sufficient probability
models are independent of the execution
process and requirements
and they're also independent of other
models so like a fault model and a
synchronization model can be completely
separate
and we can also include multiple sub
models in a model
so they're easy to combine and we can
reuse the definitions of models across
systems and works
more specifically a model is a set of
pairs pi beta which we call
specifications
um our pi is a predicate and that has
the base function which specifies the
probability which is allowed for the
adversary to win against the predicate
and since models are set so we can
combine them by taking their union
and the reason for the base function is
that we might want different predicates
to hold with different probabilities for
example confidentiality we might want to
allow the adversary to win with
probability one-half
and for authenticity and we might want
to allow two to the minus l probability
if we're using l-bit tags
um in the protocol and for others you
might just want negligible or zero
probability of winning so then you can
just use the constant zero
and we can define these probabilities
easily in the base functions
so how do we define an adversary
satisfying a model
for the case where the model includes
just one specification we would say that
adversary a satisfies model m
which includes this one specification pi
beta
if for every protocol the probability
that the predicate over the transcript
is false is the most negligibly greater
than the base function
and t here is the transcript output by
running the execution process with the
adversary a and protocol p
and i mean by negligibly i mean
negligibly in the length of the
parameters per params
and then if there are multiple
specifications we can just check this
for each one of them
as an example here is a model which
assumes bounded drip clocks
and the probability function is the
constant 0 here so the adversary should
not break this
ever or only with negligible probability
um and the predicate and algorithm one
checks that the local clock
values which are set by the adversary
and execution are always within delta
clock of the real time which is also set
by the adversary
and also checks that real time is
monotonically increasing over the
execution
and so this is simple and small and
reusable
and there are many situations where you
might want to use this model to assume
boundary drift clocks
okay so now let's look more closely at
requirements
on the left we have examples and
requirements we can define
again it's a nice menu
and we can have generic requirements it
can be used for different protocols
like indistinguishability
a false positive verifiable attribution
can have pki requirements
and this work actually began after
trying to use the game basin simulation
based approaches
for pki specifications which turned out
to be impractical so we designed moss
so you can have accountability
transparency privacy requirements
and we can also have other specific
requirements for specific protocols like
for example authenticated broadcast for
a broadcasting protocol
requirements are defined just like
models and then we check that a protocol
satisfies a requirement
under some specific model
and we basically consider adversaries
which satisfy the model and again we
look at the transcript to see if it
if the requirement is satisfied with
sufficient probability
and since the adversary controls the
execution then by checking
that the adversary satisfies
a model we are effectively checking that
certain assumptions are held during the
execution
so this is how we specify requirements
for a protocol under a model
and requirements are well defined using
predicates like models
and they can be compared and can include
sub-requirements also and the generic
requirements can be reused
so just like for models a requirement is
a set of pairs pi beta which we call
specifications
so these are these pairs of predicates
and probability
functions and for the case where the
requirement includes one specification
we say that a protocol p
satisfies requirement r which includes
this one specification
under model m
and for every adversary a which
satisfies m the probability that the
predicate over the transcript is false
is at most negligibly greater than the
base function
and t is again the transcript output by
the execution with a and p
so as an example here is a delta
transparency requirement which is a bki
requirement
intuitively we say that a certificate
adjusted as though the transparent must
be available to all interested parties
within delta time of its transparency
activation being issued by a proper
authority
below is the delta transparency
predicate
notice that this predicate is more
complicated than the clock drift one but
we can use sub predicates
in this project kit so we have one to
check that an entity is honest when to
confirm public key we want to verify a
certificate of station
so you can also have modularity and
predicates and you can use and reuse the
smaller predicates for example we can
reuse the honest entity predicate and
other pre-ki requirement predicates
so as i've been saying in mostly support
modularity of models and requirements
and we have some lemons which basically
formalize the intuitive modularity
properties you thought you might expect
so you can know some properties about
combined or stronger or weaker models
and requirements and i'll just talk
about two of them here the first one is
the requirement model monotonicity llama
which says that for any two models where
m is a subset of m hat so
m hat is a stronger model and m is the
weaker model and any requirement are
if the protocol satisfies the
requirement under the weaker model then
it must satisfy it under the stronger
model
and the second lemma is the requirement
it's union level
which is that for any two models mrn
prime and any requirements are in our
prime
if we take the combined uh the union of
the two models in the union of the two
requirements
and if the protocol satisfies the first
requirement under the first model
and also satisfies the second
requirement under the second model
then it satisfies the combined
requirement under the combined model
and you can see the paper for more
llamas and proofs
so let me describe an analysis example
using moss
so we have these
separate focus models and requirements
and
this facilitates gradual protocol
development and analysis and as an
example
we analyzed a simple authenticated
broadcast protocol which i call p here
and we did it in three steps under three
models so in the first step
we use the model that assumes secure key
sharing
and initialization assumptions
and then we showed that the protocol
ensures authenticity under this model
and then the second step we assumed also
a bounded clock drift
so we didn't define a whole new model we
used the union of the
model from the first step and the
boundary clock drift model
and this and then we showed that the
protocol achieves freshness also so
authenticity and freshness under this
stronger model and then the third step
um we also added assumptions about
bounded delay communication and the
first interval and showed that the
protocol ensures
correct boundary delay delivery of the
broadcast messages
under the stronger model
so let me mention three additional
features of moss which i didn't discuss
so far
the first one is um that the execution
process can be extended
so we define a set of execution process
operations
which we call x and then we can add
operations which the adversary can use
to this set which adds additional
functionality which the basic execution
process doesn't provide
um our support for example entity
corruptions confidentiality and shared
keys
and one reason for this design is that
it keeps the basic execution process
simple
so that it can be understood by people
not used to formal model models and
definitions
and uh sometimes we don't need the
extra
uh functionality like for example you
could have added confidentiality to the
basic execution process but it's not
always needed for
different protocols which only care
about authentication and not
confidentiality
so
we only left this for the full execution
process using these x operations
and the full execution process includes
everything that the basic execution
process has
on second mos also supports secure
concrete security facing a small
extension to the execution
and concrete security definitions for
model satisfying requirements satisfying
are quite similar to the asymptotic ones
but they include concrete bounds
and this is important to provide support
for applied protocols so that we can
have concrete bounds and concrete values
of parameters
and third um we can also ensure
polynomial time execution
so
because we have this problem
that even if the adversarian protocol a
polynomial the total runtime
might not be polynomial because over the
execution there's this interaction and
the outputs become inputs
and so the inputs can keep growing and
eventually allow exponential time
for
for the
for a for the adversarial protocol
in the size of the original parameters
or for both of them and this should be
prevented for a synthetic analysis
and we have considered this in moss
mouse does have some limitations and we
have some errors for future work so the
first one is that currently we don't
have composability like uc does
and this is a useful feature for
protocol design and analysis
and actually uncomposibility also
provides modularity but its modularity
for protocol design rather than
for um the specifications so it'll be
great to have this and also so and as i
said we have some intuition and our
optimistic that it can be done
and the second area is that moss is game
based but some definitions seem to
require stimulation like zero knowledge
and as i said there is the open question
of whether we can have all modular
simulation-based specifications also
and these could be modular
specifications and simulation based
frameworks
and or extending moss to support
simulation-based specifications
and third we don't have automated tools
for computer-aided analysis so these
could be developed either for
translating mass specifications to other
forms supported by such tools and or
tools for moss directly
in conclusion omos facilitates modular
security specifications for protocols
it allows verbal security for practical
protocols
which may assume complex models which
might include communication
synchronization
faults and other assumptions
and it allows the reuse of models and
requirement definitions across protocols
and across works
which can also make it easier to compare
words
of course please see the paper
for details and proofs
and thank you