hey everyone uh i'm excited to talk to
you today about our work on
non-interactive batch arguments for np
from standard assumptions this is joint
work with my wonderful collaborators
abhishek
so before we get into the question of
assumptions uh what is a non-attractive
batch argument for np
uh consider the scenario here between
alice and bob where both of them have
access to a common reference string or
crs
further alice has case at instances and
wants to convince bob that all of them
are true
specifically that there's a weakness for
each of them such that the circuit c on
input the instance x and the
corresponding maintenance w outputs one
so the budgeting is essentially over
multiple np instances
so the non-interactive nature indicates
that alice just sends over a single
message referred to as a proof to bob
and then bob can verify given this proof
in fact we're going to require something
stronger we're going to say that the
proof must be publicly verifiable
meaning not just bob but anyone with
access to the crf should be able to
verify the proof
so the argument indicates that
any computationally bounded cheating
alice cannot produce an accepting proof
if even one of the statements are false
right
so without further constraints this is
actually fairly easy to achieve alice
just sends over all the witnesses w1 to
wk to bob who can then take the
witnesses and then verify each of them
one by one
so for any non-trivial protocol we
actually require that the length of the
proof that either sends over has to be
significantly smaller than the length of
the combined witness of the case
statements
okay
and what about bob's verifier
verification time
means at the very least to read all the
case statements and we say that the
overhead after
reading the case statements is only some
polynomial in the
length of the proof
okay
so what do we actually know about this
problem from fireworks
uh so there's this uh wonderful line of
work started by rand goldberg
which considers interactive batch groups
so it's interactive in the sense that
alice and bob now are able to
communicate over multiple rounds
uh but the security property is
something actually stronger
that
you know security is required to hold
even against the computationally
unbounded cheating address
so
this line of work essentially constructs
interactive batch proofs for this class
up which is a subclass of np where each
statement has only a unique witness
and then we have sustained
non-destructive arguments or synonyms
for np
uh these are non-interactive arguments
where the length of the proof is
significantly smaller than the
size of the np witness
so now if we were to take our uh
batching of saturn systems and write it
as a
single language uh defined here you know
it's a natural way of
writing this language out we just
concatenate all k instances and the
corresponding witness is the
concatenation of the three witnesses
and then the slog property essentially
gives us a you know a non-reactive batch
argument because the length of the proof
is going to be significantly smaller
than the length of the combine with
unfortunately we know of stocks but np
based on these strong non-falsifiable
assumptions or in the random oracle
model
we actually relax the requirements from
the verifier for it to be designated
verify meaning that only your designated
bob can
verify the proof
then we actually have non-interactive
batch arguments for np based on fairly
standard assumptions uh starting with
this work of bratiski homebrew
and if you want to go to the publicly
very family setting we had this
wonderful recent work of kalai panetta
who considered
you know construct non-attractive batch
arguments for np based on new
non-standard assumptions uh this i
should note that these are falsifiable
assumptions
on groups with bilinear maps
uh so given the state of affairs it's
natural to ask are there you know
non-interactive batch arguments for np
based solely on standard assumptions
and in our work we show that assuming
the quadratic reciprocity assumption uh
in addition to either the learning with
errors or sub-exponential hardness of
the decision of different
assumption there exists a non-attractive
batch argument for np
where the size of the proof grows
roughly square root in the number of
instances times the circuit size where
the circuit is the circuit in the
corresponding definition of the saturn
states
uh you can see that
with
large values of k this is actually
significantly better than the triggered
solution
um so
i don't have time to go over all the
details in our paper so let me start off
with some key insights
and what we actually want to do is
leverage all this exciting recent work
uh surrounding the future made
transformation and specifically the
security of the future transformation
so for those unaware uh feared shamir uh
transform lets you start with an
interactive protocol between approval
and verifier where the verifiers
messages are just random strings and
then it allows you to make a
non-interactive in the crs model where
the cr simply contains a description of
the hash function
and so the prover can generate the
verified messages non-interactively by
applying the hash function
the present in the crs on the transcript
so far
and this is publicly verifiable since
anyone with access to the crs can verify
the proof
so the security of this transformation
has seemed like some really really
exciting recent progress
uh you know with connections to this
correlation intractable hash function
and there's some really cool work and as
you can see this is a long line of work
and i will touch upon this uh briefly
later on in the talk
but for now let's focus on the
communication in both the protocols as
you can see the total communication from
the proven to the verifier remains
unchanged
um
with the transformation so that gives us
the following idea let's start with an
interactive protocol for batch np
uh then hopefully we can apply the
futurme transformation and then use
hopefully one of these uh
you know these cool exciting recent
works and proof security of the
transform protocol
so unfortunately uh
for all of these works uh
you know the security is only proven if
one starts with a protocol that's
statistically secure these are also
called interactive proofs and as you're
seeing these mean that even an unbounded
cheating approver should not be able to
convince a verifier of false statements
uh i should note that there's no
inherent reason for this requirement
this is just what we know from the
state of art
so you might say okay this is not so bad
but like i already indicated based on
the prior works that we don't actually
know of interactive proof so batch np
the best web that we have is our
ub
so
instead we choose a different starting
point for applying the featuring
transformation that we call dual mode
batch arguments
so since the resultant protocol is
anyway going to be in crs let's start
with an interactive protocol in the crs
model that's going to achieve
computational security meaning that any
computationally bounded cheat improver
cannot convince the verifier of false
state
so where's the dual mode so dual mode
comes in to how the cr is generated so
what you have on the left is the normal
mode
of the crs generation
and this is the mode that's used with
the actual protocol execution
and what you see on the right is the
trapdoor mode specified by 7xi and this
is going to be used solely in the
security proof
so for starters you shouldn't really be
able to tell which mode the crs was
generated in
especially if you're computationally
bound
so what's so special about the track
road mode so the tracker mode guarantees
statistical security at index i
meaning that even a computationally
unbounded cheating prover cannot take
the verifier except if the in statement
is false
so for all intents and purposes in the
trapdoor mode at least for index i what
we have on the right is an interactive
proof
so this then provides the following
security intuition for applying the
future transformation to dual mode batch
arguments
uh when the prover is trying to
specifically cheat on the i instance
meaning that the ith instance is
actually false
so we make this computational
indistinguishable switch to the trapdoor
mode at index i for the crs and then
hopefully we can rely on the future new
transformation uh because you know we've
just talked about how this uh
trapdoor mode crs protocol is actually
statistically sound
and then you know we have a
non-attractive protocol
so
what does this dual mode batch argument
look like
so recall that the prover is trying to
batch proof uh k statements and we have
you know okay witnesses w1 to wk
uh each of like them and we're going to
write them out in these rows that you
see here
the crs in our dual board match argument
is just going to correspond to a
commitment key k and we'll see shortly
what this commitment scheme is
uh and the next thing that we're going
to do is we're going to have the prover
commit to the witnesses in a column wise
fashion meaning that each cj
is a commitment to a k length vector so
there are m such uh
cj's
and the prover then sends across c1 to
cm after the verifier
we require the length of
this commitment depends only poly
logarithmically on k
so next the proven the verifier interact
via this information theory component
meaning that it doesn't require any
cryptographic assumptions we'll leave
this as a black box for now and i'll
come back to this later on
and then
some function f which is determined by
this information theory component is
specified and the program is required to
open
the function f applied to each of the
witnesses
and then there is some final checks
performed by the wi-fi
so what about this commitment scheme
that we have so the commitment scheme
that we're going to use is going to be a
somewhere statistically binding
commitment scheme
so these commitment schemes have already
an inbuilt tractor mode so if you
specify an index i you get a commitment
key ki star
and if you use ki star to
compute the commitments then it's
statistically binding at the index act
uh meaning that
with high priority there is a unique
opening to the ix position of the vector
so given how the you know the
commitments have been structured what we
essentially have is if each of these
columns you use ki start you have a
single row that's statistically binding
here it's going to be the i through
so we have this
it's statistically binding nwi and now
if you look at the rest of the protocol
in the triangular mod everything is
information kit
so for the iit instance we have an
interactive proof as design
so to be actually able to compress it we
want this information theoretic
component to be futurely friendly so
that we can essentially use
some prior works and then compress it uh
using a hash function based on the lwe
or sub exponential dth and i'm going to
talk about this next
uh but i just want to say that
we are going to actually also
construct these some ssd binding
commitments with an appropriate opening
to f
uh based on the quadratic reciprocity
assumption and i'll come back to what f
is and we'll
touch upon this uh later on again
okay
so in whatever remaining time i have let
me give you some technical details
regarding the information theoretic
component that we use in our protocol
uh so recall this is the template that i
just showed you and we have this
information theory component that i was
going to talk about
so the first thing to note is that you
know just gonna have one information
third component we just we're gonna have
k copies of the same information
theoretic component and correspondingly
k openings
and uh you know for the purposes of this
talk it suffices to look at a specific
uh a single copy of
this
information theoretic component
specifically the ith club because that's
mainly what i care about proving
security
but before i can go uh into any further
detail i need to take a small detour and
revisit something that i earlier
mentioned in the talk uh regarding the
future transformation
uh remember this is the slide that i've
shown you for the future transform
and how does one really go about proving
the security of this transformation
so let's look at the interactive
protocol on the left
uh and let's uh define this notion of a
set of bad betas
so what does that mean so once uh
alpha is sent
for statements that are not in the
language we say a beta is bad
if there exists a gamma that leads the
verified to accept
so you know verify is accepting on false
statements
so in the interactive setting the prover
has no control over the betas it sends
over an alpha and the verifier sends
over a random data
but that's no longer quite true in the
non-attractive setting because what the
prover can do is it can try different
values of alpha
until it reaches uh gets a
beta that it likes
so essentially for security we want that
any computationally bounded cheating
prover cannot find an alpha
such that it results in a bad bit
so if the hash function satisfies this
condition we say that the hash function
is correlation intractable for bad betas
so this is then the following uh
template for
proving a protocol
with the futurenet transformation so we
start with the protocol that has the set
of corresponding by betas and then
we then have a hash function that's
correlation and interactable for this
set of bad beta
and that gives us a
transform protocol that's secure
so we actually need to construct these
hash functions h and so what do we know
about them so it turns out if this set
of bad betas can actually be computed in
polynomial time then this wonderful work
of uh pikachu and shahan
show us that you can construct these
hash functions simply based on nwe
and if further
these bad betas can be computed in low
depth specifically in dc 0
and these are circuits that are
polynomial size
but have constant depth
with threshold gates in them
then you can actually construct such
hash functions simply based
on some exponential ddh and this is
wonderful work
recent very very recent work by
so
uh given this understanding of you know
what kind of bad uh betas and what kind
of assumptions that we have
so if we want this uh information
genetic component to be future family
all we need to show is essentially that
the corresponding bad
betas can be computable in pcc
um so the building block of this
information theory component is going to
be this wonderful protocol introduced by
shetty called spartan and specifically
we're going to focus on the information
theoretic component of the spartan
protocol called spartan code
so just for context uh you know spartan
is an interactive protocol used to prove
np statements
so in the spartan protocol note that the
function f is simply a linear
combination of the bits of the witness
and the coefficients of the linear
combinations that the sigma js are
specified by this partition
so for those familiar the spartan code
primarily consists of the sum check
protocol
but you know for this talk i'm going to
keep it at a very very high level
and i'm going to say that what the
prover sends across in most messages is
some polynomial g of x and what the
verifier sends across is a random data
that is samples from some specified
field f
so
we talked about bad beta so how do we
define the set of bad betas the set of
bad betas is defined to be all the roots
of this polynomial uh g of x minus g
star of x
g of x as you can see is clearly the
polynomial that the prover said and g
star of x is the true polynomial and
honest proof of this
i won't go into the details but this is
how essentially how g star is defined
so in our work we show that
once you start with an appropriate field
f
the set of bad betas can actually be
computed in dc 0 for the spartan core
protocol
i want to reemphasize that you know this
is a
very very high level overview of both
the spartan and some of the ideas that
we use in our work
and i would defer you to the paper for
details
okay so putting everything together uh
we saw that the function f
for our protocol is simply a linear
combination of witness bits
uh so in fact what we have is uh or what
we require is a ssb with linearly
romantic opening that we construct based
on quadratic reciprocity
uh it actually requires some additional
properties that i'm really not going to
get into because that's going to make
things a little more complex again
you know i request you to look at the
paper for further details
about that
and then for the information theory
component we run k copies of the spartan
core
uh and show that
the set of bad betas can actually be
computed in dc 0 for this
so this then results in our main theorem
which i've restated here
and i just want to say that in
follow-up work
we actually
construct batch arguments for np with
improved parameters and you know
furthermore we actually show that
you can apply these batch arguments to
construct delegation schemes for all
polynomials and competition
um
and that's all i have today uh feel free
to send me or any of my co-authors for
that matter
an email if you have any questions and
one of us will also be available to
answer questions during the live session
so thank you so much for listening