hello everyone i'll talk about
non-malleable codes for bounded
polynomial depth tempering this is based
on joint work with dana dachman soled
and rafael pass
so the problem that we'll be talking
about is really simple it's just two
parties the sender and the receiver the
sender wants to transmit the message to
the receiver
what makes the problem challenging is
that we consider a main dimensional
attacker or a tempering function you can
think of it
that sits on the channel intercepts all
the messages that come from the sender
inspect them in any way it wants
and then
speeds out a possibly different message
to the receiver
what we want to guarantee is that the
adversary this adversary that sits on
the channel
cannot meaningfully modify the message
and what we mean by meaningful
modification
is that we want to make sure that the
decoded message that the receiver sees
in the end of this game is with very
high probability either the original
message that was intended to say to be
sent by the sender or something
completely unrelated and notice that
the adversary could always just
intercept the message that the sender
sent
throw it away and just send something
completely random to the receiver in
this case we want the message received
by the receiver to be completely
unrelated because it's independent of
the message underlying the real code
word
or we want to make sure that the
adversary no matter what it did he tried
to modify the underlying message it
could it didn't succeed
so this this primitive is called the
non-valuable code it was introduced
about
10 years or a little bit more
10 years ago by zimbabwe checking weeks
and it has received significant
attention from various communities in
the past decade or so
it was a for instance it was used as a
building block
in modern constructions of multi-source
extractors uh interesting connections
with active combinatories have been
rediscovered and it was
more naturally
used as a as the building block in
various non-malleable cryptographic
constructions
so this is a very useful and important
notion
but before i tell you what we know about
it i wanted to draw some connections
with
existing primitives that you may have
heard about and explain the differences
so two primitives that i'll be talking
about or comparing normal about those
two are error correcting codes and
non-valuable commitments
so the first distinction between these
three primitives comes in the
in the class of adversaries that we're
willing to tolerate
in an error correcting code the
adversary sees the code word but is
limited in the way it can
modify it or tamper with it and
specifically usually what we allow the
adversary to do is to choose a subset of
coordinates let's say one half of them
or one third of them or some fraction of
the cold war of the symbols in the
message and modify them arbitrarily and
we want to guarantee that the receiver
can recover the original message
non-variable commitments the address
receives the message that is sent from a
sender to receiver
but it can apply an arbitrary polynomial
time function on it so it's not limited
in the way that it accesses the code
word
it can do arbitrary computation and
do anything on it as long as it's
polynomial size and in a non variable
codes as you we're going to see the
adversary somewhere in between
it's it's not an arbitrary polynomial
side machine
and but we hope that it's going to be a
little bit more than just changing the
subset of
coordinates and the
the second
difference between these three primitive
is that we want to be able to
decode and this is why for instance this
is why none other commitments you can
allow arbitrary polynomial sized
adversary it's because we don't really
expect the the receiver to decode it's
just a commitment
in non-valuable code and in the error
correcting code we do expect the
receiver to decode
and this is why we cannot support any
polynomial size of factor okay so this
is uh just to put things a little bit in
context
so here's uh some very basic facts about
non-valuable codes
so first of all like i
as i alluded to in the previous slide if
decoding can be done efficiently
then there's no way to support all
polynomial size tempering functions
right because the adversary could decode
if it's possible in doing doing
polynomial time
and if the message is equal to some
predefined message let's say it's all
zeros then we just output the all zero
string
and otherwise we output the code word by
any meaningful notion of uh nominability
this is a
valid tempering
tempering attack
and that's why we have to limit
the adversary in some way if we're
willing to
if we're
requiring that decoding is polynomial
so there has been
many suggestions as to how to limit the
adversary so
for instance we can limit its running
time it can run
slower than the decoding
it might have a small space namely it
might
use less space than is required by the
decoding or we can limit in some way the
access to the code word for instance
we can allow an enter temperable common
reference string
or we
limit the
way the adversary
accesses the code word not in the amount
of things he can modify but in the way
it can modify them and this is where
for instance one useful note in it
is split state adversaries
so here are some results that are known
so first of all in the very original
work of zimbabwe education weeks it was
already shown that this primitive exists
it lives non-explicitly namely if you
choose a random encoding scheme it will
be secure for any
circuit of size 2 to then over 2.
and what about explicit construction so
there has been lots of work and here are
a couple of examples
if we limit the adversary to be a
polynomial size circuit an arbitrary
polynomial size circuit
and then we can support the we can
indeed guarantee
if we assume an untemperable crs so we
assume there is some
crs that's written in the sky
it had to be bigger than the size of the
adversary so
bigger than this s
and the adversary is not allowed to
tamper with it and it's not allowed it
won't be even allowed to read it because
it's so long
but
there is an explicit construction
and there is there's also explicit
constructions in in models with some
something like
like a random oracle model if we assume
the adversary has bounded space so we
cannot just store the whole random
workflow in memory
and then more recent work uh focused on
constructing online level codes
uh against classes complexity classes
adversaries that come from some
well-known complexity classes like ac 0
and c0 and the most up-to-date results
is
are even construction secure almost
again and against nc one so it's log
depth circuits
specifically they obtain log over log
log depth circuits
so we have many constructions under many
assumptions some of them are a
trustworthy assumption some of them are
are
assumptions about
the explicitness of the construction
and
arguably the holy grail or this whole
line of work where it leads to
is a construction of an explicit
non-valuable code right so we first want
an explicit construction
of a non-variable code and we wanted to
be secure against the best we can hope
for which is
just a bounded polynomial size circuit
so i give you a bound let's say end to
the 100
and i want to construct an explicit
nonvariable code
that is secure or non-variable for all
attackers of size up to n to the 100.
so this is the the holy grail you want
to be able to do this for any polynomial
not just 10 to the 100
and ideally
we would like the encoding
to run in fixed polynomial time so
independent of this 100 so maybe n to
the fifth for any fixed polynomial
which bounds the running time of the
adversary
but as i mentioned decoding has to take
longer so
we want encoding in fixed point on time
and decoding to depend on the
class of the adversary
so this is the holy grail
so what has been done towards this holy
grail and
so the first attempt to really achieve
something that looks like the
comes close to the holy grail was done
by boletal about three years ago
they suggested well let's use crypto to
see if this task is even possible
and they indeed obtained the result
they showed that
if you assume
public encryption
and non-interactive zero knowledge
plus some average case hardness for the
class of attackers that you're willing
to
uh
to capture
then there exists a non-valuable code
for this class of attackers
this is a great result
in terms of feasibility the downside
is that the
is that they're using a public
encryption scheme and their music
which both of which rely on
crs in the case of a public encryption
scheme it's just a public health scheme
and both of them have to be
written in the sky in some sense and
they're untemporable
by the attacker
the advantage of this construction over
previous ones is that here the crs is
short it's independent of the class f
so this was the first result and then
the follow-up by bullet al
was the construction in the plane model
so right they got rid of the crs
and they got construction in the plane
model albeit they had several cats still
had several caveats
the first is that they relied on p
certificates this certificate is a
rather strong assumption it's a succinct
one message argument for a p for all
polynomial time computations and it's
succinct in the strongest sense that you
can imagine
the proof size is independent of the
computation the
and or the instance right it's just
it's the best notion of success you can
imagine and one candidate for this
construction is michael's cs proof
system when you instantiate
the random market with the complete hash
function
and this is the best of our knowledge
this is the only candidate up to the up
to now to date
so this is a rather strong assumption
and
but they had even ignoring this uh
this strong assumption which perhaps
we're willing to settle for they had a
couple of more uh downsides like one one
was that they obtained normal ability
only for uniform adversaries as opposed
to the standard notion of non-uniform
security against non-uniform attackers
they
only obtain non-variability with inverse
polynomial distinguishing advantage
namely an adversary could perform a
successful tempering attack with with
some inverse polynomial probability
and
lastly both their decoding and encoding
run longer than the adversary
and
optimally we would like to achieve in
coding in fixed polynomial time
so this is what's known about this
problem
what we do we we have like a meta
theorem
that implies a new construction of a
non-malabar code so here are the three
building blocks that we need for our
metatheorem
let me just say that this is not a
generic construction in any of these in
any instantiation of these primitives
wield specific constructions and
specific properties
that i will explain a little bit later
but the general recipes
is very easy to explain in a generic way
so we use three primitives it's a time
of puzzle a one message non-valuable
commitment and the one message zero
knowledge scheme
by one message i mean just single shot
one message and no crs or anything like
that
to be clear a time lock pass is this
method to create puzzles that are
easy to create
but require
some moderate polynomial uh sequential
effort so even if you have
many processors in
even if the addresser has many
processors that he can run in parallel
it's a way to generate
problems that are still hard to solve
as long as the sequential running time
is less than some predefined down
so we have these three primitives
with sub-exponential security and we
obtain the following non-variable code
so for any polynomial t
there exists a null variable code where
the encoding takes time polynomial in
lambda so that is the security parameter
so it's the fixed polynomial
decoding takes time polynomial in t and
lambda
and notice that the dependence on t is
necessary
and we guarantee nonverbality for all
adversaries of size at mostly
so this is really
achieving the holy grail
i mentioned before
and we check all the boxes that you can
imagine we
we achieve non-uniform security
we achieve negligible advantage with
negligible non-valuability like
like what you would expect
we have past encoding uh as i mentioned
and we even get normal ability for
for a larger class of adversaries
because we're using time lock puzzles
we actually get nominability for all
polynomial size adversaries as long as
their depth is operator rebounded so you
only need to bound the depth of the
attacker
namely the further runtime of the
attacker and then you can we can support
arbitrary polynomial size attackers so
this is the main theorem let me tell you
about the specific instantiation that we
have
so these are the three primitives which
imply non-variable code
a non-variable code for boundary
polynomial tempering
we inferentiate the time of puzzles
using repeated squaring assumption the
most well-known construction
and we use two other assumptions the
keyless multi-collisions in hash and the
new way to instantiate the other two
primitives
so all in all we get the construction of
our non-variable code from three
assumptions it's the repeated squaring
assumption
kill its multi-collision resistant hash
and new wave for np
so this is the main result of our paper
let me tell you a little bit about how
the construction works
the construction is very easy to explain
in steps let's first do the time of past
them and see what we get
we encode the message using a time lock
puzzle and we can decode using the
solving procedure of the timeline
function this achieves in terms of
functionality the chips what we want
right we encode really fast and we can
decode within
some
predefined time again to the 100
the problem is that time of puzzles are
not not malleable
so we cannot just uh so we cannot claim
non-valuability they're in fact not
non-valuable
so let's add the component on my level
component to the scheme and
together with the time of puzzling the
encoding let's also commit with a
non-verbal commitment to the message
so this adds some non-valuable
non-malleable component but the problem
is that the coding is independent of it
and the adversary could just ignore it
right it could
tamper with time or puzzle and modify
the output of the experiment so we add a
zero knowledge proof that shows that
um
that the two components
are encoding the same message so the
timer puzzle and the nonliable
commitment are consistent with respect
to the underlying message
but this construction is really in the
spirit of norian level encryption
methods
and and i'll talk a little bit more
about that soon so this is our final
construction
the security definition that we achieve
uh that this the construction achieves
uh is the standard one in the
non-violable community coding literature
there are two experiments that need to
be
distinct indistinguishable the real
world experiment
allows an attacker to obtain a code word
modify it in an arbitrary way and then
the code and the output of the decoding
is the output of the experiment
in the real world experiment there is a
simulator that doesn't know
the underlying message it either outputs
some message and field
which is independent of m or it outputs
the word same same meaning that the user
didn't change anything
and the output of the experiment is
either the original message if
the adversary if the simulator outputs
the same or it's the unrelated message
and field so this is the natural thing
you would expect and this is what you
achieved
here's a couple of words about the main
proof of idea
so i mentioned that the construction is
in the spirit of no nor young double
encryption except that instead of using
two public encryption schemes like they
do we use a non-member commitment then
in time of concept
but
one natural approach for the proof would
be to say okay let's replace the real
decryption with a simulated one and
decryption in our case is decoding so
let's replace the
decoding procedure with a simulated one
but the challenge is that
for us the the simulated decoding
procedure um
is to essentially extract from the
commitment
so the real decoding procedure is to
solve the term of puzzle but the
alternate one would be to break the
commitment and breaking the commitment
is a super polynomial time task while
breaking the time log puzzle is a
polynomial
time task so it's really in
it's really not clear a priori how you
would be able to move to the simulated
decoding procedure without breaking
the scheme security of this game
so here's the problem in detail and
where it comes up
so once we in the proof once we simulate
the zero knowledge proof
we are and we're trying to move to the
to the alternate decoding where we
extract from the
where we extract from the non-member
commitment uh two conditions must be
satisfied
the first is that the extractor of the
non-malleable commitment should not be
able to break their knowledge the second
one is that the simulator should not be
able to break down malleability but we
get two inequalities
also
for all known one messenger zero
knowledge
schemes
for all of them the simulator simulator
running time is larger than the time of
uh then larger than the guarantee of
zero knowledge like the distinct
running time of the
of the distinguisher in the zero
knowledge experiment
and it's a major open problem to
construct one where the inequality is
reversed and the simulator is after
it's really fast
so we cannot use that so if you take the
three inequalities that are written now
you see that the time to extract has to
be much smaller than non-valuability
and which is a contradiction right
because the structure of the commitment
can extract the underlying value and
should and can trivially break normal
ability
so we get a contradiction at least
in the usual
proof strategy
the main idea in the proof is to take
advantage of the specific primitives
that we're using and specifically we're
going to introduce in the crew another
axis of harness specifically in
non-uniformity we're going to
instantiate the primitives in a very
careful way so that
the inequalities that we need work out
what we're going to do is to instantiate
the zero-knowledge system to be zero
knowledge against sub exponential size
attackers
while uh
while showing that simulation can be
done in polynomial size but
using a non-uniform simulator that has
some advice art
non-variability is going to be for a
polynomial size attackers and extraction
will be possible in sub-exponential size
if you stir this for two minutes you'll
see that setting the parameters of the
schemes of the primitives
in this way you indeed satisfy the three
inequalities that we need
extractor cannot break your knowledge
the simulator cannot break
non-variability and the extractor can
break normally
before concluding let me mention a
couple of more technical challenges that
we encounter during the proof the first
challenge is that
the time of puzzles are a polynomial
time primitive an adversary that runs in
polynomial time
can solve the time of puzzle
so in particular the
step in the proof or the the step in the
reduction where we use the hardest of
the time of puzzle
must be implemented in polynomial time
and this seems a priori a little bit
challenging but the point is that the
thumbnail puzzles are polynomial time in
terms of depth or parallel time but they
don't have to be polynomial time in size
namely we instantiate the time of puzzle
in a way
that
it's secure for attackers that have that
might have super polynomial size but
some
polynomial fixed polynomial depth
and this is how we implement this step
in the reduction
the second challenge is that
non-uniformity needs to be dealt with
carefully
and the reason is that the instantiation
of the zero knowledge system that we're
using
because we're in the uniform setting and
the zero knowledge system is a one
message system there's no crs there's no
there's only one message
then the system only satisfies a weak
notion of soundness and this weak notion
of soundness roughly very roughly means
that the adversary might know some
amount of cheating proofs or proofs for
uh valid proofs for false statements but
not too many of them and the proof needs
to take this into account and we need to
deal with it i'll refer to the paper for
more details
so let me summarize our results uh
so the result is a non-valuable code for
all bounded polynomial depth attackers
uh the construction is in the plane
model without any trusted setup
assumptions
the construction can be viewed because
we get hardness for parallel time
for a priori bounded polynomially
bounded parallel time the construction
can be actually viewed as a non-valuable
time lock puzzle so we're taking a
timelock puzzle and we're
making it non-malleable
and in the follow-up work we
it was together with a
frying flight again pass we perform a
thorough study of non-valuable timelock
puzzles we have more efficient
constructions and what is presented here
which is primarily the theoretical and
feasibility results
there we have a really practical and
efficient construction
with very weak set of assumptions
and we also showed that this primitive
is really useful for applications and
for instance we get multi-party fair
quality protocols
and multi-party fare auctions and so on
and
i think that this work uh
introduces a couple of very interesting
open problems the first is to improve
the assumptions prove the underlying
assumptions of course
and mostly the thing to to focus on in
my opinion is the keyless hash function
that
we rely on
and
of course the concrete efficiency of our
scheme is not that great if you use
existing construction existing
instantiation of all the schemes and it
would be interesting to come up with a
with an efficient construction a
practically efficient construction
without setup assumptions
so thank you very much
for listening and have a good day