uh hi i am hussein i will be talking
about a quadratic secret sharing and
quadratic conventional disclosure of
secrets uh this is a joint work with the
almost saved email and the nativity
so i will start by a general
descriptions description of our results
the notation that i will use in this
slide will be familiar clear in a few
slides
so we study polynomial secret sharing
which is which
generalizes the well-studied linear a
secret sharing
the motivation in studying polynomial
secret sharing first we want to
construct a new efficient secret sharing
schemes for x structures and second we
want to prove lower bounds for a larger
class of schemes
so in terms of result we we construct a
quadratic secret sharing schemes that
are better than the best
is secret sharing schemes and we
construct a quadratic
to conditional disclosure of secrets of
protocols that are better than the
linear protocols
and we prove lower bounds for polynomial
secret sharing
so in this talk i will start by an
introduction of secret sharing and the
previous results in secret sharing i
will then
introduce polynomial secret sharing
define it and they
describe the motivation by studying
programming and secret sharing then i
will
present our results in polynomial secret
sharing and then i will
describe a building a block that we use
in our reconstruction which is
polynomial conditional disclosure of
secrets then i will summarize and
discuss open questions left
by our work
so secret sharing skins were defined
independently by shamir and black
in 79 for the threshold case and by ato
it was certain
it is even for the
general case so in secret sharing there
is a leader who holds a secret s and
there is a set of n parties the the
dealer
applies a function on the secret s and
some random string r
generates and shares and gives each
party a share
we say where we define an access
structure gamma as a collection of
authorized sets of parties and we say
that a secret challenge scheme realizes
gamma if the two following conditions
first for correctness we require that
anything that is in gamma should learn
the secret
and for security we require that any set
that is not in gamma and it's called an
authorized set should learn nothing
about that
so in this talk the secret is only one
bit which is a zero or one
now we start by a warm up which is a
secret sharing scheme realizing that
structure
so in this axis structure
there is only one of the right set which
is the set of all the parties
and every other set is an authorized set
so
the construction is as follows the
cigarette you have the secret is that
the data it chooses n minus one random
bits r one to r n minus one
computes rn at the exclusive or of s and
all the other a bits and now gives party
pi the share is a bit for i so for
correctness if all the parties
participate then they can
learn the secret by ignoring all the
the shares
and if
one
party missing then there will be a
random bit missing and we can prove that
they have
they have actually
a independent random bits
okay the share size in this scheme is
only a one a bit okay
so now we move to present our scheme for
arbitrary access structures
the secret is that we look at an access
structure gamma that has a minimal
override sets
so for every minimum of right set a of
size l
we independently execute
out the ascii and l out of l secret
chain scheme among the vertices in a
so for example for the following axis
structure
there is two minimal authorized sets p
one b two p one b three the third the
infrared set is not minimal so we
execute a two of a two out of two scheme
among the parties a p one a p two and
independently execute a two out of two
scheme among the aborted p1 and p3
so since each party can be in at
in up to two to the n a minimal
authorized set
said then the number at the shell scan
in size can be as large as the two to
the n this is what the best charge does
the shear size
known for realizing arbitrary axis
structures until a few years ago
so recently after more than 30 years of
research we have a bitter upper bound
for realizing arbitrary axis structures
so we have an upper bound of two to the
zero point five eight five and this
achieved by a sequence of uh
works started from 2017 and our last
result
was achieved in a paper that is
represented in this conference
when we look at lower bounds we know
that the best
known lower bound is due
the sensing is the 97 is a omega n
square over a logarithm so we can see
that there is a huge gap between the
best upper bound and the best lower band
we know at and it's a central opening
question in secret sharing to reduce
this
gap
okay this is what's a general secret
sharing now we will move to talk about
linear secret sharing which is a class
of skins
so this is an important class of schemes
due to reasons first the many of the
nonlinear
learners secretary schemes are linear
and second it has a
useful properties such as homomorphism
which is a critical for many some
applications such as a multi-party
computation
so this linear secret sharing is
constructed in a finite field f
the secret is one element in this in the
field and the randomness is the l a
is
not a finite number of field elements we
donated by l
which are uh chosen by e with uniform
distribution so for example here we the
leader chooses r1 and r2 with uniform
distribution in f3
uh
okay
so we say we defined in our sharing
we say that the sharing is linear if the
share is i is a vector
in
the field f the vector of c i elements
and each element in this vector is a
fixed combination of the secret and the
random bits so for example here p one is
given only one element which is r one
plus two r o two plus s and p two is
given
two random elements a r one and r a two
uh
we said that the linear reconstruction
is linear
if each of the right sets reconstruct
the secret using a linear function for
example p1 and p2
an authorized set computes the secret by
s11 minus s21 minus 2 is 2 2 this is a
linear combination
so we know that linear sharing is
equivalent to linear reconstruction this
is by a result by a very previous say
words
okay so now we talk about the previous
result in results in our secret sharing
so first the scheme that we presented in
the beginning of this talk is linear and
has the share size two to the n recently
after 30 years more than 30 years before
we have better upper bounds
the best about
known today is two to the zero point uh
five seven five seven five n
which is achieved in a paper in this
conference
and the best lower bound is uh two to
the n over two for explicit axis
structures we know a lower bound which
is two to the omega n
so we can see that the gap between the
best upper bound and this cover bound
and linear secret sharing is much
smaller than the gap in general is
secret sharing and this
motivates us to study in new
classes of a secret share
therefore we study a polynomial is
secret sharing
so polynomial secret sharing
winnex to present motivation the
definition represented in next slide so
polynomial secret sharing is a broader a
class of secret sharing
done in our schemes
in a previous work
previous work defines secret sharing
with a polynomial sharing and in our
our conceptual contribution is the
discussion of two additional uh
polynomial secret sharing a classes
uh so we introduce and discuss
schemes with a polynomial reconstruction
and the schemes with both polynomial
sharing and reconstruction
so the motivation in studying polynomial
is secret sharing first
improve lower bounds for a broader a
class of schemes and second
explore new techniques
for constructing efficient secret
sharing schemes therefore some or all
access structures exploiting the a
nice
algebraic structure of four of
polynomials
so next we define a polynomial a secret
sharing it's a polynomial secret
chaining is constructed in a finite
field
the secret is a an
element in
s which is a subset of the field for
example
is here we construct a scheme where is
all the field
fe3 the randomness is a finite number of
field elements donated by l
that are chosen with uniform
distribution so here the dealer it
chooses two random elements r1 and earth
2 with euro from distribution
with if we said that the sharing is
degree d sharing
if the share is
a the share of each party is a vector a
of ci elements in f
and each element in the in the share is
computed by the greedy polynomial of the
secret and the random bits
so here
p 1 is given to one element which is r1
plus r1 r2 squared plus s this is a
degree 3 polynomial p2 is given two
elements r1 and r2 this is a linear
okay so the greedy we say that this
reconstruction is degree d
if each authorized set reconstructs the
secret with a degree d polynomial so for
example p1 and p2 computes s11 minus s21
minus s21 is 2 2 square in order to
learn the secret this is a degree 3 a
polynomial
so we said that the signature is degree
d secret sharing if it has degree d
sharing and degrading reconstruction
okay this is was polynomial secret
sharing now we will talk about present
our results in polynomial secret chain
so in our first result we separate
between shear polynomial sharing and the
polynomial a reconstruction
so we prove that polynomial sharing does
not imply a polynomial reconstruction
this is improved under some
complex complexity assumption so in
order to prove this we show an efficient
secret sharing schemes that has a
polynomial sharing for an axis structure
that
under this assumption does not have a
secret sharing with a polynomial
reconstruction
we prove in our second result lower
bounds so we prove a lower bound of
omega 2 to the n over d plus 1 for
secret sharing with the greedy
reconstruction
and we prove a lower bound of t to the
omega n over d for secret sharing
schemes with the greedy reconstruction
for an
explicit access structure
so now we present our main result which
is about bounds for quadratic secret
sharing
so first quadratic secret sharing is
secret sharing with degradation to
sharing a degree to to sharing and
reconstruction
so in our main result we construct a
quadratic secret sharing scheme for
arbitrary axis structure that has shear
size 2 to the 0.705
n so this is
worse than a better than the best linear
scheme which requires share size 2 to
the
0.75 n however it's worse than the
nonlinear scheme which requires share
size due to the
0.585 n
also separate the secret quadratic
secret chaining for a and linear secret
sharing so we construct a quadratic
secret sharing for almost axis
structures with share size to 2 to the n
over e3
and by a lower bound
that we know and in our secret sharing
which is 2 to the n over 2 for realizing
realizing almost all axis structures we
get the
required saturation
okay so this is was
this was our results now we will move to
talk about uh our constructions
so as building a block in our
constructions we use a polynomial
conditional disclosure of secrets
so conditional disclosure of secret
there is a function f a boolean function
which with k n bots each input is in
domain n
there are guest servers if you want to
qk and each server has
a secret s and holds a comma randomness
r there is a referee the referee knows
all the inputs x 1 2 x k
and now it should be server it sends one
message to the referee such that uh when
sending the the each message of its
server depends on his in private input
on the secret s and on the common common
randomness r
the server does not see the inputs of
the other servers and does not see the
messages that
the other server send to the referee
so very correctness if the value of the
if if a function f is one then the
referee should learn the secret and if
the value is zero the referee should
learn nothing about the secret
okay so now we present a bar bound for
upper bounds for cds protocols
so for a function f with case in both
each input in domain n
we will have a linear case server cds
uh for if every function f with message
size and to the k minus one over two
this is a tight upper bound by a lower
bound proof in previous work
we also know there that there is a
non-linear cds protocol with k servers
for every function f with message size
due to the squared low k log n
we know that there is a quadratic cdsa
protocols with a two servers for every
function f with message size and to the
one over e3 so in our paper we construct
a quadratic kcdsu protocol with k
servers for every k
for every function f with message size
and to the k minus one over three
this is a tight upper bound by a lower
bound that
we we prove
okay this was the results in cbs
protocols now we we we moved to
the
uh
our ideas of our construction of cds
so first we present the road map of our
main result that we use
the cds in it
so we start by quadratic to server cds
from a previous work we transform this
protocol to quadratic case server cds we
represent the ideas of this
transformation in the next slide
then
we transform the quadratic server cds to
quadratic k server robust dds okay
robust cds is a new primitive that was
defined in the previous work
then from using using transformations
in
previous works of converting
cd robust cds to arbitrary secret
sharing for arbitrary access structures
we get our quadratic secret share
okay
now we will talk about our constructions
for s quadratic cds we start by
quadratic force server cds and they
present the ideas in this
protocol
so we want to construct a protocol for a
function f with four in both each input
is domain n
so in our protocol simulate the
quadratic to server cds of a previous
word for a function f
in which the first input is in domain n
and the second input is in domain into
the three
so there are two servers q one and q
q1 has inverted x and n y eq 2 has input
y and in in into the three so that each
chord you and
we look at the natural mapping of y to
the three coordinates y one y two y
three each coordinate is in n
there are common randomness s one is two
is three which are subsets of n
and now the sku1 sends a message of size
order n we will not describe the message
as is not relevant to our
ideas
now q2 sends three subsets a1 a2 and e3
such that if the secret is zero then a h
equals s h and if the secret is one then
a h equals s h x or y h
that means that if the
uh if y h is in s then we remove it and
if it's not then we add it
okay
so we have now at two additional servers
q3 and q4 the input of q2 is divided
among a then but y is divided among q2
q3 and q4
and now a server q2 cannot send
it to the sets a 2 and a 3 since a they
depend on
the inputs of u3 and q4
but he can send a one as it depends on
only in his inbox so he can
send
he sends a one q to similar q3 since a2
and the q4 sends a3
so the message in this protocol is order
n
now we present a
quadratic 7 server cdc protocol that
samuel s the previous protocol
so
now we want to construct a protocol for
function f with seven inputs each input
is in domain n
now we look you we want we simulate the
quadratic force server cds where
where the input of the first server is n
and the input of the other three servers
is in square
so we treat x2 and x3 as y1
and x4 at x5 as y2 x6 and x7 as y3 and
now we are back to the circulation of
for server cds
so q1 the server q1 sends the message of
the first server in the for server cds
which requires shares message size
and square and the other servers should
send those messages of the other three
servers in the first service server cds
so in order to do this
u2 and q3
execute a pcm protocol for sending s1 if
the secret is 0 and s1 x or y1 if the
secret is a
1.
so this means that
q2 sends one message q3 sends one
message and the referee should
learn
s1 or s1 x4 y1 without learning anything
about the secret and our technical
contribution is to show how to secure 2
and the q3 send the messages
similarly q4 and q5 execute bcm for
sending s2
and the q6 and q7 it would be simple to
call for
sc3
so the basin should be quadratic and we
show how to construct this say psn
so this is the protocol can be
generalized for every ak
using
the
psm this so our this so we have a
protocol for every ak
okay this was the ideas of our
constructions
and now we summarize and present open
egg problems
so we started bologna meal secret
sharing which is a broader class of
secret sharing schemes than the
willingness studies in our class
we improved lower bounds
for secret sharing with balloon
polynomial reconstruction we proved a
new upper bound of for quadratic secret
sharing and quadratic cds these upper
bounds are better than the best
non-linear upper bounds
we separated between linear and the
quadratic secret sharing for almost all
axis structures
now we discuss open problems so the
first question is to prove lower bounds
on the shear size
secret sharing schemes with degree d
sharing in our work we proved lower
bounds for secret chaining schemes with
degree de-reconstruction and it's
interesting to extend the lower bands to
degree d sharing
so we constructed which constructed
constructed the quadratic secret sharing
schemes and it's interesting to
construct the new degree d secret
sharing schemes that are better than the
quadratic secret sharing schemes that we
constructed
and perhaps the most
interesting question is to construct
efficient degree d secret sharing
schemes efficient could be
schemes with polynomial shares
so construct efficient degree d secret
sharing schemes for a larger class of
axis structures
uh then accesses the class of access
structures that we know that have
efficient linear secret sharing schemes
okay that's it thank you for your
attention