welcome to this talk about receive
anonymity in randomizable rca secure
crypto system
for crypto 2021
an e1 announces a joint work with remote
chair
young
a public key equipment
consists of three algorithms for
degeneration
encryption and decryption
in the message communication scenario
suppose alice wants to send a message m
to bob
first bob uses key gen to generate a
public secret key pair pk and desk 8 and
send the public key pk to alice
the alice encrypts m under the pk and
sends this advertised c to bar
finally bob can use the secret key sk to
decrypt this advertise and obtain the
message m
the c security has been widely
considered as a golden security standard
for public key encryption pke
however it is evidence that for some
practical purposes or somewhat weaker
security notion than cca security is
already sufficient
to this end canadian and co-authors
introduced the notion of replayable cc
security
rca security is the same as cc security
except that the adversary is allowed to
modify several tests into a new one of
the same plaintext
so it is a relaxation of cc security
the relaxation in those pke with
desirable features
brand as even measurable rcc security is
one of them
we say a pke scheme is randomizable if
there exists a efficient algorithm
prevent
that takes as input public key pk
and the advertised c and outputs a new
advertised c prime of same public key
and
plain text
if the
randomization does not need public key
then we say this pke is universally
randomizable
when rcc security
turns out to have numerous applications
such as mixnet control malleable and sdk
and
cryptographic reverse firework
however for some privacy oriented
applications ran rcc security alone is
not enough
taking the mixnet based anonymous
communication as example
in the mix net the mixed node receives a
batch of several tasks from sender a1 to
am
and then the mixed node
randomize them and send them to the
receiver b1 to bm
the universal randomization performed by
mixed node or links several types ci and
the cs star in terms of contents such
that the adversary cannot correlate the
sender and receiver
however we notice that the underlying
public key of civil tests does not
change after randomization
so if the pke is not receiver anonymous
that is the adversary can obtain some
information about the underlying public
key from the cellular test
then
the adversary may
still be able to correlate the server
types for the same receiver
therefore
randomizability and
receiver anonymity are both required for
the mixnet based anonymous communication
it is able to achieve both
for cc sources under cpa security
but it is not the case for cca security
because it permits strong adversary to
curate the decryption
oracle that is
the adversary can probe the system with
safer tests
the first perfect and universal brand
rtc pke
in the standard model was proposed by
grab hurricane and russell lake at
crypto 2007
we call this construction the pr scheme
for short
unfortunately the pr scheme does not
achieve receivability
and how to construct a receiver
anonymous rent rtc pke was left as an
interesting open problem
but more surprisingly even after many
years its open problem remains unsolved
to date
the main technical challenge of
achieving rcc receiver anonymity arises
from the fact that the decryption oracle
in the game would output replay
if one of the decryption results
equals to the challenge
plaintext
m star
so the adversary can guess
the bit b
and that gets the b
and guess the bit
b star and encrypts the challenge
several times c star
with
p k b with p k b star and curious the
decryption oracle to verify its guess
if if it
gets the b correctly the equation oracle
would return a bot
if the otherwise
if if the adversary gets the b2b
correctly the dilution oracle would
replace would return as replay
thus to defend against this attack
it is a required that the randomization
of civil attacks should not involve the
public key
that is to say universal randomization
is required
however
achieving receivability
is more challenging than realizing
uniform
universal randomization
example is the pr scheme
it is universally randomizable but not
receiver anonymous
to explain why the pr scheme does not
satisfy receivable anonymity we review
the scheme briefly
the separatist of the pr scheme is
composed of four strands
the strand c1 carries the message while
the strength c2 is to help randomize c1
without public key the encrypted mask u
shared between c1 and c2
disables the adversary to mix together
strength from two different separatists
to obtain a valid separatist
the component exponent of strength c1
are perturbed by
an additional vector z
to restrict the matter of recombining
those two
strands here the blue errors illustrate
the only way to randomize c1 and c2
however one can note that there is no
such mask or vectors in string c3 and c4
so those two strengths can also be
randomized with public keys
which means the adversary is able to
guess the public key
and verify its guess we are curing the
decryption oracle
so the particular randomizability of
several types breaks the receiver
anonymity of the whole scheme
to achieve rcc receive anonymity we have
to disable the randomization of string
c3 and c4 employing the public key
note that randomization
of string c1 and c2 is restricted by
mask u and vector z
if we also apply this technique to c3
and c4
extra strands are required to encrypt
the mask
in c3 and c4
which would incur the partition
randomization of ciphertext employing
the public key again
passed by this problem we move the mask
and additional vectors to the validity
tracking part
since this part contains only one
component
no additional component is appended to
each strand for perturb for the
perturbation on the ready checking part
the randomization of strength c1 and c2
is still restricted by mask u and vector
z1 and z2
as for strength c3 and c4 the
randomization is restricted by mask u
and vector c bar one and z bar two
the blue errors illustrate the only way
to randomize ciphertext
note that the several times construction
of our variant
still shares some similarities with that
of the pr scheme
it is essentially a double strand of
creamer soup salvatized
so we're going to explore why whether it
is possible to generalize our treatment
following the
chromosome paradigm
so next we will start by recalling the
chromosome paradigm based on
smooth projective hash function sphf
and then seeks to extend the notion of
sphf to interpret our proposed variants
under its security
smooth projective hash function
svhf was originally proposed by creamer
and the sub for generally constructing
practical csa secure pke
roughly sbhf is a family of hash
functions h indexed by k that maps the
element set x
onto the hash value set pi
has phf is associated with an mp
language l where elements in ao are
computationally indistinguishable from
those in long language set
x minus l
this is
the heart subset membership problem
for any language element x in l its hash
value
h s k x could be efficiently computed
using either the hashing key sk or the
projection key pk with the witness w to
the fact that x belongs to l
every sphere should be smooth 1. that is
to say conditioned on fixed projection
key pk for any long language element x
its hex value is statistically
indistinguishable from the uniform
distribution over the space pi
some sphf's satisfy stronger smoothness
smooth too
it is to say condition on fixed pk and
the hash value of any non-language
element
x star
for any other non-language element x
its hash value is statistically
indistinguishable from uniform
distribution of the space pi
the notion of sphf could be generalized
to tech sphf where attack tau is also
taken as an auxiliary input by hash
function h
algorithms priv and the pub
the regular sphf can be regarded as a
special case of tech sphf with empty
text space
the creamer soup paradigm is based on a
smooth one as bhfi and a smooth 2
attacks sphfi hat
the public key
is pk and pk hat
and the sephora test consists of three
parts
the language element x
m times hash value
h
s k x
and h value h hat s k hat
x tau
where the tactile is the h value of the
first two parts
to make our later arguments easier to
follow
below we first provide a overview of
justification of cc security for sph
considering the challenges advertised
zeta star
in the cca security game namely game
zero
in game one due to the hardness of
subset membership problem
we can replace
the language element x star with
non-language elements
and compute
pi star and pi hat star
using the hashing key
in game 2
the decryption oracle also reject also
rejects all the
parts of all the biased effort tests
with long language element x
by the smooth two property of sphfi hat
in game 3 we can replace
pi star with random hash value from set
pi
by the smooth one property of sphfi
now the challenge server attached zeta
star perfectly hides m b
which yields the cca security
following the idea of commercial
paradigm we also can interpret our
construction from sbhfs
taking strength c1 and c2 as example
they can be generalized using three
different sbhs
the bx and the b y are the hash values
of x and y on same hash function h
the validity checking parts of c1 and c2
are hash values of x and y under two
different hash functions
h hat and h tilde
well the edge tilde can be viewed as a
special case of h hat with vectors z1
and z2 equals to zero now from the
perspective of sphere the separatized
randomization can be regarded as the
randomization of hash values
meanwhile one can note that there are
two kinds of randomization
the cf one within same sphere and the
pairwise one between different spheres
motivated by those observations
where outputs will put forward the
notion of randomizable sphf iesphf
which is a regular sphere augmented with
self and pairwise randomizability
based on the typical definition of
sbhf we formalize three actual
algorithms namely rent x when t
and the rand h to capture both cases of
randomization
let's say r x x denote the set of all
randomization of x obtained via brand x
c r x x prime denote the set of all
randomization of x
obtained via rain x with x prime and the
c r t tau denotes the set of all
randomization of tau obtained variant t
similar to the classification of
randomization
we redefine two types of smoothness for
iesphf as below
the controlled self
randomizables smoothness says that
condition on fixed pk and the hash value
for any long language element x star
and any tech call star
for any non-language element x and the
tactile
the h value is statistically
indistinguishable from the uniform
distribution over the space pi
it is
required that the x does not belongs to
say r x
x star
or tau does not belong to c r t tau star
the controlled pairwise randomizes both
smoothness says that
conditioned on fix the pk hat the hash
value
h hats
h hat
h h hat sk heads
x one star call star
etched sk
x to start house start
for any language element
x and the tactile the hash value is
statistically indistinguishable from the
uniform distribution over the space pi
pi hat
also it is required that the x does not
belong to
crx x1 star
x2 star or the
tau does not belong to c r t tau star
meanwhile we also define two new
smoothness
as this must one means that condition
unfixed at p k for two random
non-language elements x1 and x2
and
random tactile
their hash value are uniformly
distributed over the space pi
the power wise between one smooth means
that
conditioned on fixed pk for two random
non-language elements x1 and the x2 and
the random tactile the hash values are
uniformly distributed over the space pi
hat and the pi tower respectively the
over construction is based on six
different
resphs
we now show how to realize
rcc security and receive anonymity with
those new smoothness
similar to the security justification of
chromosome paradigm
we provide the argument to justify the
rcca security of our variants
let game0 be the rcc security game
in game 1 due to the hardness of subset
membership of
membership problems
will replace all the language elements
in challenges advertised zetastar
with non-language elements
in game 2 by the csr and the cpr smooth
the decryption oracle also rejects all
the bias advertised
at this the oral code would not reveal
more information about the sacred key
in game 3 by the
st and the pt smooth one we replace all
the hash values in challenge several
tests with random ones
now the data star perfectly hides mb
and the rcc security of our construction
holds the justification for receiving
anonymity is indeed familiar to above
argument
in particular the decryption oracle also
relies on csr and the cpr smooth
properties to reject all the band cipher
tests
in the end the uniform distribution of
all the hash values in zeta star implies
the receiver anonymity in rcca setting
in this table we'll compare our
scheme with previous works
besides our exclusive property of
receiver anonymity compared with the
recent work or found or found you on the
courses
also our 2 liam 2 linear based
instantation is based on special groups
which are larger than regular setting
but it does not involve any pairing
computations
so
in this work we provide the first
receiver anonymous grant rcca pke and
resolves the open problem
then we designed a modular framework for
constructing received anonymous random
rcc pke
with our newly extended sphere iesphf
and rigorously proved its rcc security
and receiver anonymity
finally we instantiated the framework
with k-linear assumption and the grid
ring
and improves the pr scheme with more
general hardness assumption
ok that's all thank you