and
good to go you can start
okay so uh welcome back
first talk uh
dual ring generic construction of ring
signatures
chi hong yuan muhammad s
please go ahead
do you have do we have a speaker with us
on
on the zoom
i don't know who
is
supposed to speak from the authors
let me double check
also if the speaker is here you might be
muted so do
don't forget to unmute
i'm not sure i see anyone from that talk
you may want to go on to the next and
then we can circle back around
yeah is is it
okay with euroheat
thank you i'll share my screen now are
you okay to go first
okay thank you so much so we'll do a
slight switch and um the first rohit
chatterjee will
present on the
paper and he will read off the
name the list of names better than i
will
uh on compact ring signatures from lwe
can you see my screen online
yes that looks great
thank you okay yeah i'm rohit and i'm
here to talk about compact ring
signatures from lwe
uh this is joint to work with sanjim
gurg mohammed abbadi dakshitakarana jau
liang julian malavolta umkat pandey and
sina shihan
so what are compact ring signatures um
hearing signatures in general have many
people
and each generates their own public and
signing keys
and
the point is that anybody in this
so-called ring and can sign on behalf of
other people in the ring and you
generate a single signature
using your own publicly and really what
you why you care is that there is no
interaction
and so this differs from group and
threshold signatures
etc
and the properties that you want are
enforceability just like normal ring
signatures and anonymity so that even
though you sign the ring nobody else
uh
can tell apart
who in the ring actually signed a
message
and for reasons
for of scalability you often want the
rings initials to be small in the size
of the ring itself
and so you want maybe something called
compactness where you want the signature
to grow maybe logarithmically in the
size of the ring
or perhaps if you can't achieve that you
want it to gross up linearly and so on
and so forth
and
so there's been a lot of work in the
internationals of course and uh there
they are present in different models i
think
uh this might be playing out on its own
time but that shouldn't matter um
yeah so you have constructions in the
rom model at the crs model and most
importantly for us in the plane model so
there's a lot of efficient constructions
and compact constructions
but in the plane model really there
aren't a lot of constructions and in
particular we'll focus on the one by
bachelor link hash like and others from
that gives you compact ring signatures
without setup in the plain model
but for our purposes
before our work there was no
construction in the plane model
and
from lwe so to speak
so
let's just look uh very quickly at what
components
barkers and others use
and
they basically have a pke scheme a
signing scheme the pk is basically
standard but it has a few extra
properties
uh it also uses a somewhere perfectly
binding hash scheme which is like a
merkle tree but you get
something like somewhere perfectly
binding it binds to one of the
particular indices
in let's say an array of committed
values
this is not important for the moment and
finally most crucially it uses a
non-interactive witness
indistinguishable proof
which can
be made from a variety of assumptions
but mostly we use them from bilinear
maps bearing based assumptions
and the point is that yes of course of
all these components the first three can
be gotten pretty easily from lwe
but
the last
component is
we don't know construction from lw or
any other post quantum assumption and
this is essentially our goal
and the way we look to do this is of
course we essentially use the same
template but we try to replace the navy
proof
uh and i will try to sketch that out
next so how we do this is
i'm going to now show you the bdhq
scheme
but i will not explain very much about
it
so bear with me so their ring
verification key has the standard
verification key and the public key for
the encryption scheme
and the
signing key just has the signing key for
the standard signature scheme and the
signature really looks like this
you have an encryption of the standard
signature
along with the hash key for the
somewhere perfectly binding key
okay
and
and also the navy proof
and now
our crucial observation is that you can
use uh
a two-round public coin argument system
a zap which we just put
in the verification key the first round
exact message
and you can have the second rounds app
uh the provers response really as part
of the signature
and so you have essentially replaced the
non-interactive witness and distribution
proof with
a zap and i mean there's a slight
technicality because if you used
your own zap first message from your own
verification key
that could give away anonymity so you
use the one from the lexicographically
smallest verification came the ring for
example
um
so so far so good so this looks pretty
simple
the catch is that
we know zaps from lwe
and this is actually a recent and pretty
nice and long line of work
but all of them need some exponential
hardness of l-w and in a very crucial
sense this is
to show soundness
and
you really need to use complexity
leveraging
in these templates to show soundness
because otherwise we don't really have
approaches for showing soundness for any
npa language
and so we do not have constructions for
the thing we are looking for in
particular which is
just use polynomially hard lwe to get
this kind of zap
and this is actually not exactly what we
get
we get something weaker but we show
how to use it
so our key observation in some sense is
that we use
we do not need soundness for all of np
languages for our ring signature
application
in fact we are only interested in
forgeability
and
the there really is like essentially two
ways to beat soundness if you're a
forger and you're forging a ring
signature
in the construction template i showed
you before you have to either provide an
invalid encryption
so you encrypt under some invalid key or
you encrypt maybe
uh junk
or encrypt the signature that is forgery
and you sort of cheat in the proof to
show this
and in either case essentially what you
have is like
a short witness to say that whatever you
did
i can capture it in the short business
so for the purposes of the
unforgivability game
you can have
the challenger
get access to this non-witness
and try to catch you in the act of
cheating so you do not actually need all
of np
soundness for all of np you can settle
for this weaker form of soundness
and
reconstruct such a proof system
so to summarize what we did we
looked at the bdhks template
we saw that you could
first replace
navy proofs with saps
and b we created this app construction
that has soundness
for np intersection q and p and we also
notice that this is enough to actually
show
that your ring signature is unfortunate
and that is it i have an extra slide to
sort of sketch out the zap construction
but i will stop for questions
so
uh we're slightly behind time so let's
move questions to uh after both talks
but do we have the
authors of the
of the other paper
is
muhammad s
king joseph liu
man
da ding
party are they present somebody
i guess has some connectivity problem
[Music]
it seems like um u.n was supposed to
give the talk
um
right he was giving the the
the youtube talk right
um
[Music]
so
well
they will get in touch and and
okay
uh i'm not a child
but maybe
they will give be given opportunities to
talk at some other session or something
like this i guess um
we don't have to have upload they have
uploaded a longer version just uh in
case people want to hear it yeah looks
like they have uploaded it
yeah it's linked from the from the
program
um
[Music]
okay so i guess we have a little bit of
time so rohit
you know you have one more slide so
let's do that and and then have
questions
sure
[Music]
okay yeah so
like i said before
the actual zap that we use in the ring
signature scheme is one essentially that
works for languages and np intersection
point b
and this works as follows we create a
special kind of commitment scheme
and we use the com we use a compressed
sigma protocol along with correlation
interactable hash functions
so there's a lot going on in the slide i
know but i will take you through this um
the commitment has the property that
it essentially uses this part that
you're using uh sound is for a weaker
class of languages
it takes in a string in the first round
and the committed value is actually
committed to in the second round and the
guarantee is that
if your
first round screen
witness proves that some string is not
in a language
you can do when you have a language in
np intersection quantity because the
complement is also an np language
then it will release the committed value
you can actually extract it out
otherwise it is statistically hiding
and if you have this guarantee is sort
of
fairly simple to see
in a broad sense why this works so you
have the compressed sigma protocol you
use this special commitment scheme to
commit to your first round value
the prover secret for the term protocol
and
indeed if you're cheating
then you have to do something specific
along the lines of what i indicated
before
and this you can imagine that
the
verifier has
what's the word
non-uniform access to it
and if it has non-informed access to
such a witness it can use it in the
first round
and then
get the prover secret the secret that it
uses with the sima protocol
and so if x is not an l then you can
catch out the prover relatively easily
and the reason is also that this is a
compressed signal protocol so it's not
enough to say that
you can catch the proofer in the act
what does the prover secret actually
give you
uh we have also used this hash function
which is a correlation interactive hash
function meaning that
it's hard to
given access to the proof of secret
it's hard for the cheating proverb to
come up with this
hash output
so that
this whole sigma protocol transcript can
be accepted by the verifier
so colloquially what we call the bad
challenge
it's hard to have it so that the
approver can send the first message
so that the hash of this first message
gives you
the second message that you want to
cheat in the signal protocol
and this is essentially how soundness
works and
also fitness and distinguishability is
not very hard to show
and this is uh
zaps are also public coin and this is
public coin in a sense that the hash
function of choice is also public coin
the first round message you use to pick
out the hash function key is public coin
and also we can make the commitment
first message to public con
and that's it
well um thank you rohit
uh
do we
do
do we have any questions
for for rohit
um
i think there is a message on on the
chat from richard goyal
uh do you need any extra special
property from zaps
or the bacchus at all template work with
any public coin two round witness
indistinguishable proofs
uh instead of the
newest
yeah well it would so this is
slightly topical so
i think it does
for the
the problem that arouses in our setting
is that since we are using this sort of
weaker form of this app so like zap
sword and painter section 1p
we have to take some care that
we do certain things uh sort of
succinctly because
you imagine if this if we are proving
some property about this ring
normally if you have full soundness or
sound is for all of np this is not a
very big problem so we can go ahead and
use this app i think
but
for our setting since we have to
use some extra leverage to prove
soundness we have also to make sure that
what we sort of verify
without directly relying on the
soundness of this app
does not add to the size of the ring
signature construction
so you have to worry a little bit about
that so
i'll be happy to go into more details of
that
um
thank you
well
let me ask the naive question how come
the first message of the zap can be uh
not your own
for the prover
well yeah that is uh
there's no technical nice answer but it
fits in nicely so that in this context
you can imagine that for example the
unforgetability challenger has access to
in some sense what the so you need to
have some information about what the
prover can do in advance and as it turns
out for the unforgetability challenge
when you construct these ring signatures
let's go here
you are generating these public keys for
the encryption scheme right
and
when you show unforgeability you can
have the challenger also pick out secret
keys so in general you pick these public
keys obliviously for reasons of
anonymity
but
separately for enforceability you can
have secret keys and it turns out that
this is enough information to set up our
sort of np interception cid
because given these secret keys you can
sort of check the provers encryption
within the ring signature
and
do certain consistency checks and that's
enough
yeah i guess that is sort of
what i would call them
unpredictable on
you know
[Music]
and all your
login
condensation or compaction comes from
because it's a sigma protocol
uh not quite so the other uh components
also have to be compact which they
really are but in the
so like i said i was talking about the
the previous question right
um there you did sort of need
this guarantee that the checks you're
doing so you want to really prove a
statement of the following sorted so you
want to say that your encrypted
signature
was encrypted by using a public key that
was part of your ring
and so really to check this computation
you have to make sure that either you're
proving something that is
compact
or if you're not technically
all the components that you're using in
proving and checking these things
do not scale you know
more than logarithmically with the size
of the ring which we do
[Music]
thank you
hi
um
well
we should we should go on a break soon
but
[Music]
richard has a follow-up about the
question on well first there is a
question from akshay aram uh is com1 the
first commitment is it
sudo random
we designed it to be super random yes
and uh photoshops i'm still reading it
okay
right
um
there's a longer comment from shop on
uh
follow up to the question of special
properties of zaps
yeah sorry you can ask me
or maybe you disrupt you can yeah i can
maybe ask it out loud i was just sort of
quickly asking that you said zaps are
here being used for
compactness as well they are not used
for compactness you just need to make
sure that any verification you do
through them uh all the components you
use in actually constructing the proof
are you know yeah because i i was just
trying to relate with the solar
construction and in that one navi's
we're not really being used for such
things because the hashes of
okay so there's something more that zaps
are doing here that maybe
no because we are not using you know a
general samp
fair enough okay okay okay
involves the ring
okay i understand okay yeah thank you
thanks
okay
uh
is there is there any uh
looks like um
is there any other questions
in the audience
i'm sure you have many questions
okay but thanks to all these
apparatus you know we can ask questions
offline and there is this uh
zulip or tulip or something that you can
the chats
and and that works great uh
people can you know ask the next day and
and
um you know ask a speaker and the
speaker will like notice
uh
so thank you rohit and uh i haven't
thanked the previous uh
part speaker so thank you all uh for for
the first four talks as well