ready to go have a good session
thank you um hello everyone welcome back
uh this is the second half of the
session on foundations
and our first talk will be
non-interactive batch arguments were mp
from standard assumptions
by akar rai trouturi abhishek jain and
zhen zhong jin and jin jong will give
the talk
thanks for the introduction
this talk is about uh non-interactive
batch arguments for mp from standard
assumptions i'm
from johns hopkins university
this work is joined with akari trothury
and object gen
the non-interactive batch argument
is a protocol between approver and a
wi-fi in the crs model the prover tries
to convince the wifi that a batch of k
instances x1 to xk are all in the
song mp language l
by sending a single round of message pi
and finally the wi-fi
needs to publicly verify this proof pie
and decides to accept or reject the
proof
to help the approver compute this single
round for message
we also allow it to take
omega 1 2 omega k
as the witness for this x 1 to x k
and we further request that the length
of this proof pi is significantly less
than the total length of the witnesses
for the soundness we request that for
any statement
that
all over x1 to xk are in the language l
doesn't hold
we request that for any efficient
adversary
its proof should be rejected
previously
this batch verification is extensively
studied for many crypto primitives such
as digital signatures or interactive
proofs
so the bachelor argument is a very
important
problem
previously by local for rain gold and
rose bloom at all
they build special verification for a
subclass of np which is the up class
in their work
they also consider the interactive
setting
and the batch verification can be viewed
as a special case for the mp class
so one can also hope to use succinct
non-interactive
argument for mp to build battery
verification
however up to now we only know how to
build snarks for mp from non-phosphate
assumptions or in the random oracle
model
recently by the oracle for braxkey at
all
they build
non-interactive batch arguments in the
standard
from standard assumption
but their protocol is only pop is only
private very variable where the wifi the
wi-fi needs to use some private state to
verify the proof
and the more recently by the work of
karla at all
they build non-interactive
non-interactive fresh argument
in the public revival setting
but their assumption is a new assumption
from binomiar maps
so in this work
we try to understand can we build
non-interactive batch arguments for np
from senate assumptions
and in this work we answer this question
positively
we show how to build
non-interactive batch arguments for np
from standard assumptions
further assumptions in the quadratic
residuosity
and the learning with arrow or
self-exponential dedication assumption
where the proof size
grows
only
only square root in the number of
instances k
to obtain our result our method is to
follow the financial mirror framework
defense general transformation is a
method to collapse a public coin
interactive protocol
to a non-interactive protocol
by replacing all the wi-fi's message
with the hash of the transcript so far
and recently there is an exciting line
of work trying to instantiate the
financial
transformation from standard assumptions
and the idea is to build a special hash
function which is called correlation
tractable hash
however
by this method we only know how to
collapse interactive proofs
where the soundness hold even for
unbounded
adversary
so to deal with this issue
our method is to start with some dual
mode interactive batch argument
such a interactive protocol
is in the crs model and the crs has two
indistinguishable modes
so in the treble mode the crs is
associated with sound indices i
and the protocol becomes statistically
sound for the ios indices in the
tropical mode
it means that for any unbounded
adversary it cannot cheat for any
exercise that is not in this language
then we'll apply the finished armor to
this
interactive protocol by using the
correlation integral hash
and in the soundness proof we use the
uh sound we use the property of
correlation interactability to prove the
soundness
[Music]
for more details you can refer to our
photograph
and our full paper online
and also in a follow-up of this work we
also build snarks for p from linux arrow
which is recently accepted to fox 2021
thank you
thank the speaker for the talk
any questions from the audience
feel free to unmute yourself and speak
up
okay
thank the speaker again
and our next talk
is on targeted lossy functions and
applications by willie koch brent waters
and daniel wicks
and willie will give the talk
welcome
hi
can you see the
and xiaomi properly
yeah okay cool
uh yeah thanks for the introduction so
i'm willie and i'm going to talk about
targeted lucy functions in applications
so this is drain work with brain waters
and then in weeks
okay so what we do in this paper
um the conceptual starting point is the
the primitive primitive code lossy
trapdoor functions that were uh that was
introduced by pythagorean waters in 2008
which turns out to be an extremely
powerful primitive in the sense that it
has
literally many many applications
but the thing that we're interested in
in this context is that this is a rather
higher end primitive in the sense that
it requires public assumptions
so what we do in this paper is we define
a relaxation of losing functions that we
call targeted lossy functions
and
we indeed show that this is a lower end
primitive in the sense that we build
targeted lucid functions from
objects related to one-way functions
and last we showed that this primitive
is also useful by showing
by showing applications of targeted
lucid functions which leads to
many to new feasibility results in
minicrypt
oh yeah so let me first recall what's a
lossy trapdoor function so so what was
introduced by pipechat and routers in
so a lucifer function will define a
family of functions so that will be my
my pictures for for the domain and the
range of the associated functions
and it will be a familiar function
indexed by some function key
so there's a way to sample a key and
given a key that defines a function that
i can
efficiently evaluate from a domain to a
range
and there will be a way to generate such
a key so that the resulting function
will be injected
and furthermore
the key can be also generated along with
a trapdoor that allows to reverse the
application of the function
there will also be an alternative mode
of something the keys called the lossy
mode and the idea is that
applying the function
should information theoretically lose
some information about the input
so what does that mean
so so say you sample some point in your
domain at random and apply the function
so you get an output
and now i'm just giving you the output
and i'm asking what was the particular x
i started from and that should be
information theoretically hard
and if that holds we say that the
function is loss
and last the a property that ties
everything together
is that
if i i am sampling a key in injective
mode or in los simon then you cannot
tell the difference so you can evaluate
the function but you don't know if the
function that you are getting is
injective already
okay so that's a lucid trouble function
so
what's the target addressing functions
as i said before it's a relaxation of a
velociraptor function so in in what
sense is the difference
so the first difference will be that we
don't require any trapdoor in injection
node
so that will be conceptually the
relaxation that makes target wc
functions not immediately
a public key primitive
and so so we only required that in
injection it just defines an injective
function
but we also relax the requirement the
lossy mode
and the rest mode will be targeted
so what do i mean by that
the resistance mode will take as input a
particular target that'll record x star
and the application of the function
should only lose information when
starting from extra
so again if i start from x-star i apply
the function
and i give you the output of the
function then it should be information
theoretically hard to tell what's where
the partial x-star i started from
and
the reason why this is a relaxation is
that i only record this essentially over
x star
and there's no requirements on the rest
of the function essentially
so in particular it could be possible
that the in lossy mode
the the function is injective almost
everywhere apart from a few points
related to extra
and last we have to strengthen a tiny
bit the indistinguishability requirement
between the between the modes because
the function key
in targeted lossy mode respect to x star
will depend on the next star and we
don't want this to reveal information
about xr essentially
so what we'll require is that the
function key should be indistinguishable
even given uh x-star
so so so that's our notion of targeted
lucid functions
uh oh yes so now what
well first we show that this relaxation
actually allows us to get constructions
uh from
from weaker assumptions
um and so we showed that assuming
injective pseudonym generators then we
can be targeted with your functions
furthermore similar to how
the original paper introducing
lucid trouble functions considered
execution branches
we can also
consider execution branches for targeted
lucid functions and we can also build
that from the same assumptions
next we show that actually for
the applications that we have in mind
we don't necessarily require the full
power of injectivity
and a slightly
relaxed form of injectivity that is so
pretty natural to define surfaces for
applications
and what that does not require the the
functioning injective mode to be fully
injective
alloys
actually allows us to get instructions
from one-way functions
so that that would be crucial to get the
final thumb statement for our
applications
and as a as a side observation that i
think is pretty huge is that it turns
out that there's a conceptual
quite strong link
between
targeted functions and distributed point
functions even though they might look
extremely different
um and
last uh as i mentioned in the beginning
which actually showed that targeted lucy
functions are useful in order to build
as a building block
so we get uh several applications
so the first set of applications in is
is in the room of
leakage residents symmetric key
primitives that we managed to build from
one-way functions
uh so in particular we get leakage
residents symmetrical primitives that
are slightly better than
the state-of-the-art by giving say a
match
where the tagging procedure is
deterministic so the previous
construction from one of the functions
required a randomized procedure
and
we also give a symmetric encryption with
uh
kind of compact surface exercise
uh another uh application that we get uh
is the the construction of
randomness extractor for so-called
extractor-dependent sources from one-way
functions where
previous constructions use public
assumptions
we also get a symmetric key encryption
that is
simulation secure against so-called
selective opening attacks from all your
functions
so so these are all applications from
our functions and last we also showed
that it's actually also useful for
higher end
kind of applications by showing a
new construction of
cca secure encryption
from extremely secure trapdoor functions
so while the
the the end statement is somewhat uh
it's quite weaker than what was done at
crypto last year by hornberger copula
and waters
uh it's um it's still a conceptually new
approach to beyond uh i i think it
should be other cca secure
encryption uh yeah so that's all i had
to say feel free to ask me or email me
questions and here's the link for the
e-prince version
thanks
thanks willie for the talk
any questions for the speaker
um i have one question for the weakening
of the
velocity functions
so
um
you weakened both the
in the injective mode and the
the lossy mode is it possible to just
weaken one of them
um
[Music]
so
you like
if you want uh to build the
the function from just one of my
functions you definitely
would need to not have the trapdoor in
injective mode and
but then you would be reasonable to
consider uh
like a the standard version of luciness
is just that we don't know how to be on
that it would be a natural thing to to
target for but we didn't manage to let
you together
okay uh if there's no more questions
let's thank the speaker again
and um
our last talk will be
on the t wise independence of
substitution permutation networks by
tyrion leo stefano cersaro and vinod
vaikonchanasen and tyrion will give the
talk
oh could you hear me now
yeah okay
cool
uh okay thanks we have for the
introduction
welcome to my tile the tui's
independence of substitution from this
network
i'm tianjin liu and destroying work with
my courser stephanie north
a central problem in crypto is to
construct random looking heated
permutations
tons of work are attacking this problem
among them there is a well-known well
not so well-defined gap between theory
and practice
the serial work called this object a
student permutation and they focus on
security based on well-studied
assumptions
the practical works call this object a
blockchain verb they are okay with
heuristical security the first priority
is being super efficient
of course everyone wants to brief gap
and has a proper secure super efficient
construction
but it seems very hard
so in the literature
we have purple secure prp based on many
assumptions
unfortunately
none of them is fast enough to be
practical
in practice people use much more
efficient block cycles such as ears
then of course everyone want to
understand whether es is secure
from the theory perspective
we want to base aes harness assumptions
but we have no clue here we don't even
have a candidate assumption
many works then try to argue the
security of practical block ciphers in
some idealized models
but still these words are not analyzing
the actual cyphers
when we got stuck proving security
against arbitrary attacks
the next best thing we can hope for
is to identify classes of attacks and
prove they cannot succeed with good
probability
to show this in a picture
the community has already identified
many classes of attacks
previous works show that aes can resist
some classism attacks to some state
in this paper we promote the study of
t-wise independent
it is the desired property of blood
suffers
and it implies resistances to many
attempts
when t equals 2
it already implies resistances to linear
and differential attacks larger t
implies the residency to more attacks
so ty's dependency is a very natural
pyramid a property
for any t inputs
the corresponding t outputs should be
close to id uniform
here we measured closeness in
statistical distance
for visibility
the key length has to be at least three
times the optimalized to have enough
entropy
this requirement can be ensured by the
standard assumption of independent round
keys
which is assumed by almost every work in
the field
from the serial perspective
independence means
security against an unbounded
distinguisher who makes at most tickers
and notice that
linear and differential text relies on
correlation between two queries so in
some sense this attacks can be captured
by a distinguisher that makes only two
curves
similarly odd differential attack can be
captured by a distinguisher that makes
two to the d quirks
and therefore
tui's independence would implies
resistances to all these attacks
and to any attack that relies on
correlation among only two queries
oh
oh in this paper
we started the block cipher designs uh
kc spa
and the concrete cipher aes
for the rest of my talk i briefly
mention our results
for kc
we show that r rank of kc is close to
slightly less than r was independent
this is science
this is a existential result and it's
proved by probabilistic method
but our result is quite tight since we
can easily show that around kc cannot be
r plus 2 was dependent
i would also like to mention here that
hour is in our result permutation pies
are fixed and are completely known to
the diversity which is different from
the result in ideal models
uh for spa
for sp when we construct we consider the
xbox being inverse
which is used by aes or cube which is
used by mimik
we show
two round spn is close to twice
dependent and the three runs sp is even
closer to twice
we also show that six strong aes
so the extra es run there's no
idealization at all
it's also close to 2s
so these are our main result
they can be easily amplified because the
distance is smaller than a half
so for example for es
by increasing the number of products
aes will be exponentially close to 2s
dependent
so that's all for my talk today thank
you for listening you are welcome to
watch the full version or readout paper
you can also find me in the social room
after the session if you want to discuss
something
thanks tyrion for the talk
any questions from the audience
feel free to raise your hand or mute
yourself
okay uh let's thank all the speakers
again for the wonderful talk
talks and the
session