moment
yeah
go ahead
okay great
uh thanks so um welcome everyone to the
first invited talk of crypto 2021
so we're happy and honored to have uh
vanessa tieg as our invited speaker
vanessa is the ceo of thinking cyber
security and an associate professor at
the australian national university
she received her phd from stanford
university in 2005 and her thesis was
one of the very first works that
combined cryptography and game theory
since then vanessa's been based in
australia and she did a lot of great
work has been doing a lot of great work
in particular she was very
she is very
extremely active working on technical
cryptographic problems that are of
public interest
so one example is protection of
government data she was a part of a team
that re-identified
doctors and patients in an open data set
set open data set published by the
australian government
which concerned over 2.5 million
people and she was advocating for
notifying the affected people
which resulted in a big backlash from
the australian government
who put pressure on her department
she was at the university of melbourne
at the time and she resigned over this
another example is the topic of her talk
today which is uh eve voting and
election integrity uh where she's also
done a lot of work and which was
recognized by a research excellence
award from the election verification
network
uh she both discovered vulnerabilities
in several
deployed systems as well as suggested
better protocols
and i'm looking forward to hear more in
her talk so i just want to say on a
personal note that i really admire
vanessa for being an outspoken advocate
for cryptography and
for society and for doing the right
thing so thank you
hey thank you tal and thanks for having
me everybody it's such a pleasure to
join crypto virtually when nobody can be
there in person
uh questions are really really welcome
i'm gonna not take up the whole
um
hour i'm gonna kind of hope to leave
some uh time for discussion for
everybody at the end
okay can you see my screen
yes which
which evoting problems do we need to
solve the
uh question is a deliberately a little
bit ambiguous because it's not clear
whether the
uh emphasis is meant to be on we or
solve and the answer is both so i'm
hoping that this talk can help other
cryptographers who are interested in
democracy in their own country
to
have a go at
making it better
everything i'm about to talk about is
joint work if i listed all the people
with whom it is joint work i'd be bound
to leave somebody else out but i always
feel bad giving these uh kind of invited
talks as if it's all about me when in
fact uh everything i'm going to say is
don't work with at least some other
um really really good people and one of
the funnest things about working in this
field of course is the rest of the
community okay so here we go
so democracy uh it's certainly in crisis
is it really stuffed well i guess i
wouldn't be giving this talk if i
thought the answer was yes but certainly
democracy is not looking that good at
the moment uh this is an article from
the
south china morning post which is kind
of tragic in itself it's from 2018 it
ticked me off at the time because of
this
idea this dichotomy between prosperous
authoritarianism and chaotic freedom
which apparently is a reference to some
quote by xi jinping about how chaotic
democracy is uh and uh the main thing
about this picture is of course now that
we can look back on it three years later
only one of these chaps is still in
charge of his country
and uh to me this is kind of the
superpower of democracy right no matter
how bad
no
i don't think anyone would claim that it
always chooses the best person but the
thing that it does is give us the
opportunity to get rid of somebody that
uh we really realize we made a mistake
about
however i think this picture indicates
to us that the threat model for
secure
electoral processes is about as hard as
it can possibly be right the adversary
is
the most powerful person in the country
who may be the most powerful person in
the world
and they have a degree of control of the
infrastructure and the process
and you have to assume that they're
willing to do just about everything to
stay in power
if we can't secure the process of
running a democratic election then then
we really lose i guess it's pretty
obvious we lose the
power of democracy altogether and when
the core property of a democracy is the
capacity to kind of self-correct
and revert
back to a different state if we don't
like the state we're in then
i guess
it's obvious that the security of the
electoral process is absolutely critical
so i don't think democracy is really
stuffed i think it is in crisis but i
think it is in crisis in a sense that we
can still
use that crisis to do something about
improving its security
in some ways the security of the voting
is the security of voting is better
motivated now
than than it has been
in the popular mind for a long time
so what can cryptographers do about all
this well this talk is addressed to
other cryptographers who'd like to help
support their own democracies and i'm
gonna kind of run with the working
assumption that uh most human beings in
most countries are basically rational uh
even though you might say that the
empirical evidence in support of this
this is a bit iffy at present i still
think it's really most literary
i'm not sadly
going to say very much about people who
are already living under authoritarian
regimes um i think it's horrific but
there isn't
i can't think of very much to do about
that i'm kind of assuming that this is
helpful for
residents of countries that are already
meant to be democratic and already have
some kind of democratic political
process that you can imagine helping to
support
okay
i've i've arranged the things that we
can do through the talk around three
approximate themes with icons as follows
first of all things we can do we can
find bugs and gaps in existing schemes
and tell people what the vulnerability
is in a thing they're already using
ah we can design nifty news claims with
uh
clever and interesting mathematical
properties
or finally we can teach people to think
adversarially and i actually suspect
that
if you've
if you haven't tried talking to your
local
authorities or parliamentarians about
security
it's
you probably don't realize how this
adversarial mindset
and thinking about an attacker is
unusual and uh you know it's a thing
that we do in this community but is not
a thing that most people think of most
people just kind of want stuff to work
so the first two things in my little
bullet list are fun right it's fun to
attack things and think about the
technical details of things it's fun to
design new schemes i assume if you're
listening to an invited talk at crypto
then you probably find the first two
things fun
the last thing is really hard actually
really really hard and often not very
much fun but i actually suggest that in
some ways that is
the most useful thing that some of us
can do for
democratic processes is just persuade
people that there is the potential for
attack and it helps them think through
um actually defending against
surreptitious attack
rather than the thing that almost
everybody else on planet earth does
naturally which is try and make sure
that everything looks okay
okay so what are the security
requirements of elections well uh they
really haven't changed for two and a
half thousand years
so the security requirements of
elections are public verifiability and
the secret ballot secret ballot is
important to stop people being coerced
to vote in a certain way and public
verifiability is important to stop
cheating and to stop people believing
that there's been cheating
so the the picture on the right is
uh jury voting discs from the athenian
agura from uh 400 something bc
and you can see that they're designed so
that
the difference between a guilty vote and
a not guilty vote is very subtle it's a
matter of whether the
little disc is perforated through the
center
um and so they're designed so that a
voter in this case a juror
can walk out in a public place
with the
vote they intend to cast in their hand
and they can chuck it into the right
earn
and everybody can see that everybody's
tossed exactly one
voting disk in but nobody can see how
any individual voted
so this process which is one of the
earliest voting processes we know was
clearly carefully designed with the
technology that they had in mind to
achieve these two crucial
um
security properties that are still the
crucial security properties that we seek
now
uh if you're in uh
france or
nearby countries you might have seen
this you might have this glass
voting urn kind of concept which again
is the same sort of thing you
uh put your vote in a little envelope
and then you put the envelope in a big
glass in and everybody can see that
everybody put exactly one envelope in
the end and then everybody can hang
around and watch the count afterwards
so how do we do this with computers well
the answer is it's hard because of
course computers are sort of inherently
unscrutinizable
so first question
um are there bugs or security problems
in existing voting schemes what do you
reckon
uh i'm not going to talk in detail about
all of these schemes but the short
answer is yes there are i'm going to
talk a little bit about the
errors that we've found in the swiss
post cycle system and what the
implications for ivote and new south
wales are
there is some very good security
analysis of a system called votes that
has been spruiked in the united states
i'm going to talk a little bit about the
chivitas jcj system
uh and
uh
i'm going to talk briefly about the
estonian system before we go on too far
okay
but but my point is if you look this
list is just about everything right this
is just about everything and everything
that we've actually tried in practice
over the internet has been
broken in some really substantial way
all right the first
thing that i'm going to talk about and
this is primarily not a technical talk
uh most of the technical details are in
i assume that if you care about the
technical details you've probably seen
it already
but i want to talk just briefly about
the
story surrounding the swiss post cycle
new south wales i vote internet voting
system
so for those who don't know this is a
story from a year or two ago
the
uh
swiss
cantons have the option of voting over
the internet in a way that is regulated
through the federal chancellery
but actually provided by swiss post
swiss post outsourced the production of
the software to a private company called
cycle
and the
federal chancellery imposed a bunch of
rules about
privacy
individual and public verifiability
and transparency of the source code in
the system
we found
two
well sort of two and a half
substantial bugs in the verification
mechanisms that were supposed to be part
of the system and which were required to
be part of this system by law for the
certification standard that it was
applying for
so there were two different ways in
which a cheating approver could pass
verification but manipulate the votes
and in this case the prover was the the
authority running the election so the
the uh the component doing the mixing or
the decrypting of the electronic votes
so the system used an implementation of
the bayer groth mixnet
uh and uh they also used
standard things that you will know about
uh the feature heuristic applied to sean
peterson proofs
uh they used pictures and commitments
for the biographics net there's nothing
wrong with any of these components
and
the but the problem arose
because of the way in which the specific
details fitted together
in the case of the bayer groth mixnet it
was implemented with peterson
commitments
without making sure that the trapdoor
wasn't known so pitterson commitments
are a trapdoor commitment system if you
know the discrete log of
some of one of the commitment parameters
with respect to the other commitment
parameter then it's a meet you can
immediately see that you can commit to
something and then open it any way you
like
in this system
the designers failed to specify that you
had to verify that the parameters have
been properly constructed and in fact
it's even a little bit worse than that
they um
they actually constructed it in such a
way that the mixers who were proving the
shuffle did actually know the trapdoor
uh even in the just the ordinary honest
run of the protocol
so this is don't work with sarah jamie
lewis and olivier pereira and it was
independently noticed by thomas haynes
and ralph haney
and it's it's it's
easy to see that if you can run the if
you are the prover in a bayer and graphs
mixnet and if you are
able to open if you know the trapdoor
for the commitments you've been using to
commit to the permutation matrix then
you can easily see that you can
you can kind of commit to one
matrix prove that it's a permutation but
then when you actually come to mix you
can mix with something else so this
allowed a cheating mixnet that was
supposed to be shuffling the votes to
substitute votes
but provide a
proof transcript that passed
verification and in fact was
indistinguishable from an honest one
so that was not good
and then in a separate thing
another important detail was that when
they were implementing their decryption
proofs
they used a weak version of the fiat
shmear heuristic in which they didn't
hash all of the statement
and that would have been fine against
approver who
was not adaptive that is a priver who
couldn't choose the statement but it
turned out in this system that they
needed an adaptively secure
uh primitive because uh in fact provers
could partly choose the statement that
they were proving and in this case
uh the weak fear chemical heuristic was
not sufficient
so uh this this bug allowed a
authority that was doing decryption
to
fake a proof
that the cipher text actually decrypted
to something else and they didn't have
much freedom over what they could choose
so they really could only turn a valid
vote into a vote that looked like
nonsense but they could still pass
verification without honestly decrypting
okay so the technical details i assume
if you if you care about the technical
details you've probably already read it
but the bottom line is there was nothing
wrong with any of the
components as such in the sense that
there's nothing wrong with peterson
commitments or the biograph mixnet uh or
even with the weak fetch me heuristic
there's a problem with the context in
which they were used requiring different
security properties from the way that
they were implemented
this is going to be a bit of a thing
so the interesting thing about this set
of bugs
was that because they
existed in one vendor's solution
they affected two different software
systems on opposite sides of the world
we found out about them in the context
of the swiss system because the swiss
had implemented a transparency program
and in fact had transparency regulations
but we found out afterwards
almost immediately afterwards
that the same buggy
mix net and decryption system
was already in use in the australian
state of new south wales so part of the
interesting thing for this talk is to
look at how those two different places
dealt with these this almost identical
problem
okay so we had two different places both
realized that they had run or were
running or were planning to run in the
very near future broken systems in real
elections here's what happened in
switzerland uh this is the swiss federal
chancellor and you can see he's been
making some quite strong public
statements about how concerned he is
about the failure of the uh verification
in the internet voting system
the swiss
implemented
a large program of engaging technical
experts to completely reassess their
system and their regulations and their
ways of doing the assurance associated
with the internet voting system so i
think they correctly
interpreted this as not only a failure
of the software system
but in some ways more importantly for
switzerland a failure of the audit and
certification process that they had had
running to check that the system was
okay
so that's been thoroughly reject and
that process continues uh in some ways
they kind of double down on being more
swiss right more evidence more detailed
analysis more careful uh examination of
the facts
i don't know how this is going to go
um and i don't know
whether they are going to
stop voting over the internet keep
voting over the internet in a much
restricted form change their regulations
substantially or exactly what they're
going to do but i'm
confident in the evidence-based
process that they're running
so i'm not necessarily endorsing the
software in its current form or any form
but the process that they're running
is uh
very scientifically informed
okay so let's have a look at new south
wales
here's what happened in new south wales
i'm not aware of any member of the new
south wales government
making any public statement that
acknowledged at any point that they had
ever got the memo
about there having been a serious
problem in the verification of their
election uh there were one or two
members of parliament who asked the
electoral commission some pointed
questions about it
uh and after five or ten minutes of
fussing about here's the answer that
they finally got in a parliamentary
committee hearing
uh so this is
this is the electoral commission
answering a question from members of
parliament in response to being asked
about the security problems
so he says one of the principles that we
try to apply is to make it so it's
verifiable from the input of the vote
all the way to the count and it's like
well you it was just demonstrated that
you failed to apply that principle right
and yet here he is just kind of
declaring that that's a principle that
he ain't saw and it's like well that's
great in principle i aim for a field
middle and a front cover of vogue but i
haven't actually done any of the
achieving necessary
for
uh either of those things but hey we can
just declare that that's what we're
aiming for
uh and he goes on to say uh
he goes on to brag about
the uh audit
and um
certification process including that
they have a cryptographer who comes in
to check all the cryptography and ensure
that all the mathematical proofs operate
correctly now we have just demonstrated
the mathematical proofs did not operate
correctly but that seems to be kind of
an experimental error that we don't need
to worry about
so in in other work
my colleagues and i have also found
counting errors just nothing to do with
cryptography just bugs in their account
and they've basically responded to it in
exactly the same way so they've taken
the information that we gave them about
the mistakes in their account they've
declared that their software was
certified to be perfectly correct we've
said well it's obviously not perfectly
correct is it and they said oh no that's
okay we'll fix it and then they've sent
it back
to the certification authorities who
certified it perfectly correct and the
first place to be recertified after the
bugs we found have been fixed we've
cycled three times through this process
for the same piece of counting code and
each time we've found a bug it's been
sent back to the same certification
authority to be certified perfectly
correct again
so um
in some ways i sold this talk as giving
you the you know advice about how to
deal with
um
improving the quality of election
administration in this country but at
this point i sort of have to admit that
i oversold it because i actually haven't
got a clue how to deal with this i just
don't know how you deal with a complete
imperviousness to scientific evidence
but i still think it's worth a go so
here are in front of my little bug
bullet point i've written injecting
rational scientific evidence sometimes
works i hope it works in your country
uh and uh empirical testing is
encouraged go and give it a go
also another thing that made a huge
difference here is that switzerland had
transparency laws
about the source code and the system
details whereas new south wales has
secrecy laws it's a crime to share the
source code without the
um
authority without permission from the
electoral commissioner and you can go to
jail so
this makes a huge difference i think in
the capacity of a set of electoral
authorities to just kind of pretend they
haven't got a problem
so get transparency laws rather than
secrecy laws written in your democracy
if you can
okay before we all get too smug it's
worth pointing out that even the very
good quality
academic systems aren't perfect either
so uh this is a drug work with eleanor
mcmetre and olivier pereira we found a
bug
in the
chivatas
electronic voting system which is based
on jules katano and jacobson's coercion
resistant electronic voting scheme
this is one of one of the
most beautiful papers in this field one
of the first papers with a
complete proof of security for
its protocol
and it has this it relies on this idea
that you can take two ciphertexts
and the uh allow the authorities who
share the
decryption key
to perform a protocol that allows them
to test whether those two ciphertexts
are equal
without revealing any other information
this is called a plain text equivalence
test
but there's an important little detail
in the use of those tests
in this paper
and if you read the proof of the
coercion resistant voting scheme
it specifically says that it requires
universally verifiable plaintext
equivalence proofs in other words proofs
that remain sound even if all of the
authorities collude to lie
and then it it kind of references a
paper and says oh you know for example
you could use this this paper
but then if we go and look at the paper
the paper references
uses plain text equivalence tests and
those are specifically explained to be
secure under the assumption that at
least one participant honestly
follows the protocol so we have here a
misalignment
between the assumption that's made in
the protocol
and the uh
the security property that's guaranteed
from the primitive there's nothing wrong
with the primitive there's nothing wrong
with the protocol but the primitive
that's pointed to does not actually meet
the assumptions in the protocol
and the
test implementation just uses the thing
that is pointed to in the paper
but this misalignment means that
universal verifiability fails because
the plaintext equivalence tests that
they use are such that if everybody
colludes together they can make sure
that things can seem to be
equal
when in fact they're not and this breaks
the kind of basic verifiability of the
proof because the cheating set of
authorities can pretend that someone has
submitted a valid credential when they
haven't
so even helios has had bugs uh which is
exactly why olivier knew to look for the
weak feared shamir heuristic in the
swiss post system
because they had already found and
corrected the same bug in the in the
helios system
so i don't think any of this should
surprise anyone given that any
sufficiently large software system
almost certainly has these kind of bugs
but it kind of surprises me that people
keep being surprised and you still hear
very brave
um claims
about the
security properties of not just
protocols but
systems
for
internet voting
and i think another thing about this is
these misalignments of
primitive properties and protocol
assumptions are in all three of these
cases very subtle and i think it's i
should have written it as a nice little
exercise or challenge for people who are
interested in formal verification of
cryptography that
if you can think of
a
mechanism that adequately characterizes
details this fine i think that would be
a tremendous contribution but i think
it's very hard right it's very hard to
do in general
to make sure that any kind of formal
analysis or model
identifies those kinds of very subtle
differences
okay what about the estonian system
everybody knows the estonian system is
perfectly secure right well in an
astonishing coincidence olivier pereira
just happens to have published today a
new analysis of individual verifiability
in the new version of the estonian
internet voting system and you can look
at you can look up olivier's new result
at this github link down on the bottom
of the slide but the key insight here is
that the
combination of
simple verification that they have
with revoting
actually breaks individual verifiability
so the estonian system has
really this very simple method of
individual verifiability you make a
ciphertext
you can submit the ciphertext if you
like
and you can just check directly
whether that's ciphertext has
the uh you can demand that that
ciphertext be opened and demanded that
they show you that it
produced the that that encodes the vote
that you wanted so it's it's exactly
like helios except that you cast the
thing that you challenged
so it seems very simple
except
it also has a feature that allows you to
re-vote and this is meant to be a
defense against coercion and because
it's meant to be a defense against
coercion it's important that the
verification process not expose
whether your vote has been clobbered by
a revote
so olivier's attack
really just takes advantage of this
opportunity for a cheating device to
revoke
and the feature that the user doesn't
get told whether or not the thing
they're verifying
has been substituted by a revote or not
so the attack is simply that the
cheating device
gets the voters instructions about how
they want to vote
makes a ciphertext
sends it off to the system but pretends
to crash
and then the voter tries to re-vote
again
and the cheating device
sends
a different vote which will now override
the
true voters first vote but it sends the
vote of the verification information for
the first vote so the voter is happily
verifying the ciphertext which truly is
the thing that they wanted it's just
that that ciphertext isn't the fact that
gets counted
so from our list a few slides ago of all
of the internet voting systems we know
we see
everything we know of has or has had
a
serious cryptographic errors which
completely undermine its basic security
properties
all right so everybody let's talk about
helios now because helios is actually
the best thing we have and i think it's
a great system
you know i really love it it's very
simple it's logic it's very clear
uh
it's had such good careful public
examination i'd be exceedingly surprised
if there are
further
really fundamental bugs
but so helios takes us into a different
set of things that we can think about
now i want to think about
real people actually using it
so
i hope some of you 35 of you
participated or maybe not 35 of you
maybe just one person who voted 35 times
but anyway some people participated in
my highly secure online twitter poll
and i asked you
how many times you had challenged your
heliosphere in an iicr election uh and
for a long time there was nobody who
said exactly to actually so for the
first 48 hours or so of this sunday
there was about three quarters of people
who said one uh and about a quarter of p
sorry three quarters of people said none
and uh the remaining people all said
exactly one and i was going to say
well then there's an obvious
perfectly successful strategy for a
cheating client isn't that because all
you need to do if you want to get away
with cheating
a good sixth or so of the time
is to
tell the truth for the first cypher text
and
if the person casts a second ciphertext
to cheat on that ciphertext
and that would have worked
for the effective manipulation of about
20 of votes which would probably be
enough to swing the overall election
result
and then i see in the last few hours
someone has said that they actually
challenged exactly to
ciphertexts which is pretty exciting
and um
that is one person isn't it yes one
person over 35.
so now let's think a little bit about
what that means for our cheating kilios
client
there's kind of two ways to respond to
this possibility now right one is you
could be a very very careful cheating
helios client and you could be honest
for the first two
and uh assume that you could get away
with cheating on about three percent
and be completely undetected
the other attitude to take to this is to
say well you know i'm going to go back
i'm going to go back to the uh the first
cheating strategy i'm going to cheat on
the second
cipher text knowing that there's only
about a 10 chance
that it's going to be challenged
and if i get caught
i'm just going to pretend that the voter
doesn't remember how they wanted to vote
right in other words there's in this
system
there's very little disincentive for the
cheater
to get caught because even if they do
get caught it's really only the voter's
word against theirs
so this is another really important
design goal i think which some of the
in-person systems have but which the
internet systems as a general rule don't
have which is
if a component cheats
and if they get caught
then is it a matter of actually having
real evidence
that that component misbehaved or even
that the system misbehaved
or is it simply the voter's word against
the computer's word in claiming what
they what vote they asked for in the
first place and i think that really
matters to the incentives for cheating
okay uh final thing before i move on to
polling placement polling place voting
uh one argument that is often brought
out particularly in australia is that
voting over the internet is good for
voters with disabilities because uh it
makes it easier for them to vote but i
think this thing about helios that we've
just seen
shows that if anything it's exactly the
opposite right the real
verification particularly real cast as
intended verification even among the
most expert and paranoid people in the
world is actually
fiddly and really hard sufficiently
signed that most of us don't even bother
to do it at all
so this argument that
internet voting is
enfranchising voters with disabilities i
find particularly
particularly hard to take because
actually if because
actual casters intended verification
without coming into the polling place
and being able to deal with a um simpler
kind of paper-based system is the least
useful thing anywhere in security right
this is at best this is a way for
cryptographers to vote it is not a way
for veterans with disabilities to vote
at all and i i really think it's often
just used as an excuse to not set up
adequate provision in a polling place
for
people with disabilities to access
all right
okay so now now i'm going to transition
from internet voting to
things that can happen in a polling
place
uh and i want to say that in no way am i
dissing helios right just to be clear i
love helios and i think helios is
fantastic i think it's the best system
we have uh i use it whenever i have to
run a real election over the internet
when i'm not using the highly secure
twitter poll helios is fantastic uh it's
really really good
but it exposes this fact about people
that we don't bother checking things
very carefully
however it's very clear that this is not
the fault of helios right not in any way
uh and in fact this study shows that
even if you do the simplest possible
thing and just print out a plain
paper ballot for people
only about 40 of
the participants in the study reviewed
it at all
and only 6.6
actually noticed or at least
told somebody else that they'd noticed
that there was a problem
so this study indicates that
even if you don't add any fancy crypto
or any sophisticated challenging or
anything the capacity for people to
check when a computer just doing a basic
simple printout has done something wrong
it's very very limited uh they went on
to say and this is again is going to be
an important theme that quote carefully
designed interventions and quote can
improve verification performance in
other words really making sure that the
person is forced to or strongly
encouraged or gently nudged to actually
check what they're supposed to be
checking
okay
so some of you might have read the three
or four page abstract that i wrote
in preparation for this talk that's gone
into the proceedings and i wrote a
little bit about code voting and
usability based on the study by uh
oksana kulik and uh melanie volkoma and
some of their colleagues
their studies showed that when code
voting was incorporated into the voting
process
it was a lot more effective than the
kind of challenge-based methods that
helios uses
um and the idea here so the idea of code
voting is that if you're choosing just
one
candidate so you're just kind of
conducting a simple kind of election
one out of k options
each option comes with a code that you
get sent on some separate piece of paper
and then when you choose that option the
system kind of gives you back the code
and you're supposed to check that the
code you got matches the candidate you
wanted to choose
so
uh it's been obvious to me for ages that
this does not work for australia because
we have preferential voting where you're
expressing a list of preferences rather
than choosing an individual candidate so
i've never really thought about it very
hard and i've just kind of
looked at the empirical studies that
come out of europe in particular
it was pointed out to me after i wrote
that abstract that it really doesn't
work in the u.s either because there are
zillions and zillions of contests so
it's one thing to get one code for one
kind of choice of party in a
parliamentary election and it's a
completely different thing to get one
code for each of dozens of different
options on a great big long us ballot
obviously also the trust assumptions for
code voting are a lot stronger than the
challenge based mechanisms for helios
but i'm just talking about the usability
of it at this point so i think the
bottom line is
think about the requirements for your
own country
and realize that studies in other
countries based on other kinds of voting
systems and other sorts of assumptions
are worth reading and interesting but
not necessarily definitive when it comes
to what works best for
you
okay receipt freeness is really really
really hard this is uh the
discovery of josh benello
uh
back in the 90s in stock and uh this so
receipt freeness is a privacy property
but a very very very strong one so not
only should the system keep your vote
secret
but also it should make it impossible
for you
to prove how you vote it
even if you actively want to
so this seems to be achievable in a
polling place assuming that the voter
doesn't control the voting device
because that allows us to hide
uh
detailed information like how the cipher
text was made from the voter
although of course you'd better hope
that the adversary doesn't control the
voting computer either
there are also plenty of remote schemes
which have a kind of a passive or sort
of honest but curious version of receipt
freeness where
if you follow the protocol you can't
subsequently prove how you voted
but really being not able to prove how
you voted even if you completely control
the device and you've got the
opportunity to communicate with the
coercer deviate from the protocol
and make up any part of what you want is
really really really hard
even in the polling place there have
been a whole series of bugs found in
good quality schemes that seem to have
this property but actually turn out not
too
okay but nevertheless i think just about
everything is easier in a polling place
and here are five things that really
stand out as being easier
so first of all
privacy or coercion none of these things
are perfect by the way so the voter is
usually alone uh
of course if they have their smartphone
or a pushy relative beside them that
doesn't work so well but the idea but at
least it works better and more easily
than it does over the internet uh
restate freeness again because we assume
that they don't control the voting
device
accountability because depending on the
design of the system
you might be able to prove that the
system malfunctioned of course this is a
property of the system design but there
are some systems for example systems
based on pre-printed ballots in which
you you can if the system misbehaves in
some
circumstances
prove that it misbehaved without having
to be trusted to
recount
how you instructed it
uh it also just opens the opportunity
for really easy individual verification
because we can base it on a plain paper
ballot under the assumption that
somebody looks at it
and also finally i think this point
about the carefully designed
interventions is actually really
powerful and the opportunity to guide
people through verification
encourage them to do it properly help
them out if they make a mistake is
actually a huge benefit of voting in a
polling place all the more so if we're
using a complicated or fancy
cryptographic design that people might
not understand very well i suspect that
a lot of the
motivation for internet voting is
actually that it kind of keeps these
problems out of sight
when actually it would be much better to
bring them into the polling place and
guide people through them
okay uh risk limiting audits uh i don't
know if you've heard about this if
you're in the us you probably have if
you haven't
uh the this is an entirely statistical
concept although i think a statistical
concept for which cryptographers could
have a lot of sympathy the idea is
that
we assume that the paper ballots are all
good
so we assume that the paper ballots have
been carefully looked after properly
secured and so forth
and we
conduct a randomized statistical order
of the
paper
evidence
to give us
either to detect that there's a problem
or to give us some confidence that the
answer is right
and there's some very beautiful
statistics and some very thorough
analysis that show that you can design
auditing algorithms in such a way that
you can prove
that the probability of mistakenly
accepting and certifying a wrong
election result is
is bounded by some risk limit that you
can choose in advance
and the idea is that you go you go along
doing this audit of the paper ballots
until either your risk is satisfied or
you
decide that
the evidence is inconclusive and you
manually count all of the paper records
so there's extensive theory for all
kinds of election setups most of it is
oriented around the us but there's
plenty of extensions for
uh instant run-off voting dehaunt
european style kind of parliamentary
elections and so on there's open source
software from a couple of different
places some from philip stark and some
from voting works by benedita
but of course there are also obvious
trust assumptions and limitations right
you can only participate in this
verification if you are physically
present because you have to look at the
paper ballot being retrieved
and there's this huge assumption on the
custody the secure custody of the paper
parts
now it's an interesting little fact that
if you actually think about how to run a
risk limiting audit there's a little bit
of crypto involved because at the very
least you need to prove that the random
selections necessary for auditing the
uh for choosing the paper ballots
have been done in uh have been done with
integrity and are not predictable so
here's uh ron rivest and philip stark
tossing dice and inputting those dice
into some codes for generating the
pseudorandom permutation for selecting
the bullets uh and so this is what turns
the statistical process into a publicly
verifiable process because now everybody
else can see how ron rolled the dice and
verify that they really are going and
fishing out the ballots that they're
supposed to not some kind of
pre-programmed set of pellets that have
been carefully chosen to not cheat
okay so the last thing i want to talk
about is end-to-end verifiable voting in
a polling place which i actually think
is
probably the most interesting thing to
do there's lots of different designs
each reflecting the requirements of a
different election system so on the left
we have the v vote project from my home
state of victoria which uses
preferential voting you can see all the
uh the preference numbers
mashed into a protocol bullet
on the right at the top we have the
wombat voting system from israel which
is just beautiful and very simple which
i think reflects probably the the um
very simple voting system uh that's in
use there
uh and down on the bottom right we have
the scantigrity invisible ink system
which unsurprisingly looks a lot like an
american ballot because
of um
the
the use
in that and they use codes it's kind of
a hybrid between code voting and uh
challenge-based voting
so there's lots of different designs
interestingly enough
neither the v-vote system nor the
scantegrity system is still in use
although they were both used in
government elections and i think the
wombat system is still being used but
not in government elections so all of
these things are they're really cool but
they're not actually being run for
electing governments
i could be wrong about one bad i should
double check
so
the most exciting thing that's happening
which um
i've been a little bit involved in um
but mostly as an observer is josh
benello's election guard thing in uh
which is a complete
open source
kit
for supporting
end-to-end verifiable elections
income in um concert with risk limiting
audits so i actually think this this is
the future of voting in my opinion
and um
if my abstract gave the impression that
i didn't think the cryptographic
solutions were
of value that was absolutely not the
impression i meant to give i think that
this approach to combine the
cryptographic solutions with the
paper-based statistical auditing is
absolutely
the way to go and the the reason i think
this is the way to go
is that if it's well-designed you get a
sort of disjunctive set of trust
assumptions in other words the
cryptographic evidence has some
assumptions the statistical evidence has
some assumptions specifically about the
chain of custody of the paper ballots
the thing that i really love about
election guard is the way that it's
designed to
take advantage of both of them so you
can either
trust the statistical evidence
associated with the paper ballots or you
can trust the cryptographic evidence
for
the continuing
proof that your ballot was included in
the telly even after you walked away
and i think the flexibility in the
combination of those two things is just
the right way to go
so i think this will give us this will
not give us voting over the internet
because it doesn't solve any of the
earlier things we talked about for that
but this will give us very flexible and
very
high integrity voting
in a polling place potentially you know
in a polling place a bit further away
from home or in a polling place a couple
more weeks before the election or it
will reduce the strain on the paper
ballot custody assumption anyway
so i think this is really cool
uh i'm almost out of time so i'm going
to summarize my favorite technical open
problems
so
one of the issues with combining the
cryptographic verification
and the risk limiting audit ideas is
that cryptographic verification
particularly individual verification
tends to be a thing that you do at the
time right you can challenge your helios
ballot at the time that you're voting
but if you miss your chance and you
realize after the election that it was
actually super close you can't escalate
in the way that you could with risk
limiting audits
you can go back and check that your
cipher text is on the bulletin board but
you can't necessarily check
that you can't redo the check of whether
or not that ciphertext reflected your
intentions so here's an interesting
little
um puzzle is can you think of a form of
cryptographic verification that can be
escalated if the result is close
a second thing that those athenian discs
had that we don't have in our electronic
systems is publicly verifiable privacy
right they have public verifiable
publicly verifiable we have publicly
verifiable integrity but i can't
actually see whether my electronic
ballot
is private or not i'm trusting usually
i'm trusting a threshold of
authorities who have the decryption key
thirdly caster's intended verification
is the hardest part because that's the
part that an ordinary person has to do
and it's probably going to be different
in your country from what it is in every
other country that has
invented something because your
elections are probably a little bit
different from everybody else's
on that note the carefully designed
interventions to encourage people to do
the verification carefully obviously
have to be specific
um my favorite
puzzle at the moment is trying to do
something like the hybrid paper and
crypto schemes but for remote voting and
trying to think about whether there's a
nice way of
getting the information on the plain
paper ballot posted back but also
using some cryptographic techniques to
give people evidence of their vote
having been properly counted when it
arrived
so again i think i wrote the wrong thing
in my abstract i i sort of referred to
what happened to the piece of paper but
what i actually mean of course is what
happens to the information
uh the last thing that's really
interesting is verifying that only
eligible people voted without
making the vital list completely public
all right i am out of time so i'm going
to skip my reality check and just this
is my concluding slide okay so what can
you do
first of all you can find out what's
wrong with your own electoral system and
fix it before the election if you're not
having an election right now then now is
exactly the right time to find out a
little bit about what's happening in
your democracy and make suggestions for
change before it gets too catastrophic
one thing that i found reduces the heat
a lot
in every country where i've seen it
happen is to get an agreement on
requirements
carefully written down in advance
because then you can have a scientific
discussion about whether a particular
system meets the requirements rather
than a kind of heated argument about
whether the system is adequate according
to what you think the requirements
should be
and finally
i think
on the theme of just teaching people to
think
in a bit more of a paranoid way
persuade them that they need to build
evidence into their electoral processes
rather than just building the system so
that everything kind of seems to be okay
which i bet you will find is the sort of
natural
instinct of almost everybody who builds
election systems
encourage them to think that it's a good
thing when they notice that something
went wrong
and on that note i will end and welcome
discussion and questions
thanks vanessa so if there are any
questions um you could i see nobody
typed any questions in the zulip or in
chat you can type them in you can try to
just jump in and talk or given there are
many people you could also try to raise
your hand
and i'll call on you but i guess the
first one can just jump in and unmute
yourself and
ask questions
oh there's something in the chat uh by
uh
niels
you wanna right
yeah yeah yeah yeah absolutely right um
i think if we see one of the most
important requirements the voting system
should be so simple that almost
everybody can understand it any use of
crypto looks like magic to most people
and that is not good no i 100 agree and
indeed um
in some ways i think the
massive industry of snake oil around
um
internet voting blockchain voting etc
is really because of exactly this issue
right that that uh
the difference between a thing that is
actually sound
a thing that is sound is
indistinguishable from a thing that is
complete rubbish to almost all normal
voters uh and you're 100 right
um
i think that's part of the reason that
the hybrid systems are really good
because
you
um
you can choose your trust assumption
and uh you know if the crypto is
unintelligible you can trust the paper
and if you
understand the crypto you can work with
that or if you trust somebody who
understands the crypto then you can work
with that
um but yes i look i agree i just i don't
know how to do crypto that everybody
understands
vanessa i have a question that's vaguely
related to this point um which is in
your first part of the talk you talked
about this issue of you know all these
implementations are wrong even though
the components are fine but they just
implemented it in the wrong context to
reveal the trap door
that doesn't sound to me special
specific to voting systems isn't it like
a difficulty in any crypto employment
yeah
and this comment that you just discussed
makes voting even harder possibly but
it just absolutely and i think i think
part of the i think you're absolutely
right in some ways i think that on
people
there's a degree of trust in
voting systems
that isn't
um
isn't imposed on anything else right um
everything has bugs right everything has
bugs including voting systems and yet
somehow people seem willing to trust
voting systems
even when they know that they actually
have no independent way of checking it
so your banking system you can kind of
see if you've lost all your money your
um
but
with voting
there's no corresponding kind of basic
double checking and no capacity to often
no capacity to recover often no capacity
even to naturally detect when there's
been a problem so yeah i completely
agree in some ways um
what i was saying was exactly what you
just said absolutely that then in fact
every system has these bugs and yet
somehow we seem willing to tolerate the
possibility in systems that have just
the strongest threat model you could
possibly have
oh to neil ferguson who said i just pen
and paper yeah i so
yes
to a large extent i'd just been in favor
today actually over in australia we
almost exclusively pen and paper um i do
think you get something out of you get a
few things out of risk limiting audits
because you can count you can just count
faster right so in countries like the us
where they're counting vast complicated
things they can't count manually in
practice so they have to they have to do
something other than count everything by
hand and and they can do that uh in that
i think what the
polling place
end-to-end verifiable systems add on top
of pen and paper is not having to trust
the paper chain of custody
but i completely agree that it should be
an on top of
rather than an instead of
there's a comment from john kelsey in
the chat
um
but if john or anyone else wants to ask
uh in person life question that might be
good
i i might have some background noise
if you can
here so but all i was pointing out is
for end-to-end systems they are
optimized for making sure that if
there's any fraud you you you have a
good chance of detecting it
that offers another angle of attack
where my goal is just to discredit an
election that's very close sort of do
the equivalent of the attack on the
naive coin flipping protocol where i
abort the protocol if the if the coin
flip's gonna go the wrong way
right so if i just tamper with some
machines so that me and some other
people in on the attack
get bad receipts then we decide whether
or not to release that
to discredit an election that we don't
like
and yeah niels i mean it's hard to
imagine any powerful elected figure
trying to undermine the outcome of an
election
yeah
yep uh yeah again completely agree
um
and again i guess it depends what you
how you respond to that
um
yeah i agree i agree that's a problem i
don't have a good
i don't have a good answer to that
except again to say that uh if i was
organizing it i'd make sure well
although i mean to some extent the same
is true for just about anything
including plain paper right that um
you can say
whatever that you saw the
um officials throwing the paper ballots
in the trash or or something i don't
know whether
the end-to-end systems actually make
this
worse they definitely don't solve it
um
yeah it seems like a
hard problem to me
um vanessa there's a question in zulip
um from carolyn how can voting be
implemented in highly untrusted
environments such as non-democratic
countries is there a way crypto can
offer a better security assumption in
these environments for the citizens
wow that's a really hard question
i think
i mean it relates a little bit to
john's point about
willful
undermining of the
perceived value of the election right
um
i think if the people running the
election uh
willfully trying to make it look as if
it is badly run
then i don't know that there's very much
you can do unfortunately
um
because exactly like john just said the
the purpose of all these um methods of
checking is to have an opportunity to
see whether it's been badly run but if
the objective is to make it look like
it's been badly run well we don't really
have a defense against that
um i wish i did have a solution to that
problem but i don't think i don't know
yeah there was a follow-up comment that
that crypto would just add another layer
of distrust in election due to lack of
understanding of the math
possibly so possibly yeah possibly an
easier thing to dis possibly another
thing to discredit yeah
sadly
do you want to ask your question
or should i read it
oh i asked it um yeah no i i think this
is an interesting question i mean is
there a way that you could
maybe keep a ballot
uh public so you know it's a well-formed
kind of ballot but then anonymize
the connection between
a voter and then a particular plaintext
ballot
that i'm
i haven't seen
one
in which there isn't a big trust
assumption on the authorities
for only
back how's this
you're back but you should repeat your
entire comments
oh dear i believe you've frozen again
vanessa
maybe unshare the screen and just talk
this
vanessa we can't hear you unfortunately
i'm so glad this doesn't happen during
the talk but
[Music]
well
in the meantime i have a comment that
just occurred to me it's a time of
attack i haven't heard anybody mention
before
suppose some of the organizers of the
collection would like to have the option
of discrediting the election later so
you run the election
and
part of the cryptographic systems
we can verify them but if my goal is to
discredit the election if i if the
people with the key central keys or
something like that do the wrong thing
it provides in controversial proof of
manipulations in the election
that seems to be a different attack
model
that's the connection now
i think you're back
sorry about that
uh so now you have to tell me what i
missed
yeah niels you want to repeat your
attack yeah
i just as part of the talk in the
comments i came up with a new attack on
the election system i never thought
about
suppose the people who organize the
election
want to have the option of discrediting
an outcome they don't like
yeah so with cryptographic systems they
could
misbehave later if they don't like the
outcome they misbehave they provide
incontrovertible proof that the election
was defrauded
and they can invalidate an outcome they
don't like
that would seem to be a separate attack
that i have never had anybody look into
yeah that's really interesting and your
point is that uh if we're all voting in
the with uh paper ballots and glasses or
whatever then uh it's a lot harder for
them to do that
the paper ballots the fraud doesn't
scale very well right i think one of the
important ratios is how many people are
in the conspiracy versus how many votes
can you be fraud
okay you're fast yep
yep uh and how how easy how likely are
you to get caught
and
the other part obviously the primary
fraud is in photo roll photo suppression
and role you know photo role
manipulation and stuff like that it's
not an accounting accounting is the easy
part
i don't know well we have why
there's suppression here in america
it's it's it is a yes primary goal of
one of the main bodies
yes yes that's true you do yeah whereas
we have compulsory voting uh in
australia so
um back again back to the point that
different democracies are different
right i think that and i think different
weak points are probably different
depending on exactly what the rest of
the set up is yeah
uh but yes i agree with that the vote
suppression in the united states is
probably the worst thing uh you don't
even need to bother fiddling with the
numbers you're
fiddling with the count given that uh
such a large fraction of voters are so
deliberately excluded pretty bad
and we're over time but it's an
interesting discussion so if somebody
wants to add another comment or question
uh we can do maybe one more before
wrapping up
there's been some comments on the chat
but vanessa just to make sure i
understood you correctly in your last
slide you don't need to share it you
said you know find out what they're
doing in your country and fix it so by
fix it your ideal fix would be
like abandon the fully electronic thing
and do a hybrid system that's your fix
yeah
yeah that's what i would do
just just wanted to make
sure i would put out that
it is
not without discussion that electronics
in cryptography have any role to play in
elections whatsoever
yeah i think that's a very fair point i
agree there are some countries in which
um
there just doesn't need to be a role for
electronic stuff i think there are other
countries in which manual counting of
paper ballots is not feasible uh it's
not really feasible in the united states
um and you could say well just do risk
limiting audits then and don't do any
cryptography um
and i think that's uh that's definitely
a
defensible
position but then what you what you get
on from the end-to-end verifiability
stuff on top of the risk limiting audits
is that you don't have to trust the
people who looked after the paper
nils you seem to be assuming this is an
either-or situation
and it's possible to have
pen and paper ballots and end-to-end
verifiability and risk living audits you
can get the best of all
i i think there are some very
interesting
ideas there and i haven't quite
evaluated them but i worry greatly about
this rush to oh we should apply
cryptography and i greatly
object to things like the icr using a
helios system
and and endorsing it with that
i
we we claim we make claims of security
for pieces of computer software
and i think that goes much too far some
of us are old enough to remember when
the ballots in iacr were cast by the
postal system and i must say the
international postal system has some
unique failure modes
yes we see this is done for reachability
not for other things
i completely understand but we could do
that without endorsing a magic box of
cryptographic formulas
anyway let's not go into that discussion
that's not but uh well i definitely
wouldn't endorse that for government
elections i hope that was clear from the
talk in some ways the whole point of
this uh analysis was to say i don't
think that yeah internet voting for
government elections is a good idea i
think it's a really bad idea uh and i
think it's been shown to fail over and
over and over and over again
this was obvious
okay so thank you very much vanessa for
a very interesting talk and discussion
um we'll end the session here yeah thank
you
okay i'll hang it on the chat for the
next few hours so anybody who would like
to ask more questions or engage in more
discussion is very welcoming yeah thanks
for having me