hi i'll be presenting silver silent bowl
and oblivious transfer from the hardness
of decoding ldpc codes this is joint
work with jeff wah and srini
along with myself peter rindahl
so as a way of introduction i'd like to
introduce
oblivious transfer
here this there's two parties a sender
and a receiver the sender has two
messages m0 and m1 and the receiver has
a choice bit c the receiver should learn
the message mc and nothing about the
other message
oblivious transfer is used throughout
multi-party computation and it's one of
the most fundamental
protocols in cryptography
there's also a variant of
oblivious cancer known as random alleles
transfer here
the parties don't exactly have input
instead the functionality or the
protocol chooses the everything at
random so the m0 and m1 is random and
the choice bit c is random and otherwise
the protocol is roughly the same and the
nice thing about random ots is that you
can sort of derandomize them and get
back to the original ot correlation and
so in some sense random ot is all that
you need
uh further we can consider sort of a
slight variant on this
is that let the messages m0 and m1 be
offset by some delta and then you can
rewrite the receiver's message mc as m0
plus c times this delta value
and this is a sort of naturally
generalizes to something known as
oblivious linear evaluation here the key
distinction from ot is that
c the choice bit
is allowed to be
a field element instead of just binary
and we can further generalize this to
what is known as vector ole
here the message m0 is a vector messages
and similarly the choice
value c is now a vector and so you get a
vector correlation which m c equals
vector m0 plus vector m vector c times
the scalar delta
and rewriting sort of the terms to be a
b c and delta to clean it up a little uh
you we can see this is the correlation
and the nice thing about this vol
correlation is that you can sort of
as i mentioned before de-randomize it to
get back to ot
uh whichever variant of ot that you want
or you can stay with this sort of vocal
correlation where uh this
choice vector a now is uh over the field
and so throughout this talk i'll be
referring to this formulation and not
the oblivious transfer one but just
understand that they're in some sense
equivalent
another property that we want is this
silent
feature where
the protocol itself
is only a setup protocol in that this it
has low communication and it outputs
some small keys to the sender and
receiver
and then by local communic uh local
computation only they're able to expand
these keys into the final vol
correlation
uh in particular the setup should be
sublinear in the size of the vectors and
the expansion should be non-interactive
our our whole protocol that we use in
this talk
is in fact silent in this way
[Music]
and it's a nice property to have because
it allows you to a get less
communication and b
uh you can pronounce
communication during a setup phase and
then sort of go offline or store the
keys for later use
the volt protocol or ot protocol
whichever is the case
that that were that we use uh
its setup phase it internally uses this
thing called a punctured prf
i'm not going to get into exactly what a
punctured prf is but suffice it to say
that so the gen generation algorithm is
run inside an npc protocol which outputs
these keys k 0 and c1
these can then be expanded using the
puncture qrf function
to get the following correlation
it's
basically identical to the volt
correlation that we want in the end with
the catch that this a vector is sparse
meaning that only say 100 or 200 of the
locations of this a prime vector
is non-zero
and overall this vector might be a
length a million so it's highly sparse
but it is close to the correlation that
we want
so the next step is that we'll run lpn
to sort of bootstrap this sparse
correlation into the standard vocal
correlation
and we'll talk more about lpn later but
suffices say now
what lpn consists of is multiplying a
large random matrix g from the left by
the vector
and then this gets you the final output
and critically lpn says that even though
this a prime vector is sparse the final
a vector is in fact uniformly random
and this is sort of concludes what how
our vol protocol or that the volt
protocol that we use that works
so drilling in to this lpn instance in
particular we want to run generate say a
million or many millions of ots or volts
whichever you have and this means that
the lpn instance will be very large so
say if we want 4 million ots then our g
matrix here will be 4 million by 8
million for example and this
for classic lpn this mean uh this
corresponds to this g matrix being
uniformly random
and therefore the multiplication would
be quadratic time uh taking you know
roughly to the power 40 untime
which is clearly impractical if we're
going for extremely high performance
this leads us to
a modification known as like structured
lpn here we place additional structure
on this matrix g
which allows us to do this matrix vector
multiplication in uh in less time
uh previous works had achieved this in
sort of n log end time while in this
work we will design a new matrix g uh
that actually allows us to do linear
time multiplication uh but importantly
you have to be careful in that uh by
modifying this matrix g you might weaken
the lpn instance and so it's a careful
balance between getting high performance
or also maintaining the security of lpn
and we'll discuss that next
uh by way of doing this we're going to
introduce what's known as primalopn this
is how it's traditionally thought of and
here you have a public matrix a it's a
large random matrix
and then
someone takes their seed s and e these
are
vectors as shown here
s will be sort of uniformly random but
somewhat short while e is sparse uh but
longer and so you'll do a times s plus e
and this gives you r
now lpn says that r should be
indistinguishable from uniformly random
sort of shown here given that the matrix
a is public
in our work we'll use what's known as
the dual formulation
here we have a matrix g
and we'll just we just do g times this
sparse vector e and this gives us a sort
of a short
ideally uniformly random vector r hat
and again the the
security statement somewhat similar is
that g and r should be indistinguishable
from uniform random
these two formulations actually
equivalent to see how this works i
relabeled this a matrix as h transpose
and then
let g and h
be the generator and parity check matrix
for an air correcting code so if you're
starting with primal then you are given
h as the lpn matrix and you can derive
the corresponding
generator matrix
for that error correcting code
and then to see why these two are
equivalent
we use the properties of the generator
times the transpose of the parity check
matrix h
equals 0. and so if you multiply the
primal lpn instance from the left by g
you get the following
g times h transpose is zero
and so zero times s is zero and so what
you're left with is just g times the
sparse vector e equals g times the
sort of uniformly random vector r
and
uh by some properties of the generating
matrix it's not hard to show that as
long as r is uniformly random then g
times r is uniformly random and that's
how we arrive at our dual formulation
and so next i'll be talking about uh the
security of the primal version of lpn
but our implementation will use dual lpn
and these sort of are equivalent
um so lpn has been studied extensively
uh there's numerous attacks based on
gaussian elimination set uh sec
recovering set information set decoding
and so forth and so on uh and since
we're in the business of designing a new
lpn matrix it'd be very tedious to have
to like go through each one of these
papers and sort of just
decide whether their attack is relevant
to our
our particular lpn instance
but fortunately we don't have to and
that
there's this framework which is
introduced previous to us known as the
linear test framework
and here
the adversary is first given the the
matrix in question h and they're allowed
to pre-process so arbitrarily uh
whatever they want and then they output
a vector v
and this and then uh
as a way of distinguishing whether the r
is from an lpn instance or uniformly
random uh the adversary will output a
bit v inner product r
uh and so if say if p is one then that's
maybe saying that uh it's an lpn
instance and otherwise it's random
and fortunately all these attacks can be
framed in this framework with adversary
pre-processes the lpn matrix outputs a
vector and then inner products the
vector with r
and now that now that we have this sort
of linear test
we can sort of reason about it
so first let us consider the case where
this matrix
h transpose is uh it's rows are d y is
independent meaning uh it takes at least
d plus one rows to be added together to
equal zero
uh
then we can consider quote-unquote a
sparse v meaning that the hamming weight
of this test vector v is less than d the
row wise independence value
and what this will look like is so v
times h transpose times s which is sort
of like the contribution s makes to r
uh will equal sort of some other uh
matrix h prime times s where h prime is
row wise independent and it's not hard
to see since s is uniformly random and
you're multiplying it by row wise
independent
matrix h which is sort of short
then the output will be uniformly random
and so what it is saying is that when v
is sparse that the s is what's saving
our lpn instance or what's giving our
lpm instance
making it indistinguishable from
uniformly random
on the other case when v is dense uh the
e vector comes into play in that to see
this uh roughly speaking is that once v
is sufficiently dense then the
probability that it intersects this air
vector becomes high overwhelming and in
this case that further derandomizes the
result and so then it becomes uh the e
makes the r uniformly random and so it's
sort of a balancing act between these
two extremes sparse v and dense v
uh this analysis strictly stems from the
fact that
we considered
h to be
h transposed to b
d y's rho independent
and uh this in turn sort of tells us how
to set how noisy the e vector needs to
be
but
this uh
row wise independence property is
equivalent to saying that the
code generated by this other matrix g
should have minimum distance d
um and so this brings us to a way of
searching for new uh highly efficient
lpn instances we simply need to find a
linear code g with parity check matrix h
which has high minimum distance uh for
the code it should have fast encode here
we actually need the transpose of the
encoding algorithm but this ends up not
being an issue and finally this code
should be efficient when the dimensions
are very large so these properties are
somewhat unique to us a lot of codes out
there aim to achieve additional
properties or some other set of
properties and so we're looking to
optimize just these properties
to do this we turn to
uh
low density parity check
codes
these codes are sort of
are
characterized by having the parity check
matrix h being sparse so this might mean
the number of ones in any given column
of h is some uh fixed constant
and then to encode ldpc codes a common
approach is to uh
instead of mult having x multiplied by
the generator which is maybe the
traditional method you will solve the
system of equations that h times the
code word c
equals zero
and we're about to go over several
examples of such ldpc codes uh
which namely the uniform code which has
good minimum distance but poor encoding
time uh in the until it's the more code
which is sort of has the inverse
but first i want to talk about the g alt
encoder this is the encoder that we're
going to use
and here uh
the way you
the way of explaining the glt encoder
first we need to consider the
systematic form of the code and here
to given g and h you can get the
systematic form g prime and h prime by
doing row operations until
h has the identity matrix on the right
and g has the identity matrix on the
left and in some sense this doesn't
change the code
it just uh you're just sort of
re-labeling things
but
uh and then this gl encoder will
actually encode under g prime the sort
of systematic form
uh but we don't actually want to
explicitly write out h prime because
even though h is sparse h prime might
not be
but that's okay because we can leverage
the fact that uh the null space of these
of h prime and h are the same meaning
that uh if x times epsilon which is of
some code word
if h prime times that equals 0 then it
would also hold true for h
and then the next step
is that
and this allows us to run sort of
solving the system of linear equations
onto h and x and epsilon that's the idea
uh but the next step in our encoder is
that we first need to perform row and
column operation swaps uh on h in order
to put it in this form known as
approximate g lower triangular
here the idea is that uh h should
basically be a lower triangular matrix
except for we allow the last g rows not
to be so
any matrix can be put into this form for
some value of g you know g might almost
be the whole thing or you know uh and so
forth
uh and then we have an encoding
algorithm that can be written like this
basically it's a form of like a back
propagation algorithm
but the important takeaway even if all
this didn't really make too much sense
is that the running time of this
encoding algorithm is m plus g squared
so
uh importantly we we uh
this algorithm is only efficient i mean
only linear time when g is a small or
square root m
so now let us consider the uniform ldpc
code
the uniform ldpc codes is described by
having some fixed column weight w
so each column will have weight w and
this and then show an example on the
right is say three but in practice it'd
be like five or maybe eleven
and then
it's been shown uh sort of analytically
that this code has linear minimum
distance which is great which is what we
want
um but the problem is that how to encode
uh you know there's various ways but if
we're going to use our g alt encoder the
first step right is to put it in this
approximate lower triangular form
and the way of doing this is you can do
row and column swaps
you don't want to do row addition
operations because that will increase
the weight
which is undesirable but just doing row
and column swaps is okay
but the problem is that you can show at
least for uh typical uh linear time
algorithms uh
is that the when you do those rows in
column swaps uh the
the gap inside the gap will remain
linear in the overall size of the code
and this
basically means our overall running time
will be quadratic and not efficient
enough for our application
uh this leads us to our second code
which is the tillage zoom or code
here the code is sort of broken up into
a left half and right half
the left half is uniformly random
subject to some column weight w
while the right half has two diagonals
right next to each other of ones
the reason for this structure is several
fold but one of them is that it gives
you a fast encoding in particular using
the glt encoder we have g equals one and
so trivially linear time
uh as we'll get back to actually the
left half although linear time is
actually quite slow due to the
randomized nature as we'll talk about
um one of the primary issues with this
code is that it actually achieves
sub-linear minimum distance uh the
authors of the code showed analytically
that it's uh yeah it achieves the
minimum distance shown here and
this is primarily or exclusively due to
these diagonals that they introduced
and their code had several reasons to
introduce them
among them was fast encoding
we in order to get a grips on the exact
minimum distance that these codes have
we actually implemented some extensive
experimental uh techniques to
evaluate an upper bound on the actual
minimum distance and given this we do
observe that the uniform code does
achieve linear minimum distance while
the tillets zimmer code gets sort of
sublinear minimum distance
as a way of explaining this you can
consider what do these minimum distance
uh
what does the minimum distance really
look like with respect to
the parity check matrix and one way to
formulate what this is is it's how many
columns of this parity check matrix do
you need to add together such that you
get the zero vector
and
one way of going about doing this and in
fact what typically are the low way
code words in this uh what happens is
you take several columns from the left
hand side which almost cancel out but
have maybe two ones which are nearby
each other which don't cancel
and then you include the corresponding
column from the right which sort of
bridges the gap between these two
as shown here if the gap is more than
one you can then include like the next
two columns in the right
half and so in some sense uh these
diagonals allow you to sort of bridge
the gap between
code words from the left which are
almost equal and that's the structure of
minimum weight code words in this code
and so given this you know you could try
to formulate ways to improve the
minimum weight performance of this code
so this leads us to our first code
silver code one and we start with the
telescope code uh zoom our code excuse
me and we remove the weight two columns
and we replace them with uh higher
weight sort of weight w columns uh we we
keep the g alt
form
but uh allow g to increase from one is
the basic idea and below this main
diagonal we fill the
uh
fill sum region uh
with uniformly random columns subject to
having the desired column weight w
so shown here right we have a gap of
four with a column weight of three
and we just fill in the values below the
cap uniformly random
and the idea here
is that you know if we go back to our
example before right you might want to
uh you know you get code work columns
from the left half which are almost
equal and then you include the
corresponding columns on the right you
can see that this no longer works
because the non-zero locations below the
main diagonal uh
won't cancel out nicely most likely and
so this sort of allows
this new code to
sort of defend partially at least defend
against these bridging
attacks so to speak
and we experimentally validate that this
alteration does in fact improve the tz
code significantly and we almost get the
same performance as uniform with the
same column weight
through further iteration and looking at
what
what type of low weight code words exist
in these codes we identified that often
in the right hand side you'll get
two columns which are very similar and
mostly cancel with each other and this
allows a similar type of bridging attack
or bridging phenomenon per se
and to prevent this we discovered
through extensive experimentation that
if you add an additional diagonals below
this main diagonal it helps prevent this
attack sort of intuitively it ensures
that the spreading is is larger
across the rows and you can't simply
get unlucky and have a few columns on
the right hand side uh canceled properly
for more details to see the paper
uh but the main takeaway is that this
further significantly improves the
performance of the code
uh now we turn to the
optimizing the left half where the main
issue is that although our
code is linear time and codable the
memory efficiency of performing the left
half of the parity check matrix is
actually quite low roughly speaking uh
what this corresponds to is taking this
left half of the matrix and multiplying
it with a vector and since it's more or
less uniformly random this corresponds
to performing uh roughly you know
million random accesses into an array of
length 1 million or you know whatever
the array size is and this ends up being
really inefficient for from a memory
perspective because every memory access
goes to main memory which is
significantly slower than say icash or
something like that
uh we tried numerous techniques to try
to improve the cash efficiency and we
ended up landing on this one which is
surprisingly simple in that you replace
the laptop with just several diagonals
or
w diagonals going across
and
they need to be spaced irregularly with
a certain structure in order to avoid
some pathological cases
uh but we experimentally validated this
that our codes do in fact work well
and in fact this uniform or this uh
silver code actually outperforms the
uniform code with the same weight which
is somewhat surprising
uh our final optimization is that uh we
change that the current most uh
inefficient part of this code is that uh
sampling this main diagonal which
consists of these sort of uniformly
random columns subject to being in this
band
is actually quite inefficient especially
when this matrix a size of one million
you could say store in memory but this
again is so undesirable due to its size
and so
we experimented with deranimizing the
this uh main diagonal by repeating the
rows after sort of every g steps
and we experimentally validated that
this uh doesn't hurt uh minimum distance
performance
we also make the rows regular meaning
that they all have the same number of
ones in each row and this further helps
improve the efficiency of the
implementation
but the final takeaway is that our final
code is sort of highly structured uh
and but still achieves as good of
minimum distance performance as the
uniform code
we designed two codes although others
could be
considered which have column weight 5
and column weight 11 and i get the
corresponding uh minimum distance from
here
uh the other
point of optimization that we considered
is the sort of the right the running
time of our codes so shown here at the
bottom is our final code silver five uh
and the weight five variant of it has
takes
uh one point one three seconds to encode
a vector of length sixteen million uh
you can compare this to the work of boil
at all which uses quasi-cichlid codes
which takes four seconds for the same
operation or the tz code which takes two
seconds so you can see it's a very
significant order magnitude
improvement over the state of art
while when applying this to our
oblivious transfer protocol we can see
that this significantly improves the
performance so our protocol is basically
the same protocol as the boiler tall one
shown here but with our code replaced
and you can see this reduces the running
time from 10 seconds to half a second
for 16 million ots
and we achieve the same
sublinear communication
another work from
2020 uses primal lpn and a sort of
similar structure
to ours and they
can perform 10 000 ots in uh roughly
like 1.2 seconds while ours takes a
quarter second so very significant
improvement uh what's more ours achieves
the silent property was theirs does not
maybe the most surprising takeaway is
that our protocol is actually faster
than the original ot extension work of
iknp this work has stood the test time
for almost 20 years and our and we
finally are able to beat it in terms of
running time and
also significantly improve its
communication
uh a similar story is true for the volt
performance is that uh we are roughly
five times faster than uh
another full work from 2020 uh and this
and we also achieve this silent property
and with that i conclude my talk silver
silent vole and oblivious transfer thank
you