welcome to my talk the t-wise
independence of substitution permutation
networks
i'm tirion this is a joint work with
stefano and vinod
a central problem in crypto is to
construct random looking hidden
permutations
tons of works are targeting this problem
among these works
there is a well-known but not so
well-defined gap between theory and
practice
the theory work
called this object a pseudo-random
permutation
and they focus on security based on
well-studied assumptions
the practice work
called this object a block cipher
they are okay with heuristical security
the first priority
is being super efficient
i'm not seeing the theory work don't
care about the efficiency of practical
work don't care about proof just as we
all know
this gap exists
and it seems very hard to bridge it
in the literature
we already have purple secure prp based
on one way function factoring or lattice
problems
unfortunately
none of them is fast enough to be
practical
in practice
people use much more efficient block
ciphers such as aes
of course
everyone
everyone wants to understand whether eos
is secure
from the theory perspective
we want to base aes on hardness
assumptions
but we don't know how to do it
we don't even have a candidate
assumption
many theory work then try to ask the
security of es or similar ciphers in
some idealized models
but still
this work are not analyzing the actual
block ciphers
when we could start proving security
against arbitrary attacks
the next best thing we can hope for
is to identify classes of attacks
and to prove they cannot succeed with
good probability
to show this in picture
the community has already identified
many classes of attacks
previous works shows aes
can resist
some certain classes of text to some
extent
in this paper
we promote the study of t-wise
independence
which is the desired property
of block ciphers
when t equals 2
it already implies resistance to several
normal attacks including linear and
differential attacks
larger t implies resistance to more
attacks
t-wise independence is a very natural
property
for any t inputs
the corresponding t outputs should be id
uniform
we'll use a relaxed form
the corresponding t outputs should be
epsilon close to uniform
in statistical distance
okay
for visibility
the key lines has to be at least t times
the author less
this requirement can be ensured
by the standard assumption of
independent run key
which is assumed in almost every work in
the field especially starting a yes
from the theory perspective
t vice independence means
security against unbounded adversary who
makes at most t-curse
notice that
linear and differential attacks relies
on correlation between two queries
so
in some sense this attacks
are captured by an adversary that makes
only two curse
similarly
degree two differential attacks
can be captured by an adversary that
makes only to the dequeries
therefore
t vice independence implies resistance
to all these attacks
and to any attacks
that relies on correlations among few
queries
quantitatively
we show a tight relation between
the closeness to towards independence
and the resistance to linear
and differentiates
now
i'm going to give a brief overview on
the cipher design kc and spn
and the concrete cipher aes
i guess they are familiar to most
audience
to encrypt an input using kc
first
xor it with a round key
then applies a fixed and public
permutation
repeat this process this is called
around the repeat around many times
to get the output
spn it's a special case of kc
it also tells you how to construct this
fixed permutation
first divide the input into
a few small blocks
apply a small partition called xbox
to every block
then
mix the output using linear function
both operation is very efficient
the xbox can be complicated but it's
only over a small domain
the linear function is over a large
domain but it's very simple
then yes
aes is a special case of spn
the block
is eight bit long and
the s box is the inverse function
here i ignore some techno details that
are not important for understanding
so
r wrong the kc
has r plus one round keys actually this
is also true for spn or a s
and therefore
it cannot be r plus two y is independent
due to length of randomness
our positive result almost matched this
up this bound
we show that
our round kc
is close to
slightly smaller than our wires
independent
this is an extension result and is
proved by probabilistic method
i would like to emphasize here that
the difference between our result and
the ideal model results
in ideal mode results
pi is typically modeled as random
permutations
to which the first three only have
oracles
well in our result
pi is public
and it's completely known to diversity
okay this is our result for kc
for spl
say there are k blocks each
has a b bits
we consider the xbox being inverse which
is used
by a yes
or cube
which is used by mimik
for these text boxes
we show two round spn is close to twice
independence and three runs spn is even
closer to towards dependence
we also show sixth round es the x-rays
at s-round there's no
idealization at all
it's point four seven two close to twice
independence
compared with previous work
at the state of art pssl
shows four on the es it's pointless
close to twice independence
our results don't implies pssl because
they are considering a stronger notion
of closeness
and pssl don't impress our result
because our bound is much tighter
because our bond is tight enough in
particular
because it's smaller than half
and it can be amplified
increasing the number of runs
a s will be exponentially close to twice
independent
okay
so these are
these are our results
in the rest of talk
i'm too i'm going to give a technical
overview
on our proof
for kc
we show r round k c is close to slightly
less than rbs independence
we prove it by induction
say we have something that has t wise
independent
what if
we compose it
with one round of casing
the composition will be
close to t plus one wise impedance
we call this
independence amplification number
and we prove this using probabilities
a probabilistic argument
okay
here we saw the notion pointwise
closeness again
it means the two of the t outputs should
be close to uniform not only in l1
distance but also in l infinity distance
that is
their probability mass
their probability mass function should
be close to uniform on every point
because this notion is stronger
it's meaningful even if epsilon is much
larger than one which is the case we
consider
in our extraction level
the condition f being t vice
independence
can be relaxed
to have been close to device
independence
the resulting distance will increase
proportionally
the independence amplification limit
already implies something interesting
okay
zero around kc which is
one time pad
it's
one of my synthetics
then by repeatedly
applying independence
in dependency amplification
r1kc is somewhat close to r plus one was
independence
the distance is huge
but this this is already
a non-trivial result
this can be complemented
by another lemma we call it the distance
amplification level
which is also proved by probabilistic
method
see
f is very close to t vice dependence and
it's some c somewhat close
to t plus one by simplest
then adding one more run will make it
very close to t plus one by c impedance
okay
now we are ready to prove our kc result
it's a two dimension induction of
shorthand table
the base case
is one wise independence
any round of cases one less independence
applying the independence c independence
amplification lemma
r on k c is somewhat close to
r plus one y is independence
then
applies the distance amplification lemma
by adding a few more rounds
somewhat closeness
will become very close
this concludes the proof
next
i'm going to show how
spn
and as are close to 2 yc dependents
because this involves only two inputs
a nice observation is that
only the difference matters here
what does it mean
let me open the spn4 bit
fit two inputs into spn
after exoring the first round key
the only remaining information is their
difference right
okay similarly for output
we care about the distribution of the
two outputs
the joint distribution of the two output
it's close to uniform if and only if
this
difference is close to uniform okay
so we only need to care about difference
in spn
xbox is the only
non-linear operation we need to
understand how it maps input difference
to output difference formally speaking
given two inputs of different data
what is the diff what is the
distribution of the output difference
we started the case when the xbox is
inverse r cube
for these s boxes
the output difference
it's a random vector orthogonal to the
input difference
so in the picture
we can replace the xbox with processed
samples from other subsidies
this might sound too good to be true and
it's actually not exactly true
okay but but almost
one exception
is when data equals zero
when input difference says zero means
the inputs are the same
in such case the outputs must also must
also be the same okay
i also ignore some other technical
details in the picture
uh these details
are not important in the in the photo
proof you can find them in the paper but
please
ignore them for now
okay
say we feed the non-zero input
difference
to subspace sampling process
then the output
must has high mean entropy
the output difference will affect the
next round's input difference okay
so what if
the input difference has high entropy we
are in the next round now
as we proved in what we called
extraction lemma
in such case the output difference is
close to uniform
we prove it by fair analysis and we
later find the alternative proof using
elementary method
so this can be generalized
to consider multiple blocks together
as long as each input block
has higher entropy
the joint distribution
of the output block
is close to uniform
okay
so the most important bits here
uh
is that the input difference don't have
to be independent
they can have archery correlations they
can for example they can be oracle
the only required maximum distribution
to have high entropy
so we also have a stronger extraction
level
says
if every subset of input blocks has high
mean entropy
again
they can have
any correlation as long as
any subset of input block has high
entropy
the output will be very close to uniform
okay so quantitatively this improved by
a factor of but it
is improved exponentially in k
now we are ready to show the domain
result
so here is a spn
as we just discussed
all the xboxes can be replaced by
subspace sampling
the input difference is non-zero
somewhere
the subspace sampling
gives you high entropy
the linear function will propagate the
entropy to all blocks
here star means
the linear function has to uh
specify a a property that is
all of its coefficients are nonzero in
particular this is not satisfied by a s
but
let's say the entropy is propagated to
all blocks
then we can apply extraction lemma
as the condition is satisfied remember
the only thing we need is that each
input block individually has high
entropy
okay
therefore two runs a spn is close to
twice independent
to show a tighter bound let's retrieve
one step
the delta two column or has high mean
entropy
which means with high-probability
they are all non-zero
then subspace sampling gives you high
entropy
independently on each block
you can think that the delta two called
the delta two prime column to be all
independent
this is not exactly true but
can be formalized
okay
then after the last mix last linear
mixing
it's not hard to show that every subset
of the delta 3 column
has high entropy
here we only require the linear function
to be invertible
now the condition of strong extraction
that might satisfy again
this is all we need every subset has
high entropy there can be any
correlation
therefore we show three round spn it's
very close to two voice independence
similarly
by making our hands dirty
we can prove six-strong aes is close to
two-wise independence
remember we also have the almost tight
result for kc
here are all
we prove
okay
let me finish the talk with the summary
slides
the t-wise independence
has a really rich body of problems we
find there and we only touch the surface
for example
uh independence amplification
is something we don't find in place work
can you show
three wise independence of some existing
concrete cipher
of course
our result is substantial also you
probably need some brand new technique
key scheduling
we
and almost every working field assume
independent run keys
that is also the only idealization we
use
is it possible to say something
meaningful
while taking the key scheduling into
account
okay
uh
the relationship between twice
independence and other
attacks
t
t wise impedance mind implies recencies
to more attacks
on the other hand
when you're looking for attacks on es
you should probably avoid those attacks
that relies on correlation
based on fuel cell tax because we know
es is to some extent uh two s different
two wise independent okay
and finally can you analyze other
concrete cipher design for example there
are
uh
uh for example like arx
and
that's all i want to share today thank
you for listening