hi everyone i'm here to talk about our
work on blackbox your knowledge this is
a joint work with my advisor amkhan
pandi
your knowledge is a so important
primitive that requires no infection in
this work we focus on black boxer
knowledge by black box we mean the
construction of the zero knowledge
protocol only makes use of the
underlying primitive in a black box way
so why we are interested in black box
zero knowledge
because the efficiency of the zero
knowledge protocol is not affected no
matter how you implement the underlying
building blocks
over the years our community has
developed so many bad box journalist
protocols
however once you want to use your
knowledge protocol to prove a statement
involving some cryptographic gadgets
things change that means even though the
zero knowledge protocol itself is black
box once you write on such a statement
you are bound to make non-black box use
of the underlying primitive that is
involved in the statement this is
actually a quite common situation for
example think of the norm paradigm or
the gmw compiler in these situations you
need to write your knowledge proof on an
encryption or a commitment then you have
to know the code of the encryption or
the commitment scheme in this work we
are particularly interested in this
simple language this language captures
the range membership of a only function
f this language itself is black box
because to test the membership of the
language if someone gives you the
witness which is a pre-image you only
need black box access to the one
function f
as we know zero knowledge can be
constructed from one function in a
mailbox way now we have this language
that also makes only black box access to
the one function f
then a natural question would be
can we have a zero knowledge protocol
for this language making only black box
access to the only function f
to capture this task formally mac result
defines the notion of functionality
black box zero knowledge
let's look at the range membership
language we defined before f b b z k
requires the existence of a protocol
where both parties has only black box
access to this f the statement is the
image y and the prover holds
additionally the pre-image x as a
witness the approver wants to prove that
y is indeed in the range of f
the companies and soundness are defined
in a natural way for the zero knowledge
property
as you can see it's also the same as the
traditional one the only difference is
now both party has black box access to f
in the real execution i want to point
out that it is not necessary to require
that the simulator
makes only black box access to this only
function f or not you can choose to give
the code to the simulator but the
parties in the real execution they must
have black box access to this one
function
unfortunately dress like shows that
functionally black box journalist
doesn't exist even for this simple range
membership language this is actually
quite discouraging because as we
mentioned before we usually need to run
zk for a capital statement and now even
for this simple membership language we
cannot do that therefore in this work we
ask the question can we somehow bypass
this lower bound
so the first question is why can we even
hope for bypassing this lower bound if
you look at the vertical like lower
bound carefully it says for given moment
function f you cannot have a black box
protocol for the range membership of
this one function our idea here is to
construct a new one function from the
given moment function and then try to
construct a zero noise protocol for the
new one function in a bad box way i will
elaborate on this in next slide
more formally we are looking for an
oracle algorithm f and an oracle
protocol pi if we instantiate them with
a one function f to the f will be a y
function and pi to the f will be a zero
knowledge protocol for the linear
membership of the new one function after
the f that is uh
this new black box language it is
important to notice that both f to the f
and path to the f make only black box
access to the given runway function
small f
we call this primitive proof based one
function we can also define proof based
prg and the clearing resistance hash
function in a similar way
then why this approach has a potential
to bypass resolute lower bound there are
two reasons first given an input this
capital f can make many oracle queries
to the small f also it can perform
post-processing or pre-processing on the
intermediate oracle answers also the
protocol pi even though it cannot use
the code of the small f it can use the
code of the capital f if this idea can
really help us bypass roswell's lower
bound then our hope is in applications
where you need to run the xenomorph
proof on one function prg or hash
function we'll just use the proof based
version instead
now the question is is this proof based
notion really possible to achieve
in this work we provide results on both
sides on the negative side we show that
proof based line function is impossible
actually due to some technical reasons
we are only able to show that
proof-based prt is impossible but this
is already a strong evidence showing the
limitation of the proof-based notion
next we show that if we give the
verifier some control over the input
then proof-based notion actually becomes
flexible i'll explain later what do we
mean by sub-control over the input let
me first give a very brief overview of
our netfield result here the strategy is
we assume the existence of a proof-based
prg and then we try to derive a
contradiction
given any one-way function f a
proof-based prg consists of two parts
first we have this oracle algorithm g to
the power f which is the prg we also
have this oracle path to the f which is
a gq protocol for the range membership
relation of the prg to derive the
contradiction we first consider the
honest execution of the protocol where
both the prover and verifier has oracle
access to the only function f and we
have all this generated pre-image image
pair x and y in this habit by the
companies of the dk protocol we have
that the verifier will accept with
probability close to 1. now we consider
another hybrid where we resample the
oracle but we keep the most likely
queries of the verifier
let's look at the view execution here
during the execution the verifier can
make multiple queries to the oracle f
now we collect all the query answer
pairs that obtained by v with high
probability
and we call this set
q easy we keep this q easy set fixed but
we resample every other points of the
oracle f we call this new oracle f prime
now intuitively because we keep all the
queries asked by v with high probability
these two executions from this point of
view shouldn't differ too much therefore
in hebrew 1 p should also accept with
probability close to 1. actually there
will be an additional 1 over poly laws
but in this talk we don't need to pay
much attention to this
then in the paper we proved a technical
letter which says if we start with an y
that is in the range of g to the power f
then we replace this f by the
composition of f prime
and q e z set
the probability that y is still in the
range of this g instantiated with this
new oracle is no larger than half this
actually gave us a contradiction
because in hebrew 1 the verifier still
accepts with probability very close to
1. this technical learner is our major
contribution in this part but due to
time constraints i won't talk about it
here more details can be found in our
paper if you are interested
now we just showed that proof-based prg
is impossible and this is also an
evidence for the impossibility of proof
is to line function then we want to ask
the question can we somehow relax the
proof-based notion such that it's still
meaningful and achievable
this is our original definition for
perfect y function here we draw some
inspirations from the famous gojek 11
theorem that is instead of viewing the
input at the single string x we want to
split it into two parts x and r we
require that f is the only function on
its first input for arbitrary r
then in a protocol we allow the verifier
to pick the r part intuitively this
allows the verifier to hold some part of
the input which he can use to verify the
range membership and as we will show
later this relaxation indeed allows us
to have a construction but here i want
to make two remarks first since the
verifier choose the r part to have a
meaningful notion of what we need we
want to see that no matter what the r is
the function should be one way this is
the exact reason why we stipulate that
one minute should hold for arbitrary r
second this r part is picked by the
verifier it's not a part of the public
statement so it becomes a little bit
trickier to define your knowledge here
we have to switch to a 2pc flavor
definition
more formally our new definition for
proof based online function works as
false
as we said before we want one minutes to
hold for r
now for companies and for z key we're
gonna use a two pc flavor definition we
compare a real execution and the audio
execution in the real execution the
sender has x as input and the receiver
has r as input these are the two parts
of the input with split as x and r
these two parties run the protocol pi f
defined by the proof based only function
at the end of the execution the sender
learns x and r which are supposed to be
the which are supposed to be the input
of the y function
f x r the receiver learns the output y
which is supposed to be the image of f
under x r in the edu world there is a
trusted third party computing f to the f
the sender will provide the x part of
the input the receiver will provide the
r part the trusted third party just
return r back to s honestly and computes
the output y and give it to the receiver
once we are in this simulation paradigm
gk can be defined by requiring the
security for malicious receiver to
define soundness we require that
whenever the receiver output a value y
that is non-abort there must exist a
pre-image such that this equation holds
if you are interested you can pause the
video and look at this more formal
version of sony's
now we are ready to talk about our
construction i'll present a first
attempt that doesn't quite work but it
gave us inspirations remember that the
proof-based one function consists of two
parts the function and the protocol that
proves its range membership
here i will describe the protocol first
because from the description of the
protocol it's easy to derive what the
function should look like
let's recall our setting first we have
the sender and receiver having black box
access to a one function f the sender
holds the s part of the input and the
receiver picks the r part of input our
first idea is inspired by the cut and
choose technique concretely we ask the
sender to pick np images query the
article and learn the corresponding well
and through button
the sender will send the image to the
receiver now the receiver has no idea of
the corresponding pre-image
but here we'll pick a random size t
subset where t is a constant fraction of
n receiver sends this r the sender will
review the pre-image in the positions
specified by the sexy random subset the
receiver of course checks if the
positions in r are open honestly
if the check passes he will output all
the images under the pre image for
position r and also this subset r as a
final output
from this protocol it's not hard to see
that the corresponding y function should
look like this
on input x and r
it just outputs the same output as the
receiver let's look at what we achieved
here are n positions the receiver checks
the successive random subset
this ensures that a malicious sender can
cheat on at most k positions out of n
where k is a constant fraction of n
this is not good enough
recall that the thirdness of the proof
based one function requires that if the
receiver accepts there must exist a
pre-image
however this protocol only ensures that
there exists some string that is a
one-man delta close to a real per image
as we said before that's because s star
can still cheat on the delta fraction
this inspires us to think of the
following idea
can we somehow extend f to f such that
for all the strings within a delta bar
of a real per image these strings are
also valid for image
now i'm going to talk about how to
incorporate this delta bar into the
domain of the one function
here we need a new idea called pre-image
editing concretely we modify the
previous only function in the following
way
on input x and r the function parses x
as x 1 through x n and an additional
beta part as we will see later this beta
part is the key component that allow us
to incorporate the delta ball
then as before
the function query the oracle to compute
y1 through yn
and as before it parses r as a set t
subset of n
now to compute the output y we consider
two separate cases the first case is a
non-editing case it is identified by
this condition
this condition says
if you collect the pi part from beta it
forms a subset of positions
if this subset of positions is
overlapping with the predictions
specified by r the function just
operates as before that is it put all
the y one through a y and in the s part
the more interesting case is the editing
case this case is identified by the
complement of the previous one in this
situation for all the positions
specified by the p set we're going to
set xi to the value specified by the
corresponding ypi prime
for all the other positions we will just
use the y returned by oracle
this must be confusing if you look at it
for the first time
but the magical takeaway is if the
editing case is triggered for the
positions specified by this p set the
corresponding s i values are already
appearing in the input anyone who's this
input can tell these values directly
let's see how this resolves the previous
problem
recall that the previous problem is we
may have k bad positions in the pre
image
now by making use of this editing case
we want to correct all these k bad
positions using the values specified by
its ypi prime values contained in this
beta part i think it will help if we run
through this mini example
let's say
after the execution of the protocol the
receiver learn the y of this form
where this s4 is a bad position also
this y tells us that the set r consists
of this one and three
now i claim that this x is a very
pre-image
let's take a closer look at this x here
we have x1 2 3 and x5 these are the
valid per image of s123 and s5
note that
these pre images exist because the only
bad position is s4 for s123 and s5 there
must exist corresponding image so the
only problematic position is s4
now in the pre image we constructed we
just put a zero string as a pre-image of
s4
we make the beta part look at 4 and s4
this s4 comes from the y to see why this
x is a very free image of y let's try to
evaluate the function f on x and r
following the definition on this set by
definition we know that the r set is one
three and the corresponding p set is
simply four therefore these two sets
does not overlap so we triggered this
editing condition
it doesn't matter what value we put here
because this position is a position
specified by p in the output we will
always put s4 as the corresponding
output
therefore if you follow the steps listed
on the left you can verify that
x and r is a very pre-image for this y
here i want to make one more remark this
x 1 2 3 and x 5 there are three images
of the corresponding
s values or y values
they may not be efficiently computable
but in the proof of security we do not
really want to compute them the only
thing we need is their existence
previously i just showed you the only
function construction to have a
proof-based line function we also need a
zero-knowledge protocol computing this
function we just defined
in this slide i will first give you an
interactive proof protocol and later i
will show you how to add zero knowledge
property if you stare at this
construction for a second it is not hard
to see how can we have an interactive
protocol computing it
so first
the sender pass the x into the
corresponding x and the beta part then
it makes oracle queries to learn one
through and case send one through one to
the receiver here since we also have
additional beta part the sender will
also send the data the third step is to
compute this random subset in the
protocol we simply ask the receiver to
send the set r as challenge
at this moment the sender knows both x
and r so he can perform the step 4 as in
the description of the function
now the sender simply sends these values
to the receiver
at the end of the protocol you can
verify that the receiver can output this
value value and the sender simply output
his input x and the r part it learns
from the receiver
now the only thing left is that we want
to make this protocol zero knowledge
up to now this protocol is only a simple
cut and choose phone call together with
our pre-image editing as you can see
this custom truth step does not review
any extra information regarding the
pre-image of the one function so the
only information we need to head to
achieve zk is actually the fact whether
we are in the item case or a non-editing
case to do that we will use the black
box commit and proof
recall that to see if we are in the
editing case and non-ideal case
we need to use both the beta part and
the y value
and this information is embedded in the
first round message to head this
information instead of sending the first
round message in plain
we use the commit stage of the blackbox
camera proof
in the third step the receiver can still
check the consistency between the
pre-image and image on the partitions
specified by the set r
however there is no guarantee that the y
values are indeed the y values committed
at the beginning so we will ask the
sender to give a zero large proof using
the proof stage of the blubox camison
proof protocol
importantly this bb proof stage only
proves statements about about y and s it
has nothing to do with the relation
between pre-immediate x and y
actually the consistency between x and y
pairs is checked by the receiver offset
of this bb proof
therefore this bb improved stage has
nothing to do with the oracle y function
small f
now let me briefly summarize our
construction of the proof based one
function
we start with a simple cut and choose
protocol this protocol is not good
enough because we wanted to guarantee
the existence of a pre-image however if
we are using this protocol there could
still be a delta bet fraction in the
pre-image so our idea is to try to embed
the delta bar into the domain of the run
function to do that we introduce a new
idea called pre-image editing
the editing case will not happen in the
real execution of the protocol that's
because there is a r part controlled by
the verifier if the verifier picked the
r part randomly the editing case won't
happen except for the negative
probability but now the security
reduction can make use of this editing
case
intuitively it plants the k values from
the output y into the pre-image x since
there are at most k bad positions we can
effectively correct all of them
to add zq property we rely on blackbox
commit and proof it is important to
notice that this proof stage does not
make use of the code of oracle small f
now we've shown how to construct proof
based on function
a proof-based prg can be built in a
similar way we will not talk about it as
mentioned at the beginning of this talk
we also want to construct proof-based
hash functions however it turns out that
this construction requires new idea let
me explain the reason why our technique
for proof based one function doesn't
work directly
recall that in the proof phase one
function construction we introduced this
pre-image editing idea
it essentially introduced multiple
images for a single y
this actually values the collision
resistance requirement if you want a
crhf to see why first notice that the
protocol is fine because in the
execution of the protocol there is a r
part controlled by the receiver if the
receiver picks this r part uniformly
random the editing case will not be
triggered except for negative
probability so a malicious sender cannot
make use of this however remember that
our proof-based notion also have a
construction of the function the
function is where the problem headed
more specifically a ppv algorithm can
easily construct two inputs both of them
trigger the editing condition and hash
to the same value and address can't do
this because when evaluating the
function there's no receiver the single
adversary can't control the whole part
of the function to solve this problem we
will embed a random string z in a
published hashing key and we change the
condition for either case we add one
more condition this condition says you
can trigger the editing case only if you
know a pre-image of d under the oracle
hash function as we know a ppt cannot
figure out the pre-image of z therefore
he cannot make use of the editing case
however our security proof of songs can
always make use of this editing case
this is how we create the asymmetry
between the address 3 and our security
lecture
unfortunately i cannot talk more about
our construction for hash function if
you are interested please refer to our
paper
let me give a summary of this talk in
this work we generalize the notion of
functional black box your knowledge
proposed by razorlak we show that
drought's impossibility result still
holds for our generalized notion
specifically we show that black box
proof based prd is impossible
next we relax the prefix notion by
splitting the input and let the receiver
control the r part of it then we show
that for this split input proof based
notion one function prg and the creation
recession hash functions become possible
our work actually raises more
interesting questions as we mentioned
before we are only able to show the
impossibility of proof-based prg i mean
without splitting the input we take this
as a strong absence for the
impossibility for proof based online
function but it is interesting to see an
actual proof for this impossibility
also this work inspires us to ask a more
general question that is can we give
black box zero proof for any polynomial
cell circuits
more concretely consider this example
let's say we have a circuit c it can be
decomposed into three parts the input x
will first go through a subcircuit c one
that is crypto free and then a one-way
function gate is evaluated on the output
of c1 the output of the line function
will go through another crypto free
sub-circuit c2 to give us the final
output y
it will be interesting if we can have a
zero knowledge protocol for the
certifiability of this circuit while
making only black box access to one
function just like impossibility result
says this is impossible that's because
we cannot even have a black box zero
knowledge for this one function gate let
alone the whole circuit but our
proof-based notion gave us some hope the
idea here is to replace the one-way
function by its proof-based alternative
the result in our work gives a black box
zero noise proof for this crypto gate it
will be very interesting to extend our
idea to eventually give a blah blah zero
knowledge proof for the whole circuit
now we are at the end of this talk
thanks for your attention and more
details can be found in the full version
of this paper here