hi everyone i am akshayra and i am going
to talk about traceable secret sharing
and applications this is based on joint
work with vipul goyal and ifanson
let's consider the following scenario
alice has some secret data s
and she wishes to store this data on the
cloud
to enhance privacy alice chooses n cloud
service providers
secret shares of data using a t out of n
secret sharing scheme
and stores the shares on the servers
however there is an adversary who is
interested in learning about alice's
secret data
and in fact the adversary is willing to
pay the servers in order to learn this
information
so the adversary approaches one of the
servers and promises to pay a certain
amount if the server sends the share
it received from alice to this adversary
even though this offer is pretty
enticing
the server is very of the following
possibility
if alice somehow finds out that the
server cheated by sending the share it
received to an external party then alice
could sow this server in the court of
law
specifically the share that alice sent
to each of these servers could have some
identifying information embedded inside
and this information could help alice
win the case against the server
and if alice wins the case then it could
not only result in a big loss of
reputation for the server but it will
also result in bankruptcy due to the
service agreement it had with us
so learning about the server's hesitancy
the adversary comes up with a pretty
clever cryptographic scheme
so this scheme has the following
components it has n functions f1 up to
fn which are called as the collector
functions as well as a reconstruction
box rextar
and all that the servers now have to do
is to apply these collector functions on
the shares
and give it to the adversary
and the adversary now pays the service
with the monetary reward that it
promised
so these functions could be cleverly
designed so that they could remove all
the identifying information inside the
shares
leaving only the essence of the share
impact
and the adversary in fact promises the
following
so even if alice gets hold of these
collector functions f1 up to fn as well
as the shares that the servers send fi
of sharing or or call this collected
shares as well as the reconstruction box
then
alice will not be able to prove in the
court of law that one of the service
indeed cheated in other words there is
no way that alice could trace a cheating
server
on examining this uh scheme closely the
server is indeed convinced that there is
no way for alice to implicate
his cheating behavior
and in fact any rational server would
send fi of share i and collect the
monetary reward
and if the adversary is able to convince
at least t of these servers to send the
shares
then it can learn information about the
secrets
so to prevent such a scenario alice
seeks the help of the cryptographic
community
so the the specific question we are
interested in is the following
so can we construct a secret sharing
scheme that allows alice to trace a
cheating server
so we are interested in not only tracing
but also extracting an evidence against
the stating server which could be
examined in a court of law
and in order to help alice with this
task we introduce a new primitive called
as traceable secret sharing scheme
or tss in short
so let me first describe the syntax of a
traceable secret sharing
so just like any other secret sharing
scheme a traceable secret sharing
consists of a sharing phase where you
take a secret from the dealer or alice
in this case and split it into end
shares sh1 to shn which are sent to the
service
there is also a reconstruction phase
which takes in at least 3 shares
that was given to the servers and
reconstructs the secrets
for privacy we require that any of these
t minus one shares reveal no information
about the underlying secret
so in addition to the sharing and the
reconstruction phase of a secret sharing
scheme there are two additional
components of a traceable secret sharing
namely there is a special algorithm
called as the trace algorithm and there
is another algorithm called as the judge
algorithm
so this trace algorithm takes in these
collector functions f1 up to fn the set
of collected shares fi on share i for
some subset c which is at least t
the reconstruction box rec star and
outputs an identity of a cheating server
and an evidence pi i
and this evidence is examined by the
judge algorithm which pronounces whether
the ith server is guilty or not killed
so we need a traceable secret sharing
scheme to satisfy the following two
properties the first property is the
traceability requirement which states
the following
for any two secrets is 0 and s1
if the reconstruction box rec star on
input the collector shares
can distinguish between
the sharing of s 0 and s 1 with some
non-negligible advantage
then trace is required to output the
identity of a traitor along with the
valid evidence that is accepted by the
algorithm with non-negligible
probability
so we here we require a very big
property on the reconstruction box all
that it required is to distinguish
between shares of two secrets with some
non negligible advantage and even in
this case the trace should be able to
output the identity of a traitor along
with some valid evidence
the second property is the
non-imputability property which roughly
protects and harness server from a
malicious dealer or else
so this requires that any malicious
dealer cannot provide a valid evidence
against a harness server and this should
hold even if the dealer colludes with
every other server
okay so these are the two properties
that we require a traceable secret
sharing to satisfy
so in this work we formally define a
traceable secret sharing scheme
so unlike the related notion of traitor
tracing in broadcast encryption scheme
traceable secret sharing is not revealed
to construct even if we ignore the
efficiency aspects
recall that a traitor tracing scheme can
be trivially constructed from any public
key encryption if you allow the public
keys and the ciphertext to grow with the
number of users
however this is not the case for
traceable secret sharing scheme
and a main contribution is a
construction of a traceable secret
sharing assuming the existence of a
secure multi-party computation protocol
and we also consider a couple of
extensions to this notion
so the first extension we consider is
tracing more than one traitor
and
recall that it's not possible to uh
trace more than t tracer traitors
because a reconstruction box could just
ignore the other shares and concentrate
on some subset of t-shirts
so here we can do almost optimally and
can trace up to t minus one traitors
we also consider a scenario where
servers could collude with each other
before sending the collected shares to
the
to the adversary and here if we allow
more than t server collisions then
there is no hope of tracing because the
uh the servers could reconstruct the
secret and send it to that person
so here we
do the best possible thing where we
allow up to t minus one server
pollutions
we also consider an application of
traceable secret sharing to traceable
delegation of computation
so here we give a protocol that works in
the offline online setting so the
offline setting grows with the circuit
size of the function that we want to
delegate and the online setting online
cost is pretty efficient wherein the
cost grows only with the uh the input
and the output
in the rest of the talk i'll mainly
focus on our construction of traceable
secret sharing in the minimal setting
where there are no server collusions and
we are required to trace only a single
trader
so before we move on to our construction
let me explain the key challenges
involved in constructing a traceable
secret sharing scheme
so let's start with the basic question
on whether swami's secret sharing is
already a traceable secret share
unfortunately xiaomi's secret sharing
does not satisfy the non-imputability
property
so this is because the dealer knows
all the shares that are sent to each of
the servers and hence it is easy for the
dealer to accuse an honest server of
cheating
so to mitigate this we consider the
following natural attempt wherein we run
a multi-party computation protocol
between the servers and the dealer
so this
functionality which is computed by via
the mpc protocol takes in the secret s
from the dealer generates the share
and sends the shares to the service
so this can be shown to satisfy
non-imputability via the security of the
mpc protocol but unfortunately there is
no way that we could trace a cheating
server because the dealer does not have
any information available with it
so the key
idea behind the construction is the
following
in order to achieve traceability we must
ensure that the dealer has some secret
information which is unknown to all the
servers
and in order to achieve non-imputability
you must ensure that each server has
some secret information that is unknown
to the dealer
so the key challenge that we face here
is that how to balance this information
available to the dealer and available to
the servers and so that we can satisfy
both traceability and non-imputability
so this brings us to our construction
so our construction also follows the
template that we discussed before
wherein we run an npc protocol between
the dealer and the servers to generate
the secret shares
however
the key idea behind the construction is
carefully designing the function that is
computed by the mpc protocol so that we
can achieve both traceability and
non-imputability
so let us consider the function that is
being computed by the mpc protocol
so as a first step the mpc functionality
takes in the secret s from the dealer
and generates the shame sharing ss1 up
to ssl
so this is just a t out of n xiaomi
secret sharing of the secret
let us assume that each of these shares
are lambda bits law
the next step
done by this function
is
the following for each j in the set 1 to
lambda
it shows us a uniform random string r j
which is lambda bits law
now the next step is the following for
each party i you choose
ah as uniform string lij from
the set of lambda with strings such that
the inner product of lij with this rj is
the jth bit of the shammy shell of this
part
so specifically
for the first party we choose a random
string l i j l one j such that the inner
product of l one j with r j is the j th
width of the first summation
similarly for the second party we choose
a another random string l two j such
that the inner product of l two with rj
is the jth
bit of the second shammyshare and so on
so once we choose all these
liks the next step that is done by the
functionality is to take this r j for
each j and sacred share it using swami
secret sharing to generate inches
and the share of a party i is the set of
all lijs and rijs for each j in one to
lambda
so the share of the first party is the
set of all l one j's and r one j's and
similarly the share of the nth part t is
the set of all l and js and
rngs okay so now what is the secret that
is available to the dealer which is
output by the npc functionality
the dls secrets consists of the
following
so it consists of the set of all lijs
but not in the clear but as a image of a
one-way function applied on these lights
it also consists of the xiaomi shares
ss1 up to ssl and it also consists of
the the set r i j for each i in 1 to n
and for e j and 1 to lambda
so these are the dealer secrets
and what is the judge algorithm
the judge algorithm takes in some proof
pi i and an identity of a cheating
server and it checks the following it
checks whether there exists some j in
the set 1 to lambda such that the one
way function applied on pi i
is equal to the one one-way function on
lij which is
available as part of the dealer secret
so essentially the the dealer has to
invert this one-way function in order to
prove that a server has cheated
and what is the secret that is available
with the servers it is these lijs which
are
the secrets available with the server
okay so given this construction let's
see why it satisfies uh the
non-imputability and the traceability
properties and let's start with the
non-imputability property
so recall that in order to
prove that a server had cheated the
dealer has to produce a pre-image of
this one-way function
and from the security of the multi-party
computation we can ensure that the only
information that the dealer
gets about the server secrets are these
one-way function applied on the server
secrets which are these likes
so in order to implicate an honest
server ah the dealer has to invert this
one-way function and the
non-imputability just follows from the
one mainness of ows
so the more interesting property is the
traceability
and
recall that
for tracing we have access to a
reconstruction box rickstar and the
guarantee that is satisfied by the
rickstar is that
given the collected shares of some
secret s0 and the collector shares of
some secret s1 this reconstruction box
can distinguish between these two
secrets with some non-negligible
advantage
now we need to use this reconstruction
box and extract some evidence against a
cheating circuit
so in order to do this
we actually define a sequence of n minus
1 hybrids between the collected shares
of 0 and the collected shares of s1
so specifically the ith hybrid in the
sequence is defined as follows
we fix the ith share and fi on share i
which is the the collected share
and we sample the other shares in a way
that sh1 to shi are the first eye shares
of a secret sharing of the secret s1 and
we sample sh i plus 1 to shn in such a
way that these form
the last n minus 1 shares of a secret
sharing of s 0.
so once we sample all these shares we
apply the collector functions on these
shares and run the reconstruction box on
these collected ships
okay so note that
height 0 according to this definition is
identically distributed to a collected
shares of the secret s0
similarly height n in the sequence is
distributed identically to the collector
shares the secret s1
so via a standard hybrid argument there
exists two intermediate hybrids in the
sequence such that the distinct such
that the reconstruction box can
distinguish between these two hybrids
with some non-negligible advantage
so once we find such a hybrid
hybrid pair then we can immediately
conclude that server i is the trader
why because if server high hadn't
submitted its share then these two
hybrids are identically distributed
however since the reconstruction box can
distinguish between these two hybrids
with some non-negligible advantage it
now follows that the server high is the
trader
so for those who are familiar with the
trade traitor tracing literature this is
actually pretty similar to the concept
of private linear broadcast encryption
that is used as a building block towards
constructing freighter tracing schemes
however for a traceable secret sharing
it's not only sufficient to identify a
cheating server we must also extract an
evidence that is accepted by the judge
algorithm
so for this purpose we do the following
so we consider these two hybrids hive i
minus 1 and high by
which can be distinguished by the
reconstruction box with some non
negligible advantage
and we consider a sequence of lambda
minus 1 intermediate hybrids
between these two distributions
specifically in each of these
intermediate hybrids we change the ith
share from a share of the secret s0 to a
share of secret s1
okay so we do this one bit adapter
again via a standard hybrid argument we
conclude that there exists two hybrids
intermediate hybrids in the sequence i
minus one comma j minus 1 and
i minus 1 comma j that can be
distinguished by this reconstruction box
with some non negligible advantage
so once we find these two hybrids we do
the following
so we take this reconstruction box that
can distinguish between these two
hybrids with non-negligible advantage
and use this box to actually
predict the inner product of lij and
some rj with probability that is
greater than half plus some
non-negligible uh probability
so once we construct such a predictor of
inner product of l i j with a uniformly
chosen rj
we can use the goldrich levin decoder to
extract the evidence lig
now this evidence lij
can be given to the judge algorithm and
this will be accepted so this is the
main idea behind extracting the evidence
using the reconstruction box of course i
have swept a lot of details under the
rug and i encourage you to look into the
paper for all the details
so to conclude we
defined a notion called as traceable
secret sharing and provided a
construction using any secure
multi-party computation protocol we also
considered extensions to tracing
multiple traders and also considered
collusion between the servers and i
would encourage you to look into the
paper for these extensions
so we also provided an application to
constructing a traceable delegation of
computation in the offline online
setting again you can refer the paper
for the details
and there are many interesting open
questions from our work
so the the main open question is
extension to stronger adversarial models
so here we considered a setting where
the adversary provides some collector
functions and the servers have to apply
these functions on the shares and send
it to the adversary
but it is possible to consider stronger
adversarial settings where the the
servers and the adversary could
get involved in a
multi-party protocol and which provides
information to that person
so our construction does not extend to
these settings and it is interesting to
see if there are construction that can
be shown to be traceable even against
such stronger adversarial models
there is also this very interesting
question of extending a traceable
delegation to constructing traceable
multi-party computation protocols
and finally are there other applications
of traceable secret sharing schemes and
how does it connect to other
primitives in cryptography
and that's it thank you for your
attention and you can find the full
version of our paper on