hi everyone i'm sophia and i'm going to
be talking about yoso
yo so is joint work with craig shai hugo
and tal at algorand and with jesper and
bernardo at orcas university in the
concordian blockchain research center
yoso stands for you only speak once
and as the name suggests it describes a
class of protocols where no participant
needs to speak more than once
this kind of protocol is particularly
useful when dealing with a strong
adaptive adversary
who can kill or corrupt a party as soon
as it speaks
in this work we make two contributions
we define a formal yoso model
and we show two npc protocols with
guaranteed output delivery within that
model
before getting into our contributions
i'd like to give more motivation for the
yoso model in particular in the context
of npc
let's start with the usual npc scenario
so imagine that alice bob and charlie
want to compute a joint function f of
their secrets x1 x2 and x3
but the problem is none of them are
willing to reveal anything about their
secrets except for
the function output
so one approach is for the three of them
to find someone that they all trust
and send their inputs directly to that
trusted party
and then have that trusted party publish
the function output y
but trust is hard to come by and it
could be that there isn't any one party
that all three of alice bob and charlie
are comfortable relying on
so using secure multi-party computation
or npc for short
alice bob and charlie can instead
outsource the computation of f to
several parties
they don't have to trust any specific
party
each one of alice bob and charlie only
needs to trust that some of these
parties are behaving honestly without
necessarily knowing which ones
so in other words uh they need to trust
that if an adversary is controlling some
of these parties maybe by having
installed malware on the machines
that adversary was only able to corrupt
up to some threshold team of the parties
so then during the mpc protocol
these parties talk to one another and as
a result of that conversation
alice bob and charlie learn the function
output the first guarantee we want from
npc is that as long as the adversary
corrupted fewer than the thresholds t of
the parties
alice bob and charlie learned the
correct why
so the adversary shouldn't be able to
trick alice bob and charlie into
accepting the wrong output
but even more than that we demand the
strongest mpc guarantee
which is guaranteed output delivery
so the adversary shouldn't even be able
to carry out a denial of service attack
and prevent atlas bob and charlie from
getting anything
and of course we also want privacy
so we want to be sure that the adversary
and the machines she controls
don't learn anything else about
x1 x2 and x3
okay but now let's come back to our
assumption that the adversary corrupted
fewer than the threshold t of the
parties
if we only have a couple parties and we
have a very powerful adversary
maybe it's unrealistic to assume that
she can't corrupt more of the parties
and if that happens we don't get any of
our guarantees we don't get uh
guaranteed output delivery or privacy
so however many parties we think our
powerful adversary can corrupt
we need to involve enough parties in our
computation to make sure that our
threshold t
is higher than the adversary's
corruption power
if we think that the adversary can
corrupt up to a million parties and
we're running an mpc
where the corruption threshold t is
equal to half of the participants
we need to make sure that we have at
least two million participating machines
but once we involve millions of parties
maybe by outsourcing to blockchain
we run into an efficiency problem
almost all mpc protocols require that
all participants talk to all of the
other participants
and when there are just a couple of
participants this isn't so bad
but when we have millions of parties
this gets to be prohibitively
inefficient
and in fact the goal we want to set for
ourselves to avoid this kind of
inefficiency
is that the total communication of our
protocol
be sublinear in the number n of
participants
so this means that in a given round of
the computation
only a small set of parties which we'll
call a committee
should say anything
and in this picture our speaking
committee
are the parties colored in blue
the issue now is that once this
committee has spoken
the adversary who's always watching the
network
sees who spoke and learns that this
committee of parties might be important
since the committee is relatively small
the adversary might be able to quickly
target all of them for corruption
maybe with some sort of zero-day exploit
so we want to make sure that even if
we're dealing with a powerful adaptive
adversary who's able to instantly
corrupt anyone they want
our protocol still gives us the
guarantees we want
as long as the adversary is limited to
corrupting
t
which we take to be half
of the total number of parties
in order to do that we need to make sure
that even if every party is killed
immediately after it speaks
we still get our guarantees
and that's
why we come to the you only speak once
or yosel model
after the first committee is dead if the
computation isn't complete yet we need
another committee to pick up the torch
and
continue but as soon as that committee
speaks it might also be killed
and so yet another committee the pink
committee
must rise to take its place and carry
the torch
and so on and so forth
so in the yosef model even if every
party is killed as soon as it speaks the
computation must carry on to completion
now that we have our motivation let's
move on to our contributions
like i mentioned at the beginning
there's two parts to our paper
the formal modeling of yoso protocols
and two yoso mpc constructions
the great thing about our model is that
it cleanly splits yoso protocols into
two components which can be considered
totally independently
so the first component is ra which
stands for role assignments
it deals with how committees can be
chosen in such a way that the adversary
can't anticipate who they will be
and the second component which is role
execution
deals with what these committees will do
once they're chosen
let's take a quick look at role
assignment
we've seen this kind of role assignment
in a number of places already
most notably we have bitcoin where the
role of block creator
is assigned through proof's work
and this has exactly the property we're
looking for
which is that no one knows before the
miner speaks
that that particular miner has won the
right to publish a block
so
even the most clever adaptive adversary
can't target the next block minor until
it's too late
and they've already played their role
algorand does something similar but
without proofs of work
they use verifiable random functions to
run a lottery
just like in bitcoin no one knows who
the winners of the lottery will be
until they've spoken and thus already
played their part
bitcoin and algorand are different from
npc protocols
in that the roles parties play don't
require any secrets
but if alice bob and charlie want to
outsource an mpc
they will have to secret share their
inputs to the appropriate committee
and they can't know the identity of the
committee if that identity is public
this tells the adversary exactly who
they should target
this leads to a difficult question how
can we enable the sending of a secret to
one specific party
without knowing who that party is
the work of benhamoud from tcc last year
gives a really elegant solution using
something called nominating committees
and we also have an ongoing work on
eprint with an alternative approach
which supports a higher threshold team
both of these solutions result in the
publication of a set of anonymous public
keys
so the owners of the corresponding
decryption keys know who they are but no
one else knows who owns the
corresponding decryption keys
so once that's done
anyone can encrypt a message under one
of these keys and broadcast it without
knowing who will be able to decrypt
only the party holding the corresponding
decryption key will know that this
message is intended for her
and she'll be able to
decrypt it
the guarantee we need from the real
assignment mechanism is that at most a
threshold t prime of the members of the
committee should be corrupt
and we take t prime to be half of the
size of the committee
once the roles have been assigned we can
move on to executing the protocol
the execution can be specified in terms
of roles not the machines executing
those roles
and examples of roles are the first
member of the third committee or maybe
the verifier in the seventh nizik
the roles communicate with one another
over broadcast channel and through
private communication to future roles
who haven't spoken yet
using the anonymous public keys
the specified protocol need only be
secure as long as at most the threshold
t prime of the members of each committee
are corrupt
and it's up to the role assignment
mechanism to guarantee that this is in
fact the case
i want to mention two existing protocols
that are compatible with this model
so the first one is the work of ben
hamudahral
from tcc 2020
which deals with maintaining and
re-sharing a secret from committee to
committee
another cool protocol is fluid npc which
is also at crypto this year and they
describe how to do
mpc with abort
they don't explicitly use a role
assignment mechanism but their protocol
could be combined with one to get yoso
style guarantees
in our protocols we prioritize
preventing denial of service attacks
so we aim for guaranteed output delivery
instead of security with the board
and this brings me to
our two mpc constructions that achieve
this
let's start with a construction that
uses computational assumptions
in this construction we're going to use
one global public encryption team
and in the slide this is the lock in the
upper right corner and it's available to
everyone
the corresponding secret key will be
secret shared among the current
committee which is in bloom
anyone can provide an input to the npc
by encrypting a secret to the public key
and broadcasting the cypher text
but in order to use this for npc
we need several properties of the
encryption scheme
the first is that decryption should be
as non-interactive as possible
this means that each committee member
should be able to derive a partial
decryption from the ciphertext and its
keyshare
and these decryptions can be combined to
recover the plaintext
so on the slide this recovery is through
addition but it doesn't have to be
and as a side note so of course before
publishing the partial decryption
the committee members need to erase
their state
and their key shares to make sure that
our adaptive adversary can't learn the
key when she corrupts them
all right
so another requirement
is that the secret key can be re-shared
with minimal interaction
this is necessary because otherwise once
our blue committee speaks
the secret key and all secrets that
haven't been decrypted yet are lost
forever
so in the same breath in which they
publish the partial decryptions we want
our blue committee to re-share the
secret decryption key to the next
committee
which is the one in green
now what we have lets us maintain
secrets and reveal them at the
appropriate time
but in order to support computation on
those secrets
we need an additional property
we need our encryption scheme to be
homomorphic
if it's fully homomorphic then we're
basically done
we can have the blue committee perform
the entire computation homomorphically
and publish partial decryptions of the
output that can then be combined to
recover the output itself
but using a fully homomorphic encryption
scheme
wouldn't be concretely efficient so we
might want to use an additively
homomorphic encryption scheme instead
then we would use beaver triples to
enable every multiplication
i won't explain beaver triples in the
interest of time
i'll just say that they can be used for
multiplication but their use does
require some interaction
and they can be generated for us by
committees that don't hold decryption
key shares
each of our key holder committee members
then performs only linear operations
homomorphic claim
and uses a beaver triple to do a
multiplication which involves the
decryption of some massed
values our blue committee performs this
decryption of best values
and in the same breath they need to
re-share the secret key to the next
committee
which picks up the computation from
there
this next green committee
does more linear computation
and the next time a multiplication needs
to be done
it again uses a beaver triple and again
in the same breath hands the computation
over to the next committee
which might do more linear computation
and finally when the computation is over
the last committee decrypts the output
this whole thing is very similar to the
cdn protocol from 20 years ago
with basically minimal changes to enable
the passing of the computation from
committee to committee
that's all i want to say about the
computational protocol
so next let's take a look at our second
construction which is information
theoretic
it might seem a little funny to consider
an information theoretical construction
when it'll need to run on top of a
computational real assignment protocol
but we think it's still interesting to
try to minimize the necessary
assumptions
trying to eliminate assumptions
altogether turns out to be quite
challenging in the yoso protocol
most information theoretic mbc
techniques use something called
verifiable secret sharing like all forms
of secret sharing verifiable secret
sharing or vss proceeds in two phases
we have dealing where the blue party
deals the secret to the green parties
and at some point down the line the
green parties might try to reconstruct
that secret
however in vss the dealing phase has an
extra verification step
where the shareholders and possibly the
dealer talk more to make sure that
everyone agrees that we have a valid
reconstructable sharing
the problem with this in the yoso model
is that after this verification step
everyone has spoken so the fact that the
green parties once had a valid sharing
is now totally useless since they're
probably dead
a simple yet powerful solution to this
is something we call
future broadcast
so in a future broadcast protocol
each of our parties takes the messages
she would have sent in the future
and shares them to a separate fresh
committee that's in charge of then
sending that message on her behalf
this lets our parties speak once
but at the same time schedule multiple
messages that can be sent at different
times in the future
and can be triggered by arbitrary
conditions
our parties schedule some messages for
the verification step
and some for future use whether for
reconstruction or within an npc
one great thing about future broadcast
is that it can use a less powerful tool
than vss
we only need robust secret sharing which
doesn't consider a corrupt dealer
and this is perfect since if our dealing
party is corrupt she could say anything
anytime she wants in the future
and we don't really need to commit her
to something at the time of
uh the future broadcast itself
another neat feature of this scheme
is that if we think of all the values
sent using future broadcast as
re-sharings of the original
share
we basically for free get the values
held by the set of read and orange
committees are equal
this is true since the honest members of
the green committee will always honestly
re-share their actual shares
and as long as there are enough honest
green parties the corrupt parties will
not be able to tamper with the re-shared
values
so there's really much more that we need
in order to get
from verifiable secret sharing to a
full-fledged npc
for instance we need our parties to be
able to prove
that something they publish is a product
of two things that were shared
and there are many more subtleties and
techniques that we need to get to our
npc that i just won't go over this is a
really simplified picture each of these
tricks uses layers upon layers of
additional committees which makes our
information theoretic solution far from
practical
but it's still a really interesting
feasibility result
that's all i want to say about our
second construction
so to recap
the yoso model gives us a neat
separation between role assignment and
role execution
and in our work we showed two uh yoso
mpc protocols one of which is
computational and one information
theoretic
both of those get us guaranteed output
delivery against an adaptive adversary
which can corrupt up to half the total
number of parties
and they both have total communication
which is sublinear and n
which is really cool
finally yoso unearths a huge number of
open problems
basically everything we've asked about
mpc before we can ask again in the yoso
model
so for instance notice that our
computational construction requires some
setup in the form of the distribution of
the secret key to the first committee
we can ask can we get efficient
protocols without setup
can we get constant round protocols
without setup
can we do best of both worlds protocols
which get
guaranteed output delivery when half of
the parties are corrupted and unanimous
abort
if there's a dishonest majority
and so on and so forth there's really
the sky's the limit here
thank you everyone for listening and i
hope to see you at the live session