okay let's start the next session uh the
fourth session on post quantum
cryptography
so the first talk in the session is
about the anonymity of nistpqc round
three chems by keita sargava
thank you for introduction so can you
hear me
yes
okay
let me start
so thank you for the introductions i am
jetta server from entity social
informatics laboratories so today so i
want to talk about anonymity of gems in
needs to picture standardization they
are following the maram
stroke so let me first talk about
background
so we know that several companies and
organizations have been developing
quantum computers so for example so
google ibm and ucsd and so on so they
constructed approximately 100 physical
cubits called the machines
so google plans to develop
one million physical tribute machine in
2030 and ibm plans to develop first 4000
physical qubits machine in 2015
and we also know that the schwarz
algorithm solves the factoring problem
and the distributed wiring problem in
polymer time over condom machines
and in addition to according to disney
and regardless estimations so if the
error rate is uh
0.1 percent and it runs with about
one kilohertz
then so it can factor the 248 bit rs
modulus by using the two at 20 million
physical tubes in eight hours
so that's so if adversary has
efficiently uh
has exchanged scalable quantum computers
so then the current public key
cryptography will be broken
and the counter measures are in the
right hand side so the one promising
counter measure is the post quantum
chemotherapy so pgc in short
so therefore the nist in the u.s have
been standardized
and pgc's primitives so here so we have
chems and signatures
fourth uh
injection mechanism and signatures so
four teams so they select the four
finalists and five alternates
uh in the left-hand side
so while and i
need to say that they would announce the
result in march but we don't share the
result yet
so the standard
so here so we consider the security of
the games scheme
and the standard security notion for pke
and kemp is indistinguishability against
the children's hypothesis attacks so the
left hand side there
and all new speech language requiems
achieved industrial security in the
landmark model a classical random local
model so roughly speaking so the
industrial security implies that we
cannot distinguish
a ciphertext to the real key and the
random key
so this case there is a real key and
keywords randomly
in the chem context
so unfortunately the industry security
doesn't improve the response privacy so
for example so let us constantly chem
scheme whose scientists contain the
public key
so in this case
so it can achieve industry security but
such scientists apparently reveals the
response
so therefore so we consider an anonymity
so some uh
anonymity against the children's
attacks
so this captures the privacy of
lifespans so because that uh so if the
automatically
so two encryption key ek there on the
eq1 but so
it cannot distinguish which encryption
key is used to generate ciphertext and
key so this is a define this defines
anonymity of the
chem stream
so they have a lot of applications of
anonymity uh for example anonymous
credential and auction and anonymous
authentic encryption and so on
so privacy enhancing technologies so uh
we have a natural question about so
whether the chem charge data
institutions we achieve
this anonymity uh anonymity is a
contemporary underground model also
because we concern the pgc
so this is a
the summary of this result in graphs
malam and pedosum so in this eurocrypt
so they're studying a natural question
obtain the following tables
so this shows that the uh variant of
flow this f4 with impressed rejection
has a
dynamic anonymity
and so
it
with a robust hybrid pks
but unfortunately so there's a lot of
problems on four finalists so for
example the classic materialist doesn't
have a anonymity
and the kaiba and the saber has no
anonymity results and n2 has no army
digits
they fortunately showed that for the
game satisfies the industrial security
and anonymity in europe and collision
freezes
the
results hybrid
pk is also satisfying
anonymity but unfortunately so we don't
know nothing on
four finalists
on anonymities
so what's the problem so the problem is
uh
so roughly speaking so we need to
simulate two
the capsulation molecule and decreasing
workload
so in the case of classical materials so
the
they have a an obstacle that so the
classical matrix is not collision free
and in the intro case so m3 uses sxy so
she's used as h over m as uh to generate
t so this is an obstacle uh
to apply their techniques
and in addition so they found that the
tweaks of a rule in kyber and sabre are
obstacles to showing that their
anonymity and even their industry
security was also according to this
table so we know nothing on anonymity or
for finance or mr big strands
okay
so i'm following a graph that was a
study so we showed that
the following result
so we use a strong pseudonyms instead of
a anonymous anime anonymity
so at first we showed that the strongest
anomalies
immediately implied anonymity
and the next so we showed that that
for
camden frameworks for strong random
hybrid pks
so roughly spacing so we
showed that the sprc came with increased
rejection has uh some apple some
additional property
uh implies that such expiry hybrid pa
and then so we have an anonymous pk
hybrid pk
so on lostness we omit the details but
we can use the robustness results of
grabs eduardo
and third so we saw that
as a strongly distanced metal
simulator pk implies us
so spr
such strong strong game schemes
and so forth so we apply them to an
institution and slicken
and then we obtain this result
so fortunately so we
show we can show that the
anonymity of classical matrix
and the anonymity of hybrid pk also
other
uh today's summary sets that so
it fails to achieve a robustness apk
and we show that in truth you need to
like this one and the bike is juicy and
uh into the intro
and prime on the side
so unfortunately so it's you see uh
the one parameter of hqc uh that doesn't
achieve the anonymity also because it
works the parity of the increase 20.
and so additionally uh
so
we note that so
the bernstein uh number time pointed out
that the problems would be solved if e
employment chandra is quantum in
differentiability on
such a combination of random workers but
we i didn't check the details but
this is a promising approach to so
to fill out this question mark as by yes
mark
okay so because of the time limitation i
want to
talk about the
0.1 and 0.3 okay
in order to do so so i i want to label
sxy
so sxy
is a conversion from a deterministic pke
into the industry chem scheme
so
and we say that pk is strongly
dischargeable so if the the random
are cipher attached to random plaintext
this one
it's in this computationally
indistinguishable from
fiberglass generated by simulator
and in addition so we required that
a ciphertext generated by simulator is
is uh
really
lies in
a ciphertext space of this one
so
that is so we require to this
this for this
so by using such a deterministic pte so
chem stream is defined as flows
so
in general of chem
we first denote the encryption key and
the description key by using pk's gene
and then we additionally choose this
random sheet
so in encapsulation we uh
it's randomly select
this plaintext and it encrypts this aim
by using the ek an obtainability
and full session key of game scheme so
it computed k as this h of m
and then returned it returns cipher
diction k
so in the calculation so
receiving a ciphertext it first compute
the m prime as a decryption result
then so it
if the receiving ciphertext is a
re-encrypted
name ciphertextus then so
it's output k as a hash of n prime so
otherwise so it's output the random
pseudonym
this k
so this is a
sxy
so uh
in order to uh so the main problem of
to show industry security so we need to
simulate the determination work object
so in order to do so so sxy are using
this approach so they
define the hash of m as another hash of
q of encryption of ek and m
so by using this approach so we can
simulate the calculation local as a
htube ciphertext
and in addition so if we
replace a vr ciphertext with the
ciphertext to generate simulator
so then this
will be looks random uh from uh jrd
buffalo so by using this approach this
facts
so uh sxy proves industry security of
game scheme as follows so we want to
show that this line
is equal to this line accommodation
distinctive this line
so in order to do so we constant hybrid
games between
these three three hybrid games
and so we can show that
uh at first we replace the decaturation
rocker with h of 2
by simulating the chapters morocco then
so we can replace this side voltage with
a simulated ciphertext generated by
simulator
then so we can
we can show that this k drk is
indistinguishable from random k
then
so replacing uh
by using a rebut approach so we obtain
this
final line
so this is fat uh sx i did in uh to show
the industry security
so by using uh this approach so let us
consider fat uh graphs and malam and
betasandies
so uh let us consider the uh upright uh
grab setup approach to show that
and occur security on sxy
so in the case so we need to simulate
two decapitation capacitor
since we don't know uh
dk0 and dk1
so therefore the knew that to do so so
gmp i used as a
modifying the hash function as this this
one rk as this one so instead of h of m
so they use the h of m and c
and so they define the h of m c as the h
i of c if
in just encryption v k i and m is a
input ciphertext
and otherwise so it output h of q
hq of c
so by using this uh
definition so the degeneration oracle
for dk0 is assimilated by this h0 ct and
the expression molecule for dk1 is
simulated by the h-ram ct
oh this is a
grab it grab that word approach
so unfortunately there's a
problem so this this simulation require
a weak robot robustness so this means
that the underlying pk so with this
green pk is collision freeness so
therefore so we cannot apply this
approach to the class command
class communicates because classical
matrix is not collision free
and in addition so
to show anonymity so we need to modify
this h h of m instead of
s we need to modify h of m c instead of
h of m
so since m 2 uses the original x square
so this is
another obstacle to show the anonymity
and through
so we solve this problem by you
considering a strong pseudonymous social
strong shoulder anomalous
means that this cyphertext pair of
ciphertext j generated by uh
encapsulation is indistinguishable from
a
ciphertext generated by simulator and
that
chosen from random
and this uh so this is a
recap of
chemistry
so
in order to do
in order to show anonymity and a and
social security
so we want to show that this and this is
a competition industry initiative
so we consider two hybrid games
so
and so
in the uh
the first two lines uh computationally
distinguishable because of
strong shoulder around the mass on uk 0
and then so we here so we can use the
dk1
and in this line so we use dk0 but so
this
switch of the
the calculation key is a
statistically indistinguishable
then so we
replace this ciphertext and k uh as a
real one
generated by ek1 so this is uh
justified by the strong student
anonymous
so therefore so we can show that uh this
spr cca
immediately implement a n o c in the
chem case
so we want therefore so we want to show
uh
sxy
imply the sprc security
so in order to do so so we
we uh back to the industry security of
sxy
so this is a6 wise approach
of hybrid games
and also we want to show that sds
stronghold strong distance
simulatability impress sprc security or
became scheme so therefore we want to
show that this is
computationally indistinguishable this
one
so and then so we recall that the
industry security
hybrid games of industry security so
then we
obtained this one and we next game and
third game this game
so now uh seeing this game
on this game
so the difference is uh how to simulate
the traffic station workload so in this
game so we use the h2 o2 but in this
game so we are we use real decay but
apparently so
we can replace this one at this one
because we define so
because so this is uh
corresponding to this approach
so therefore
we just obtain this
uh sprc security uh as a industry
security of this xy
okay
okay let me laptop
so this is summary
so
we showed that uh
so in order to consider uh anonymity so
we first intermediate security notion so
strong should randomness
so then so we first showed the strongest
randomness implies anonymity
then so we construct the camden
framework for such sphere hybrid pks
unfortunately so on robustness so grab
sector already shows that i show such
hybrid candidates framework and then so
we use a robustness framework
then so to construct such a sprcgame
streams so we consider sxy and hu and h
u and so on
then so
we can show that strongly distinguished
metal pk implies us
sprc chem schemes
then we apply them to institutional
three games we then obtain these
tables so uh
as a open process uh we want
uh open pro we have two open problems
the one is showing the spr or
strong numbers or anonymity of kyber
without quantum indefinite stability
so this is a
open problem by uh
graph center
and then the second open problem is
showing a
strong shoulder randomness or anonymity
of
airflow
tightly
as a so because
we obtain such tight industries security
institute quantum molecular
any questions for the speaker
okay let's thank the speaker again and
proceed with the next talk