so uh welcome everybody again uh the
second uh talk of this session is battle
t with optimal right by sveka brakerski
pedro branco nico duckling and uh
and see heinz gonna give a talk
your mic is off
right
now
okay
all right uh
okay okay
um sorry for that um
thanks for introduction again uh mchang
i will talk about uh batch ot with
optimal rate it's a joint who work with
uh suica brexit pedro branco and
nicodellin
so let me first uh recall the
functionality of obvious transfer there
are two parties a sender and a receiver
so a sender inputs two bits m0 and m1
where the receiver inputs a single
choice bit and the functionality rather
outputs the chosen bit mb to the
receiver
so for security we requires that
the sender doesn't want the receiver to
learn
the other unshortened message and one
minus b
similarly the receiver doesn't want a
singer to learn which message is chosen
by him
so there's a there's an amortized
variant of ot called a batch ot
basically it's a an independent bit ot
where cinder inputs uh unpaired bits and
receiver inputs
and choice bits to retrieve
and b1 to mbn
so in this work
we focus on the two rung ot protocol
which means each party in the protocol
only sends a single message where the
receiver sends the first message
encoding his choice bits and the sender
responds with a second message including
the children bits
the two notions we are interested we are
interested in this work is our upload
rate and download rate absorber rating
means is a ratio between the
trust bits and the first message
download rate is a ratio between the
children base and the second message
so it's natural to ask can we build a
batch ot protocol with optimal rate
here optimal rate means
both upload rate and download rate are
close to one
in other words the total communication
complexity tends to be a two times n
where n is a number of bases you
transfer
so it's sweet it's a it's uh the
straightforward solution is to use um
with one fhe
uh return fg uh makes uh
uh it says uh for a bit stopper test
your uh it also can contains or convey a
roughly embedded message
but there are a few drawbacks uh the
first is it requires lattice assumption
second it's
it's not computationally efficient due
to the strapping mechanism used
so we tend to ask can we build a rate 1
batch ot with assumptions not implying
fhe or without lattice or assumptions
so the answer leads to our main result
we are able to build a batch ot protocol
with overweight 1 which secure against a
semi-honest adversaries and we need a
ddh assumption to argue similar security
and we need a ddh plus lpa assumptions
to argue receiver security
as an additional result we show how to
emulate a small subgroup in the p which
gives us the first
statistically function private linear
homomorphic encryption under ddh with
rate one summer test
here's a road map of this talk uh i will
first show you how to build a standard
ot from el cama encryption schemes
then i show how to achieve download one
via
standard test compression next i will
show how to
achieve operator 1 via the encryption
technique
at the end i will briefly describe how
to
tackle two small issues appearing in the
last step
okay as a warm-up
let's see how we can build a standard
bit ot from
from ergoma scheme
the receiver generates a public key
namely generator generator g and group
element g to the y where y is also the
secret key
to generate the server test
the receiver encodes has transparent b
as g to the b
notice uh this encoding can be decoded
efficiently due to the small small
message space
the receiver sends a public key and a
server test to the sender
the sender will morphically compute the
ot function on this server test this ot
function is linear
you can see if x equals to zero
the output would be m zero at x equals
to one the output would be m one
so after the
evaluation the sample test will increase
the g choose mp
and of course with a refreshed
randomness and then uh the sender sends
back the suffer test to the receiver
receiver can decrypt it can
can decrypt it by his secret key to
learn the children bit
um considering the communication banner
wise the download rate is a one over two
times a group size as there are two
group elements in the second message
and upload rate similarly is one over
four times group size there are four
couple elements group elements in the
first message
so this basic protocol is not satisfying
as it has poorer rates
so how can we
improve on that
we use a sub test compression technique
to
to achieve a downward rate of one
and that is uh to encrypt l bits uh our
public key is gonna be l plus one group
elements
and uh the uncompressed server test also
contains air plus one group elements and
they share the same randomness
after compression
uh the subtest is composed of a header
and l pillow bits the header contains
scissor and key uh the header uh the
size of the header only depends on the
security parameter so in this way we can
compress the support test into l bits
plus some constant this
is a symmetric written one server test
so with this technique we can amortize
the sender's message as follows
the receiver encodes uh his trust bit
for each shot speed encoded as a vector
so he has a
l choice bits so there are going to be l
server test of vectors
and the receiver sends the public key
and
l server tests to the sender the sender
also homomorphically computes the ot
function on each server test
note for each server test he runs a sim
function on each coordinate of the
vector so after evaluation
the server test will encrypt the
the chosen bit at its specific position
after summing up and the scenario can
compress it to
a small or a short server test using the
sample test compression technique
after receiving that
the receiver can decrease it to
get the to learn the chosen bits
so in this way uh the download rate is
because becomes a l over l plus some
constant as long as we transfer
as long as the number of bits to
transfer is large enough so this rate is
close to one
however in the other side the absolute
rate is even worse because um we use
airsquare
group elements to encode just uh
airplays
so how to improve on the upload rate
uh our approach is to use ring
encryption technique uh what we need
actually is a red one encryption scheme
with linear decryption
so
lpn
almost fulfills these requirements
uh recall option means for any uniformly
random matrix and a random vector and a
error vector with small hamming weight
elp n holds f a s plus e
is computationally indistinguishable
from a uniformly random vector
and uh symmetric encryption also simply
works as follows given a secret key s we
can encrypt a binary vector m as a
compute a s plus e n plus m to decrypt
it just uh just compute d minus a s so
for the moment we
we we will ignore this uh decryption
error
so with lpn the receiver can encrypt
his can encrypt his trust base
under the lpn scheme and additionally he
will include the option secret under the
lcm scheme
so then the receiver sends the el comma
public key and
of the test and also the instable test
and the matrix a to the center
the scenario will first homomorphically
decrypt this
instrument test under the hood of
argument so here we will get a
a test encrypting the receiver's trust
bits
and then he can automatically evaluate
the ot function and compress it to the
small separate test as before
the receiver then just
decrypt it to learn the trillion bits
but doing this way
the up to low rate is out over n times
poly lamina plus plus l this uh also
close to one as long as the dimension of
the gap in secret is much smaller than
the number samples l
also notice that we ignore the
matrix a in calculation because we can
reuse this matrix for multiple bunch of
choice bits
and um azir is due to small issues
the first one is
option has decryption errors
so it will produce incorrect outputs
second
augment is actually not a function
private uh scheme over z2 but
in this step we need to
homomorphically decrypt in server tests
we actually need to operate in z2
so let's see
how to deal with option errors
we need to run additional protocols in
parallel let's first consider the
positions with error which means
the trust bits at this positions will be
flipped after option decryption
since the receiver knows the error
positions so for each error position he
can compute the the first message of an
additional ot protocol with the speed bi
as its input
it computes
another computes the first message of
pll protocol and with the position i as
input
then he sends both of these messages for
each error position to the senior
after receiving them the sender also for
each error position
computes the ot response
based on these messages
for all of his inputs so in this way the
sender will get a database of ot
responses for each for each organization
then the sender just uh computes the pll
response
based on each database
for each position
then to send the
responses to the receiver the receiver
can locally recover the chosen base at
this at error positions by finishing the
pir protocol followed by the
ot protocol
okay but what about the
the bits as the positions without errors
we cannot just directly send them to the
receiver because the center doesn't know
which positions
has error and which are not
the sender needs to use a
additional technique called a
distributed punctual prf
so the center holds a
prf key and uh
and mask all of his inputs at the prx
values and
the center then
obliviously generate and transfer the
puncture key to the receiver
with this puncture key the receiver can
unmask prf values at all positions
except for the arrow positions
this can be
constructed by knowing techniques
so
the last issue
is about the function privacy
so similar privacy actually doesn't hold
in about verticals because argument is
not a function probably over the two the
reason is
the group zp
doesn't have non-trivial subgroups
so if we encode the bit and as a g to
the b it will leak information and we
cannot do modular reduction
however if we want to encode it in
higher order bits like in lattice
setting
let's do accumulated errors which leaks
information again
so our solution is to use a random
master only
with randomized rounding we still want
to encode a bit uh in high order bits
but uh
now this time we
we want to integer close to
zero or q number two
according to a discrete gaussian
distribution
in this way we can solve the problem and
it actually gives us a statistical
function private schemes
yeah and there are a few open questions
to be solved in future works
for example can we upgrade our
semi-honest security to malaysia
security
or
can we remove or replace appearance
assumptions with others
thanks for listening
thank you
and
do anybody has questions
hi thank you for the talk very nice uh
tricks i was wondering what kind of
error rates do you use in the lpn
assumption okay uh um yeah uh thanks for
the question uh the
error rate is uh slightly uh sublinear
to the
to the number of samples it's a
uh one is inverse small polynomial error
rate
okay thank you no problem
are there any other questions
um
can i ask you
if you could go back to slide i think 12
uh to which slider
12 12.
oh yeah it's about here okay
so
um so this is uh
lpn uh
and at the same time elgamal right yes
so where where is el cam what are you
applying elgamal to
uh sorry what is elgamal encrypted which
okay the ergomer encryption encrypted
the airplane secret
um yes
and the server the sender
sender applies elgamal re-encryption uh
yeah
the sender applies a sender who mostly
decrypts the option under the ergonomic
schemes since ergoma is linear
homomorphic
ah
also
server evaluates
evaluates a decryption algorithm over
over the algoma scheme yes or argument
subtest ah
and that's what it sends back
uh yes yeah yes
and um
so this packing it's uh you use the
packing technique right yes so
it has no limit like i can pack however
many bits i want into the single
algorithm
object group elements or it stops at
some point you you're seeing how many uh
this we can pack in the algoma super
test right
uh
for the elements of the test uh
i think it depends on your since
ecommerce has a
super polynomial modulus so in a packing
we need some we need a prf to
to detect to
to generate a breakpoint in the group as
long as the group is large enough we can
we can pack as much information as we
want
and
so
this you do you think this kind of
extends to
outing larger messages and bits
you mean uh the string otr
uh
i mean uh what we saw is uh what we
focus on the bit ot means uh the message
is just single bit but for if if you
want to do for string ot
you can you can do with easier
easier techniques i mean bit old implies
string ot right uh but not the other way
around
ah so you just you just repeat
over right because you only have honest
bacteria yeah yes
security yeah
yeah
okay thank you so much
uh thanks
if there is no further questions then
let's thank the speaker