talk um
let me maybe announce the last talk so
the last talk will be co a secure
obfuscation and applications by iran
kaneti super dev checkerboty dakshita
kurana nishant kumar oksana
will tell us about this result uh ron
kennedy would like to
speak a few words um
about the reason recent and tragic
passing of uh one of the authors of this
work
thank you
um
so uh one of our uh co-authors nishant
kumar uh uh died last month in a tragic
accident
and uh i would like to say a few words
in his memory
with your permission
um uh very very short so um
some of these words they uh were written
by uh the kshitakarana which is which
was a nissan advisor and some of my own
are my own
so um sun nishant was born december 2
and 1994 in ranji jacquelbard india and
he passed away in a tragic accident
on april 10th this year in hawaii
illinois in us
he was 27 years old
um
tanishan was a bright star in our lives
uh he was especially in his contagious
almost childlike enthusiasm and
curiosity
he was also very insightful and smart he
had the the uh the makings of a
wonderful researcher and his passing is
an immeasurable loss to our community
even more importantly though he was kind
patient humble and a caring mentor to
many others
his passionate curiosity extended to a
very wide array of topics spanning both
theoretical and applied cryptography he
was bearing with questions and ideas and
he loved long deep technical
conversations
he would take it upon himself to drive
project forward he wouldn't shy away
from spending long hours thinking about
hot questions he was a dream student and
collaborator
he spent two productive years as a
research fellow with microsoft research
india where he worked on multi-party
computation compilers for machine
learning
two of these papers titled script flow
and creep flow 2 had an important impact
on the area of secure inference
at the uiuc he worked on a
non-malleable and verifiable obfuscation
which is the work that you will talk
about today
and on new ways to achieve security by
exploiting the properties of quantum
information which is forthcoming work
in our joint work uh he was first very
tentative
but as he learned more about the work
and developed literature he became more
confident and started uh catching us
when we were
saying something wrong
or just uh bsing
uh soon enough he started owning the
work and rewriting uh
large parts of it
uh throughout i was very much impressed
uh with uh nishant uh
inside insightfulness
and uh
and his ability to say
that he does not understand that he
didn't he just did not understand or
just know something but when he was
saying something for sure if he was
invariably right
last uh something last month
in march we were working on
finally putting a full version of the
paper on eprint
i was uh uh writing a new proof for one
of the uh the theorems
and uh uh i was uh very proud of it was
very nice i thought to the next ideas
and uh i uh it looked just fine but i
sent everybody please say can you take a
look
uh
and
and the uh then the following weekly
meeting uh uh that monday uh
uh nation said you know it's very nice
but there are two issues which i don't
really understand
and uh i knew i was in trouble and sure
enough you know those two issues were
but were deep flaws in this in this uh
in this truth which we spend uh uh a lot
of time or the the entire meeting to
discuss
then time went out
and
and uh and we had to you know stop we
said we'll talk the next week
spent i spent most of the week thinking
about ways to get around those issues
and i was looking forward to the next
monday's meeting to uh uh to discuss it
again with nishant and the others
but then monday morning i opened my
email to the terrible news
so um
so i would like to uh to tell you sean
forever he is that we now think we have
it done and uh it's in the same uh our
relief if you can take a look would be
great
um
let me just uh uh
say uh
a few uh the one last paragraph
saying that nishant's a beautiful smile
sincerity energy and cheer and and and
cheer touch the lives of everyone around
him
it is still very hard to accept that he
will never come back to us
but we always keep his the memories of
in our hearts and use his life to guide
our own
when we move forward
thank you
thanks ron for the obituary
um indeed it's very hard to accept that
nishant is not with us
anymore and i would like to dedicate my
talk in the memory of nishant
okay so uh
so this talk is about co secure
obfuscation and applications
um
this is joint work with ran dakshita
nishant aksana and manoj
yeah
so uh a one-minute summary of the paper
so this paper provides a framework that
endows software obfuscation with
proofs of wealth firmness so in
particular
this uh it enhances many of the existing
security notions for of obfuscation to
provide uh verifiability and
non-malleability guarantees
and we show generic construction
satisfying our
definitions
so the roadmap will be i'll start with
some motivations
why we consider such a notion followed
by
our new definitions
and some new applications to complete
cca encryption and stronger software
watermarking so in the interest of time
uh in this talk i'll be talking about
the complete cc encryption although the
software watermarking is also one of the
main applications of our paper
and i would i would encourage people to
look up our paper for the watermarking
application
and finally i would end my talk with um
the construction of coa officiation
good
so general purpose software obfuscation
holds great promise for enhancing the
security of software in general
softwares can be distributed and
executed without fear that the internal
design secrets of the program or the
keys that are hidden inside the code
will be revealed
and this is great for software creators
because they can use obfuscation to hide
the
keys both in the code and functionality
however ubiquitous use of obfuscation
might also call for some drawbacks in
particular it's hard to verify
properties of the obfuscated program
um in general it reduces to black box
testing the program
and this is of um and this is highly
unsatisfactory
particularly if the of for example the
creator of the obfuscated program is
untrusted or unknown
so yet another pressing issue is the
issue of malleability in which the
adversary might create an obfuscated
program that depends on the secrets that
are embedded in some other office credit
program in illegitimate ways and when i
say illegitimate it could refer to the
legitimacy condition could refer to both
the structural and functional properties
of the office of the
obfuscated program so for example
obfuscation might help to facilitate
software plagiarism
imagine that i publish an office credit
program a
that hides the details that it's
potentially using the malt version of
some proprietary software
and it's not publix publicly announcing
it right
and this is a problem even if the uh the
program b is implemented correctly
because the behavior of a might depend
in malicious way depending upon the
behavior of b
so one might expect that the already
existing notions of software obfuscation
like io gives some sort of
non-malleability guarantee
um and in particular this is somewhat
true if for example io uses inside it
some module that directly does not
affect the functionality of the program
but for example imagine that you're
obfuscating a pseudorandom function like
a puncturable prf with a key k so that
directly affects the output of the
program so in such case it might be
possible that adversary takes such an
obfuscated program and produces another
program
that
computes the same function but on a
related key
k plus one for example
right so
hopefully this provides enough
motivation
why we should study verifiability and
non-malleability for obfuscation in
general
so um having said that let's see what
are the challenges
that arise when we try to define such a
notion of obfuscation
so
so since we're talking about some sort
of verifiability or non-malleability
we should have a verifier
that takes an obfuscated program and
outputs say accept or reject
okay
so
let's
uh try to define
um in the following way that when the
verifier accepts a program then a
specific circuit is being obfuscated
of course this is not desirable because
ideally you would like to hide the
code of c which ideally obfuscation
should do but if you prove that a
specific circuit is being obfuscated
then you reveal all the details of the
circuit
the second attempt is that you would
want to say that okay if the verifier
accepts there exists some circuit c
which is functionally equivalent to this
obfuscated circuit
this sounds reasonable however this is
trivial to achieve because for every
office credit program there exists some
plain text program corresponding to it
so
let's define a class of predicate for
the simplicity let's consider a
particular public predicate phi and now
the verification algorithm also takes as
input some predicate
and
um outputs accept
so we would want to say that if the
output of the verification on input and
obfuscated circuit and a public
predicate is accept
then there exists an underlying circuit
which is functionally equivalent to the
obfuscated circuit and satisfies the
predicate
now look that what we can do is that we
can define the predicate in a fine-tuned
way that hides the code of the circuit c
yet attest to some of the properties
that you would want to um
verify so for example it might attest to
the programs of some particular
functionality or of some particular
structure
whatever you would want
okay so what's the trivial way to
achieve this uh you have to get a
program and attach your music proof that
there is some circuit c and randomness
that results in obfuscated circuit
and satisfies the predicate
right um the drawback is that it
requires a trus a trusted setup phase
that is a common reference string
um and the goal of this work is to
construct verifiable and non malleable
obfuscation in the plain model
good
so uh before going into the details
let's review some prior works
so um so the best of our knowledge the
closest uh work that is
related to this topic is the notion of
is is the verifiable functional
encryption by
um bhadri narayan goyal jain and sahai
from asia group 16.
um
so the upside of their construction is
that they provide a construction for io
that's verifiable and does not require
any trusted setup assumption
however the drawback is that their
technique is stellar made for io so
their idea is to use newy instead of
nesix
however if you think about it if you use
neemi then the me only guarantees that
the witness is hidden if you have some
alternate witnesses so if you just
obfuscate a program you don't have an
alternate witness to proof so what they
do in their construction is basically
obfuscate
the same program say three times
and then prove using nemi that two of
the programs are uh same or functional
equivalent
and now i can use newmie in um
in some way to
to gives verifiability
um and i think the main drawback of
their work is that it provides a limited
form of hiding
that is the require that is they can
only guarantee indistinguishability for
indistinguishability for obfuscations of
functional equivalent circuit for which
there exists only a short proof of
equivalence say if you obscure for
example a prf and a punctured prf you
have such a short proof of equivalence
but in general this is not true for
general circuits and also it does not
provide any sort of guarantee against
malleability attacks so it only provides
guarantee against verifiability
okay so there is another work by um
ran and mayank from tcc 2009
um
in the uh with the title on malleable
obfuscation
uh and
the this gives um
um however this considers obfuscation
for point functions
and related functionalities because this
is a simulation based definition
and
as we know that for all class of
functions you cannot get vvv obfuscation
so this paper considers uh obfuscation
for
point functions and multi-point
functions okay but if you think about it
uh to define non-malleability it's
natural that you would want to have a
similar simulation based definition that
whatever the adversary could come up
with the black box access you can also
simulate
unfortunately it's plagued by
impossibility result
so this brings us to the our definition
what is
coa stands for chosen obfuscation
attacks
so
um
as before let's consider a class of
circuits and some predicate
phi
and
you'd expect that um so the office the
obfuscation algorithm also takes some
circuit c and a predicate 5 and outputs
um the program um c hat
and the verification algorithm also
takes the
predicate
phi and it should output one or zero
however it turns out that uh
so the software scatter can be
randomized and the verifier is
deterministic right so in this setting
it turns out that it's very difficult to
achieve security
i mean even verifiability for a general
class of circuits so what we do is relax
the notion and say that
the verifier can also be randomized
and the output of the verifier is not a
single bit instead it's a circuit
so let's try to understand this notion
so it's a so the obfuscation is
basically a two-step process
where
the obfuscator
takes his input some circuit c and
outputs um
some semi-functional obfuscation like
it's not yet a fully functional program
so think of it as an um encoding and the
verifier then transforms this encoding
into a fully functional of obfuscated
circuit
so what is the currentness guarantee the
correctness guarantee is that for a
legitimate circuit that is a circuit
which satisfies the predicate the output
of the verifier is functionally
equivalent to the circuit that you
obfuscated
soundness says that
for any arbitrary
program intermediate program c hat
if the output of the verifier is not
bottom that is
it's a it's some circuit c tilde which
is not bottom then there exists an
underlying circuit which is functional
equivalent to c and satisfies the
predicate so which means so this means
that if the verifier outputs some
circuit
then there exists some sort some
explanation of the circuit in the
plaintext space
and
such that the plaintext program is
legitimate
and finally i come to the main notion
which is coa security
which says that for sufficiently similar
circuits c0 and c1 the observation of
these two circuits
is indistinguishable even given access
to a de-obfuscation oracle so i'll make
it more explicit in the next slide
so
let's consider this game between a
challenger and an adversary
so the adversary
uses the sampler to sample
circuit c0 c1 along with some auxiliary
input z and passes it to the challenger
now when i say that the circuits must be
sufficiently
similar
so what do i mean
by that is that the sampler should be
admissible
so in some sense the the circuit c0 and
c1 should satisfy the predicate and they
should be indistinguishable by black box
access
okay so note that this is powerful
enough to capture um any notion of
obfuscation that provides some sort of
hiding guarantees like in case of i o c
0 and c 1 are functional equivalent and
z is just
null or you can think of z s c 0 c 1.
you can also capture p i o x i o in this
notion where
you can define the sampler accordingly
now uh the challenger
samples a random bit and obfuscates the
circuit cb and sends
c hat so note that c hat is still not
the fully functional program right it's
the intermediate program
now
the adversary can ask for de-obfuscation
queries
so it gives us input to the challenger
some string c hat which is a
semi-functional program
and what the challenger does is that if
it is equal to the challenge
intermediate program it outputs it
outputs bottom else it runs the
randomized verifier to transform it into
a fully functional office credit circuit
city law
and if citilla is not bottom
um
it returns um
it returns um so there is a typo here so
basically you can think of it that when
c tilde is not bottom it returns a
lexicographically first circuit
which is functionally equivalent to um
c and satisfies the predicate
so this is how the obfuscation oracle is
defined
so note that
this holds because if the output of the
verifier is not bottom then as i said
then there exists an underlying
plaintext circuit
uh which satisfies the predicate and in
particular there can be many such
circuits so the um
challenger
is inefficient of course and it outputs
the lexicographically first such circuit
which satisfies the predicate
okay and it returns the plaintext
circuit to the adversary and the
obfuscation circuits can uh queries can
be made adaptively and in arbitrary
order
um and for simplicity i've assumed that
the adversary in the first step gives
the c0 c1 but this is not necessary it
can also ask the official the
obfuscation queries and then uh give the
challenge
okay
um and finally it uh outputs a bit b
prime that um that's a guess for which
of the circuits was obfuscated
okay so in our work we also provide a
second definition that is more handy to
work with so in particular this
definition says that you give me any
offers
any notion of obfuscation that satisfies
some hiding guarantee which is
represented by the admissible sampler
definition and i can augment this
obfuscated circuit to give you a coa
guarantee on top of it so we call it coa
fortification
so
as before we consider a class of circuit
and a predicate phi
but now let's define o to be an
obfuscation scheme which is injective so
why do i need it to be injective i later
explain
but in general you can
transform any obfuscation scheme into an
injective obfuscation scheme by
attaching a perfectly binding commitment
of the plaintext program along with the
office credit circuit
okay so as before
the office the offer skater takes us
input the circuit and the predicate
outputs a semi-functional program which
is then transformed by the randomized
verifier into a fully functional program
see tilde so the correctness is that
for a legitimate circuit
the output of the verifier should be in
the image of the obfuscator o
so in particular ct let can be explained
as an obfuscator of c with some
randomness r
soundness says that if the output of the
verifier on some arbitrary arbitrary
string c hat is not bottom then there
exists an underlying circuit c
such that it satisfies the predicate and
is in the image of the obfuscation o
and finally cos security says that again
for sufficiently similar circuits c0 and
c1
given access to a de-obfuscation oracle
o inverse
so this is where it it becomes important
why the obfuscation scheme is injective
so when i say an obfuscation scheme is
injective it means that no to pro no to
plaintext programs map to the same
obfuscated program so for each office
career circuit there is a uniquely
defined plaintext program and hence the
challenger can inefficiently invert and
recover the plaintext program okay so
now uh the security says that if the
obfuscation of the two circuits c0 and
c1 are indistinguishable i can use this
distinguisher to build a distinguisher
for the underlying of a scatter o
okay
so uh pictorially so
this is the
it says that
um suppose in this world where in the
left world where there is an adversary
and challenger and
it runs this game
where the
adversary where it the adversary
receives um a challenge semi-functional
program which is an obfuscation of
either c0 and c1
and it makes d obfuscation queries
arbitrary and adaptively and suppose
there is a distinguisher
uh so if the adversary can distinguish
which of the two circuits uh was
obfuscated with a non-negligible
advantage
then i can use this adversary to build
an adversary in the right right right
hand world where note that there are no
differentiation queries
so this translates to an uh
distinguisher for the underlying of a
scatter o
okay
good and um
it's not hard to see that this
definition two
for
injective pio implies our definition one
so
if you have coa fortification for
injective pil for some
class of samplers so more technically x
in pio this implies our definition in
the
um
the the definition that the earlier uh
showed you
okay so let's jump into the application
um given the definitions
so uh the application that i'll be
talking about is a complete cca public
encryption
so um
so this is basically an enhancement of
cca secure public key encryption where
the adversary has access to a strong
decryption oracle
so
normally in cca the adversary has access
to a decryption oracle where it can feed
different ciphertexts and get messages
but with respect to the challenge public
key but here the adversary can submit a
couple of public keys and cipher text of
his or her choice
and get um
and get it decrypted
okay
so
this is this is a strengthening of the
notion of completely non-malleable
encryption which was uh defined by
fishlin and uh
some later uh works uh when defined
appropriately
so it turns out that this notion is too
good to be achievable in the plane model
so fishlin
showed that
completely non-malleable public
encryption is impossible to construct in
the plane model if you're using blackbox
reduction and
if the assumption in your hand is a
polynomial time falsifiable assumption
okay
so in our work we bypass this
impossibility result by
uh using sub exponential hardness
assumptions
okay
so before going into the model we
require one technical
condition from the public encryption
namely unique decryptability so what
does it say
so for any public key there is a way to
test whether this public key is useless
so i assume that the encryption
algorithm can output a string button
and the decryption algorithm on input
such as ciphertext which is bottom
outputs bottom
so i say a public key is useless
when the probability that the for any
message
the cipher text is bottom is some
negligible
okay
and for um non useless keys there should
be a unique opening for this public key
so that means there should be a secret
key that decrypts the cipher text
correctly
and moreover for this unique opening
there should exist a um
a public key that is under the
support of the key generation algorithm
so note that the public key pk
might not be in the
support of key generation
so pictorially
the challenger runs the key generation
and
gives the public key the challenge
public key to the adversary now the
adversary can ask for
um
like tuples of his choice like pkici
now the challenger checks if pki is
useless
if it is not useless it inefficiently
finds the opening there is a secret key
and returns the message mi which is the
result of decrypting
ci under the opening okay and it can do
it arbitrarily and as many times as it
wants and then it uh the adversary gives
to messages m0 m1 and gets the
encryption of one of them and it can
continue the um
strong decryption oracle phase and at
some point it uh outputs a guess for the
bit b
okay
so uh having defined this notion let's
see how to construct this strong form of
public encryption
so for this we would of course be
requiring our notion of coa
fortification
for an injective io
so
with respect to a predicate which says
that the predicate attests to some
program which i will shortly show
so we need a sero-random generator which
is length doubling and two
prfs which is puncturable
so the key generation algorithm
samples two keys and the public key is
an obfuscation of the following circuit
so it has two prf keys embedded inside
it it takes this input a message and a
randomness
and
expands the randomness and
uh uses the c1
to basically um
encrypt the messages like a one-time pad
and c3 is basically you can think of it
as like a mac on c1 and c2 so this is
basically the sahai waters cc secure
public encryption and uh what we do is
kind of replace the obfuscation with the
coa fortification for injective io
so the encryption algorithm
so note that the public key is not yet a
fully functional of a skelet circuit so
it's the p hat is a semi-functional
program so the encryption algorithm runs
the verification transforms it into a
fully functional program
and then runs the
program on input the message and some
randomness that it samples
and the output is basically the cipher
text from the first credit circuit
and the decryption uh key is basically
the two secret keys and um
the decryption is trivial okay
so
why is the scheme uniquely decryptable
so it follows from the soundness of um
the coa fortification of of i o and the
injectivity of io so
this is because if the encryption
algorithm outputs
um
some
some circuit pitilla
um which is not bottom which that means
that there exists some plain text
program
such that um
that program can that program is
obfuscation of so such that ptl is
obfuscation of that program and since we
say that the program should attest to
this predicate phi
which is this program pk1 k2 it means
the plaintext program must have this
structure so in particular i can extract
the keys k1 k2
and use it for decryption and since of
io is injective there exists a
unique such plaintext program okay
okay
right so let's go to uh let's see the
proof of this on a very high level uh so
recall this this is the program that you
are obfuscating
so
so broadly the two cases might arise for
each strong decryption query first
the public key pki that the adversary
queries is equal to the challenged
public game this is an easy case because
then we are basically reducing to the
cca security of sahai waters because the
challenge has not been changed
the interesting case is when the public
key is changed so the adversary queries
on some pkc where pk is not equal to
pkstar
so in this case you can you interpret
pks some semi-functional program
you run the verifier and get a fully
functional circuit uh p tilde
and you know
and by the soundness of coa
fortification you know that there exists
a plaintext program which is obfuscated
by
io
to get pitilla
so now you recover uh this plain text
program by using the defecation article
and um since the secret keys of the form
so once you have the plaintext program
you can read the code of the program to
recover the underlying prf keys and use
it for decryption
good
okay so
finally i'll go to the construction of
coa offers station very briefly for this
we need a non-interactive
distributionally indistinguishable
argument
that was introduced by dakshita from
last year eurocrypt
so what is the needy argument a media
argument is defined with respect to an
np language
with some relation
rl
such that um the prover and the verifier
has input the language l the prover in
addition has some secret distribution d
of
which it can use to sample statements
and witnesses from the distribution
inefficient efficiently
the prover hands over to the verifier uh
one message think of it as a sampler
and the verifier can use the sampler
and its randomness to verifiably sample
members from the distribution
so
so in particular completeness says that
the output of the verifier is in the
support of the distribution
on the statement soundness says that if
the output of the verifier is not bottom
that means that d is in the np language
l so think of it as the instance being
in the language
and privacy says that for
distributions which are
indistinguishable the proof does not
break the indistinguishability okay so
for every distribution d1 and d2 um
which are indistinguishable the samplers
which are output by the prover are also
indistinguishable okay and
this paper shows that assuming
sub-exponential i o and one-way function
there exist needy for all of np
so in our work we need a robust version
of needy which we introduce
which is a needy um that guarantees
similar indistinguishability but with
respect to an oracle o
so as before
we have the prover and the verifier and
the completeness and the soundness
guarantee but robustness in general says
that the two distribution if the two
distributions are indistinguishable
maybe a couple of minutes
then the output of the prover is also
indistinguishable even if the
distinguisher get access to this oracle
okay and we show how to construct this
robust needy uh by uh modifying the
construction from
the paper last year um but i don't go
into the details
so
for the construction i need a cca secure
commitment scheme
where the oracle o is basically the
decommitment oracle and i need an
obfuscation scheme that is
that is secured against
adversaries that can internally store
this oracle okay
and the obfuscation scheme is very
simple so the distribution is defined as
follows you obfuscate the circuit c with
some randomness r1 and you commit to the
plaintext program okay so having defined
this distribution the
proof is basically uh so the obfuscation
algorithm is basically the sampler of
the needy prover
and the verification algorithm is just
verifying the needy proof okay
um and i won't go into the proof
uh but the high level idea is that in uh
in the first hybrid i
um
obfuscate c0 and commit to c0
and now i a d df the obfuscate using the
decommit pen oracle so note that um in
the first game the obfuscation was done
using o inverse but now uh
i will
defuse it using the d commitment
directly and efficiently
and in the next hybrid i will switch to
obfuscating and committing to the other
program c1 which i can show to be
indistinguishable based on another
hybrid argument
and roughly
since we assume that all the underlying
primitives are secure with respect to
the decommitment oracle in particular
with respect to adversaries who can
store the decommitment oracle um the
proof goes through
okay so finally uh i would conclude with
some open problems
um
so note that the main drawback is that
our definition relies on this two-step
randomized process is it possible to
construct co secure obfuscation for the
more traditional definition where the
verifier is
deterministic and secondly can we come
up with more applications of c way of
fiscalization um just this seems to be
um
this seems that it will find more
applications in other areas of
cryptography uh with that i like to
conclude and i'm open to taking
questions right
thank you so much
we have time for maybe one quick
question
yes go ahead
so in all most of your notions the
challenger is inefficient right i was
wondering whether this leads to uh
problems with you know the final hybrid
proofs and reduction
uh so yeah good question so it does not
because we assume that the underlying
primitives basically are also secure
with respect to so are sub-exponentially
secured so for example in the
construction last construction that i
showed the the de-obfuscation article is
basically inefficiently opening the
commitment so it's the commitment oracle
so if you assume so suppose um
that oracle you
like is of size some capital t
because it's a finite truth table you
can write it down and if you assume that
the underly other primitives are secure
with respect to adversaries that run in
that time then uh then it's possible to
uh argue security so yes
we need uh security of all the
underlying primitives um to set i mean
to satisfy some exponential hardness so
that's how we kind of cope with the
inefficiency of the challenger
okay
so
uh this would conclude this session i
would say let's thank all the speakers
again
[Applause]
see you after lunch break