okay
so let me start again uh welcome to this
uh first session of the morning of the
day
uh it's gonna be about real-world
systems we're gonna have three different
talks one being online the second one
and the first talk is about cocoa
concurrent continuous group k agreement
by joel alvin benedict auerbach
miguel quetto noval karen klein
guillermo pascal perez
chester piechak and michael walter and
guillermo is giving the talk
good
yes
that's what works now
kind of
so
now it seems to
thanks
okay so is this working now yes good
so as i was saying i will talk to you
about coco a concurrent continuous group
agreement which is joint work with joel
benedict miguel karen
schistov a michael
and
so the motivation for our work is
is secure group messaging where a set of
parties want to communicate and they
want to do so
in the presence of an adversary that has
control over the network a moreover can
corrupt parties so in particular we will
talk later about this but the parties
will want to rotate their keys so what
do they do in this case
so the naive solution of course is just
to use bi-directional channels
for example each between each pair of
users they can instantiate a signal
protocol at the double ratchet protocol
but the problem here is that whenever
they want to rotate the keys this would
need to be communicated independently to
each individual user which has linear
communication cost linear in the size of
the group of course
this means it's not scalable so instead
what we want to do is to we want users
to agree on a shared common key
which they will then use to encrypt the
messages right
so this brings us to the primitive of
continuous group key agreement or cgka
that was coined by alvin ital in crypto
and very roughly this allows a group of
end users to agree on a common key with
the following properties so we wanted to
support dynamic membership so in
particular we want to be able to add and
remove users from the group
we want it to be asynchronous meaning we
don't make any assumptions on the online
behavior of users
so we have some untrusted server that
buffers the messages and relates them
afterwards
and we wanted to be secure against
compromise and in particular
so as i said we assume the adversary can
corrupt users
and
wait
if i can remove that bottom part from
[Music]
can it be removed so the the bottom of
the slide can be seen properly
well
so we want some security property to
hold called pcfs which is the
combination of forward secrecy or fs
and post compromise security
or pcs
and for those of you which are not
familiar with these two notions let me
just recall them very quickly so if we
imagine the group timeline with time
running from left to right
and we imagine some compromise in the
middle which in our model means that
that bursary can read everything in the
corrupted device so from all the keys
that are currently stored there to all
the random coins
uh sample during that period
what forward secrecy ensures is that all
the keys up to
some point in the past remain secure and
pcs or post compromise security in turn
ensures that after some point after the
compromise ends the keys remains
keys are again secure
and of course as you can imagine and i
discussed before we will need to rotate
the keys that parties have so what we're
aiming to do is to do this efficiently
in particular with logarithmic
communication per rotation
so this brings us to our contribution
which is a new protocol coco a new cdk
that allows for concurrent key rotations
that do not have um
that do not degrade the efficiency of
the protocol
and in particular protocol
overcomes impossibility previous
impossibility results on the
communication of such concurrent
protocols by relaxing the requirement on
post compromise security what this
relaxation mean i will i will go into it
later and we also introduce the notion
of partial states which allows us to
decrease the recipient communication of
such protocols
so during this talk i will give you an
introduction on tricom which is the main
example of such cdka we will discuss a
bit how concurrency intricate looks like
and then i will tell you about our
protocol we will talk about how
concurrency is handled efficiency
these partial states and a few words on
security just before introducing a
couple of open problems
so let's talk about trigon
trikkem is the ck
underlying mls which stands for message
layer security and it's a working group
by the ietf trying to standardize group
messaging and its aim is to scale to up
to 50 000 users so in particular these
efficient key rotations that i discussed
before are really important right
because we're talking about the very big
groups and just to give you a historical
note this was proposed together with mls
in 2018
and replace art which stands for
asynchronous ratcheting trees
so what does mls look like
it assumes a binary tree
where each node has an associated keeper
and the users are associated to the
leaves and the arrows here denote either
encryptions or hash evaluations so in
particular what this means is that
if a user knows the key
at the node that is at the source of an
edge they will also notice the secret
key corresponding to the node at the
sink of set edge
so in particular it follows
that a user will know the keys for the
nodes in their path right so in
particular this this
user a will know the key is highlighted
in green and the key associated to the
root which is shared by all the users is
the group key and this will be used
later um
to encrypt messages or derive a
symmetric key to encrypt messages or
whatever this cka is used for
before i told you that we can rotate our
key material using only logarithmic
communication so how could we do this
so let's say here a
wants to
rotate her keys so what does she do
and
so what she what she does is she will
sample a new seed for her leaf a zero
and by evaluating a hash function she
will just sample new seeds for all the
nodes in their path
from this you can derive keepers so
secret key public key
and then she will create encryptions of
these seats under the node in the copa
so in particular
if we look at this node here for example
we see that a single encryption from the
root node allows all the all the four
users in this in this subtree sorry this
tree to learn the new key right so in
particular this means that we only need
an algorithmic number of cipher text to
communicate the new keys to everyone
so the the continuous edges here are
encryption edges in case you cannot read
it and the other one is the hash edges
and then the new keys substitute the old
ones uh so what uh what this means is
that now all the previous keys that were
in all the keys that used to be in alice
in eighth estate are useless now and not
part of the tree
uh and let me just very quickly go
through how our how we can handle
removes because this will be relevant
for later so if a here wants to remove e
what she does is uh samples all the no
sorry blanks all the nodes on each path
and blanking here means that these nodes
will then have no associated key
so these keys are useless
and effectively e is removed from the
group uh and the effect that having a
blank node in the tree has is that
if we imagine that a now wants to update
um
so what this what it says below it says
that if you want to encrypt a blank so
in this case a the root she would want
to encrypt to this node but this node is
blank here right so instead she will
need to encrypt to something called the
resolution which are these two yellow
nodes
and essentially informally it's just the
the smallest set of nodes to which you
needs to encrypt so that all the users
in that subtree learn the new key
so effectively having blank nodes
degrades the efficiency of the protocol
because more encryptions are needed
um
in concur when with respect to centric
and we can differentiate between two
versions so we have plane tricking which
corresponds to versions before seven
and this is not concurrent and updates
need to be processed all in order so in
particular if we imagine two users a and
b that want to update at the same time
one of them will get their update
accepted by the server the other one
will be rejected and the one that gets
it rejected say b will need to then
process the update by a and then issue a
new update that hopefully will now get
accepted so in particular this means
that if we want two users to update to
rotate their keys we will need t
communication rounds
in contrast we have propose and commit
which corresponds to versions 8 and up
we are currently in version 14 and this
does allow for concurrent updates and
what it does is let me see if
i do this
perhaps you can see the bottom
bit better
yeah but here i don't have it actually
no
uh i actually see a different screen
from here than there but
um
yeah well
perhaps we can do it like this so you
see slightly more of the screen
so we have proposed commit which is
another flavor of trichome where
actually we can have concurrent updates
and what we have here is at the coupling
of operations between proposals and
commits so users can send proposals
which just get buffered and not applied
immediately
and then a commit will collect several
of these proposals and execute them
simultaneously
so what this means for for
post-compromise security
is that we cannot we can achieve it in
two rounds regardless of how many
corruptions we have in the tree so
before we call in the previous flavor of
chicken if we had t corrupted users and
we want all of them to update we will
need t rounds so here we need two
and the way this would look like is all
corrupted users could then issue an
update proposal
and then a second user could just commit
all of these proposals would get
executed concurrently and that's it
and this incurs a
communication which is linear in the
number of updated users so this is
actually shown to be optimal if we want
to heal in two rounds like bishop at all
in tcc20
this sounds good
the problem of course is that having
these update proposals ruins the tree
structure so having this fast healing
into rounds degrades the performance and
just to give you an example of what this
looks like
let's say that c e and f want to propose
updates here
and then a comes along and
and
and commits them so what uh
so what a proposal does is it just
simply
send so if c wants to propose an update
they just simply send a new key for
their for the leaf here are martin blue
and when these proposals get committed
what happens is that
the ot gets substituted by the new one
and then all the other nodes in their
path get blanked
so now uh these new keys sampled by a
need to be encrypted individually to all
the leaves because all their inside
notes of the tree are blanked so of
course this tree is fairly small but in
general you can see that the
communication can be
can be degrade
all the way down to linear
so in particular we're back at this
trivial case of
of bi-directional channels that we
mentioned at the beginning which is what
we wanted to avoid
so if we want to
see look at this pictorially perhaps
to have a clear idea
playing tricking we could imagine it as
some long queue of users waiting to
update
whereas proposed commit would allow a
lot of users to do it all at once
at the cost of perhaps degrading the
or making it harder for future users to
update
um
the realization that we have in our
paper is that we can actually do better
if we don't require pcs to hold into
rounds but instead we relax it to
perhaps heal in a few more rounds
so let's talk about how concurrency is
handled in cocoa
so let's say here that two parties a and
c want to update concurrently
so they would propose updates just as
intricate so a would sample the new
seeds together with encryptions c in
blue would do the same
and now the question is how do we apply
them
so if this effect
so if if a node is affected by only one
update such as would be the case for for
this node for example we just apply them
as intrica
however
if an update up if a node is affected by
two updates like the node in the
intersection of of the two paths
then we would use some ordering to
choose which update takes precedence uh
so this ordering can be chosen arbitrary
can be chosen by the server it could
just be some fixed pre pre-agreed
ordering like right most user wins
and
we just have a new tree where we see
that the update from a didn't make it
all the way to the root but that's okay
uh what does this mean for for pcs so
let's take the same example where now a
and c are corrupted so here the the red
key signal rc
red signals the keys that the adversary
has knowledge of
and let's say they both update with the
same ordering as before
so what we can observe here is that as
before if a node has only been affected
by one update it will heal
but the node and the intersection will
get encrypted to an old key from the key
sorry the c that the intersection
will get encrypted to a null key from a
which is under the knowledge of the
adversary so in particular the bursary
can display the crypt learn the new seed
derive the new key and learn then two
new keys for those two red paths right
so even though both users updated there
are still some insecure keys but
nevertheless we made the update in
parties made some progress
and in particular if any of them do a
future update they will heal
so this sort of highlights the
difference between our protocol which
heals the tree layer by layer
as opposed to to trick and the plane
tricking we would just heal the tree
path by path
or propose and commit which would just
heal the tree all at once by just
flattening it
um
yeah sorry
so
of course we don't consider such simple
examples where the corruptions end at
the same time
but in general the the statement we get
very informally is if we consider a
group key k in some round
then we say that this key is secure if
the following is true for every user so
for each user we look at the last time
they were corrupted
and then we required the following
either the user performed a logarithmic
number of updates from the last time
this was this corruption hap finished
or they performed at least one but such
that no other user updated concurrently
to them
so if we again go back to our pictures
we could imagine a scoco as something
where the users do need to go through
more updating processes but they can do
it all at the same time and without
damaging any
structure
when it comes to efficiency
i have a table here with uh which
highlights some of the the points so
on the top we would just have plane
tricking which as i said is just
non-concurrent so we would just take
end rounds to heal so sorry here i
should say
i am
plotting the cost of healing uh an
arbitrary number of corruptions per user
and here we are assuming that there is
no knowledge of who is corrupted and no
coordination so in particular all users
will try to update since they don't know
whether they are corrupted
and also they cannot agree on on an
ordering
also for simplicity of course there are
no further corruptions or adds and
removes in between this process
uh so as i said that the top protocol
non-concurrent will just take in rounds
then we have three protocols so propose
commit the binge talk at all protocol
there's a typo should be tcc20
and bi-directional channels that all can
heal in two rounds
at the cost of linear communication per
user
and moreover they have the cost that
they destroy the tree structure to some
extent so subsequent updates per user
would cost either linear
or in the case of bing stock
linear in the worst case but logarithmic
on average
the trade-off that cocoa brings is
fairly obvious
so we can we take a few more rounds to
heal so logarithm n plus one
but on the upside the communication both
for senders and recipients is now
logarithmic square
and moreover the subsequent update cost
is still logarithmic
and one
particular thing to point out is that
we have logarithmic number of rounds we
have a linear number of users updating
in each round so we would expect the
recipient communication to be at least n
log n
right
however it's log n squared and this is
due to uh partial states which is the
the thing that i will talk about
now uh the observation here is that if
we keep if we want users to keep track
of the changes that happen in the whole
tree
then this incurs a download size in
which is linear in the number of
updaters
uh however uh
a in this case only needs uh the keys
for the green nodes which are the the
ones for which she knows the the secret
key of so she needs this for decryption
and she needs the public keys for the
for the purple notes because she needs
to encrypt these notes whenever she
sends a message
however she doesn't care about the black
keys about the keys for the black nodes
so what we have is we have the server
only relay packets for a
whenever these packets correspond to ads
or removes or correspond to update
information for the green or purple
nodes and all the packets that
correspond to black nodes
the server just does not relay so it
does not need to download those
this seems simple enough but it actually
poses a lot of challenges
which i'm not going to go into detail
here but just to give you a flavor of
the sort of things we need to solve
so one is consistency
intricate consistencies and shorts to
through mechanisms called transcriptase
and trihash these are both a hash of the
group history and some miracle
commitment to the tree
but of course as i just said in cocoa
the users nor know the full tree nor
know all the updates that take place
so we cannot no longer have a unified
definition of um where
users cannot agree on which
operations have taken place or how the
tree looks like so instead we rely on
the server to somehow complete the view
of the tree through some commitments to
subtrees
the second issue we run into is what it
means defining what it means for a user
to process an update and i'll motivate
this with an example
so let's say that b updates here in
green samples a new key
and a before updated login times or
rather ceiling of log n plus one so from
our predicate we would want corrupt we
would want um security
uh but the server is assumed to to be
malicious so what happens if the server
ignores a updates and never sends those
to b
is the key secure well of course not
because the new key sent by b is just
encrypted to the old key of a
right
so we need some notion of b processing
ace updates and this turns out to be
fairly non-trivial in the non in the
partial states regime
and as a last challenge
consider the case of removals so
as i mentioned before when when when a
user is removed blanks are created
and what this means is that if you
recall if a now wants to encrypt to this
note here she will not she cannot
because there's no key so she will need
to encrypt to these two notes
so a after e is removed a will need to
learn the public keys for those two
nodes
and the question is how does she do that
because of course by a synchronicity we
make we have no guarantee that any party
knowing them is online so the server
will need to send those public keys to
to a
but then a needs to actually guarantee
that these keys are correct and again
this also poses some challenges
so if you want to see how we solve all
this and how we prove it secure then i
invite you to read the paper
but in terms of security we prove coco
secure in the random oracle model
against an adaptive partially active
adversary and partially active here
means that they can control the server
but cannot impersonate users
our proof has a polynomial loss
and we've adapted proof of client at all
from s p 21 for tainted trichome
and just so to give you a summary so
i we in this paper we present coco a cdk
protocol that can recover from arbitrary
number of corruptions in a logarithmic
number of rounds
without degrading the efficiency
of subsequent updates and in doing so we
circumvent a lower bound by relaxing pcs
and we show that special estates are
possible and in particular that they
bring a great decrease in recipient
communication
and as uh open problems we would like to
better understand the trade-off between
communication costs and the number of
rounds that it takes to heal as well as
whether we can prove active security for
coco where we allow the adversary to
actually impersonate users
and just to give you a taste of some uh
related work that just came out
um called decaf for the centralizable
cdk with fast healing we actually
do a different uh consider a different
way in which you can merge concurrent
updates
and this allows us to heal in in long t
rounds at the cost of no not being able
to use partial states and with that i
will finish and i'll take any questions
thank you if there are any questions for
guillermo please come to one of these
two mics over there
can you scroll
down ah sorry
i'm sorry t is just the number of
corruptions
sorry
hi
any questions for guillermo
all right
all right so um
do you use the
random oracle um to make some adaptive
proof some programming possible or is
this just to simplify the proof
uh no
so
our proof needs a random oracle for
proving activity yes
thank you for your for your talk
i was wondering um
what kind of key agreement is used in
publicly available
messaging apps such as a signal for
example
and you have discussions with them so
they can adopt your solution in in their
app
um
so i think
uh most i think each app is different
but uh
so signal will actually use
bi-directional channels i believe
whereas whatsapp i think will use
something called center keys
um where the key for so for groups the
key is only rotated i believe when when
users are added and removed from the
group so you actually don't get as
strong pcs
um and no we have not talked to them but
the work we're doing is sort of
complementary to the mls which i guess
this is a standard by itf
which
hopefully would be the one that would
get adopted
right i'm not sure what their particular
views for example signal does care about
the ability which i'm not sure
uh is
totally compatible with with some of
these but you know
one last question maybe
very quick one
no everybody's happy okay let's thank uh
guillermo again
and the next presentation will be online
it's about efficient schemes for
committing authenticated encryption
by mihir belare and vietng wang
and viet tong should be online to give
the talk
let me share my screen