everybody hello everybody hello
everybody hello everybody um welcome to
um the first session um i hope you've
all recovered from whatever you did last
night and we're it's about zero
knowledge and we can have families of
smart friendly two chains of elliptic
curves um and the speaker's gonna be
joseph over to you
this
is um
is
um
it's non-interactive arguments of
knowledge so those are
so
proofs so so that so they are
uh
complete sound but only computational
computationally sound so with respect to
a computationally bounded prover and
they are non-interactive so there is no
interaction between the proven the
verifier throughout the protocol
and
its accent which informally puts means
that
approve is very short and easy to verify
[Applause]
so among those zk snacks so there are
pre-processing zk snacks for np language
so we will be proving statements about a
word belongs to our non-deterministic
polynomial language so just to put some
notations
so uh we have our np program f with
public input x and z a private input w
such as the relation is satisfied so z
equal to f of x and w
so slack is typically
consists typically in a three algorithms
so sits up so it takes the program f
some security parameter lambda and
output some key material so pk has
improving key and vk is in verification
so the proof algorithm takes
basically all the inputs so the public
input and the private input and pk which
encodes the program
to the approval
and output some proof here denoted pi
and
so the verification algorithm takes
basically all the public inputs and the
proof pi and outputs of body and whether
the proof is verified or not so the
setup can be done by anyone or in some
protocols which are trapdoored by a
trusted party or in a multi-party
computation way
the the proving algorithm is done by
what basically the one who knows the
secret w and the verifier anyone who has
access to this proof and the public
inputs
um
so we've been talking about zero
knowledge rules ck snacks as a subset
and pre-processing dk slacks and those
pre-processing zk slacks are best
instantiated with
pairings over added t-curves
so we need an electric curve so here
he's giving it's given in short fire
transform so defined over
a finite field of
prime characteristic or prime power so
it has a subgroup
of prime order r
[Music]
so r divides q plus one minus t so t is
the favorite trace and so for pairings
we need this
in between degree to be small enough so
the embedded degree k is like the
smallest integer such as r the sub order
divides q to the k minus one
and so billionaire appearing is this uh
billionaire map that goes from g1 cross
g2 to gt so g1 and g20 t
are groups
of order r
so g1 is the group of the so they find
the group of points on the elliptical
divided by the base field g2 over an
extension field and gt is a
is on an extension uh fq to the k so
it's afterwards of the article for of
unity and those three groups are
of the same order
so i will just give an example of one of
the pairing based
snacks that is widely used and
implemented nowadays so our relation is
z equal to f of x of w so x z and w here
i'm giving them in
vectors
so the setup uh so output these key
materials which are a bunch of elements
in these groups
in these pair angles g1 g2 and gt
the proven algorithm output are
three points on on the curve so on g1
and g2 so we see that they are constant
size with respect to some security
parameter lambda and what we are
interested in is the verification
algorithm so the verification algorithm
is where the pairing computation is
needed so to verify the proof it's boils
down to verifying this pairing product
check
which is up uh so a checkoff so we just
need to compute some pairings between
the proof element and the verification
element and this is basically how we
verify the proof so why we are talking
about this is because we need to do
so in this talk a recursive post that is
proof verifying other posts so there are
a bunch of applications for this one of
them is the proof aggregation because
we've seen here that
the proof is constant size so imagine
you have like a thousand of course and
if you do a proof of a thousand of
proofs then the resulting proof will be
constant size so you have like a single
constant size proof that verifies a
thousand of those there are other
applications for a
recursive pro such as
space on time complexity and we as we
will see in the next start by miguel
um
so what we want to do is
approve of above so
in pairing based snarks so our
np program f
uh so leaves uh so the computations are
performed in
fr without the subgroup order
of the elliptic curve
and the previous relevant is done in g1
and g2 in instance for gauss 16 which
are of order r but the verification
algorithm is a pairing computation which
takes place in a different field which
is uh so the gt target group or at least
the the extension field fp to the k so
if you want to create a proof that
verifies another proof then there is an
arithmetic mismatch the problem is
you need to express the parent
computation as an arithmetic circuit in
fr and the parent computation leaves in
fq what is fq to the k so one first
attempt would be to
have a curve
an elliptic curve that has q equal to r
but this is like the kind of curves that
we do not use in cryptography because
the discrete logarithm is working in
this case the second attempt would be
to simulate or to emulate the operations
f q in fr so q is now equal to r so r is
the sub order q is the field so the size
of the base field so this is
theoretically possible but it results in
a huge overhead
and the third attempt would be not to
use the same elliptic curves for the
proof and for the recursive proof but to
change the elliptic curves in order to
not have this arithmetic mismatch and
this is what we call chains or cycles of
elliptic curves
so just to to to to to to explain this
so we will have here are what's what i'm
calling a snark zero so it has a pairing
e so three goes g1 g2 and gt of order r
and then so we instantiate this with an
elliptic curve that we call an inner
curve
so e0 defined over fq of prime order r
and we need to have a second snack so
snack one that verifies apparent
computations that takes place in fq so
we will instantiate it with a different
electric curves so with a pair in e
where the the pairing groups are of
order q so this is the outside curve so
e1 defined over difference field fs but
it has a loader equal to the base field
or the previous one or at least that
divides
so so we can unload some some cofactor
so
if we make abstraction of these so given
some some integer q
we search for apparent friendly curve e1
of order h times q over any finite uh
field fs so this is uh
already known in the literature but
if we take a look back what we need
exactly for a slag is a curve that is
pairing friendly but there is a
condition for
efficient implementation which is r
minus one so the sub group order minus
one should be a highly to addict which
means should be divisible by a high
power of two
and this is for implementing efficient
fast fourier transform so because as i
told you the computations of the prover
take place in fr and it is basically
some polynomial arithmetic which are
best implemented using fast fourier
transforms and fast fourier transforms
are best implemented using radix two
ffts so we need the sub order minus one
to be highly to add
so this is just for slacks we can pick
any ellipticals from the literature that
is pairing friendly and we can
see if we can make the r minus one
highly to addict but if you want to do
two chains so
recursive two chains we can have we can
look at cycles which means basically two
electric curves for which the subgroup
order of one is equal to the finite
field or the other one and vice versa
but unfortunately we know only mnt for
mnt6 for these
cycles which are not quite efficient at
128 bit security because basically this
the impedance degree is 4.6 which is
small
but in our recursive snarks with two
chains
we can create we can construct these
ellipticals in a
sequential fashion so we start by
finding our first so the inner
elliptical which is which has to be
pairing friendly r
minus one to be highly to addict but
also q minus one the final the the base
field characteristic minus one because
this base field characteristic will be
the subgroup order of the next curve so
the next curve should be pairing
friendly and should have a sub order
precisely equal to the base field of the
previous one
um
so
so we know methods from the literature
in order to find an elliptic apparently
ellipticals with precisely uh with a
precise sub group order so for example
the quick speech method
so in order to find the performance
elliptical we need the base field to be
a prime our prime power the four minus
trace to be relatively prime to q so in
order to hold allow super singular
elliptic curves in this case uh the sub
order to be prime to divide q plus one
minus t
uh so this is the the order of the curve
and r divides q to the k minus one so
this is the embedding degree and the
complex multiplication equation should
be satisfies for
not some not too big discriminant in
order to find the coefficients of the
curve so here we just need to fix r
uh
so here first so the cox pinch method is
basically just
relies on the observation that t minus 1
is equal to q modulo r so we just need
to find the generator of z out of rz and
to raise it to r minus 1 out of q so
that it is a k root of unity
so there is like the translation mutatus
mutandes to this algorithm to the to the
polynomial domain
uh
so which is called so it is due to
brazing wang and independently also to
buy tolling and scots
and the ratio of
the sizes of the base field and the
suburb orders
is
is at least two in cox pinch but in
rising wing is smaller strictly than two
because uh we we reason about
degrees of polynomials
and also the polynomials here are
expressed so the the parameters of the
curves are expressed as polynomials
which help us
have faster implementations
so there are
a long line of research in order to
optimize perineum implementations when
when parameters are given in
in polynomials but the problem we have
here
so inverse negative method we just look
for a polynomial r of x but in our case
the polynomial of x is already fixed
because it is the polynomial p of x of
the previous curve of the inner curve so
we do not have any flexibility here and
in all the families we've looked at so
barito linscott or baretona or even kss
families
the resulting polynomial q of x so the
base field of the outer curve
is never irreducible which means that we
can never it can never output
polynomials so we were obliged to lift
the polynomial parameters of the curves
and here
basically the forbinos trace and the
the complex multiplication equations
with respect to this r in order to make
q
uh
a reducible polynomial that satisfies
the buniakovsky conjecture which means
that we can so this polynomial can
output
primes
so with in mind two applications which
are two kind of snacks one is gross 16
and one what i'm calling here is
universal kzg snacks so universal snacks
are instantiated in the piop model with
a polynomial commitment scheme and the
polynomial commitment scheme here i'm
taking the kcg polynomial scheme which
relies on parents so we have the same
mismatch arithmetic than in growth 16.
but
look at what we want so we want 128 bit
security for both we want the curve to
be the curves so the first one and the
second one will be pairing friendly but
here we're looking at the slug zero so
the first one
and we want efficient so for cos16 we
want efficient arithmetic over g1 g2
gt so all the three groups and the
pairing but for universal kzg snacks
such as if you want if you know plaque
or marlin or sonic
we do not need g2 arithmetic and we do
not need gt arithmetic we just need
efficient g1 arithmetic and efficient
pairings so we look for
two families of elliptic curves for
which we have these and we need p minus
one and r minus one both to be divisible
by a high power of two so we looked at
families from baritolin scott family of
course
of mbd degrees 12 and 24 and
the congregancy
that it needs to to to satisfy is just
the seed of the curve so the the value
on which the polynomials are evaluated
is congruent to one mode three times two
to the l and l here is your input is
this
the power of two you need
to divide the both p minus one and r
minus one but most interest and uh
so most interestingly is a
second curve so the slack one
uh
so we needed to be 128 bit secure
pairing friendly efficient arithmetic
for all the groups and the pairings and
ought to be equal to p so we looked at
blazing rank families and cox pinch
families and we have some result that
shows that you can have atomos k equal
to six so the mb degree
equal to sex
and
so we derived the formulas for
arithmetic over the three groups and the
novel
pairing computations for for this case
just in terms of the seed x and the
lifting cofactors h h t and h y so
whatever the curve you start with
the the outer curve will always have the
same formulas in terms of these
parameters which gives us
a family of uh
of two chains
uh in this sense
uh so we looked also at cox pinch uh
curve of embedding degree high of higher
mbd degrees so eight and twelve for more
conservative
security um
so uh we shortlist a bunch of curves of
two chains
uh that we spent to some form these
families and uh
so for ghost section we took so
our method uh rediscovers uh some old
curves proposed in the literature so
namely bls12 377 and bw6761
and for universal kzg
so we samples new curves based on the
bls 24 families and so the b sub bw6 so
we showed that bw6 is always faster than
cox pinch eight or cox pinch as well so
here i give the example of gross 16 and
universal kcg is
one of the versions of of planck so we
see that the prover only so the
computation of the approval only
takes place in g1 and the photo section
takes place also in g2
so the fv program which is the program
that verifies the the old snap which
basically verifies
the pairing computation so
i3 so snarks reason about arithmetic
circuits so the number of gates if we
want to
to translate or to port
state-of-the-art implementation of bls
12 curves into an arithmetic circuit it
results in 80 000 constraints or 80 000
gate multiplication gate and we were
able to reduce it to 19 000
and here are some benchmarks to for
so for those
shortlisted
shortlisted curves with respect to the
algorithm setup proof
and uh
and verify
um
so i don't think i don't know if i have
connection here
so um
no no it's not shut
so this is a playground so
that's uh so so we use the glark
ecosystem so an ecosystem already
for smart proofs so it's it's already
implement gross 16 and plonk and we
implemented all the curves we we
shortlisted into this ecosystem and here
there is a playground
that
creates a smart proof
uh in the in the browser so in web
assembly
so i have examples for so you you can
look at it
on your browser so it is played.gnar.i
so i have one of the examples to create
proof of proofs and basically you can
create a proof on the browser and you
can check the number of constraints and
it prints all the
so the arithmetic circuit in order to
verify a pair
um
so yeah so that's it so the pairing is
so the paper is on a print the
implementations are open sourced under
mit license so it is written in go we
have also implementation in stage math
and magma in order to verify uh the
formulas we propose in the paper so we
which are basically this novel pairing
computation
some tricks for
subgroup membership
on all the groups and there is a
follow-up work with the aurora and
iguania which is a survey of elliptical
support systems
and that's it for me
thank you
do we have do we have any questions
i've got i've got a question sure so
you've got uh two elliptic curves that
kind of related to each other um
have you thought
and you've got like a lot of constraints
in the system you know that's a really
match up so have you thought of actually
making one like a curve of genus two and
then like using the pairing on a curve
of genius too because that's going to
have a smaller field
it might be a bit more freedom i haven't
looked at the curves of genus too and so
so the pairings on curves on genius are
efficient enough
because that's i saw the idea down there
i mean no
idea because at the end of the day the
parent is
needed for the verification part which
should be success otherwise
any other questions
oh yeah can you yeah okay i'll run down
hold on
hi thanks for the talk uh you mentioned
proof systems like plonk which have uh
high touristy and lots of roots of unity
how much easier does it get to
come up with cycles and stuff would you
have had to do so much work if you
didn't need
all these roots of unity
uh so cycles if you do not need those of
unity they are trivial to find from
complex multiplication theory
so
if you do not if you do not know i'm
sorry if you need pairings then uh the
only cycles we know about are m t fund m
t cycles so it's the same problem so
maybe it will be just the the size so
for example in luna protocol it's just
seven seven hundred uh something bits uh
and for one twenty twenty eight bit of
security you need uh more than this you
need a thousand of bits so it will be
always the same problem if you need
pairing friendliness if you do not need
parent friendliness so if you for
example you use a halo where where to
use up polynomial commitment that
doesn't need bearings then cycles are
easy to find uh
okay no more questions well i thank the
speaker again thank you
[Applause]