so the last talk of this session is a a
complete characterization of game
theoretic for multi-party coin toss
regulator of elaine she and kevo and
this will be a recorded talk and k who
will give the talk
videos
hi everyone i'm cool from kanning malay
university i'll present our work a
complete characterization of game
theoretically fair multi-party coin
tasks
this is a joint work with gil ashara
from bar elon university in elinchi from
cmu
my advisor elaine and i
are two co-organizers of the cmu crypto
seminar and we need to decide the food
for the seminar
i prefer sushi while owling prefer cake
we cannot persuade each other so we
decide to toss a random coin
if the output is zero then i win and
we'll order sushi otherwise a ling wing
and we will order cake
since we're in different city this week
we decided to do bloms coin toss
protocol on blockchain
we each choose a random bit and post the
commitment of the random bid on the
blockchain
if you're not familiar with blockchain
you can think of it as a public bulletin
board so after we post the commitments
everyone can see them on the blockchain
after we both post the commitments we
each open our random bit and post the
opening on blockchain
let's say elaine's random bit is zero
and my random bit is one
the output will be the xor of these two
random bits which is one
so elaine wins and we will order cake
however i really want to eat sushi
after ellen post her bid on blockchain i
know that i'm gonna lose the game if i
open my bit
so what if i refuse to open my
commitments
in this case elaine just automatically
wins and the outcome would be won so
still we will order cake
this is the famous blomscoin host
protocol back to 1983.
it guarantees that a strategic player
like me cannot bias the output towards
my preference
formally in the coin toss protocol the
goal is to output a random coin that is
publicly verifiable
the correctness requires that um if
everyone is honest
then the output should be uniformly
random
the fairness notion considered in
traditional literature
is called strong fairness or
unbiasability
which requires that a strategic player
cannot bias the outputs towards either
direction
unfortunately
this is shown to be impossible by cleve
in 1986.
indeed even in bloom's coin toss
protocol we just saw i can always bias
the output towards one
by refusing to open the commitment
the fairness notion achieved by blum's
coin hospital is actually more of a game
theory favor
for game theoretic fairness
it requires that a strategic player
cannot benefit herself by deviating from
the protocol
now that we've seen bloom's coin host
protocol which achieves game theoretic
fairness for two party coin tasks
a natural question to ask is that can we
achieve game theoretic fairness for
multi-party coin tasks
in multi-party coin toss several players
get together to toss a binary coin
each player has a preference that is
publicly available
let's say uh for example kittens and i
prefer sushi and we call them sushi
people
while puppies in elaine prefer cake so
we call them cake people
some of these players will get together
to form a coalition
they will coordinate with each other and
try to bias the output to increase their
utility
the utility we consider is quite natural
if i like the output i gain utility one
and the utility of a collision is just
the sum of the utility of the players in
this collision
for example if the output is cake then
this collision in the figure means
utility 3
and if the output is sushi then this
coalition gain utility 2.
therefore the preference of a coalition
is actually the preference of majority
players in this coalition
now for maori party coin toss the game
theoretic fairness notion we consider is
slightly different
now we care more about the behavior of a
coalition rather than a strategic player
for multi-party coin toss game theoretic
fairness requires that a collision
cannot increase its expected utility by
deviating from the protocol
so if a coin-host protocol is game
theoretic fair against coalition of size
t
then the honest protocol is actually a
t-sized coalition-resistant nash
equilibrium because this best strategy
for the collision is just to follow the
protocol honestly
so why do we care about this game
theoretic fairness
because we know that strong fairness is
impossible against half-sized coalition
however in many decentralized
applications for example
voting on a blockchain
many pseudonyms may be controlled by the
same entity and these pseudonyms they
will coordinate together and they may
deviate from the protocol to gain
benefit
it is very likely that these pseudonyms
form a majority-sized coalition so we do
need some meaningful fairness notion
that is achievable against a
majority-sized coalition
game theoretic fairness is exactly such
a notion that is slightly weaker than
strong fairness yet still meaningful and
suitable for decentralized applications
um
unfortunately game theoretic fairness
for a multi-party coin task protocol is
shown to be impossible against a minus
one-sized coalition due to cleves result
uh due to chain at all sorry uh
adults result back to 1918.
so a natural question to ask
is that can we achieve game theoretic
fairness for multi-party coin toss
against small sized coalition
let's say majority size but not
necessarily a minus one
and the answer is yes
to convince you i'll first show you a
very simple strumming solution for four
players let's say we have two sushi
people and two cake people
in the straw man solution each group
first arbitrarily choose a
representative let's say it's the kitten
and the puppy
then these two representatives do with
each other using blum's coin host
protocol
the output of this blums called protocol
will be the coin for four-party coin
tasks
so this very simple protocol is getting
theoretically fair against coalition of
size 2.
note that if the coalition contains one
sushi person and one cake person
then this coalition actually has no
preference and they can never increase
their expected utility so we don't care
what they do to the coin
if the coalition contains two sushi
people
then by bombs coin toss protocol
the sushi representative cannot bias the
output what sushi
and so this coalition cannot benefit by
deviating from the protocol
the same argument works for the case if
the coalition continues to kick people
so we can achieve game theoretic
fairness for four-party coin toss
against coalition of size two
this isn't evidence that it is true
that we can achieve game theoretic
fairness for some meaningful parameter
region
actually this very simple german idea
generalizes to any number of players as
long as the coalition is outside at
those two
so on the achievability side for a
collision of size less than half
we can achieve strong fairness
and of course game theoretic variants
through multi-party computation
if the collision is of size smaller than
then we can use this drawing solution
on the impossibility side
turn at all showed that it is impossible
to achieve game theoretic fairness
against a minus one sized collision
so
we ask the question under what size of
coalition
is it possible to achieve game theoretic
fairness
exactly where should we draw the line
the boundary between feasibility and
invisibility
this work answers this question
we explored the broad range of
parameters of collision size between
half and n minus one
so in this work we give a complete
characterization of game theoretic
fairness
we give a
construction of a game theoretic fair
coin toss protocol against team-sized
coalition
and we show that game theoretic fairness
as impossible against t plus one size
coalition
um i'll give the expression of t to you
later
so
in the rest of the talk we will mainly
focus on the construction of the
protocol
still to convey the main idea we will
use a simple example of six players
three sushi people and three cake people
the structure is quite simple we let the
sushi people choose a random going as
zero
and then we let the cake people choose a
random point s1
the output will just be the xor of these
two random bits
but where do the random coin s0 and s1
come from
so for easier understanding we assume a
secret sharing trusted authority
parameterized with k
that choose a random queen s for us
and satisfy the following properties
first only k or more players can ask the
authority to reveal the value of s
and second any k or more players can
choose to rewrite the value of s before
any reveal request
as a heads-up this trusted authority can
be implemented by standard crypto
and we do not need to assume trusted
authority in our final protocol
so this trusted authority is just um for
better understanding during the talk
with this trusted authority our protocol
works as follows
first each group has a trusted authority
with parameter case set to be two
the sushi authority first choose a
random queen at zero
and then if and then if the collision
wants to rewrite the value of coin at
zero it has to be now
then the cake authority choose a random
coin s1
still if the coalition wants to rewrite
the value of s1 it has to be at this
point
no rewrite is allowed after
then sushi people sends reveal requests
to the trusted authority to reveal the
value of s0 on blockchain
then the kick people send reveal
requests to kick authority to reveal the
value of s1 on blockchain
if both coin revealed successfully the
output is the xor of these two random
coins
however if s0 is not revealed because
two or more sushi people refuse to
reveal
but coin s1 is successfully revealed on
the blockchain then in this case the
output of the protocol is just the coin
s1
on the other hand if the coin s0 is
revealed but s1 is not revealed what
should we output
should we output s0
so definitely not
we should output 0 instead of s0
this is because by the time when the
sushi people decides whether they want
to reveal s1 they already see the value
of s0 on the blockchain
so
even if a collision of only two cake
people
they can bias the output by deciding
whether they want to reveal the coin s1
after they saw the value of s0 on the
blockchain
this means that if we choose to output
s0 if s1 fails to be revealed then we
will only be able to tolerate collision
of size 1.
so instead we will output 0 as a heavier
punishment for the kick people if they
refuse to reveal the value of s1
so this six player coin toss protocol
actually achieves game theoretic
fairness against coalition of size up to
four
to see this
if this collision contains two sushi
people and two cake people
they actually have no preference
and they can never in because they can
never increase their utilities so we
don't care what they do to the coin
if the collision contains three sushi
people and a single kick person
then this coalition can decide the value
of estero because they can rewrite the
coin
however as we mentioned when they
rewrite the coin s0 they know nothing
about s1
so the coin s1 is still an independent
uniformly random coin chosen by the cake
authority
that is guaranteed to be revealed due to
the two honest cake people so if the
coalition choose to reveal coin as 0
then the output should be serial xor
with s1
if we choose not to reveal s0
at the time when they decide whether
they want to choose uh reveal s0 they
know nothing about coin s1
so the output is an independent
uniformly random point s1 shown by the
cake authority
on the other hand if the coalition
contains three cake people and a single
social person
by a similar argument
they can control the value of point s1
at the time when they know nothing about
s0
so if they choose to reveal s1 the
output would be s0 xor with s1 which is
uniformly random
if they choose not to reveal s1
then the output will directly be zero
i believe smart as they are they will
never do this because this brings them
no benefit
so
this protocol is game theoretically fair
against coalition of size 4.
can we generalize it
and the answer is positive
this idea actually generalizes to
arbitrary number of players
and this table gives the maximum size of
the coalition we can tolerate with this
protocol
in this table m1 is the number of kick
people and n0 is the number of sushi
people
for simplicity i ignored the ronnie here
and without loss of generality we assume
n1 is at least n zero
and this is the landscape of the
achievability and ancient ability of
game theoretic fairness
it turns out that the landscape of game
theoretic fairness is darkly different
from the de facto strong fairness
in this plot the x-axis denotes the
number of sushi people in the y-axis
denotes the number of kick people
the z-axis here is the size of the
coalition
this red plane is the boundary between
visibility and invisibility of game
theoretic fairness
for any region below this red plane we
can achieve game theoretic fairness
and for any region above we cannot
as a comparison this blue plane is the
boundary of invisibility and visibility
for strong fairness which is exactly
half
of the number of players
from this figure we can see that there
is indeed a meaningful region
for which we can achieve game theoretic
fairness but not strong fairness
and moreover we can see that
the achievability of game theoretic
fairness is not only related to the size
of the coalition but also the
relationship between the number of sushi
people and the number of cake people
to wrap up in this work we give a game
theoretically fair coin toss protocol
against his science coalition and we
show that game theoretic fairness is
impossible against any t plus one sized
coalition
and t is summarizing the table below
here n1 is the number of cake people and
n0 is the number of sushi people
when m1 is much larger than n zero then
we can tolerate coalition of size up to
a one minus half and zero
moreover if m one equal to n zero and
they're equal to odd then we can
tolerate n zero plus one sized
coefficient as in the six clear example
we just saw
otherwise we can tolerate a coalition of
size up to two-thirds and one plus
one-third and zero
in the work
we also give other results we give a
complete characterization of another
fairness notion which requires that no
coalition can harm any honest individual
we also give complete characterization
of these two fairness notion on their
other natural utility functions
and this is the reference for the paper
mentioning the talk
and thank you if you're interested in
more details of the paper you can read
our paper which is posted on eprine or
write me email
that's my talk thank you so much
i believe that gilad should be available
for questioning the questions
yes i'm here if you have any questions
glad
can you say when the game theoretic
scenario is uh
reasonable
when people have to declare in advance
what's your preferences
um so we give few examples where this is
uh
this is maybe reasonable
i agree that it's also interesting to
discuss the case where um
you don't know the preferences in
advance
one example that we gave is like let's
say we do some voting or like we need to
cause uh
just a coin
uh well we do know the preferences of
each other let's say we need to decide
what is
how to um
in in some
in some
let's say uh we want to do
um
we have two possible candidates and we
want that the candidate that is closer
to my geographically um
that's closer to me geographically will
be the the winner
then because you know where i'm located
you know who i prefer
or if you have like uh
you want to fund two candidates and you
know we have like a public forum where
you can actually
can estimate what is the the preference
of each one of the
participants
but in that case it is
a question like would you actually toss
a coin or just run majority vote
but yeah this is a natural question i
think
any other questions hello
hello um i want to ask if this easily
generalizes to like um dice rolling or
like more than more dice rolling not not
only two outputs but like more i don't
know
oh we did think about in the beginning
we had some initial results um
it is quite similar to the
to the normal to the regular like
generalization of
from two to from uh
from a coin to like uh
more than just two results
um
but i think the characterization will be
completely different so
it is a good question to explore
okay thank you
if there are no
other questions so let's say speak again
at the speaker of the session
thank you