okay so now last stock in this session
is refined cryptanalysis of gprs ciphers
ga1 and gea2 by itai denude and daw anja
lake and i will present this paper
okay thank you
very much for the introduction i hope
that you can hear me well
so uh
this talk is about the g
ge a1 and ga2 ciphers
uh that were used in the gprs so uh gprs
is a
mobile data standard was used to encrypt
data
it was widely deployed in the early
2000s
and the encryption was used to protect
against ease dropping
on
the communication
and uh initially uh
gprs used the two proprietary stream
ciphers named ga1 and ga2
now at the last year at eurocrat a very
nice paper by eight authors that are uh
given here
so it presented the the first public
analysis of the cyphers ga1 and ga2 and
in fact this paper actually uh
first disclosed the specification
of this items
so i'm going to call this paper in short
bdl from now on
so uh
ga1 and ga2 both have a 64 bit session
keys
nevertheless
the
previous euro curved paper
described the weakness that allows to
recover the session key of the gea 1 and
time complexity only 2 to the 40 given
roughly 44 gigabytes of memory
now the attack only required
65 bits of known key stream that
can typically be obtained just by
knowing some fixed headers so that
actually is kind of practical
um it's really practical it was actually
implemented and
however it requires kind of a large
amount of them
so uh
the attack is based on the weakness uh
that
was believed is believed to be
intentional and the weakness is probably
due to some export regulations that were
in place at the time that the cipher was
designed
now the
use of ga1 was already uh prohibited
back in 2013
but kind of surprisingly uh video
noticed that the
modern mobile phones still supported the
cypher ga1 and this could
could actually lead to some downgrade
attacks uh
so it could uh
um have an actual uh impact in practice
uh but this defect is uh is now uh
supposedly uh fixed
uh by some removing actually verifying
that the gaa 1 is no longer supported
now for ga2
so gi2 does not have a as far as we know
a significant weakness as a
ga1
however
the
others still describe an attack on a
cipher with time complexity uh 2 to the
but the main
kind of
practical obstacle in this attack is
that
it requires uh
800 key stream bets uh the knowledge of
them in order to uh that are used to
encrypt the full gpr's rs prime
so this attack is kind of uh this kind
of limits the practical the practicality
uh of of this attack
and therefore uh
the previous paper also presented the
data time tradeoff that
beats exhausted search but only given at
least a thousand uh 400
bits of known
keyswing
okay so that was the previous paper now
now let's uh let's move
uh to our results
so basically what we do in the in the
paper is uh describe improved and
refined attacks compared to the previous
eurocrat paper
so for ga1 we reduced the memory
complexity uh by a factor of roughly
eight thousand a bit far from 44
gigabytes to about four megabytes
while the time complexity remains about
2 to the 40.
so we implemented the attack and the
attack runs on a standard laptop in
roughly two and a half hours
on the other hand the
previous paper uh previous authors ran
one of the attack on the cluster
probably due to the high memory
complexity it's not trivial to implement
this on the standard laptop the previous
attack of things
so uh before moving on to ga2 i want to
just stress the motivation in improving
this attack so in the early 2000s uh
high memory complexity such as the
previous attack was actually not
obvious to implement
especially if you want to uh
to run this attack uh you know
is dropping to multiple sessions and you
want to uh implement this attack at
scale so it's not obvious how to do it i
mean it's not obvious you need a lot of
resources to do it with a lot of memory
um
and another uh motivation and i should
say this is a general motivation for
this workers to better understand the
security of ciphers that were at least
once uh widely uh used
okay so that's for ga1 um and for gia ii
uh we actually present two attacks so in
the stock i'll only focus on uh just one
attack
uh the first attack so uh we improve the
data time trade-offs and presented in
previous papers but
the improvement is only up to uh seven
given seven thousand bits of uh
uh consecutive key swing that's what we
assume about the type of complexity
and uh
the techniques that we use uh as we will
see as uh is are borrowed from uh
techniques for solving uh cakes or
problems
okay so first uh i'll focus on the ga1
attack
uh
but before describing the attack then
let's see how the cyphers actually works
so um i'll start by describing the
initialization process so this process
takes as input 64-bit session key and
32-bit iv
and
first this these inputs are used to
compute a 64-bit scene it's not very
important how it's done
and then in the second step of the
initialization the seed is used to
initialize the 96-bit
initial state
of ga1 which is composed of three lfsrs
a b and c of uh sizes 31 32 and 33 bits
okay as you can see here
and the the snapping from the seed to a
96-bit state is
we will denote it by m and
it should be mentioned i will mention
that m is is actually a linear function
okay so that's the initialization
and after the initialization the cipher
is uh is ready to produce a keyframe or
to encrypt so how do we do this um so um
before i actually describe to you how to
do this then let's uh fix some notation
so uh so given some internal state
a of this first
lfsr
um i'm going to denote f a applied to
this internal state uh indexed by by an
integer tau it's going to be uh just the
function that computes the next tao
output that's from the
internal state
a underscore
and how is it it is done basically we
have a tau uh iterations and in each
iteration we apply some function output
function to the
internal state it's not very important
what is this function it just produces
the next output bit then we clock the
lfsr to uh
it will take the next
uh internal state and we have 12 of
these integrations that produce the tau
output bits
okay so now let's understand how the key
stream is generated so basically um the
inputs to the keystream generation are
the 96th
bit of the
initial state abc and a 12 800 bit
packet which we denote by p
and uh basically what we do is uh just
uh produced uh 12 800 uh
bits of keystream just by storing the
outputs of these three registers and the
ciphertext is just the xor of the key
string with the plaintiffs
okay of course you do this bit by bit
but in general it doesn't really matter
you produce case frame and then you
store it with the plain text to uh
output
the ciphertext
okay so now that we understand how the
ga1
works uh let's uh let's understand let's
think about how to break it
so uh the attacker what we assume is
that
the attacker obtained 65 bits of uh
known key stream which were
denoted by uh
by zed
for some packet
so how do we obtain this actually this
key stream in practice what we need to
do is to actually ease drop to get the
cipher text
okay it is up to the communication and
we also need to assume that we know the
corresponding plain text that was used
in the encryption and and
65 bits of keystream uh is not uh
typically difficult to uh
to get to actually guess or no because
uh you can guess it from some known and
fixed headers
okay and then uh the key stream is just
the sort of the plaintext and the
ciphertext
okay so uh we assume that we have the 65
bit the key stream uh and now the the
goal of the attacker is to run some
state recovery attack and to recover the
initial state abc of the registers
and now given the initial state the
attacker can actually invert the
initialization process of
of ga1 and obtain the seed
used to produce the states and and from
this it can actually
go backwards and obtain the session key
i'm not going to describe how to do this
this is actually described in the video
paper but it's kind of simple
okay and given the session key you can
actually uh
by continuing to is drop you can
actually decrypt the full gpr session so
you have all the communication
so now the goal is basically uh to uh
right to focus here on the on this how
how do we recover the initial state
given the history
let's uh see how to do this
uh and before we see that let's describe
the the actual weakness that was used to
uh
that was uh described in this video
paper
so uh the weakness is actually a
weakness in the initialization process
of uh
ga1 uh in the second step of this in the
initialization step that maps the 64
bits into a 96
bit state by this uh this mapping n
and uh
specifically let's focus on the internal
states of a and c so it turns out that
the joint internal states of a and c
which are 64 bits they can actually
assume or obtain only 2 to the 40
values out of the 2 to the 64 possible
values
okay so uh that's kind of uh interesting
um
and equivalently this means that the
dimension of the image of this mapping m
this linear mapping
when
projected to the registers a and c is
only 40 out of 64
which
can be radically
okay now given this let's see how to uh
to break the cipher uh
more efficiently than
just exhaustive search
so uh in the attack what we do is we
search for internal states a b and c
that actually produce the given key
screen set
as in this equation
and in order to do this we will split
that up into the equation into two parts
uh so the right part uh only contains
the internal states b and the left part
only contain internal states f a and c
so how does the attack work we first
focus on the right hand side here and
what we're going to do is we're going to
build the table which we call tb for the
function fb
and it's done as follows so for each
value of the internal state b so we have
2 to 32 such values we're going to
produce output 65 bits of output and
we're going to store all the
uh all the states and the the outputs
and some table which we'll denote by tb
and it's a of size 2 to the 32. okay
that's the right hand side and that's we
focus on the
left-hand side so for each a and c and
the image
of m projected to a and c we know that
we have only 2 to the 40 such
joint states uh then we compute the
left-hand side here and we search it in
the table tb that we prepared for the
right-hand side
okay and uh basically each match gives
you a candidate for the internal state
and uh because we are using 64 five bits
here then essentially you can do some
calculation and show that we expect to
actually only output the right internal
states if this if everything is done
correctly
okay so um the complexity of this attack
is basically dominated by uh the
this uh second step because we only have
two to the 40 uh joint ac states
in the image
and the memory complexity is dominated
by the stable tb
which is of size to the 32 words or if
you do the calculations 44 gigabytes
now the goal of course our goal in the
in the paper is actually to reduce the
space uh to roughly 2 to the 19 words or
4 megabytes so how do we do this
so here's an additional observation it
was actually already made in the
previous paper um
so
let's look at the dimension of m
of this lithium mapping of course it
maps a 64-bit uh
seed so it's it's only 64.
and on the other hand let's look at
let's look at the dimension of the image
of m projected to ac which it's 40 the
dimension of the image of m projected to
be it's 32 so they sum up to 72. so you
can see that there is a gap here of
eight and this gap basically means that
there is a shared subspace between uh
kind of between
this and this subspace both these images
of dimension
minus 64 which is a
okay and uh using this kind of shared
subspace you can actually uh decompose
the images of m a b and
m ac and to this search uh subspace uh
let's call it ub
projected i mean this church sub space
projected to be x or some
direct sum with some
other subspace of small dimensions
dimension only 24. okay and you can do a
similar thing uh for uh
mac okay yeah you can decompose it
similarly
and uh
we're going to exploit this uh actually
to reduce the memory it was exposed
previously in order to obtain more
filtering condition for the attack but
here we use a relatively standard trick
to reduce the memory complexity of data
so how does it work
basically
we have this
subspace and in general if there is a
common part between the two sides of the
mid in the middle attack which is
basically the
subspace then it can be used to
partition the large beat in the middle
attack and do smaller attacks
each of these
smaller
attacks require smaller memory because
we kind of
can reuse the memory for each attack
so let's see how this is done
so specifically
we have we'll have an outer loop that
iterates over all uh
elements of the shared subspace
and now for the first part of the attack
so
so instead of just uh iterating over all
these we it need to iterate now given
the seal we need to only iterate over
the remaining uh elements of e1 and
there are only two to the 24
and uh for each one of them we compute
the internal state according to kind of
this equation
of b and then we
compute the output and we store it in
table t b of course it's a smaller table
because we're only iterating of the this
p1 space so the table is only offside 2
to the 24 for each
iteration
and uh similarly we do the same thing
for the second
part of the attack we need to iterate
only over this v2 space compute the
joint ac
state uh
compute the left hand side of the
equation search it in tb and so forth
okay so that's basically how the
uh how the
the attack works
and uh the complexity here well the time
complexity remains the same uh we didn't
do anything uh too special to optimize
time complexity however the space
complexity is reduced to 2 to the 24.
just because uh the smaller tables tb
here uh
only require two to the 24
uh
words which is the basically the
dimension of uh v1
okay so the memory complexity is now
reduced to 12 to 1
56 megabyte roughly however if we
remember correctly we want to reduce it
to 4 megabytes so we're still missing
something
okay so how can we reduce the memory
further
and the main observation here is to
notice that the steps if you look at
this attack the steps are actually not
balanced
um the first step it requires relatively
small amount of time but a large amount
of memory to build this table tb
and the second
step requires a relatively large amount
of the time but the smaller amount of
space so we can try to kind of balance
the
the steps of the attack
and the idea is to use a technique
called clamping through pre-computation
that is a
[Music]
typically used to
solve to solve in
to solve the cake store problem
the general idea is as follows we're
going to add an additional condition to
this loop okay so let's assume that we
just fix some five-bit string uh let's
call it t just five bits it's just a
magical parameter here
um so we'll have uh more loops here but
uh
um for each uh for each loop what we do
is we're going to store
um we're going to store
fb we're going to store this internal
state only if it produces this uh speci
the special output prefix
so we add another condition another five
bit condition
and uh because that's uh because of this
we're actually uh right storing less uh
less elements in the table by a factor
of two to the five so the tables will be
smaller that kind of makes sense
okay and this is basically how the
attack works so we add this condition we
of course need to iterate over all the
overall output prefixes and now we uh
we're storing in the table only uh kind
of uh output prefixes that uh
uh only sorry internal states that
actually uh uh produce this output
prefix
okay so uh
the space is indeed in uh reduced like
what we want to uh four megabytes okay
that kind of makes sense
um so that that works we did reduce the
space
unfortunately we did not optimize the
second step so the second step was the
bottleneck in times of time complexity
and we did not optimize it and therefore
because we have more uh loops here we
have 32 uh
factor we increase the number of loops
by a factor of uh 32 or two to the five
that overall time complexity will be
increased from 2 to the 42 to the 45. so
we kind of have to uh
optimize the second step in order to uh
to actually uh reduce the time
complexity back to 2 to the 40.
now it's not trivial how to do this uh
actually if you kind of try to look into
the details it's it's actually not
obvious uh if you can that you can do
this at all
it turns out that you can do this uh you
can implement this step in the second
step in reducing complexity so i'm not
going to describe to you how to do this
the details are in the paper but i will
mention the main observation uh used to
reduce the time complexity the main
observation
is that is that the output function of a
restricted to uh to five bits it only
depends on 26 bits out of the
31 of the
of the internal state a okay and then we
have a similar like a slow diffusion
property for c and you can use this
properties actually to optimize this
second step so the details are a bit too
technical to describe in this stuff but
uh please look at the paper uh to uh to
understand better
so this uh will give us the tongue
complexity the 2 to the 40 and the space
complexity is like now really small four
megabytes so it actually fits into cash
okay so that's uh the details about the
ga1 attack
let's uh move
quickly to the ga2 attack and then i'll
conclude
so uh
recall that ga2 does not have a
significant weakness as the ga1 but the
previous paper still described an attack
on it with that
um and the attack is it's faster than uh
the
exhaustive search only from kind of uh
one thousand four hundred uh swim bits
so this is kind of the data time
trade-off and that that only bits uh
exhaustive search kind of from this
point
moving to the right
so we describe a different attack that
improves the previous attack uh given
the
assuming that we have less
peaceful bets at most uh 7000 so you can
uh imagine that this uh
i mean it's probably easier to obtain a
limit more limited attack amount of data
so in some sense it's
it's uh
you can say it's more practical for this
this region of
data
and you can see the
kind of the points that we get here
so specifically if we can focus on this
point here so uh given uh 1 and 100 bits
of available e3 and the time complexity
that we get is 2 to the 54. whereas
previously the
best known attack was the exhaustive
search of 2 to the 6 t4 so we improved
it by a factor 2 to the 10.
so i should mention that this attack is
actually a generic attack it applies to
all the screen cycle combiners
as
we will
see shortly
okay so that's an overview of the attack
now let's say i won't go into many
details in this attack but let's uh kind
of see how flavor how it works so i'll
begin by describing the structure of the
ga2 ciphers cipher
so uh during an initialization a 64-bit
session key
and
32-bit ib as in
ga1
uh there are the inputs but now they are
mapped into a larger state a b c d with
four registers
uh so we have an additional register d
of uh of size at 29 bits and this gives
a total size of the internal state of
125 bits
and not 96 bits like in gaa1
okay so the details of the energy
initial ascension are actually not
important for this attack
okay and the key swim is basically
generated in a similar way to gaa1 just
that we need to sort the outputs of four
registers instead of
basically everything remains similar
okay so now moving on to the attack so
we
assume for simplicity uh that the length
of all registers is 32 bits they're kind
of close to that but let's assume that
they're over 32 bits for simplicity
now the attack is going to recover the
initial states given uh the initial
state given l uh known keystrom bits
uh so like in the case of ga1 from this
initial state you can actually compute
the session key and uh and decrypt the
entire gprs session so again the focus
here is on state recovery
okay so let's first assume that we're
given uh
just 128
output bits of the cycle
okay so we assume you're given zed this
is the key stream of uh
length 128
and again we're
fine to mental state recovery attack so
we're looking for internal state abcd
such that uh that produces this uh
k string z
and once again we can split this
equation into two parts a part that
involves only n b and this the right
part involves only c and d
and because uh kind of each part has 2
to the 64 state then a standard tweet in
the middle attack
will give you time complexity 2 to the
64 and space complexity also to the 64.
okay
now we can actually improve the memory
complexity based on the classical chapel
and chamier algorithm for subsystem
subset sum
so um
the idea
is as follows so
first if
if this equation holds for states a b c
and d
then uh once again we kind of partition
it into two parts but the idea is now to
enumerate over uh 32-bit values t of
each side of the equation kind of
independently and this allows us to
spread the forks or problem here into
two took store problems and each one
will be solved using a meat in the
middle attack but it will operate on a
smaller
table
okay so specifically let's fix some
32-bit value here once again 32
bits is is kind of a magical parameter
here used to optimize the complexity
okay so let's take some uh 32-bit value
here for each side and then what we'll
do by a meter in battle attack so we can
compute all internal states a and b that
uh actually satisfy this left hand side
and we'll store all these internal
states and table tab and if you do the
calculation the size of the table will
be 2 to the 32.
okay so that's the left-hand side here
and the right-hand side you do a similar
thing okay you compute all cd states
that satisfy the right hand side and
store them in a table uh tcd
and then you merge these two
two tables according to the full
equation here okay on the full
whole number of
okay so that that's basically the attack
and if you do the analysis then the
sizes of tib and tcd are each 2 to the
32 so the space complexity is indeed 2
to the 32 because we're reusing the
space across iterations and the time
complexity we have the 232 iterations
each one of them takes two to the 32
times so the time complexity cube
remains 2 to the 64 as in the previous
second
okay but remember that our goal is
actually to improve the time complexity
and uh using more
uh
larger uh keystream let's see how to do
this
um so we have an attack with the
128 bits of key string with time
complexity two to the 64.
so how can you optimize it given the
larger amount of keystream
so the idea is to kind of artificially
create multiple solutions for
uh the attack for the for
uh
that
that actually solved the problem so what
is the solution here what what are we
searching for we're uh we're looking for
an internal state abcd
at some uh and the the thing is is that
uh
um we don't actually need to recover the
only the internal state we can actually
recover some internal state at some
clock c so if we kind of try to focus to
recover one some internal state that is
used in the computation of the key
stream then
then we can we may have multiple
solutions
uh that we can work with
and once we recover one of them then the
attack will actually work okay so assume
that we actually can do this that we can
actually uh you know uh
obtain some for in some way multiple
solutions then we can actually mount a
more efficient
more efficient attack and how this is
done
so if we look back at the previous
attack so now assume that there are
actually
uh r solutions meaning our good a b c d
states that actually uh produce
uh there are actually solutions to this
problem so assuming that we have our
solutions meaning that we have basically
our good values of t
so we actually need to iterate uh only
uh over roughly 2 to the 32 divided by
our values of t because uh we we just
need to find one out of our solutions so
on average we need to iterate only to
the 32 divided by r varies of t
and then the complexity of the attack
drops by a factor of r so it will become
to the 32 divided by r
okay and this of course assuming assume
that we can actually obtain this magic
solutions
our solutions so how can we actually do
this so how do we how can we produce our
solutions or target states so given a
longer key string the main idea so i'm
not going to describe this in detail you
can look into the paper but the main
idea is to actually look at shifted key
strings uh that uh so we have a long
piece frame and we can kind of uh look
at the
key string that starts from the first
bit the key string that starts from the
second bit and so forth and
and if we have a l uh
that instrument that we actually have uh
roughly oh it's it's not really l it's a
bit smaller but roughly l shifted each
being produced by l internal states okay
and this gives us actually the the
solutions the multiple solutions that we
need for the attack again this uh the
details are described in the paper
okay and uh one last thing that i want
to mention before i conclude this that
the attack is actually generic uh it
does not actually uh use any of the
properties of the
internal
stream cycles that are stored together
i mean it can be applied also to if you
change the
output functions of the stream ciphers
arbitrarily as long as you stored their
outputs together so it the attack is
actually generic and it's applicable to
all uh source screen cycle combiners
okay so uh finally let me conclude so
where i destroy the improved and refined
attacks uh on the cyphers ga1 and ga2
the techniques that we use are based on
on the new applications of cakes or
algorithms to stream cipher
cryptanalysis
and in particular the attack on ga2 is a
generic attack that's applicable to all
uh
sword combiners of uh
four stream setters
and finally i think the main open
problem here is that uh is uh we want
what
we would really like to have as a
is to
uh to have a really uh efficient attack
for ga2 given a
low amount of data and i i think maybe
uh yeah if you can optimize uh our
attack third or maybe exploiting the
structure of the
internal structure of the stream cipher
uh
then it would be i think
really interesting
okay so basically that uh that concludes
my talk thank you very much
[Applause]
question
comments
hello uh hi thank you very much for the
talk um i wanted to know is that the ga2
attack is generic was it so is this in
contrast to the bdl work or was it
already generic there no no the bdr
attack actually exploited the low
algebraic degree of the output functions
of the cipher
so that they did i mean they exploited
the fact that it's an lfsr and the
output function is
the filter function is of algebraic
degree four
so if you kind of change it to a
nonlinear uh say
feedback
shift register then this attack will now
no longer work but our attack will work
okay thank you very much
no problem
so this is on yes
um when you show the attack on ga2 right
you you sort of searched over the a b
registers and the cd
individually do you think it would be
possible to
exploit the inherent weakness between
the the a and c registers right that
only can take two to forty states
in the ga1
yeah well could you reuse the because
the weakness from da1 is also inherent
in ga2 right no that's uh it's not so i
uh i try to
i mentioned this uh
here maybe
i did it quickly but uh yeah you
yeah because the a and c registers are
the same there
no no but the initials by the initials
they
the weakness is in the initialization
it's not in the actual registers
so the witness is in the mapping
that takes a seed and maps it to an
internal state and this mapping is
different for ga2 so
uh the weakness that's present in ga1
does not uh actually yeah right okay
okay thank you weakness wasn't this
initialization and the initialization of
the ga2 is is different from the one of
ga1 so
it does not have the same weakness
yeah so it does not depend on the tap
positions of a anc there
yeah okay good thanks no it does depend
but it's different i mean it's not it's
not the same uh it's not it's not the
same weakness i mean it's not it's not
the same
function so it doesn't have the same
weakness
yeah any other question
sorry
no any other question comments anything
okay then let us thanks
again