so i was curious actually um
are there other classes complexity
classes that are interesting for this
kind of problem besides nc1
or is that is there some reason why
that's the right thing to look at
yes i actually have we have considered
this uh this question and we have
constructed some new skin other
complexity
classes
also
[Music]
maybe it's desirable to consider a
complex complexity of classes which are
larger
than the nc1 class such as for example
in c2 and c3
or maybe
maybe in the other fingering settings
such as the
memory boundary setting or the time
boundary setting
good christian yeah awesome thanks so
since we're behind time let's uh thank
the speaker again and then go to coffee
thank you