good morning everyone good afternoon
good evening
wherever you are in the world welcome to
track three
i'm very excited to be kicking off track
three as one of your mc's
to start off i'll introduce myself give
you a little bit of background
my name is adrienne corn also known as
ak47 intel
you can find me various discord slacks
twitter by that handle
i'm one of your content organizers for
today and i'm also the director of ocean
operations at trace labs i'm also joined
today by
our second mc for track three james
leolius
also known as blackbeard and we also
have andrew nolan
also known as zoomer another one of our
content organizers
manning all the backhand logistics for a
track three and really the whole
conference actually i should mention
um so before we get started with our
first speaker here david westcott
um i want to take a moment to give a
little bit of background on trace labs
in our mission um
as one of the main missions of content
today
is to support uh trace labs and also a
national child protection task
force so trace labs for those of you who
don't know
we are a not-for-profit organization
based on canada but we operate around
the world
our mission is really to crowdsource
open source intelligence
to assist law enforcement with a variety
of missing persons cases
around the world so we leveraged
crowdsourcing to
get volunteers to essentially conduct
these open investigations on these
real missing persons cases and then we
crowdsource all those leads
put them into a report uh summarize them
and provide that to law enforcement so
they can have some actionable
intelligence there if you're interested
in learning more
highly recommend you join us tomorrow on
sunday for
the ocean search party ctf we're going
to be running
uh we'll have a more in-depth background
there on trace labs as well
so hope to see many of you there
so to get started with our first talk
i'm very excited to introduce our first
speaker for track three
david westcott david is an information
security professional with over
13 years of experience in a variety of
security disciplines
and really his main areas of focus have
been on
ocean digital forensics incident
response
android application analysis and also
building linux distributions
today david will be sharing his talk
osint focus
android analysis with us and in this
talk you will be covering
an outline of the basic breakdown of
what is an android application we'll
also be highlighting some primary pivot
points
that can be derived from analysis and
then you'll be stepping through an
example of an android application
investigation so with that i'd like to
give
david a warm content welcome and we'll
be passing over to virtual stage to him
so
david the stage is all yours hey thanks
for that intro
um so today i'm going to be covering
ocean focused android analysis
so as was already alluded to in my bio
my primary areas of focus are ocean
differ android and building linux
distributions
some of them you might have used boost
gador and remnecks
right now for day job i'm presently
focused on incident response
so just to highlight what this talk is
and what it's not
um this is a talk covering basic android
analysis concepts
an ocean focused approach to android
investigations so we'll be using pivots
you all are used to
deriving from other types of
investigations to gather more
results contextual pivots and
an example investigation of a google
play application
so what this talk is not this is not an
expert's approach to analysis
i'm by no means an android expert it's
more of a hobby at this point
it is not an introduction to android
reverse engineering
and it is definitely not a detailed
explanation of android concepts
so just to highlight what we're going to
be talking about
we're going to discuss why ocean should
care about android
go over why you don't need to be a
reverse engineer to
add this to your toolkit the breakdown
of an android application
and then some of the pivots you all are
used to using infrastructure
email addresses names locations
some other fun stuff and then we're
going to apply all of that in an example
investigation
of a lovely app that's presently in the
google play store
so i just want to highlight why you
should care about android
if you're doing ocean a lot of people
still approach this as sort of a
niche analysis concept they don't dive
into it too much
but there's so much data that's freely
available for android
and we'll go over some of those sources
at the end
a very few people are taking it on even
in the professional vendor space
apk analysis and android arm analysis is
very rarely done
most places generally only have a team
of three to four people
unless they're a vendor that specializes
in the protection of android
there's a very low barrier to entry
versus other analysis
so pel maco and all that stuff are way
more complicated
involve way more background information
before you can even take them on
from an investigator's perspective if
you are going after a specified target
or an hvt
there is a 50 50 chance based on market
share that your target will be using it
and it's even more of a likelihood if
that person's doing nefarious stuff
um burners that are macs or apple
devices
are much more expensive especially if
you're only going to utilize them for a
specific purpose
it improves your overall analytical
capabilities any toolkit
or tool set that you add to what you
know
as an ocean investigator or cti analyst
or anything like that
it's going to make you approach things
differently regardless of what it is
you're looking at
and most importantly there are so many
different pivots
that will be going over that you can
utilize
without even being an re
so here's my very fun slide
um just going over you don't need to be
a reverse engineer
by any means um an apk is essentially
a compressed file format that has a
whole bunch of java kotlin or c
plus plus in it um there are bunches
and bunches of free tools there are
obviously
like with anything else there are
professional tools for reverse
engineering
apks but from an ocean perspective
you probably won't require those
and that's where the dynamic execution
comes in there are a bunch of free
sandboxes
ways to dynamically execute applications
for complete free
by people that that have them on github
freely available for you and a lot of
them are very well supported
and most importantly you don't need to
do full reverse engineering
of a given application to gain insight
about what it's doing
who made it and what their targets are
so here's a quick breakdown of an
android application
i tried to make this as visually
appealing as possible
and then the colors sort of uh showed up
this way
so at the top we have the android
package so the android package if you've
ever looked
at an android application is probably
what you're used to seeing it uses the
apk extension
once you decompress that you have all
the goodies inside so there's the delvik
executable
which is generally represented as a
classes.txt file
and then within the classes.txt file are
the actual classes
of the application sometimes called the
source code
of the application and it's pretty high
level java for the most part
there's also the assets folder so the
assets folder
is anytime you want to bundle a file or
a library or a configuration file
you just put it in a folder for the most
part they're unencrypted
they're not obfuscated unless you're
looking at malware a lot of times
and then you also have icons and images
shared libraries
generally represented as a so file it's
an l
file primarily targeting arm the signing
certificate
what we'll find out later in this
presentation is you can use a generic
signing certificate
and be very successful in the google
play store and make a lot of money
it does not have to be named you can do
this for free in android studio
and it'll create a new one every time
if you've ever looked at sort of a
report either in buyer's total or cudios
or
apk lab or anything like that you've
probably noticed they break down things
from
the android manifest the android
manifest
comprises activities services receivers
permissions application names and
package names
all of which are very good resources if
you're trying to figure out what
something does
who they're targeting and what the
expectation from the developer is
about what the app is going to do and
then there's the miscellaneous stuff
that you'll use from an re in an ocean
perspective
what they use to compile it target sdk
or target android version
and the target demographic so a lot of
times the target demographic can be
derived
either from what application it is or
it's trying to impersonate
what language all the prompts are in etc
so the first section i wanted to
highlight and sort of the way i break
down each one of these slides specific
to
the overarching out workflow that we
just
did is the the name size modification
time
and hash are going to be pretty
consistent for the
overlay files so the apk the libso
and the dex file itself are generally
going to have all of those so you might
notice
in all the slides following this one
those are the main things that we go
over
but the contents and the previous
versions i feel
are often left out in either a lot of
the re reports
or someone sharing the file on twitter
and that's really important because a
lot of stuff either in the google play
store or from a malicious context
is going to have previous versions and
that's when the developers usually mess
up
they'll either have the apk reaching out
to previously hosted infrastructure
they'll leave their name in a compiled
seo file
etc
so the dalvik executable uh you might
notice i left name off
the name of the file is very generically
just classes.dex
so depending on how complex the apk is
you might actually have two three four
of these
and they're all referenced individually
but for the most part
simple apks especially like the one
we're going to be looking at
are really small just have a single
classes file
and they're often reused so if you're
looking at a malicious builder
often what they'll do is they will
package the application using a
different application name different apk
name
different pictures but they're really
lazily just
reuse the same classes.dex file and
that's really
easy to pivot from because the hash will
be the same and often the
contents and the modification time will
be similar
and then within the classes this is
where a lot of the source code and a lot
of developers mess up is they will
actually go out and
they'll have a generic signing
certificate a generic email address
associated with it
but they'll forget to remove their their
compile path
from say their so or the will actually
have their name defined within the
variable if they're a very vain
developer
which happens a lot and they'll often
reuse variable names
especially when you get into the
malicious context or people that are
making
say a bunch of vpn apps like we're going
to be looking at shortly
and another really important thing that
gets left out of a lot of reports
is code originality and strings so
android studio has a very useful
analysis capability where it will look
for typos
within the source code of a given
application and then you can compare
those typos to a previous apk
so especially when you're looking at a
lot of non-english developers targeting
an english demographic they will often
spell things incorrectly
and they'll always spell that same thing
incorrectly so it's a very good pivot
when you're looking at family analysis
or you're looking at targeting
the primary things as we alluded to
earlier contained within assets
are html files encrypted content
especially when you're looking at
dynamic dex loading and malware families
sometimes they include an embedded apk
if they're too lazy to have dynamic
decks loading
you'll have configuration files
configuration files are pretty standard
especially if you're looking at things
like vpn applications
security applications or
just malware in general and the etc is
because you can put
pretty much anything you want in this
folder there's nothing
within the android development guide
that says
you can't put something in there so
sometimes you'll often see
things within assets that are never
actually used within the application
because they'll leave it or you'll have
someone building something and they
don't really understand what it works
like
so this happens a lot when there's a
stolen
or an unreleased malware family of the
source codes released you'll find people
rebuilding it
without realizing that a bunch of
stuff's left over
something that a lot of people in the
ocean community very familiar with
the icons and images are primarily
contained within a res folder
and all of those unfortunately most of
them don't have exif
because they're either stripped pngs or
jpegs
but you'll still have the size hash and
you'll be able to do reverse image
searches
especially on generic icons to find
originally where they're developed
a lot of times people will use
deviantart
or five dollar stuff on fiverr to have
someone develop a logo for them
and then they'll use that in their
builder and you'll be able to trace it
back to
who originally requested it when it was
requested and be able to build the
timeline that way
the libraries this is where it gets a
little more into actual doing reverse
engineering
a lot of these are l files and they're
targeting arm
and so with these very similar to how
you would look at a pe or a mocko file
you're going to be interested in the
name
the type of file the target so the
target in this context is referring to
which target arm it's looking at so if
it's looking at
mips if it's looking at arm 64 etc
hashes
size constant source the nice thing
about this is
virus total and similar sites have a lot
of this information that's
indexed and searchable so finding other
applications that use the same so for
example
is very easily done and that's a good
way
again to see reuse and to see where
developers mess up
signing certificates are very generic
this is what an example blank one looks
like the objects highlighted in red
are the most pivotable things within
here
signature algorithm the validation
data from the timeline the algorithms
and all that stuff are not really unique
to a given certificate
but the subject when it was initially
cut
the issuer the serial number all of
those are pivot points that you can use
in something like virus total from an
android guard perspective to see
other things using that certificate the
one gotcha i will say with this
is if someone's using a stolen developer
certificate which is very very common
with malware you'll have a generic
google signing certificate that was
stolen years ago
and then thousands and thousands of
applications are using it
when you do your initial search it's a
pretty safe bet that if you see over 100
apks using the same
certificate unless it's from a known
builder
it's too generic to be used as a pivot
the activity services and receivers are
really great for pivots because they're
generally named
so anything that is unique to an
application
that's named especially in the context
of a string is a great pivot
so all of these are named sometimes
they'll call them rats sometimes they'll
call them
vpn and just like the source code people
spell things wrong a lot
or they'll reference things as a
receiver that are specific to the
application
so example rat.keygen
might be a named service and you can
pivot off that to find
other applications that are using the
same thing and then
function from a source code analysis
perspective you can figure out what it
does and this is where the dynamic
sandboxes come in if you're not
comfortable looking at it statically you
can use a dynamic sandbox or you can use
freda instrumentation
to figure out what it does and do an
activities
search so if you're using a tool like
mob sf it'll actually run all the
activities for you and capture
screenshots
so you can see what all the workflows
would be that are defined within the
code without having to
individually step through them
and permissions this is where it gets
really murky with android depending on
the sdk version that it's targeting
there are defined permissions there are
dynamic permissions
so with android 10 and further
a lot of permissions are deemed to be
restricted or dangerous permissions
and as a result if anyone's running
those google play will mark them off as
malicious and possibly block them so
what a lot of developers have started
doing
is they do the permissions dynamically
once they either load a dynamic
dex or they load a dynamic apk that's
encrypted
because as we'll find out google play
does not too much verification
on most stuff to do with things they
host in their store even if it's a paid
application
and what you'll also run into sometimes
is people define permissions that are
not defined by the android sdk
sometimes it's a typo sometimes it is
something specific to the application
where they're referencing it so
sometimes
you'll see this with obfuscation they'll
call a permission
and it won't be named until it actually
executes what it is so for example if
something requires
a course permission they might not
define it until the application actually
runs
and another thing you can do if you're
getting
really low on pivot points is you can
look at the order in which permissions
are defined
i've been working a little bit on trying
to define this as sort of an impact
but you could take the permission order
and you can classify it for a given app
so they always request these permissions
in this order
and that's different than say the next
app that requires the same permissions
it's not required very often but it's a
good thing to reference when you're
doing an analysis of an apk
again with an application name this is a
string you'll see this a lot
with malware you can make the
application name anything you want
it does not have to actually be that
thing google play does a really bad
job with impersonation you'll see this
with a lot of phishing applications
or people just trying to get credentials
is you can call something say the bank
of america application
and then the apk reference has nothing
to do with b of a
they just took all of their application
icons and their background images
so with this uniqueness uh typos again
happen a lot and um it doesn't have to
do
anything with the apk so you could call
it
bank america online and if you don't put
any spaces that would be unique to the
application
and often especially with a builder
depending on targeting
this would be the same no matter what
the apk is so where a lot of people get
hung up and pivoting is they only rely
on the apk name
or they only reply on say the main
activity name but they forget that the
same application name
is used and they have hundreds and
hundreds of different apk name
definitions but it's all the same thing
and then from the malicious context is
it impersonating something
so is this going after a specific
application
and this is really helpful when it gets
in the targeting of a specific
demographic
so especially if you're looking at
countries like turkey
or aipac where they use banks or
messaging applications that you're not
familiar with
from an ocean perspective it's really
good to say what is this app
why would they create it and who are
they targeting
with the package name it's really
straightforward it has a defined name
it's good to look at what the defined
name is not what the file is submitted
as
so a lot of times if especially if
you're using virustotal
people will often submit things as a
different name
but you want to actually look at the
name defined
within the manifest to figure out what
it actually is
is it associated with known malware
again with the application impersonation
and say like with metasploit right the
the default metasploit package name
is always the same regardless of the
application name so is this apk
tied to a known malware family what's
the malware family is it actually that
thing
and then with the uniqueness just like
application name
a lot of times the application apk
string identifier
is going to be unique to the developer
or unique to a given family
and another one is the package versus
main activity this is a really good way
to determine
if the package is actually the package
so
a lot of times what you'll see is
someone will take a package from say the
google play store
they'll make that the name of the apk
but the main activity is either
an embedded apk or a lot of times it'll
be an
encrypted dex within the assets and it
won't be loaded
as the main activity until there's
dynamic execution
so a lot of antivirus vendors and google
play will just look at the apk and say
oh i know what that is
i know what those permissions are green
light
so if you're really really getting in
the weeds you can also look at the
compile time
and try to create a timeline of all
package versions
so if i'm looking at the timeline of say
when was the first time
this malware family or this developer
targeting the specific application
started working and then map out every
version
you can actually build out a timeline of
developer release cycles
you can build out of when did they start
using a different compiler
when did they start doing different
versions and diffing along the way
very similar to how you would do with
different binary application timelining
which compiler did they use for the most
part unless it's in a commercial context
this is going to be a pretty weak pivot
but it's something
to reference and then packing and
encryption so
this does not happen with a lot of the
really lazy developers
say subarus or anubis or any of those
they'll actually just do the same thing
over and over
they'll obfuscate it in base 64 with a
hard-coded string
but if you start getting into the more
advanced developers
the staged loaders and a lot of times
the commercial entities
they'll either pack it or encrypt it in
a way that makes it really annoying to
reverse
and the only way to actually get at the
true apk or the true decks
is through frida instrumentation or
hands-on device
but that is unique and even if you can't
break it it might be unique to a given
application
and you can make note of it for the how
the developer works and how they operate
this is a really big one and this goes
back to my cti days
one thing left out of a lot of our re
reports because they don't look at this
from an ocean perspective and where
ocean really shines
is you can build out sort of a portfolio
of who they're targeting why they're
targeting them what language they use
what people are involved um how they're
sharing it so this
especially if it's very specific
targeting
say for example they're only sharing it
in a given telegram channel or they're
sharing it in a specific
facebook group or they're doing a
watering hole that way
when are they releasing it what target
sdks are they going after
this is really relevant because a lot of
malicious developers
will go after the target sdk of the
market share for the region that they're
going after
market share by region is very easy to
figure out there are a lot of places
that keep those statistics for free
and so they'll go to a different country
and say what's my most common
target sdk i'm going after because once
you get to
present day android sdks you have to do
a lot more
to bypass security checks um and to get
into the play store with permissions and
stuff like that and this is one
everyone's very very familiar with i'm
pretty sure
at this conference and this goes into
like anything else who's hosting the
file
what a lot of people are having to do
nowadays because google play
is quote unquote getting stricter with
what they allow in the store they'll
actually host it
outside of the store and then use social
engineering to get the end user to
disable
unofficial play restrictions so they'll
say
if you really want this awesome file or
you want to see
what your girlfriend's doing on her
phone you have to disable the
restriction and load this application
from a third-party url
happens a lot unfortunately people click
stuff
in their sms and they'll install it to
get it that
new tick tock background um that that
they've been
looking for so outbound inbound traffic
and this is specifically if you're
looking at reverse shells
who's hitting it when you load it in
dynamic execution
and where is it going and then from a
static perspective once you've developed
those indicators
what passive dns is associated with it
is it associated with any who is
has this developer made any other
applications that reference the same
infrastructure
or are they what appears to be leasing
out their infrastructure
as we'll see in our investigation
uh who registered the domains associated
gdpr and other privacy restrictions have
made this less and less of a well
to dig from unfortunately but depending
on the service you're utilizing
sometimes
they'll still have this information and
then the key one that happens a lot and
this is a
big point in the investigation we're
going to go over today are there any
other applications utilizing similar
infrastructure
so this can be derived either from the
base url and uri
down to the uri syntax
again uh email addresses most the ones
on google play
unless they're a commercial entity or
fake unfortunately it doesn't appear
that google play verifies
for the most part um so a lot of these
are going to be dead ends unless you
have a really sloppy developer
what advertisers are they using the nice
thing about advertising is
if you use it in most sdk context it's a
static identifier
so that is something that you can
reference very similar to a ua string on
a website
the api key and all of that is a
requirement for something like admob or
for google play
ads within the application and then
again as we'll see today um oops i
forgot my email address strings within
the source code
and you can use this as a pivot so a lot
of times with developers their email
address will either point to their
github repository a personal website
and you can do all the infrastructure
pivots with the email address string
that you derived
and then once you have that email
address either from google play
or from other methods you could say is
that email address
tied to any name personas or companies
or llc's
and then who's listed as that llc or
corporation oftentimes
especially with front companies and
malicious contacts
they'll forget to actually use an email
address that's not tied to a named
persona
whether that's their legal counsel their
name or they forget
like a lot of people do an ocean that
the internet's a thing
and historical presentations of the pdfs
for their initial llc paperwork
is easily accessible
and then with the names aliases and
relationships
this is a very big ocean thing i don't
need to tell a lot of people on here
once you have an actual name you can do
a lot of fun stuff with it
you can derive relationships what
aliases they use
and the big thing that we're going to go
into the investigation is
can that name actually be verified
especially with vpns for some reason
in google play they don't use real names
so you'll see a lot of burner names like
karen smith
and google's like that seems legitimate
i'm gonna let that
hang out and make money and then
physical locations this one's left out
the most i think from most re reports
because most reverse engineers
to their credit they're awesome at
reverse engineering but once they've
reversed it
they sort of stop carrying or they pass
it off to a separate team
from an ocean perspective the developer
location
is sort of a complicated ask to look
into
you have to determine what their
language is in the source code often
they'll say
they're an american developer that lives
in california and loves surfing
but all their source code is in mandarin
and
they will only share their stuff say on
chinese websites
ip locations this goes into
infrastructure domain who is
similarly the llc is a really big
giveaway for a lot of these companies
they'll use an s corp for
an llc or a lawyer as we'll see in
our investigation to associate their
company so that google will pay them
or so that google doesn't think that
they appear fraudulent
but a lot of times this will give us a
very good idea of where they're actually
located so say
delaware as an example is referenced in
a lot of llc's
but most of the time people that use
delaware llc's are
trying to obfuscate something the
signing certificate locality is often
a really good one as we'll highlight in
our investigation
you generally want to declare there's a
country string within the certificate
for the issue we're in for the source
and a lot of times people will mess up
they'll say they're a us-based developer
but oops their country code says hong
kong
and most importantly from an osa and a
research perspective is any of this
verifiable
so you don't want to take anything in
the google play store
or on a website or anything like that as
an actual verifiable fact
you want to make sure that you prove it
yourself
and then from a miscellaneous
perspective um how did they compile it
what packages would they utilize and
that they don't actually maintain
a sort of a gotcha here is if you're
just looking at the strings
or the resource src for a given package
all the strings in there are not to do
with
the developer so you'll see a lot of
analysts when they're first getting
going say aha like i found this string
this is who did it
or this is their compile time because
it's referenced here
i would advise pretty heavily against
just looking at strings just like if
you're looking at ida
you're not going to want to look at the
string sub view and assume
that you have the the complete picture
make sure that the string you're looking
at
is the string associated with the actual
developer but it is important to see
what packages they're using because that
is something you can note and say oh
they always use these third-party tools
or they always use this malicious
builder
target sdk target demographic and target
region
go a lot into building out an overall
profile or a dossier of the given
developer
if you're looking at a team or if you're
looking at someone
that might may or may not work for a
nation state front company
you want to see okay they primarily only
go after this specific region
this target sdk always and their
demographic appears to be the minority
in that country
and then the business site or
application impersonation
who do they generally try to spoof are
they always going after the financial
vertical
are they really interested in decrypting
whatsapp for telegram
and they're trying to make it look like
it's a real telegram application
and then a really fun one is who are
their competitors
so there is a lot of back and forth
between developers
especially if you get into the more
closed off
forums about who has the best malware
or who has the best vpn application
doesn't even necessarily have to be
malicious
but they'll write reviews on their own
stuff within google play and forget that
they're logged in
they'll make videos on youtube and
forget that they're logged in
and then you'll see their other stuff
that it looks like oh they make this
us vpn but they also make a vpn for
turkey and china
and those ones are flagged as malicious
and here are the certificates that they
use
and then from a competitor perspective
from you can also social engineer their
competitors to possibly give up dirt
now for the the most fun part of the
presentation
i did an example investigation of a very
popular app
in the google play store if you have
this app installed on your phone
or know anyone that does definitely
uninstall it
um don't install vpns from the google
play store
unless you've looked at them yourself
and you'll see why in just a second
so the three apps that i looked at are
about this company named
signal lab you might notice that green
signal vpn
not super popular only has about 59
reviews
and not many people have downloaded it
like a thousand users but then when you
get into thunder vpn
and secure vpn they're super high speed
and they have unlimited vpn
powers um they have over 10 million
installs each
and as you can see they have a lot of
really really great reviews
before we get into this uh they claim to
be
u.s developers that live in a place
called alhambra arkansas
for anyone on the call and anyone doing
fact checks in the twitch stream
there is no alhambra arkansas this is
their listed physical location in all of
their applications
all three of them are still on the
google play store and as we'll see
that is not actually a real address
because they
i don't know typoed it and google never
got back with them
so the quick pivots you can get just
from looking at a google play
application
without getting into any of the
nitty-gritty of the analysis of the
application
there will always be some type of email
address
whether that's a legitimate email
address or whatever it is a requirement
of google play
um they do i believe have some specifics
around what providers that you're
allowed to use you're not going to see a
lot of free mail or to
not or protonmail in here they generally
want you to use either a gmail address
or a verifiable email address to their
credit
the second email address here is taken
from
what they call their vip support section
as you can see
also a gmail address and then the dev id
so in this instance we got lucky
they're dev ids in numeric but for the
most part if you're a developer
um you're gonna have a name you're not
gonna get lucky enough to have
a numeric so the physical location
alhambra arkansas 91803 in the
u.s of a and then the base domain of
what their website is so
the website here is free signal.com
and then they have a sub domain for the
given apps so
there's uh green signal thunder
and secure the best vpn apps
and here you can get a simple timeline
so with
developer tools that are freely
available with an api
you can see the first time an
application was available in the google
play store
and not just the last time it was
updated the google play ui
does not give you a good way to do this
but it's easily queryable
so we can see they started in about june
of 2017
and then they had another release in
november and then another one in march
their apps cost anywhere from six to
sixty dollars
and that's just a range they offer a vip
option which you'll see a lot with a lot
of these freemium tools
the tool will work the same but if you
want those ads to go away
give us money the description
also a very good pivot as we can see
here
it is a lightning fast app provide free
vpn proxy service
not need any configuration if we take
that and throw that into google
you can see that that is uh used a lot
by avpn wolfvpn
expert vpn warlier vpn and hide you vpn
these are just a few examples it's used
an awful lot
and a lot of times with descriptions you
can tie it back to the first time it was
referenced and use it as a base for your
timeline
this about sums up my
my utilization of this vpn it's okay
from a physical perspective um right
away seeing arkansas 910803
was kind of red flag because that's a
california zip code
if we look at what they were trying to
put they were meant
alhambra california specifically
building one so you might
ask why why would they use this address
well
alhambra is an office suite and there's
a few different reasons they might use
this
um either they really wanted an office
there because a1 is the building offices
or in my research i found out
that there happens to be a law office
for a legal professional
that only accepts cash payments of this
address so this might be the person
that handles their mail handles their
notifications from google
and most importantly gets those awesome
checks for their premium vpn service
this is what their base domain looks
like as you can see very well maintained
this has not changed since 2017 but we
can tell that they're using
a very basic nginx front on fedora um
there's nothing here
they only have their web server set up
to handle the sub domain so like here
would be an example
of this totally legitimate website that
has over 10 million
app downloads on google play it looks
like
oops they forgot to take out a string
when they used h track
and they copied it from devittfamily.com
and they use
the subdirectory from apex one so the
important thing to
see here with apex one is apex one
is a developer that handles mobile
application development
and website company services for
individuals
companies and developers so what
probably happened here
is they were too lazy to make their own
website
they heard vpns were the new hotness and
they don't know how h track works you'll
see this a lot uh there's actually a
story this week where people forgot that
this was the thing
but from a pivotal perspective as a
gotcha
devotfamily.com probably has nothing to
do with this developer
neither does apex one they just really
liked the way their website looked
so here we get into what their original
certificate looked like so if you look
at any of these apps right now
you'll see all of them just have a
generic google developer certificate
it's perfectly straightforward
it's really great but if you go back to
the previous versions
oops they forgot to leave out the fact
that they're in hong kong
and the timeline associated for 12 2017
aligns with the original domain
registration
as well as their original amazing green
signal app
that did not have as many awesome clicks
and reviews
and i'm guessing monetary benefits so
from here
you could use this issuer the serial
number
as well as the hash to see if any other
applications
either within virustotal or cudios or
any other libraries like that
um use the same signing certificate in
this investigation unfortunately
um i didn't see any others but this is
very good to know
um it looks like this is probably not a
legitimate application
i could not find any llc's either in
arkansas or california
that use this name and i'm guessing they
use signal lab
because they heard signal messenger it
was a really well-known security tool
and they decided to piggyback off of it
here's a quick overview of what the
packages look like
i did a diff of all three and and the
one thing you might notice
is they all use this lib channel.so
so the lib channel so in my research it
looks like they're using that for their
vpn router
so based on what we know about people
leaving stuff in code
i took a look at their libeso and oops
there's his name
i've obfuscated it because i won
i don't really know where this person
lives if they truly do live in hong kong
i don't want them to get in trouble
but this is freely available information
cha cha 20 is a stream cipher
aes gcm also is used for the vpn routing
of this application
if you look into this particular
developer's name
and this particular string it looks like
he's worked on other vpn apps in the
past
and he also has a project on there
because he's into video games
if someone's using virustotal you can
look into this
here is a quick overview of what the app
looks like in its true form
because i decided to take the veil off
and uh
yeah this is the exact same app in the
us
or the uk or wherever you use it but
this is it in its original language
as you can see it's the best vpn of all
time
and you click one and it uses its
built-in statically assigned ops key
and des key to connect a totally secure
vpn
to a totally not owned by a hong kong
developer
vpn network if we go in here do a little
network analysis
we can see that it reaches out to some
subdomain called
s for it free signal i've redacted all
the fun things but as you can see here
this is the secure vpn context if you do
reach out
using the auth token and the rec token
and the auth id
what you get back is all of their vpn
ips
associated by location tier and the ops
keys
and then you can throw it at a fuzzer
and map out their entire network
if you map out their entire network if
you wanted to get into
a very complicated investigation which i
did not have time for
for this presentation you would be able
to say
all of these other apps are using this
network i'm pretty sure he's either
leasing infrastructure
or it's all the same person oh and look
at that
here are all the other vpns presently on
the google play store
using the exact same infrastructure uh
the same lib so
um oops he's probably making pretty good
money
um but if you're using again any of
these apps
it's probably a good idea to uninstall
them
and in the future it's probably a very
good rule to not
install an application called free vpn
or vpn internet or turbo vpn
etc if we look at the infrastructure
here
one thing you also might note is he's
really a big fan of bulgaria
if you look into that specific itl in
bulgaria
you'll notice there's only one person
assigned to it
may or may not be the developer but it's
not very widely used
and oddly enough for a u.s developer
none of their infrastructure is in the
united states
and then from a dynamic execution
perspective what we talked about before
you could look at the uri
context and say okay what else reaches
out to a file called
hello.txt and returns the value of
signal
which shared prefs of example signal lab
green signal
persistentconfig and
createsignal.database files
if you look into this i did a very quick
glance there are a bunch of other apps
and if someone with more free time than
me wanted to take a run at this
probably uh find a lot more fun stuff
than is
in this presentation so for getting
started here are the places i would
recommend
these are not tools these are just
places
that offer the ability to freely pivot
on stuff
virustotal is kind of at a freemium
point where you can look up hashes but
most of the pivots
require a paid account or researcher
account apk labs free but it's inline
invite only but all of the other
applications are free securios is free
and all the other ones listed so what
did we learn today
um you can do pivots for days because
all the data is freely available and
it's not very widely used
it's a great way to expand your skill
set everyone can play with this
you don't have to be a reverse engineer
and most importantly we learned that
google does not verify any information
so if anyone has any questions i believe
they're monitoring
right now and i can respond to those
yeah just looking here in the twitch
chat david uh
no questions yet so if anyone has any
questions on the talk for david
please drop them in the twitch chat now
we can definitely get to them
and also want to say david fantastic
talk really
great deep dive into these android
application investigative techniques
i really enjoyed it myself
okay so we have one question for you
david uh someone is asking if he could
go back to the
additional resources slide just for them
to see sure
uh this one
uh i believe so let's see let's look in
the chat
they're asking to show the list of tools
again is this the list of tools
yeah yeah
awesome i also want to remind everyone
that this talk will be recorded so
we upload to youtube at a later date so
if you miss any of david's slides it
will be available in that top
where you can see them
okay anyone else have any questions for
david
before we finish off the talk for today
okay we have one question here is it
relevant to analyze
the network traffic of a specific
application
if it isn't suspect with the data from
the apk
itself if the
so let's see if i so is it relevant to
analyze the
network traffic for the apk if it's not
relevant to the apk itself so like if
the device is just reaching out
to a given network
let's see um men elk are
is that uh your question essentially do
you want to clarify in the twitch chat
here
i think what i'll do for you as well
david i'll drop these questions into uh
the zoom chat on your side so you can
just read them on your end as well
because i'm asking them
oh yeah it's so i believe the question
if i'm understanding it correctly is
is it relevant to look at network
traffic even if it doesn't appear
suspect
and so if if that is indeed the question
uh definitely
so this traffic itself is not suspect
it's just insecure but it's definitely
but it's definitely very relevant
because from here
we were able to get other applications
that use the same network traffic
so even if you're not looking at a
malicious apk
if you are looking at a developer or an
organization that makes
that application it's very relevant
because it's the best way to map out
their infrastructure
fantastic i got another question here
for you david
um the question is what can we get for
more advanced
forensics for android and how can a
forensic analyst
use it to solve and how can an attacker
misuse it just drop the question as well
for you and then zoom chat
yeah i'm just trying to think of a
concise way to answer this um let's see
so from a forensics perspective it would
depend on what the investigation context
was so if you were looking
to see what someone was doing from a
nefarious perspective
you could very easily and there's a lot
of great training on this that's free
but you can look at a device very
similarly to how you would look at a pc
so they have the same folder structure
and they have the same applications so
that is
is pretty easy it just depends on how
you want to approach it so if you want
to use a professional
tool if you are using this for
investigations i would recommend a
professional tool
because most of the open source ways to
do this are not great
the open source way to do it would be to
use
adb to interact with the application and
the device itself but if you want to do
this from a forensic perspective of how
to analyze what an apk does
an open source way to do this would be a
tool called mob sf
or the mobile security framework the
mobile security framework's free
and it keeps track of everything that a
device does so what files are created
the hashes of all those files it takes
screenshots of the interaction
it also will get all of the network
traffic and allow you to replay it to a
fuzzer
so for this particular research
investigation i use the fuzzer to get
all their vpn ips
if you want to do it from a forensic
perspective or you need to pass it off
it's also
a great tool because it can create pdf
reports
so that would be the open source option
i would recommend
it's far better in my opinion than
unfortunately the sandbox in things like
virustotal
and it's the best way to do it if you're
looking at an investigation you don't
want to be made public
you can do it man in the middle proxies
so if you don't want it to
you don't have to do outbound network
that's just a good way to get file
creates
great i had a quick follow-up question
on that david from someone in the chat
they were asking what the name of that
open source option was
again sure it's the mobile security
framework
if you just type mob sf plus get
on a search engine it'll bring it up for
you
but it's my go-to option for android
analysis
just because it's so easy to use there's
even a docker option
and it has a public facing interface
on the host that you stand it up on so
you have a web server to actually
interact with frida
because if you've ever tried to use
frida before manually
it's doable but it's not the most
intuitive thing
this will actually dynamically control
freedom for you
and it works with jenny motion free so
also a free option for doing emulation
jd motion has a just for fun
option that doesn't require payment and
then you can use mob sf
to interact with the genymotion and you
can create everything i believe from
android 5
up to android 10 and then analyze how it
interacts with
each sdk target great
thank you so much for that david so we
have just about one more minute left
before we're gonna
finish off the talk had a couple more
questions but i think we'll just go with
one more for now um so the next question
is
do you know how to identify if a phone
has been hacked
by looking at a dd image that is a
question
okay yeah so the i'm guessing the base
assumption would be
um if you have the dd image you could
mount it and see if
root um if the phone had been rooted
there are a bunch of free utilities
i can't remember the names off the top
of my head
but there's a quick way to see if it's
been rooted uh the the term
hacked i guess you'd have to define what
what you
want that to mean so the question is
does it have malicious software
installed on it
um like spyware or a keylogger or
something like that
the best place to start looking would be
in the installed services
and the installed applications
but that yeah the the term hacked it
just would depend
because some people take hack to mean is
the phone rooted
other people take it to me and it's
their malicious software installed on it
but the installed services and
applications especially if you only have
the dd
would be the best place to start
fantastic thank you so much for that
david
and that brings us to the end of david's
talk
i want to thank everyone for coming out
to this first talk of track three
david thank you so much again for
joining us for the first edition of
content
we will now be taking a short
five-minute break as we transition to
our next speaker
dhruv magendar where he will be giving a
talk on
cti and threat hunting so come back on
in five minutes to hear from dhruv
and thank you again david thanks for
having me