[Music]
hello and welcome back to uh
conant and we're back on track one now
for paul
raphael for open source intelligence to
enable
real-time crisis mantra i've been
actually really looking forward to this
talk so i can't wait to hear someone's
gonna let them go ahead and just jump
right into it
all right awesome hey folks thanks
everyone for joining us today um thank
you so much for conan for bringing
um all of us together for this awesome
day of opportunities and trainings and
uh gaining so much more information so
happy to share with everyone today
um kind of a unique use of open source
intelligence i know we got some folks
talking about investigations
analysis um today i kind of want to
shift the discussion towards uh using
real time or near real-time
um open source intelligence to help gain
a better understanding of emergent
crisis
um as they occur we're going to focus
this presentation today on
global crises so um usually
international cases i'm based in the us
but uh
um we'll cover cases from around the
world and how even
um one person sitting at a desk 3 000
or 10 000 miles away can gain a um
real-time on the ground advantage um
seeing what's happening in near real
time
so let's go ahead and get started
all right just a little bit about myself
my name is paul raphael my background
i'm an
intelligence analyst by trade i've
worked in private sector
and also on a few government projects um
i was a lead analyst at a fortune 500
pharma where we covered everything from
geopolitical analysis crisis management
travel security so
i'm going to share some cool case
studies from that experience in my
background today
um so yeah private sector intelligence
analyst analysis is pretty cool
um a lot of similarities with
what you normally think of as an
intelligence analyst on the government
side so
oftentimes we use the same tools the
same analytic techniques
and uh hopefully i can share some of
those with you all today
and then a few qualifications over on
this slide so um
that'll give some more background about
me and why i'm presenting on this topic
today
all right so just a quick rundown um
pretty much we're gonna start with
defining open source intelligence really
quickly i think we've just got one slide
on that because this entire conference
is about intelligence so
i think by this point we have a pretty
good understanding then we'll jump right
into intelligence driven crisis
management
and primarily what we're going to focus
on is using um real-time signals in
order to develop that
better situational awareness better
context about
crises that are occurring on the ground
in real time
then i also do want to talk about
vetting and verifying information
as you all know social media open
sources they're known to be not the most
reliable sources
at times so i'll give you some tools to
help um
identify potential disinformation
misinformation
and how you can really validate and vet
information
before you do anything with it and then
lastly we'll just add some
few tips and tricks about using ocean to
enhance other aspects
of international crisis monitoring all
right so let's just
jump right into it um these tools are
pretty much accessible to everyone well
they are accessible to everyone um
totally free online tools that we're
gonna discuss today
and anyone is really open to use these
tools
um you know this presentation may be
especially beneficial to crisis managers
security and intelligence analysts watch
officers and journalists
but also this presentation could totally
be used by travelers
financial analysts disinformation
warriors and even just curious minds if
you
um want to develop a better
understanding in real time maybe before
incidents even break the news
uh we'll give all those tools out today
so uh
it's really for anyone all right so just
a quick background on open source
intelligence i think everybody knows
by this point in the conference that
osint refers to
information collected from publicly
accessible sources
so um i use this in contrast to
what we typically think of as
traditional intelligence
gathering disciplines so sigint massen
geoint human
a lot of these are military and
government terms but open source
intelligence ocean has really been
accessible to
anyone in any type of job
i do like to add that um osent in my
view um i kind of take the idea that um
especially as we talk about it in this
presentation open source intelligence is
almost the new type of
secant or signals intelligence so
historically with military and
government
operations they would use signals um
that are
basically you know tripwires or other
types of um
just signals around the world in order
to develop information about what was
happening
but nowadays we can really use social
media and open source intelligence to
um to leverage that same fidelity and
context of information on the ground so
really open source and social media
intelligence is the new signals
intelligence in my view
so open source and intelligence takes
all shapes and sizes um you know these
can range from public records to
uh peer-reviewed reports and articles
news media
government alerts especially in the
context of crisis management
and of course as we already talked about
social media so use all of these at your
disposal today we are going to typically
talk about social media
um but of course you can use all of
these in
open source intelligence all right so
let's kind of gear the conversation now
towards uh the topic of the day
crisis management so osun can
really enrich international crisis
management programs
um it's a hugely valuable tool um that
you can use to assess global risks and
gain more information about those risks
so ocean can help you track things in
real time it can help you enhance that
situation awareness
and improve um your crisis
responsibilities especially if you're in
a position in your job
where you're a crisis manager or
security analyst
you can definitely use osint to gain a
better on-the-ground advantage
so i kind of laid out on the slide four
different um swim lanes where ocean can
really apply but today we're really
going to focus on that situational
awareness piece where we're going to
talk
talk about real-time intel situation
updates as they occur
and also how that information can help
with your own contingency planning
all right so open source intel is
available for all types of global crises
we can talk about security incidents
health incidents
outbreaks diseases uh severe weather
um that's coming up protests
natural disasters and even a wide scale
travel incidents
so all these types of global crises
there are
always always always open source
indicators um
that pretty much give advanced notice to
most of these incidents
and then i wanted to use this slide to
really break down
information versus intelligence because
sometimes we get these confused
um information can include a lot of
things
um but intelligence is really
specifically tailored curated
information that went through a level of
processing
that went through a level of analysis
and the real point of intelligence is
for it to be actionable
so while information can basically
constitute the entire body of knowledge
on a subject
intelligence really is that honed in
specific
actionable information that you need to
know about a situation which i think is
incredibly pertinent
when we're talking about crises because
during a crisis and when minutes matter
um really actionable intelligence is
super important so i wanted to start
with
a um incident reporting time variance
study
um that my team did so we looked at um
when are mainstream media news stations
um reporting breaking news about an
incident versus when is the first kind
of
open source risk intelligence alert
about
an incident so we did is we compared the
two we looked at the same incidents that
were reported on both types of platforms
and then we compared all right which one
is breaking the news quicker
and i think you guys can probably guess
that we found
the intelligence alerts had a huge
advantage
um when it comes to timeliness and
reporting breaking
uh global incidents so
um as you can see by this chart a lot of
examples where
um the intelligence alerting had a major
time advantage over breaking news alert
um there were four instances in our
study when the breaking news
alert did come before the intelligence
alert so
kudos on those incidents but um you can
definitely see how
that having a robust intelligence
collection and processing system
um can help you gain that real-time
advantage especially when minutes matter
um so yeah just picking out a few
examples um
from this slide so uh the first live
shot that was fired in the hong kong
protests uh back in quarter four 2019
um that was reported uh almost six hours
in advance uh from an intelligence alert
before breaking news actually reported
that incident
and that's important because um that
first live shot in the hong kong
protests
um drastically escalated the situation
i'm sure you guys remember the news
reports of millions of people gathering
in the streets
after that first live shot was fired um
things did escalate
lots more people a lot more violence so
it's important to know
um incidents in real time before they're
even
alerted on by breaking news then another
interesting example here we basically
had
a three full day advance notice um when
british airways was cancelling about 90
of their flights back in september um on
one weekend
due to a workers strike um so
just knowing that information three days
in advance before mainstream media even
reported on it
um that's huge especially if you're
traveling with the company you don't
want to get stranded abroad or anything
like that
um so yeah this can really range in
anything from travel incidents
health outbreaks uh security incidents
protests etc
and then one more slide on this topic uh
we added a few more down at the bottom
at the end of our study
and it turned out that um we received an
alert about
uh coven 19 almost nine days in advance
before it even hit the first
major international or u.s mainstream
news publication
so imagine just having that advantage
that there was
the knowledge that there was a viral
outbreak it seems to be getting worse it
seems to be
abnormal and it doesn't seem to be
contained so
imagine what that nine-day advantage
would look like especially if you're
um you know part of a business that has
a large supply chain in china
or if you're a crisis manager that
manages um
travelers that are going to china um
lots of good information here from
open source intel um on average we were
seeing that
emergent incidents uh were reported
almost
about five and a half hours faster with
intelligence alerts versus
breaking news
and then just one more slide on the
coronavirus topic
in four out of five instances as the
coronavirus was worsening
and in making major news updates
we did find out that four out of five
times
these major updates were reported first
by
open source intel feeds versus u.s news
all right so let's dive right into some
case studies with real-time crisis
management
so the idea here is to use real-time
ocean to enhance your situational
awareness about incidents as they're
occurring
so you can see some icons on the screen
i'm sure you maybe recognize a few of
them already maybe a few are new to you
so we'll go through all of these and
others to talk about how
you can use a mix of tools at the same
time simultaneously
in order to really gain an enhanced
context in situational awareness
about incidents as they're occurring on
the ground
all right so here's just a quick index
of some of the tools we're going to talk
about i'll give
everyone just a quick second to maybe
screenshot this live this one's a good
index and
a good item to keep in the back pocket
all right so with this first example i
really want to
talk about how we use osim to layer
information to gain that situation
awareness
so let's say for example um you
subscribe to the u.s geological survey
major earthquake alerts system so let's
say you want to hear about
any earthquake that's above a 7.1
magnitude pretty impactful
so you get this alert and you see all
right so a 7.1 magnitude earthquake
occurred
in pueblo mexico looks like on your map
it's a little bit south of mexico city
so you're wondering
all right does this earthquake impact
mexico city
um you don't really know how many miles
away it is at this point unless if you
do
a little bit more research but really
this is all the information on your
screen that you get
from a usgs early morning alert
so not a whole lot of information and i
still have a lot of questions
so it looks like this alert said the
earthquake epicenter was 48 kilometers
deep
i don't know what that means i'm not a
geologist i i don't study earthquakes on
a day-to-day basis so
does a 48 kilometer deep earthquake mean
that you don't really feel it on the
surface or does that mean
you feel it worse don't really know um
7.1
i think that sounds kind of bad but
maybe it's not as bad as i think it is
so we still have a lot of questions and
let's use some open source tools to
really define
um these questions that we have and find
some answers as well
so usgs also provides additional context
um through their seismic sensors and
projections
so you again you can go just to their
website and see this occur
um you can see kind of the orange in the
middle maybe that's pretty bad maybe the
yellow you feel a bit of trembling
maybe in the green and blue maybe you
don't feel much at all so
um that's just an assumption let's see
how we can actually
find out more so usgs
interestingly has a did you feel it kind
of crowdsourced
information where people on the ground
are able to report back and into this
aggregated system to say all right yes i
felt extreme
shaking there's a lot of damage or you
know it was a moderate earthquake
no real damage here in this location so
as people report this information back
you can see how this is more useful
and gives you more context and actually
gives you some
language that you can associate with
impact in certain areas
so you can obviously see where where the
earthquake probably um
hit the hardest and where was most
impactful
now going one step deeper what we can
then do is use social media
around each of these particular
locations you can zoom in find different
city names different town names
um search those keywords search those
locations
on social media websites we'll talk
about a few and you can see information
to add more context into what's
happening here so
um we've we've basically changed
you know a 7.1 48 kilometer deep
number which is it doesn't have any
context at all
and now we've added so much context uh
to this situation
here all right so this is another
example and i want to dive into more of
the the social media
aspect here as well so um
this is a case study based on the
barcelona spain uh vehicle ramming
attack that was back in 2017
um in the initial alert or first
indication of this incident occurred
from a tweet where someone said
uh there's a stampede right now at el
corte english and
plaza catalunya in barcelona so um based
on this little red icon on the map you
can kind of see where that is
and then if you know anything about
barcelona if you've ever traveled there
or just a quick google search you can
see that la rambla
is a pretty populated uh market area
with a lot of
um just pedestrian traffic on the street
there
so this first incident um you know kind
of indicates that it's
it's in one location it may be isolated
um but as we get more information and
more tweets start coming in
we start to really see the full picture
of what's happening so
pictures videos from social media on the
ground start to spread using the hashtag
barcelona and also using the
geocode for the location of barcelona as
well
so as this information starts coming in
using those hashtags you can start to
develop a better situational awareness
because you start to see different areas
that have been impacted
um you could look at different buildings
street names you can look at
business names on the side of businesses
and just google where they are
on the street to determine the full
length and the full impact of this
incident
and then we start to see um social media
coming in about where the van stopped
and you can see that there's a really
distinct street art
um over which the van is stopped with
that um
uh interesting mural i guess on the
ground
in the tile so using this information
and the information you just basically
pulled from social media you can almost
map where this incident has occurred its
entire trajectory
um knowing the amount of foot traffic
that's probably in this area during
rush hour you can already start to make
judgments about the magnitude of
potential casualties
um in this case um there were a lot over
100 people
injured 14 fatalities um and that is
something that you could expect
um before news even started to report on
it so
using this situation awareness you can
already start to make judgments about
magnitude about proximity
um and yeah have
basically judgment over a a situation
before
really starts to hit the news
um entering another layer of context you
can also look at
3d maps so in this case google earth was
super helpful in this incident
so if i go ahead and search
la rambla
it should come up all right
so use tools at your disposal like
google earth this is a great 3d visual
representation
um that that you can use to make
judgments and actually interestingly
right here where this map brought us
this right here is placide catalunya
where the incident supposedly started
and then what you can do kind of as
those tweets start coming in
um and you start to see more context
about buildings and
different businesses that are impacted
you can pretty much
oh i might go in the wrong direction i
am going the wrong direction here
um it is
this way so yeah a little bit of trial
and error maybe the first time but as
you get those feeds and more incidents
happening you can almost follow it um in
real time
or near real time and ultimately
where the van stopped oh
let's see yep you can follow it all the
way down and
estimate basically the the entire
duration the entire trajectory of that
attack
um estimating out the mileage the
how far it occurred and potentially the
number of casualties there as well
so i also want to bring up tweetdeck
because i mentioned tweets a lot in that
example
and treetech is great um basically it
creates a number of feeds for you
um you can use different search terms
so in one of these feeds i would
probably just put hashtag barcelona if
that incident was occurring
and get real-time tweets using that
hashtag i would also probably put
another alert in
for um the geocode location of barcelona
so
even if someone doesn't use hashtag
barcelona if they're still tweeting with
that
geolocation on on their phone it'll
still pop up as being in that same area
all right so here's another example
um that's way for all the videos to come
up great so this is back in 2019 when um
mumbai india was having some really
severe monsoon flooding
um so we had some travelers who were in
india at the time
and we were trying to figure out the
best way for them to get back home from
the office
um it was really difficult they ended up
calling us because they
they felt at the office they didn't know
which way to go there was a lot of news
about
streets flooded things like that so we
were asked to advise them
basically on the neighborhoods that are
at least impacted by this monsoon
so that's really difficult because news
articles aren't really updating in real
time like that so we we went to social
media
and we found a lot of live videos um
some near real time videos so like
facebook live is
our live videos uh snapchat maps are
near real time
um snapchat doesn't typically post um in
exactly real time but you can find
videos
from say 10 minutes ago 20 minutes ago
to assess the situation in a certain
area
and then earthkam is another example
i'll show a few examples of basically
city cams that are around the world
um so snapchat map i think most people
probably are familiar with this one so
um let's see snapchat map shows you the
activity that's occurring in a certain
area so
let me just scroll into paris here
and it looks like let's see let's click
on what's what's happening in this
neighborhood of paris all right it looks
like someone's enjoying a
some steak and fries um all right it
looks like
things are normal in this area
looks like a lot of people at this train
station so let's say for example
if there was an incident happening in
this train station you would be able to
just
scroll exactly into that area see if
there are any recent tweets there
um and actually it's funny because i
recognize that train station name as
they went over to it um as a station
that gets evacuated like almost every
weekend
uh due to suspicious packages being left
around
so um let's say if you're responsible
for any travelers going through the
garden or
gerda nord station in paris um and
you're getting tweets about that station
being evacuated
um you could inform your travelers in
real time
all right so snapchat map um covering
earth cam really quick so
um earth cam is a great example of just
one of those city cams
um you guys maybe remember these sites
from like 10 years ago
where people just post like uh live
video feeds from different cities around
the world
so let's click on a popular one here
here's a good map
uh you can search for any particular
cities like if you hear about something
major happening in chicago um
particularly at a major tourist
destination you could go ahead and click
on chicago and
a lot of those destinations just have a
webcam that runs 24 7 over that area
and then similarly to earth cam there's
also worldcams.tv
um same idea same concept um
so if i want to click over to i wonder
let's see what uh shibuya station looks
like in tokyo at the moment
i wonder if it's too dark there right
now
yeah it looks like no one's really on
the street it's probably super early in
japan at the moment
um but let's click on maybe something
with more activity maybe something like
damn square in amsterdam so if you've
got an alert about some incident
happening in amsterdam maybe a major
protest maybe there was unfortunately
an attack um you can zoom in
kind of judge what's happening in the
location are there a lot of people
congregating here
are people running around the city like
crazy do we see a lot of police officers
um things like that um all right so this
is another good example both of these
kind of
live webcam sites um
interestingly i i did want to show this
one um just as an example so this is a
camera at zurich airport again just on
worldcamps.tv
um interestingly some of these cameras
that are connected to the internet you
can actually control
which you would never think that someone
online could control a camera at the
airport
so if i wanted to just for example go
over to this location
it'll pan you right to that location
if you want to go to the tower oh
is it going to bring me there maybe the
tower's offline
but um
yeah basically it's funny that you can
control some of these cameras to
to get a better situation awareness
about what's going on on the ground
there
all right
so this is another example about um a
potentially an incident that was
occurring at los angeles international
airport
for any travelers that were there in
2016 you might remember there was the
active shooter scare
um basically nobody really knows how
this started um
it was just a loud sound and people
started running thinking that it was a
shooter
it could have very well just been
something someone accidentally dropping
their luggage on the ground creating a
large noise and people just started to
disperse
but with that initial information there
were people running out of the airport
evacuating onto the tarmac
you're seeing a lot of tweets social
media that's just the trend nowadays
where uh
as you're in an emergency situation you
know first instinct
maybe you still get out of there and
then second instinct is
share on social media although i think
some people have that reversed where
you're gonna start sharing on social
media before you start to evacuate
um but anyway so um
the icon down on the bottom right is one
that we haven't talked about
and that is the icon for broadcastify
and if you're not familiar with
broadcastify that is
a basically an aggregated online source
of police
radio chat or communications they have
feeds from basically every major police
department around the us
and i think they do have some
international as well so
if you've got you have a domestic
incident in a major city or even a
non-major city
um chances are that there's probably
some police chatter
and some radio that you can tap into
online through broadcastify
you no longer have to be within radio
proximity in order to
collect that information so in this
incident we've received we were
basically hearing that all officers
respond to shooting in progress at lax
that sounds really bad um you know
active shooter
populated area um all officers
responding
um but then as we kind of wait and see
more information we kind of well we've
kind of get the idea that all right the
possible danger
um is maybe in terminal seven six or
five
that's where we see a lot of the running
a lot of the evacuating out to the
tarmac
um a lot of chaos
but then what we see kind of in the
other terminals terminal one terminal
two
terminal three and four um it's a little
bit more calm
people are still evacuating just because
it was a full airport wide evacuation
but nobody is really running all over
the place it seems calm
the nice woman on the bottom left is
calmly directing people
um and then also on broadcastify we hear
uh the phrase
all clear in terminal four so we
basically already know right terminal
four is all clear
no issue there terminal 1 looks like
it's okay terminal 2 looks like it's
okay
so if you're a traveler or if you're
responsible for any travelers who are
scheduled to depart out of lax today
um you already know where the safest
area probably is in the airport so it's
probably not near
terminals five six and seven um but it's
probably closer to one two and three
and if you're evacuating if there's a
lot of chaos people are probably going
in all different directions
um so just to know where there's
potential safety versus a potential
hazard
great information to have when minutes
matter
all right so this is an example of
when i was working again as a security
analyst a lot of our travelers
had an app on their phone where they
could alert us if a security incident
was happening around them
and we would automatically be alerted
start to respond
um and help them out of whatever crisis
they're in so this wasn't the exact
video that was occurring but it's a good
good representation of what we saw um on
their
app when they alerted us what's really
cool with a lot of the apps nowadays
especially the traveler safety apps is
once you hit that sos button it can
record
what's happening kind of on the other
side of your camera for a quick 30
second interval
and also stream that to whoever is um
receiving your sos alert so in this
instance
we get the video and we get the
coordinates of where it's happening
so already very easy plot those
coordinates on a map
all right so i see some difficulty with
this map right here first of all
um my korean is not that great so
i probably wouldn't be able to guide
travelers on where to go in this
incident
so let's think of some other things that
we can do
oh where did that slide go
oh no we're missing a slide here okay so
basically what we did here
is uh we used google street view
and we used bing street view and i think
yandex also has a good street view
another good one is open earth cam and
what we did is we took a street view of
that exact location
and we kind of panned around we got a
360 view of what was happening on that
ground
on the ground there um we can see that
all right over on one side there's a
there's kind of like a market that's
it's only one story the buildings don't
look super secure
um on the other side it's just a field
um
no real cover no real protection no real
shelter and then if you turn again
on the other corner there's a large
building um
which happens to also be uh have an
american flag that you can see outside
and as you zoom in to look at what that
building actually is it's a jw marriott
hotel
it's like a five-star hotel that just
happens to be at this corner here
um so if your job is to advise a
traveler or
anyone what to do in this situation if
they're caught in the middle of a
protest
if the options are a field with no
protection
or a small one-story market with kind of
rickety buildings
or on the other hand you've got the
five-star jw marriott right there
um pretty good idea to have your
traveler just hold out
for a few minutes in the lobby of the
marriott
a lot of the american branded hotels
european branded hotels abroad are very
safe very secure
um they're up to american code and
safety standards
um and especially if you're a traveler
in distress they're gonna try to help
you out even if you aren't staying at
that hotel
so here's another example um back from
istanbul turkey and i'm sure everyone
here remembers the
coup attempt um so
we were first alerted to this incident
and kind of three things were happening
all at once it was a lot of chaos
um so first thing we were hearing about
were jets were bombarding around the
presidential palace in
ankara which all right that's pretty bad
um
even just by itself um
our company at the time we didn't have
any offices we didn't have any travelers
in acura so
we were just monitoring the situation um
but then we started to see a lot of
activity happening in istanbul
where we have a huge office we have a
big supply chain distribution we have a
lot of travelers and employees there
so we just wanted to make sure that all
right is this going to impact our
our staff and our sites there and
ultimately
it did um so in istanbul
versus ankara what we're seeing is a lot
of the police arresting
military military arresting the police
vice versa
um basically martial law to some chaotic
degree
we were also seeing tanks basically
blocking
all of the bridges from the european to
the asian side of istanbul back and
forth
soldiers were blocking a lot of the
major roadways and it turned out to be
a huge incident obviously a coup is not
something that occurs on an everyday
basis
so um kind of interesting story
about one of our travelers um if you
guys recognize this date
that's um 7 15 in istanbul um
if you remember the day before was
actually
the day of the um nice uh terrorist
attacks over in france where the
that um lori or the the truck
rammed through again another large crowd
in nice
we actually had a traveler on this day
the day after he was in nice
during the attack he was coming back to
istanbul through istanbul at a turk
airport today
so he just leaves the scene of one
terrorist attack is flying now
into a coup attempt where the airport
for for a time gets even controlled by
by military
um so he just has the worst luck of any
traveler in the world
but anyway we have to be prepared for
when he finally lands
and um tries to try to find shelter for
him because it's just madness
lots happening on the streets here so he
ended up
getting in a car trying to find some way
to evacuate some
some safe um some safe haven
um he ended up getting caught in some
traffic and there was another blockade
on that road so he really had nowhere to
go at that point
um and the difficulty again we had with
this situation was a little bit of a
language barrier
um some difficulty with street names uh
he was giving us street names
cross sections that that we just could
not tell
in the turkish language like how to
spell that how to find it on the maps
so there's this really interesting kind
of newer company out there
um that provides a free service called
what three words
um what three words.com and
let's say for example i'm already zoomed
into this street um in istanbul
and it's like akikiya
sk i'm sorry i'm pronouncing that
terribly wrong
um i already know it and just imagine if
you're a traveler on an international
phone line and there's a lot of static a
lot of delay
we're not going to be able to understand
each other especially if all the street
names are like this
so about what three words does it's
really cool um what it essentially has
done is it has mapped
every three by three foot square across
the entire
face of the earth so you can click on
any of these cells
um and it gives you a unique three words
um that you can use to communicate and
someone on the other end of the line
can kind of reverse engineer so pocket
stumpy
spines that's a little bit easier to say
than octa cured
moreni um so um
you know there are of course easier
words to say than others and you can
just click around until you find a good
one
so we just have the traveler basically
translate all right
what's in in plain english now what's
the
the location of where you're at so um
it kind of works both ways too you can
you can click on different
locations here and you can use these
locations for travelers and then they
can
translate it back to location on their
end um
or if you have the app on your phone you
can just go to the app
um click the button say where am i and
boom you have the three words right
there
so you can just tell those three words
to anyone on the other end of the line
and they know the exact pretty much
three by three foot square that you're
in at the present time
all right so i do want to quickly spend
the last couple minutes just on vetting
and verifying information because as you
all know open source and social
social media information can be and is
manipulated
all the time so this is one example not
exactly social media that kind of is
kind of our social signals in a way so
obviously google maps crowd sources
their their traffic information
um when when everyone who has the map on
in that location
is stuck in traffic google knows and
updates that traffic for everyone else
so just a funny example here here was
this guy who pulled those 99
iphones around in a trolley um outside
the google berlin
office to try to make it show that there
was a lot of traffic on the street at
the time
as you can see in the pictures there is
nobody on the street
so here's a more serious example of a
major crisis that was occurring
back in 2014 um at the colombian
chemicals plant
and i think it's st mary's parish in
louisiana super small town um
nothing super notable about it sorry if
you're from there
but no real reason why it would be the
epicenter of a major disinformation
campaign
which it was in this incident so all of
a sudden
back in 2014 uh the russian internet
research agency
decided it wanted to either troll or
provide some
um i guess chaos
in the united states maybe they were
testing out some of their social media
disinformation campaigns at the time
but fake cnn websites fake no local news
websites
tweets um even a terrorist video went up
claiming responsibility for this
explosion that happened at columbian
chemicals plant
except what happened what happened was
there was no explosion
everyone in this town was freaking out
because they felt like the major
employer in the town has just exploded
plenty of casualties
um when in fact there was no truth
behind this incident at all there was
just a coordinated misinformed
information and disinformation campaign
uh again perpetrated by this building in
st
petersburg russia that we know now is
the internet research agency
so while i was studying them back in
we can kind of see the impact that they
had now in 2016
and can still continues to go through
this day
so i like to think that was probably
just their first test of a major
coordinated
information attack in the u.s so here
are some
verification techniques um use lots of
sources
look at the right reliability of those
live video is a good indicator but can
still be manipulated
um use reverse image searches a lot of
crisis imagery is recycled from past
incidents
so if you see a tweet that maybe sounds
a little bit far-fetched
reverse image search that see if that
photo was actually used from
an incident that occurred years ago um
so again just quick instructions on how
to do that in chrome you can just right
click the image reverse image search it
so you can see this protest that was
supposedly happening two days ago
um was actually from a photo four years
ago
um i know we're in the last couple
minutes here so just a few more examples
about you know fake news articles how to
spot them um basically all these
examples are fake so in the first
example
uh supposedly headline was italy cracks
down on protests
you can see there are chinese characters
on the street side of the image
and you can also see that twitter handle
is an impersonator account it's
supposedly looking like new york times
it's a c instead of an e so always take
a look uh one more time with those
usernames
uh similarly you know we're looking at
um extremism
lots of uh you know false information
with a fake british
website that image of the cop car has a
france flag on it
and then in the third example this was a
widely spread image after
a an earthquake in taiwan this breaking
news article came out with it saying the
philippines president was killed in a
manila earthquake
um philippines again was felt wrong in
the title so
just some things to look into there um
quick screenshot over on these risk
keywords if you're on monitor on your
own i know we've got just a few seconds
left
based on our analysis most global
security and travel risks occur between
7 am and 10 am eastern time this makes
sense because the us is waking up
europe is already awake and asia is
still up about to go to bed soon
during any other time um on this range
you lose one of the continents because
they're all sleeping all right
and i think we can bring this right
towards the end
um sharpen those skills formalize an
internal training program if you use
these skills for
corporate uh exercise your skills with
simulations and tabletop exercises
there are some great geolocation and
chronolocation games
uh geoguesser is a great one just google
that same with quiz time over on twitter
and also consider some professional
analytical training techniques
um so conferences trainings just like
this one um and
incorporate those structured analytic
methodologies so i'll go ahead and end
it at this point so crisis management
programs whether you know you're an
actual crisis manager
or just a curious mind or a journalist
or a security analyst
you can all use this information to go
from reactive to proactive
qualitative to quantitative and ad hoc
to risk focused
so i'll go ahead and end it at this
point
let me just pull up my information here
feel free to reach out i hope this
information helped you today and you can
use some of these
skills and tools for your day-to-day
activities
all right thanks everyone
thank you paul that was amazing thank
you