well everybody uh i am absolutely
delighted
to be joined by sid windy with his
amazing talk which will
will be an amazing talk um on ocean and
dark web markets
why opsec still matters so the floor is
also doing windy and
uh welcome hey
stu thank you so much for the
introduction uh
so thank you everybody for joining me uh
as stu said this is actually my first
public talk i am really excited um
and so we're going to look at ocean and
dark web markets and kind of show why
you know despite being on dark web
market
your operational security really does
still matter
so just a little bit about me first um
i'm an ocean practitioner i come from a
traditional intelligence background
and i spent most of my career sort of
bouncing around from
uh different parts of the public sector
different military government and law
enforcement agencies
and so more recently i've actually
switched over to the private sector
where i'm currently a strategic analyst
for a major tech company
and there i focus on a particular subset
of cybercrime
i don't really have much of an online
presence however your best bet is to
find me on twitter
under the same handle as sendwindy
and on the bottom there you know we
gotta have the disclaimer
keep in mind as we go through this
everything in this speak
this talk it's my own views my own
opinions my own comments
and it doesn't represent anyone that i
may or may not have worked for at any
point in my career
all right so first off what is the dark
web market
uh well in the simplest terms it's
exactly as the name implies
uh it is a marketplace that is hosted on
the dark web
and so these type of markets are often
attracted to dark web platforms
especially with tor partly due to the ip
anonymization that tor provides
and so it makes it a little bit more
difficult for law enforcement to
identify their targets
these marketplaces also tend to heavily
rely on cryptocurrencies
rather than say you know traditional
debit or credit cards
uh to make that money trails a little
bit more difficult though
not impossible for investigators to
follow
and while these marketplaces might
contain some legitimate goods and
services
instead honestly they tend to be stuck
to the brim with more illicit items
things such as drugs malware
fake identity documents uh counterfeit
banknotes
user data passwords hacked and cracked
accounts you know
those sort of things and so i feel like
there's this common misconception that
dark web users are generally safe from a
rest
right because oh hey you know i'm using
tor i have encrypted messaging
i'm using cryptocurrency you know people
think that
they're going to be fully protected and
they can sort of rest easy simply by
relying on these technological
safeguards to protect them
well that doesn't appear to be the case
there is absolutely no shortage of dark
web arrest headlines out there
so how exactly are these users being
arrested
despite what some people might think
these arrests are not caused by
usually a flaw or a back door within tor
nor are law enforcement agencies using
some sort of like technological wizardry
to identify these users
and instead it tends to be good
old-fashioned investigative work
combined with some failures in
operational security
that have led to the downfall of many of
these dark web markets and vendors
so keeping that in mind what i want to
do we're going to take a look at three
case examples
of different users on the dark web in
which they made some critical object
mistakes
and then we're gonna follow each one of
them up with some tips and techniques
uh that would help a new osun analyst in
exploiting similar opsec mistakes
should they choose to pick up an
investigation on a dark web market
all right so i think honestly it would
be a disservice to talk about dark web
markets
and not mention what is arguably the
most famous of the dark web marketplaces
so i want to kick the case examples off
with the silk road administrator dread
pirate roberts
and so the silk road launched back in
early 2011
and it was the first major dark web
market to really take off
it garnered a lot of attention both from
the users
as well as from law enforcement and so
this attention
probably played a pretty big role in why
the original silk road only lasted a
little over two years
before the site was shut down by law
enforcement and the administrator dred
pirate roberts
was arrested so for this case example
we're going to look at one of
dread pirate roberts more notable opsec
mistakes which is actually the reuse of
online identifiers
and see how it played a role in his
identification and later arrest
okay so during the course of the
investigation into the initial silk road
marketplace
special agents were just sort of poking
around the internet
in an attempt to locate some of the
earliest known references to this dark
web marketplace
they managed to locate two threads
posted right around the same time as
silk road's initial launch
one was on shroomery.org and the other
one was on bitcointalk.org
so as you can see they both follow a
similar pattern of wording
almost like an advertisement for the
silk road marketplace
and they're both made under the same
username of altoid
and they were both made only about two
days apart
so the language used in these posts it
almost suggests users looking to attract
visitors
or obtain feedback on the silk road
marketplace
with one of these posts even ending with
the phrase let me know what you think
and so i want to point out at this point
it's not too much of a stretch right to
assume that
someone posting under two forums using
the same exact username
just posted days apart only talking
about the same topic
that they could likely be the same
person right
so a couple months pass altoid comes
back to bitcoin talk
and he decides to post again however
this time he's seeking to hire some
it pros for what he's referring to as a
quote
venture back bitcoin startup company
i'll give you one hint to what that
startup company is
uh one guess so although provides his
email which is
rossulbrite gmail.com within this post
so that anyone can interested in
applying can reach out to him directly
and follow up with an email
well we know now that this email address
posted by altoid
was later associated to the silk road
admins real identity
and it was kind of one of those puzzle
pieces that allowed law enforcement to
identify this marketplace administrator
agents were able to pivot off of this
email address to find albright's other
social media profiles
some of which contained additional
information that sort of corroborated
the suspicion
that albright was indeed dread pirate
roberts
and so one of the bits of information
that really strengthened this theory was
this
apparent shared interest for the mises
institute
and dread pirate robert's signature on
the silk road forum
included a link including a reference to
the mises institute
well investigators also observed while
looking into the ross albright email
that the google plus account and the
youtube account associated
also included a playlist that oddly
enough had a video
posted by the mises institute and so
you know admittedly this is all very
circumstantial however having some of
these threads
along with some other things to pull on
it allowed law enforcement to eventually
put albright under surveillance and
they were able to actually confirm him
as red pirate roberts later on
so knowing this uh let's take a look at
how
we can take some similar steps to
collect and pivot off of
very similar breadcrumbs in our own
investigations
so as we saw in our albright example
users tend to reuse identifiers
whether it's usernames email addresses
whatnot across different platforms
and this could occur for many you know
many reasons
it might be just due to laziness it's
convenient to reuse something you
already have you don't want to make a
new account
but at the same time it could also be
due to maybe this prestige or some
trustworthiness
that you established under that moniker
previously
and this this is actually particularly
true on the dark web where
your reputation especially as a vendor
means everything
and so because of that you're going to
be less likely to change your moniker as
you move from marketplace to marketplace
now knowing this we can actually search
for similarly used usernames and emails
to locate
additional accounts for our target where
perhaps they practice less than ideal
opsec
and for dark web market identifiers we
don't really need to treat them much
differently than those we already run
across on the surface web
and instead we can actually fall back on
some tried and true methods
for example we can use username
enumeration tools something such as
what's my name
to locate the same username on a variety
of different platforms
and i've also found that a simple query
of that same username in quotations
you know run across a couple different
search engines tends to help
catch many of those that these
enumeration tools might have missed
for email reuse you can also do the same
throw it into quotes
across a couple search engines i also
find it's a very good idea to remove the
domain at the end of the email
and treat that as a username as well
for direct email reuse you can also
query
some specific email lookup tools
something such as
melissa's data or that's them
one thing i do want to point out that is
different though about a dark web target
is we have already confirmed that they
have a dark web presence
right you know considering we originally
ran across them on the dark web
so for this reason i would also suggest
running any of these identifiers you
find
through dark web search engines
something maybe like torch
or recon and also be sure to check the
usernames on dread as well
just to make sure you're covering all
your bases
and then once you've located all the
pieces uh all the places
in which a target exists both on the
clear net as well as on the dark web
then you can really start digging deeper
into these profiles and their posts
to gather additional information to
pivot off of
okay so next up our next case example
was actually from alphabay
and just for some quick background alpha
bay launched back in 2014
it lasted up until around 2017 and it
was actually seized along with a number
of other dark web markets as part as a
big sweeping operation known as
operation bayonet
and following silk road seizure a number
of dark web marketplaces kind of popped
up to take its place
and during this sort of you know dark
web marketplace boom that was occurring
they tried to learn from their
predecessor's mistakes and
many started incorporating or enforcing
the use of some additional security
methods
to try and prevent any further seizures
arrests from occurring on their specific
platforms
and these methods vary from marketplace
to marketplace
it could be something as simple as
utilizing a more anonymous payment
method
uh maybe something such as the
cryptocurrency monero
which doesn't have the easily trackable
public ledger like bitcoin does
or maybe they require their users to
encrypt all correspondence
using pretty good privacy or pgp and
that's actually what we're going to
focus on for our next case example
so even today many many marketplaces
rely heavily on pgp
to encrypt the correspondence between
the buyers and the sellers
and this is a sort of mitigate the risk
of data leakage
uh the idea is you know should law
enforcement intercept the messages
or even seize the server they that
they're sitting on
that they wouldn't be getting this huge
treasure trove of plain text messages
they might have identifiable content
something such as the addresses used for
shipping
but at the same time this also opens up
an additional avenue and an additional
point of exploitation for ocean
investigators
and one such vendor that kind of learned
this the hard way was the alpha bay
vendor dark apollo
now this particular vendor was offering
heroin and cocaine on alpha bay
and like most vendors they they posted
their public pgp key
so that customers could encrypt the
messages they were sending to them
however dark apollo made a very fatal
flaw when he set up his key pairs
and he generated them using an email
address
that when you remove the domain actually
match some of those other clearweb
social media handles
and this is actually one of the reasons
i suggest you know removing the domain
from the end of the email and treating
it as a username
so after extracting the email address
from the public pgp key
law enforcement were able to find
similar handles on twitter
facebook instagram that not only
belonged to dark apollo
but it contained his real name and his
current location information
as well now
let's take this particular case example
of dark apollo and i want to use it to
walk through the same steps
to show just how you extract this
information from a public pgp key
so for starters you need a public pgp
key
and you can get this a number of ways
some vendors might include this on their
storefront
in their forum signature if not you can
actually also search for
a pgp key if you know the username via
the
recon dot onion website and luckily
enough for us
dark apollo's public pgp key is still
available here via recon
so as you see on the the right there
that ptp key
where it says begin pgp key public key
block
and it is cut off but you're going to
want to copy all of that text
into whatever the text editor of your
choices
and once you do that you're going to
want to save that as a dot asc file
and so from here you can extract the
email or whatever other information was
given
when the user generated the pgp key
pairs by simply importing that asc file
into software
something like cleopatra maybe or you
can also extract it via the command line
depending on your operating system so
for example
on a db machine you can simply open the
terminal and run the command gpg
dash dash import and then point it to
the location.asc file
and so despite many dark web users now
being fully aware
that there are risks associated with
including real information here
i still regularly find legitimate
clarinet emails using this simple
technique
and that being said because a real email
is not required here
users might pick a fake email they might
put
a red herring email you might find
gibberish
and i personally have seen my fair share
of not so nice messages they've been
left for investigators
all right and and finally for our last
case example we got a vendor here known
as cannabars
who was on both dream and hanson
marketplaces
now you know canon bars i mean he
offered the gamut of drugs
everything from marijuana codeine
xanax crystal methamphetamine uh he
he had quite a bit of stuff on these two
marketplaces and a number of factors did
play into his identification
a lot of traditional undercover
purchases were done
they traced some of its bitcoin cash
outs but i want to focus on a very
particular
photo that the vendor had posted
so the initial investigation in canada
bars began on dream marketplace
and during this investigation one thing
that the investigator noticed
was that canada bars actually had a
review on dream market
from what appeared to actually be a sale
of
on honza market and so prior to this
investigation the dutch police had
actually arrested the administrators of
hanza
they had seized the servers and they
were running this marketplace for about
a month or so
as sort of a honeypot to collect any
additional information to make more
arrests
so having known this the investigator
looking in the can of bars reached out
to the dutch counterparts
seeking you know any information they
might have on this particular target
so the investigator sends the request
out gets a response back and while
sifting through all this data
they came across a request from a
potential customer which was sent to
canada bars
asking him for some additional photos of
the marijuana he was selling and
in response to this the vendor links an
imager album containing some additional
photos
now as you can see from the photos on
the screen here these images
at least don't have a whole lot of
information that we can pivot off of
they pretty much just show the product
only however
in the same imager album there are a
couple more photos in which
canon bars is actually seen holding the
marijuana in his hand
so you know the photos you guys are
seeing here do not do them justice
they are of a pretty high resolution
good quality
and so what law enforcement did they
downloaded the high resolution photos
from imager and they submitted those
images to the forensic lab
the lab then analyzed the fingerprints
in the photo and found that they
actually matched
fingerprints already on file for candle
bars from a prior arrest that was made
and so since these photos are still
publicly available what i want to do is
we're going to go through some of the
steps that i took the using nothing more
than open source software
to extract these fingerprints from these
photos
and i do want to point out that although
the fingerprints are known to belong to
candlebars
i have still partially redacted them a
bit just to give him a little bit of
privacy
however you should still be able to see
enough of these images that you can
follow along with how each step looks
in order to replicate it yourself should
you choose to
all right and before we get started i do
think i need to reiterate here
you do need a high resolution photo for
this technique
this is not csi miami right zoom enhance
will not get you very far
if the fingerprint information is not
already in the photos
so step one what we need to do is we're
gonna upload that high quality photo
into the [ __ ] photo editing software
once you've done that you're going to
actually desaturate the image
and so the reason i do this it's going
to make it easier to see our changes
as we go through me playing the photo
following that we're actually going to
want to invert this image
and the reason we're inverting this
image is because we're actually wanting
to extract the ridges of the fingerprint
we're not as concerned about the valleys
and so if we're going to if we're going
to trace the ridges we want them to be
the darkest part of this photo
after that we're going to really crank
up the brightness and the contrast of
the image and as you can see those those
ridges of the fingerprint are starting
to kind of peak their way out we're
starting to see them a little bit
but we can still we can we can still do
better than this
so the final step we're going to take in
[ __ ] is to apply a sharpen mask
and that really makes our ridges pop out
we're almost there at that point
um however what we're going to do is
we're going to save this image
and we're going to import it into
inkscape instead
once we get it into inkscape we're going
to apply the trace bitmap function to
the image
and as you can see it just removes those
last bits of gray left and leaves us
only with the black ridges and the white
valleys of our fingerprint
it also gives us a vector that we can
resize later for our comparison
and so that's pretty much the steps that
we know we're taking to extract this
fingerprint
but how do we use this information
so if you have multiple high resolution
photos which have visible fingerprints
you can extract
this technique can be used to compare
the two prints for a match simply by
resizing them
you know you can overlay them on top of
each other or
lay them side by side see where they
intersect see where they match up
uh keep in mind though that due to a
photo's lighting and their shadows
you're never going to have a perfect
match right
and so for this reason i am actually
more likely to use this technique to
disprove a possible match
rather than using it to correctly
identify one of my targets
and as you can see in our example here
we got two separate fingerprints that
have been extracted
when we compare them side by side down
the middle we can see that they
you know they're not in fact the same
print um the bottom does actually match
up pretty well
but as you move up towards the middle
and near the top you can see that the
ridges
don't quite match up
and so that's actually all i have in
terms of case studies
however before i open up for some
questions i do want to leave you all
with
a little bit of words of wisdom that i
that i find are applicable
whether you're an ocean analyst a law
enforcement officer
uh or even a dark web vendor and that is
simply that
you know a rest will continue until
opsec improves
and so with that uh yeah thank you guys
for joining me
i'll pass it over to stu to see if we
happen to have any questions
okay my my uh my jaw just dropped like
literally for the first time
in like a long time when you just did
the fingerprints thing um
i actually do i don't have no reason to
but i've always been um
every time i took photos online and it's
on social media and stuff i always mask
out my fingerprints anyway not because i
have anything to hide
but because i don't want someone else
looking at fingerprints as a way of
identifying you things like this right
so yeah i just can't believe people
don't do that normally
but now i know why they do because uh
wow that was
that was super impressive um amazing
um okay i've got i've got a question
while i wait
um uh oh there's loads of questions now
coming in which is brilliant okay i mean
for your first talk can i just say that
was that was
phenomenal that was an amazing talk
thank you very much
thank you if you know if someone wants
to
to kind of pick up on these kind of
techniques or wants to
to kind of get into you know maybe law
enforcement investigation things like
this what what should they
start doing to kind of pick up their
skills
i think for one thing is you should
really leverage what you already know
um for those who don't know i actually
started off with an art background
that's how i initially went to school i
did art and computer science
and so when i started looking into
investigative roles i looked into those
that included
you know for one computer science uh i
did lots of
analysis of like you know code i've done
i've used some of my art skills to not
only extract fingerprints but
you know extract text from maybe
an image that was a piece of paper that
was upside down
and so you couldn't quite see what the
image on the
piece of paper said but by using some
known photo manipulation techniques i
was able to actually flip the image
and extract the text to be able to read
it
so i've actually been able to leverage a
lot of my not
so much investigative techniques and
skills but brought them over
when i started doing investigations so i
think leverage what you already know
yeah that's amazing yeah our background
that would be really really useful for
this
um amazingly so um rags got a question
as well
um i thought i might switch my camera on
so there you go
uh rag's got a question um
he said to me have you found a greater
degree in personal risk
uh uh while from investigating.net
actors uh personally no um
and this might be giving a little bit
away here i'm a huge fan of
misinformation
so anytime i set stuff up you know i
like to use usernames for example
to when you search them that you're not
going to get a hit
uh and altoid with dark with uh dread
power ops is a great example you do is
google search for altoid
what are you going to find you're going
to find advertisements in the website
for the altoid candy
so i'm a big fan of using this
information to kind of protect myself
when i'm doing those kind of
investigations
i also like to use you know the standard
you know virtual machines
tor vpns everything's a burner at that
point
i don't reuse anything whether it's a
username
an email address i also like putting
numbers at the end of everything to make
it a little bit more difficult so i know
i can't repeat it
um but yeah you know burn everything
after you use it
yeah absolutely what what's your kind of
best opsec
kind of obviously talking about you know
attackers making upset mistakes but
obviously for investigators you know
what is your kind of top three opsec
kind of dudes i guess um
talk to your family first and foremost
you you would be surprised how many
people
you know especially people who are
breaking the law practice really well
on their own opsec and then you find out
that
their you know their girlfriend their
spouse
their you know their mother most of the
time actually
practice this horrible opsec and you can
actually go you know once you pivot to
their accounts
you can find so much information on your
target that the target is actually not
sharing himself
so always look for that person who's
like one level removed
and in my experience it's usually the
mother who's the best or sometimes the
the ex-girlfriend those are usually the
ones that uh
kind of lead you know lead them astray
other than that
um so after after you've kind of you
know cleaned up your
your parents and you know the
girlfriends and such have them clean up
their opsec
another thing i think that's really
really helpful is
don't reuse your email for personal
things
and sketchy things um if you're going to
do something illegal you know we always
we always joke if you're going to do
if you're gonna break the law only break
one law at a time
and so if you're gonna make an opsec
mistake only make one at a time because
when they start stacking up
um it gets worse and worse and you're
more likely to get caught so
you know practic practice good hygiene
don't don't
intermingle personal accounts with stock
puppets that kind of thing
um and i think other than those are
probably my two biggest
yeah i think other things that catch
people out right especially don't don't
mix your legends basically it's the kind
of key one isn't it
yep yeah i've seen those posts where uh
it was that employee from um
bbc or something like that that
basically had a fake account and then
actually logged in and managed to post
the same
reply to a thread with their with their
actual live account or something
um yeah it was pretty bad right uh
okay i'm just gonna check for other
questions because this is amazing
um i think you scared everyone that's
the problem
no one wants to talk
uh with the crazy fingerprints um
okay if i can't any more questions
before before we wrap up
no okay
i think everyone's just deleting
themselves off the internet so you can't
find them so i think that's been a
that's a good talk right um said wendy
look seriously that that was
a superb talk um really really good
really interesting um i think you should
definitely do more talks
um because it was it was fantastic thank
you mate
seriously and and also you should bring
back the uh the ocean
mondays geolocation stuff but
that's just a personal thing i got i got
plans for that it's in the works
ah okay more questions coming in now
they go um
okay some questions now here we go um
how do you build
and age profiles
um unfortunately if you're asking that
right now it's kind of too late
uh no so um
it depends i know i'm gonna touch
specifically on facebook here because
it's kind of the the worst in my
experience for aging
they usually tend to hit your sock
puppets pretty quick compared to anybody
else
um i like to use photos
that's not a face and
you know i know there's that you know
this person does not exist can be
helpful but
i think they're getting a little bit
better at finding those so you know if
you're trying to use a female profile
you know maybe some high heels if you're
trying to use a male profile you know
i found that like those stock vector
images from like tattoos
work pretty well um and
you you to keep from getting banned you
need to make it look legitimate
so if you come in early on with a
tor vpn node or something that just
looks sketchy
you're going to get banned pretty quick
so if you can find
a you know a burner phone number to add
validation that's going to help out
if you can make it you know treat it
like a real account for a little while
like a couple things
maybe add a couple friends you know if
you're able to
just just to kind of make it look a
little bit more legitimate and
don't make too many changes at one time
if you go from having everything based
out of say
california you put california as your
information for your location using the
california vpn
and then all of a sudden you know you've
pivoted and now you're in the
netherlands
that might get called out um that might
be seen as suspicious so so make
incremental steps as you're as you're
aging your accounts
don't do anything like all at once
that's really good advice um yeah i
create profiles right
for uh for sock puppets things like this
so you have like a vpn profile for sock
puppets you can log in from the same
location each time
yep another question as well um
uh it's a bit of a weird one so i'll ask
you anyway have you upset failed
absolutely um
yeah and i don't remember if i've i've
mentioned this before anywhere else but
i made the mistake at one point of
logging in this was years and years ago
i logged into a
a sock puppet and i had not turned on my
vpn when i did so
and so i was coming off from the same ip
address that my personal
at the time was my personal facebook
account and after like
two or three hours i saw my sock puppet
actually pop up in the people you may
know
so so yeah it's it's crazy you know
on the back end some of the things they
can use to kind of
bring accounts together such as you know
an ip address that says we're in the
same location so you guys might want to
be friends
yeah and that can also be useful for
when you're investigating people as well
at the same time absolutely
all right i think i think that's it for
questions um i i just again
like to thank you amazing talk seriously
um and
um oh there is one more question here we
go i will do that question then i'm
going to wrap it up
um can you fix identity issues for
people after
creds released
so that's not something that i really do
however
one thing you know going back to
misinformation disinformation
i found that that's been very helpful so
when i when i go to scrub my information
off the internet um
it shows back up you know days or weeks
later because there's a there's another
person who's selling it
you have to kind of get to the source i
found that you know kind of poisoning
the well helps
um if you can when you sign up for stuff
i use
part of my real information and part
fake information so that
you know when someone pulls a like a
lexus nexus report on me for example
um they're getting hundreds of pages
with different names different email
addresses some of which are real
some which are not um you know it looks
at that point like there's like 40
people living in a one bedroom apartment
so i'm a big fan of poisoning the well
you know once your information has been
has been linked it's kind of hard to
bring it all back so just kind of
throwing some misinformation
or some disinformation to to kind of you
know make it a little bit harder to get
the the real information
i think on that note that's a perfect
time to end your talk
so look thank you very much it is
amazing um
for a first talk that's a blinder
seriously you should be proud it's
really really good um and uh are you
gonna hang around for the rest of the
day or
yeah i'll be here for a little while
okay excellent if you've got more
questions then you know you can ask that
in the
twitch chat or discord or whatever it
may be but uh
thank you sid windy it's been an
absolute pleasure and thanks for thanks
for supporting our conference as well i
really appreciate it
thanks thanks