welcome back
to conant track one we are here today
with will thomas from zyjax
he's going to talk about using
intelligence to defend against
ransomware to me sounds pretty awesome
but
let's see how it goes will over to you
buddy
thanks dean uh hello everyone welcome i
hope you're enjoying conan
this is my talk about ransomware and
gathering intelligence
i currently work as a security
researcher for uh scijacks a uk
based uh threat intelligence company and
uh i'm a moderator of uh many house club
and i've really been enjoying the
conference so
let's get into it so just to start with
everyone loves a good meme especially
ones about ransomware
uh i like the ransomware operator
starter pack you know it's just
it's got everything you need there good
to go for starting your ransomware
campaigns
okay so what this is what gathering
intelligence looks like
when you're talking about ransomware
groups and where what you need to look
for and where from
you've got the you know ransomware is
it's a entire cyber criminal ecosystem
it's not just
one separate groups running campaigns
it's it's multiple
threat actors that specialize in their
own sectors
and you know it's divided up between
access the actual
development of the ransomware itself
development of the malware
and you know using the malware in
attacks you know all these things can be
gathered from the different
parts of the internet pretty much
including the dark net
forums communities such as like cti
league
um social media such as twitter it's
always a good source of intelligence
uh mainstream mainstream news you know
reuters
and that usually first to report on
these major things
and uh vendors as well for iocs and
and new tactics techniques and
procedures uh ttps
once once you have collected all this
from these sources
you then analyze it and you understand
what
what you're actually dealing with here
and uh
you know narrative based analysis what's
what with these groups done before where
it's come from why is it important
and then you pass it off as as
intelligence to your clients
who can then use it for mitigation of
their systems and prevent
these attacks from actually happening
so what is ransomware how does it work
and why is it so
successful um you know kaspersky
basically did a
pretty good diagram here basically
encapsulating everything
about how these ransomware as a service
platforms work
uh you know it's different teams working
together um
you know these these groups can be split
up between access brokers data brokers
exploit brokers and the actual malware
developers themselves
uh the main one of the biggest issues
with
ransomware is how they get in so initial
access
initial access uh like how do they get
in rdp brute forcing
is uh usually one of the the favorites
but you know it also includes phishing
for malware deployment such as like
emote trick bot drydex you know and then
once those malware are in the system
they can be sold as access
to the ransomware gangs and then
ransomware's deployed on the network
um they also exploit remote services
such as you know vpns
uh microsoft sharepoint and exchange um
but you know these groups are so well
funded now that they use
zero-day vulnerabilities and they don't
have to develop them themselves they can
buy them from someone else
so you know public sector notifications
uh you know regarding these ransomware
groups because they are now the top
tier threats you know you know you're
not so worried about
you know nation state espionage
campaigns as much
as uh you know ransomware because it's
much more likely to happen you're gonna
get struck with ransomware
and um you know these are organized
cybercrime
groups organized crime um you know the
guy
in the bottom left here is uh also known
as aqua
the evil corp uh guy he's also known as
the guy with the
the lambo he's uh he
uh owes an investigation into him which
i've linked in the references
uh uncovered his wife for instagram
for a very uh particular
logo in her car and very unique
coloration of the interior
and the location and in further
investigation into this found out that
she is actually
connected to one of the heads of the fsb
uh who's
you know pictured there vladimir putin
so these ransomware gangs are actually
really well connected and protected and
you know these threats are not going
away
so who are the ransomware operators um
these are
uh split between cyber crime groups
from or like mainly from russia and
eastern europe but you know
those gangs also have connections around
the world you know
south america uh asia you know
even the americas you know the
[Music]
the uh yeah you also got like the
state-sponsored groups
they as as well as cyber crime you've
got the state-sponsored groups that
you know they use ransomware either
financially but like
like from iran and north korea or as
disruption like
um the sand worm team that from the gr
also known as the gru
unit um as well as um you know chinese
speaking threat actors
using ransomware such as cold lock and
i'm freezing there and one of the most
uh
successful uh ransomware operators are
the the combination between the emote
downloader trojan the trickbot banking
trojan which is basically a malware
distribution
network as well uh with and then that
usually leads to the riot ransomware
which has costed organizations millions
over the years
and then you also have ics and scada
targeting ransomware
so like the mega top mega cortexes and
yakins
and you know these target your
industrial control systems
and you know one when those goes down it
costs millions of dollars in damages so
that's why they target them
so the largest ransomware attacks of the
quarter one
quarter three uh to of 2020
include a whole range of sectors pretty
much any sector whether
where they can extort the data um you
know you've got the travel x1
in early january i think it was new
year's day they got struck by uh rival
ransomware
and you know that one personally
affected me because i i went to heathrow
and i went into the travel x there and
i could see them all there like using
their pens and paper
and you know they're all just stressed
out and it was horrible you know
so yeah there's a whole range of sectors
they go after and huge brands that i'm
sure
you'll recognize their honda cannon
ubersoft uh uhs
universal health services 400 hospitals
were
affected by that one
uh you've got so here are the ransomware
leak blocks so
since november ransomware has been using
um
data theft and extortion hybrid attacks
so you know since since since they've
began this they will
not only will they infiltrate your
network they will persist and steal
data for months or weeks or months or
you know override weekend
and um and then when they encrypt your
network they will also extort
your extort the data they have stolen by
publishing them on these leak blocks
so you've got 14 link blogs here
and uh they are that there's more the
i think the ragnarok ransomware that you
just came out two or three days ago
that you know they're coming they're
popping up here and there all the time
and the data
exposed in these leaks inc are really
really really
massive you've got gigabytes of data all
types of sensitive information
card credit cards passports intellectual
property
emails communication and you know that
just
it just gets uploaded every single day
um like let's start with the
uh one of the most infamous ones is the
maze ransomware they actually started
the data
theft extortion hybrid attack they they
pioneered it and they
worked with other groups basically uh
the ragnarok ran somewhere they've
worked with them
and they're responsible for attacks on
canon lg orange this and crap you know
recognizable brands
so the anatomy of a leak site is uh
it includes the current leaks uh so
basically if
if they have encrypted a network they
will then
you know try to extort the the customer
or the
they call them customers um and into
paying the ransom so if the if the
client is still
dealing with the attack um then they
will publish the data
or threaten to publish the data say like
you have three days until we publish it
so it's just like an extra bit of
pressure on them
and try to really force them to to pay
out because they don't want
you know passports of employees and
emails and passwords and everything
going out there
and anyone who doesn't pay it goes into
the archive so it's there forever
pretty much and it like even if you took
this one site down
you you can see that you've got your
duplicate size your tour mirrors
um so you know that data is not going
away
and here's just an example of a part of
the ransomware as a service offering the
decryption site
so once your network's been encrypted
there'll be a note and they're in the
link there'll be
you know a link to the description site
and this is basically where
you go to get your files once you've
paid the ransom
and um you know it says there the price
can actually be negotiated like these
cyber criminals they think they are
businessmen and they think they can
uh you know like swindle you out amount
of money in in
multiple ways
and here's example of the control panel
so as i was saying
the the maze ransomware developers are
actually the ones who
create the malware handle the payments
handle the decryption
they actually what they will actually be
working with other
other cyber criminal teams or
individuals or groups
and you know this obscures attribution
because
every time that something gets hit by
maze you just think oh it's the maze
ransomware gang
no actually it's like three four five
however many groups that are using maze
so i want to do like a bit of a case
study here of
uh my investigation into
uh a ransomware developer and just sort
of try and
understand this more and provide it as
intelligence to our clients so
they can understand better like the
threat
and stop it from actually affecting them
so talking about the the thanos
ransomware
uh through ocean i was able to
you know one day whilst monitoring i get
a pop-up of these uh
bits of intelligence really um from
security researchers and journalists and
and what comes up on the on the malware
forums
um the the developer popped up on
on the 17th of november 2019 saying that
he's very pleased to offer
a new product so that's interesting and
then
pivoting off that you can look at the
username and and the tech
text analysis and try and find if it's
been advertised anywhere else
and then you've got this is what we
found basically through pivoting off
that
you're able to look at the usernames
look at the images of the logos on the
profiles
and the titles and you're able to
basically
build up a picture of this operation and
find out more
more intelligence from doing this
i was able to uncover the ransomware
builder this is actually where
this is the little bit of kit that is
used to basically create your
custom version of the thanos ransomware
includes like
what extensions to encrypt and you know
what you actually
want to append to the to the
file and then you've got the control
panel like we saw with mace
and then also while i was investigating
this ransomware offer i found that he's
also developing a banking trojan as well
so he's like a highly skilled veteran
malware developer
and through further pivoting of those
bits of intelligence we've got the
usernames elsewhere email addresses
forum names you know he's also
responsible for the silver crypter
which is what is used to basically
further obscure your malware code and
encrypt it
so that it bypasses antivirus and the
edr and things like that
and it's also connected to the the the
same account there posted
another information stealer there it's a
loader and a grabber and
probably is also advertised in part of
their campaigns
so here's an example of the ransomware
operator and
access brokers working together through
the forums
you've got access as a service this was
was like to be called
where one user will post
all the types of access they have um so
selling that so the post they're selling
network
full access domain admin um you know
you've got
the revenue of the company the the type
is hospitals you know revenue one
billion domain admin
price um and then underneath you've got
the ransomware author who's saying he
vouches for him
and because the access broker and the
ransomware author are actually both
looking for clients and they they are
both offering a service
so you know this is this is how
the under under underground cyber
criminal operations work
and the types of access that they offer
includes vpns pulse secure and citrix
those are two very
popular vpns that had very quick hike
highly critical
vulnerabilities were disclosed early
this year and last year which have been
used in multiple
campaigns and then other things like
credentials and
web shells and and other things like
that
so the other the threat reports are also
important
when gathering intelligence because you
want to build up a picture you want to
build up the narrative
of what is going on and to support uh
you're looking for what other
firms have found to support your um
your your hypothesis really and then
you've got
so from here looking through these
reports um who
who you know these firms actually have
sandboxes and
and uh constantly monitoring and that
they have
like detection systems on clients all
over the world so they're actually able
to pick up samples
very easily and provide really detailed
technical analysis
um so what we also know about the
finance ransomware from here
is that uh it's a ransomware affiliate
program that's what it calls itself
um it uses aes advanced encryption
standard which
cannot be decrypted it like it requires
very powerful uh decryption
tools to be able to get past that so
and and then you've got uh the targets
the uh mena countries middle east and
north and africa
from unit 42 there and then other
techniques and capabilities the
ransomware is capable of
one of the most recent reports from
clear sky said that it's connected to
the muddy water
advanced persistent threat group from
iran so
we know that these cyber criminals
actually work with state-sponsored
operatives
uh i put an asterisk there because that
it
it's basically it's unconfirmed but it
there's a every everything is pointing
to it
so what and so what have we like
what have we actually learned from
looking at a ransomware operator
we know that the threat actor is
responsible for developing distributing
and advertising the ransomware
they are continuously like updating and
developing the ransomware
making sure new features are available
and to make sure it has a low detection
rating that's always a key
part that they try to push to their
customers and try to attract customers
you also so so what what's the point of
this why why do we want to know about
this so
we know that the the ransomware as a
service market is a growing threat
it's attracting more and more cyber
criminals uh more features will be added
to the ransomware to attract customers
so one thing that thanos added was an
mbr locker master boot record
locker so basically when like
one of the winner team uses the mbr
locker on a customer
or on an organization such as a hospital
something like that
then it actually deletes the sort the
actually deletes the software in between
the operating system and the hardware so
you know
you can't actually turn on your computer
once they've hit you with that
and you know the only way out of it
really is paying the ransom
and they also try to add
uh they're trying to build the community
up around their services you know it
there is it does come with the risk they
do
expose themselves to you know the rest
of the internet
but you know it comes with the reward of
attracting clients and making money
really
these they're all about making money
and and you know other things we learn
about monitoring
a uh raz like this is that they rely on
communication with their customers
and they and like most net markets the
trust needs to be maintained so you know
if if a customer goes along and
pays for the ransomware and then the guy
never gives it to them
you know his reputation is lost and
people won't trust him
they won't make any more money
whilst whilst we also monitor we found
video demonstrations
you know this is it's to prove you know
is to
boost his reputation and prove that it
actually works
um they also were able to receive
feedback from
from forum users and and other platforms
so that you know
they a customer will be like i want to
add
i want to make sure that it's got a
custom
encryption algorithm or something like
that so you know they can implement it
other malware we found offered by the
ransomware author
uh as i said silver crypto nemesis
uh rem cross uh rats which is uh open
source but i'm pretty sure they modified
it the quasar rats also modified
chimera crypto another crypto and
that unknown banking trojan which you
are actually yet to see
um we've also got the aliases for the
for the operator as well
um there
so like i want to talk about one example
of how it goes from access
a sale of access to an example of a
ransomware attack
so it goes from so bank security here
great to account on twitter you know i
really really recommend anyone who works
in
uh threat intelligence to follow this
account because he's always giving away
good bits of information and for
in this case he was actually able to
provide
you know this actually could have
stopped the ransomware attack on the
bank
he notified he noticed that a forum user
was had access web shell access to a
bank located in chile
you know you always have to take these
at a pinch of salt but
you know it's very i know it's very um
it's not always they don't
just post it to you know be a troll or
something like that i'll try and
bait users and they are actually selling
things trying to make money at the end
of the day
and if this bit of intel's actually make
able to make it to the
bank in chile they wouldn't have been
hit by reeve or ransomware
banco estado you know like the next day
if you look at the times there you've
got six at six of september 2020 it's
the 7th of september 2020 if that
intel was actually able to make it to
them then they could have
stopped it so you know that's the is
exemplifies the importance of threat
intelligence when you're trying to
defend your organization
especially against ransomware which is
one of the biggest threats
so i just want to you know reflect and
think about you know ransomware and how
it's
you know how it's one of the biggest
threats and it's not going away it's
only growing
um and it's that you know they're
they're modifying their campaigns and
they're trying new things one of the
most recent is they're starting to also
ddos
attack as well so
yeah is there is there any questions
just checking there well
thank you
i'm just gonna i'm gonna chime in as
well uh well that was
awesome by the way really good talk
really interesting as well
thank you thank you one question here
straight away from angus red
how do you stay so chill
how do i stay so chill when when do you
when dealing with ransomware
yeah it's um there's one
i think an incident uh an instant a
veteran incident responder
said um that there's something called
the uber ooda loop
it's called the observe orient uh decide
and act
and then just repeat that process so
when you're actually in the middle of
dealing
with the ransomware attack because it is
a stressful thing you know your
organization's gone down
um your computers are locked your
business reputation is a
jeopardy you've got to basically
pull yourself try and pull yourself out
of it and think
uh so you've got to observe and then
you've got to you know do something
you've got to come up with a plan then
you've got to decide on the plan
and then act um and then once that
once you've done that action step back
again observe did it work did it not
and just just go bit by bit
you know you and one of the most
important parts is having a plan
what what are you gonna do when you get
hit by ransom and i say when
because it it's so so many organizations
are being hit it's
it's a matter of pretty much a matter of
when rather than if
nowadays awesome awesome
and that's right up to the line now
isn't it that's straight up to the line
that was a great talk will good job
thank you amazing thank you for coming
on thank you for sharing your knowledge
with people
i'm sure everyone here has enjoyed it as
well as you can see in the chat
thank you i want to be i want to give a
big shout out to conan and the nc
ptf and chase labs and it's just been an
awesome conference and i can't wait to
just to listen to the rest of the talks
thank you no problem