[Music]
so thank you all for for being here this
is my first ever public talks if you
have any feedback afterwards somehow I
did the talk please do let me know I'd
appreciate a lot if you have any
questions just feel free to raise your
hand and I'll go on and as I see up here
I just flew in two days ago from from
Dublin so I'm quite jet-lagged if I
start to ramble incoherently or speak
Dutch which sends the exact same please
give me not to not try and rephrase
things so what I'm talking about today
is what makes some product teams great
and others not so much
this is very much in the context of Riot
Games so it may or may not apply to your
company what I hope you guys get out of
this is really a few of how Wright sees
this problem and what we're doing with
this information so a little bit about
me my name's Ken Hendrix I'm Dutch hands
my first name
I have been with riot for
four-and-a-half nearly five years now
and throughout the time I've been
involved as a development manager within
our security team most of my time I
spent herding cats make sure we do the
right things the right way and make sure
we get things done on time on the side
I've been focus a lot recently on how
teams within write do or don't do
security and see if there's stuff that
we can distill from from the steams and
apply that elsewhere I spell the content
and in five parts first I'll give you
guys some more context about what riot
is what the culture is what engineering
culture is as that context that's a lot
of of the tone of of the rest of this
talk I'll then share a little bit about
what my viewpoint in that is and then
I'll share the challenge of answering
the question why are some teams great
and why are is not so great I'll then
give a little bit of of info on how we
are trying to improve the gamer riot
city quickly has had a bit of a stage
about riot
I'll share a little bit about who we are
and what we do and what the history is
so riot was founded in 2006 with
mission to be the most Larry focus games
company in the world and that means that
everything in the company does is few
through the land stuff okay how much
value does this give to a players and
the same goes for security if we want to
take on an initiative we will be asked
okay how does this improve life for our
players we currently have one game out
in production it's called a league of
Legends which was launched in 2009 you
played as five versus five online and
it's very strong competitive team
oriented game and it's very like I said
very competitive there's a large eSports
scene behind it there's currently about
143 I believe unique characters you can
pick from and every 30-minute session
you can pick a new champion so every
game every session you play is going to
be different and that gets a lot of
people hooked back when League was just
released in 2009 rod was very much just
a small starter but only about 40 to 50
people working there and the game grew
incredibly fast there's numbers from
2016 so in seven years time the game
proved from just not being released to
having to support a hundred million
users every month and that was that's
quite a growth the kind of further
illustrate that every year we have a a
world championship and a season one you
could see this was a Dreamhack in Sweden
it was just just a small booth and maybe
a few dozen people there a bunch of
nerds were playing video games right
this isn't - we had the Galen Center
here in LA completely filled to the brim
about 8,000 people there
season 3 the Staples Center also here in
LA season 4 we managed to fill up a
soccer stadium in Korea and Seoul also
completely filled to the brim in season
5 the mercedes-benz arena and Berlin
season 6 the staple center again here in
LA and in the end of 2017 we went to the
bird's nest in China which also got
absolutely filled up I believe it was
like 70,000 people there so League had
to keep scaling with those numbers and
when a company is in that phase where it
just wants to keep operating and get
people even play the game their priority
is not going to be security their
priority is keeping
engine running so currently the current
world in 2019 is we have over 20 offices
and almost every one of these offices it
does to some extent some engineering
work whether they do themselves or
whether they outsource it there's some
technical component happening in nearly
every office we have I think this number
is a little bit outdated already about
3,500 people working at riot and about
700 of those work in engineering and the
values of our engineering group are
player focus total ownership one team
two teams improvement and especially the
total ownership and play focus part make
it harder for security to get involved
because what it means is that any
product team alliant completely owns
what they built how they build it how
they organize themselves and they they
not only control that they completely
own that we can't just go in and tell
teams you have to do X Y & Z they they
can easily defy us and go about with
their lives so the challenges that we
have is it's sometimes just really hard
to get security in there for teams so
this team's at riot every product team
has a super high degree of independence
autonomy and freedom to organize
themselves whichever way they want
because their focus is to deliver more
value to our players and that
unfortunately means that security isn't
always where we want it to be and only
over the past few years we've been
gradually been able to get ahead of the
game and improve significantly and we've
done that but becoming a lot more
proactive so rather than mandating heavy
security checklist or 400 pages long we
just go in there have a lightweight and
applicable conversation lightweight and
political tool the teams can adopt and
that has proven a lot more successful
for us the guys that actually put it
really nicely and we have this printout
as it posted in both our Dublin and Los
Angeles office here if security
introduces blocking to your organization
it will be ignored none embraced this is
one of the core pillars that our
security team operates by because if we
make it really hard for teams to do
actual work to deliver their their
software to products
players then I gotta work with us or
they're not gonna want to work with us
so for us it's nearly impossible to mend
a top-down security or to make security
become gatekeepers before teams can
release the guys that's it they had it
right all along so this is where I come
in this is what my vantage point is so
as in role in a row of a development
manager within security I have been in a
lucky a privileged position to interact
with a lot of teams a lot of product
teams to come to us with various
requests and reviews and comments and
concerns and that allowed me to build up
a bit of a perspective see how some team
that I do or don't do security and how
to steam to succeed or fall short on
security and they tend to do that in
quite similar ways so over the past few
years I've learned quite a bit about
security but here are the key three
lessons that I learned preaching to the
choir to those teams that are doing
security fantastically doesn't move the
needle so when we release a new tool or
new process or a new workflow for teams
to do things more securely those
fantastic teams they will adopt it but
that doesn't necessarily improve the
security portion of the company the
teams that need to adopt it that we want
to adopt we are not reaching them
because they will typically ignore it so
if your purity focus on optional tooling
of processes we're not really moving the
needle secondly many teams regard
security as a face they have to go
through they don't see it as an ongoing
process they're like we build something
we deploy it let's let's get some
security work done maybe a review and
there you got off to production but we
know that nowadays there's a lot of
patches happening a lot of updates
happening new features being push a
production so five months down the line
that secure review we did is much is
obsolete it's just a snapshot in time
and a third there are somehow those
magical teams that do everything
perfectly right and the time to the
point is talk we haven't really been
able to figure out what that magical
thing is so those teams have the right
somehow have the right processes the
right tools and make the right tech
choices but yeah we don't really know
what it is
so obviously recently but I've been
trying to figure out is what makes those
special teams there's medical unicorns
what makes them so special so trying to
figure out what processes these teams
use what-what Tex Tex they use what kind
of conversations they're having and see
if there's anything we can distill from
that and apply that to other product
teams within riot yes for diving into
the meat of that I want to emphasize the
disclaimer I don't need to explain to
anyone here that security is a difficult
and owns topic but what I'm sharing with
you guys here is valuable for us at riot
and in the context of a highly agile
company where all the teams are very
autonomous and this may not be relevant
for you at your company and I'm
definitely not saying this is a silver
bullet but for us it helps this is only
one of many security efforts we have
ongoing a riot so I'll be sharing some
numbers later on those are
representative of all the security
efforts not just these efforts we're
focused here on elevating the bar we
will never get to a perfect secure world
especially as long as those teams are
completely independent and that's fine
we just want to make things a little bit
better than what they used to be so I'm
going to share now is how we try to
answer this question how did we how do
we approach this and what are the
results of that question so I went about
over 210 50 teams in riot and we have
about 80 of them and asked them within
the team how do you guys collaborate um
on security and asked a bunch of
questions or I took notes on a bunch of
questions is when those teams sit
together and talk about the work they're
going to do do to talk about security if
so who talks about security is the only
one person or is it all ten people in
the room what do they do with that
conversation does it go into the abyss
of a whiteboard or JIRA or do they
actually make something useful out of it
and how do people react when those
conversations happen in the first place
so for most of the team's there's 10 50
teams are set and on the call
all of their sessions and I just watched
and observed I asked him permission to
do that and that was all I didn't raise
my hand didn't say anything that was all
I did and they did that twice for about
a month during 2018 and notes notes
notes I took a lot of notes so I started
looking at those notes and yes some
pattern started to emerge there were
definitely groups of teams that exhibit
similar behavior and potentially similar
results and as we are a games company
obviously we call those levels and you
can kind of see that as a maturity model
so on the Left we have what we call
level 1 teams and in level 1 teams
security awareness is kind of limited
doesn't mean that these people don't
care about security it just they don't
really get to think about it it's not
really coming up into conversations if
this team has seasoned developers that
still produce a pretty decent quality
coat if you have a bunch of junior
developers and you probably want to get
involved more closely there things get
better when we move to level 2 these
teams for them security is still
reactive what we see here typically are
key stakeholders or a tech lead and
deemed assess hey guys let's think about
security and these are the typical teams
that see security as that face right
before they release so typically what we
see here team bolts on security after
they did that security review phase or
security phase in their development and
that's about it
the challenge with these teams is that
because security is dependent on that
one tech lead or one security advocate
or that one stakeholder that does value
security as soon as those people are
removed from the equation this team will
drop back to do a level 1 team and that
kind of means that security for this
team is unsustainable but it gets better
when we reach level 3 so for level 3
teams
security is just part of nearly every
conversation and they kind of have a
force mechanic to do that for them is
really a muscle if they have a planning
session part of the agenda items will be
let's talk about security
however it's not natural to them
something that needs to be brought up
over and over again but the whole team
value says the conversation and they
will actively engage in it so it's no
longer just one or two people caring
about security it's the whole team
having that conversation and that means
that for these teams security has now
become a sustainable practice that they
will keep on going for a long period of
time so that's that's better and then we
get to these these magical teams level
four teams as we call them
I mentioned that we were trying to
distill what those teams are doing
serious practices we can apply to other
teams the answer to that is we cannot
because for these teams security is like
breathing they will automatically do it
every conversation it doesn't need to be
brought up they will automatically think
about it
and that means that security is a lot
better but it's very hard to say this
team has these in these practices
another interesting thing that we found
was that a special level for teams are
not so much about three teams but also
that a bit is that there's very strong
focus from the leadership of the team
and people above that on security trust
integrity so that's where the product
owner will say no we hold off release to
get better security versus more value to
players over security in or limited data
set and experienced teams that reach
level four are typically working in
highly sensitive areas like
authentication or all rep shops kind of
kind of teams we are seeing more regular
product teams get close to love for so
we're keeping on that in the future
while describing levels this really
should be seen as a continuous spectrum
so a team being level two-and-a-half is
absolutely possible so we've gotten all
this these levels and we realized okay
well that's all nice and fun but does it
really mean anything can we see where
most of the team to riot are at so we
went through that exercise and we
drafted up this model I wanted to see if
we could see the bigger picture at riot
so we did this at the end of 2017 with
all 80 ish engineering team that we have
at riot
obviously excluding the security teams
the step will be cheating and we based
this information on okay
kind of conversations are we having with
those teams what kind of things do we
see in bug bounty and security reviews
do those people reach out to us in
general if yes what kind of questions
are we getting and and out of that we we
were able to bring up these these
statistics so this was not entirely
unexpected we are seeing a lot of teams
in level 1 and level 2 I hunt from Team
2 level 3 or 4 so there are definitely
some Rockstar teams arrived but there's
plenty of room for improvement what we
also found was traditionally the teams
that are on level 1 we typically have a
very hard time communicating with those
are the teams in the local offices where
security isn't physically present or
teams were a lot of developments being
outsourced it's a lot harder to get
security even part on part of being part
of their radar so ok nice and fun we
have known the percentage of level 1
level 2 level 3 teams oh yeah that's
just know just the number of teams and
within riot that are level 1 or 2
challenge of the total we did not look
at that but my gut feeling it says yes
so yeah we looked at all that data and
figured ok that's all nice we now know
where teams are does it really matter
where the teams in level 4 level 1 can
we actually see an impact on that on the
bottom line of what a team does so riot
has a bug bounty program and we're very
happy with that and that gives us a lot
of interesting data so over all bugs
that were reported over 2017 we looked
at okay which team built this product
and what level are they great and we
started looking at the metrics that way
so when we look at we're gonna look at
two statistics the average payout on the
bug bounty issue and average time it
takes a team to fix a high-risk issue
because those are the ones who want to
fix fastest immediately typically so we
said it we average and index it out on
$1.00 for a level one team and for one
unit of time for the epigenetics fix
high-risk issue in level 2 teams
we already saw a huge improvement
average pay for a bug bounty issue went
down to 80 cents on the dollar
and the average time took these sorry
took those teams to fix the high risk
issue to up to 65% of the time level one
needed when went to level three teams
improved even further they on bangbang
issues on average paid only sixty five
cents on the dollar compared to level
one teams and the time it took them to
fix high-risk issues was less than half
of what it takes 11 one team and in LA
for four teams it again gets better
where the average payout drops to 55
cents on the dollar and average time
takes them to fix a high-risk issue
drops to less than a third compared to
level one teams so not just bug money
but also security reviews we looked at
and we see some some different type of
engagement that we get out of those
teams so level one teams they rarely
come to us for security views would they
release something and when we want
something to review something because we
feel and may be sensitive we typically
have to do a lot more poking and pulling
on getting all the right information get
it properly set up for level 2 teams
it's already a lot better typically it's
only a natural reminder saying like hey
we want to review this and typically the
team will get it set up and ready for us
in very short notice that's already much
better enough three teams as I said they
always think about security it's a part
of the formal agenda so we practically
always gets fury views for level three
teams and love for four teams and we see
interesting second behavior did not just
only send us reviews for their big
features or big new products they will
also come to us for check-ins on hey
we're modifying this sensitive code okay
guys give us a second pair of eyes so
that allows us to very quickly
turnaround on their request as it will
only take us a few hours or a few days
to do review those those changes so we
took all the other review reports we had
up to the 17 and looked at if this issue
was reported by a bug bounty what would
we pay out on it and again we said it on
$1.00 for level one team in level two
teams we see the average issue severity
dropped 70 cents on the dollar for level
three teams we sell drop to 65 cents on
the dollar and for level four teams we
sell drop
to 58 cents on the dollar so both
reviews and bug bounty are quite well in
line and we are really seeing
significant changes in impact that it
has on the security posture of a product
but depending on what level that a team
is at um I am aware that this is kind of
a self-fulfilling prophecy
yes teams that do think more about
security will produce more secure
products but it's kind of nice to
finally have some numbers to support
that and be able to bring that to two
other teams and stake holders to say
Security's a point so next part I'll
explain what we are trying to do with
this information how are we trying to to
level up securely at riot so how do we
use and apply this framework so the
level that a team is at for us changes
how we approach that team so now we have
this level three or four teams when we
release a new processor tool yet those
kinds will immediately adopt it but they
don't need it as much as as level one
and two teams so what we try and do is
figure out okay where's this team at if
they are level one or two team they
won't adopt our process or a formal
tooling unless you really force them to
and we don't really want to do that as I
mentioned so first what we need to do is
level up the actual amount of care that
those teams have to think and work on on
security so we need to figure out how
can we move this level one or two teams
up on this model so we've seen what the
current landscape looks like what do we
want to do in the future
so going from level three to four it
takes really long time and effort that
usually is a multi-year journey and the
statistics you just saw they show that
the return on investment areas is pretty
low however going from level one or two
to level three is a huge improvement so
we know we have a bunch of level one or
two teams on our belt and we're trying
to figure out how we can move those
teams to level three if you take a
further look at what you actually see
written down here a lot of this is
conversation of process based it's not
necessary not necessarily technical
competence
and so that means that a lot of changes
we would encourage our teams to change
how they work day by day rather than top
down security requirements so so we
needed to drop a systematic approach for
teams that they could easily talk about
security and whatever it is that they're
working on at any moment in the
lightweight manner but still try to be
as complete as possible and that was
really difficult so we started looking
at a bunch of commonly used methods like
stride threat modeling but we found that
that was already way too heavy having a
30 minute conversation every sprint
planning there's no team around that
will sign up for that so we needed to go
more lightweight than that because
remember teams at riot are highly
independent and autonomous so whatever
we want them to do it has to be
lightweight and easy and applicable
so yes lightweight and easy and
applicable so when we talk to engineers
at riot what we know is that every
engineer wants to write secure code the
challenge is they don't always consider
security so when we have conversations
with our engineers they typically know
what the most common form of building
your threats are how to protect against
that but it just don't always good to
think about it so we know that all we
need to do is prime them to think about
security we don't need to come with with
400 page checklists to them to think
about everything we just need to get
them in the right mindset so every team
orion's uses some form of agile
development and those are evolved around
user stories basically what they are
doing with that is that story on the
JIRA or Faro Trello board to make sure
that a conversation happens in which
your product owner explains this is what
I wanted to look like this is how it
should feel like and the engineers will
talk about what kind of coat challenges
they have and the designer will talk
about what kind of design challenges he
has and a teamwork conversation happens
there so we wanted to get in on that
action so we started to figure out okay
how can we do that how can we make
security part of that come
and once again it has to be lightweight
and easy if it's if it's a long
conversation team they're gonna throw it
out of window straightaway so after some
brainstorming we came up with with one
security question and the emphasis is on
one security question you only want
these teams themselves one question on
every item that they're having in their
sprint and that is this question how can
a malicious user intentionally abuse
this functionality and how can we
prevent that and then secondly question
and a half but we'll go with it
and we want this team just have this
conversation for two or three minutes
and that's it no more now us just just
have the conversation and if the team
concludes that yeah we can't come up
with any security considerations that's
that's fine with us at least if they
have a conversation we know that it will
already be quite a bit better so how
does this look like in the wild so I'm
bringing with me some examples two of
them and both of them are in a product
called battlegrounds which is what
tournament organs are organized in the
community can use to organize in a
tournament so you want to make brackets
you want to organize people to play your
tournament a group stages yada yada yada
organise the tournament everything can
go with this tool this team consists out
of a about five engineers a scrum master
a designer a QA tech and a product owner
so we've got them in the room or they
get themselves in a room at a sprint
planning and we said in well they were
trialing this and we just asked them
have the conversation so this is the
first example I have the team wanted
needed a functionality that allows
tournament organizers to create mass
tournaments think of 5,000 people
playing a tournament it would be a
little bit too much work to sign all the
players and team them one by one so they
want to have something simple like
upload two seas fee but there are the
names in it and go from there so the
team had already drafted up everything -
the two items are on the bottom and they
had the conversation and what they
realized was okay yeah we need to do
some some logs and who uploads the files
and validation or actually talking about
Aziz view file but then in the second
item
something interesting happened the
engineer that was assigned asylum had
not yet thought about that this actually
had to be prompted by another engineer
who said okay what if someone provides
us with a malicious playername or a
malicious team name what do we do then
and that conversation happened and now
this was part of the accepts criteria of
this piece of work ergo the team now
built something slightly more secure and
second one was also an interesting
example talking about a feature that
would allow players who were indie
tournaments to ask for help from the
tournament organizer and all they would
do is click a button that says I'm going
to chat with the organizer and a chat
window would open and it was actually
the product owner of this team who was
not technical at all who asked during
the security conversation okay what if
someone would just rapidly click that
button and the team's heart have a
conversation and they actually realized
well then yes actually a
denial-of-service vector exists there
the team found that the scope or was
somewhat limited so they opted for a low
effort solution but this conversation
happened and that man that security
level up for this team and because of
these conversations now this team has
moved on to a become level 3 team over
the last year so in both cases because
of this conversation taking place we get
better results of Ross this was a very
successful trial of teamwork so there
are some caveats to this though
unfortunately um let me start by saying
that this is a difficult muscle for
teams to develop all right starting to
think like a breaker or having a two
minute mini threat mulling session is
not easy it two teams on average like
four or five weeks before they really
start to get hang of it and started
doing this on their own
so it takes time and but that's fine
secondly is this exercise is absolutely
not perfect we were sitting in a room
myself and one of the security engineers
and my team and we could come up with
like 20 other things to do when you're
uploaded
his fee file but we didn't speak up
because we want this to scale we don't
want this to be perfect because we
cannot be in every planning session so
it needs to be scalable and we do that
by just having a live conversation
within the team and we just set back and
in the room not getting too involved so
after a year of working on many fronts
we we poked him our numbers again and
they were looked at okay where is Ryan
at at the end of 2018 and what we see is
that a bunch of teams move from level 1
to level 2 and some teams move from
level 2 to 3 so overall we saw quite a
bit of progress there's still a lot of
work to be done but we're moving in the
right direction so next steps with this
work is the security question that I
just mentioned we have integrated that
in the SDLC secure development lifecycle
that we're trying to roll out to our
teams in that we try and train and
educate teams to just have this
conversation or as you'll see is really
focused on lightweight interactions and
we basically say to teams we want you to
take to do X Y and set and let us know
about a B and C but that's all you don't
need to perform long strenuous actions
except for the review that's still
something we really want to do secondly
we are trying to figure out ok how can
we get better at measuring this right
now it's super time intensive and a lot
of the indicators that we have are rod
are lagging rather than leading so what
are the key takeaways I hope you guys
get out of my talk first of all most go
and try and have a look at what teams
are doing sit with them for a few weeks
have a conversations sit in on the
planning sessions I figure out that way
what are they working on how do they
work and do the solutions that you have
in mind actually fit with their model of
operating because if you're in an
organization and your ideas go against
what these teams are doing they are not
gonna accept it
obviously like I mentioned earlier it
seems to talk up more about security
will do better at securely but if you
have teams that aren't good at security
folks on using lightweight conversation
tools
get them started think about security
more often I don't come to them with
massive tools or significant processes
that may be very hard to adopt so thank
you a lot for your time do you
appreciate a lot if you have any
questions feel free to let me know if
not now I'll stay around for a while
shameless plug for my employer we are
looking for people in security so if you
want take a look at our website yeah you
mentioned the lightweight tools other
than the security question you have did
use any other tools to improve the
levels yes we're trying more to focus
more on conversations like more formal
threat modeling at the design phase and
we're trying to figure out if there's a
way we can teach teams to do that
themselves while still giving the right
value without being an eight-hour
conversation so those kind of things we
have constantly ongoing so between 2017
and 2018 did you guys ever notice any
teams slip and drop their security level
yes especially teams dropping from level
2 to 1 because a security champion or
advocate left the team we did see that
happen yes we have a bunny program that
gets pretty close yeah do you tell the
teams their levels and did they ever
take offense to being rated lower than
they'd prefer to be the latter answer
off sleaze yes uncommon offense but
people will feel hurt about being not
good at something ride is a very
competitive place so people are
typically gamers so they wanted proof so
we find it more of a good stick to use
rather than I any damaging thing and one
more question prior to your intervention
did the level 4 team simply consists of
more senior engineers is there any
other demographic composition that led
to them happening to be better so they
had you they have an average senior
engineers I'm gonna call it more senior
engineers but they were working in very
security sensitive areas that's the only
commonality that we found
how long do teams stay together that
really varies from team to team some
teams stay together for years on end
it's one of the two teams that we had
level four in first year those have been
together and nearly the same composition
for like four or five years we also have
teams that do a quick spike of three or
four months and then I realized that
that product isn't viable and there
they'll yeah get broken up and team
people move to other things so you
sounds like you kind of do see a
correlation between teams that stay all
over a longer period of time to kind of
getting a higher security consciousness
is some sort yes and no so we do see
that some teams that were level three
were relatively fresh but because they
brought in people that did care a lot
about security and were able to quickly
teach the rest of the team to care about
security that they nearly immediately
started off as a level 2 or level 3 team
did you use any code analysis tools or
offer training to bump your engineers
acuity to security we've had challenges
with finding training that engineers
found valuable and relevant to what they
were doing so we currently don't have
formal training we do are frequently run
like CTF sand those kind of things can
peak their interest we have a bunch of
static analysis tools one of the
challenge that we have a riot is because
every team is free to do what they want
we have over 20 languages of use and I
don't know how many frameworks and
libraries a user it's really hard to do
stack analysis effectively that way so
our headquarters is here in LA and we
have about four or five offices that
mostly do development however doesn't
mention practically every office has an
engineer or some release technical
efforts or even a community manager that
says hey we need a new websites burn up
and they'll engage with a third-party
developer
relatively yeah yeah so you said you
disclose levels do disclose levels just
to the developer and not make the public
what do you mean with public meaning
everybody knows their level but nobody
knows the other person level we will
only tell team with their own Lovelace
we won't chat and you compared to how
are they compared to other to enterprise
so then how does it okay thanks but we
will tell them what the overall
statistics are but we won't share you
our level two and the team rednecks use
level three that we won't do this is
more of a curiosity question I guess
about management style of the
organization you talk about how every
team is allowed to kind of run things
away they want to run and sounds like
you're using very much a carrot approach
versus a stick approach you know forcing
something down their throat but at the
end of the day I mean there's you know a
lot of other businesses you know you
have like compliance requirements and so
on and I'm guessing that that's not in
the picture for you guys so is each
individual team managed based on like
revenue generated like is there some
accountability in terms of the negative
impact of something they you know
they're not doing doing things right in
a secure way and it impacts some level
of performance like is there some kind
of a measurement there so riot in
general teams aren't really measured on
on revenue that teams create because
teams operate and some teams operate
merits when it cannot generate revenue
however we do make teams aware of Hades
are you Bob Anacostia you review costs
and those kind of statistics are
dripping through ABBA dad's also slow
change of culture because four years ago
we wouldn't have been able to do that
and right now as a company is maturing
those kind of practices are more
becoming more acceptable all right thank
you very much
[Applause]
[Music]