so thanks everybody for joining us talk
about a tiara
but first the most logical question I
have to ask at a nap SEC event is how
many people here know somebody in their
family or a friend that has diabetes
right so it's a pretty large segment of
uses so I actually started my career in
health and biomedical innovation helping
combat diabetes so it was actually an
early research project that was looking
for new means and methods to detect
diabetes before traditional methods
could do that and it was also a
non-invasive approach so this was an
approach that didn't require taking
blood samples and these other methods
and what we actually built out was this
process where we would actually have a
patient come into the clinic and they
would have a camera on one eye and then
with their other eye they would actually
be looking at this interactive mapping
chart and what it would do is as the
user would follow this chart we're
actually recording their eye with this
five hundred times magnification camera
and would actually let us get access to
this kind of these nerves at the back of
the eye and what we actually designed
was the system that led us map out these
nerves so it wasn't just we see like
these small pieces I actually let them
build this system that we could actually
top the entire nerve plexus of the back
of the eye and this technology was kind
of a cornerstone to the seven year study
that's still underway today and this is
kind of where my background started with
a piece of technology called MATLAB has
anyone here heard of MATLAB or used
MATLAB right it's awful software for
those who've used it perhaps category
let me move my mouse out of the way as
attractive as that is and what we would
use it for was actually to stitch these
images together so my background comes
from image stitching techniques this is
kind of what it looks like to have so
this is actually my eye this is what a
healthy eye looks like
so there's kind of this world complex
that forms in a healthy eye and all the
nerves kind of come to come to this one
central location this is what a person
without diabetes as far as I'm aware
looks like this is what a patient with
diabetes looks like and this is two
years before traditional methods would
even pick up that this patient actually
has diabetes all right so this is really
cool stuff so I wrote a paper on this
and did a lot of work with this research
institution this is actually a research
institution in Australia where I'm from
you may have noticed the mild accent and
you know obviously the next clear
progressional action in my career would
be to go on to become a doctor
right that's what makes sense given this
well no of course not I'm here talking
to you about security so I didn't do
that so what I did was instead of
becoming a doctor I went on to build
games obviously so this is me
well is this me unclear this is me when
I was five so what I actually designed
at the University that I was working
with was a piece of technology that used
some of the similar image breaking
techniques that I pioneered with a study
to track people so we were actually
partnered with a small company called
Microsoft on a piece of technology
called the Kinect has anyone here heard
of the Kinect what is the Kinect - young
sir yeah so it's a it's a piece of
technology and what did you play any fun
game so it was your favorite game you
have played no fun games with the Kinect
this is the problem this is why the
Kinect is not around anymore right this
is the kind of user reviews they would
get from the Kinect
it's terrible technology we actually
were one of the first to use it for a
commercial means as a not not actually
building Xbox games but actually
building what it was was an interactive
system so we had this this floor surface
that we would project a screen onto and
we would use the Kinect to actually
determine where the user was standing on
this this floor area and it actually let
us build this giant multi-touch
multi-user
effectively an iPad that was 2 by 3
meters this is a low-cost system and we
built a whole range of educational
applications with this technology we
first built it using this technology
which is built by a company a company
called primeSense none of you are
probably heard of the company primeSense
who here owns an iPhone or an iPhone 10
specifically so do you use face ID don't
use face ID as a cuz your own security
and you're like don't want Apple to see
my face what's the reason I want to
understand do you have a pin on it okay
oh kind of old-school but I guess
alright okay that's fine
this is other user reviews see this
technology wasn't going places but this
this company primeSense three months in
our relationship with them they actually
got applied by Apple this was five years
ago almost now maybe a bit longer and
that technology is actually the camera
that is used in the iPhone 10 they
basically went silent for many years
while they were miniaturizing the
technology it used to be like this it
used to be the same size as the Kinect
and then it became what's now inside the
iPhone so we were kind of upset about
that but then we ended up getting a
relationship with Microsoft instead who
actually had to rebuild the Kinect v2
from scratch because Apple then owned
all the patents on on the technology
they were originally using for the first
Kinect which was based on the private
Sense technology fun fact this is kind
of some of the games the applications we
had like a lava game don't stand on lava
who's played back game as a kid I'm sure
someone's played this game it's a great
game right see see good reviews on games
better than the Kinect we did better
we had like a dodgeball game we had like
jump over these bombs we have like the
sheep herding game when you had to herd
the right sheep in the right pen and
these kind of different applications and
use cases but I'm actually not here to
talk about games and diabetes
surprisingly even though we've spent a
lot first entire chunk of the
presentation on that topic I'm here to
talk about single request attacks
specifically in the context of account
takeover so account takeover obviously
is this interesting new problem who here
has bought something online that's been
shipped to them
right so what did you buy that was
online that you had shipped here some
stamps what store did you use to
purchase this Amazon and I'm assuming
you probably stored your credit card
details on Amazon does anyone else store
their credit card details on Amazon well
okay a few people and if you don't it's
a really poor user experience once again
so you know they kind of require that so
account takeover is this concept of
someone wanting to get into your account
so there there's something in there
that's valuable to them and they would
like to get in and take that from you
that's effectively the concept of what
an ATO is and they use a whole range of
methods so they they try and break in
they try and buy credentials they try
and figure out what your credentials are
with the entire golf getting in and
stealing something so because you stored
your credentials in Amazon this guy is
now coming for you unfortunately he's
very scary I don't know if you can tell
he's very hard to see so this is how you
solve the face ID problem he can a mask
you wear a mask when you use face ID
that makes sense
that's just logical so this guy he's
probably probably in this room actually
as a security conference he's probably
here learning what we know about him but
his job is to figure out a way in and
illicitly do some things with with your
credentials such as we know that if you
can ATO UPS account people are getting
in there
well actually who here ships something
with UPS anybody has ever shipped with
UPS because there's more people than
that who's actually shipped with the UPS
yeah there we go
right so UPS is a pretty common package
delivery service if you can get into
something's UPS account the fun thing
you can do is redirect packages so what
they do is they ate here UPS accounts
get in there and then redirect your
package mid route to you back to them
and they sell it on third-party websites
it's a fun fun fun vector of attack
scraping content you know if they can
get into your account maybe you have a
premium service with a photo website or
something they can
get in there and grab all that content
sell it through a third-party website
and then the more obvious use case is
making transactions obviously they can
get in there and buy things and then
resell them in the context of games
they'll buy virtual goods and then you
know sell them to throw party websites
and contacts of a web site like Amazon
they will just simply buy a product and
ship it to themself and then resell it
so there's a lot of reasons as to why
they would like to do this who has heard
of have IB important so what does have
ib m-- porn do so this week there was a
new breach who was on that list I was
yeah so there's a 800,000 No 800 million
I believe yeah 800 million accounts and
this is a kind of an older leak but have
I been important as a website you can go
to put your email in and it will let you
know if your accounts been breached
or leaked and they actually leaked both
the email and the password so you can
actually see what password you have had
lost and this is obviously the starting
place of someone that wants to do an ATO
attack they get access to your leaked
credentials and they can then use those
to go and attack and get in and start
doing some of the nefarious things we
described the most common attack vector
with ATO is they take all of these
leaked emails and well who sees their
password on this list
which one's yours is it football one two
three four five six it's the same same
as my luggage right so you know
unfortunately a very large majority of
people use one of these ten passwords
like hi hi double digits use one of
these passwords so what you do is you
take people's emails and you start
testing those emails on every service
that you find of interest with passwords
like these and also all the passwords
that will leaked on those lists of 800
million new passwords leaked on that
list that are valid passwords people use
so you can automate this process using
software that goes on attempts to log in
to every single service that's out there
and basically once you get some valid
credentials you can then hand that off
to a human who can then go in and do
their job but you can use automated
software to start this process
does anyone here earn an IOT device like
a light bulb what is your name sir
Patrick what IOT device your own
Raspberry Pi base well that may be
better or worse unclear what what what
do you what what is like a good example
of an IOT device you have yep that's
probably - yeah light bulb can determine
if it should open the door or not
probably those kind of things
now of course very very safe very
logical totally cool
yeah highly recommend everybody have
that garage door be a so these are
pretty popular there's a lot of them out
there and there's a lot of really cheap
ones being made and there's a lot of
really expensive ones being made with
the same quality as the cheap ones and
unfortunately these same devices can
also be a tea owed and they're even
easier to ATO because the default
credentials are the same across many
millions of them there's one device we
know of which is a photo frame which has
access to your Wi-Fi and therefore your
intern
the identity and it has the same login
and password and they sold tens of
millions of them and you can just log
into them anywhere you would like and do
all kinds of fun things so what we've
actually seen is people route traffic
through these to launch attacks and what
they do is when they're launching these
attacks against whatever website they're
trying to ATO they're actually proxying
traffic through things like IOT devices
we've seen this ourself and they're
using this to get access to a vast
number of identities effectively a near
infinite number of IP addresses they can
now access so you can't rely on IP
address as a signal of is this user bad
or not because they'll use it just on
one request then they'll never use it
again it's just like are they bad or not
who knows they just came in tried and
potentials with one IP address and then
they moved on in reality we didn't move
on they just changed their IP address
they're still there testing other
credentials the next logical thing is
well what about the fingerprint how
about we look at the user agent and
their points well guess what you can
change that too it's not overly
difficult I'm sure for those of us in
security client-side data can't be
trusted right who would agree with that
statement yeah it's logical
you can't you can't trust client-side
dart you can't trust network data
anything coming from an end user can't
be trusted so you can't rely on these
identities either browsers have gotten
increasingly easy to automate chrome
released a fantastic browser that allows
you to automate it so they have a
headless version of chromium chromium of
course is the source for chrome and this
is a browser that is open source so you
can download the source of chromium and
modify things such as what user agent is
this saying it does you know what
JavaScript support does it have yeah
actually we've seen attacks that do this
and they're using real browsers then a
modified that let them bypass security
checks that the chromium machine built
in because it's open source this is the
better federal foot and the negative of
open source is you can kind of do fun
things like this and of course there's
more legacy systems like selenium which
is more useful automated testing that's
a bit easier to detect and of course
phantom Junior
a bit more old-school product but you
know we we see proper attacks just using
chromium nowadays and just modify it in
such ways that you can't determine that
it's actually chromium
what about biometrics fingerprinting the
way users interact with websites of
course that must be real right
who thinks biometrics work to a certain
extent so you believe they do work what
in what context now that's fair it's a
it's an additional signal we can look at
right but the downside of course is as
with all clients ITIN telemetry this is
once again something that the attackers
have control over we've seen BOTS where
they actually let you record using a
macro feature your mouse movements as
you go through a website and then adds
randomization to your human movements
you do a thousand recordings your
randomness is gonna be better if you do
five recordings it's going to be more
obvious but it actually built-in tools
now in BOTS you can buy off-the-shelf
that do some of the other things I
described that also let you randomize
this signal too so even this signal is
something that BOTS have overcome we
can't rely on this as a true/false
signal of automated attacks we're here
sort of recap sure anybody heard of
anybody here like recaptured so anybody
that doesn't like recapture put your
hand out Randall
do you like recapture that's true as
with all things more is always better
than less that's fair recapture
unfortunately can be quite easily broken
so these text CAPTCHAs we don't see
anymore because this technology is being
well and truly defeated all right you
can use an optical character recognition
which is a commercially built piece of
technology with I'm sure if you've added
your credit card to a phone it's asking
you to take a photo just
in right who's had that happen when you
recently you know I think like the uber
app and stuff like that you can now just
take a picture that same technology is
why this technology couldn't progress
because machines were getting
significantly better at the concept of
associating metadata with the text image
then humans were human solve rate was 2
& 3 1 & 3 users would fail these on
first attempt machines now are 100% so
anyone that's using a text capture it's
nothing more than a glorified honeypot
at best something is better than nothing
but yeah in that context you're losing
users so probably not ideal this is a
good example of capturing the credit
card so they moved on to this this photo
image challenge has anyone seen this
come up in the wild tell me more about
your experience with this photo
challenge iffy
just a little iffy so this is once again
a commercial problem do these kind of
self-driving cars I hear it's a
up-and-coming thing I live in San
Francisco we see them around I'm not yet
convinced it's like around the corner
thing but we'll see self-driving cars
will not become a reality until this
thing is 100% bypassed because guess
what self-driving cars have to do let's
take photography of what's around them
and associate metadata and label that
data and that's the exact same way that
you break this technology good news for
self-driving cars machines are really
good at doing this and can pretty much
one percent bypass this technology now
as well there's a piece of software you
can buy called
X evil any Russians in the room
the Russians is Russian software of
course it's $400 is pretty expensive but
this will 100% bypass recapture we
bought it of course we like to support
our Russian friends and tested it and
yes it does work on every website that
uses recapture so if anyone is
frustrated with recapture X evil dot
something just Google X evil it'll come
up it might say Google I'm safe when you
click it just ignore that what does
Google know what is Google know about
that this is a competitive product to
them they're not gonna let you into that
website so that's kind of what a single
request attack is right so here's a bit
of a road map as we're walking through
our presentation in case anyone's bored
can anyone tell me what a single request
attack is anyone being paying attention
that's correct
fantastic so I'm paying attention doing
well in the world so let's talk about
how we automate account takeovers now
that we have all these techniques that
we know we can use to basically bypass
all defenses websites are using today to
combat BOTS
you cannot rely on fingerprints you
can't rely on the identity can't use
captures so what what have you got left
well I'm not much turns out ten dollars
piece of software it's called an T
public has anyone heard of an T public
no one has this is no exciting this is a
Russian tool again this is
industry-leading software when it comes
to ATS
ten dollars paste bin is my favorite
website for finding breaches and hacks
I'm sure some of you do research on
paste bin to make sure your websites
haven't been breached on no one's
sharing leaks if you're not I highly
recommend it this is a spam database of
four hundred fifty eight million
accounts specifically designed and ready
to go straight into anti-public and what
it is is it's emails and passwords
pretty simple and what it does is it
takes that list in and it uses this
beautifully Russian software should go
off and do some nefarious things
and it does the same single request
attack stuff behind the scenes but it
does this in the context of getting into
a login page so you tell it what logins
like what login websites would you like
to try and break into today and then you
feed it the list of passwords and emails
that you would like to test and it will
go off and do that it will give you
success rates it will give you ratios it
gives you all kinds of great telemetry
and metrics we all we're a data-driven
world so it's great to have awesome
software like this this is the my resin
by the way I don't know what that means
but I'm sure it's important somehow it's
probably other editions maybe there's
cooler editions they're so confident who
he gives free trials are their companies
anyone any companies give for us what is
your company give what does your company
do sir hiring and what is the free to
what is it and why do you give a free
trials because you're confident in your
and your product in your service and you
know that upon giving a free trial users
will be converted and use your product
so our good friends at Auntie public are
very generous and very confident in
their software they give away free
hundred five hundred free uses of their
software you just plug in an email and
it will go off and do its thing and be
like yep here they crack this account
for you and go log in and do whatever
you want now you don't have to pay and
it's ten dollars ten dollars and it's
still giving five hundred free samples
away mm-hmm exactly so I'm surprised no
one's heard about this but I'm very
humbled to be the first to reveal these
fantastic tools these same techniques
don't just apply in the context of ATO
though so this concept of single request
attack is attacking other places who you
flies today one fly to get here to upset
California where did you fly from that's
a long flight I'm from Australia I used
to fly it from Estrella to come here
that's a short flight as well anyway I
digress
was it a cheap airfare did you find a
good deal that's good how much should
you pay fly well that's pretty good
actually
so we're always looking for the best air
fest right who wants to pay more when
you can pay less unless it's like a
specific airline and a specific speed or
something time of day the goal is you're
always gonna kind of find the cheapest
fare and that's that's the standard
right like maybe if your company's
paying maybe you'll opt for a slightly
nicer flight but if you're paying you're
probably gonna pick what's the most
economical flight right this airline we
work with in Hong Kong had a problem
where their seat inventory that they
were selling this is a low budget
airline so they're a very famous airline
at Hong Kong and they are selling the
city inventory but the city Montori was
going missing it was just vanishing and
they were not getting so people could
buy inventory from this website right
and what was happening was well because
they couldn't buy from this low budget
airline they were instead of having to
go and buy from more expensive
competitive airlines interesting what
could have been happening sir what the
other airlines were doing was they were
using automated software doing single
request attacks going through the
booking engine on a Hong Kong Express's
website reserving a seat to whatever
destination they would like getting to
the payment flow so the checkout page
and then they were using a payment
redirection method all you pay is the
primary one but more familiar to us is
paypal here and here in the US and what
that would do is when you click all you
pay a PayPal it takes like who's used
PayPal to buy something right like it's
it's a pretty commonly used product
right we can click that option it takes
you off the website takes you to PayPal
to complete the transaction and what the
airline does is of course I can't give
you the inventory until it hears back
from PayPal so it actually holds that
seat I just it pauses that inventory
whilst it waits for the call back from
PayPal and they do that for up to 10
minutes while they're waiting for the
transaction to go through and of course
the fraudsters were not transacting and
what they were doing was perpetually
locking inventory in this redirection
process and completely eliminating the
airline from selling any of these
so this is kind of a denial-of-service
right and what we what it would look
like is when you go to the website to
buy inventory
it looks like it's sold out for up to 14
days in advance every flight every
destination is eliminated but in reality
that inventory is sitting there in this
seat hauled loop so they were using
single request attacks through that does
anyone know who this guy is
he said Bieber why do you know that have
you been to one of these you're a big
fan a canadian well that makes sense
because the canadians hate him
so I'm assuming no one's been to except
the Sherman's been to a Justin Bieber
concert no what about a small band
called ac/dc we call them acadec Oh in
Australia this is this is an Australian
band for those who aren't aware full of
knowledge in this presentation has
anyone been to a concert recently no one
has been to a concert recently what
concert did you go to recently last
night Elton John where he oh wait you
invite us whose tried to buy ticket and
missed out because there was no
inventory available in five minutes
right
the gentleman recording so what ticket
did you try to buy well that's that's an
abrupt end to that story so we'll just
move on
so ac/dc more importantly they actually
have Australian currency we actually
minted currency in Austria because
they're so awesome as of course you all
know I says they this is what our 50
cent coins look like in Australian
currency it's worth maybe mmm it's worth
maybe a mint at best in an in the u.s.
their currency is not things have so
great right now well we'll move on from
that so ticket inventory famous
ticketing websites have told us that
this is a fact this is a fun fact this
is another fact so many
seek inventory today sells out in three
minutes and that's because the vast
majority of inventory is being purchased
by bots if you eliminated bots they're
all doing single request attacks right
if you eliminated bots from buying
inventory it would take six hours to
sell out the same inventory alright so
if ever you're in the inner queue and
you're there in the first six hours you
would be guaranteed tickets to the best
concerts in the world if they were not
being bought by scalpers and why are
they doing this
can anyone tell me why they would want
to buy this inventory that's right so a
$7 ticket you can sell up to 5x the
value of that ticket and you make a lot
of money doing this because you know
yeah if you really want to go at concert
a fan will pay more money and who's
who's actually puck pocketing that money
fraudsters it's not the ticketing
company it's not the artist so everyone
loses in this scenario except the forces
and it's huge margins alright if you can
sculpt you know 50,000 tickets think
about the margins on that right it's
huge amounts of money and that's why
they're so invested in doing things like
single requests attacks and they frankly
just completely overcome the defenses of
these ticketing companies even though
they invest huge amounts of money in
this problem that's a really hard
problem so this is the stuff where you
want to use if you would like to buy a
ticket early because you're not going to
get them in six hours I at least can
help you get it in three minutes
it's $1,000 it's a pretty pricey
software and go-to ticket but dotnet
well you can just google this it'll come
up and what it does is it lets you
select how many threads would you like
this to run on your PC so you can run
you know parallel processing it's the
future and you tell it what time of day
you would like it to log in what tickets
you would like it to buy and it goes off
and does its thing and behind the scenes
it's doing these single request attacks
on your behalf you can route proxies
through it all this good stuff get
access to some IOT botnets and get some
cheap inventory and then you can resell
it and retire young that's what many
people do so we're moving through so
what did we just cover one big invention
young sir what do we just cover that was
the one before why don't we just cover
know what we can do to become rich why
is no one listening I'm giving you all
these great things so there's these same
attacks are also used in other use cases
like gift cards all right I found this
on paste in my favorite website this is
a very simplistic brute-force attack
it's literally JavaScript that's just
randomizing numbers and then putting
them into a check gift card feature and
guess what happens if you come back with
a valid gift card balance on your random
brute force you now have a legitimate
gift card you can go and spend anyone
here bought a gift card before at the
back what did you buy what was the gift
card for this is a very different story
that I was expecting but what kind of
gift cuts okay yeah
has anyone given away a gift card for
like a Christmas present or something
all right
so how long on average does the gift
card sit if you gotta buy it for
Christmas that's a yes I guess if it's a
poorly given gift card present very
untargeted to the individual but yeah
like mom's right so typically it'd be
months so you buy this one it's actually
on the shelf it's deactivated so you
can't you can't get into that gift card
it doesn't it's not activated until they
go to the register and they they pay
that's why they have to like scan it
into the credit card system you'll
typically see that right that's what I
actually connects to the service of
whoever is backing the gift card and
then that's activated from that moment
until it's redeemed that gift card can
be attacked so whilst it's sitting under
the tree for months people are using
software using single request attacks
with this kind of stuff on top trying to
get into those gift cards because once
you can get in yes you can redeem them
and then one the person that actually
owns leave card goes to redeem it well
it doesn't actually exist and it's not
valid so that's that's a it's a problem
for them but the fraudsters right what
about credit cards I guess credit cards
are also a potential attack right if you
can do a single requests attack on a
credit card use case who has donated to
a charity online right so how much money
did you donate well you can give me a
rough number right okay that's that's
too high stop being so generous so what
people do is they go to charity websites
and they'll donate $1 but then actually
using their credit card they're trying
to use someone else's credit card you
can buy credit cards or dark web
millions and millions of them that have
been leaked but they're not yet proven
that you have valid street address and
validation etcetera CCV is three digits
guess how many times it takes to
brute-force that guess how long that
takes for a computer to brute-force
I've already brute-force a thousand all
of the values of these credit cards can
be brute forced and this is an attack
called carding where they will randomly
guess the credentials to give cards
using websites such as charity websites
we can just test a doll
most of these websites don't have
defenses against bots so they just let
you keep testing they'll even be really
generous and say your ccd was wrong
you're a street address was wrong try
something else on this one right you
find a website like that you can get
through a lot of credit cards and then
and then you know good luck good luck
from that so this is a great forum if
you would like to buy stolen credit
cards
I'd recommend checked net it's a
fantastic website and this is a an
individual but a busy bee who is looking
to purchase Australian or New Zealand
credit card and this gentleman actually
tells him where you can buy the credit
cards from chase - tapas are I believe
that's a tour website URL I don't think
I went there any one know why you would
want to buy a New Zealand credit card I
don't know if anyone's been to New
Zealand but they have a lot of sheep
there but if you like I can understand
wanting to buy an Australian credit card
that makes sense we have beautiful
beaches if I was presenting in New
Zealand I'd have to pixelate that image
can I don't tell me I'll pronounce this
sorry I'd be TAS it's added ass nice try
there what about this one Neil and
aluminum is such a fancy word but all of
those letters don't exist I don't
understand whatever marketing that's
marketing his marketing team told him it
sounds more fancy the Americans all of
this what about this word Carmel sounds
it's caramel caramel all right now we've
got that other way so we have I have a
story to tell now the story time just
everyone some silence please
so I want to tell the story about Jimmy
so Jimmy is a young child who likes to
purchase very expensive shoes
but when he purchases or tries to log on
and purchase these
they're not available and he's very
upset about this
he tried Benny thing this is Jimmy yeah
he tried many things he went and lined
up a shoe store assuming he'd get it and
get the inventory in time but he's
always late these parents don't let him
out you know
at the bright early in the morning to
come line up so when he gets there sold
out it's very upsetting so he turned to
cyber crime this is Jimmy attempting to
use cyber crime he's not very good at
cyber crime he is Jimmy poor Jimmy he
gets access tonight when he tries to use
you know multiple computers at once to
try and purchase who's done that with
ticketing websites or something right
sure I'll go on my phone and my computer
and this or that they know that they're
all you by the way they're really good
at that so they block that fortunately
Kayne West came to help him to buy shoes
of course and Kanye West sold to him all
in one bot this is a great website she
got it this is an actual video that they
have they built Slyke a full high
production and they hired Kanye West
it's very legitimate and what this
software does is it does single request
attacks on sneaker websites and it will
buy the inventory that you would like
when it's available
it's three hundred and twenty-five
dollars which yeah it's pretty decent
these shoes can go for a couple of
thousand dollars if you can automate one
pair of shoes you got pretty good ROI I
think on the purchase this is an
individual who obviously was just like
Jimmy and just wanted one pair of shoes
for some reason he ended up with like 10
or 12 or whatever this is 16 it was like
I'd aggress so he clearly was not
looking to buy well III think it's
hilarious when like literal people
committing fraud just post images to
Twitter of like I just afforded this
website I got a whole bunch of shoes
that I'm gonna resell and they even like
talked about the companies that they use
like it proxies and goo
proxy's which they're using to do single
request attacks through so what this
software does you download it it's got a
very very nice UI actually unlike the
other ones you pick your website
including added ass pick the shoes that
you would like the size and the color
and all these things and then you turn
it on and it goes and does its thing
they have a term actually it's called
copying copying is apparently there's
that like a thing here
copying and it's not the time we have
Australia I thought was strange but
maybe just me
and they have you know 60,000 cops so
far so they've got like great stats they
clearly have some kind of call home
mechanism in their software which is
cool 10,000 testimonial shoutouts on
Twitter 10,000 people committing fraud
talking about it on Twitter I thought
that was really really strange
this really impresses me three-hour
support time reply like that's better
than most companies like legitimate
companies right like that's actual like
top-tier so I think that's really cool
and they just happily talk about you
know all of the totally legit things
that this this company helps you do and
at the end of the day for some reason
Michael Jordan will actually deliver the
shoes to you I don't know why I guess
it's some kind of resale agreement with
Kanye but anyway Jimmy is very happy so
this is good does anybody know these
characters anybody over here know these
characters who are a who is this Pokemon
that's a very high level of who these
characters are do you know who this
character is this funny looking yellow
rabbit that is pick a Chu correct has
anyone played Pokemon go
nobody has played Pokemon that's a lie
no one's going alright you've played it
what level did you get to that's
pathetic
I'm unimpressed unimpressed you've
ruined my talk now I don't know I can't
go any further with this
so the purse the first player to max
level and Pokemon go yeah it was a bot
of course makes sense I mean they come
play 24/7 they can do things humans
can't do they can click things faster
they can play better then you just keep
going through and doing the sort of
stuff
Pokemon goes community were the first to
defeat a piece of software called
Android safety-net so I don't anyone
here uses Android safety net to protect
their properties they work for but
Android safety net is a piece of
software that's designed to stop
emulation of Android OS so it's supposed
to tell you is this actually a real
phone or is this an emulated version of
the phone of course people using bots
want to run emulators because then they
can do everything automatically at as
large a scale as they would like much
harder to do when you have to use
physical phones so of course this
feature by Google Android safety net
which is a true-false service is it real
or not is a fantastic feature only
problem is Android OS is open source
just like chromium so what they figured
out when they rolled it out in Pokemon
go there's a large community of hackers
it's called Pokemon go-devil and reddit
if anyone like to go to it and check it
out they were stopped momentarily from
running their BOTS so what they did was
they reverse-engineer the Android OS and
made it's a true instead of false so now
they can run their Android emulation and
it completely bypasses Android safety
net because once again you cannot trust
client-side information you know for the
company making the OS as you can they're
wrong you definitely can't Pokemon Go
has proven that does anybody know anyone
in their family or maybe it's you who
has died and voted recently nobody
that's dead and voting in the room just
nope okay well so there's a thing called
a Death Master File it's quite morbid
it's a real thing
can look it up later and it leaked one
year and what this list has is a list of
everyone that's passed away and their
social security number and where they
lives and all kinds of fun things this
is a government owned thing that's
perfect it makes a lot of sense why the
government would have this it's just
unfortunate they leaked it so what
people have done with this Death Master
File is they've used it to do all kinds
of fun things with BOTS because now you
can effectively take over these
of people that no one's checking on and
do interesting things like voting in
certain polls so this gentleman found
out that his mother whom would have
turned 71 but didn't turn to everyone
because she was dead
voted made three separate comments in
support of ending net neutrality right
and there's other scenarios where
similar things are happening so these
websites don't validate if these users
are alive or not just that they have a
valid social security number and valid
of the details and bots have been using
this list to do amazing things and
support of all kinds of things that they
would like to win and there's a whole
range of other use cases that these same
attack techniques can be applied to
right you know auction houses buying
cheap selling high you can basically
control the economics of the market
we've seen scenarios where people are
doing denial of service on auction
inventory where effectively maybe you're
selling a comic book for thirty dollars
and you have six other people competing
selling their comic book for $30 but
suddenly yours gets bid up to one
hundred and fifty dollars and and at the
end of the day the buyer bounces doesn't
actually purchase it they bought one
other people have bought the other
cheaper ones and this keeps happening to
you what they're actually doing is using
software to create accounts on these
websites and make false bids and
actually give you effectively denial of
inventory where you can't sell your
inventory because they keep bidding you
up more expensive than himself
and they can kind of control the price
this is happening on major auctioning
websites right now and it's hacking and
scraping and ratings of course and all
kinds of things you can do and I'm sure
we're familiar that social websites have
this concept of news that's propagated
and certainly not interfered with by
Russians using similar techniques like
this to bypass all of those very same
defenses they don't actually have a
magic bullet to solving this problem
they're in the exact same situation as
all of these other companies all right
so you can use software single request
attacks to disseminate anything you want
online and when information online
has enough people backing it and
following it they get social proof right
so if you see a comment that has 200,000
likes or retweets you're probably more
likely to trust it than something that's
got none
unfortunately BOTS can also like and
retweet things so you can do all kinds
of fun things in that scenario so how do
we stop account takeovers that's tricky
obviously we've gone through scenarios
more than just a TOS but one major
recommendation is rate limiting by the
email and the identity of the user if
you can if you have software that does
that so this means that maybe give them
three attempts on an IP or on an
identity that is one thing you can do
obviously the goal is how we how do we
make it more expensive for the attackers
to use software to attack us then the
value that they can theoretically
extract you can break the economics of
it by putting enough roadblocks in their
way they'll go attack somebody else so
these are the kind of techniques you
want to employ to do such a thing
lock accounts with suspicious activity
definitely do this unfortunately this is
a really bad user experience because if
your account gets locked in you have to
contact someone at the company to unlock
it that's horrible you might lose users
because of this but you're definitely
gonna lose users if they find out that
credit cards been stolen from your
platform so you have to take care with
this kind of balance right who uses
multi-factor authentication would you
use multi-factor on a game you play
versus a bank what's more likely you
would enable on
do you use it on everything that
provides it or just things that are more
important like banks you're very
generous with your time then because
it's quite a quite an effort to use
multi-factor as we all know you have to
phone out
is it token-based or SMS based well
that's unfortunate I have a slide just
for you SMS based multi factor is
breached now so you can actually quite
easily attack and get into accounts
there using SMS so token is currently
still very viable that's probably the
most secure approach to stopping ATO so
if you want to stop ATO token-based mfa
no really what did that happen well on
SMS on SMS yes but not on token really
that's hilarious yeah we're all screwed
this is what I love about working in
fraud it's the attackers of geniuses
like they're smarter than we are it's
awesome it's always very interesting and
then the other thing of course is if
they're going to be using bots and
things like that to try and get into
your account if you're not using MLA
then
strong passwords are very good who uses
LastPass or one password or something
yeah good that's what everyone should be
using it's the best defense against ATO
right other than NFA how do I be
important also have an API for
enterprise companies that you can
actually test as users set up an account
you can test if those even when they're
logging in you can test if those
credentials have been ever used by
someone else before or if they've been
leaked before and if of course they're
on the lists guess what they're going to
be broken like that right so this is a
good service that you can use to just
stop that problem so that's kind of kind
of what we're talking about today so I
hope you enjoyed that I think we're
pretty well over time but if anyone's
interested
and kind of what we do so we're a fraud
prevention company we're backed by
PayPal we're doing stuff with some cool
companies we work in this space and
that's why we've seen all these great
things but we'll be we'll be hanging out
around front but no one's got any
questions which is fine but it just
moves the problem to where they're yeah
you haven't solved the problem use
nuclear problem there's still better
having a centralized location it's like
LastPass right you centralized it to
last boss they still have a login as
well so yeah yeah all right exactly
all right thanks everybody to show you
time
[Applause]
you