[Music]
what everyone welcome to app set
California how's everybody sorry about
sorry about the Sun a lot of people with
pale complexions my apologies but
hopefully you'll enjoy yourself today
welcome we have people from all over the
world I know a couple of people then
from Ireland and Israel and Asia so it's
it's a great gathering of people who
want to share and learn and we
appreciate your joining us and we'll do
the best we can to entertain you we also
want feedback so make sure we get plenty
of that what is this all about we have
six chapters in the California have come
together to put this on for you
who's our wasp we're a global community
that drives the visibility and evolution
in the safety and security of the world
software everyone is free to participate
no wasp and all of our materials are
available under free and open software
license our wasp is are registered not
for profit in the United States and
Europe so all your financial
contributions are tax deductible you
know what that means we'd love to have
you join right consider it so what what
is owe us what's our purpose all right
be the thriving global community that
drives visibility and evolution and the
safety and security of the world
software in a couple of words we want
all software written to be secure is
that possible maybe but we wanted to get
as close to that as humanly possible we
want everyone here to engage with your
team's at work developers please talk to
your security folks security folks talk
to your developers and both of you guys
somehow get meetings with executive
teams to drive standards policy and get
some money for this right so we'll hear
more there's talks all about this
throughout today and tomorrow and what
are our core values in owe us it's open
everything is transparent including our
finances and code you can find
everything online innovation we
encourage and support innovation and
experiments for solutions to software
security challenges and its global
we're international organization we have
chapters all over the world and we have
representatives today
from all different chapters integrity
this one is one of the core things that
we love because it speaks that greatly
of who we are right we have to have a
high moral imperative and we do it out
of love and because we believe in it
there are I think this is the correct
number might be one or two different
because you know it's a dynamic fluid
world but we're all over the world but
as you can see United States and Europe
have the majority but we are growing and
one of the passions of the board is to
grow us in areas that are
underrepresented and that's something
that we need to do so if you happen to
be from a country where there aren't a
lot of chapters the board is committed
to help you reach out to us if you are
not a board member that's okay you can
help start one or find your local
chapter and join up so we have lots of
things that we do lots of people busy
with projects and our WASC top ten is
the most famous that's we get our name
we have standards they ASVs standard is
becoming more and more popular there are
teaching environments webgoat for
example is a deliberately insecure test
bed that people use to test and learn
about how to find insecure code how to
improve web sites we have cheat sheets
an example is the CSRF we have
checklists there's a mobile application
checklist now again what I have here is
just the tip a very tip of the iceberg
there are 110 projects going on with
with people on teams from all over the
world and if you want to get your name
out in the field what better way to do
that right yes we want you to join us
you've got a lot to offer everyone in
this room you're here because you're in
the field and you can be doing some
great work to help share we have all of
our projects available for anybody to
use so if you need to beef up your
knowledge and experience and application
security we're your go-to place so
please get involved join a chapter that
end a meeting give a talk you'll have
something to say right visit our project
and those change they're very fluid
because new projects are starting up
right so you consider joining a project
we all need help or start your own right
if you are an application developer if
you're a software architect if you're an
information security author consider
helping out give back to the community
write conferences like this speakers are
taking their time to come see us why
don't we do something also all right and
build a better environment for everybody
we have a lot of supporters we are
recognized as the leader in applications
security information the world wide
these are some of the things that we are
proud to put into our bag as our resume
continues to improve and I'm proud very
proud to share the our Watts global
board position with a team that I am we
had our first annual meeting I'm new to
the board best group I think I've been
around as a team so I want to thank them
and I want to introduce them and I want
everyone to consider giving them a round
of applause we have worldwide
representation and so I'd like to ask
Martin Noah block and come on up Martin
and Chen Qi Wang come on up and Sharif
Mansour and Owen Pendlebury come on up
Richard Greenberg who the hell I don't
know and then Garry Robinson and we also
have over my or from Israel yes okay
so Israel Netherlands Germany America
London Ireland and I well once Northern
Ireland couldn't wait
oh wait wait sure you can you get
between them please anyway let's give
him a round of applause a great group
[Applause]
thank you folks
yes if you want to find out more
information about Oh wasp you can ask
the volunteers but here the global board
member so they might be your first stop
so they'll be here all day and partially
tomorrow some of them they have to fly
back to the various places so this is
great because it's the first year we've
had the whole board a tap set California
we've had representation in the past but
you know and we promise to listen to you
folks so pleased that we have lists the
police join our lists give us some
feedback things that you like or think
that can be approved in a wasp you all
have stuff they can help us with whether
you think it now or not you will think
of something I go oh let me just send an
email we're very open and receptive so
we'll do our best but let's build a
better community so thanks everyone
my pleasure
you