hi there my name is Cesar Archie I'm a
senior security engineer at Netflix so
Netflix when global in 2016
very started streaming content like in
more than 190 countries but when you
think from an enterprise security lens
like what did this actually mean so not
only were we going to stream content in
more than 190 countries but when you
think about from an employee and
contractor perspective that population
was going to see an equal amount of
expansion which meant like we would have
new office locations more remote workers
and these remote workers might be the
connecting from home or from any public
Wi-Fi we started making more original
content than ever before both here in
the US and all across the globe and
people who are actually working on these
productions we started making
applications that are primarily focused
for our production use cases which meant
people who are working on the
production's they would need access to
these applications they're going to be
on the go and they will be again
connecting from any public Wi-Fi as
we're on the go our other facets of
business which basically comprised of
our pre and post production partners our
studio partners our media device and our
ISP partners all of these various facets
of of business was going to see an equal
amount of expansion as well and to add
to the mix the kind of applications that
were built or that were going to be
built not only was it going to see an
equal amount of expansion but the same
applications have to be a made available
outside of the traditional like
corporate network so we clearly had to
think in terms of how we imply trust
just here because you're on a corporate
network and how we can detach ourselves
to be more aligned in terms of where are
actually businesses going and both from
a risk perspective as well as from the
costs and the complexity that is
involved in mint setting up the
infrastructure and actually maintaining
it going forward so we clearly had to
think in a different
direction and this is where we actually
started moving towards more of a zero
trust model and last year's talk on
Netflix is Lisa Lisa program is gives
you a great insight into our approach in
terms of zero trust and there has been a
lot of work done in the industry around
zero trust and Beyond Corp is one very
good example as well so what exactly is
zero to us so the core principle about
zero trust is access to any resource
just because it comes from a corporate
network should not imply any trust or
privileged access you should assume like
an attacker is already present on your
corporate network you should start
detaching Trust which means think of
your think of your network as any public
Wi-Fi then coffee shop
so this basically led to the inception
of our identity platform which we
indicate which we term it as Meechum
they're the core building block behind
the platform is Federation and by
Federation I mean we want to federate
every single application to our platform
which means the act of authentication
and authorization we want applications
to delegate that process out and
applications can actually focus on
building the application and let us deal
with the the stronger authentication and
authorization so this has got a lot of
advantages in terms of like how
applications actually can start thinking
about the platform in general from an
our team perspective we can adopt
standards standards is very crucial
because we can now have the same attend
occasion and automation process both for
our own build applications as well as
third-party saps
we can layer a security and at the same
time we can provide the best of the user
experience as possible for our end users
from an application developer
perspective they can now focus on
actually building the application and
let us deal with the stronger
authentication authorization piece we
can give them pluggable security and at
the same time all of this can be
achieved via self-service whatever the
end user itself they can get the best
experience via a single sign-on
so the court of the platform is the
identity itself what do we know about
you as a user who's trying to access any
netflix resource and when identity is at
such a core to the infrastructure we
don't want to be in a situation where we
have identity silos silos are very
problematic to any organization they
pose a huge risk because now we have
multiple identities to access multiple
applications different axes our
authorization model followed by these
silos and different security practices
followed back in these silos and what
about the end user it produces the most
confusing experience because people have
to remember which identity to actually
use and we cannot have single sign-on
also on top of this so we have
streamlined
the identity landscape in in two
different aspects from an employee and
contractor perspective so we have
streamlined the identities to be in the
googles like cloud identity offering for
all other business or business use case
which includes our studio partners our
content partners our ISP media and all
of the b2b use cases they are they are
basically managed in our in-house Ville
directory service but the aspect of
streamlining of identities is one aspect
but how do actually identities come in
and go out of our ecosystem and this is
where they go through a strong like
provisioning and de-provisioning process
and this is very crucial especially when
access to our resources granted with
respect to these identities so there are
three fundamental principles about the
provisioning and de-provisioning process
you're going to tap into external event
sources once we receive those event
streams we're going to take those event
streams and propagate the identity and
provision them in the right place once
we have done that we need to post out
notifications because that's again yet
another key aspect so that other
applications and services in the
ecosystem can actually tap into those
notifications and carry out post
processing but what type of events do we
actually
tap into so we tap into HR event sources
like the workdays the es ends for
production use cases we tap into other
b2b use case events start an indeed of a
production
it could be start and end date of a
vendor contract itself what about the
activity of the user itself just because
we provision an identity for any user
doesn't mean that it lives in our
ecosystem forever so this is where the
activity of the user behavior is taken
into account and if there's no activity
notice then we we disable them and get
them out of our ecosystem so
streamlining of identities and making
sure we have a strong within occasioning
and deep provisioning processes one core
building block so how do we start
establishing enough stronger assurance
in terms of who the user is and is that
the user the real user so at the core of
the authentication processes
multi-factor up so users go through the
regular first factor and an irregular
cadence they go through a step of factor
and step up because now we have a range
of user base both your in the US and all
across the globe we have to make sure
like the the options that we support
they they they they are they follow like
in terms of what the user population is
so we support from security keys to push
notifications to your TP and so on but
does all application have same level of
risk associated with them when a user is
trying to access them should be multi
factor auth everyone every single time
that would lead to a very bad and user
experience accessing a lunch menu
application is it really risky versus
accessing an application that exposes
like some sensitive data so we really
need to think from an attacker
perspective in terms of what an attacker
might be looking into when trying to
actually compromise an account or access
any netflix resource so this is where we
take into the risk level or the risk
factor associated with the
authentication requests itself and make
it go through our adaptive
authentication process and there are a
lot of core ingredients that actually
drive our risk risk level associated
with the request
the first aspect is what is the
likelihood of a user actually going and
accessing an application what are the
data points that we have with us so we
have the previous user authentication
history in terms of what applications
that they have accessed we have the
users information in terms of what are
the which organization that the user is
part of what are the team that is a user
is part of and what kind of applications
are those users actually going so we can
come with a nice heuristic in terms of
what is the likelihood of a user going
to a lunch hang an application versus
actually a financial application what
about the previous authenticating
authentication activity itself so if
this is an attacker who has compromised
somebody's first factory credential most
likely they are laterally traversing
through a range of applications trying
to break in and those cases they might
be blocked at every step of the way or
with a second factor so in in those
cases there might be a failed at a
negation request or a bunch of abandoned
requests so can we take that into
account and feed that into our adaptive
authentication and bump up the risk
level certain applications we won't want
to actually time box make sure we go
through a regular step up for example
AWS console you might want to step you
up every six hours versus some other
application which actually exposes
sensitive data as well so timeboxing
applications is also yet another
ingredient and our adaptive what every
application pose a certain level of risk
and that risk is basically driven in
terms of what kind of data that they
expose and what is the sensitivity of
that data
so applications can indicate like what
kind of data they expose and that feeds
into our adaptive authentication again
to drive our risk association and if
you're coming back from the same device
that you previously logged in from we
might want to actually bump you up in
terms of the confidence level so device
is yet another key ingredients what
about the location from where you're
trying to access our applications if you
see that you're coming from very risky
locations in most other cases where we
might want to actually step you up in
such cases especially with respect to
location we might want to outright like
deny you so look
please yet another Korea crucial role in
terms of our adaptive authentication so
adaptive authentication is yet another
core ingredient for a layered security
what about the health of the device that
you're using is a device in a healthy
state it should be in so that we can
grant you access to our resources so
there are a lot of endpoint security
software that do a great job in terms of
you define a policy what meets your
organization and you can use that but
with Netflix things a bit different
especially our culture around freedom
and responsibility people can walk into
any store pick up any device and they
can actually use it for work so how do
we cater our security in terms of how we
want to present our man or know the
health of the device itself so this is
where you built a native application for
both Mac and Windows that guides user in
terms of what are the best practices
that we think in terms of the health of
your device but how can we use this
information actually and make it more
valuable in terms of how we drive our
layered security so right from the
authentication process itself we query
the device and the app to get insight
into like what the state of your devices
in this case it's clearly indicating you
that the device is not in a state that
we like you to be in we recommend that
to the user users can actually take
appropriate actions self-corrected and
give a get a positive confirmation so
it's kind of a win-win situation from
both us as security team as as well as
from the end user and the best thing
about this is like me now we have
actually educated the end-user how to
make sure that devices are healthy so
health of your device plays a very
crucial role in our adaptive
authentication as well as into our
layered security so now we have really
strong authentication process that you
just go through from a federation hub
but how do applications actually wire
this up in their application one common
approach that you'll see in the industry
is having a mega proxy where every
possible request will go through the
mega proxy before it actually reaches a
target application there are a lot of
advantages with this particular approach
but there are few things that we would
like to stay away from one is
maintaining a are setting up an extra
infrastructure and maintaining it but
the most important aspect is we don't
have single point of failures in our
infrastructure so what we want is we
want to push the authentication process
like right to the application layer
itself so if you want to read if you
don't reach that end goal we don't want
to be in a situation where and we have
centralized admin or devops team that is
actually managing all these like various
client integrations this is adding yet
another like failure point and slowing
and slowing us down so cell service is
very crucial cell service is great but
it can it can become another bottleneck
if it's not simple and intuitive and
especially when things like
authentication and authorization things
can become really complex so we want to
make sure like we present information
and in the most intuitive and simple way
so that we hide all the complexities
behind the scene so we have built an
open ID Connect compliant self-service
where developers can actually go in well
we have one click they can actually wire
up their integrations and at the same
time we support advanced configuration
options where they can actually
fine-tune things that they would like to
with respect to their configurations so
this is great like so this makes us not
be the central point of failure but how
can we spread the integration aspect far
fresh into our ecosystem and for this
like api's are very free and at Netflix
everything is API first but yet another
thing that comes with our ecosystem is
freedom responsibility is developers can
actually pick any language they want and
they can build their applications using
that so one possible way for developers
to actually integrate with our platform
is we can recommend some open source
libraries they can plug in or they can
go through the configuration aspect but
then we are playing a constant catch-up
game in terms of the new languages
coming out new libraries being needed
and we have billing constant catch-up in
terms of existing libraries having like
one
abilities so how can we move away from
this model one common thing that Netflix
you'll hear is the notion of pay prude
in a nutshell what pay pro gives you is
when you're on the paved road you get
certain base level things by default so
how can we make use of this to our
advantage when you're on the paved road
one of the things that you get is Apache
by default so in this specific case what
we end up doing is we use the model open
IDC Apache module to actually wire up
those integrations another common thing
at Netflix is 300 % AWS so can we push
the authentication right to the load
balance will here itself so we'll a year
and a half we have worked very closely
with Amazon to have authentications
available at the load balancer layer
itself it does support Amazon Cognito
but the best part about this was it you
can fire up your own IDP and configure
the load balances accordingly but we
want to spread the integrations and make
it one click far fetched in our
ecosystem this is where we have
integrated like our CI CD platform which
is spinnaker into it with the plan with
our identity platform and other
developer and spring boot in this case
so a bunch of like other single click
registration with our platform itself so
we have stronger authentication we have
made it easy for people to actually
integrate with our platform but what
about access control does everyone who
are strongly authenticated gets access
for every application probably might not
be a good idea so right from the same
self service that we have what we do is
we provide base level access control in
which you can actually indicate what are
the user or the user groups that
actually can access your application so
this becomes very simple in terms of how
people actually go about setting it up a
database layer itself but if this
doesn't work what developers can
actually indicate what are the
attributes that they would like us to
package so we package these up as an
access token and give it to the
application
itself to apply find a green
authorization so the same package
information can be applied using other
internal like access control
applications as well so in order to
protect all these different applications
that are coming out in an ecosystem both
that will be accessed by employees and
contractors identity is at the really
core of it and we want to bundle up
identity with our adaptive
authentication so that we monitor every
single authentication requests and and
figure out like the risk level
associated with it and when we need step
up users using multi-factor
authentication options and authorization
is yet another key ingredient along with
standards again like standard is very
important for us to reach to our end
state along with self-service and
simpler integrations are all the core
ingredients that we need to make
identity as the real security parameter
thank you very much
you