Callisto is a figure in Greek mythology
she was a nymph in the garden of Artemis
and had taken a vow of chastity she was
raped by Zeus and became pregnant with
his child one day Zeus his wife Hera saw
Callisto pregnant and became furious and
she punished her by turning her into a
bear and banishing her from the garden
the story of our heroine Callisto was a
myth but it also reflects the reality of
sexual assault in her society today for
many survivors they are victims of
powerful serial offenders and our victim
blamed by society my name is Anton
Origen and I'm the chief technology
officer of Callisto we're a nonprofit
that builds technology to combat sexual
assault support survivors and advance
justice our company is focused on two
problems one how can we empower
survivors to hold their perpetrators
accountable and 2 how can we ensure that
the institutions that are meant to
protect survivors actually do so today
I'm going to talk to you about how close
so thinks about the problem of sexual
assault and how we've built products
that take the users privacy and security
into account using advanced
cryptographic methods 20% of women 7
percent of men and 24% of transgendered
students will be sexually assaulted in
their college career 90% of those
assaults are committed by repeat
offenders in fact on average a repeat
offender will commit 6 assaults before
they graduate however less than 10% of
survivors ever take the action to come
forward and those who do wait on average
11 months before taking action only 6%
of assaults that are reported to the
police will result in a perpetrator
spending a single day in jail which
means that 99% of them don't face any
real serious consequences this
essentially means there is no real to
turn to sexual assault in the United
States a few years ago we surveyed over
200 college sexual assault survivors and
we asked them why they didn't report and
the answers varied some of them said
that they didn't think they'd be
believed others felt that they didn't
think that the university would take any
meaningful action and others felt that
it wasn't worth it to relive their
trauma but then we asked him another
question we asked what would you do if
you knew you weren't the only one and
suddenly their answers change they
suddenly said that they would come
forward because they felt more likely to
be believed and they felt an obligation
to protect their community we see this
phenomenon of low reporting rates as a
game theory
problem namely that there's a huge first
mover disadvantage of coming forward
with high consequences but once that
first person does come forward it opens
up the doors for all the other survivors
to take action and so we became very
curious about this how can we solve this
game theory problem and build a system
that actually allows nobody to be that
first victim martyr at Callisto our work
is built around a central thesis which
is if we can empower victims take
coordinated and informed action to
protect their communities we can prevent
the majority of sexual violence in the
United States from ever happening in the
first place
a few years ago we launched our first
product called Callisto Campus students
use Callisto Campus can go to the school
specific Callisto site learn about the
reporting options and then create a
time-stamped encrypted record of their
assault and then they could do one of
three things they could either save it
and Callisto and do nothing they could
send it directly to the title nine
office at the University to start an
investigation or they could enter into
our matching escrow which means that
unless a second person names the same
perpetrator no one will see that data
we're now on 13 campuses and serve
approximately one hundred and sixty-two
thousand students and in the last few
years we've seen some interesting
results we've seen that students who are
used callisto are six times more likely
to report they report three times faster
and most interestingly we've actually
detected several serial perpetrators who
would have normally gone undetected and
that's because 15% of our users who are
in the matching escrow are matched with
another victim the same offender we also
know that any gender can be a victim in
any gender can be a perpetrator 16
percent of our users are not women
activists so we think it's incredibly
important that any law a policy or
program that is designed to help
survivors is inclusive of people of all
genders and backgrounds so for perhaps
the first time we're starting to
understand the spread of sexual violence
and a unique and data-driven way
in the summer of 2017 news broke that a
prominent venture capitalist in Silicon
Valley had sexually coerced several
female founders then we heard about
another VC who had sexually assaulted
several female founders and another then
we learned there were serial offenders
in the entertainment industry and the
media industry and pretty much every
industry after that we learned that
victims weren't just women but included
men and people of other genders we also
saw that serial offenders could belong
to any political ideology even when they
pretended to be allies and perhaps worst
of all we saw what happens when
institutions turn a blind eye and that
don't protect victims and enable more
abuse to happen the me2 movement which
has started in 2006 by tirana burke
exploded in the fall of 2017 and this is
not surprising because many people could
see their own stories in these headlines
they started to share their stories
publicly because it was the only way to
hold their perpetrators accountable and
people started to ask the question how
can we shift power so that it takes days
and not decades and the power of two
survivors not 20 to stop serial
predators and in an attempt to answer
this question there were a lot of wealth
in tension but frankly dangerous
solutions that popped up that ultimately
put victims and more harm's way in
October of 2017 a crowdsource Google
spreadsheet called the shitty men and
media list was created that collected
allegations of sexual violence of
approximately 70 men in the media
industry and the intention behind this
was to allow survivors to anonymously
name their perpetrator and warn others
if they were not the only victim this as
you can imagine did not go as planned
within 12 hours that list got leaked the
creator of the list was doxxed and one
year later one of the accused offenders
created a lawsuit not only against the
creator but also threatened to reveal
the identities of those who named were
named in the document
there's an incredibly urgent question
here which is how can we stop the spread
of sexual violence while also protecting
the privacy and civil liberties of both
the victim and the accused as you can
imagine in the fall of 2017
Kalista was flooded with enquiries of
how we could bring our product from the
campus space and apply it to this
problem at large and as we thought about
it we there were three main
considerations we had to think about to
see how we could bring it to the meeting
movement so first when you look outside
of a campus setting and you look at
industries like Hollywood or Silicon
Valley the victim and the perpetrator
don't necessarily belong to the same
institution so authenticating a network
and defining the bounds of the network
becomes quite hard second unlike a
college campus there isn't necessarily a
central investigatory body that manages
these claims and even if there were
would you really trust them and then
finally when you look at the data the
difference between a perpetrator power
and a victims power in a professional
setting
it is incredibly asymmetrical so the
fear of retaliation and the need for
security and privacy becomes even more
necessary and so it became clear to us
that if we wanted to expand we would
have to build a new platform in a new
delivery model to do this in November of
2018 we launched a new product and
service that we call Callisto expansion
that aims to serve every victim of
sexual violence and misconduct in the
country which is one platform that can
detect serial offenders of sexual
assault sexual coercion and ultimately
childhood sexual abuse and we're taking
this step by step but we're first
starting in our own community which is
supporting fellow founders in the tech
industry who've been assaulted or
coerced by a venture capitalist and
here's why a year ago we participated in
Y Combinator and during our time we
conducted a survey of female founders
and asked them if they had ever been
sexually assaulted or coerced by venture
capitalists 22 percent of female
founders and YC said that they had been
but only six percent said that they had
reported it and the reason for not
reporting it included wanting to protect
their company fear of retaliation and
frankly not clear of whether there was
any place to go to but the main reason
that they did report was to protect
others we launched our new platform
Callisto expansion on November 15th to
approximately 2,000 startup founders of
all genders
from there we'll continue to serve as
many survivors as possible in the US
here's how the model works a user is
invited to Callisto and they create a
time-stamped encrypted record that names
our perpetrator using a series of unique
identifiers such as a social media URL
an email address or a phone number they
enter that information into Callisto
Callisto holds that information in
escrow so that nobody not even Callisto
can see that information unless a second
person names the same offender if there
is a match each victim is connected with
a Callisto legal options counselor who
is a lawyer who can protect these
conversations under attorney-client
privilege the options counselor will
talk to each victim and help them
understand all of their options and help
them pick a path towards justice that
makes sense for them and because and for
detecting serial offenders one of those
options can include connecting both
victims together to take coordinated
action to pursue justice we think about
this model and two key frameworks one is
a legal framework how do we protect this
data from from a legal perspective but
also from a cryptographic approach so
let's first talk about the legal
framework survivors have many options
but those options are quite risky and
understanding what they are is hard
without an attorney it's hard to find an
attorney it's hard to afford one it's
hard to trust one and Callisto solves
that problem by providing match dictums
a free lawyer that's focused only on
supporting them and we call those
lawyers Callisto legal options
counselors once there's a match the
legal options counselor will decrypt the
record and find out the person's contact
information and preferred contact method
and set up an appointment to establish a
client attorney relationship and then
they'll just listen they'll understand
the survivors experience but create a
safe space to help them feel heard and
understood and then they'll help them
understand all of their goals and their
fears and based on those goals to help
them understand what path makes sense
for them what those risks are and what
is the path forward to pursue that if
they choose a path the legal options
counselor is there to connect them and
refer them to the next phase and if they
decide Moochie that both victims want to
meet each other and pursue action
together the legal options counselor
will serve as a second escrow to make
that comp that connection confidential
and safe now why does this matter
in a world without Callisto the main
pass forward are twofold you can either
go to the police or go to HR and frankly
those aren't easy options to navigate
sometimes they're not applicable
sometimes they're not easy to trust
they're very hard to navigate alone but
with Callisto expansion now you have a
wider array of options and you're no
longer doing that by yourself
those options can include getting a
restraining order filing a civil lawsuit
pursuing a path through social media or
the press confronting the perpetrator
and believing restorative justice and
for the first time you're now enabling
survivors to define what outcomes of
success looks for them rather than
having to become martyrs in a broken
system now let's talk about the
cryptographic approach but before we do
let's first understand what the user
journey is so when you're first invited
to Callisto you are basically getting a
whitelist and email invite to activate
your account and you're first called an
invited user when you activate your
account we consider you an activated
user when you submit an entry into the
system you're now an escrowed user when
you're matched with another victim you
become a matched user and finally if you
are assigned a legal options counselor
and have begun the process of counseling
you're now in assigned user so what this
means is as the user progresses through
the user journey we need to understand
what data is being revealed and how do
we ensure that it's protected but still
able to be shared with informed consent
before we get started into the crypto
part I want to first acknowledge some of
our collaborators who've helped us think
about this problem and threat model this
to ensure that we can design something
that and protects the privacy of our
users and you can see more about our
work in greater detail in our white
paper but today I want to talk about a
specific user flow which is that
escrowed user because we use a
combination of a combination of very
interesting cryptographic techniques to
protect our data and some of those
techniques include client-side
encryption Shamir secret sharing
oblivious pseudo-random functions and
federated key servers in order to
protect their data so I'll walk you all
through an example of that right now so
let's say we have a user Alice who's
experienced sexual misconduct against
perpetrator Mallory and she wants to
enter her information into Callisto to
be able to get connected to an options
counselor if there's a match so Alice
will input a series of unique
perpetrator IDs such as a social media
handle an email or phone number and and
that information will be stored into a
vector that we call P we use an
oblivious pseudo-random function over
elliptic curve federated across two key
servers to randomize that vector P and
turn that into a vector that will call P
hat from P hat we can run a
deterministic key derivation function
that returns three values first is a
value that we'll call pi which will
serve as a matching index second is a
value a which we'll use as a slope of a
line and finally a value K that will
serve as a key using client-side
encryption we doubly encrypt the record
using K and the public key of the
options counselor using the formula of a
line with the derived values a and K we
can create a secret share use which we
define as s equals au plus K where a is
a slope of the line K is a key and we
that key ends up being the y-intercept
of that line and we take that hash
coordinate of the user ID and the secret
share and we send it over to the kalisto
database now even though Alice has
entered her record into the system
we can't decrypt it without a match and
this is because we can't derive the key
K located at the y-intercept without
another point on the line now let's say
we have a second user named Bob and Bob
also has the same perpetrator Mallory
and he enters in the same unique
identifiers into the vector P that will
turn P hat into the same value which
will then return the same values from a
k and pi but because he's his own user
his secret share will be different
because his hashed user ID will be
unique at this point he will also send
that information to the Callisto
database now Callisto can't see the
identity of Alice Bob or the perpetrator
Mallory but what they can infer is that
both Alice and Bob share the same PI
value which means that they must belong
to the same line at this point the
options counselor is prompted to enter
in their secret key through their
dashboard and they can then prompt the
command to run the interpolation of the
y-intercept which will then receive the
key k so at this point the options
counters are now seeing Alice and Bob's
identity in the clear for the first time
but because their attorneys they've
established attorney-client privilege so
that the conversations moving forward
are protected now what happens if a
third person submits a record with a
different perpetrator so let's say we
have a user Carlos who submits a record
with the perpetrator Sybil you'll see
that the PI a and K values are actually
different connecting Carlos is pointing
to either Bob or Alice's won't
interpolate the correct way
which means he won't have the key to
unlock Carlos's record this means
Carlos's identity is safe and
mathematically protected and this means
that no victim will have to fear the
risk of coming forward without knowing
that somebody else has their back this
is just a tiny piece of how we protect
our users right to privacy there's a lot
more in our privacy scheme and our legal
scheme and you can read more about it on
our right here but you can also go to
cryptography to project kalisto org to
see an open-source demo we built that
shows how this model works we've seen
how the dialog completely changes when
there's more than one accuser of a given
offender the most effective way to stop
sexual assault and harassment is to
prevent perpetrators from reoffending
and the only way to do that is to give
survivors a safe and empowering way to
report this topic is dominated the news
cycle for the last year and a half and
like many social justice issues is been
polarizing and controversial but this
topic must transcend politics because
this is a pervasive human rights crisis
that affects us all at callisto we are a
team of engineers designers lawyers
activists and researchers and we are
team of survivors for survivors in fact
many of us are building the product that
we wish we had when we had to report but
I am optimistic because change is
happening and our security community can
play a key role in this conversation
because we can build and design
solutions that help people speak truth
to power in a safe and just way we
believe in a world where sexual assault
is rare and survivors are supported come
build that world with us thank you
you