great to be here and be able to talk a
little bit about some of the past
research on the human factor of security
issues particularly security
misconfigurations
so this is joined to work with constant
iteration from lecture consultants
Katharina Krumholtz from c-span Germany
as well as to be as feedback from the
Technical University of Delft in the
Netherlands I'm sure many of you
remember Equifax from essentially their
incident that happened in 2017 just to
bring everybody back on the same page
what happened in the Equifax incident in
the ex-fix breach was basically that
they lost the information of around 150
million between and possibly up to a
hundred ninety million largely US
citizens including Social Security
numbers potentially passport information
so actually a fairly sensitive data
breach and from actual breach to
discovery it took Equifax around
two-and-a-half months to actually
discover that they were breached and
once they disclosed that they were
breached some people started to
pentesting their infrastructure legally
or illegally because they were
unauthorized pentest doesn't really play
into this but it just went downhill from
there the Argentinian website wasn't
really secured correctly and the u.s.
website informing people about the
bridge later even started serving
malware but do you remember why this
actually happened to the ACTA to Equifax
and the reason why it happened is
largely security misconfigurations
so in the firmware case the first breach
happened because they didn't actually
apply a patch for a critical security
vulnerability which was disclosed by the
United States search two days before
which was this case an apache struts
vulnerability and they didn't discover
it because the monitoring system wasn't
configured correctly so in this case
they had an expired certificates they
weren't able to actually look at
encrypted traffic happening on their
network and once you actually fixed the
first miss configuration in this case
actually replacing the certificate and
suddenly noticing well there's some kind
of encrypted traffic on our network
which we should be able to take a look
at but we currently aren't they started
to immediately notice that they were
breached in the case of the Argentinian
website of Equifax it's not even simpler
and this
the username was admin and the password
would also admin so in both cases it was
really security miss configuration that
led to a security incident rather than a
potential zero day which somebody was
discovered so what we're trying to do in
this research is we're trying to figure
out what our misconfigurations exactly
how do they happen and in which case do
they'll actually lead to security
incidents so why do these
misconfigurations occur and then once
we've answered this questions we can go
one step further and we can actually
start answering the question how can we
actually prevent Miss configurations in
the first place
so how do we prevent security miss
configurations by possibly improving
either what the responsible people do or
what the organization's do the question
here is of course what is actually the
reason why we're deploying security and
the reason why we're deploying
Security's of course we want to ensure
the safety in this case the safety of
data the safety of the computers that
you are on your network which in turn
you're doing to protect the data that
you have and in our case in the case of
IT systems the people responsible for
this of course operators be that system
operators be that network operators so
what we did in our research is we did an
empirical survey of operators of both
network operators and system operators
we started by doing a qualitative study
to understand what kind of Miss
configurations happen what kind of Miss
penetration to occur in the practice and
then we also started to understand we
wanted to understand what are the
contributing factors of why
misconfigurations occur what might lead
to security miss configurations in
practice and then once we've actually
received some anecdotal evidence of how
miss configurations occur in practice we
tested them by doing a quantitative
study and quantitative survey over a
larger group of operators and in our
case just looking at the demographics of
the operators that we've surveyed we
have around almost 200 operators from
largely Western Europe and then a few
operators from different locations
around the world
so we're largely based in Germany simply
because at the time the majority of the
authors were based in Germany and then
also looking on the demographics
of course a question whether this
generalizes from Western Europe to the
United States which is at this point
unclear but we expect so in terms of age
education and work experience we also
have a fairly diverse set of operators
so we have operators which are aged
between primarily 25 and 35 as well as
35 and 44 years old then which might
surprise you a little bit is that from
an educational point of view we have a
lot of operators who have a master's
degree the reason here being our set of
operators is primarily based in Germany
at which point it was still common and
it is still common to do both bachelor's
and a master's rather than just going
into industry right after your
bachelor's and similarly the people in
the age group of roughly 30 to 44 years
old didn't even had a chance to
basically go to industry right after a
bachelor's but they had to do a
consecutive master's on top of it which
at the time was called the diploma in
Germany in terms of work experience we
actually see that most of our operators
have around 10 to 20 years of work
experience which if drive provides us
with a good idea of why this happens and
how more senior operators actually see
misconfigurations and security incidents
in their actual daily work starting from
the demographics we of course wanted to
understand what kind of
misconfigurations exists in practice
which kind of misconfigurations occur
regularly so we started to ask what kind
of MIS configuration issues did you
actually encounter and in terms of
prevalence we actually see that for
almost every category of
misconfigurations this everybody saw
more of them and encountered more of
them than they made themselves so
there's clearly some kind of social
desirability bias here as in that you're
happy to report that others did
misconfigurations but you probably don't
want to report that yourself did one and
looking at the different classes of
misconfigurations you see that in a 85%
of our operators saw weak passwords for
example and then similarly also updates
were often delayed which you might be
able to relate to by saying yes I don't
want to apply this update right now I
want to do this later today or I want to
do
tomorrow or as in the case of Equifax
trying to delay it until you actually
encounter that there you were breached
the question of course is now knowing
that security misconfigurations occur
everywhere where do they actually occur
and how do they're being discovered by
actual operators so how do operators
discover security misconfigurations in
practice which then allows us to figure
out how we might be able to improve at
least the discovery part of it
unfortunately we actually see that the
majority of security misconfigurations
are effectively discovered randomly by
just stumbling upon them by possibly
doing something completely unrelated on
the other side we also have various
parts which we can actually actively
improve too and actually encourage to be
doing more off which helps to actually
find security miss configuration in this
case is we can improve and do more
audits we can do more monitoring we can
improve on testing and they can also
just basically make it easier for
operators to participate in conversing
with the other operators to understand
what kind of miss configurations they
might have made what kind of impact
these miss configurations what they
might have on the systems and their
operating so that then they can mitigate
them and this way
realized and fix them before and
security incident occurs the question of
course just discovering it doesn't
really give you much insight into why
these miss configurations happen just
because you were able to discover them
this is not where you want to attack
them you want to actually tackle
security Miss configurations by making
it more difficult for them to actually
be made by your operators and for that
you need to understand what the reasons
are for why miss configurations occur so
we also asked operators of course what
kind of reasons they saw and
interestingly in terms of reasons for
miss configurations we split this in
three different categories so you have
personal reasons environmental reasons
which also includes organizational
reasons as well as system related
reasons so these are reasons which
relate to the system that the operation
needs to manage for example the switch
that they need to configure or the
Windows machine that they need to
configure and interestingly what we
found is that the two most common
anecdotal reasons that are given
by operators and by other people are not
actually the most traveling reasons for
security misconfigurations incurring and
that is unqualified leadership or
financial decisions they actually have
the least impact on why security
misconfigurations and to occur and the
reasons why misconfigurations require
operators at least the leaf
misconfigurations of current practice
are actually a lack of knowledge as well
as that there's no shared responsibility
that the u.s. an operator are
responsible for a system alone and if
you made a mistake it's effectively your
own personal failure if there's a Mis
configuration which is not something you
actually want to encourage interestingly
we didn't stop with just trying to
understand the reasons but we also
wanted to understand what kind of
opinions hold do the operators hold
about the companies that they work at
and why if they might be related to
security misconfigurations if they might
actually be contributing factors to it
so in our case we asked them for example
if the software or hardware that if it's
certified if it means that it's secure
and unsurprisingly the large majority of
operators actually saying no just
because it's certified doesn't mean it's
actually secure and I want to focus on a
few different parts and specifically I
want to focus on the parts that
operators don't believe that their own
company is budgeting that they might
make mistakes effectively the companies
assume that operators are perfect which
of course as we all know humans aren't
perfect humans are making mistakes and
at some point this mistake might
translate to security incident for you
interestingly it's also that operators
don't actually trust the tools and the
equipment that they're using which might
lead to effectively and not invented
here syndrome where operators start to
roll their own system administration
tools at every single point rather than
possibly relying on tools which might
have not worked initially but now
started to work much better and then
even worse there's a part that a lot of
operators believe that security
incidents reporting them is not actually
important but rather it's not even taken
seriously
they don't even feel the need to report
a security incident that they might have
encountered because they don't believe
that there's actually will have any
potential impact on the general security
posture of the organization that they're
in fortunately not all hope is lost here
because at least the direct supervisor
usually understands what they're doing
which should help to actually
communicate potential security incidents
or misconfigurations to them which might
make it easier to actually take it up to
the chain to hire management
I want to float like zoom in on two
different parts here and specifically I
want to zoom in on the part of tooling
and whether all operators trust the
tools and the equipment that we're using
and that's actually not the case and in
fact it actually correlates with
experience of the operator and
specifically junior operators so once
you actually new in the job if you're
still green then you actually still
trust the tools that you're using you're
still trusting whatever tools you're
given by your organization to actually
deploy and you're not necessarily
manually verifying it after the fact
junior operators left around one to
three years they might have realized
that they got burned a few times that
whatever the tool told them wasn't
actually true so they start to trust
them less I'm sure a lot of you can
relate trying to like automate some
things which then doesn't really work
and then suddenly you have to manually
verify it every single time and then
ultimately senior operators effectively
don't trust them anymore and they're yes
no I do not trust any tools at
effectively the entire spectrum in terms
of budgeting for the inevitable human
error
we found effectively therefore largely
contributing factors to it and a there's
eventually the factor of insufficient
Quality Assurance so for example that
you're not having enough testing you
don't necessarily have a staging
environment you might not have a
development environment but you're
forcing your operators to immediately
deploy to production
similarly it might be simple time
pressure and work overload by not having
enough operators or forcing operators to
schedule downtime in the middle of the
night on Saturday every other week which
of course drains them in terms of
work-life balance which is not
necessarily something you might want
courage and on the same side you also
have the part that sole responsibility
is a reason that a lot of operators do
not have the problem that a mistake
might be make mate and nobody else is
there to catch it
nobody else is there to point to them
and say like you might want to think
about this again you might want to
consider that this might actually be a
bad idea you might want to change the
cipher suite because the combination of
the two actually is more it's less
secure than if you just omit it entirely
and then additionally you also have the
part which is just an inherent problem
in security the cultural gotcha
mentality of starting to point fingers
and not allowing people to make mistakes
but rather saying like hey I told you so
this is going to be insecure why did you
do this rather than trying to figure out
why this might have happened in the
first place and what might have led to
security the security miss configuration
happening and what organizational
reasons you can work on to actually
improve it and make it less likely that
they happen in the first place
fortunately we also have the benefit
that individual actually learned from
security incidents so if your company is
actually impacted by a security incident
it actually results in your operators
becoming more security aware so it's not
all hope is lost here but rather once
they start being part of the security
incidents they start looking at them
more carefully in looking and thinking
more about the configuration that they
make and if they might cause the
security Mis configuration the question
of course is just because your operators
learned this is actually mean that this
has an impact on generally your entire
organization or does your entire
organization stay the same and basically
nobody's doing anything fortunately just
a simple security miss configuration
already improves the organizational
position as in we noticed a security
Miss configuration and security is going
to get better at that point procedures
are being put in place to improve
security unfortunately just because you
found a miss configuration which might
have had a severe impact if it would
have been led to an incident
organizations still learn significantly
more from actually being breached rather
than
laying out how a security Miss
configuration might have been exploited
to them being breached and even worse is
that in a lot of those cases these
changes are actually not permanent but
after a few years these changes
effectively roll back because whatever
is being put in place is often being put
in in place too rapidly so it doesn't
actually help and it doesn't actually
improve the process it just usually just
makes it a little bit harder it makes it
a little bit more difficult so in that
case it just it's not being adopted as a
general standard at the organizational
internal procedure but rather it is just
quickly adopted to then make it improve
security for a year for five years but
in fact in ten years down the road your
security is as bad as it was initially
and what we can do to actually fix this
and to actually make it better and
improve security is we should actually
start learning from safety Sciences in a
lot of cases people have started to not
necessarily figure it out entirely but
if you look at how planes are being
operated they seem to have a
significantly better record of operating
commercial flights then we have on
actually operating commercial IT systems
and some things that we can actually
figure out and that we can adopt from
them is for example adopting automation
making sure that all things that we can
automate automate it as much as possible
then I mentioned to you already that we
want to have shared responsibilities you
don't want to have one operator deciding
that okay this checklist item is
actually fulfilled but at best you want
to have a second person making sure that
it actually is in terms of documentation
you want to understand that what kind of
changes did you make to a system you
want to have these changes documented
and you want to understand later
possibly by a third person who might
take over your role or you might be your
next operator why these changes were
made so they can actually follow and
understand what the system is supposed
to do and the most the two most
important parts that as an organization
you should probably adopt are largely
you should probably adopt incident
role-playing and that does not only
include for example pen testing which
I'm sure a lot of organizations are
already doing
but this is actually more emphasis more
emphasis on the side of your operators
and rather than just telling giving them
a list of effectively vulnerabilities
that might exist to security
misconfigurations that might exist you
actually want to have them play through
an entire incident okay what would
happen if they would discover a bridge
how would they react to it what kind of
what is the press release that
essentially your organization would put
out what is the different procedures
that you would actually have to go
through effectively everybody is doing
it already - if there's a fire in you're
simulating that there's a fire drill in
your organization's building but nobody
is doing something any similar for
actually trying to understand what would
happen if data is being extracted from
one of your data centers in terms of
blameless post-mortems the simply points
and captures to some degree the Gotcha
mentality you should not start pointing
fingers to understand once a Mis
configuration was made but rather what
you should start looking at as what led
the operator to actually make this Mis
configuration you should not start a
pointing blame and even if you argue
that you have a blameless post-mortem
and you're not a pointing blame if at
some point in the process you at least
appointing a little bit of blame this
actually wrote a lot of trust that your
operators and your employees have in
leadership because at that point they're
not actually comfortable speaking out
anymore they're not comfortable pointing
these security Mis configuration of
incidents because they feel it's either
personal failure or they're being
essentially cast as a scapegoat in this
case so overall what you should be doing
is don't just don't be the next Equifax
and instead you should choose your own
mistakes thank you
you