thanks very much so in this talk I'm
going to be talking about how browser
vendors in general and brave in
particular are pursuing privacy
protections at layers below the
extension layer and what kind of privacy
gains became gained by going deeper in
the stack so in a single slide here's
what I hope to cover first I'll take it
as read that privacy is a mess on the
web and then we got to do better but I
want to make the argument that most of
the work that's being done that's
practical in terms of protecting privacy
has been focused at the extension layers
so far and then I want to argue that we
can do better by pushing further into
the browser into the runtime into the
JavaScript engine etc to improve the
privacy the browser guarantees in that
new browser vendors are making this
possible so the way I'll push this talk
is first I'll talk a little bit about
kind of a folk history of how I think we
got to this extension focus then I'll
talk a little bit about some specific
examples of privacy modifications or
privacy improvements that brave is
pursuing that can only be achieved by
going deeper in the stack that wouldn't
be available at the extension layer then
at the end lock end with a color action
for ways that I think browser vendors in
the in the privacy community can work
together to improve web privacy so first
how do we get here
so here's a I don't mean this is a
specific technical history but I say at
a high level I think this is what
happened we have people who are
extremely interested in privacy and they
work they do extremely hard work and
extremely valuable work trying to
improve the browser but their interests
are different from the browser runners
browser vendors have an extreme level of
technical technical expertise in
maintaining runtimes and ensuring
correctness etc so these are both
extremely technical parties but they
have divergent focuses so what I think
shook out is that the browser vendors
agreed to give other people the hooks
that they needed to try to pursue their
goals and these hooks have been quasi
standardized as what we call the web
extensions API and so the web extensions
gives authors and privacy interest
privacy interest in people a limited set
of API is where they can try to make
some changes without having to maintain
the deep changes the very technical
changes that modify the runtime
in the contra that the browser vendors
can focus on what they know best and so
in a lot of ways this has been a
successful story there's a long list of
privacy-preserving extensions that have
made things much better on the web and
it's an appealing story for developers
as well the web extensions API is much
simpler to work in much more pleasant
and working and much easier to iterate
and then working down the C++ level
where most browsers are implemented and
there's we have evidence proof of this -
that extensions are extremely popular
and they have millions and millions of
users but there's a downside to this as
well extensions only have so much
understanding the web page and browsing
behavior and with this limited
perspective it comes limited
capabilities so we're ceding some ground
to what privacy privacy improvements
could be achievable that's the primary
problem and then there's also
performance issues with with focusing on
the JavaScript layer and the extensions
API so what I want to focus on is this
area of the graph up here what kind of
privacy improvements could be feel good
- or what could how could we improve
privacy on the web if we combine the
expertise of browser vendors with a
privacy focus of the privacy community
so that's how I think we got here now I
want to talk about I want to motivate
this by talking about two specific
projects that are going on at brave
where we are achieving additional
privacy by going deeper in the stack so
think of it this is the kinds of
improvements you can get if more people
focus in this area so the first project
I want to talk about is something called
add graph which is a classifier for
tracking and advertisements on web on
the web and the second one is something
we call speed reader which is a
privacy-preserving reader mode and I'll
talk about these in order so first ad
graph paragraph is something that we've
been working on a brave for a while now
this is working submitted that's under
review right now but the problem it's
targeting is we want to be able to block
Network requests that we think are going
to seed or harm the users privacy and so
this you can think about this is sitting
next to or alongside a number of
extensions these extensions are
extremely useful and they use well-known
approaches I'll talk about two different
approaches in turn but the
the goal of a graph here is both
competent to be more comprehensive but
also to be more robust against evasion a
problem that we see increasingly in the
tracking community report tracking
libraries so the first first approach I
want to talk about that a graph is gonna
iterate on top of is URL base blocking
this is an extremely common technique
that's used in extensions a block plus
plus easy privacy is probably the most
well known combination where basically
you identify URLs that fetch some sort
of privacy harming material and then you
build rules that just say anytime you
see a request that looks like this don't
fetch it so for example if we knew that
example.org slash tracking was the
privacy violating URL you might do
something like never touch anything
that's called tracking yes but this is a
relatively fragile approach we know that
there's a number of evasions that we see
being used today online some of these
are rotate through different domains so
you avoid domain based blocking by just
using DJ algorithms or things like this
to change that we're getting your code
from you might move the code from a
third party to the first party to make
it more difficult to block just the
tracking later material or you might
compose all the code you're on your site
together so you combine both the benign
code with the tracking code and making
it much more difficult to block using
these URL based approaches the second
approaches you that's fairly popular
online is a behavior based blocking and
this is a good example of this is
privacy badger shipped by e FF and so
the approach here is a little bit
different key privacy baby your base
book tracking attempts to look at the
behavior or what the types of code or
the types of actions that code is taking
as it's executing it attempts to
identify things that look very
suspicious and then possibly prevent
that code from being fetched in the
future and so for example there's ways
of using the canvas API and the WebGL
API to to fingerprint users so a privacy
based approach might say anytime we see
a single piece of code using canvas and
in WebGL we're going to see that to eat
that is very suspicious and we're going
to prevent this code from executing in
the future this approach is also is
useful but it's also prone to evasion
this is done again
a number of different ways one is again
just to move the code around so if you
block me block the code burners at
location a more people will just move it
to location beam a second one in kinda
more pernicious one is to break the code
up against multiple or the suspicious
behavior up into multiple different code
units so instead of having a sealed code
unit that does several suspicious things
you might have 10 code units to do 10
different suspicious things and that
makes it much more difficult to classify
by code unit and then third is just as
an artifact of how JavaScript engines
are implemented it can be very difficult
difficult to attribute what code is
doing what things and in v8 the the
engine that brave ships with from Google
these are known as micro tasks and micro
tasks just by as it optimization in v8
it'd be very difficult to attribute what
code is operating what code what code
unit was the owner of that function so
ed graph is an alternative to these
systems ad graph is facing the same
problem we want to decide what network
requests to allow and what never
requests to block but we do it in a very
different way instead of using blocking
based on URLs or blocking based on
behavior we want to instrument the
browser in a number of different layers
we want to understand the never West's
that are being made the layout
properties of the page so those are
things like the Dom structure and what
code units what JavaScript code is
modifying that and then things that are
just specifically in the JavaScript code
so ways of doing deeper attribution them
is able than it is possible in the gate
right now and understanding what code
units launch other code units that sort
of thing we we can post these things
into a graph and we use that graph to to
inform a machine learning based
classifier just decide whether or not
tell our request to happen so I want to
make this more concrete with a specific
example imagine a JavaScript blob the
web author dumps into a page that code
executes and fetches another piece of
JavaScript that it appends following
that that JavaScript code reads cookies
or some other sensitive information and
then pushes that into the URL of an
image that it appends to the document
this is how a number of tracking or
analytic libraries are implemented ad
graph will implement this has the
following well first notice that a
script
is created and will notice the vet
script element created another script
element will also then notice the vet
script element modified the source of
the URL with the source of the script
element and in that script element
fetches some code from somewhere else
well then notice that the script element
created an image element that I modified
the source of that image the image
element then made a request Emeril's so
by composing getting this kind of rich
understanding of what's going on in the
browser it allows us to make more
informed choices so instead of trying to
classify just based on the URL or just
based on what a single unit of code is
doing we get this much richer picture
which allows us to be more robust to
these very kind of simple equations and
the results of this so far have been
very promising we were able to replicate
human labels of whether or not code is
tracking related with over 95% accuracy
we're able because we're not susceptible
to the kinds of DGA or other kind of
evasions that current approaches are
susceptible to we're able to track or
identify code that look that avoids
other tools we're also able to run very
quickly by pushing things deep down into
the the runtime layer and not just
operating at the JavaScript layer and
the extensions API we're also not we're
not we don't the fragility of relying on
the static list like easy lists and easy
privacy which are very useful but are
also very fragile in what I want to
highlight here is that this approach
wouldn't be possible by just focusing on
the job as an extension API we wouldn't
have the breadth that we needed to
inform the graph who wouldn't be able to
reach down to the JavaScript engine to
understand how the interrelationship
between code units and we wouldn't be
able to do this quickly and if it's not
done quickly then the users are not
going to be interested in the privacy
protections we can deliver so that's a
graph now I want to talk briefly about
another technology we're working on
called speed reader which protects
privacy in a very different way so speed
reader is an additional research that
we've been working on it brave and the
way speed river works is at a high level
it also protects privacy but by blocking
network resources but instead of trying
to identify the network of resources
that are the the resources that are
dangerous we instead invert the problem
and just focus on the content that we
think is useful to users and we ignore
everything else so is anybody who's used
a reader mode tool
can attest a large portion of every page
is not directly useful to the user in
any given time that might be boilerplate
like menus or animations or things like
videos that are playing on the side
that's not strictly needed to enjoy the
content of the page so the approach here
is to focus on the good and ignore
everything else
well I graph is focusing on the bad and
trying to exclude that so I want to
explain how speed-reader works by
comparing it to the functionality of
existing reader modes so in existing
reader modes as they're implemented in
most shipping browsers today the browser
makes a request to the server the server
responds back with some HTML the browser
executes to the page by fetching all the
sub resources in the page those might be
ads images videos things like that in
each of those with their own network
requests so each of those also post some
privacy evaluating risk then once those
are executed in the page the reasonable
reader mode is usually operated by
injecting some JavaScript into the page
the JavaScript understands what's going
on in the page and tries to extract just
things that it thinks are useful use it
usually by using some heuristics like
link to something and then this
extracted subsection is presented to the
user as the reader mode version of the
page speed reader is different speed
reader starts off the same way by making
a fetch to the server we're caring
receiving the HTML but instead of
rendering it as a page we use a number
of different heuristics to try to
identify whether or not there's a useful
subsection of this page that we think a
user will be interested in this is a
machine learning based approach using a
large hand labelled data set and if we
think there is likely to be some some
subset of the document that will be
useful to users then we don't fit we
don't learn to the page at all we don't
issue any number requests for sub
resources I said we just do the
extraction on the HTML itself and render
that and then that result of this is
that we're doing dramatically fewer
Network requests to a dramatically fewer
parties and we're not executing
fingerprinting related JavaScript code
if you don't if we don't think there's a
readable subset then we just proceed as
normal and the results of this are
pretty tremendous both in terms of
performance but also in terms of privacy
protection
so on the top row here we have
measurements of just using a default
version of chromium and visiting a large
number of pages so and I'm just to pull
out a couple of the numbers here on
average our automated versions of
chromium will interact with hundreds of
with over a hundred third parties in the
average case fewer in the median case
but still an enormous number of part of
third parties informing them or
potentially informing them of the users
browser behavior we also see that a
large number of scripts are executed on
a single page 51 scripts in the median
case 24 percent of which are 24 of which
are identified as tracking or or
advertising related using a number of
filter lists speed-reader because it
doesn't doesn't render the page before
it attempts to extract the meaningful
subset does a far just far less
communication with third parties we see
that in the average case we're only
talking to a single third party meaning
62 different 62 other parties never
learn about the first party
communication we don't see any scripts
executed we don't see any add or
tracking material it fetched so this
isn't gonna work on every page only a
certain sub certain type of pages can be
amenable to this type of intervention
but first for sites where this is useful
you can see that the performances the
performance and privacy protections are
dramatic and again I want to want to
make the argument that this is not
possible by focusing on web extensions
extensions aren't most web extensions as
they're the most extension API is there
implemented in most browsers don't allow
the user to modify the page and/or thus
the extension to modify the page in real
time there are exceptions to this but
not in the common case which means that
most extensions don't have the bandaged
point to do this kind of work in general
excuse me and then also because we're
doing classification in a number of
different levels both what they're not
we think there's a readable subset of
the document and then also extracting
the readable subset of the document
there's a fair amount of machine
learning going on here under the hood
and that's also something that we don't
want to be doing at the JavaScript layer
where we're blocking everything so
pushing it down lower in the stack ends
up being vital to making this a useful
turn a useful tool
so so far I've talked about what how I
think we got to this extension focus and
some benefit I hope I've given some
examples of benefits of moving beyond
this extension focus no now I want to
make the claim that it's important that
we keep pushing things further to
protect privacy so again consider this
this this region at the top of top right
of the graph where there's a focus on
privacy preserving extensions no sorry
but where we can combine the the domain
knowledge of browser vendors with the
privacy focus and privacy concern of
extension authors and if we the more we
can focus up here the more and the more
new browser vendors move into this space
the the deeper we can protect users
privacy so the what's new now or what it
allows this new approach is that there's
no longer just for large browser vendors
there's a large number of new browser
vendors that are moving into the space
and they're making these kinds of
approaches practical and this means that
these browser vendors who are willing
and interested in working with you to
take your complex ideas and maintain
them over time so if extensions allow
you to take a subset of tools and share
them a large share them with large and
order of users new browser vendors want
to ship complex approaches to large
number of users and not only are there
new browser vendors that are different
sizes and different levels of
aggressiveness site many of these
privacy new browser vendors are
explicitly privacy focused brave is one
of these but we're far from from the
only one and now and because we're we're
smaller fish in a big pond we're also
extremely eager to work with researchers
and privacy activists and we're willing
to take ideas that are maybe a longshots
and think about how we can actually ship
them out to working users so the thing I
hope I hope you take away from this is
that if you have an idea don't don't
limit yourself to the extension API
don't limit yourself just to the hooks
that browser vendors provided to you
today but reach out to other browser
vendors and work with us so we can help
protect privacy for everyone thanks very
much
you
[Applause]