hi today I'd like to talk about the
mismatch between the security and
privacy tools that we design and kids in
the K through 12 classroom
if you're concerned about your safety
online you know it's a struggle out
there it's even tougher for kids who
were exposed to computers earlier and
more frequently than ever as adults we
may be frustrated by the permission
prompts privacy policies and passwords
that are intended to keep us safe but
for kids these tools don't make sense
and they're also tough for the teachers
administrators and software companies
that are trying to help kids access
technology in school I've been thinking
about student data privacy and security
for the past three years as a member of
the engineering team at clever clever is
an identity platform and single sign-on
portal that's used in over half of the K
through 12 classrooms in the United
States
I came to clever because I believe that
technology can improve education and a
better education better educated
educated society means better outcomes
for everybody as someone who cares about
people's right to online safety I know
that if we give children access to
technology in the classroom it needs to
be safe that's where all of us come in
we need to understand how children use
technology in the classroom to build
effective security and privacy
mechanisms for them and I'd like to talk
about what I've learned for the past
three years first I'm going to talk
about the risks of what's happening
right now the security and privacy
threat model for education technology
next I'll talk about prompts policies
and passwords things that are difficult
for adults that are huge challenges for
kids next I'll talk about what I see
that's working and after that I'm happy
to answer any questions that you might
have
if you're a kid in school people want
access to your educational data for a
variety of reasons the Department of
Education recently warned that hackers
are targeting elementary and high
schools they attempt to extort money
from school districts by holding student
data for ransom
researchers at Fordham look for and
found student data brokers selling
personal information about students
including their ethnicity affluence
religion and lifestyle these lists are
used for everything from college
recruiting to targeting advertising for
family planning services as we can see
in this transcript of a voicemail that
the researchers received from a data
broker as adults were concerned about
cyber criminals targeting our identity
for theft corporations targeting our
personal information for profit and
governments targeting our businesses
kids faced a different set of concerns
like cyber bullying abuse educational
data mining and algorithmic
discrimination but we give them our
adult defenses those of us who build
security and privacy mechanisms should
be able to empathize with kids since we
all used to be one
but even software designed for children
inherence the security and privacy
problems of the one-size-fits-all
internet we know this so we restrict
kids access to technology but if we're
overly restrictive kids don't get the
benefits of technology and this is
especially important if you believe in
the potential for technology to improve
educational outcomes you may remember
the early days of educational software
and titles like Oregon Trail number
munchers and we're in the
world is Carmen Sandiego in today's us K
through 12 classroom kids have access to
hundreds of different software services
some are designed specifically for the
classroom like I excel math or flick AB
you Larry
others have crossover appeal like Khan
Academy or duolingo or Google Docs kids
use Chromebooks iPads and Windows
devices that are either given to them
directly or shared with other students
or brought from home
curriculum departments evaluate software
to deploy across entire districts with
the goal of personalizing the learning
process
improving assessment scores and
ultimately changing people's lives for
the better research has shown that
students using computers have improved
motivation problem-solving abilities and
assessment scores and we spend a lot of
money on education technology 27 billion
dollars in 2017 alone but if you step
into the classroom and you look at the
data it's not clear that it's working
there are many barriers to deploying
education technology in the classroom
like broken screens or inadequate
training on usage one of the very
persistent barriers that technology
brings with it is a legacy of security
and privacy problems and when you're
talking to a concerned parent the bar
for the acceptable risk of a new
technology is very high when security
and privacy don't work in the classroom
we end up with two outcomes that we
don't want one if children lose control
of their data before they can possibly
be expected to understand the
consequences that's bad but it's also
bad if they're stuck and they don't get
access to the beneficial aspects of
technology the educational potential I'd
like to talk about three
kid-friendly security and privacy
mechanisms and then I'll talk a little
bit about the work that's happening that
I think can make things better the
prefrontal cortex is a part of the brain
implicated in complex decision-making
planning and social interaction it's not
fully developed until around the age of
25 that's why kids don't vote or decide
what they eat for dinner or even decide
if they can go on a field trip adults
act as surrogate decision-makers for
kids especially when it comes to safety
decisions in the school context
school officials make safety decisions
for kids and this should include
decisions about how they share their
data but it often doesn't because the
tools we give them don't support it
think about how you share data online
many of the interactions aren't designed
to deal with this idea of surrogate
decision-making and this is an ethical
problem not only for students and
schools but also for adults incapable
medically of making decisions if you're
a student in school who should even get
to decide where your data goes is it
your teacher or your principal
maybe the curriculum Department what
about your parents do they get a say or
maybe software companies should decide
ultimately each of these people need to
agree and showing permission prompts to
students doesn't help that researchers
research suggests that permission
prompts don't even help keep us safe
when we encounter permission problems
frequently we become habituated to them
where we ignore them because we have a
finite amount of attention when we show
permission prompts to kids they're not
only exposed to the habituation effect
but they also get confused and if you
read the AppStore reviews from kids or
if you field support tickets from
teachers you learn that these permission
prompts are barriers to using software
in the classroom eating away at limited
instructional time
another prompt that leads to the
habituation effects in adults RTLS
warnings often they're just
configuration errors not real attacks in
the school environment they're
especially prevalent because internet
content filtering is required by the
children's Internet Protection Act these
filters are often architected as
middleware boxes with root certificates
installed on every student's device but
they're often misconfigured so that
students go to visit web sites and the
certificate isn't recognized and they
encounter a TLS err that they learn at a
very early age to ignore another prompt
that adults and students struggle with
is built into the weight-bearing
protocol for identity on the web oh ah
in the OAuth flows the person making the
decision about whether to share the data
is the same person that the data is
about this doesn't make sense for
students when adults have already
decided for them to share this data as
platforms become more integrated and
tightly controlled we as designers lose
the flexibility to modify these default
behaviors prompts don't work well for
the fully formed prefrontal cortexes
that they were designed for they don't
work at all for kids when they put the
responsibility on the end user to make
complicated safety decisions they
probably still work better than privacy
policies which work for almost no-one
we've known this since the early 2000s
when USA Today published an article that
said the top 10 sites privacy policies
we're all written at a college level or
higher whereas the average reading level
is at a grade 10 there's an obvious
mismatch between the information that we
give people to make decisions and the
information that they actually use to
make those decisions I don't think it's
even moderately surprising that privacy
policies can't be expected to hell
kids are elected legislators seem to
agree and 121 state student privacy laws
have been passed since 2013
these laws like privacy policies attempt
to set obligations for companies that
handle student data but are they
effective let's take a look at a federal
law The Children's Online Privacy
Protection Act Coppa regulates how
companies can collect and process
personal information from children under
the age of 13 researchers at the
Berkeley laboratory for usable and
experimental security built a static
analysis tool to look at Android
applications and determine if they were
sending personal information to
third-party services they ran this tool
on over 5,000 applications from the
Google Play stores designed for families
program which must be Coppa compliant
they found that 73% of these apps
transmitted personal data to third-party
services an apparent violation of Coppa
here are some examples of the data they
found being sent the reason this was so
common third-party SDKs that are
designed for analytics and advertising
not children in Coppa even if companies
want to follow every letter of the law
it's still very very difficult for them
to do so a recently enacted California
student data privacy law the student
online personal information Protection
Act mandates that companies that handle
student data must maintain reasonable
security procedures the translation of
this confusing standard into day to day
engineering decision-making means that
at least some companies are going to
have data breaches and sure enough they
have designing secure systems for
children is just as tricky as designing
systems that respect their privacy and
passwords like prompts and policies are
designed about assumptions for adults
that don't make sense for kids
if you're a young kid entering even a
simple password takes a long time
schools don't even attempt to have
complicated passwords for young students
but even complicated passwords aren't
that secure which is why we have to
factor but two-factor systems that rely
on you having a phone don't make sense
for kids who don't have phones or aren't
allowed to use their phone in the
classroom
imagine your teacher and you've somehow
successfully been able to hand out a
cart full of shared tablets to your
students and they're signed in and on
task and then at the end of class they
hand back in the tablets and you have to
go through each one to make sure that
they've logged out otherwise the next
student in the class will get their data
the security and privacy tools we build
don't always work in classrooms so what
do we need to know to design for the
classroom context we should design for
misuse because kids are chaotic and
resist control we've seen DLS attacks
that originate from the classroom we
went to teach coding at a local middle
school and some students felt like
hackers when they were able to modify a
web page and the browser inspector but
others crowded around a student who
found a web page where you could fire a
virtual machine gun at Justin Bieber's
face keeping control over classrooms
means giving control to teachers
teachers hand out passwords on the first
day of school to students they help
students who can't log in they answer
questions and provide support they're
the glue that holds the classroom
together and their role needs to be
baked into the security and privacy
tools that we give kids district
administrators tackle huge security and
privacy challenges with limited budget
and support
fortunately there's some great work
going on in the EdTech and privacy
communities that's trying to help make
sure what we have is safe at the
symposium for usable privacy and
security last year there was a workshop
around designing security and privacy
tools for children and teenagers they
reviewed a mobile monitoring application
with a group of children redesigning
some features the children thought
parents shouldn't be able to control
they sketched out a system for safely
responding to messages from strangers on
youth-focused social media they show
that it's possible to guide children
towards safety by cooperatively
designing technology at Kleber I've
helped build a single sign-on portal for
the classroom and one of the problems we
noticed was that young students have
trouble entering passwords and it takes
up a lot of time so we built a system
where schools can print out badges with
QR codes on them that students can hold
up to webcams in order to sign in I'd
like to show a video that brings in some
of the voices around who this talk
centers the teachers and students who
use the technology we build
just really eager to learn
alright something you should lock him in
but their username
password it was very hard for them
because they don't know their ladders
and they don't know their numbers how do
I stop
like for them to lock it and type in in
their username and password can take
between well get through this Wi-Fi is
making it a little choppy a minute to
five minutes just depending on the
student when they logged in
using their username and password they
weren't really excited about now I feel
like I seen right away their soul
eager and excited to even login to use
their online mentor counselor
when we designed for children we
designed for a range of awareness
capability and autonomy and similarly
when we design security and privacy
tools we shouldn't make things
one-size-fits-all if you work on a
browser or an operating system or any
piece of software that might impact
children I encourage you to think about
their unique threat model EdTech can
change the world but first it needs to
be both safe and useful kids face
security and privacy challenges in the
classroom and to help solve them we need
to understand how our technology impacts
them Thanks
[Applause]