pretty big trend dance pretty much
touches everything take everything is
regressive dress that's right three
bowling with that as far as an agenda
for today looking for on-the-fly am
going to talk about what it is routine
white matters what it really means it's
not everything is connect that sets are
talking about that talking about the
architecture security considerations
conference i will talk a little about
what about my experience with my
question
so first up my name seems to work fine
Christopher below troll technology
architect for its architecture for your
company currently focus on the Internet
of Things megatrends technology
obsolescence technology disruptors and
other megatrends second if you want to
follow me on twitter my body count is
pretty active got like six hundred
dollars which is pretty interesting but
I post a lot of stuff from our business
for you going to eat that stuff so as
far as i wake up in the mornings Martina
my daughter probably on top of 13 my son
play 15 on the bottom
I myself and the third generation in
erosion grandfather mother and herself
pretty sure it was one of these two is
going to end up here as well three
classes away from having my masters and
organizational leadership as far as my
background goes pretty much primary
advantage on here since i graduated from
Ambrose
I've worked as a system
never have been i been with the desktop
crew has never approve away and type
stuff
the infrastructure manager for your
tracks which is the largest construction
forestry dealer west telecomm project
managers so we're going to negotiate
contracts design wired networks and
stuff
product manager for OLAP group and
finally wearing today just so let's talk
about
oh and then when I'm not doing these
three or no stop taking pictures travel
so what about what kind of things is
what it is part of a big megatrend push
right now technology that would be the
cloud a lake machine learning and all
those things together can shape the way
the future is going to look we're going
to talk more about that
so today we're talking about the
internet of things so I like to be
interactive so next question who knows
what is Wally very good
can you tell me what people did in the
movie water they did not write to
develop robots friendship tried the AI
artificial intelligence
so in a nutshell this is the Internet of
Things this is where we're going when
you look at these megatrends all those
coming to add to this this is the future
it's a little scary to think about it
here sit around all day watch to be but
if you look at be origin of the internet
of things around for 17 years and what
you find is that Internet of Things is
actually probably missing that Internet
itself is utility right like powers like
water expected to be there and so people
in my team uniform believe that it's
easy to rename too smart connected
products
we're going to talk about smart a lot in
this presentation
that means but some things that you're
called the internet of everything I OTE
industrial Internet of Things or IOT
your products industrial and are
connected products and finally the
fourth Industrial Revolution
so why does that matter
well it's because it's part of the
fourth Industrial Revolution right so
you think of the first one cotton mills
colleges that were steam-powered got a
second just henry ford you can happen
any color you want as long flat back
assembly lines you've got computer and
automation seventies and eighties right
one for taking our jobs and then finally
today cyber-physical systems cyber
physical systems themselves are
mechanisms that are controlled and
monitored by computer based our straight
so these are in advance for about this
is a Gartner hype cycle of anybody here
seen Carter before but we do a lot with
darker we're going to trust their
expertise and if you look at this you
actually seen the Exorcist and
expectations on why you're seeing time
and then you're seeing basically the
innovation trips as things come to
market as people need to be aware of
that innovation trigger then you get
into the peak of inflated expectations
take everybody shut up this is awesome
right
and then you get to draw dissolution it
can about it because of this right here
because we're not ready for you get the
slope of enlightenment where people go
ok we can use it to use it for this
right and then finally you get in
productivity production for us if you
look at this is actually from july 2015
on purpose if you look at the Internet
of Things look at the dots here instead
of that kind of things especially
expecting to go wide 5-10 years right
values crosses that Internet of Things
platforms the things that make smart
isolated to go live for a little bit
after that and what's interesting is
this slide this 2016 so this you want
your letter says here's the internet
platform so it's actually moved from
innovation trigger people that inflated
expectations but where's the other
things it's not so what is happening
between this slide right where is out
there 5-10 years of inflated
expectations
where did they go
so I'm not saying that they moving on
purpose but i'm saying something about
torch here
that's what I guess I don't know I don't
know what you're thinking I haven't had
a chance to talk about you but we think
about the internet of things that we
break it down a little bit harder but it
really means smart connected products ok
risk / smart for second you find out a
second why but if you like you're
connected right
basically anything that can talk to
everything around it that's connected
right we don't care how just gonna talk
the other thing is that these are
products throughout the show the gold
sit in my office and take a razor I can
work we just by reading we must support
them we don't have to do anything we've
been always taking on blocks plug-in
work so that's a key part there with the
smart part that's where we get it it's a
little love reputation straight so smart
for me being something probably those
for you so let's take a quick quiz
raise your hand if you agree or disagree
but is yourself
just what makes smart solid at how those
sort of artist
ok
yes cell phones are because it uses the
transfers whatever I told ok so in the
world of innovative things ourselves and
get that excited so same thing cover
your computer basically your mobile base
computer a this is part of this app
well that's smart to be no it's not why
is that well this is we doing the
science CJ so these IOT versions here
these are minor and the reason they're
not smart because of this here and i
have version 1.2 smart things on your
device yourself actually sensor right
who makes the decision use right it's at
77 degrees out and grab a jacket
it's gonna rain I need to grab a relic
great you've made the decision so that's
better and things first point out if we
if we look at our gateways right so
anyways we're singing a thousand
cellphone stock gateway to get all the
information from the sensors in basic
decision it sends those notifications
back out pay you to where you need to
wear a jacket relevant right just having
sex okay then you got the future right
is the wally world which is in the
future the smart devices the device
itself right all machine learning all
the ends around all the advanced
algorithms happened on the device so
that's it in the same point
okay that makes sense as far as smart
goes we have argued that like to do like
rivers makes right so here's where Matt
straight so today people make the
decision makes a decision making this
fun right people take a vacation they
have politics have a bad day
great real great work whatever is up and
that's a problem right
Gateway's little bit faster right we're
now taking from the device to another
device making the decision sending it
back so we take people out respectively
it's a little bit faster right there's
one point a to point be loaded with the
Vice it's a lot faster rate because now
its resident even if it was real time
right so we're seeing a lot of things
today with a call near real-time parties
right or three or four second flag that
three or four second flag can affect
other decisions that place has great
success
okay so-so i'm horrible example to your
question when so into the net
issues like do next
fire protection with that balls of the
feet pointing to be more between want to
do you still have to make the decision
to learn for your input to learn from
you sending the dial at one o'clock in
the afternoon or whatever it says that
information out to a gateway or platform
right google tools nest and then sends
that information back grade one percent
of like fire crackers prices our
community child device i was sure that
machine machine is that yeah it's
another big piece of it but I think when
it comes to smart decision making until
that device itself can make that
decision it's not it's not it's on 93.1
we're still just eight to 10 it's still
residing on relying on something else to
make the decision itself so horrible
example but one that picture simplicity
and IOT one right now so you're smart to
brush
ok let's say I'm going to 6am and it's
not for me but this hookup with 600 and
I'm going to straight Russian team done
brushing with toothbrush down and
toothbrush to coffee maker broke up that
simple i want talking up and populate
your tells the marches and shut off open
the garage door starts okay this is a
normal day with linear logic we can
program this what happens when something
changes so let's look at is doing right
so now I go downstairs it's 5am I mean
india i'm getting up a little bit
earlier I don't brush my teeth go back
to that we don't have a right well
coffee cover the coffee maker has to be
smart enough to know not to turn off the
alarm system not open the grass or not
to ruin your heart why's that cause its
marking it has learned that something
has changed something in that pattern is
no longer the same and you had to make a
decision so we talk smart we have to
talk decision and that's kind of a keen
of the internet of things and really
understanding what it means
the media thanks man you got it all
figured out internet of things are
connected products / huh right every
jeep grand cherokee 2015 20 today is
happening here but they don't make
decisions look at autopilot systems in
airplanes Greg had those seven do they
make decisions really follow rules right
so we're kind of in a weird place where
things have to get smart things
happening decisions and way to do that
do that is by talking to everything
around taking all that information and
training back right
cognitive that's kind of where we are
thinking this is going to go it might
get by with quantum computing will see
so i don't know how many people in here
architects but because i'm an architect
partner lost to show architecture slides
so here's the Internet of Things pyramid
this is the things on the bottom right
and then you got communications and
controllers next up is platforms will
process talk about platforms in the
second to the operators right so right
now this is a version one final slide
things began makeup sensors would take
those sensors and have to invent a
computer device like a raspberry pi r
you know it's several that gives you a
little more dance thing ready to close
your cell phone but still not making
decisions get the communications and
controllers right because all the stuff
moved without some way to get the data
out where to transfer the data between
itself and other devices you've got
platforms and processes platforms and
things we're thinking on board right now
I don't know how many people use md a
permanent whole device management
basically you got a cell phone in your
corporate network they can talk on your
device right from from that any platform
same thing in those days as things come
on we plugged into the network they get
on board by the platform the platform
here's the ruleset platform is an IP
address platform get some task right and
so that's how they started again one
point of those things are expected to be
smart they're expected to contribute to
human machine inner strength so right
now version 1.2 this is where things get
people insights people react to those
insights that works when you look at
Gartner again and this is one that I
actually subscribe
two from corporate standpoint is they
break it down three times and that's the
engine platform in the enterprise and so
manager where your advice stars for
machine-to-machine happens between ok
boys are the aggregators what's credible
that helps lie on it is the gateway to
actually take business rules and then
strip data that's coming in from the
Internet of Things devices actually
strips it and it forwards a lot of
what's important and that's how flat was
able to make decisions lot quicker so
the decision back out to the Gateway a
very sensitive to these devices and
everything moves on now if you look at
overlaying the pyramid with gardeners
far as a reference architecture kind of
all right so it's very seamless and I'm
basically giving you three architecture
of using the same thing and see which
one sticks but in both of these examples
that you're seeing your board this is
the other things
this is right another thing is not a
raspberry pi cell phone device traits
multiple devices it's multiple things
across the range if you look at this
model so this is actually thinking from
cisco start the bottom kind of those you
know the OSI model to start the bottom
to the top physical devices conductivity
Gator mapping so on and this is how they
kind of work do you work from the bottom
to the top with another models you can
get your brains around what it takes to
make all so security-wise not going to
spend a lot of time I because it's
pretty pretty peppy subject but hackers
remotely got energy blasts year my wife
actually has the model that itself is it
is actually challenging hackers is
actually people who had information to
get into the product with the idea there
was that the Jeep was right down Highway
they turn the radio all the way up
they roll down the windows and turn heat
internal card jokes aside so with those
in mind we have to be where I think we
have to understand that relax security
concerns around that security has to be
first foremost in any Internet of Things
project great any
things product so some of the other you
know
add the other god particle seasons here
you go officer for yourself but when you
think security that there's an
interesting piece here that's device and
SD security right so we know those
things have to be encrypted if they have
to be locked down but what happens when
your things usually get a device and get
card right so these devices today or not
hardware that they're not protected
against walking away
they're just smaller devices that's what
empowers the Internet of Things smaller
process so as you get thousands of these
teeny tiny little raspberry PI's are you
know it's whatever you can get the
device to walk away and get the card
lock with the car bombs away
data logs away right IP walks with and
data is the new what so going to be
thinking about ivy compliance we think
about the device encryption about the
sdcard inversion think about
standardized protocols things that we
don't even believe in like an ETA and p
we have to trust that the business is
actually training those rules were not
gathered too much data and putting that
out of the cloud where somebody else
could use it against us we think about
securing that scores right when it does
get out of date us how do we know how do
you know you can access that we have to
secure that aggregation extractions who
does get access to it working to pull it
out to their what can access the I'm
sorry
well we can access the idea what
applications are plowing into that that
data link if you order that cloud of
information and finally great
none of these are groundbreaking
thoughts on security but it kind of fits
into that staff great the cisco
reference model yet but it just to get
you thinking about what it will take to
secure the internet effects
so my first project is only in the
presentation i gave on this but
basically I was tasked with the point
for temperature sensors to lab
environment track of Dragon temperatures
in AWS just chill out all right well
there was a problem right number one is
that these vices come in from today
we're going from bottom they're not
built for the enterprise for corporate
partners before house very simple to use
I think the raspberry PI's raspy and iOS
four LS that can run Windows 10 IOT
isn't people so we have to be very
simple so we can start playing around
them
what I did was I went out and got those
red eyes 35 bucks each
I ended up using a great point which is
a high five
basically the extended range and I have
my own account with us and lambda to the
graphic right so really simple really
cheap circumvented all the corporate
issues all the wireless issues as far as
getting onto are really well protected
wireless network getting past the proxy
I couldn't do that which for those you
wanted a corporate environment processes
that kind of filter internet access to
make sure you should go so i used a lot
of these things to get around some of
those systems right just to just do it
and as a result the business happy
everybody is super happens fast and easy
to do on really looking for being told
ya 1.5 hours didn't take much at all and
I was here
however write some of the things I had
to do like packing the wp7 package I
didn't clear text prudential prosecute
them from jobs to constantly refresh the
proxies was constantly looking out and
it likes him listen so ended up going
that creative way
finally the Creator point is that
oh no we're not going to have those are
corporate environments because they can
open up our devices that are connected
to them to outside hackers traits in
certain that scary is a personal account
for company assets data in the cloud and
again which is great when plants so
after doing that director of operations
which closes the profit after closing
the project director of operations
basically for me that they found that's
how groundbreaking is always into the
thing things where you have to work with
corporate policies you have to work
around some of the compliance issues
some of the IP issues to make sure that
you're you're meeting the business
challenge with the same time you have to
work from within those walls to change
those policies change those procedures
as well so that you don't fire which
surface so finally inclusion will take
questions you can't stop here this is a
baby trend is coming already felt it
raised its members were not got your
first iPhone and Apple decided to open
up tracking right where i can find
iphone back myself people known to do
that but now we use it for everything i
want to actually accidentally left it on
the go back state plan exactly where I
left right so that's an example of
things once we know where things are
connected there's smart reading the
sensor in that phone told the platform
to find iPhone platform Apple where my
phone is like a decision but it was
forming that information
oh you gotta all know what smart means
now I'm hoping from the internet of
things right so one point two point
three point you realize that word so a
lot of people are thinking it's everyone
Robert is not think we'll get smarter
than I see problem next 10 years this
machine analytics team learning advanced
analytics all those things kind of fell
together all these megatrends come
together you're going to see a lot more
of this and so good example is this week
were announced their first autonomous
track you see that pittsburgh right
pretty amazing another company and
oncology or Singapore only time you
really six autonomous taxes free in the
gold errors to your cards right
basically smart products will drive
around the city to go so those are just
a couple of examples smart right so
there's 1.2 and finally make security
foundation of any IT project kahn all
singing job and then your seat on the
accident
questions you do it we're not gonna get
well if you have a major gap train that
did not tell you that you couldn't take
custom coding region so we are allowed
to wear a lot of little cloud connected
to so as available on Amazon want to
give a direct connection to so we're
allowed to use our corporate accounts to
sort of our corporate Dana in corporate
accounts audience but not your personal
zone
ok so now that one way the other way was
bringing unsecured devices to the lab
partner labs are kind of those typically
go with that together with that pot area
where some of the data so temperatures
are not a big deal in fact as a result
of that project we figured out that
people were accessing leaving for lunch
coming back into from lunch into a door
that's causing the temperatures luxury
and so as it as a outcome of that
project basically fix people's behaviors
in that it's affecting some of the tests
they're going on so that's one thing
that the second thing was putting
company assets so evening temperatures
have been the deal
what can our competitors to look at that
temperature data rates only they'd
understand when the data came from the
lab environment production product
development area they figure out that we
like it
71 degrees well whatever
that's right so those are some of the
areas that didn't think about it again
came from my director to go do this
what can you do that sure I basically
got rid of all the rules for law of the
door right this temperature that's the
deal parents so there's not much I could
have done
I should've known better as that it
typically we can drop our apartment
58 Oh God by the guys again right you're
playing with this and that but that
particular case the director of
operations was not happy with the
decision of the party and talk about
sensors and the biggest challenges of
action are you going to market devices
work so all of your match up to ya
breath by for each other down
great so what do you see for use your
gift that point out our sure true so we
don't dabble lunch in the device aspect
of this because right now it's kind of
well bless right everybody is coming out
with something and so when it comes to
just dabbling very much basically buying
things off shopping with them i'm
looking at the transfer of because you
know argument really big for the most
part factor tg's modular telematic
gateways are actually on all of our
vehicles vehicles are all that hard
they're scanning or basically so we
don't really look at the size of things
break down as far as the trans go
things are getting smaller and smaller
smaller bike probably knows the law with
the IT laws for Los hores law Wranglers
basically technology doubled over six
months 18 months 18 months okay right so
you can inspect these things get smaller
and smaller far one of the presentations
on giving next week because i'm taking
transit in that presentation or talk
about smart materials and polymers and
copolymers are expecting three silicon
because we're getting to the they're so
regular level
comes into play so you can expect to get
better with your right is going to take
a few needs a few different technology
aspects to get to where we think the
party just started asking questions
speaking smaller so if you could not
repress about agriculture and they
frequently and flower a description of
our robots replace tractors through it
jet printer type devices are your
seating for you
we need all this big o and O frankly
11-week I kind of wonder if the
conductor in sorry what john deere
whether John your visions any areas
where conceivably you could be replaced
not just against apply our great
question
so first thing into that is I was in
Germany the summer vacation with my son
and have kids with soccer for sliding we
have to get this giant german complex
and I noticed there were no lowers even
if you place a couple Jack Morris and
figure out its hole and that's when I
realized over the corner of every single
fuel was a giant gray box giant meeting
the size of the screen right I got a
little closer to a relationship right
after hours that motor which is fully
charged with go out and it would line
the entire you know just that and then
we go back part was probably three to
five thousand straight
John you're actually we actually make
similar products that we actually call
25 their travel rumba great example of
that we'd actually only sell in Europe
we don't sell here because
one guard to conquer the day kill
anything
oh but hearing you must be policies
against in-laws instance we can actually
type of thomas equipment out there was
lots of changing every day so one of the
things we're talking about next weekend
megatrend are the rise of so people that
you actually come in Sheriff right you
all probably were heard something coming
to pick you up
those are fungible access to assets so
they were pics now the Angels so the
fixed with a company car just sits there
money appreciating vs fungible mean we
take the car running somebody think
about mid line with it is you can kinda
way the depreciation there separately
but you're exactly right John your
fashion are very much focused on what
that's going to be our high horsepower
products like I heard data this week
that horsepower as far as John as far as
tractors as far as farming it actually
paint the 1920s bar but the tractor
market itself the next 20 so it's not a
downward decline entire time for reason
that is because every year there's a
recent uptick horsepower right so you
have more power so we do that
yes the future is probably know that
John you're a gag driving itself for
about 12 years right
actually the farmers still in the
equipment he saw that works out of
control but it will go from point a to
point b line and plant or a tail or
whatever that entire field and in turn
around come back we actually make
products that can do that so we love
that hustle but uh we're bored
you're right in what is it going to look
like you are we have drums they go out
and spray everything i'll write the drug
drug laws are changing between nineteen
where you have bigger ones they could go
higher altitude that isn't what's that
we're very much heat is what does look
like it up to you
one of the things I've been talking
about the concept of training people to
wrap their brains around John Deere used
to be attracting companies that use
technology is not technology company
than the extractors that's the way we
have and that's what we're pushing
people to thank for trying to meet the
next generation knows maybe 50 billion
devices on the internet for 2020
so that's a lot of devices we also
deliver to be 9 billion people on this
planet few years back so we're not
seeing your asking any major competitors
as far as what is going to come at us in
the next 10 years as far as how that
works power will have to go away but we
are still doing that startups these
things below ground with the stuff those
things that drive us we pushed so I
think we're out of time
watch for lunch time we got pretty good
friend touches everything everything is
your best interests of things right
rebuilding that as far as an agenda for
today we're going to ongoing and i'm
here to talk about what it is
19y matters what it really means it's
not everything is connect that sets are
talking about that talking about the
architecture security considerations
conference i will talk about looking
about my experience with my questions
so first up my name is a work of finding
Chris verbal
using trouble the technology our
technology and art architecture group
your company currently focus on the
Internet of Things megatrends technology
obsolescence to healthy disruptors and
other megatrends things second if you
want to follow me on twitter my body
count is pretty active got 600 followers
which is pretty interesting but I post a
lot of stuff from our business for you
and I see that stuff so far as i wake up
in the mornings Martina my daughter
Polly on top of 13 is on the plane
15 on the bottom I myself in the third
generation in erosion grandfather mother
and herself pretty sure it was one of
these two is going to end up here as
well have three classes away from my
masters and organizational leadership as
far as my background goes pretty much
primary in a minute job here since i
graduated from Ambrose
I've worked as a system and network
admin I with his desktop fruit has never
approve a and Plan type stuff
the infrastructure manager for your
tracks which is the largest construction
forestry dealer west telecomm project
managers so we're going to negotiate
contracts signed wired network second
stuff product manager for OLAP group and
finally wearing today Justin out Kara
text so let's talk about
oh and then when I'm not doing with
these three or no stop
mountain biking taking pictures track so
let's talk about what kind of things is
what it is part of a big megatrend push
right now technology the cloud a lake
machine learning and all those things
together can shape the way the future is
going to look we're going to talk more
about that
so today we're talking about internet of
things so I like to be interactive so
next question who knows what is Wally
very good
can you tell me what people did in only
one they did not great who did all the
robots membership
try today I artificial intelligence so
in a nutshell this is the end of this is
where we're going when you look at these
megatrends all moved to add to this this
is the future
no it's a little scary to think about it
here sit around all day watch to be
helpful but if you look at be origin of
the internet of things around for 17
years and what line is that Internet of
Things is actually probably missing in
that Internet itself is utility right
like power water expected to be there
and so people had 19 people Stanford
believe it's easy to rename too smart
connected problems we're going to talk
about smart a lot in this presentation
what that means but other things that
you here called the internet of
everything I OTE industrial Internet of
Things IOT products industrial units are
connected products violator fourth
Industrial Revolution
so why does that matter well it's
because it's part of the fourth
Industrial Revolution right so if you
think of the first one cotton mills
colleges that were steam-powered and
you've got a second just Henry Ford you
having any coloring was long black back
assembly lines you've got computer and
automation seventies and eighties right
robots are taking our jobs and then
finally today cyber-physical systems
cyber physical systems themselves are
mechanisms are controller monitored by
computer based on straight so these are
in advance for about this is a Gartner
hype cycle of anybody here seen Carter
before but we do a lot with guard we're
going to trust their expertise if you
look at this you actually seen the
Exorcist and expectation of why you're
seeing time and then you're seeing
basically innovation trips as things
come to market as people need to be
aware of that innovation trigger when
you get into the peak of inflated
expectations hey everybody check out
this sauce right and then you get to
draw this solution
we can about it because of this right
here because we're not ready for you get
the slope of enlightenment where people
go ok we can use it to use it for this
right then finally you get the
productivity production for us if you
look at this is actually from july 2015
on purpose if you look at the Internet
of Things the dots here instead of that
kind of thing express expected to go
live 5 10 years right values for awesome
that Internet of Things platforms the
things that make smart isolated to go
life for a little bit after that what's
interesting is this slide this is behind
2016 so this you want your letter says
here's the platform so it's actually
moved from innovation trigger people
index inflation expectations but where's
the other things it's not so what does
that mean between this slide right we're
out there 5-10 years inflated
expectations where to go so i'm not
saying that they move it on purpose but
i'm saying something about torque here
that's what I guess i don't know i don't
think i haven't had a chance to talk
about it but we think about the Internet
of Things that if we break it down a
little bit harder but it really needs
smart connected products ok risk / smart
per second you find out a second why but
if you look at connected right
basically anything that can talk to
everything around it that's connected
right we don't care how just gotta talk
the other thing is that these are
products throughout the show the
building to sit in my office take a
razor by work we just by the way we must
support them we don't have to do
anything we've been always taking on box
plugging in and they were so that's a
key part there with the smart part
that's where we get it it's a little
love trepidations right so smart for me
being something probably those for you
so let's take a quick quiz
raise your hand if you agree or disagree
but is yourself
just what makes smart software at
knows certain purposes
automatic ok yes because it uses this is
just transfers right all ok so in the
world of things and i'll get that
excited so same thing
come on your computer right basically
your mobile basically tries puter a this
is part of this app but that's smart to
me
no it's not why is that well this is we
did with the science CJ so these IOT
versions here these are minor and the
reason they're not smart because of this
here and have version 1.2 smart things
on your your device your cell phone is
actually sensor right who makes the
decision use right it's 77 degrees out
and grab a jacket or it sets the rain I
need to grab a relic great you've made
the decision so let's finish things
first point out if we if we look out
with gateways equator where the same a
thousand cell phone software gateway to
get all the information from the sensors
amazing it sends those notifications
back out pay you to work you need to
wear a jacket relevant right just having
sense
ok then you got the future right is the
wally world which is in the future the
smart devices the device itself right
all machine learning all the ends around
all the advanced algorithms happened on
the device so that's it end of things
three-point ok that makes sense as far
as smart goes we got that like to do
like rivers right so here's where Matt
straight so today people make the
decision right so decision-making spa
right people to education they have
politics have a great range of weight
work whatever it is and that's a problem
right
Gateway's a little bit faster right
we're now taking from the device to
another device making decisions that
get back so we take people out with
respect it's a little bit faster right
there's 1.2 2.1 with the Vice it's a lot
faster rate because now its resident
even if it was real time right so we're
seeing a lot of things today with a call
from your real-time parties right or two
three or four second flag that three or
four second flag can affect other
decisions that device has success
ok so so horrible example to your
question with someone that definition
state like New next fire protection at
the balls of the feet pointing to be
more between want to do you still have
to make decisions and learn from your
input to learn from using the dial and
one o'clock in the afternoon working on
whatever it says that information out to
a gateway or platform right google tools
nest and then sends that information
back grade one percent so like fire
peppers because of your device's our
community child is nice i was sure that
machine machine is that yeah that's
another big piece of it but I think when
it comes to start this decision-making
until that device itself can make that
decision it's not it's not it's on 93.1
still just David we're not still
residing on relying on something else to
make the decision itself so horrible
example but one that face picture
simplicity and IOT one right now so
you're smart to brush
ok let's say I'm going to 6am and it's
not about this cope with 600 and I'm
going to straight russian teen done
brushing with toothbrush down and a
toothbrush to coffee cup simple i walked
down talking him and populate your tells
the marches and shut off open the garage
door starts are ok this is a normal day
with linear logic we can program this
what happens when something changes so
look at is doing right so now I go
downstairs it's 5am I
meaning of india i'm getting up a little
bit earlier I don't brush my teeth come
back to that we don't have a right the
coffee cover the coffee maker has to be
smart enough to know not to turn off the
alarm system not open the grass or two
rules or heart why's that cause its
market rate it has learned that
something has changed something in that
pattern is the longer the same you have
to make a decision so we talk smart we
have to talk decision that's kind of a
key of the internet of things and really
understanding what it means the medium
thanks then got it all figured out the
internet of things are connected
products know huh right every jeep grand
cher people 2015 till today is connected
to the internet but they don't make
decisions look at autopilot systems and
airplanes have had those settings do
they make decisions really follow rules
right so we're kind of in a weird place
where things have to get smart things
happening decisions and the way to do
that do that by talking to everything
around taking all that information and
training cognitive and that's kind of
where we are thinking this is going to
go it might get by with hard-hitting
we'll see
so I don't know how many people in your
heart attacks but because i'm an
architect parking lot to show
architecture slides so here's the
Internet of Things pyramid this is the
things on the bottom right and then you
got communications and controllers next
up platforms will process talk about
platforms of the second page of the
operators right so right now this is a
version 1 mile flight things again
makeup sensors would take those sensors
have to invent a computer device like a
raspberry tired and you know it several
that gives you a little more dance thing
close yourself but still not making
decisions get the communications and
controllers right because all the stuff
was moved without some way to get the
data out where to transfer the data
between itself and other devices you've
got platforms process platforms and
things we're thinking on board right now
I don't know how many people use MV and
permanent whole device management
basically you got a cell phone in your
corporate network they can actually
device right from that any platform same
thing in the day as things come on be
plugged into the network to get on board
by the platform the platform games in
the ruleset platforms an IP address
platform get some task and so that's how
they start to meet again this one point
out that these things are expected to be
smart they're expected to contribute
valuable human machine right so right
now I'm version 1.2 this is where things
get people insights people react to
those insects that works when you look
at Gartner again and this is one that I
actually subscribe to from corporate
standpoint is they break it down the
three things that the engine platform in
the enterprise and so immature where
your devices are for machine-to-machine
happens between gateways are aching
aggregators it was credible that slide
on it is the cake place actually take
business rules and then stripped data
that's coming in from the Internet of
Things devices actually strips it and
forwards on what's important and that's
how flat is able to make decisions
quicker so the decision back out to the
Gateway sends it up to the devices
everything's up now if you look at
overlaying the pyramid with regard
ourselves as far as a reference
architecture that kind of roll out right
so it's very seamless and I'm basically
giving you three architecture of using
the same thing and see which one sticks
but in both of these examples that
you're seeing your board this is the
Internet of Things this is into right
another thing is not a raspberry pi cell
phone device ratings multiple devices
it's multiple things across the range
here if you look at this model so this
is actually taking Francisco start the
bottom half of those you know the OSI
model star bottom to the top physical
devices conductivity gave mapping and so
on and this is how they kind of work as
you work from the bottom to the top with
another models can't eat your brains
around what it takes then they call
stuff so security-wise not going to
spend a lot of time line because it's
pretty pretty peppy subject but hackers
remotely got into the last year
my wife actually has the model that
itself is actually challenge was the
hackers is actually people who had
information to get into the product with
the idea there was that the cheapest
driving down Highway they turn the radio
all the way up
they roll down the windows and turn heat
internal card jokes aside so with those
in mind we have to beware think we have
to understand that they're like security
concerns around so that security has to
be first foremost in any Internet of
Things project any Internet of Things
project so some of the other you know
add 300 articles you can see here you go
officer for yourself but when using
security there's an interesting piece
here that's the device and SD security
right so we know those things have to be
encrypted if they have to be locked down
but we'll have to put your things
usually get a device and good card right
so these devices today or not hardware
that they're not protect against walking
away
they're just smaller devices right
that's what empowers the Internet of
Things smaller process so as you get
thousands of these teeny tiny little
raspberry PI's are you know it's
whatever you can get the device to walk
away need the card lock the car drives
away data logs away IP walks with and
data is the new what
wait so we have to be thinking about ivy
compliance we think about the device
encryption about the sdcard inversion
think about standardized protocols and
things that we don't even like an ETA
and p we have to trust that the business
is actually draining those rules or not
gathering too much Gina putting that out
of the cloud or somebody else can use it
against us we have to think about
securing that storage right it does get
out of the US how do we know how do we
know we can access that we have to
secure that aggregation extractions who
does get access to it working to pull it
out 231 can open the unit there
what can access the IRS can access the
IPA what applications are
that data link if you order that cloud
of information and finally connect is
great
none of these are groundbreaking
thoughts on security but it kind of fits
into that staff bring the cisco
reference model again but it just to get
you thinking about what it will take to
security benefits so my first project is
already in the presentation i gave on
this but basically I was tasked with 2.4
temperature sensors to the lab
environment track record temperatures in
AWS just chill out all right well there
is a problem right number one is that
these vices come in from amazon today
we're going from wow they're not built
for the enterprise for corporate
environment before house very simple to
use
I think the resident advisor raspy and
iOS four the LSO they can run Windows 10
IOT isn't people that have to be very
simple so we can start playing around
them
what I did was I went out and got you
those red eyes 35 boss ended up using a
great white which is a high-five
basically extend range and i never use
my own account of us lambda to the
graphic right so really simple really
cheap circumvented all the corporate
issues all the wireless issues as far as
getting onto are really well protected
wireless network getting past the proxy
I couldn't do that which for those you
wanted a corporate environment their
proxies that kind of filter internet
access to make sure you should go
oh so i used a lot of these things to
get around some of those systems right
just to just do it as well
business happy everybody is super
happens fast and easy to do on really
looking for being took told ya 1.5 hours
didn't take much at all and I was your
trade
however write some of the things I had
to do like packing the WPS application
I dad clear text prudential awesome
script and cron jobs to constantly
refresh the proxies was constantly
looking out and it likes him listen so I
ended up going that creative way to find
out later the cradlepoint is actually no
we're not allowed to have those are
corporate environments because they can
open up our devices that are connected
to them to outside hackers raised in
certain that scary is a personal account
for company assets data in the cloud and
again which is critical in class so
after doing that with director of
operations which closes the problem at
the closing Project Director of
Operations basically for me that they
have found that three
that's how groundbreaking it's always
interesting things things where you have
to work with around corporate policies
you have to work around some of the
compliance issues some of the IP issues
to make sure that you're you're meeting
the business challenge with the same
time you have to work from within those
walls to change those policies change
those procedures as well so they don't
fire which service so finally inclusion
will take questions you can't stop here
this is a megatrend coming already
melted and cooled remembers we're not
you got your first iPhone and Apple
decided to open up tracking right where
i can find iphone back myself people
have known to do that but now we use it
for everything i want to actually
accidentally left it off at the next day
I exactly where I left right so that's a
little things one point out where things
are connected smart writing the sensor
in that phone told the platform to find
iPhone platform Apple where my father is
like
decision but it was forming that
information
oh you kind of all know what smart means
now I'm hoping from the internet of
things right so 1 point2 points3 point
you realize that is bored so a lot of
people are thinking it's only one
forever it's not think you will get
smarter is a problem next 10 years this
machine analytics team learning advanced
analytics all those things go well
together all those megatrends come
together you're going to see a lot more
of us and so examples this week we were
announced their first autonomous travel
to see that it's pretty amazing
another company on call for singapore
helmet I'm really six autonomous taxes
free in the gold errors to get rid of
cards right basically smart products
will drive around the city to learn
people are going to go so those are just
a couple of examples of smart right so
there's 1.2 and finally make security
foundation of any IT project is a job
and then you're ready to proceed on the
accident
questions you do it how do you think
you're not going to get well if you
don't know what was the gap train that
did not tell you that you can take
region so we are allowed to a club or a
lot of little cloud that were connected
to so as available on Amazon want to get
a direct connection to so we're allowing
use our corporate accounts to store our
corporate Dana in corporate accounts but
not the original
ok so that one way the other way was
bringing toys unsecured devices to the
lab partner
laughter kind of workers to go with that
together with that rod area where some
of the data so again temperatures are
going to big deal in fact as a result of
that project we figured out that people
were accessing leaving for lunch coming
back into from lunch into a door that's
causing the temperatures luxury and so
as it has a the outcome of that project
basically fix people's behaviors wrinkle
in that it's affecting some of the tests
on cloud so that's one thing that the
same thing wasn't putting company assets
so you think temperature the deal
what can our competitors do with that
that time that you're dating Rachel they
understand the data came from the lab
environment production product
development area they can figure out
that we like it
71 degrees well whatever it's right so
those are some of the areas that didn't
think about it again came from my
director to go do this do that
sure I basically got rid of all the
rules for law of the door right this
temperature that's a deal parents so
there's not much I could have done I
should be better as that it typically we
can drop our department 580 guys get
right there playing with this that but
that particular case the director of
operations was not a decision one of the
party and talk fast ocular sensors
biggest challenges as actual interview
you go to market devices work so all of
your match up to have pressured by for
each other so great that age so what do
you see for more gift that point out our
sure true so we know damn lunch in the
device aspect of this because right now
it's kind of well plus right everybody
is coming out with something and so when
it comes to just dabbling very much
basically buying things off shopping
with them
we're looking at the trends for those
because you know argument really big for
the most part in fact our MTG modular
telematic gateways are actually on all
of our vehicles vehicles are all that
hard their scam or basically so we don't
really look at the size of angry down as
far as the trans go
things are getting smaller and smaller
and smaller my product is the law with
the IT laws Moore's Law Lords law
Wranglers basically technology doubled
over six months 18 months 18 months okay
right so you can expect these things get
smaller smaller smaller one of the
presentations on giving next week
because i'm taking transit in that
presentation or talk about smart
materials and polymers and copolymers
are expecting some point break is we're
getting to the so regular level the
content play so you can expect to get
better but you're right it is going to
take a few weeks to different technology
aspects to get to where we think we're
just starting to question speaking
smaller so if you could not repress
about agriculture
types of friends and they frequently and
the flower a description of how robots
place tractor is just a jet printer type
devices and do your seating for you
don't need all this big o and O frankly
a lot of it tweaked I kind of wonder of
the conductor in the service sorry what
john deere whether John your visions any
areas where conceivably you could be
replaced not just against apply our
great question
so first thing into that is as in
germany this summer vacation with my son
and have it was played soccer for
sliding we have to get this giant german
complex and I noticed there were no
lowers even a few places that cynical
Jack your powers and figure out this
whole snow college college and that's
when I realized over the corner of every
single fuel was a giant gray box giant
meeting print size of the screen right I
got a little bit closer to a
relationship right after hours that
motor which is fully charged will go out
and it would line the entire you know
just after noon and then we go back
reprise three to five thousand straight
John you're actually we actually need
similar products that we actually call
25 their chemical bond great example of
that we actually only sell in Europe we
don't sell because the 1-yard to be
given the day I hear you must be
policies here to this laws against this
we can actually type of thomas equipment
out there with the loss of changing
every day one of the things we're
talking about next weekend miniature are
the rise of so people that you actually
planning to come and share right you all
probably were heard something coming to
pick you up
those are fungible access to assets so
they were pics now the Angels so they
fixed everything with them so that
company card just sits there money
appreciating vs fungible mean we take
the car running somebody think about mid
line with it is you can get away the
depreciation there separately but you're
exactly right John your passion are very
much focused on what that's going to be
our high horsepower products and data
this week that horsepower as far as John
as far as tractors as far as farming
going to actually paint in 1912
horsepower but the tractor market itself
we can make twice it's been on a
downward apply the entire time for a
reason that is because every year
there's a three percent up taking your
spot right so you have more power so we
don't do that
yes the future is probably know that
John your leg and driving itself for
about 12 years right
actually the farmers still in the
equipment he says that works under
control but it will go from point a to
point b line and plant or tell whether
that entire field and in turn around
come back for shipping products that can
do that so we Google of that tests butt
up when we forward your right and what
is it going to look like you are we have
drones to go out and spray everything
i'll write the drug drug laws are
changing and sex between nineteen where
you have bigger ones they could go
higher altitude that what's that
we're very much key to what does look
like it i'll tell you one of the things
I've been talking to people about the
concept of training people to wrap their
brains around John Deere used to be
attractive pumping that use technology
is not technology company than the
extractors that's the way we have to and
that's what we're pushing people to
thank for trying to meet the next
generation know it's going to be 50
billion devices on the internet for 2020
so that's a lot of devices we also with
nine billion people on this planet x few
years people so we're not seeing what
I'm seeing any major competitors as far
as what is going to come at us in the
next 10 years as far as how that works
power will have to go away but we are
seeing that startups these things below
ground with the kind of stuff
those are things that drive us we pushed
so I think we're about time watch where
you stick around