we're going to talk about mining
cryptocurrency like a couple of dollies
because that's what before we start over
I saw still unwilling to start out who
we are I'm top-hole this is brandon
murphy we're both from Des Moines we
belong to a little group called set PSM
it's a city second out of Des Moines
where we you know get together a lot of
monthly basis to talk about the
information security related topics
first of all there's another there's
other city sex around the country so
there's one down in Kansas City that
like bunch of awesome guys is like a
couple hundred people every month so
we've been going down there quite a bit
we love those gangs and think they
created the cryptocurrency we've gotta
be hilarious of Des Moines somehow
control their entire cryptocurrency
market so so that's that's kind of the
premise of where we started from so we
love those guys who that's what you
don't know yeah so who here knows about
big one who's ever heard that term
Canada's cotton very sweet so our talk
is not about Bitcoin what we're actually
going to be talking about with a
cryptocurrency that the guys down at
decades he created called set Casey coin
and so this is actually a fork of light
corn so so everyone knows like one who
knows it big
like my know I select ones a fork a
Bitcoin and so they made a fork a flight
point because I Casey so when we got
started things that we we knew like we
were told ians we're certainly we still
are told News definitely holding lives
when we started and you know we knew we
want to mess with the stuff but we had
no idea how we didn't understand Clark
change with it understand miners or
anything and so we wanted we need to
figure it all out nor mess with them you
know first we have to figure it out then
we have to figure out how we're gonna
mess with them right so you know kind of
a cryptocurrency 101 you won't talk
about the wall to death so with
cryptocurrency you need somewhere to
store your money right you're mine your
points and so you use a wallet to do
that and there are two major forms with
walnut paper wallets which look like
this and and electronic balls which is
using gooey looks kind of like this so
the concept of the electronic wallet is
you mind your miners when you you're
trying to search for a blocking in beg
fine over rewarding hash board if that
that goes to your wallet right so the
miners find your money and they put them
into your wallet it's important to
understand that relationship because we
had no clue right now they know what
wall it was yeah so actually in the
wallet is what keeps track of like the
entire block chain right so so you know
whereas like your wallet is like
typically standalone right like you've
got money in your wallet it's not that
kind of thing and that's how the paper
wallets work but like leaves electronic
wall it's actually kind of keep track of
the entire block chain so I as other
people do transactions your wallet
software actually downloads all those
transactions and then I'm able to verify
all that transaction so we'll get into
it later we're basically a transit
isn't really a transaction until like 50
people confirm like yeah that's a
totally legit transaction that occurred
right and so so it's actually your your
wallets that kind of helped coordinate
that work effort to validate everyone
else's transactions on an hour and so
that's where you know that's a big
distinction between like a paper wallet
that can have value and electrical
electronic wallets that do more than
just keep your keep your coin but then
they also you know help validate the
rock watch am as well as if you decide
to start mining and giving your own
point out of thin air they're the kind
of the traffic at that kind cortisol
that so here's how the set Casey coin is
supposed to work right so so they did so
there's a bunch of parameter so when
they fork like point there's a bunch of
parameters that they can choose and the
parameters that we care about the most
work how often is the point supposed to
be generated so I add at the normalized
hashing ray whatever that is everything
for or 86 seconds it's supposed to
generate a new point so it means about a
thousand point every day are going to be
generated by the attack now so it's just
like a leg up you get one now you did
some more do you get one kind of thing
and so and then every maybe four hours
so just over three days then there's
this concept of difficulty that gets
recap so that's an important upfront
grammar and in like a but unlike a
Bitcoin markets and litecoin we're like
the price of the coin goes
down because it's a economy kind of
market where people actually spending
real money to get going or spending 20
real life set Casey decided that they
just set an arbitrary like a hundred
coins is worth your diet and the only
thing that you can use these coins for
is to buy slack so like at their
meetings of stuff they'll have like
velcro badges they put a new backpack
and t shirts polos or hoodies and things
like that and so you can either pay them
with real money or you can pay them skc
and so 100's Casey will get you dollars
worth of you know of credit you don't
have their swag and so these are that's
how it's supposed to work now one thing
that we learn is is that there's kind of
a mining arms race right so you go so
basically you start with like you can
you see use the mind and then you know
meta gets in the GPU my and then Jason
and then you know like all out mining
basic mining or somebody else will do it
for you and so as we go through this new
attack cpu money yeah so we didn't
really know anything about psych a Seco
undermining when we started right so
like two months ago two months ago when
we actually started this effort decided
to mess with these guys and so I'm
sitting down there after that their
commutes pumpkin do like over in a
corner and boobs like spinning up clock
at cost instances that are paid for it
i'm i am the mind the crap out of this
right and i didn't know how to do that
right so we had to go compile that
electronic wallet and i used my nerdy to
connect to that wallet give work and put
the ones back into so one of the great
things is that since they're trying to
get people to mind like they put
together a nice wiki like hey what do
you know what don't you know and here's
the step-by-step instructions to do it
so we were just kind of blindly
following that just to try to figure it
out they got great destruction so
they're basically telling us how we can
mess with them right yeah I honestly
when I went through that I wasn't sure
if they were just roll on everyone right
off right like I
yeah well in they have problems with the
gate up revo Winkle so the problem CP
you might know is that it causes the way
on the cpu load right like this will
fire up one instance of my dear one
thread my nerdy for each CPU that you
have and it uses one hundred percent of
it right so cooling is important so at
your shit is a certified but they'll
mitigate that risk you use mana cost
right like these are my CPUs anymore
Alan care if i use on presentable it was
clouded cost of already pigs that eps
for life so I just really have no cost
to me so good way to mitigate that so
then so then moving on from you know you
know basically once we just discovered
that you looked at a fast CPUs are super
over subscribe and like our little
computers or whatever like i had an i7
with the four course or whether i could
do like 40 kill attaches per second
whereas like entire network goes like a
300 Tommy knows a significant percentage
but we wanted to do way better so we
heard that you know you could use things
like GPUs in order to do mining faster
right so one of our bodies has a nice
GPU and one of his boxes at home he's
like oh let me try this and spin it up
so so there's a different version
instead of my nerdy called cgminer
that's optimized for GPUs and you
basically just take the the CG mine use
it well here's my wallet go you know get
the work from the wallet and start doing
buying things and he was getting I don't
know Floyd something like 400 or 600
killa hashes per second so we were able
to been essentially with one card in his
home computer double their network great
at hashing just because we went to GQ
money which was awesome but it wasn't
enough right yeah um I know you've got
AMD Nvidia displayed up there yes GPU
mining I've heard AMD is a lot better
than nvidia that it's I've heard the
same thing we don't have any experience
with what sandy so
we were messing with nvidia it's not
going to be a work just fine and
actually our buddy had just like a
brand-new what was a GTX 10 a GTX
pennies on the Western collar yeah
things like this is going too much shit
but you turned it out and it didn't yeah
because it turns out that that GPU is
passed out ways again cgminer hasn't
been optimized for pass gas so that's
part of the problems with why one may be
better than another it may be with how
it does the math in the car and so his
like three year old card was actually
you know not going to shit out of his
brand-new car because you know he was
using cgminer optimized for nvidia they
know it you know that was in the right
math algorithm to the car so you know
you kind of have to match that off but
I've heard the same thing like per watt
like I think aim things supposed to be
better but we actually in the course of
all that's never had any access to empty
because of the next step was we would
deny me have a GPU in class right so so
we're like in a double yes so so you
they've got two different types of GPU
instance I was up like you know this is
dallas on you you have the smorgasbord
of like all these instances i'm surely
they've got to have something together
they don't they only have two GPU types
both of them are an ebay or sorry nvidia
based what they're smaller instances got
one card that can give us about two
hundred and fifty-six mega our killer
hackers per second and that they've got
their bigger instance which basically is
that having one cards got four cards and
it can do about one mega hash per second
and so so we first like a bunch of
dummies would spit up full price
instances of these guys right so so you
look like down about fifty two of us an
hour to 30 an hour how's it going what
was it was
right and we're like and so we were we
were spending some we're spending some
point because it makes cool right and
we're like this kind of sucks this is
not you know this is not catch
advantageous to us and that's when we we
discovered that that there's these
things called spot instances and i'll
owe you can see here it says request by
instance and there's this market price
because there's at any given time
there's a bunch of surfers out there
that they're not using right so instead
of paying 230 an hour right here like
when I took the screenshot i can pay as
low as twelve cents an hour so what you
do is just kind of like a bid system
where you say how I spit up a hundred
instances it looks like the market price
is about twelve cents an hour so I can
put in a bit like 15 cents an hour so
this would cost me if I spot 100
distances fifteen bucks for one hour but
I get a hundred servers doing this right
so it's like it's eally going oh this is
going to be pretty kick-ass because if
you do the math this is the big instance
for fifteen cents an hour I'm going to
go blow the crap out of the the hash you
great that that's a second second season
it's a and then what happens is that as
your as that market price of the supply
and demand of the spot instances that
market price goes above whatever your
maximum did was your machines just get
shut off and you can make it like
persistent so it's like whenever that
mike rowe Price gets down to wherever
you want that'll spin up as many
machines as it can and to you know kind
of turning machines on and off and
actually I was previewed slot you see
that we create our own customized so
that basically as soon as this machine
fire started up by start CPU mining on
the box and then I start GP mining and
all mine back to buy it when we started
my personal wallet right yeah that was
one thing that kind of
yes where we didn't know about spotted
so they know how anything with AWS
worked right like I'd never dealt with
this and so I grade this image that
minds to itself rights like the wallet
is on the minor well then my spot
instances sort of shut off and now I
just lost all that corn and so it's very
important that you send all of those all
these servers that they bind to a wallet
that will always be up so yes because
money could your mom so when once you
get a lot of cost instance those always
up he's mine back to that so that man
while that money wasn't walks right so
yeah I don't know how much money we lost
a sec Casey coin but yeah it's a fake
money the fake as well it's wrong but
fake money can have real fast and so so
then after we decided okay this is good
and we actually got some hashing rates
of pretty decent like 15 mega actions to
120 maggot hatches we decided we take
you we learn oh there's these things
called a six and basically what a sick
is is there's different ways so people
can either custom fab it or you can take
what's called field programmable gate
array any computer engineers in the
house now okay so what it is is imagine
like a regular CPU in a computer it's
just a bunch of transits because hook
together right Intel figures out how to
weigh them out and hook them up well
what math PGA is basically it's a bunch
of transistors but they're not hooked up
and you download software to it and the
software will hook up those those gates
to basically create your processor and
so asics are basically people develop
you know the Verilog programs whatever
to hook up those transistors so that
although they're not good for running
like Intel processors they're good for
that one task of doing like we're doing
script or a script based hashing
algorithms and so since there there's
Spencer specialized just to do that one
thing you can do that thing really
really bad so you can get these a cig
boxes so we went on when you get out
evening our hands on amazon yeah you
won't tell
yes yeah so we wanted to you know so
that the highest a straight on the
single instance of a single GPU that we
were looking at was 256,000 and hashes
per second and we wanted more so we
started looking at these days dicks and
this one was advertised at 28 to 32
million hashes per second right he'll
attach this isn't that good factor of
magnitude value Mart right so we wanted
to do this so I don't know where to buy
these things right like there's shady
like Bitcoin formzee shit and I kind of
burned myself a couple times like
finding ones that did like 14 Tara
hashes I'm like oh my god right it's
like eight dollars and but that's redic
going right so is it and so big coin is
a different algorithm altogether shot to
50 states and that shit don't work with
sexy going right so learn that one hard
way but so I find this guy on on amazon
and the seller basic he's got it
nameless rockin like a boss hopefully he
doesn't watch us cuz he's the only link
icon and so I'm like hey so I i I'm like
so is advertised for 265 box and I'm
like I messaged him oh hey I'm really
interested in this I want to get started
into this like minor niche coin but it's
a little bit outside of my price range
life I'm just beginning like it do you
have anything different that would be a
little bit cheaper for a beginner and
he's like no I mean this is the best
thing to the beginner but what I'll do
is I'll knock a hundred bucks off so on
your 160 bucks I get this sign of you're
like done comes with a power supply so
the nice thing to know about these suits
boxes are that I've really any any a
steak is they consume power right so the
power supply that came with this was a
1200 watt power supply and it was really
shitty like so it was clear that it
wasn't supposed to be in this box like
he must have had a good power supply
that he'd kept for himself and gave me
like a really shitty I won and it was
like an electrical tape together
but I'm like all right whatever like
let's do it i really wanna mess with
these guys so we're on the DEF CON or
we're going out to rest on and this
thing's all neon on the way reddit ship
in from the sky i have some problems
shipment but whatever you get worked out
so in the meantime i'm setting up a
raspberry pi so these aren't standalone
miners you have to have a computer that
runs the wallet that is designed to work
with that minor it is like USB yep yeah
USB so this is actually the back side of
the fans look on the other side of this
you've got like just a big golden mole
where Graham cables out our supply and
then there's just like it's a fee like
USB to serial adapter inside the box and
so I instead of my raspberry pi and i
tell my wife she's knocking down to deaf
night until I'm like hey this big box is
going to show up all I need you to do is
take it downstairs plug in the power
supply plug in the USB cable every about
an enrollment right so she calls me
she's like uh I don't know how to hook
this thing about least two cables baby
what's going on she's like it's not two
cables there's like 18 parts to this
pictures yeah so yeah so the power
supply was not connected at all why
cause i right gregg and she's like I
think I got this right I'm like don't
mess it up and so she makes it up
insertion it works like I couldn't I
can't believe it but so the power supply
she's like there's not enough room
inside the box for this power twice the
cables are huge and so that's why we
just ran it out of a hole where the
power supply would normally mount and
just at the bars play on top it's really
shady well and then you know it after
you got that in a dead cow yeah so I
come back and it's working for Yelp the
while I tweak some settings whatnot and
so I come I'm gonna work Monday and get
this alert that says hey you're my hair
stuff work you know like oh that's not
good right so i'm at work old
politically so i get home i start like
halfway on this raspberry prob hi trying
to figure out why it's not working so
finally I can't get it to work and so I
walked downstairs in my basement where
this index cloud was hell on hotel and I
smell fire
oh right and so I get down there and
sure shit this power supply where that
electrical tape was it's all melted and
like the cave that the wiring like I
just pull it apart like a slow like
Kristin aren't right it's shot so the
thing almost burned my house down just
that she a power supply so I'm very sure
the only thing that saved me was the
electrical tape that shows like melted
goo and I'm like that stopped it like
that stuff oxygen from getting onto this
and actually starting to fire so be
careful ended up buying the power supply
off ebay 28 bucks for an HP 1200 watt
power supply 39 bucks for a breakout
board and then I just required about
myself and it works great so I don't
rest better yeah actually runs better
said she power supply was like starving
it so now so I actually broke it while I
was rewiring it but so its source just
replace us all to screw with your
buddies yeah yeah yeah yeah everybody
else but suppose so so as we're ever
gonna you know work along here so so we
kind of the other sizes covered like the
actual mining side so so we figure out
that that we were you know once you get
above the hat trade right so you were
getting more mining majority of the coin
so like like when the hatch rape
everyone else was 300 kilo hatches and
we were at like 10 mega hashes or
something like that end yet ten nine
matches in that low you know we were
getting like ninety-five percent of the
coin right so like they weren't getting
any and we're getting a bunch and but
we're like we can do better right so
we're just like that at this point so
then what happens is as you blow through
the blockchain so every 3,500 so each
block is so you know every block is
gonna happen
so once invited some you move on to the
next block and so every 3516 blocks is
is when it says okay how long did that
take the quote through those 3516 blocks
and then it recalculates difficulty so
when we like jumped in with a high
amount of CPU turn to blow through that
those three 3,500 bucks in no time now
like a nap and it's supposed to take
your member back on that your Ian
supposed to take me six hours 3-4 hours
right and so so then what happens is
that like well that took two hours or
one hour is supposed to take 84 so that
the difficulties got to jump up so that
it tries to make it so that if we stayed
at that hi caching rate it's going to
take a steam forever so so we'll we'll
jump in and we'll get those first 35
buttons really fast and then it slows us
down so it takes us three in or Die 84
hours in order to get the next 3500
clock so so you know and so then what
happens is is will jump in we will get
the Hat trade up get through a bunch of
coin and then we are we weren't getting
stuff that's that's where the loot at
first we didn't understand difficulty at
all right we're like why this is not
working as well as it was yesterday
right because it's because we realized
oh we blew through the whole you know
kind of that round with block change and
now we're on the new round and they're
making we may be more difficult for
ourselves and so then what we what we
did at that point we're like well let's
just throw more in it and throw more at
it so so so there is actually kind of
stair step approach that's actually the
next slide though if we did with more
right so so we're still trying to figure
out a better time so we're still try to
figure out the light we haven't figured
out that difficulty thanks we're like
throw more at red and so yeah so that
apparently Mike
Matt rentals com is instead of trying to
burn Brandon's house down with what
minors in the basement that are actually
useful out of powering its it's
consuming what about eighty dollars with
power any dollars a month eighty dollars
a month with discount minor we realize
that for low low price of I don't know
point zero zero one Bitcoin you can get
like 24 hours of some kickbacks miners
on mining rig rentals com and then you
just give them some Bitcoin say here's
the pool or the wallet I want you to
mine to go for it and then they
basically you know hook up to your walk
to your wallet server or in our case we
have this one we're running pool server
which we'll talk about a little bit they
did basically do all the work and you
can get some really good action at it
get it for the essay on the hardware
they binding example yeah so they're so
these guys are like kind of a
conglomeration company so there's tons
of people that made rigs out there and
do it sighs rings like Brandon's and
then but like they stop mining because
like like that arms race for whatever
pointing their mining is passing over
that much gold hardware put it on my
Ingrid Gretel so they're kind of like
the clearinghouse for poking you like so
this guy may have a rig that you know
he's guys he wants to run it for so much
an hour so they're just kind of the
go-between to hook Brandon up with that
guy right so there's an eBay oh there's
a goober they were yeah okay yes it's
like uber fucker crypto printed yet haha
and so and so so instead of us being
smart we're like well we just need to
jack up the hash rate so we can keep
longer than that 3,500 point before the
difficult because up of course we
weren't smart about this right so we
really started all and yeah pushing lens
isn't so then so so I wanted to know
like what the biggest egg was so on
money Rick Rick rentals you see like the
the biggest box they ever in our these
game
Titans which do about 300 million hashes
per second so that's about like the peak
that you can get right now with a script
and yes that are publicly available so
the next biggest thing that's going to
come publicly available is 84 which you
can do about 400 hashes per second and
the key thing to know there is that like
so the KNC Titans can i watch you to do
and once one of those comes out like it
raises the bar for everyone right now
everyone has to test compete for that
difficulty and so right now though I
think we're starting to push the limits
of what that s correct might need to do
at least it was publicly available well
in so then now they're focusing on
getting it cute less power right so that
they're super fast but it's like well
let me just be more for space is more
cooling and more energy well how do we
make that more efficient you'll make
them smaller make them cooler take less
power so they can keep going right so
just to kind of be reiterate where we
started right it was that the network a
straight overall was 300 killa actions
per second right and the difficulty was
0.002 which means it was really easy if
you stay around that that that are not
hashing to get a thousand point a day
across everybody right so that our
attack and so this is basically our
tactical what we decided to do we're
like step one wait for the difficulty to
be low so when we started with a super
low right and thence that's too is we
mind everyone make sure you watch chain
and then step three is as we go to step
one right so once we did so then so then
we got the difficulty up here and then
we turn all of our shit off right then
we let them in a couple of times it took
them like a week to turn through the
hell because you know the difficulties
up here but there you're there minding
like they're in first gear right you
know when we had a 12th year you know I
in so the end so they
it was really slow see we back off you
know we're not doing anything at this
point and there are ballplayers early
we're not getting any cooler good you
can see you know graphically this is
steep so this is where like we jacked it
up and then we're like oh I want you
know vibe up you know right here we're
like we're not getting coin year lease
at so early let's get on board and then
finally we would get here we're like
okay let's just turn it off and then
sure not a few days later they blew
through the rest of the black king the
difficultly went way back down because
it took about this is probably about at
least right here and there were like
guys guys guys it's all on let's go kill
it and we took it up here and then we're
like kill it and then kill it Greg this
is about what we added be a six you know
I'm the binding regretful you see we
went through way to the roof and this
point the difficulty of you can't read
it that's a 0.35 right so we started at
0.002 and we got the difficulty all the
way up to 0.35 right all right and that
was making it difficult for that just
wait until you see what happens next and
then here is where we gotta to
ultimately we took it to 20 right oh
yeah we just to make it really difficult
and so so what's funny is it there's a
flash show me I i was told them unlike i
got this like no and this is like still
when we were just doing GPU mining I'm
like I'm like man it looks like somebody
just threw so through something is like
we got enough to like 51 at one point
but yeah 12 and 15 megatons and and
there whatever I wasn't it like 300
kilometers earlier
what's the line they're like holy fuck
you stop right where do i hack stuff guy
right there like lightning each other
who's doing this they have no idea oh
man you know and so they're just
freaking out because there's some guy
that would show some interest I like new
Bob this stuff they like did that can
jump in and he's you know lying the crap
out in or hats crew from going out like
there were seriously working thing and
so the problem we had was that we were
over spending right because because
since the whole network when we started
about three hundred killer hatches we
probably could have gotten away with
having it at one mega hatch right
because we were significantly higher
than the rest of the network that we
could have we could have just been good
there and that just kind of gone up and
up and down and then they still because
he's like but seventy percent point is
better than ninety seven percentage
points is the ninety-seven percent point
means we take the difficulty way up here
we've got to keep a high level hashing
and so and then the second problem we
had was that we were just making it
difficult for ourselves to write so we
had to mind so we kept having to raise
the bar on our own selves in order to
keep because of our whole goal was to
get a whole lot going on shortly alright
so we're making it difficult for self
and then the third problem we have is we
were just simply overspending right
yeah yeah well we've been so one of the
things problems one so one of the issues
when she had was that we were mining
everything to our style to our own
wallets and we couldn't like I didn't
know how much brandi was doing he
couldn't see what I was doing so we
create a full server so that basically
we could see collectively how fast your
remaining compared to everybody else so
so then we can figure out why oh we
don't you know charles adler stuff and
yes so that the night that we gave the
talk down at second that's I Casey we
got the network up to 12.3 nigga hashes
and I'm not talking till it hatches or
mega hatches we're talking right to just
you know through the roof and so then
that's what we create a point but then
what are we doing you know what gave it
all back like like during the talk we
made these custom psych dsm paper
wallets and and we went super early that
they tasted to all underneath the seats
every night I had one that you know
during the talk I'm like I've got lon
come yo yo guys were complaining i spent
i use my $10,000 computer one way for
defcon for we got i got one going
because it's right so i'm like sorry man
you're here you get the paper wall
within which we put 500 point like it
looks like you know it's enough to buy
some swag right and so so then we're
like I gotta get back up breath and I'm
like pocket y'all got point don't look
under your seat and so we put paper
wallets everywhere each was enough coin
to x square right I put enough on
because they're cheapest wagons 500
second AC point and so my whole goal was
dogs the swag
paper wallets I got a copy of all the
press key so I'm like you gotta use this
point tonight around back so go yeah go
gosh this right giggles so we ran them
completely out of whack it's awesome oh
yeah yeah right now right now we've
jacked up their difficulty so hard I and
current rate it's gonna take at least
two months time Jack be watching there's
a whole bunch of stop John yes is like
oh yeah we want to do I to put point on
exchange because if we do that then go
like you'll actually have real value it
would be like my mom did catch up for
some really really yeah but you know
double spending in fact there's a whole
bunch of things you know that like we
feel now that this is like kind of a you
know kind of a public project we can
paint it right it's not like Bitcoin or
something like that work young people
probably come and kill you you put the
coins lovable that's about all we had
you guys have have any questions it if
you want to find us on Twitter Brandon's
doing with them you know the notorious
hacker named Tom pool but come to the
wine he'll second thursday of every
month we definitely we have our
apologizer would rain a little dopey
let's go yeah ultimately how many coins
did you mind about 70,000
in perspective they're only about a
hundred thousand going created your side
Casey going to heaven right at the time
so we only we were shoot more than fifty
percent and we got to
you