welcome to the one I guess what are we
scheduled for probably five
45 we're gonna tell the major that I to
Ramsey written comments desert fox for
rigging a starter so I have Richard
rushing here to talk about some Star
Trek stuff Richard's day job is the
richest a job he has a motorola device
in their pocket you're some way
connected the motorola yeah kind of like
the sea so said fair enough so yours
okay thank you very much I'm definite
everyone as asking to give a mobile
security talk and typically you don't
get mobile security talks not because I
don't like mobile security it's just you
you get into certain areas of oh can we
talk about exploitation android or iOS
and you get all sorts of things so this
is actually kind of a high-level pot
that talks about the issues that you
have with mobile security and this is
one of the reasons i deem this the
Kobayashi Maru scenario kind of matching
the Star Trek theme it came to me when
the for those that don't know the
Kobayashi Maru scenario it was in the
second movie and it basically was an
unwinnable scenario there was no way to
win this in the area about it and mobile
security is very much the same way if
your scenario is to make mobile security
our mobile devices secure you're not
going to be able to win that argument
and well it helps text go talk through
why that actually is
make some suggestions around the area
that's function a minute um a couple of
ground rules always kind of start my
presentation to travel so you understand
some of the concepts of the erickson
house and it goes back to the Kobayashi
Maru adversaries bad guys criminals for
a lack of a better term sheet they don't
follow the rules they don't do anything
that's around that they will get at data
any way possible even through illegal
means that's their us being the good
guys we don't we have to follow laws and
different things that allows things that
actually happened and this you're
starting to even see very much in
government and everything else whether
it is getting a very strong divide and
Christian arguments mobile device
privacy these things are not going to
get any better there's not going to be a
massive solution it's going to be the
same thing that's there when we talk
about exploiting we're typically
especially when we talk about mobile
devices its predictability and patterns
um I love when people say that they've
taken what they want to call anonymized
data from mobile devices and think oh
we've ran this anonymized data sources
most of those sources when universities
take that data set they can calculate
its no longer anonymized roughly about
anywhere between 68 and eighty percent
of the device information they're able
to track back to a single device based
upon patterns we all follow the same
kind of patterns we all follow the same
kind of productivity we go to the same
train stations of shopping centers or
anything else would use their devices in
and around the same area and you go home
you still use your devices so if you're
looking at tracking GPS coordination
everything else it's very easy to track
an individual device with a high degree
of accuracy just by where it started its
day from where it went to and then
we'll return to and those are all parts
of predictability impacts if you look at
the OSI stack this seven layer stack of
that's based on different properties
that you go up through until I refer to
it as RF cargos or radio frequency goes
so I can put some glasses on and
actually see where the signals are going
from that in the air I will never be
secure simply do the fact when this
comes up and says I connect you to a
cell tower or connected to a Wi-Fi it
may be the access point in the back of
the room it may be the access point
that's somewhere behind this wall I
don't know I have no idea saying with
the cell tower I think it's the one
that's outside down the street but it is
no guarantee that it's actually there
because RF or radio frequency is about
range and power so how far does my
single go and then if I want to see that
signal I have to amplify the reception
of that through an antenna or if I want
to transmit to that device that's their
time and time again we've seen where
RFID or other things like your passport
says you have to be less than six inches
away and the next thing you know there
is somebody's article that talks about
how they were able to pull off the RFID
of people's passport from 30 feet away
by using an antenna or pick of Bluetooth
will walk from a mile and a half away
these are different things that you get
into this as well it's all about power
and all that the functions of that
that's there so mobile devices are
really cool
I love about them I can do so many
things so they get cooler every time to
go on there's a huge speed of
development process and they do more and
more more more data more abilities more
capabilities things that are going on
the power of devices has grown back when
cellular phones were first there the
wonders of gamy was snake just really
boring lack of a better term but hey
that is the only thing you have it
wasn't anything is on that side but
other things that came into it or less
environments change different operations
different capabilities would actually
they're the same we have networks we
need the storage of devices and storage
capabilities while remembering megabytes
was the capability was there we're now
in two gigabytes on the capabilities
they are the number of radios and your
device went from one toe somewhere in
the neighborhood of five to seven and in
most modern devices that are actually
there's some good statistics just data
looking at how the buses I make one
thing about these the devices that a lot
of people don't realize is that they
have a unique characteristic of a really
powerful you just have the same
processing capability as list your
modern gaming consoles on a graphic side
and a cpu side so they're really really
powerful devices but most of the
applications that you're running are
talking to other things outside of this
device this device is kind of a hub and
it's pulling data down so if you start
looking back and this goes back to 2000
I'm going starting first starting see
any quote smartphone arena was that you
had a very large number on a subnetwork
of 2g which which gave you about a
throughput speed of maybe about 150k
really
hello but you didn't need that much
that's there and the total global
traffic was about one terabyte per month
one pair of my per month back in 2001 so
relatively small amounts of data that
was there it took almost to the point
2002 to we reached 1 billion text
messages per day on that side of it I
think my daughter sometimes then that
many and just a day but it's truly
amazing where we've actually come from
into the next area and you can see how
it pretty much is just skyrocket almost
a logical thing so as you get into it we
went to one petabyte around 2007 you had
social ads that launched from twitter
facebook iphone introduced android
integers spotify 3g and only 3g back in
roughly two thousand nine which is not
that far back you had a vast majority of
the phones still in the gsm 3g was brand
new and only consumed about ten percent
of the population it was there as you
continue going up you get into more and
more networks 4G coming out in 2012 we
rolled out so if you look at that that's
less than four years ago and now we have
5 g on the cusp again be a prototype
down and we keep continuing to do this
over it over
has regrets and if you start looking at
what the capabilities are you really get
to the point where mobile traffic is
roughly about fifty percent of all IP
traffic somewhere before 2020 so you're
talking a huge amount of data is all
going to be traveling over these devices
and in some cases insecure not secure
different ways and talk a little bit
more so let's kind of break down the
device this is a way to look at it so
mobile devices in instead of the self or
typically the operating system now we
used to have a hundred different
operating systems for mobile devices
renowned to pretty much android and iOS
um it's software it's just like
Microsoft it's just like everybody
else's they have bugs they're read by
people their own abilities some of them
were really big somewhat were hatched
for those that didn't see in the news
this week google announced their private
part of their project zero interfaces
with android was basically a quarter of
a million bug bounty program do these
large-scale attacks by stage fright and
some of the others that's the payout for
some of them so they're trying to get
things better same goes for apple
introducing their butt bounty program
again people are trying to make this
offer better patching you always have
two sides of the coin when patches
released how quickly the carrier's adopt
them and allow them push to their
devices do they embed other patches and
this is the common issue you
to patch it in everything else is do I
roll a lot of patches into the system to
be keep the patch level this they are
going to catch just the one time
capability and don't the maintenance
release stuff this there so there's long
term fragmentations that occur of
devices that go don't get love and care
for lack of a better term other devices
would get here on a regular basis and
some do better than others some carriers
do better than others some independent
device is the hat on how to carry some
of those do better than others sometimes
those are forgotten so it's one of the
continual areas to focus and some of the
things applications are kind of slightly
weird so I'm talking about applications
in this context we talked about
replacement applications so people are
replacing their internal application cuz
they want additional features oh my
camera I want to have filter sets or
anything else they'll download new
cameras and replace the entire camera
which can be you really good but at the
same time on OS hope that becomes really
problematic because you're now have to
associate with this and it's typically
impersonating some of the other camera
capabilities so it's kind of like if you
on a PC you set something to default so
anytime I see this file always open up
this application and that maybe not the
case and sometimes that causes problems
inside the devices one of the biggest
issues that things have is dealing with
routing or jailbreaking devices so I
take a device that's designed to have
some levels of security and when I break
it through jailbreaking or I rooted I
take that security level away so
everything runs with full permissions
everything run is this in using time and
time again malware that focuses on
jailbroken phones and routing from
because in a lot of cases that's of
around twenty percent of the market
share and a lot of times it's just done
because people think they need that
capability and in most cases right now
the used to be the biggest argument list
for tethering capability inside of
carriers because some carriers charge
you for different things for tethering
you most of those have temps went away
and went oh so the need for jailbreaking
and some of the other ones has kind of
dropped off but you never know where
it's there the phones do have more
protection than your PC's do they
operated on these privileged mode with
accounts they also operate in a sandbox
environment they also operate in enough
permission level so when you have an app
you can tell what actually 22 which if
you look at it as much different than
the PC people always ask it's like how
cell phones are so insecure and I'm like
they're much more secure than any
Windows environment or in a conveyor in
a lot of cases just because the
capabilities that are built around back
native operating systems now one of the
things that these devices communicate
over is a cellular networks so cellular
networks been around for a while but
it's been around for a while it's older
protocols gsm was an older protocol that
had been around forever and they
basically figured out how to crypt it
just like all cryptology after a while
it's weak and this is same case but as
people were like oh i can now have a
conversation and i didn't
so your conversation as it goes across
the airwaves become gsm so people
naturally moved off of gsm into some of
the others from A to G to the 3g
environment but as in the carrier's if
I'm out of range too far away my 2g
networks travel farther than my 3gs
agains the idea of power and range so
there was always backwards compatibility
I had a row I connected to things so
that backwards compatibility typically
meant your device you either tricked
into connecting to a 2g network or if
the network wasn't available or your
network said hey it's really congested
downgrade the device is listen you have
to understand these devices have a nice
communication pattern with outside
entities on the cell towers and
everything else it's like Hello and some
targets hello there's like I said lots
of data and you go now you shouldn't
wear maybe you can or yeah I'm free and
you have there's a conversation that
goes whoa stop there's other people here
need to wait your turn there's a whole
sets of protocols that are actually done
on them from the carrier controlled and
this is one of the things that they take
advantage of that if I pretend to be a
cell tower in here which takes about
five hundred dollars and parts to be
itself hour so it used to be you needed
a hundred thousand dollars a big truck
lots of things now five hundred dollars
a PC and you're good so the portion of
it is that able to say hey how is the
statue at work and the carriers have
always had lots of control over the
devices if you travel you had software
always download
to your device when you came to another
GSU Evans arm by default if you roamed
over to somebody somebody says hey
there's my roaming profile of this onto
your device that you know how to operate
in my network so you've always kind of
trusted this carriers but now I have a
capability to be a carrier for you your
phone in your device explicitly trust me
in a lot of cases with that and
sometimes people take advantage of that
through authentication which she calls
you solve one last week or somebody was
like hey I didn't buy a sim yet I was
able to use the text or voice or data
and all three of those have different
sets of controls in some cases voice
will always work if you take your stem
out of your phone it says you can still
make emergency calls in a lot of cases
but you shouldn't I can this is part of
the some of the issues that are there
sometimes text through the kind of the
next level up and data is the final
level this is yeah there's different
levels that I allow you to operate and
everything else um you also have the
cell towers themselves how they operate
some of those operate as a local network
so in other words if everybody's here
and everybody's devices are connected to
a particular a can t cell tower all
those devices kind of operating can
communicate in some cases back and forth
on a pure pure of level inside that
environment because of the network the
way is actually set up there's been a
lot of cases where the ss7 switching
signal generation seven has been
exploited and looked at of Haluk towers
do handoffs how the towers talking you
get with that it cell phones are
actually really remarkable we take a lot
for granted
my phone and call somebody somewhere
anywhere in the world and get an answer
and drive down the road at 60 miles an
hour and it goes from one color to the
next hour to the next hour to the next
hour and typically doesn't necessarily
drop the cost sometimes it does but
that's truly remarkable as you get into
try to do the traffic analysis hey how
does it go from here and then also it
appears five miles down the road and it
still maintains that and you don't hear
anything communication is still there so
now we looked at the cell your side of
it OS let's take a look at the
applications that are there and
applications are tricky why because
their applications not really written by
the manufacturers some cases they are
but most a month array by third parties
or other people or other organizations
um so you always have the rogue
applications that you can do so any of
the applications that I want to I can
pull out of the phone or off the
marketplace and typically make
modifications and then put them back
into the marketplace or come back into a
website that's actually there I can take
things that are branded to somebody else
bring them on and brand them as myself
hey this is Rich's camera it's not I
just stole it and decided to sell it use
it leverage it as something else it's
actually there um so that's always that
issue with rogue applications in the
environment / Commission is always a big
issue the number of times that I've seen
an app that's like I need things that I
want to talk to the contacts on what
store stuff to your drive do all these
different things in lot of cases it's
like your flashlight you just turn on
and off my camera flash
the move do not need to my gps location
for anything but over permission is
really really common both for the
sinister side so both for the side is
okay i want to track of this or I want
to do malicious things I might use your
phone to do conscious things like click
fraud and some of the other things that
are actually there because it's mobile
people ask why why do you want to take
her with my thumb why would you do it
myself it's mold it constantly changes
IP addresses to it can get two different
things almost any point in time it does
no barriers to stop it in a lot of cases
so it's kind of the perfect thing when I
want to do kind of things that I wanted
to be malicious on butter sighs go to
open pages and things like that all
behind the scenes that you never see
them so I'm actually doing so sometimes
people do things sometimes apps are
created that we all remember this
snapchat hey we don't save your pictures
oh sorry we kind of do not our fault
forgive us it's there a lot of
applications on Android and some of the
other words you select databases to
store their data in a sequel light and
everything else they dump everything in
there and like oh it's obvious cated you
can't figure it out and make the keys
are in it happens it's like 30 seconds
to code like oh look here's everything
that's there I've access to it so a lot
of times the application vendors do not
go back excuse me do not go with the
idea that this is an insecure platform
they go with I get at this pure platform
you're not going to lose your phone and
your phone as well I to know when you
get to the data except that's
unfortunately not the way you should be
really creating things the second area
for application issues is typically
where do these devices talk so you think
about it it's like well where these
device is talking with
why do they talk to you to everything
else and how do they talk the number one
thing that you can typically find in the
apps talk a lot they talk in clear text
they send crap all over the place
everything from your imei two distinct
pieces of parts of the information that
you really don't want shouldn't be
disclosed for any given these shapes our
capabilities but they do it just because
hey that's there hey if you enter this
information in this stays if I enter a
credit card in here maybe it's that
keeps it here or maybe it keeps it on
the website where does it actually
storing the data and we see this on
different areas the question is is
leaking just an accident or a privacy
issue or is it just on purpose The Hague
we can get ahead of this and do
different things that are actually there
this is probably the biggest issue
that's actually there and the apps that
are receiving this data are relatively
for lack of a better term not very
security tested phone ability
assessments penetration tests or
anything else because it's mobile it's
kind of like hey this reports to em
snapchat calm which is not just
something else and these applications
are not necessarily tied together we see
this time to time again where you can
see hey this was broken into through the
mobile app and not the website the
website was checked and checked and
reach a the mobile app not so much or
the server that's supporting the mobile
app not so much
authentication is really important how
many times that we selected hey I want
to authenticate for facebook or I wanna
think it through any of these other
sources and we do it on the web we do it
on mobile apps that again parts of the
things that are there sometimes those
are actually stored into the phone
itself which means that if I get access
to the phone I get access to your
credentials and can leverage then use
those these illusions their marketplace
issues are also super common
marketplaces are kind of weird very much
now since we have two flavors of
operating systems we have google play
store itunes for apple and it's there to
be perfectly honest people are now we're
so awful most of the malware always
comes from untrusted sources there are
few exceptions where malware is
downloaded from the market places but
those are much rarer than that when you
look at the volume of downloads and
everything else that actually occurring
it's a much lower percentage than your
average see you think about where you
get pc from it's like you don't even get
to choose a marketplace go out to the
internet and go on to google and say hey
I'm looking for adobe flash player
kicking you the first ten links they're
all malware those are the areas are
there the marketplaces did have issues
when they first got established everyone
wanted it the carrier's wanted their
pieces of the marketplace the providers
wanted their piece of the marketplace
everybody wanted their piece of the
topic to monetize your cell phone usage
the problem was that gone in most of
them are free or cost a little bit in
there
not that much generation on that side of
it's almost the marketplaces guide or
they kind of core less into a hey here's
just our t-mobile toolset or our verizon
tools not anything else that's on those
sides what we're trying to sell other
things on the market places that are
there and then some of the marketplaces
just got really out of control and just
anybody could put anything on there
which must go to time ended up being
malware most of the marketplaces now
have code review kind of they'll go in
and statically and look at the staff and
say hey we've seen this before it
doesn't look like any other application
if it does well will flag it if it
doesn't then it goes on and it keeps the
applications and keeps the things in the
marketplace pretty much secure it will
bounce anything that's not developers of
your new developer is kind of a
reputation based hey have you a couple
of this stuff before train be done and
how you wanted it up there are some
people say hey there's a static code
review done where people look at the
code that's really not the case we see
come again where there is definitely bad
and evil code that people were got
really just came in with that's there
now one of the things that do want to
tell you is that if I put code in there
to say go out to XYZ server calm and
download an ad stream or download
something the code is still good that
server that you're going to download the
information from get bad so a lot of the
bad applications people are talking
about and putting on different sites
they look perfectly good but in six to
eight weeks that server that you're
going to now turn evil and start sending
stuff into your thing that's like all i
gotta pop up now what's this about where
is this or icon will appear magically on
your device so this is some of the areas
that you get into the stair and there
are evil applications they target things
like keyboard translations other things
that are downloaded say hey
if I can watch what you're typing that's
perfect don't have to do anything else
so hey I can speed you're taiking up by
25 percent we have a very sophisticated
keyboard keys swell according to your
typing characteristics people like wow
cool yeah unfortunately yeah as that
streaming is taking all this data and
sending it to a server in Russia which
is now partially putting all your stuff
back together when a my own gentleman
from trusted sources do not ever
download any application from any
sources and try to site loaded which is
basically has loaded it that will cause
you to brief at some point of time they
all do and most the time everybody is
now trying to push things to the
marketplace go here go here go here you
go to Amazon you can go to Google you
can go to iTunes and you'll find the
same stuff Pokemon go with a perfect
example of this when they had to rush
and it was being slowly released there
were so many bad versions of its looking
around that there were so many people
that got their phone zone because they
get a loaded a bad version that's
actually there and when you get your
phone on people like ah how do I never
so point most of this stuff is we're
going to be designed just to sit on top
of everything and suck everything else
off doesn't care about what you're there
is looking for bank accounts is looking
for things that are going to type
it's looking for password potentials
another thing it's whole purpose is just
to sit quietly by listen to what you do
it send it someplace else not really to
say hey I want to annoy you i want two
things start control things or do
different things that are actually there
now if you look in the actual device
there are some specifics that go with
every device you have the radios so
there's multiple sets of radio Bluetooth
NFC Wi-Fi cellular all the radios have
device issues there's an exploit in
Wi-Fi for the next blade bluetooth guess
what it's going to be vulnerable in a
discussion it's but it's not like it's
running some special software that's not
horrible if this protocol is exploit so
anytime you see that regardless you like
ok emotion her blew you off other
capabilities their their external
interfaces are also key don't mind me
better as yeah we use our USB is
charging but since it's also us in other
words if you have malware on it some of
the more prolific now where the copies
itself to share drives and USB keys and
everything else Oh copy itself to the
phone won't infect the phone as it's
designed to infect a VC but when you're
I need to charge my phone and plug the
USB in oh there's your pc and then every
other person you can give to you go to
the charging station at the airport put
it in you potentially and set that as
well so there's all sorts of different
things that are actually there
especially on external interfaces that
are there teach you the interfaces
always have a deep
which gives you direct access onto the
device doesn't matter of the devices all
sets and devices have it debug mode it's
either enable or not enabled by default
and enabling it you give your device a
lot of control through that USB channel
I would not recommend doing that on a
regular basis it's really cool if it's
have got all these additional things you
never use them you're not w memory or
accessing files directly for USB or
anything it would go hey here's my
picture drag drop onto the side so
that's some of the areas storage used to
be a big issue because everything was
unencrypted and whether i do my SD card
non SD card now most everything as we've
seen with the last Apple fiasco is
encrypted we are storing things and
encrypted formats which is good and bad
at the same time why is it good I'll is
my phone don't have to worry about it
why is it bad because if I pull out my
SD part of that the only device that can
read that SD card with that phone not
anything else it doesn't go hey can you
enter your password in can you do
something else know that phone has to be
the guy that does it so you have this
kind of issue when you're trying to
transfer data in and out so most of the
times people transfer data via either
over the air through some kind of
connectivity are during the USB function
that's their pin lock or any kind of
walking mechanism others pan pattern
facial better than nothing do never
leave your phone with no lock code ever
that's it simply do the fact that that
means
that in case you get pics up your phone
has complete access to it unless you
don't put anything on your phone which I
find really hard and people I don't have
anything on my phone good I take it here
and hit it with a hammer you won't have
any loss and you watch people and like
no you can do that fine well oh my god
that way we have stuff on here you
always what hap stuff it doesn't matter
if you I don't like my facebook anything
y'all going to have all my contacts um
there's also other budo protections so
if you think about it from a boot up
perspective if my device prompts me for
a password what does that really mean
well if somehow my device has ever get
turned off and then it turned back on
you want it to prompt you for a pen or a
diagnostic before it comes to pull me up
simply just do the fact it's that way
nothing gets loaded onto a before it
does there's a security level that's
actually there that's something that
usually has to be an in typically go hey
just boot up without having to recognize
a pen for that but the idea behind it is
that if my phone is over powered down or
lost or with anything else I can get the
information back one of the other areas
that is they're mostly operating
environments are going to a TPM type
interface safe stone from qualcomm
chipsets and other thing which trusted
platform is basically an idea that says
hey think of it as a safe I can stick
stuff in here no one can get it out
except for me I know the combination I
can pull it out at any point in time and
use it but I'm only going to use it
inside this asian that i might like to
see so you have that capability it is
very quick and very most of the software
is there it hasn't
up to the hardware component yet so
Qualcomm is using one kind of area p.m.
there's a lot of other areas that are
kind of you focused eventually they'll
put a TPM chip on the thing just like
most of your laptops have TPM chip sign
so if I want to do a biometric on my
laptop it's set on that side of it so
those are some of the areas that you get
into on a regular basis that's a little
better there's a popular idea that
people like to say is the halo I can
bring my own devices to work yeah you
can I don't know if it gives you benefit
there's lots of people that say oh this
is great no it's not other so many
hurdles to jump through it's their idea
behind it is hey you're accessing
corporate data on it applies and I have
to be able to protect it through
containerization or other things to be
able to adopt her take control of that
device how's the easy way to actually do
that and this is some of the stuff that
gets into her limit to support costs
driving understanding it's a corporate
functions usually driven by cost with
other things sometimes it's maulin
transition to work as well you get
enterprise level it's hard put in DM on
it you probably have more girls you go
through on an MDM device that if I just
handed you a device and said hey this is
your corporate phone and here is your
you can use your personal fun you don't
need to have two phones and so there is
there some disruption in that how much
of that is being driven is kind of
questionable um we talked wireless
issues the same thing Bluetooth NFC
casting sharing
ethernet cellular dramatic there in the
air and can't see them you're there but
also think about them as a social
engineering aspect the bad guys sitting
at a location can pick out your phone
and go hey look welcome to starbucks
please click here for your free coupon
oh cool done in some cases airport
stores other locations where I'm trying
to get people either through wire via a
wireless hotspot looking for
commissioners Bluetooth other types of
things that are there I now have the
social engineering aspect on electronic
aspect of that when you're like oh you
must want give me a few comp because i'm
standing in starbucks or I'm walking by
starbucks or I'm at the airport wow I'm
with the United club all those little
places you can now do different things
based on your device just by pretending
to be a Wi-Fi hotspot or anything else
bring up a page asking for information
and believe it why because you're there
in a mobile devices time I don't have
the same capability out if you see about
validation um connected device issues
are always there your phone's connect
everything thus also the weakest link
there's a lot of times it's like hey I
trust my phone and when you program it
for your car it's like hey you want me
to remember your phone and then the
first thing we heart is like downloading
all your contacts the number would throw
Barlow got into and went up I hope
everybody's contacts let's make some
phone calls because it does it's just
that way the connected device you have a
transfer of trust and it's usually
through some little mint yes or no yes
done as I transfer trust I didn't want
my phone to unlock my house not a chance
ever on that side of but it's part of
the thing is like yeah I want to be able
to have an app on my phone that go to
garage I'm going to apple my phone that
tells me things there is a one beers of
things that go on in a connected
environment between the house the home
the apartment and there are so many cool
things you can do just understand the
security implications of when you're
doing that and always think about are
you transferring trust from one place to
the next because if you are you can go
back to the simple thing shouldn't there
be some kind of authentication shouldn't
there be something and maybe there is
maybe it's all behind the scenes or
really maybe it's a four digit PIN with
that and again managing your wife and
it's going to get worse before it gets
better one thing key takeaways on this
is that if you look at around 20 19 the
number of connected devices connected to
get will be the amount of global
internet traffic that was in 2012 so the
amount of information that in shared
through these connected devices
somewhere in the not so distant future
will actually be the size of the
Internet three years ago so into
conclusions on this there are lots of
different things that you can do I
really wish there was like hey this is
the perfect solution there's not a good
perfect solution
there's not anything that's actually
point across so if you think about it
and going back to the original idea if
you're playing the game that has a
no-win scenario i can choose not to play
so i take my mobile device and take a
hammer and smash it that's not going to
happen I like my mobile device so what
are you going to be left to do I have to
do something have to have some levels of
controls and someone will aspect to be a
look indigenous so it's easy you cheat I
know that's bad term but you basically
know I know what I go into and I'm not
going to go into a scenario where I'm
not going to win so in some cases i know
my device is not secure so I treated
definitely I questioned anything that
comes off of this device may or may not
be potentially mine at the same time I
have controls around this device where I
know what went into it I know what
applications came on to it I know what
I'm actually connected to and I don't
just connect and any open Wi-Fi network
I don't connect at me strange into the
network I don't you might be turned on
when I'm not using my bluetooth headset
or my bar it's just normal best
practices of doing something is amiss so
caught up in this that you walk away
then you're no longer here or I think
hey this is really cool I don't want to
type in my four digit PIN that's so hard
do I really seriously four digits is
really hard for you to get a remember or
take the time to actually type no it's
not get over because if you don't I'm
going on your phone you're going to own
your wife because the consequences are I
have access to everything this is kind
of your wallet so if you allow me access
to your wallet and I can make it
copy of it I can beat you really really
really easy faster than anything else
this is what the criminals are after is
this because I don't have to do research
I don't have to go in and try to guess
your bank account information on it's
all there so this is the issue that you
run into a simple thing of not doing
something is just getting the complete
access to your life if there are um good
question there's lots of lots of
protections and I think part of the
protections are kind of what you do with
your phone I'm not a big believer in
mobile malware if you get your apps from
reputable sources you don't need mobile
malware but if you're downloading every
other camera app because you're looking
for some feature film when you go you
have 40,000 apps on your phone yes you
need mobile malware um depends on the
operating side on that side up whether
it's Android or iOS Android side lookout
is probably one of the better ones to
leverage on that side and again what's
the operating systems now psycho view
malware and what we also do all this
other stuff Oh your permissions and
things that's that's okay it's not
anything that
there that's gets on that side of it if
you're very sophisticated you can always
look at things like buy our school now
has all the schemas for mobile apps in
there as well so you can scan for a hash
put it up in there and go hey guys
anybody seen this before oh this is bad
and we've seen apps from the cellular
providers that turn bad over the periods
of yours as well so um some of that some
of the sofa stuff is actually pretty
good some of the other stuff gets into
some of the other areas the apple stuff
is really from the jailbroken scoffs
item if you're not running jailbroken
devices you're in here in the same
androids I'm not getting my stuff for
different areas and I think that's kind
of what's your behavior around you and
the problem with mobile is very
different than the rest of the
environment because everybody uses their
devices differently it's very much about
a PC but even more fragmented with
different things that because you can
have somebody that use a nap and they
will they will never get rid of that on
that side of it which could be okay this
is a big issue now I can do this have i
need this capability for subscribe 3