what I was thinking about a topic post
hoc I located focus on the toxin trains
have gone before China finds his blue
duck down and if that many talks tend to
do with just one topic of time for DMI
are either post or network analysis it
can seem like the system presidents and
network forensics are two completely
separate fields separated by the wall
and evident usual meet but that's not
what our clients environment alike and
certainly not how they looked or
attackers attackers are using the
network to send commands the hosts and
uh move laterally between the hosts and
between the information up became corner
they leave evidence in both the host and
the network but the traces are quite
different granted we do have some
clients that are only willing to sign up
for a host site attention and other that
old setup your network attention but
either way we've been feeling like
missing import cars of the picture for
one of our never bowling clients we can
see the ongoing backdoor activity a lot
of the traffic is encrypted we can't see
what the attackers are doing with the
back door we can't acquire their tools
to determine if their new bearings we
can only see what detectors are doing
over the network and that we've
signatures for for example if the
tackles brought a pasty cracker to the
domain controller craft and a costume
the environment I started using legit
and credentials to gather information
and ftp audio organization we not might
not be able to see any vet at one of
oakland stalactites we've been
identifying instances past attacker
activity but finding active back doors
for current a track activity is much
more difficult too time-consuming the
terms level of detail analysis and
numerous systems which is time consuming
for us inexpensive the climate having
access to the network traffic would
quickly show us which systems are being
used which allows better scope intrusion
and tree analysis it would give us clues
the lateral movement and orders to
active data fat without that inside and
maybe start playing black normal i
identify
Christmas remediation while allowing the
types of fulbright addresses never
network and whose forensics can ensure
complement each other each has its
strengths and weaknesses but net web
site strikes tend to complement history
physics and vice versa network analysis
is great for alerting us to evil its
current and ongoing but often osco for
previous best if network traffic is
recorded as a visit it's gone which were
host nalysis can come in on the other
hand even with periodic endpoint sweeps
post analysis usually brings back data
after the fact but when we do find
assistant al Weis we can gather a
atonement previous activity sometimes
covered years of photographers this can
be critical for non droid breach network
and holistic tivity also in value in
context we children tell your client
that they have a tremendous deal
eroticism as much more impact when we
can identify specific dimensions which
have been uploaded remote server
similarly Mottola clients to these
systems are beaconing they cruised on
veteran when we identified which files
are met door and how they have gone
there no acknowledges grid for detective
product from no vectors which can show
tap directions as is happening as long
as factor traffic is eyes as their text
or can be decoded if it's not captured
or can't be decoded and when's the hosts
can detail be tagged his actions on
system attackers also often reuse their
infrastructure and tools traveling
traffic to no command control serves to
reveal neubauer and put two more
compromised close on the other hand
because easier to find new attack tools
on the pro side looking for suspicious
Bob Methodist analyzing those tools can
identify new network indicators can
detect the tools and other hosts using
both sides in our analysis is made
possible to detect and analyze breaches
faster since in just sokol minutes I'll
get just two examples in the first hour
network censors alerted us to points
listed beginning resuming HTTP responses
including known malicious 18
command control instructions in response
to download an additional hour and then
switch to encrypted ssl traffic end of
life the network site so we pull back
down at penises for analysis we analyze
the analyst of those prefetch files show
these sequence of commands photography
music together information about hosts
since we got a prompt alert to the
network traffic who were able to the
club is able to remove revista network
within hours the engine bridge in a
different example and honest needs to be
alerted me to a suspicious registry key
missed registry bronkaid are pointing to
an upscale javascript file bianca
skating and analyzing the file showed
there was a fully functional backdoor a
gradual stealer there's also people
downloading an executing additional
matter we wrote now exhibit was based on
analysis and again detecting its traffic
and other clients the host said finding
gave us the intelligence that we needed
to identify more breaches elsewhere in
this and in other examples without both
on her side and the network site
analysis it would be window full extent
attacker activity it will be much slower
to detect and respond to three just