it talks i was actually ballin told that
i was going to be speaking so that
you'll notice that i have a my topic
is not you know pregnancy-related
however i think it's a very important
top it needs to be given and i'll be
giving it in the full hour length of Der
Beek on this September in Louisville so
my name is Joseph and I'm a hacker did
someone because someone to say hi Joseph
but anyway I'm a hacker and I mean that
the traditional sense I'm not talking
about ponen systems though I've
certainly done that professionally you
know but I believe that it's important
to understand technology from a very low
level I believe you need to have an
in-depth understanding of it and I would
love that sort of stuff so the top of my
is raising hacker kids for good or
for awesome now in the past couple years
we have had a trend in the infosec
community where we started actually have
events for kids you've got at kids gone
you've got DEFCON kids now I have
opinions on one of those that are very
strong haha and the reason is toby is
important to me is because these are
three quarters of my children yes three
quarters when I for those of you who are
fraction challenge that means that I
have eight children ranging in age from
14 all the way down into to 20 month old
twins who are on this picture that's our
class photo for 2012 so one of the
things that I really worry about is that
one hackers very word right but I want
to raise hacker children does that mean
I want my children to have that in-depth
understanding of Technology I want them
to understand that we live in a world
where technology is ubiquitous computers
are connected to our lives the types of
technology would carry on ourselves cell
phones our laptops iPads tablet devices
it's everywhere it's a part of our daily
lives and most the underlying sort of
mindset is that because recent
generations use so much technology but
they understand how it works they don't
I work with Cub Scouts workers
scales they use it they're comfortable
with it but they have no idea how the
underlying technologies works they don't
understand they're being trapped in gps
they understand that all that text all
those text messages persist and most
people don't so I want my children to
understand that so I do things like I
could teach them out a program I believe
that idle hands are definitely the
devil's playground and to illustrate
this point in a non technical way back
in the 90s when I was growing up in the
city of Houston there's a master-planned
community very beautiful lots of
cottonwoods bike trails hike trails
parks but it was designed for young
families at a certain point those young
children became teenagers and they
started to quickly realize it beyond
going to school and going home there was
nothing for them there so a lot of those
kids turned to drugs and alcohol and at
a certain point someone who started
knocking over liquor stores with guns
and breaking into houses so and you know
rough lives were ruined those kids
simply weren't engaged and anything they
cared about and so they made their own
engagement I'm a big fan of not teaching
kids about certain types of technology
you look at the DEF CON kids and I'm not
picking on DEFCON kids my oldest
daughter learned to walk in DEFCON 7 she
was 9 months old I've been going I went
to DEFCON for a long time I don't think
it's appropriate to teach a
seven-year-old kid out of a box a dump
and the reason why is because several
kids do not have the ethical maturity to
understand the consequences of their
actions should they use that skill in
the wrong context right locks are
important the first time you learn to
pick a lock you realize it locks me
nothing I got my first set of pics I
went to went to a competition picks for
locks without any instruction whatsoever
got home picked every lock in my house
is like didn't matter anymore besides if
someone really wants to know
freaking window so I'm not a big fan of
teaching kids how to pick locks and then
letting them go I'm not a big fan of
having social engineering contests for
children where you teach these kids
these techniques why I think it's good
thought to teach them that they can be
socially engineered I think it's good to
teach them things at a high level so
they can be aware that maybe they're
being socially engineered I don't think
it's a good idea to say hey here's
social engineering and here's how you
can be better at it at 10 or 12 simply
because these kids don't have the
emotional maturity to be able to handle
so if we're going to raise these kids we
have to give them not only the skills
not only teach them how to do these
things but to give them they will try to
teach ethics we don't do a good job of
that knowledge is knowing tomatoes
approve not you know wisdoms company in
fruit salad you know it's hard to teach
that it's just something you kind of
kind of art and that's part of the
problems right a lot of that maturity
doesn't come until we get older I think
it's greg's teach get out of program I
think you should cease kids about
exploits when you teach them how to
program because that's something they
need to be aware of I think you're going
to teach a kid how to write exploits you
know I think that's a bad idea I just do
they don't have to they don't know how
to they don't have to use it responsibly
they don't have the wisdom so here's
what I've identified as some of the
biggest issues facing us and I think
this is actually my last slide third
electives classes taught anymore we
don't teach kids about ethics really
until they get to college that's bad no
hard and fast rules on what's
appropriate for your children because
you know them but unfortunately I mean
if you have enough kids are you doing
enough kids you realize an emotional and
ethical maturity different same kids say
they do similar things not the same what
works for me or my family may not work
for you but you should always learn from
whatever people doing you got to keep
your kids engaged and interesting and
important ways you need to make sure
important then and I'd like to thank all
these people for helping me out to be
still this talked down from an hour 26
at five to six