Hardware hacking with microcontrollers: A
panel discussion.
Moderating this panel and introduction to micro controllers and it seems
like every seat is filled here.
Pressure is on.
I mean, I'm not wearing pants so this gets more interesting.
And your crotch is right at the level of Joe's giant red fist.
Excuse me a moment.
It's going to be one of those panels.
You don't want to know what's going
on behind the podium.
On my left we have FirmWarez.
We have LosT who everybody should know.
And I have a personal grudge against for number of years
of mystery torture challenge, Smitty Halibut
on the end and custom made hat and vest and Joe Grand.
I'd like to correct that RenderMan.
That's TV's Joe Grand.
Discovery channel.
Please, no applause, please.
So we're basically here talking microcontrollers.
I'm elated because I get to pick these guys' brains
for an hour here.
That's something I would have killed for at any other time.
So basically, we're just going to go down and just sort
of have everybody sort of introduce how they got
into micros and just sort of their history.
And we'll go from there.
So FirmWarez.
I started hacking code on an ATH800B.
And a lot of you guys loved writing software
but I wanted to do hardware stuff but I ended up in the day
of 8051 microcontrollers and that was all for fun and ended
up being an embedded systems near making my way to being VT
for contract design house I love making hardware that does something
and some of it has blown stuff up and some helped people live so
a good balance.
A 50/50 there.
First foray was Motorola.
We just dated ourselves, right.
'80s called.
They want their street cred back.
I've just always been interested in how things work not just electronics
but just things in general.
I was always taking stuff apart and occasionally being able
to put it back together.
Usually things hacked to have different functionality.
I've had numerous jobs over the years.
I've worked for Parallax, I worked as a design consultant
for companies doing embedded systems and specifically embedded
systems security because that's where my interests lie.
And you have experience with badge design.
A little.
Not as much as Joe.
Yeah, so I'm Joe Grand.
TV's Joe Grand.
JOE GRAND: Thank you.
I got started with computer in 1982 with Atari 300.
My brother was interested in this stuff and
he threw electronics and tools at me.
Didn't literally hit me but I was exposed to a lot
of electronics at an early age which was cool.
So I first started getting involved in kind
of nonmicrocontroller development.
So making boards for red boxes and blue boxes and various phone
phreaking stuff.
The state of limitations is probably up.
I got involved in embedded development
in teenage years, I was Motorola HC05 guy
and got involved with microchip picks
and stayed with those.
Motorola scaled off into free scale so I started
using that.
But, if you notice for DEF CON 14 badge was
a microchip pick and 15 18 was all free scale.
That's because they would talk me out to dinner more than microchip did.
So.
Fastest way to Joe Grand's heart is through his stomach.
JOE GRAND: Free food.
So remember that.
So yeah, I sort of specialized in embedded system development
of low end consumer and household devices.
And then of course I do hardware security break
stuff once in a while, too.
Interesting side note, Joe, did you notice that some
of the stuff you submitted to parallax for sail I was looking
at them with Joe bare man.
I know.
That's how Joe and I met so before we met through DEF CON,
I was looking at his products and I think it was the GPS module.
When we were having before GPS was easy to deal with.
And we were standing outside and was it John Williams
busting your balls about something?
I just remember the interaction we had
and you were going to    I think Ryan was at DEF CON
and I was at DEF CON but I don't know if we knew each other,
you work at Paralax, weird.
Embedded world is a small community.
And Ford for the record I do not work
for them any more.
The first question for everyone    The funny thing
is Smitty put this whole thing together.
MARK "SMITTY" SMITH: I'm not sure how I convinced these people to do
the panel with me.
I'm Mark Smith or Smitty, I'm the only one who does not use
microcontrollers professionally.
I'm a lobbyist.
I spend most of my time at@mail and not.
Thank you for saying that and not the other A word.
Got a bad reception on that one.
But I got a start at I very I don't think age.
Older sister got a TS80, I think the 8800 beats that.
So I started on that doing basic.
I didn't get into assembly until comment in the early 90s,
my first micro controller work was on 801 but I didn't spend a lot
of time on Intel because that assembly sticks.
I'm a lobbyist.
I'm network engineer and system administrator by trade
and I do this on weekend for fun and I like making stuff
and thing that work.
I've been into electronics for a long time and then once
microcontrollers started getting really cheap in the 90s,
that's when I started add being programmability to my projects.
And thanks for putting this panel together
by the way, Smitty.
(Cheers and applause) You're welcome.
So everyone who is not playing with microcontrollers or just starting
like I am, initially it's the question of where do you start?
Because it is such a huge field and so many platforms,
so many development tools out there.
How the hell are you supposed to know where to begin.
Some of you teach classes on this.
What is a good place to start and learn this?
Should we go down the line?
Let's just talk.
I think that's definitely like people come up to me and ask
the same thing.
There's so many different choices.
And the good thing about nowadays is that there are so many choices.
Back in the day if you wanted to get
into the micro controller development, you had to get
the individual microcontroller, deal with the development environment,
add a bunch of external stuff just to get the platform up.
And then you were writing like assembly.
So now it's like you have Arduino platforms,
you have propeller processor, Raspberry Pi, beagle bone.
And all these things it depends on what you want to do
with that device, because there's so many different
flavors and so many different levels, if you're doing something basic,
maybe use a basic stamp or Arduino, maybe raspberry pie which
is Linux based so you can write Linux stuff.
You don't have to be a hardware guy.
You can just write code and have it work on the stuff.
I agree it depends on what you're doing,
but for somebody who's new, it depends on the tool chain for me.
I can't take a n00b and drop them into certain tool chains that are
like slamming your nuts in a door.
Certain PGA development software packages, for lack of a better word,
are not exactly user friendly.
I think a lot of engineering tools suck anyway,
so you have to find the one that sucks the least.
Yeah, you mentioned the A word.
But the one thing I think Arduino has above many of the other platforms it
is meant for artists not engineers.
So the thing that Arduino did that made it so popular is that
they made everything so incredibly simple and trivial to use.
You don't have to buy a programmer.
The programmer is on the board itself.
The only problem I had with the Arduino and
the Arduino zealots.
I don't have any problem with AVR.
To be clear I'm not a zealot.
I get that.
The thing that frustrates me is they talk as though it's
the first time it's been done because there was a lot of money,
0'Reilly and the maker crowd started backing it
and processing and environment.
But they're not doing the basic stamp, yeah.
So I mean I think really, as far as going that route,
the stamp was really the first chip to do that.
Yeah, that's true.
The problem the stamp has had and I'm so are people out there,
they haven't grown with the pay that user space has grown.
And they're still charging 50 bucks for a basic stamp too.
And you can't compete at that price point and actually have
talked to Ken Gracie.
I love the basic stamp.
I do.
On a number of occasions I've heard Joe say when
I'm prototyping I grab basic things off the shelf but it's ridiculous
to charge 50 bucks for that chip these days.
If you're going to stay competitive as far as the stamp is concerned,
you're going to need to lower the price on that.
I don't mean to be airing dirty laundry but that's
the kind of stuff you want to hear.
People bash on Arduino on hackabay, Arduino, lame.
There's a religious war just like open source
and Linux versus whatever.
But Arduino for what it is it's good.
If you want to get something done, there's lots of example code out there.
There's lots of support from the community versus something
like the basic stamp.
You have community support you about you have support directly
from parallax but the community support tends
to be okay.
My only problem with Arduino is that a lot
of the open source stuff that's out there, the modules people write,
nobody's validating that stuff.
You don't know if it's good.
Paint by numbers, plug stuff together.
Great for prototyping but once you're done if it's a one
off project, that's fine.
If you want to move it forward, that's when you have
to start going through and making sure it's
actually good.
But with the subject on the subject
of how do you get started, though, I would rather have somebody who
is new to the hobby get an Arduino for 30 bucks, plug it
in with a USB cables, load up the blink code, get it functioning
and go that's fucking awesome.
Look at the blink code for Arduino and OS2.
I can put my mom in front of a OS2 and she'll understand it.
Am I mom did not do computers.
Or the board of education stuff.
So I'm not trying like I said, I'm not a zealot I'm not trying to put
the Arduino in instead of basic stamp stuff.
Definitely not doing that.
So I guess we need to make two categories
of the simpler consumer targeted microcontrollers versus
the industrial I work on this shit all day, I have the programmers and
the you know, I can write together.
Smitty just as a matter of confession, I've sold Arduinos
at DEF CON before.
I'm not anti Arduino, what I'm anti is the attitude of this
is the holy grail come down from high to save me
from my microcontroller ignorance.
Or the idea that anything else is way too difficult.
You know, I don't know how many guys think
Arduino is great because I don't need
an in circuit programmer until it blows up.
What's an in circuit programmer, a piece of hardware you plug it
in and say program.
Not that hard for people who is used to pushing packets around a network
to use that.
TI's MS3 chain is getting perfect easy good in terms
of being usable.
But you can't have her load up MSP30.
Arduino is good for that.
One of these days we'll let Render ask another question.
I don't want this to be me asking all questions.
There's a microphone.
Ask us questions or we'll just keep bitching all day RenderMan one.
One of the biggest difficulty I've had getting meeker into it is you get
the idea and you want to build it now I've got
to do spark phone Ikea order and you have
to wait weeks I'm in Canada.
That's your problem.
I'm cheap and don't want to pay FedEx.
One of the things I used to tell students you can get engineering
sample from microchip than just about anywhere.
That's the question.
Inevitably you end up with parts bins.
But the problem is sinking a huge amount of money into that.
Is there shortcuts or ways like engineering samples
to get base stuff.
Constantly harvest.
Pretend you're a squirrel and just start gathering stuff.
If vendors think they're going to make money,
they'll give you free stuff.
But, if they think you're doing something
cool they'll also give you free stuff because it gives them something
they can promote and write about on Twitter or whatever.
To Geoff a few samples out to a lobbyist isn't going
to kill them hearing.
I live in San Francisco and there's a weird cycle
of people put stuff on the street and you can take stuff and put other
stuff on the street.
It's weird.
Sometimes it makes neighborhoods look really shitty.
Sometimes it's awesome if you get there
before the city comes and picks stuff up.
Oh, a printer.
Go into local surplus stores.
You don't have to pay full price for things but even if you do,
full price is like pennies or a few dollars
for stuff unless you live in Canada.
And make friends with engineers
because all of my engineers had desks that were filled with sample.
Oh, this part is so cool I can call up the distributor and get it.
But scavenging parts.
That's how I learned how to solder.
It's harder these days with the service mount stuff.
Back in the day that's how I got parts.
Worst case Radio Shack.
I know they've had I'm dead serious, they've got a really bad reputation
over the last 5 or 10 years when they got rid of a lot
of their electronics stuff but they kept that one little section
where you could get resistors and capacitors and stuff.
Now it's like 9/10ths of the store is selling cell phones
but there's that one drawer.
Last resort.
So 8:30 at night my DSL modem just died
and I have an exploded capacitor.
I could still go down to Radio Shack and buy that 660
micro capacitor to get my Internet back online so my
wife can watch game of thrones.
So Radio Shack.
They're also getting into sell things I got a fan out here.
They're also getting into selling microcontrollers
like the A word and basic stamp and a lot of modules.
I totally didn't mean for you to start saying the A word.
(Laughter) But they're not the cheapest around,
but when you need it right bloody now, they're there.
The fact they have modules.
That's recent and I love it.
Hardware has come full circle.
We built heathkit and it died out when computers got big.
Computers nearly went away as a hobby.
Why do I want to do this hard stuff and get chloride
on my hands when I can write code and compile and compile.
It fucked up.
It didn't cost you anything it's moving more with the advent
of FPGAs coming down in price.
Just recompile the hardware.
Electronics as a hobby, more of a system level hobby where some
of us still build our own boards.
There's so many modules you don't have to do that.
It's true, like LEGOs.
AUDIENCE: What do you do whenever you're
up against a particularly crappy tool chain?
What's your method of attack to get past that?
Cry.
A lot of mountain dew.
I think it depends, I've had crappy tool chains.
Sometimes you're stuck.
If that's all vendor offers you, mile have contact and say you're tool
chain sucks but most of the time I'm dealing
with the crappy tool chain and when I talk
about crappy tool chain what I've encountered is the tool crash or it
will disconnect from the debugger or something annoying that you have
to restart.
And that's I think the nature of engineering tools
because they're designed for engineers and they're not designed
for the mass public so they don't go through the testing
as like a normal piece of software would.
And yeah, I mean, they're just annoying and sometimes
crappy, but as long as they end up compiling properly
and working properly, sometimes.
On the hardware sigh I don't use Kai cat any more,
they crashed too many times.
Same guy.
I'll buy you a beer afterwards.
Did you hear when I was doing stuff for this year I used the free version
of eagle because I wanted everyone here
to be able to recreate the badges with free software and I found
an error in eagle that says too many pixels
in the Y direction and it says it in German on the bottom.
So I took the work and rotated it in the other direction and it doesn't
exist in the other directions.
Now everyone can make their own black badges.
If they can do that, they deserve a black badge.
Next question?
Yeah, so I wanted to ask you guys what do you think
the best chip is for, like, DSP, like, audio D.
Religious war.
Start.
DSP audio.
Not the best but the best to start with for DSP and audio stuff.
I got nothing.
The one you already have code for.
I mean, you know, from a professional's viewpoint.
Oh, this one is cheaper.
This is faster.
But how does that equate to a few hundred hours
of engineering time.
If you've got code, if you can code what you want to do,
that whole project, where do I start?
Find a project that's similar to where you want to go.
Or find a vendor that has reference code
or application note for where you want to go.
Make really good friends with the FAEs.
The only experience I have with DSP stuff
is the DEF CON 17 damage had a controller so it was
a microcontrollers that had DSP functionality and that's all I know of.
The tool said it's not open source but it's free.
And which is to me, fine, good enough.
It's even better than open source if it's free.
There was one thing called the processor expert and you could
select modules and say I want to implement
an FFT and you double click and there's a GUI and set it
up and that will configure the DSP side
of things and you can do mode um old school 1200 baud so that's
a good place to start but I'm sure there's
a reference design somewhere or project that does something similar
to what you want to do.
I do a lot of audio work, audio electronics stuff as well
as digital and that's generally where I'll start out.
I look for different chips and look for they'll have the application note
in there of this is a typical application for this chip
and I'll try to find one that matches closely what
I try to do.
Do you have to do that standing behind me?
That looks awful.
It sounds like render is peeing.
AUDIENCE: Is there like a resource that I can go
to to kind of, like, browse through all these different chip
examples and --    Google.
There's this thing called the Internet.
Each of the different vendors have going to have their own site and list
of things and they're going to talk about why they're chip is awesome.
They don't necessarily say better than the competitor
because they don't want to acknowledge that
the competitor exists but they'll say we're awesome
because we have all these things.
And the competitor will say we're awesome
because we have the same things, you look
at the list and they're 90% overlap.
See which one takes you out to dinner more.
Have you used octo part?
Yeah, it gives you data sheets but it's not as easy
as like a parametric search on a vendor site.
Octo part will tell you which distributors have stock
of the current part you're I searching for and give you data sheets.
But, if you search for DSP, you might see stuff, but go
to digikey and do a search and organize by price
or    Mousers is much better.
So other than the big dogs,Ikey, mouser, Janeco and places
like electronics are there any other major houses you order from?
I use Ikey primarily.
They just started doing first class mail shipping so you can pay 2 bucks
and depending where you live get it within a day or two.
Doesn't work for me.
You guys don't count.
The fun thing about digikey for the longest time.
I key, right?
I complained and it got bigger and bigger and it used to come
with stickers so you could tag the pages
because there was so much shit in there.
When they stopped making the catalogs I complained
because I'm against the trees I like something I can flip
through and look.
I used that catalog.
That's the only way to find a connector.
Try to find a connector on a damn parametric search.
Next question?
I'll out myself.
I love my Arduino.
I'm sure most of the people here are here
because they got started on Arduino.
Show of hands.
Yeah.
Who used Arduino.
Who's going to admit to using the A word?
I will.
How many people their first experience was a basic stamp?
How many was like pick?
Really quickly, I want to interject this
before you ask your question.
My first experience with a pick was hacking your hex code
from the DEF CON 14 badge.
I was the only one who successfully reprogrammed that badge and I did not
get picked.
I'll have to review the contest entries.
The guy with audio, this was cool.
I'll admit.
I'll review the notes.
No, I've got MSP launch pad on tomorrow.
I started on M bed 32 bit.
That thing is awesome.
Going back to the Arduino and lobbyist artist thing.
Spark fun, ate A fruit.
Love spark fun.
Good stuff.
The drop in hardware.
The LEGO I can drop the code in and compile it, run it there,
do you think that's devaluing the industry at all.
Not at all.
I love the I'm sorry.
I know the guys at spark fun and they love their stuff.
It shows up all the time.
I think it's great.
I think it's happening.
People who wouldn't be able to accomplish certain projects
because it's making it LEGO slap the pieces together.
Especially thinking the lilypad with the folks doing
the clothing hacks and stuff like that.
I think it's opened that world to people who otherwise couldn't get
throughout barrier in the same we the Arduino and stamp both made
the pick and ABRs accessible to people who weren't otherwise.
If I can interject a question on that, one of the big things I've always found
is tinkering with stuff with the goggles you've built it
with basic stamp or Arduino or whatever.
Taking it to that next step, I no longer need all the accessories,
I just need the chip.
My problem has always been where the hell do I figure out how to do that?
Are you trying to make a product or stuff.
Just one off stuff.
Like a more refined things.
Not a stack of shields.
(Talking simultaneously.) I want to answer that but I want to say
with with respect to fruit and spark fun and
all these places, it doesn't only help the people getting into it
and the hobbyists.
It make break outboards and saves a ton of time.
It definitely doesn't hurt.
It's great for prototyping as well.
I want this particular chip with this troller and see
if I can make this product work.
I'm going to do it first with these shields.
Slap it together and say now I'm going to proof the concept.
I'm going to design and fab a board that has just
the components I need instead of a stack of shields this tall.
That's what Render, you're asking.
How do you distill it from all the crap.
Render, you hire me.
But, if you don't want to pay money
at that point you need to look at schematics
of every individual model, see which pieces you're using
and I have a big prototype of all the crap and I identify which parts
are useful.
Create a smaller schematic and just get
a board layout package that whatever you're familiar with.
If you're not, use Kai cat or dip trace or whatever.
Eagle.
I use Altea.
There's a trial version.
Use OS8 park.com to get your boards fab'd, it's
a dollar a square inch or something.
FM I going to get kicked off the panel
if I admit I use express PCB.
No, for a lot of people for prototyping purposes there are
some not so the way PCB express and a lot of those guys work
is they'll release their own proprietary server with you
they don't give the Gerbers.
I know two different groups writing stuff to take the stuff that their software
produced and give you your real Gerber's.
Yeah, it's like jail break in the design process.
But express PCB is a great service
because they have their own software that is not nearly as complex
as eagle or Kai cat or anything else.
It is so incredibly dead simple to use to do circuit board layouts.
They can do silk screen on the top, not on the bottom unfortunately.
But once you have the design, if you can keep your board
to 2.5 inches to 3.8 inches, you click a button and give them I think
it's up to about 60 bucks right now if you don't need a soldier mask
or 60 or 80 bucks if you weren't a solder mask or silk screen
for three boards.
And they'll get them to you in a week.
It's incredibly cheap way of prototyping.
That's not a tiny board, not huge but you can fit a lot
on that amount of space.
It's a great way of getting in.
And I'm going to draw traces from here and inspect the pins.
You don't have to worry about making it nice and clean,
you're not making a product.
It's just a prototype.
Service is great.
Orb park is a great way of doing it expensive,
but they have a lot of lead time.
He runs boards every other day.
Laying outboards is a completely different discussion.
But for the most part if you're doing
a prototype and it's not something that as a specific board layouts.
It's an example tool.
I want to mention for Canadians there's AP circuits.
Someone is like A.
You can use it.
Alberta circuits.
There's similar type of prototype quantity simple board type
of house.
They're expensive but they're fast.
They're Canadian.
They ship to the U.S.
AUDIENCE: I'm not afraid to ask dumb questions.
We're not afraid to answer this.
AUDIENCE: Excellent.
I bought two boards a week ago, one was the beagle bone and
the other was I think I just went to YouTube and searched
on embedded program and found guystatemachine.com who
did a 9 series lecture on use, the TI Solisis launch pad walking you
through a CIDs.
I guess the first question is are those microcontrollers
or bigger    The beagle board is a great board.
I like the beagle board stuff.
I don't know if you guys have any thoughts
on those.
I would consider those modules, there's microcontrollers on them.
But the distinction I think he's trying to make is they're not microcontrollers,
they're CPUs.
There's a very subtle distinction
between where you're writing assembly or a C that's running on a chip timer.
Intel considered there was an 8186.
They interested it a microcontroller because it had
a timer on board.
I thought a microcontrollers had on board peripherals.
So memory and stuff on board you don't have exposed
busses going to outside stuff but a microprocessor was
a CPU you needed to have mapping and data bus.
But when you're talking about things like the beagle bone
and the raspberry pie, the main difference
is you're not necessarily writing code that has 100% control over the CPU.
You're writing an application that runs
inside an operating system.
So it's a different in development environment
and I'm not trying to make a religious distinction here.
If they both have their place.
You know, if you're a software guy and you don't need to worry
about you don't want to have to worry about how to write
a boot loader and you want something that does stuff and you're comfortable
with GCC and you write applications in Linux all day, then put Linux
on your chip or put Linux on your embedded environment.
That's fine.
It's gotten cheap enough that you know, Dr. Moore solved that problem for us.
The reason we had microcontrollers is because they were smaller
and simpler and cheaper when a full CPU was so much
more expensive.
That is no longer the case.
We can now throw transistors at these things and it is the cost
is no longer the problem.
So we can put an entire Linux operating system
on the thing and it's still 35 bucks.
Costs about 30 35 bucks about depending where you buy it.
Raspberry Pi is 35 bucks?
What's the difference?
The Raspberry Pi has a shit ton more resources
but it needs it because it's running a full operating system.
It's no longer a matter of which is better.
They both have their place.
It's a matter of which suits your application better.
So the answer comes down to what you're trying to do.
A lot of is that comes down to high performance timing.
If I need to get down to the hardware level
on something like that's when it becomes more
important to be able to get down to that level and have control.
Most of you guys don't say interrupt latency as much as we do.
Would you rather write a custom application that runs natively
on the hardware as opposed to a device driver.
Depends on the application, what you're trying to do with it.
Think about robot.
Do you really want an OS to control your motors on a robot,
or do you want something that's very simple and predictable where you know
exactly what you can do to take control.
I'm not waiting on this to message that and for the OS
to decide to come around and then turn the robot
off before it drives off the cliff.
But, if you have a good deterministic Artos,
that's fine for embedded.
You could run Windows you.
I wouldn't but    I've got friends at willow garage who would shoot you
for that.
Depending on product.
Surprised nobody brought him before now.
Like in the robot example, I would put con tolls
on mike low controller but I would use a Raspberry Pi to do
the route processing and high level process and taking
in video stream data and doing analysis of what's going on around me
but have it send a signal to the microcontroller
and say turn wheels around going my speed this long
and have the control the motors.
So that's the kind of decision making process you have
to make at design time of what is it I'm trying
to do and which platform is better for that particular task.
If was just briefly mentioned here.
The dreaded word that nobody likes to deal with is dealing
with interrupts and interrupt timing and I think that's why we're now
breaking into this point where we've got even, what I would call
a microcontroller with multiple cores and stuff like that.
Like the propeller is because you don't have to deal
with time slicing and interrupt problems and loop timing and I think we're
starting even further than that I think the real future for all of us is going
to be what we see coming from the FPGA world.
Thank you?
AUDIENCE: Hi, oh, I'm happy to see the embedded stuff
and I think Smitty for putting up this panel, really.
My question to you is I'm a systems student and being I want
to be in the field professionally like you know,
not hobbyist but professionally.
But earlier it was like if you're in microcontrollers you should know
interface and you should know basic control logic design.
That was the basic thing, stereotype in my mind.
But now the time has changed a lot that the programming part,
the controlled logic part has evolved and it's reached such
a high level you can do software system, database systems,
you can do control like all the systems.
So designing and schematics and you know, sensor is still there.
My question to you all is as a base as systems engineer, what are
the basic things that at least I should know firmly?
I hope I'm clear.
I guess you're just asking what is a basic skill set to enter
into that world as a professional?
Is that correct?
Yeah, the basic skills, yeah.
And what later on I can decide on my own where I'm interested
Well, I'm not the professional.
You guys are.
I'm never professional.
Go ahead    Well, I almost feel like that's asking how do you become
a hacker.
To me it's a natural progression of hobbyists building stuff and then oh,
wait, helping out at the a company and now they want to hire me
and they're paying me to just do this stuff?
So a lot of it is once you get this foot in the door, you already named
off a lot of the things that are important.
Once you find a company or a project that you're in love with,
you just start doing it and you will gain stuff and I don't really know
what the best thing to know.
Especially if you get company, hands on real world experience you get
whether it's a product development company
or a specific product.
Not consulting.
That's where you get the best experience.
As long as you love what you do and you learn more
about the things you already said, it's a natural thing.
I don't know if there's any better way to explain it.
You know, I've been giving this answer a lot
but it depends on the application.
Obvious skill sets electronics if you're going
to be doing microcontrollers as well, programming.
Lower level the better, understanding of how assembly works is going
to be important.
I second that.
Here's the big difference between embedded guys
and you know, pure software, speaking as a hiring manager,
here's a skill set I would list if I was doing the official thing
and I'll tell you the kind of I people I really hire.
But big difference, physics.
Because okay, you're going to be turning motors and interfacing
sensors and talking with people about this frequency of whatever
or this coming in and I need to turn it in this real world thing and I'm going
to turn it into software, understanding the physics is going
to be more important than pushing packets around.
When it comes down to hiring people, we had
a kid what did you do last summer?
I rebuilt this Chevy 350 just to understand it.
Shit, you're hired.
I want somebody who does hands on.
In the embedded world you've got to touch the hardware.
(Applause.)    The one big question: Have you ever brought
up a new system?
Because again, it goes back to what I said earlier
about doing hardware.
If your code doesn't work, you recompile.
You've got a board, spent all this money.
You laid the board out and put all your parts up there which
is a fucked up mistake.
You've got this board and turned it on and it doesn't work.
Now what?
You've got to understand what's going
on on that board.
It could be something like, again, physics, it could be you laid it
out wrong and it ain't going to work.
It could be chips not running, traces left off.
Hands on.
Being able to troubleshoot circuits is a huge skill that and
like when I was teaching at the university, it used
to frustrate me to no end, I was really honest
with some students if they come to me and ask a question,
I would always say have you tried it?
Have you gone out tinkerers, we need more tinkerers.
If they haven't tried it, you don't have the mindset
to be doing this kind of work.
To be blunt, we need more tinkerers.
Right now we call them makers but we need more tinkerers,
we need people putting their hands on stuff.
I'm always championing in the embedded systems we teach kids
that electronics are dangerous, expensive and breakable.
In our community, just look at the participation
in the badge stuff here at DEF CON, we have orders
of magnitude more people involved in badge stuff
if it's not electronic because people just have that
intimidation factor that haven't made that first step.
That's where we have the hardware hacking village.
That's why DEF CON kids is doing electronic badges this year.
We need to propagate and keep that momentum
moving forward.
AUDIENCE: Cool.
Thank you.
Just one thing, one more thing.
When you're discussing about forgetting stuff for a beginner,
we're discussing with Arduino or the thing which I wanted to know
is I when I use Arduino, I have us used, I have got things done.
But by doing it by using it more and more, getting deeper into it, it
will give me the basic concept of you know, like which makes me
if I get any new programmer, any new microcontroller in the future,
I'll be able to hook up a programmer
into it or something like that?
I'm looking for some to get started in that way which makes me able
to later on work on my microcontrollers
and not just Arduino.
Pick one.
They're all different in little ways and they're all the same.
(Audio difficulty)    I have a barn full of that shit.
I think one advantage of Arduino, I think the question was going
from sort of like vendors going if one to the module down, you want
to start working with more at a lower level.
And that one thing with Arduino is and you see this a lot.
The Arduino is the code working on the Atmel.
You can start with the platform board and
if you want to try to go a level down, you can take an Atmel LVR
and load Arduino software on it and that you know,
use that so it's slightly more refined.
And then eventually you're going to want to get
to the point where you have a microcontrollers or maybe you don't
need to get to that point but you have a microcontroller
with just the stuff you want and it's not a module but it's
a refined product that's stuff you want.
You can go the other way for those running
the dark net game this year, the badges software was written
in the Arduino IDE even though it's not Arduino itself.
It's just a front for AVR GCC so it takes C++ code
and turns it into Atmel code.
And if you give it the right hardware files,
you can find them online for the AT tiny 85, then you can use
the Arduino IDE just because it is so incredibly simple
and program nonArduino devices.
By the way, if you haven't talked to the dark net guys, they did
an amazing job this job and it's a great program.
We have five minutes left and I want to bang
through as many questions as we can here.
Come on up.
AUDIENCE: Hi.
I started on the propeller and I'm still on it because I'm pretty addicted.
So I've built a whole bunch of stuff.
And they're all unique, they're all completely digital circuits.
But I have a problem on one of my specifically where if I run it
at 3.3 volts I get data corruption but when I drop it down to 2.8,
everything works.
So how would you go about starting to debug something like that.
When you drop it works?
AUDIENCE: Yeah, it's bizarre.
That's fucked up.
Look at the signals on the scope and see if you're actually getting noise
outside the chip or if it's something being caused
by overvoltage or something else inside the chip and make sure it's noise
versus parity issues.
Maybe there's some other weird configuration thing.
It has an RF modules on it so noise is possible.
Even something as strange as battery placement.
AUDIENCE: Physics.
It goes back to exactly what he was saying welcome to the world
of hacking your circuit or troubleshooting.
That's really one of the greatest skills that I think some
people are    As soon as you start talking about RF,
Ryan was mentioning one of the things you should mention learn
is physics.
I bet you have a trace somewhere that is exactly
the length of your RF a quarter wave.
Your quarter wavelength trace somewhere that's picking it up.
You'll be able to visualize that on the scope.
Scoping.
Trying to troubleshoot a board without a scope is like trying
to troubleshoot code without a debugger.
It happens all the time.
There's startups I've seen in San Francisco that kids have
dropped out of school and move to California to start companies
and they don't have a oscilloscope to do basic things.
I brought a logic analyzer with me but that ain't going to help me.
Yeah, probably not?
AUDIENCE: Thank you.
That's old school.
AUDIENCE: Yeah, one question for one person up here.
We'll just kind of keep the discussion going and ¯.
What's with the porn music.
Are we done?
Is that the get off stage music?
Nice.
I've got three more.
Just keep going.
One person one question.
Lightning round.
Go quickly.
AUDIENCE: When you're making a decision designing
an RF signal processing board, which point are you drawing
the line between saying I'm going to use DSP or FPGA for this solution.
Not me.
I would lean toward the DSP just
because FPGA when I think of FPGA, I think of hard care digital side
of things and DSP might give you more I don't know, may be easier to kind
of manipulate if that makes sense, you could always maybe port FPGA
but I would tend to go with DSP first.
AUDIENCE: I have an 11 year old boy who is come of age,
what can I do to introduce them to this world?
I don't have a lot of experience.
Go get the -- what's a microcontroller kit.
Get it at Radio Shack.
The what he said.
It's a parallax microcontroller.
It comes with a huge book that was help move
you forward and that's the difference between that product
and any others is the supporting documentation
is a no kidding book.
Free sample.
No, I don't work for parallax any more.
But I still think it's a great way to introduce people to.
I have a long list in my Palm Pilot.
I'm a system engineer at mission critical embedded systems
and I got started on 8080 in '76 so I'm an old fart.
Two things I'd say is the tool chain, the Atmel and
the Arduino gives you a solid reliable tool chain.
Stay away from the CCS compiler.
It should be checked into the heart of the sun I lost 60 hours of my life
on a professional project because of the figuring CCS compiler.
The other thing I'd say is learn C.
Yeah.
Yes.
I second that.
And keep your cold simple.
I would say learn see and then learn assembly.
And, to be fair, the CCS compiler is good for certain things.
I found bugs in that too but when you do,
you get free subscription.
The natives are getting restless, they're going
to start throwing spears at us.
One comment.
Tell everyone who is just a programmer do embedded
systems stuff.
It will change the way you program.
Yeah, you know what the fuck the machine is doing.
This one is awesome.
Thank you.