we're here because I'm sure if I stand
behind that they won't be able to see me
Co CC Oh like a head floating I'm taller
then I promise
so I'll just step back sit back and step
up ok so hello
so welcome to personal data privacy the
original title of this was blocking Big
Brother Big Brother and personal data
privacy so my name is Todd Brazel and I
am a consultant for nice Tech which is a
non-profit consulting firm we do work
with state government IT my background
is actually as a software engineer in
test so I'm not actually a hacker but I
do work with them and they say I'm ok
sometimes I don't like touch anything so
he'd like to be a hacker yeah I really
want to be a hacker my introduction to
this this part of information security
came from the software world but
actually my introduction to privacy came
from Michelle and when I was working
with Michelle at another company I was
checking my email one day on my phone
and Michelle said why are you checking
your work email on your phone I said
well it's it's convenient I do that all
the time and Michelle said you shouldn't
do that because by using a personal
device to check your work items storing
documents PDF files anything connected
to work in your personal email on your
personal computer if there's a criminal
or civil case your personal account can
be searched to use against you because
you've now had your work stuff
touching your personal data so everybody
be careful on that one so we all do it
it is convenient I understand just try
to keep it separate so that was kind of
my introduction to it and then from
there I started thinking about
separating my work in my personal life
and that's also a good introduction to
Michelle and I'll let her talk about
herself for a moment so I'm Michelle
Warner I'm a senior consultant with nice
deck I am a lawyer sorry I don't
practice so my lottery comes in handy
for reading privacy policies laws
regarding privacy HIPAA all of those fun
acronyms
I first became interested in privacy
when I was reading an article about a
woman whose picture of her child had
been stolen she posted it on social
media and it was used for a purpose that
she never approved and didn't know
what's happening until it caught up with
her months later so the other person
that I wanted to introduce is Big
Brother and in this case for the context
of this presentation we're really
thinking a Big Brother as any entity
that has access to your private data so
it could be a vendor like Amazon it
could also be a government agency or
something like that what well
specifically cover today are some some
thinking about why is your data
important how you can make better
choices about what information you share
and what are some basic strategy and
tactics that you can follow for
protecting your online privacy this is
for us it's a non-technical presentation
we know that this is kind of a technical
conference everybody saw the keynote
this morning so we roll here here we're
just going to focus on really the
strategy and some of the tactics you can
follow and you can adapt your own
technology or approach to technology in
your own way so the first thing that I
want to cover here is just thinking
about the movie I Robot so I think
everyone here is have seen iRobot or is
heard about iRobot or even read the book
which is actually better than the movie
and iRobot it's really interesting
because it's a case where there is a
crime that's been committed and the
police come to do their interviews and
not only do the interview people but
they also interview the robots that are
a part of the world part of this
fictional world so there are robots
everywhere robots are doing work well
butts are helping people be more
effective
robots know a lot of personal
information about ourselves and it's not
something where I'm familiar with we all
know we all carry these personal devices
with us they are around there in our
environment and they collect a lot of
data and I found a case that happened in
2015 in Bentonville Arkansas where a
crime was committed after her party the
police came to investigate and they
found
an Amazon device they also found some
other smart devices in the house and
they have since gone to Amazon and ask
them for data to see if they if am is if
the Amazon echo device had collected
anything that could be used to prove say
crime had been committed and they also
are going to the public utility about
the smart water meter to see if there
was any unusual water use either during
or after the party to indicate perhaps a
crime scene had been clean up and this
is something that I think also brings us
home is that the world of iRobot is
really the world
deborah today and we think about privacy
at least I think about privacy in a very
kind of abstract way I think about it as
this thing that I run about and a book
well at least it was a book that I
started to read and I was really going
to finish it and I just never got around
here because I was too busy doing other
things but I know that privacy is
important but really security is the
thing that's more important than privacy
right Michelle sorry Todd
no not me no why do we give away
information up here she posted to thank
you on Twitter and in that post
she put where she lost it the town she
lives in we know she says to her home
and spit fill and I'm guaranteeing
Eustace Mills of air in Middletown and
she also has a picture of her so now any
of us if we're familiar with the town at
all can locate her we know where she
likes to shop who know she's a
are you there so we might be able to
figure out where she is at that moment
maybe she's posting that shit at
Carleton Place with her friends right
now is we all compare our our personal
email types right anything I put in my
email nobody else is reading
unfortunately that's not the case an
example here is Google and Gmail privacy
policies at point blank states that
their automated systems are analyzing
our contents including our private
emails to provide us personally relevant
product information customized search
results tailored advertising and spam
and malware detection so they're using
our own data against analysis I think
the reason why this actually happens is
because we undervalue the value of our
own data we think about our data and I
think about my data as just a little bit
of rock in a big pile of rocks and it's
not really that important it couldn't
possibly have value to anyone else but
the vendors that use our data and other
people that access our data see it in a
different way they see our data as nice
chewy delicious candy and want to take
that candy and they want to bundle it up
with other candy and they want to sell
it or they want to use it for some
purpose and one of the problems that we
deal with as consumers is that every
decision we make is really a trade-off
between our own personal convenience and
our privacy we use an online service
which is convenient for us but it also
as a trade-off and we have to give away
some of our private information for that
service actually work because we're not
necessarily paying for it every data
consumer knows this about humanity they
know that we're lazy and they know that
in the long run
convenience is going to win and we'll
give up our privacy willingly and that
brings us to an interesting topic that
Michelle and I like to talk about which
is
from store that's all data that's going
out and you're putting out there
yourself technology companies who are
continuously developing new ways to
collect data from us everybody got a
Fitbit thank you we're phone it's all so
much
gotta get those steps in all right
you're ahead of me benefit providers
insurance companies employers marketing
firm everybody in your data if you put
it out there somebody's looking at it
consumer legal agencies those are the
agencies that are out there to help you
protect your data there's a problem you
can report breaches or if you think your
privacy may have been so isolated
executive orders state and federal laws
all of those impact privacy some
beneficial and some negative there are
laws out there like HIPAA FERPA that
protects your data but there are a lot
out there like public law one one five
to two that actually first your
protections because it allows broadband
companies to use your data without
without your permission
you have to opt out of using it instead
of offense so the point that I'm trying
to make is that there are forces
impacting your data and they change
everyday they can change in a minute by
Congress hiding a lot at going into
effect so just be aware of what's
happening out in the world so if you
bring this to a concrete example
something as simple as ordering
groceries online can affect our privacy
hid this in this case target is is
something I'll pick on right now so a
young woman was ordering if goods from
Target and she started ordering things
like cotton balls and magnesium
supplements uncensored lotion and a
bright blue rug so if you're not
familiar with this you may not put the
pieces together but target did and they
started sending coupons to the house for
diapers and baby products
and her parents were not impressed what
happened here was that target uses an
algorithm based on 25 different products
that they used as a pregnancy prediction
score so not only can they look at what
you're buying and determine if you are
pregnant but they can also look at what
you're buying and determine what state
of pregnancy you're in and send your
appropriate sales and coupons for that
phase another way that we affect our
give up our privacy is something as
simple as ordering a cup of coffee
so although here it's something that we
really don't even think about it just
happened these are these are
transactions that happen many many times
a day you don't give them a second
thought and here I've outlined a few
ways that we can give away information
to the app that we use to to buy the
copy so a lot of these default a lot of
these settings on our phones are default
settings so when we do a transaction we
can give away things like how long we
were at the visit how long we were at
the store what we ordered what her
location was what song we were listening
to and all of this information is
gathered by the sensors on our phone is
gathered by various apps and these are
the things that we've already given away
we don't realize it because when we got
the phone we didn't bother to read the
privacy policies or we didn't think
about what data we were sharing on a
more serious note Facebook has publicly
stated that they have used user data to
determine user moods and they've changed
ads based on what the moods of the users
are so you may think yourself it's not a
big deal but on the other hand think
about what might you buy on impulse when
you're happy what might you buy and
impulse when you're sad data can be used
by a government to determine if you
should be detained for questioning Moxie
Marlinspike is a security researcher
finds himself often detained because his
information was gathered together with
in the course of an investigation into
WikiLeaks even though he has nothing to
do with WikiLeaks he's still detained
for questioning and all of that data was
legally obtained that's a great point
this is
data that legally obtained that's part
of their online services or part of
people's phones and it was obtained
legally and that actually brings us to
the third point which is that this data
can be used in different ways to
actually form a case against you
the Wallow Connor who's a privacy
researcher who works for the Center for
Democracy and Technology stated in an
interview this question in an interview
rhetorically how much information do you
need to build a case against you and as
Michele pointed out in a conversation we
had earlier some of us we made think of
this information is circumstantial but
when it actually is from a legal
standpoint it may not be circumstantial
for example something that Alexa records
a lot of people have an Alexa echo or
other smart assistants are called
sitting in our homes even our phone
could be considered that and there's the
conversations and what you asked for are
stored so if they get a copy of that
sound file that's direct evidence that's
not circumstantial if somebody goes Jeff
how could you stab me with a knife
that's a direct link to the crime in it
sorry and it's a direct point to who did
it and it can be used against you in
court finally and something that I
thought was even a little bit more scary
was that this information about us
that's out there available it can also
be wrong we assume that the information
is correct and right and you think no
big deal we have some co-workers that we
have who don't really feel that
concerned about their data being out
there because they've been breached it's
there they have protections but in some
cases that information is wrong and that
can have a negative impact on your life
Spokeo which is an online database that
acquires information through third
parties and through marketing agreements
was had action taken upon it by the FCC
so it turns out that Spokeo had violated
the Fair Credit Reporting Act so okay I
was taking the information that it had
gathered about all of us and was selling
it to employers as a background search
database but the problem in Spokeo is a
lot of their information was wrong and
people were being denied jobs because of
the incorrect information that was
available in Spokeo so as we're going
about our research we were trying to
figure out what can we possibly do to
take some action at least personally to
help prevent these kinds of situations
so the question is how do we balance the
need for convenience with the need for
privacy we all need to be able to get
that file to our doctor to help with a
medical condition we all need to be able
to send the video to Aunt Minnie of your
daughter's graduation well the way to do
it is to have a personal privacy
strategy which kind of sounds bizarre
but this is the world that we live in
today yes unfortunately we need a
privacy strategy to buy a cup of coffee
so don't worry it's not that complex
based on our own experiences and drawing
from the experts out in the field we put
together an approach that's very simple
easy to follow make informed decisions
about your online presence what you're
putting out there think about it
carefully
compartmentalize create boundaries
between the accounts and identities
monitor for data leakage know what's out
there and know how it's being used so
the first one up is informed decisions
know the value of your data know what
people could get out about you on it if
I post a picture to the show that I love
pink does it show that I love grapes
does it show that I love whatever also
think about what you're posting about
others what you're putting out there
even though you think it's a simple easy
thing somebody else might not appreciate
that being out there about them to you
it's just a picture of the two of you
hanging out at a party but to somebody
else it indicates to maybe their
employer they're concerned about what
their employer might think we're all
connected
in this world today and so just because
you are okay with it doesn't mean
somebody else's think about where your
data is how can it be legally accessed
to help with your decision-making we've
also created a few categories of when
sharing data yeah so specifically we
split it up into three areas so the
first they're based on color so there's
green yellow and red and this is kind of
a common way of classifying information
and but here we're just applying it to
our own so green our is data that is
something that it's really difficult to
be used to harm you so it could be a
throwaway phone number like a Google
Voice number which can be easily changed
or it can be a credit card or not a
credit card but a debit card that you
set up it's a gift card yellow
information are things that can be used
in combination with other information to
harm you or someone that you're you're
concerned about and your loved ones so
things of this nature can be things like
the phone number a primary email or
credit card number again you can change
it but it's a little bit more difficult
to change from the green information and
we're going to get to some examples
later red information is stuff like pH I
so or biometric information something
that's extremely difficult if not
impossible to change and again this is
not an exhaustive list of course why
does it matter where your data is stored
every day we all put things up in the
cloud how many people have pictures
documents whatever stored on a cloud
server somewhere I thought so do you
know where that actually is stored we
all know that it doesn't
most people know and especially here
that data has to resign on a physical
server somewhere just because it's in
the cloud doesn't mean that it's
actually just residing up in the puffy
white things that should be out there
today but aren't when you're storing
data in a cloud it could be anywhere
it could be China it could be
Switzerland
it could be Taiwan it could be Ireland
and that matters because where your data
resides physically you are now subject
to the laws of that country
so some states city states law countries
have stricter provisions on privacy the
European Union is one of them your data
is probably better there than it is here
because there stricter than the US but
other countries such as Russia do not
have stricter laws China Taiwan they all
have much less protections and so now
not only can't you control who is
actually accessing it but you have no
recourse if something happens because
the US can't go in there and enforce
their own laws an excellent example is
protonmail if anybody's part of it
they're based in Switzerland and under
their private standards or law they have
an obligation to and I'm going to read
it I apologize the obligations provide
the technical means for lawful
interception is imposed only on Internet
access access provider so protonmail
cannot be compelled to build in the
technical means to intercept community
community so protonmail because of the
laws of switzerland cannot provide your
data to the government or other entities
it would also be extremely difficult for
a US law enforcement agency to try to
access that data if there's no data
sharing agreement we said I'm aware of
Michele with Switzerland so they would
actually have to go through some
international court to get out your
information so aside from knowing where
your data is stored read the company
privacy policy I know it's legal
mumbo-jumbo I know it could be confusing
but be aware of what they're saying as
we all know Google is a great resource
Google the company name you're looking
for in privacy policy they have to post
them somewhere think to yourself and we
actually have more questions on a
handout if anybody would like one after
the fact key questions to think of an
answer are how and when do they collect
or view information when are they they
should tell you when they're collecting
information on you how do they store and
protect it two-factor authentication is
important it should be considered when
you're reading the privacy policy what
rights do you retain to your information
there are social media sites that when
you post a picture they now also have
rights to that picture not just yourself
and can they can use it at will what can
the company do with your information can
they sell it to
the marketing agencies can they just
hand it over to the government there are
we don't may not consider it data or
information but when you do a cheek swab
and send it to a genealogy company or a
blood testing company to find out your
history there are several of them who
can just hand it over to the government
without getting your approval and it's
right there in their policies where is
the data stored might be listed in the
privacy policy if not you should check
their security policies and other
policies again try to find out where it
is policies change frequently so part of
our strategy is to recommend checking it
multiple times a year they typically
notify you by email and send you a copy
yes I know read it again but just
continue to check because it changed
they do change very frequently it's
important to note that Facebook has
changed their policy privacy policy at
least once every year for the past five
or six years and that also coincides
with a change to their default privacy
settings I actually learned while
researching this project I do typically
check my privacy settings especially on
Facebook mine were not as secure as I
thought they'd been because since I last
checked they added the ability to check
which app sell you stuff didn't know
that learn that recently so the next
topic is something that should be
familiar to people who do social
engineering so it's kind of the opposite
of that so we are looking at personally
compartmentalization so we want to make
sure that we separate work life and
personal life so that there aren't any
links there at least as few links as
possible I'd like to take the approach
where I tried to define roles around
parts of my life and this is a process
that I'm going through so I've stopped
which separated work and personal life
but I also try to separate other
activities so if I have any social
activities such as in this case a head
of a Cheeto head coach of a softball
team kids softball team maybe you have a
social media site just for that team and
so you have to be on Facebook I'm kind
of in the same situation either Club
load belong to and they're on Facebook
so therefore I have to be on Facebook
but I don't do anything else on Facebook
it's just
personal choice and then you have
another part of your life more personal
- maybe you are dating so you want to
try to keep that separate as well and
this goes back to the idea of thinking
about what data you have how important
that data is how it can be used against
you so again it's thinking about
yourself from a social engineering
perspective and then applying that so
let's say you belong to tinder you will
probably want to create a email address
specific for that tinder account a
burner phone number specific for that
tinder account this isn't something that
I thought of myself by the way I just
want to make that clear
I should tell your wife no it's all
right that's how we know it by the way
did I tell you about that you actually
did that we went to one of the dating
sites just because they had that
commercial and so we put our data in and
it turns out that we were a good match
for each other
that's good point yeah I know we're
weird like that we do that kind of thing
so this also goes back to what we said
at the beginning about keeping your work
and personal separate not using your
personal devices personal items you have
an Evernote like account don't put your
work items for in your personal account
have to okay that's what actually
started the whole conversation with us
before so the next one is to monitor the
use of your data everyone I'm sure in
this room is very very familiar with
Google use protecting yourself security
security all of that but just continue
to check there's a big difference
between your security being breached and
privacy more often than not privacy is
breached especially by something we've
done and we may not realize it's been
breached
yes our personal health information has
but that doesn't mean but other details
of our personal lives have been it
doesn't indicate in your ph i that you
like blue and love grapes
it just says i went to this doctor on
this date so google yourself check your
accounts from different viewpoints most
social media sites have the ability to
show you what it looks like from a
certain perspective my settings are this
lockdown it'll show you what others can
see about you review your settings
several times a year I'm sorry I know we
have a lot of sites it's very
frustrating bye
the risk is too high to not keep
checking your settings continue to scrub
your account of extra information do you
really really really need to post that
you're on vacation right now and your
house is sitting empty do you need or
that's you've been on vacation for the
same time for the past five years at the
same spot also think about what you're
bad if you're posting pictures of other
people get their permission stuff like
that continue to use have I been owned
and other services to check what is out
there about you
you'd be surprised I actually had
somebody come up to me after a different
presentation he goes I'm 60 some years
old I have nothing out there I've never
really googled yourself to find out he
goes no but I don't think I have
anything out there
we all have data out there and if people
know it's based on what they see us on
Facebook or social media if you need to
find it I select a talk and we are
researching this presentation just think
about how easy it would be to find out
your security question on Facebook
Twitter you often see is people feed hey
here's a list of st. questions answer
them and then repost it to your site all
you have to do is say what's your
favorite color what was your first car
what's the name of your first pet people
would do it and they'd have their name
their address you could be hackers I
just saw one the other day which was
people who would potentially respond to
this and in what way they would respond
name them and people were circulating
that one on Facebook I think you know
there are other tools - we know about
these tools so again this is kind of
tailored towards a non-technical
audience but of course the tactical
people here will know that there are
other more intense tools that can do
searching we can write our own tools but
what I see for myself and from other
hackers that I work with is that we tend
not to do it you know just because we're
busy or we don't think about it in the
same way a non-technical person or
somebody with a legal background you
think well if I lock it down if I
encrypt it it's safe but that doesn't
necessarily mean your privacy is
protected because of the information
you're posting willingly yeah the other
thing is
about a man regard there's also work
data and because we're responsible for
the data that we hold when we find
something we discover something I have
worked with people I won't name who
posted things to Trello and they try to
coordinate through Trello boards which
are in this instance not necessarily set
up to be the most secure way of doing it
are ways it's securely accessing Trello
but they weren't really doing that so
let's get to some more real-world
examples and we want to focus on social
media because that's I think it's a hot
topic right now so we have social media
has become a major part of our lives we
use it every day to connect to people
who maybe live across the country we
find out what our friends from high
school or college are doing keep in
touch with family find out who had a
baby who graduated but think about do
you really need to use that site or that
service will you be able to get what you
need to accomplish by using one and not
ten think about what else may be
involved with some of the information
out there is there another person in it
does it give away your address a lot of
people like to post if they get a new
apartment or a house a picture with
their address number on it talk about
opening a door think about what the
picture says about you to others try to
step into their shoes and see what a
marketing company might think about the
data you're putting out there or about
your children so a big one for me is
children when you post a picture of a
child online you're creating a social
media profile for them without their
consent if you're posting a picture of
your child or other people's children
definitely get the permission of the
parents before posting and ask your own
child I know several who have asked
their parents to stop posting pictures
because they were embarrassed about the
you know bathtub picture that ended up
there or the picture of them falling in
the mud that the Peres thought was
hilarious they weren't so keen on that
being out there once it goes out out of
your control it is out there forever
it's not going away even if you delete
it we all know it doesn't really get
deleted so Big Brother
what you see when you post a picture of
a party let the police see police mine
social media to build proof to profile
you and Bill CSIS and gather evidence
legally because you are putting it out
there for them to see there's no
restrictions they can gather
relationships create patterns and
determine your weaknesses may be they
determine that this one individual likes
to go for a run every day at five
o'clock maybe that's where they're
picking up the drugs a prime example
that I like to give is the house party I
remember when Facebook first came out of
the campus police we're using it to see
what houses were having house parties so
that they could go arrest the people for
underage drinking so how would following
the strategy help here it's the making
an informed decision thinking about what
you're posting what it says about you
what it says about other people and
being aware that the police are on
social media and are using it the same
way everybody else to gather information
about you so we talked about Big Brother
we're going to talk about talk about
middle brother so middle brother in our
model is a company that is mining your
data for a profit and are trying to see
what they can sell to you or it could be
even an employer who is using this to
either evaluate you as a job candidate
or perhaps for some other purpose and
could before review it's going to happen
you know it so in this case what you see
is the convenience of signing in with
another account so you can sign in with
Gmail or Twitter you can sign in with
Facebook it's very convenient in some
cases it's actually kind of secure
because you might be signing in to a
service that doesn't have the same kind
of protections that these other services
offer and we think about that as a good
thing on the negative side that site
you've signed in to that data consumer
that vendor because of the reciprocal
agreements that they have set up to
allow themselves to to be used as a in
this way they actually have access to
the information in your Facebook account
or your Gmail account
[Music]
so one way to prevent this of course is
not to do that and go through the extra
step the inconvenience of having a
separate sign in and and this goes back
to the idea of compartmentalizing so
you're not looking accounts and if one
account is compromised and you don't
have a cascade of account failure social
media and what we call little brother
these are your everyday average people
your neighbors your network people who
see your data you post the picture to
show them what happened this weekend and
that you had a good time but they can
use their data in ways that your data in
ways that you don't expect
this is an actual post from someone
posting that she went for a run that
morning she shows her start and finish
time probably her house we did we didn't
knock this up this is an actual yeah
oh yes another cat so what could a
neighbor see that gene nobody's home but
the Kenneth and free for picking if you
share information from your social media
account with a friend and they in your
settings are very locked down I'm sure
many people in here are aware and
conscious of their privacy on on a
social media site but if your settings
are very locked down but you share a
picture or a post and somebody else
shares that post to their timeline or
likes it it's now on their settings and
their settings Trump so now it's
available to their network and if their
network is not nearly as lockdown as you
are everybody can see it I just think of
the connections from there of they
posted there somebody else took it and
posted it to theirs and then and so on
and so forth so just how would following
the strategy help in this situation
I can't repeat it enough to make an
informed decision think about what
you're putting out there how it could
enter a pattern how it could leave you
open for a break in what it says about
you
this person literally does in fact go
for that morning run every day same time
every day
[Music]
so social media and the unexpected
brother this is what goes back to what I
said at the beginning about somebody
having their child picture stolen so
didn't want to use me job pictures yeah
we were huge to violate somebody privacy
and use an actual children's photo so we
did a mock-up so somebody posted a
picture of their child and had it stolen
and using what is called a sick child
hoax they actually took the picture of
this individual and posted it all over
the internet saying that they were sick
and needed money and people were sending
money we also found and this is why we
have what really messed up people see is
that people were using pictures of
children in online sexual role-playing
as their avatars again unexpected
brother yeah when you're when you're
doing a presentation like this be very
careful what you google you just stay
with you forever so this just goes back
to the point we made earlier about very
very cautious with your children's
photos they can be used in ways that you
don't intend and you are creating a
social media profile for them whether
they're aware of it or not that is out
there staying with them and somebody
else might be able to use it in ways you
didn't intend you sent it to Aunt Minnie
but George and the next county got it
and you don't want to know what he's
doing with it so to summarize I wanted
to call this keep your crap off the
cloud but I didn't think I would go over
well on a slide so I call it be aware of
what you share and I know that a lot of
us are highly technical we have a lot of
experience in this field and I want you
to think about this your the tip of the
spear you're the hardpoint
you go after the bad guys who's around
you your boyfriend your girlfriend your
spouse your child your brother your
sister these people are not the tip of
the spear when you're going after
someone when your social engineering who
are you going to go after you're not
going to go after me I could I'm pretty
easy Michael after my wife
I go after my family so something to
think about and I hope that even if this
information is review for you that it's
perhaps presents something that is kind
of easy to digest and you can give to
your loved ones and that they can apply
so that they can be more secure online
as well so any questions the reminder
that big better yes I know a little bit
do you have you found anything okay okay
sorry well you know collaborate so
actually it's not a lot it's really
interesting I was expecting because I've
done research into the economy of cyber
security and cyber crime that's pretty
much what you'd expect it's you know
forty dollars I think it's one figure
that I had for your personal data in
Google with about forty bucks so in the
in the aggregate though it does add up
to a lot when you have millions and
millions of users but so individually
yeah it's not really that much unless
it's something like not even a bank
account isn't really that much so yeah
I'm sorry did everyone hear the question
I should have repeated it it was what's
the value of your own information on the
open market
yeah the cost to you is I think on
average it takes about six to nine
months now to recover from identity
theft actually it's gotten better
there's so many identity theft cases
that it's gotten faster used to be over
a year and you're looking at anywhere
from
I took six thousand to twelve thousand
dollars in legal fees and other costs to
recover your identity permit identity in
that case yeah so yes it's about twelve
bucks a year for user control bucks per
user yeah
it's about right so it's not we have a
list of questions that you should ask me
you should ask yourself when you're
posting so you're talking like we're
saying well you talk about us what
you're saying yes that's a great point
which is something that I think because
of our position and I stack you can't
really speak about but yeah that is
something that me personally I believe
in advocacy so yeah
something we talk about after after the
presentation yes everything again just
keeping the conversation going and
telling people I know I know that kind
of evaded your question but well to kind
of Evernote you talk about Evernote
earlier I was using Evernote to capture
notes about what I was working on and I
got the updated policy privacy policy
notice that came out last year where
Evernote and the policy said that they
were changing their policy to allow more
internal people to have access to your
account for quality I think it's quality
control purposes or something like that
and ordinarily I would have just ignored
the notice and not read it but now that
we're getting in going down this kind of
rabbit hole I runned out I thought oh no
I've got information up there that could
potentially lead to information about
clients that I'm working with so I
immediately
I did what I needed to do to get rid of
that account delete the information
permanently I read hit the the
instructions they had on permanently
deleting information I downloaded the
downloaded I had as a backup and I
cancelled my account and then I got a
confirmation from them later that they
had removed all the information and then
took a you know lesson wearing their
what was I thinking putting that up in
the cloud to begin with and so I really
I've begun to change the way that I work
I've taken stuff off the cloud I have
instead of using OneNote or something I
have a personal wiki that's you know
that's on my hard drive
it's like laptop is stolen or something
someone could get that but at least it's
not available for other people to go
through for whatever reason question on
the back so are people being penalized
in some way for not using social media
have you seen anything about that I've
seen I've seen some anecdotal things you
know about people who generally it's
when they apply for a job if the company
has some kind of wacky HR practice where
they review social media sites and you
don't have one that it's kind of
suspicious I don't have any other
thoughts on that I haven't seen any I
think if anything else it's actually
probably best that you don't have it so
oh thank you sir god
[Music]
yeah putting it yes but yeah that's a
really good
I thought about that but yeah that's a
good point so there's a bigger incentive
for them to do it they have less
awareness potentially so yeah so yeah
also they would have to participate
potentially more in government programs
so there's automatically more data
collected on them anyway so yeah that's
a good point so so unfortunately no but
that's that's maybe uh maybe next
presentation I don't forget to add that
that's an interesting one I like that
[Music]
but we have good coupons yeah yeah it's
worth sir yeah yeah okay any other
questions or comments all right thank
you very much I hope you enjoyed it I
hope you got some good information thank
you
[Applause]
[Music]