how you doing I'm John my talk is uh
hold my red bull penetration testing
within higher education so not very
technical talk more of an overview or I
guess throwing you into the deep end but
it's not going to be anything that's
going to go over your head or I hope not
if it does please let me know so I can
explain it in a better way so let's get
started really quick my three months
left at Champlain College I attend the
online program and uh finishing
cybersecurity and networking I have an
associate's degree from Herkimer County
Community College I'm security plus
certified my official title according to
my boss would be a cyber security
samurai but really my role is a security
consultant and penetration tester so
this talk has a lot in it but it's going
to consist of the ethics the game fiying
or gamification the academia standpoint
and then some definitions or
explanations so that maybe you guys can
understand the concepts of offensive
security a little bit more ethics is a
really important thing especially to me
and in this field because when you get
hired as a pen tester they give you
access to things that you know they
don't normally do even to their own
employees it's a it's a lot of
responsibility and a lot of risk they
put so it's really important that you
keep the the ethical and the moral
obligation and responsibility that
they're giving you in mind and that's
what really is first on this talk
because they really it scared me
thinking about giving this access to
people that I went to school with
already or that I go to school with I
mean you know people in their 20s don't
always do the smartest things so I would
start ethics being a huge part of it
starting you know the first day freshman
year sophomore year you should
have some form of ethics especially
directly correlating to cybersecurity or
offset the security I mean it's just
it's something that really would have to
be hammered in and you would really need
professors who know what they're doing
and really care about the ethics as well
and understand you know what what you're
training these people to do um so the
next part would would be you need to
have some establish honor code it's an
honor system like a lot of things and
it's really similar to the honor system
that we have with clients because they
don't have the time or the resources to
monitor us all the time and so there are
times where you know where we will probe
a client or do some tests and and they
have no idea that we did this and that's
not again that's not something I would
want to leave us up to any 20 year old
or anyone who has an interest in it it's
something that needs to be you know
hammered in that these this is pray and
this is wrong and it would have to be
off some honor code which if you do
break it you would be you know uh kicked
out no exceptions and I think it has to
be like that and I'll get to July it
would have to be over the course of a
capture-the-flag framework which is a
type of game that has grown in
popularity and I'll get explain what
that is in a few slides the learning
management system which you know
blackboard canvas a lot of us have
experience using that if you've gone to
undergraduate school and then a wiki and
all of these things should span multiple
majors a lot of this stuff it doesn't
necessarily have to be for offensive
security there are things that computer
scientists that you know defensive
security professionals can benefit from
and they should and you should want to
educate these offensive security
students in a way where they're learning
off the defensive security students so
kind of pitting them together again zero
tolerance and the most important part I
think to deter people from doing stuff
they're not supposed to would be a
immensely large virtual
simulation I would think of you know
having a CTF framework that's not the
one where they do all their homework but
one that they can test a learning
management system say company a fake
website all of this up and needs to be
there so that if they feel the need they
can they have some way to get rid of
that that need or that desire to try
something because the more you go into
it the more you look around and think
well what is that how does that worker
maybe if I try that and you can't do
that in education why I think we should
game fi it as much as possible well one
it's a popular approach a competition is
really useful and it pushes other people
and I think competition in this case
especially it's not something where it's
like you know good versus evil or one
person wins and one doesn't I think
gamifying offensive security like in
CTFs it pushes people to learn more and
off of each other and it is like the the
most useful competition around something
important to note would be that honor
system that needs to be established
would not have anything to do with the
point system in this this game so you
know you you finish your homework you
submit and you get ten points towards
your 100 for your homework it needs to
be completely separate from the honor
system because the honor system needs to
be again you know if you step out of
line that's it there's no second chances
whereas in the CTF if you try to submit
something so if you try to submit an
answer that's wrong I I think that they
should absolutely be able to try that
again it shouldn't be you know remember
obvious and spit it back like like a lot
of tests are today I think this game is
fiying it would also keep people engaged
I mean you see apps on the on the app
store that are you know life games you
know the how how much have you ran today
how much have you eaten and it gives you
points and it raised you and and it's
the same idea can keep people engaged in
the same way one thing that does
correlate is that point system and that
would correlate to the grade system so
how I would vision it would be instead
of going to these learning management
systems where it's you know write your
paper in this with this template and
submit it the points in these games so
the more they find the more they hack
the more they submit the higher the rate
and I think that pushes teamwork
together as well and then the last thing
would be leaderboards and that's the
last piece from gaming I think that we
should take and that is just it gives
people a better view of where they stand
to compare to their peers where they
need to work on where they don't need to
work on where they can help others and
it also you know it may push you to try
harder just to do more within academia I
can see an offensive security degree
being you know perfect legitimate and
plenty of material to do that and I
think that should be a thing you know
there is cyber security and I love
degrees I have and I'm happy that it's
that I have the possibility to do that
but there needs to be an offensive
security degree I mean no matter what
you can't cover everything in a two year
or four year or six years
oh and offensive security is one of
those things and needs it needs its own
major we need to produce people who who
know what they're doing you have a
passion for it and that's been studying
it for years before they enter the job
market I also see it as a minor for IT
for information security for cyber
security or even for computer science
because there are all these are all
fields that you could take us takes
topics you know take things that you
learn and apply it in offensive security
so just in case you don't know I'm going
to explain a little bit about the
capture the flag is counter the flag is
it's like a like a war game kind of you
have missions and you have that you're
given and you know you're supposed to
take certain steps or find certain
things like maybe an I Spy you can think
of and you submit them and you get
points you go through stories and learn
things you go through networks go
through systems and explore stuff and I
think because it has such a huge
following now I mean there's there's
ones online ones of schools everywhere
it needs to be picked up more it needs
to be used across schools across States
across the country across the world not
just through these nonprofit
organizations or these these private
entities but through the education
system because they're just missing out
one really good resource for that is a
bone
and that's a website that contains a lot
of boot to route and that means you
download this this image of an operating
system you install it and you you load
it up and you get right to work and it's
meant to be broken into and I think
people look past the value in that a lot
and especially in schools because you
know you don't you don't have to set up
your giant virtual lab that I suggest
you know you don't need to do it from
scratch you don't need to buy all these
operating systems you there are
resources out there already for the
professionals use and that you know I
use for fun and for practice that that
would work great in the CTS it would
work great in this context and the most
another important thing would be you
know freshman year a lot of students
walk in they may not have the the
technical skills or the expertise to do
a professional CTF but they do have
enough that they could do trivia
questions and I think that alone
even though it's the same as a
multiple-choice question that formatting
you know monopoly or not a monopoly I'm
sorry jeopardy like formatting that
would engage people more that would keep
people interested more you know so it's
not doesn't have to be super technical
people here CTF and they think of the
most second devil thing they can and
then it's not always the case and I
think that you should get access to this
at day one all of this needs to start
the second you walk in so that they
understand what they're signing up for
how serious this is and what this could
lead to for them in their life um very
similar to CTF but not exactly the same
would be these red versus blue I could
explain it it really is a cyber war game
I would say that's where it started on
red team versus blue team so offensive
versus offensives um it's in scene in
first-person shooters very often as well
how I think about it is his games where
you have to there's a team that goes and
tries to plant a bomb and there's a team
that tries to defend the bomb or defuse
the bomb and I see it very similar to
that you have the IT students you have
the is students you have the computer
science students protecting these assets
and you have the offensive security
students trying to break these assets
take control of these assets and then
also in politics I think besides just
the colors I think it's very clear
especially recently you know how it is
red vs. blue in politics and the the
biggest point of this is there's a two
field approach and it's not how it is
right now right now with cybersecurity
which is in which encompasses many many
fields including ones in seen in
intrusion response computer science
information technology information
security and I think if we look at it
from an education standpoint as
offensive and defensive we can reach out
to more students it would make sense to
more students and there's more there for
students to learn so really quick I'm
just going to go over the fields of
study with an offensive security and
the security so in offensive security
that consists of operation security
network security system security
physical security web security for first
engineering social engineering
open-source intelligence methodologies
and mindset and then basically anything
with in IT is or CS for those who don't
know I picked a few of those fields just
to explain so maybe if you don't know
you will when you walk out of here
so social engineering is something that
a lot of people associate with phishing
and other digital attacks phishing being
those scam emails that you get to try to
trick you into putting your you know
username or password in or your credit
card number spearfishing where it's
specific to one person so instead of
sending it to a thousand random emails
they pick you and they send it to you
whaling would be when you choose an
executive and you choose them and only
send that that attempt that fraud
attempt or scam to them war dialling
where you enumerate or call a list of
numbers that own or that are owned by a
company in hopes that you identify a fax
or some other sensitive information
maybe a an executive internal phone
number and then as I was saying the
physical side of social engineering is
like conning so it's the con men you
know you see in Ocean's eleven and
Ocean's Twelve and that's important
because in most context you'll see
social engineering they're talking about
fishing or whaling or or something like
that but there's a lot more to it
there's the whole physical side to it
open source intelligence which is
probably the one I think but most people
have the least amount of experience with
it it's fairly new it's called ocean
sometimes maybe Orion as a human
intelligence it's generally passive so
it's gathering intelligence or
information about a company or a target
without going to their website without
going to their physical building and
dumpster diving without you know calling
these people and trick
them into telling you something this is
all stuff you use the crazy amount of
websites on the internet for and I use
this on engagements all the time
so you use services like a search engine
that indexes Twitter and you look
through tweets that people have sent out
before hopefully finding emails or
pictures of people or you know other
sensitive information like that some of
the stuff you could find or that I have
found in the past documents people's
names emails phone numbers IP addresses
license plates reverse image search is a
great example of open source
intelligence I also have found thin
numbers I found garage codes I found I
mean that are discussing a lot of
information about people methodologies
and mindsets methodologies I guess I
would define as general instructions
sometimes they come in the form of
topics or points to cover sometimes
they're just tools and instructions but
really they're they're basically
guidelines and the mindset is things
like an attacker and that is something
that you hear a lot but may not make
sense to you how I like to think about
it is for years I carried a USB Drive on
my keys and I named it risky and I put
some malware on it and I would walk
around into businesses I walk in the
interviews for my first day at a as a
sales associate at the mall and I
thought about how my manager locked me
in her office to fill out my paperwork
to watch my training video from
cybersecurity and how bad it is to do
that with a USB pocket or USB Drive in
my pocket that I could have easily
plugged into her computer which is
perfectly unlocked and you know wreaked
havoc and I think that's something that
a lot of people overlook since I've
started this job and a little bit before
you know this is something that is 24/7
I think like an attacker you know I walk
around and I I guess you could call me
paranoid but I I think about you know
the last security I think about you know
why are they let Y houses how do they
let me in the manager's office
lock me in close the door put the
shochet down and leave me there until
you know I I tell them that I'm done
it's it's mind-blowing and I think this
is one of the biggest things to do but
once you do it it's for life you will
never look at things the same it changes
your perspective and I think that's a
good thing by physical security
you know the 3GS gates guards and guns
another example cameras man traps um the
big thing about physical security is
they only do as much as the thick gates
guards and guns do so if you put someone
who is not happy with their job as a
security guard they may not be a very
good security guard you know if you put
someone who is told well if something
happens you know you need to come hard
you need to hurry and stop that well now
you're telling them to be reactive not
proactive and it's tough to get past
that that hump and I couldn't tell you
what invisible security could be
proactive or more proactive but I think
is just something to keep in mind that
you know just because there is someone
with a you know a good person with a gun
and a badge and a fence does not mean
that they're making sure that no one
gets past that fence or they're gone or
their badge it sucks but that's just the
way it is and operation security which I
could have put a definition but I
figured this one making a little bit
more sense to people because operation
security cover stuff that may have been
covered within network security or
physical security so I'll tell you a
story that I read on Reddit last a few
years ago and so basically around
September 15th 2016 an Isis member was
killed by US airstrike you know not
something that's very uncommon nowadays
unfortunately but it does happen the
interesting part is this was 8 days
after he hosted I read it ask me
anything which is when you go to the
site reddit you sign up and for a few
hours you respond to everyone's comments
so anyone could go on there and say hey
how does this work or hey what do you do
and he was doing it he was answering
these people's questions the mistake he
made was when he was asked for a selfie
and his coordinates he said I'm not
giving you my coordinates that's silly
but he did put a selfie on there and it
turns out that he did not have P o
tagging off and so his coordinates his
exact location was in it and sure enough
eight days later supposedly he was
bombed and killed so that's what happens
when you don't follow operation security
it's a very extreme example but I
thought it would get the point across
another interesting one that was I found
while I was looking some stuff up for
this talk what's war talking and we're
talking itself is not operation security
but that is the act of drawing symbols
in public places to advertise an open
Wi-Fi network and I just thought that
was a very interesting attack on
operation security you know a
vulnerability I guess you can say in
Opera security that I never would have
thought of because I you know I would I
think that someone who was walking by
looking at the Wi-Fi networks would
would Marcus on my wall so that everyone
else knows but that is a very again
extreme example of how someone can break
your operational security and how
important it is so within defensive
security it's a lot of the same stuff I
would say the the biggest differences
are the hardened programming so when you
are making a tool not to say the NSA or
the CIA's tools aren't good but they do
not think about security in their tools
there are offensive security tools you
know and that's something that defensive
people really need to do more and more
and more from the beginning it's not
after the fact don't don't you know
patch stuff after the fact but make it
secure from the beginning digital
forensics and then incident and disaster
recovery and that's not to say that any
of those things aren't helpful or useful
when it comes off offensive security but
it's more stuff that you would want
experts in for defensive not for
offensive
so red versus blue I would want this to
be a competition and I think this needs
to to be to be picked up so whoever's
willing to do that it needs to put
defensive security students against
offense and security students and
simulations that will resemble real life
experiences and real life job
opportunities so how I would see it you
know you have an asset and you have
people trying to break in people trying
to stop it kind of like the northeastern
college gate defense cup of cyber
competition but instead of having cyber
scary or offensive security
professionals being the red team in this
case I think they should put other
students in as the red team and I think
that would benefit more people and bring
more students to the schools and I could
really see this being growing into
something like eSports is today you know
a team a team for both blue and red
teams you know cyber sports if this ESPN
wants to reach out but I think that's
something that's going to happen whether
you know schools jump on board first or
not or whether they're the ones to do it
first or not another big aspect that I
don't see at colleges above bounty
program and a bug bounty program is
basically when a company or an entity
organization has steps you can take that
give anyone or select people access to
testing substances you know we get
contracted but this is stuff open to the
public or open to registration you
register they say okay you can try to
break into you know our website and if
you find something we'll pay you for it
and that is supposed to deter people
from going to the black market or
selling it to criminals or to you know
to the high-level government and I think
schools I mean I have no idea why
schools aren't doing it now and almost
every company does and I think schools
need to do that in my case how I feel is
juniors excuse me juniors within the
offensive security major or minor they
should get access to this
their junior year it should be unique to
each school because unlike the CTF these
vulnerabilities or these bugs will be
unique to the school most likely they're
not going to be you know stuff that you
can just set up in a virtual lab because
this is stuff that has to be live as the
difference I think you could reward
scholarships
you know school store credit or school
branded items that's something they
could put on their CV and advertise when
they they go to transfer it's just it's
very beneficial to both the school to
find these bugs so that bad people don't
and for students who can then go to
schools and say look I've been you know
a lot done this and I've done this and
and they could leave with a more of a
boat verbose and more confident CP I
also would suggest a plaque for the
student because I would imagine at least
after the first few years you wouldn't
you wouldn't find many or a lot of
students winning because you know
they're not starting with access to this
or with the knowledge that they you know
maybe you could do a lot with it but by
the time you know maybe three or four
kids graduate you probably would find a
lot of bugs I mean there's a lot of
people and a lot of people spend a lot
of time and have their own unique ways
and I just I think this would push
people to become more technical in their
outside time for more reason than you
know I want to know how to do this
because that may not motivate everyone
but if they know that they get a
scholarship maybe that would I think
this would be a minor test for students
as well for their ethics and if they
understand what's right and wrong and
you know if they're they understand the
responsibility that they're being given
it's good practice taking technical
notes and writing technical reports
which is something I have to do every
day and it's really important and good
to take you know learn how to do it and
how to start practicing it as soon as
possible and I think a bug bounty
program which puts help out with that
and then it would also help with
practical use of following these
instructions or these
upset you would take in the real world
but not in the real world
or not in an environment where you're
being contracted you're being paid this
you know company is letting you see your
sensitive information if it's something
for your school it's something I think a
lot more people would be willing to to
participate in a little more specific so
we have the fields of offensive security
and now we'll have some topics and this
is the biggest reason why a current
cybersecurity degrees
don't cover enough love offensive
security because there is so much that's
why we need our own degree program our
own major
so within offensive security there are
vulnerabilities assessments internal
penetration tests external penetration
tests web app penetration tests phishing
social engineering physical penetration
tests reconnaissance operations security
offensive security tools and tool
creation and then cyber intelligence or
counter cyber intelligence these are all
things that I I do for my job and I
think more people would want to do if
they had you know access to the the
steps they can take to do that or the
opportunity to do that and obviously you
know I'm no expert in every one of them
I will never be an expert in every one
of them and that's why I think it's so
important that we get people started on
them as early as possible tips and
tricks so this is just a random I guess
blop blop of facts tips and tricks that
I've acquired or learned over the years
because I've been doing this stuff way
before I was in school the biggest thing
you know push through if you get lost on
something or in something you know I
can't tell you how many times I've spent
four hours trying to just turn something
on that wouldn't work when it boot up
just to find out that you know I put it
down to the night and come back and I
just you know was sitting the wrong
or something it's the wrong key one time
but I spent four hours on it and you
have to learn how to stop yourself how
to recognize those types of things so
that you don't waste six hours of the
client's time you know looking into a
vulnerability that you knew from the
beginning wasn't horrible anyway or
wasn't applicable in that case anyway
and that's it's tough but it's something
that you need to keep in mind when
you're experimenting with this stuff we
all get lost into it we all get
overwhelmed we all is you know something
goes over our heads every time and you
just have to persevere through it if you
haven't
you can't tell with my ethics you know
involving the legal system is not worth
it never worth it especially in this
context you know I'm not going to tell
you that they're going to find you if
you try to do an SQL injection on some
website in China but that doesn't mean
you don't know what you're doing you
don't know what could happen and you
don't know what a company would view you
like you know are they going to hire you
just because you weren't caught if
you're a notorious or infamous or you
know you go into your interview and say
well I did this but I wasn't supposed to
and the cops never came so you know I
don't have a record well it's like yeah
but but if you're willing to do that if
that's you know if you don't understand
the the moral line your risk you're a
bigger risk you know then an attacker in
some cases even well something I think a
lot of people have trouble understanding
is there's no hack that will make you
the best coming from someone who has
explored the darknet art or whatever you
want to call it who has explored hacker
forms that have come and go you know
every other day
they are very tunnel very small view and
they are very tunnel vision they don't
see the big picture they don't see the
steps that you would have to take in a
real penetration test they are specific
to you know if you're running Windows
and it's Tuesday and it's raining you
could exploit it and that's it and it's
it's great and you could spend the time
to learn that but it's not going to help
you you know in the long run it
it's too specific and almost everything
you read all of this media stuff it's
very specific if you have this version
number you know and the media will say
if you have this version if you're
running Windows you're screwed and
you're going to get hacked and that's
not the case no matter what 9 out of 10
times when I find something that comes
up wonderful on a tool that has a
vulnerable version that has the library
that's that's old and needs to be
updated I can't do anything with it
anyway
maybe it's not implemented you know
there's a thousand reasons why but it is
what it is there is nothing that you can
just download or that you can just learn
and that's it now you could apply this
in any context in any case every system
every infrastructure every organization
is different well another big thing that
was hard for especially me you will
never know everything I go through
phases where I very confident in my
abilities in my knowledge base and I go
through phases where I am not very
confident in my ability in my knowledge
base one of those times is when I
started working at a lead cyber security
and I mean I walked in you know was
confident I could do anything you guys
do we could do it better and I got you
know thrown on my ass really quick and I
appreciate that and I see that and I
don't think everyone has to go through
that if you just understand that it is
constantly growing is constantly
changing there's more and more being
discovered you won't be cocky you won't
be over-the-top you won't become
infamous you know if you don't do it for
the lulz and you do it because you care
you won't you will end up with that
attitude another thing I found very
helpful is how you view things you've
learned so for a year I was a computer
science major I did not like it at all
definitely not for me and it didn't it
didn't until about two years later did I
really look at it and say wow I actually
benefited a lot more from that than I
then I thought you know I can look at
this this C++ code that I found
on a client site and I can understand it
and that alone is something you know
just the context that you learn things
in especially in school is not the
context that you have to use them in and
that's important especially in all sense
of security it helps when I read things
about cybersecurity or policy or you
know I could look at policy the same way
I look at a CV or an exploit or an RC
you know even though they're very
different so everything from body
language to the guards gaze and guns is
applicable to offensive security and I
think is something a lot of people
overlook as well they don't realize that
something that it took me to get hired
to know was a it's not a nine-to-five
job and never ends I work till four in
the morning a lot of the nights just
because I can and I I just get in the
mode and I get addicted to it basically
and I just can't stop I mean it's just
so interesting to me but it is extremely
frustrating and discouraging when you
spend you know every waking moment
twenty hours a day for a week and find
nothing and I found that if you step
back at those times and give yourself
time to recover and go back you know I
mean I remember this one night I spent
60 hours and that Monday I didn't go in
after that that was a week I spent 60
hours on this one one website and I went
in Tuesday morning I sat down turned it
on I looked at one of the URLs that I
saved and they listed the login portal
and I had no idea that that was there at
no memory of it I was just in such you
know tunnel vision on I need to find an
RCE
I need to find you know X or Y I need to
find a cgi script that it just it ended
up not being helpful and then also look
at the big picture not through the eyes
of a single exploit so I kind of
mentioned that but you know again you
know wanna cry seeker
great example um there is no end-all or
be-all and in this and there's no
exploit that's going to work everywhere
there is no you know no pen test if I've
been on that's been okay I use one
exploit and I have through access to the
domain administrator so that's just it's
not the case you have to pivot you have
to go through and until you get to poke
around real infrastructure or really
good virtual infrastructure you know
you're not going to know what it's like
and I you know like I said I went in my
first day and I was very confident and I
was learning things less and right
because I I never even thought about
looking at you know LDAP ports or SNMP
because I don't have those at my house
no I don't I don't have those you know
on my my PC that I have in my virtual
machine because you know I didn't what
was the point of it but there is a point
that it is used there are things that
you will miss until you go on a real
engagement until you do a realistic CTF
and I think that we need to do more of
those for students especially um I think
you need to spend hours upon hours
that's never ending because there's
constantly more and I find it easy to do
that you may not but if offensive
security is what you want to do prepare
for it because you will have to you know
nothing you do I would say nothing but a
to the ten times that tool that works on
the last engagement will not work on
this one so just be prepared and strive
to understand what you were doing and
not just how to do it I think this is
something that I've met people in the
industry and they look past as well you
know if it works why why mess with it
and my my eyes um the reason to mess
with it so that you understand why it
works because just because it works you
know just because it looks like it on
the outside doesn't mean it's actually
happening on the inside
another thing research which is a loose
word that can mean anything from
googling to reading white papers to
reading
jars joint analysis responses you know
from the DHS or the FBI or stuff like
that all of those are very interesting
and take them with a grain of salt but
you know you can learn a lot just from
reading a paper and then people look
past that you know if it's not a talk I
don't want to know about it I don't want
to have to sit there and read it but you
have to you have to spend the time you
have to research always every day see
what's going on you should keep one eye
on current events within the field
another thing you know like again want
to cry we had a contact some clients
when we read about that because we were
afraid they were going to be targeted
and it's the same idea
you know you're gonna stuff that is
useful today will be obsolete tomorrow
and I know you've probably heard that a
lot but it's never been truer till today
you know it's it's going to be worse and
worse and worse
so you have to pay attention to what's
going on and that means more than what's
on it Fox or what's on CNN that means
you know going on the hacker forums
going on tour going on free net going on
IRC you know all these sites that you
know I'm not telling you to register and
sign up and and participate in these
anonymous operations but I'm telling you
you know look at it see what they're
doing see why why are they so upset
what are they targeting you know why are
they targeting it etc you know what
tacks are they using what etc I mean
there's just there's so much and you
need to if that's going to be your way
into the community that's fine but just
don't get lost in it don't get lost in
that one exploit they're trying to do or
that one operation don't don't help them
but just pay attention to what they're
doing is it's more useful than you think
and practice what you preach you know
anyone can stand up here and say don't
use bad passwords don't repeat your
passwords but I would guess that
probably have people you've heard ever
say that do use weak passwords do repeat
their passwords
you know and I can tell you that from
experience because I see a lot of
organizations passwords I mean I was on
an engagement and I saw the CTO who used
the same password from his website which
you know some some like bug tracking
system all the way to a domain
administrator on the domain controller
and we use that from that website and
SQL injection on that website we were
able to connect remote connect pivot to
the domain as an administrator and we
own their network in ten minutes just
because he did use the same password so
I think that's really important as well
okay all right so that's it
short shorts we talked about ten minutes
so if anyone has any questions concerns
all right thank you
[Applause]