okay this is kind of a talk up and
kicking around in the back of my head
for about a year and a half because it's
advice I've been trying to give to both
people I work with and people I mentor
so Who am I on this is the standard
disclaimer I am a senior security
consultant at Leviathan security group
in Seattle I'm a consultant by day which
means I exchange money for security
advice I practice law as a hobby
standard disclaimer nothing this talk
should constitute legal advice are good
advice for that matter I mean after all
I'm here on a Saturday and I'm also a
lawyer so I've made many many bad
decisions in my life don't follow me
I'm a the disclaimer I'm an attorney I'm
not your attorney yet hopefully not so
why this talk I've watched too many
competent security engineers pen testers
defensive side coders and the like get
promoted yay promotion except and
becoming competent managers just mess it
up and they're they're angry they took a
look at 10% pay raise and they're there
they gain weight they get angry they get
divorced and it's like you screwed up
you were a hot-shit pentester and you
could make decent money and you were
happy doing that thing and then a
promotion came you know like all of a
sudden now I'm the security manager I'm
director of InfoSec or god forbid you
went to a start-up in your size oh and
look at me I'm a size oh except like
you've lost your hair you're drinking
more than even we do it's a problem
right like so so it's in a way it's this
is a pre intervention before we all have
to read you a letter that says we care
about you and we've all wrote a letter
about how much we love you
stop being a manager but if you do
decide to go into management this is the
advice I wish I had
this is the advice I am now giving and
instead of my random things given when
people ask me questions I like that I
have the opportunity to one get feedback
in to have aid report me so that way I
can just now instead of having to have
you know a conversation with people to
say like refer to my talk so find a
place to be a rock star if you want to
stay in pentesting if you want to stay
in your thing there's still enough money
in it you know I don't think anyone here
has needs that high that they have to go
into management go into management
because you think hey I can now do more
interesting things but they're new
things and here's the concept specific
competence versus general competence we
all know that person who has no social
skills whatsoever maybe even no idea of
how a shower works and yet they are
absolutely genius at disassembling code
like I'm thinking of actual reference
notes in some code which was first step
to do this second step called this
person and we actually have sold that at
my shop as we will do code review and
this I've watched them do that and I
don't know how this does like you pump
the code through app scan our very code
or something like that and spits out
stuff and he just looks at in kind of
Cox's head and says oh no that too like
so I'm in an automated system didn't
find the phone you just looked at it
funny like it
and like yeah oh yeah yeah that's a
that's a that's kind of like a nested
buffer overflow if you have this
conditions I can like you just stare the
code and it did that and God forbid that
person should ever go become like
director in Memphis like because he will
fail he'll be a genius at just put them
in a room with code and eventually the
code will come out and say and you'd be
able to point on the code where the bad
person touched it
so this is what we call the Peter
Principle I'm going back to general
competence there are people who like I
will figure it out whatever it is I
would like to think I have some of that
because I have done things like with no
with no forewarning just like look at
something and solve it because I have a
generalized model for how to solve
problems
the last time I did I was very chuffed
about it was I'm parking my motorcycle
and someone just says hey do you know
how to fix my bike and I realize what it
is is that the the kickstand switch is
broken so I just pull up put up put it
in neutral and start a it's like how did
you know to do that like it would take
me longer to explain than just fix the
kickstand switch it's sort of a
generalised confidence I can take a
problem and a new problem that I haven't
seen before and fix it that's why I'm a
consultant right people come to me and
go you know how to fix this I'm like no
I don't have a solution for you but I
will go into the room with that that
problem and a week later and the size
will bill I will come out with something
that hopefully looks like a solution but
the problem is is that many people come
up through security and they're really
good at one thing and they get shoved
into another and don't realize it's a
new context you have to code switch you
have to become it different you have to
learn a new skill set so I hate watching
people flounder I hate watching people
who are smart and capable just take a
new job and screw it up
and I hate being on the outside but
yelling I'm like at a at a movie yeah
horror was like don't open the door
shoot the bad guy again
- shovel smack him into the shovel
brakes now you're done right and I hate
having to like you know I'm thinking of
a particular mentee of mine who like
managed to screw something up so basic
it's like I'm screaming that you didn't
either anything to call me or be just
like why aren't you bright enough to
figure that out
and it was something really simple so
this is the advice I'm trying to give as
like recognize your context so some of
them my client employees and that
also in a way sadder when an existing
security resource at one of my clients
quits they go on to a bigger better job
and then they look around and go well
who around here oh you've been running
DevOps you're now chief of security and
what competent DevOps people don't have
to move into security management to make
more money like a competent DevOps
versus going to be DevOps until at least
the next whatever whatever replaces
agile happens right but for now there is
you don't have to take the promotion to
make more money just get better at it
and I've met people like do automation
stuff and I'm like I don't know half the
words you said but I can't admit to that
because otherwise and I would look like
the idiot
I can't look like the idiot but the bit
is I hate watching smart people take a
new job and screw it up so moving on up
your security or pentester and now
you're doing all the things your charge
of compliance your charge of answering
those security vendors vendor security
questionnaires some of you chuckle some
of you go what's that and that's really
where it's show us on this doll where
the vendor touched you and made you feel
bad really it's show us on this show us
on this spreadsheet where the vendors
going to touch you and make everybody
feel bad it's a different environment
right you're now having to go and be
nice you can't just bash code your life
is not spent in a meta you know running
Metasploit you're now dealing with
non-techies on a regular basis some of
you may go oh dear god what is that like
and others you may look at that as a
challenge and it will be but now the
problem is now that you're managing you
are one of many needs you no longer are
opening and closing tickets you are now
in a somewhat gooier space you are also
a cost center now and some of you may
understand that inherently I will talk
about this in a little bit
you have new metrics there are new ways
by which we determine how valuable you
are to your organization when you are
pen testers like imagine it rain shelves
and you know yay you're a genius
right now let's Wow yeah and I talked to
people who are security managers and
they talked about how weak pen testers
they were and I once went yeah I want
Allstate and football and he's looking
he's glaring at me it's like it's the
same conversation just different context
stop talking about your previous
achievements that's not your job anymore
and if you go and do a pen test as a
security manager that's a stupid idea
for mobile reasons one you're too
expensive - you're not letting the new
pen testers get some experience and
three you're supposed to be doing other
things so it's a strange new landscape
you're in you have new friends you have
UF now you have people like me you knock
in the door and say hey I would like to
be your friend for money that doesn't
sound right
actually it's very much what I do except
I get I get I get it in check so I don't
get it left on the the nightstand okay
so what got you here isn't going to work
anymore
there's a difference between good at
finding exploiting bugs and doing
security for your organization you have
a lot of things you have to watch
you're not the line cook anymore you're
the expediter you're the chef you have
to make sure that everything meets a
certain level you have to worry about a
whole bunch of other things a little bit
even if there's someone else who's MIT
supposed to worry about that all the
time you have to worry about them and
the thing you have to work with others
you have to explain yourself you have to
justify your existence you have to put
findings in context this is hard this is
really hard it's hard enough when I
watch pen testers try to explain how a
CVS s-10 means something and then
explaining it to a non-technical manager
at
Our client and they get angry but it
means total fucking ownage it's like
well except it's not yes it's a
vulnerability and you should fix it if
you can but does it affect their
day-to-day business and I remember one
this is several jobs ago where someone
found a phone and it was in the
application to reserve specific machines
in the in-house gym at the company and
pen testers like look I can randomly
assign things is like Wow Wow yeah you
did oh my god you made it rain shells so
that means that you could completely
take over the Nautilus system you could
take over availability of the Nautilus
system he's like but it seems like
that's great it was a web app but like
someone made in like 12 minutes and yes
it hits all 10 of the OWASP top 10 but
it doesn't matter because it's still no
one's gonna hack sir it and the gliders
I can't but no one cares right like ok
yes you have now Maldonado's machine is
owned by wal dongs you win but no one
cares put it in context so new game new
rules everything that brought you here
that confidence you had as a really good
security engineer is now 5% of your job
you know the language you could go back
and talk to the engineers but you're now
a people person please someone get that
reference so it's no longer cool to be
Punk as fuck as fun as it was as fun as
it was to be that lead guy or gal
doesn't matter your tools our resources
attention and buy-in and I find that
when I do occasionally do interviews and
people ask what pool sets do are you
familiar with my PowerPoint and
conversation oh so social engineering
like yeah close enough um
yes I still know how Metasploit works I
still like I still you know remember
many of the flags for nmap but that
doesn't matter it's now I have to get an
organization and people in that
organization to pay attention they're
doing this out takes time and you don't
have much of it your department or your
organization needs things you need money
you need a budget you need resources you
might need software but most importantly
you just might need attention from the
rest of the organization and this is the
em I hate leading with fear because
that's what we're that's what we as
security people do but I've met people
who didn't get this and they isolate
themselves and they still remain being
that I say no all the time and that must
feel really good except then your job is
when there's a breach what happens to
you you go bye-bye look we fix the
problem it was Bob we got rid of Bob and
we assure you that the problems will be
fixed so you had a job and your job was
to be the sacrificial lamb so you are a
minister without portfolio this I'm
thinking of a specific friend of mine
who got to be the security director at
his firm and I asked so you've got a
promotion yep what's your budget I don't
have one
how many direct reports do you ask I
don't have any oh we don't call that a
promotion you committed your now yet
yeah you got a raise good job so you
have minimal hard power you can't make
anybody do it damn thing you're the
small budget or no budget you have not
much actual Authority right you and if
you have to use it you have none that
never test it and let you never test how
much actual authority you have because
you may find out how little you have you
demand someone get fired and you realize
nope so few staff but all is not lost
you have soft power soft powers persuade
of power you can see you can get other
people to say things like look refer to
you know come to me when you have a
security question the security person
said this and you get them to say this
if you have to say it you're kind of
weak if you get them to say it security
person said we needed this when you're
talking to IT when you're talking to HR
when you're talking to other groups and
you have allies you don't know about and
I like this joke strangers or friends
you just haven't met so making friends
and explaining yourself and this is the
fun part recognize that details about
security can be deadly technical details
we eat sleep and breathe them as
engineers as in the management space
they just get boring the people who
don't care really don't care and the
analogy I come up with is it's like a
refrigerator how many people here know
what kind of refrigerant the
refrigerator uses how many people one
two okay however for most people when
they buy a refrigerator are worried
about things like the warranty does it
sit with the rest of the deck or in my
kitchen is that one of those the freezer
on the top of the freezer on the bottom
you care about things that matter to you
and the technical details are locked
away under a container under a cover
that says no use of user service of
parts inside in a way that's how you
should be talking about security when
you're talking to non-technical people
you're talking about benefits and
capabilities not how you do it
bike shedding can slow you down getting
hyper-technical with the few people who
might be able to go with you sidebar
that shit have a conversation with just
you two and and come up with a organize
come up with your your your joint
solution before you board the hell out
of everybody else before you get bogged
down in details that mean that you lost
time to convince people about budget and
violent agreement can stop you dead
that's where you have two people who are
arguing such fine points they don't
matter and if if you can figure out a
way to not do that tell me how because I
find it all the time talking with my
fellow security people but it's you want
to very quickly get to a consensus where
there are details you haven't worked out
sidebar them put them aside but move on
and this is what I like when you're
talking about budgeting a check box
check really hard doesn't check other
boxes we need a firewall this is a super
awesome firewall it's going to eat up
ninety five percent of our budget don't
buy it then because you just do it I
checked it real hard and it doesn't
matter right sometimes it's handled is
ten times better than an explanation
like try to explain the details of your
IDs to the nice people in HR
and what they wanted to hear was got
that handled once once you've built a
some level of trust with them like good
because they have 95 other things they
want to deal with and you're talking
about packing inspections like they're
just gone right you want your wannabe
able to report in like here's the things
that I do that you care about so taken
care of trust me if you have specifics
ask but even then when they when they
ask still keep it simple you know the
executive level which is three bullet
points and two of them are oxygen is
needed for life and I like money so you
know that's the one remaining bullet
pass understand motivations why do
people care about what you're doing
understand their motivation why all of a
sudden are the people from legal talking
about our DLP huh all of a sudden you
come down to my pit and ask me questions
instead of going well or deeply worried
and not in a confrontation way but like
a you seem to have a problem
I'm not even tell you the solution I
want to understand your problem
why do you have these questions about
DLP and if you can do this any in a
diplomatic and friendly enough manner
they will give you their problem and
have you solve it which makes you win
because now you have power over some of
your environment understand your own
motivations - I'm thinking of every
security person I know and this is an
early on where they're still like I will
be the bad cop I will get people fired
for not following the information
retention policy and you're like and
realize if you have a cop fetish save
that for at home with your significant
other and not real law enforcement so
natural allies this is the first group
of people who are going to want to help
you
they're the strangers you haven't
they're the friends you haven't met yet
they generally want what you want they
don't know it yet they may not want
everything you want they may care about
one small slice of your portfolio
because you are one small slice of their
portfolio but they care about that thing
figure out what that thing is and help
them help you because one person asking
for I need this really expensive piece
of technology the example I come up with
is DLP I walked a client through this
and the security person wanted deal be
Thomas is that the DLP solution they
wanted was something like worked out to
be about 8% of their annual IT budget
yeah and it's like oh it's like we're
women now now it because you need to
make this other people's problems at
well there are other people out there
who also want DLP they just didn't know
it yet and we got them like what do you
mean like okay regulatory affairs
compliance because there's a healthcare
organization like oh wait whoa whoa it
this will solve this problem
yeah Oh we'll find a budget for it and
all of a sudden it's not 8% of the IT
budget it's one half percent of some
other budget as well I'm like okay solve
like go make friends don't complain to
me that you can't get a cheaper DLP
solution I'll do that I'll find one
but maybe there's money elsewhere you
just have to go make a friend to go look
I have this problem like oh we have that
same problem with that well that thing I
don't care about the details I don't
care about the refrigerant in the
refrigerator I promise my beers remains
warm you know like well I can make your
beer cold I can make you not worry about
data leaving the premises problem is
easier to solve now so they may not
understand your problem you have to
figure out a way to explain to them how
if it is their problem and not in a
stampy way in a let me understand your
problems and when I hear the words data
all of a sudden I'll pay more attention
they may not want your exact solution
god forbid and this is one of those
things those of you who are going to go
into technical sales I will teach you an
evil trick never talk to IT people talk
to the people who can make the IP people
do things go talk to HR go talk to legal
I have watched solutions get rolled that
we're like who who bought this product
oh well HR made us like because you let
the HR person in a room with a
salesperson from Symantec did you check
to see how many fingers were left but
like you bought whoo oh right and it's
like so if you do technical sales go in
that direction go find it avoid the IT
people until the last minute like oh by
the way I need I need eight you in this
rack who are you and why see this this
is a signed statement of work see ya
okay so you want to do is you want to
able to talk to the other groups to say
what are your problems that visit the
data and if you if you're that no guy or
gal you're going someday you're going to
show up and there's going to be like
what's that box what's it doing in my
data center and it's too late you didn't
make a friend early enough you guys
you've got a solution crammed down your
throat by another department because the
salesperson cut you out so examples of
people these are your natural allies the
first core people who generally are
going to want things you want risk
management if you're big enough because
probably you have insurance policy for
data breaches what determines the cost
the premium your controls so risk
management if you can go and say what
controls are required hey wait a minute
I do this it's going to cost me $10,000
for that control and we'll save the
company maybe $25,000 in premiums
everybody looks like a hero talk to them
HR HR has compliance needs and usually
if you go and say I can solve that for
you or I can help solve I can partially
solve that for you I'll get that fixed
yay legal go make friends with a lawyer
are all the lawyers because they're
worrying about things and oftentimes
they there's a natural divide between
the legal side and the technical side I
know I went to law school and I I think
I repaired more laptops and pulled more
viruses out in three years of law school
than I did as Pena didn't like 10 years
of straight IT and Skippy there's a
problem though all those groups have
something in common and relax talk about
corporate real politic all those groups
have those natural allies that first
core people would probably want what you
want or want things that you want are in
similar
constraints they are cost centers legal
doesn't make you any money HR doesn't
make you any money they prevent losses
but it's akin to I often my wife often
says that our cats prevent bears because
there are no bears in our house but
there are two cats that is something we
say to our cats because it's amusing but
as a cost center it's hard to say well
we can prove that the our house is bear
free because of the cats the cats are a
cost center they bring us no revenue
legal brings you no revenue you bring no
revenue you are fighting for that same
kind of budgetary pool for other stuff
you are fighting December security is a
product enhancement nobody once is often
a real problem our wants to pay for or
even once to think about I had an
argument about early safety safety
engineering in u.s. cars 1950s Ford gets
the idea of we're going to sell safer
cars make it an option called the life
guard package it's going to be soft
dashboards collapsible steering wheels
and seatbelts and why didn't it sell hmm
cost Mart but the other problem was what
does it make you think when the
salesperson is talking about things like
things are going to bash your head into
are things that are can prevent you from
hurting yourself this is this car unsafe
like no it's we're making it safer if
you buy these options all of a sudden
you no longer friendly up it's now a
creepy conversation it took years and
and Volvo to very very effectively make
safety a selling point security is often
not a selling point because all the
sudden it makes you feel squeaky so
second group of people you should be
looking for our influencers outside of
your natural allies your first
to group are those natural allies they
think like you but their cost centers
and their their people you'll have the
most interactions with so let's talk
about influencers revenue generation
groups sales and product if you're in a
if you're at a software company or
you're in a manufacturing company you
have product that may or may not have
had security aspects salespeople if
they're selling your services and
security is a part of those services
they are also natural people you want to
talk to then you have senior management
and then you have customers or business
partners so sales people their outward
facing they don't they spend most of
their time talking to people who are not
your co-workers they're talking to
customers they have good insights into
what the customers as a whole want so if
you have to modify product or if you
have to modify the way you provide a
service they're the best people to get
an actual finger on the pulse to know
what customers want they have influence
I mean Turin sales for a reason right
they're good at influencing people
they're bringing in revenue a sales /
you go to you go to senior management
say I need this thing salesperson says
our customers say this and the customer
who asked for at last brings in 1.2
million dollars worth of revenue a year
all of a sudden you put a price tag on
security that you can't do that
salesperson did because what are you now
afraid of you're afraid of that customer
walking they can help for general
awareness how important is security to
our product if your sales force calm
pretty much because well no one wants
their pipelines leaking many you know
they can say things like many of our
customers are concerns you're talking
theoretically I think our customers
should be concerned that
how do you know you don't talk about you
don't talk about stuff the salespeople
talk to them on a regular basis and know
the elements that they want their
product and then specific ones if a
customer is asking for an external code
review that's helpful
that gets you leverage to go get that
external code review that you wanted
sales concerns here the problems you're
going to run into what they're worried
about they're worried about sales
friction hey I just sold this thing or I
got a meeting with the head of HR for
our HR is product yay someone's going to
make a commission security caveat slow
the pace from initial meeting to when
they get to get a commission check and
if you can somehow make it easier to
talk about security and make it easier
to say yes we're secure in a way that
convinces that customer you've reduced
sales friction which is very important
to the salespeople maybe even a sales
advantage I've not seen this too often
but it can happen where we are more
expensive than our competitors but let's
talk about your security does the
security matter about you you're now
playing the volvo game right hey we do
the same thing everything else does but
chance are we have a lower chance of
killing you
so what great way of selling a lot of
products however you may have to write
marketing copy explaining our security
in a page with some icons to people who
didn't take a math class ever in their
lives this is fun I do this now I did it
for one client and now other clients
like hey I saw this like yeah I wrote
that do you want me to write it about
you sure and sometimes it's like a hey
that reduce sales friction or I got
someone who's like hey you seem to be
better at this than the competitors
guess what
you just made security more valuable you
made it a value add into the product so
talk about the product side people this
can be these are your engineers who are
developing your software service or
maybe they're actually making product
they'd like to have secure product most
engineers care about this but they
promise will be in the next sprint are
in the next release are we promise
before the heat death of the universe
right because it's like hey we should do
security it was like yeah we should do a
lot of things so sort of looking at
their scrum board going whew that's a
lot of work yep security yeah that
that's going to go in there right so
their fears missing a deadline
dear God we blew that deadline we're
late to market against her competitors
who rolled out a version so they're
afraid of that they're afraid about not
at it hey we can either add this what we
think it's a competitive feature or your
debt security noise you're making about
huh and it's a hard sell so how can you
help you can help them define rank
understand security needs you go like
okay you came up with your whole laundry
list we need to do these 87 things and
they go like like no ok let's let's
prioritize these we really need to do
these three these three are like gotcha
and you have to now now now you're
you're you're negotiating you're working
it out and you could basically it sounds
like you are giving up a little bit but
what you do is you're getting those
three things in make them count
so senior management these are you know
cxos VPS and the like they can be
concerned about security I have had
those conversations and sometimes they
are absolutely painful because you most
people got to senior management did not
come up through engineering there are
exhales people are at a particular
investment shop I did some work for they
were ex investment officers and talked
about security I watched their eyes
glaze over so either like how do i
bullet point this how do I get this down
to one or two bullet points about these
are the things you need to do the
problem is is that they're concerned
about a lot of things I'm having a
conversation with somebody they have
five deals in flight for more than 20
million dollars they maybe have
something else they're worried about and
I'm trying to slot my security concern
somewhere in there so I get I get very
little of their attention even when I'm
in the room with them because they're
still kind of running through things in
their head the problem is is that I have
to explain things in terms they can
easily digest and they're going to make
a snap decision that's always the great
way of doing something very very
detailed right I just do that so sell it
to them as cost risk loss quantify it
even if you have to be a little even if
you have to make some good guesses make
good guesses but explain it to them in
terms they understand don't talk about
total ownage don't talk about a breach
and what say we will lose customers we
think will be worth this it will cost
this much to remediate ok these are
prices I can understand it will cost X
amount of dollars to roll the solution
and I think it reduces our chances and I
realize that you're there's a lot of
assumptions in the middle of that but if
you speak it in those terms they can at
least grapple the problems that are
easily distracted right one of their
other bigger problems that 20 million
dollar deal might start getting shaky so
they're going to veer off and they might
just group they might just say like yet
do that thing like oh great you know the
story I there's a I think of like the
ultimate member senior management would
have been Joseph Stalin and there's a
building in Moscow that is two different
architectural styles because they had
two different sets of plans Stalin was
drunk and so there's there's like you
know dots of wine on the on these two
plans and they're overlapped and he
signed across them
[Music]
nothing this way you're the project
manager going but Comrade Stalin which
Stalin is drunk Stalin is hungover
Stalin has sent people to the gulag for
less than this so I build it as he said
so it's one design and then breaks to a
second like why that way like no one
wanted to go to senior management as for
a clarification so we did the thing so
never invoke senior management with an
absolute plan in place where they can
just go and say okay yeah that works
fine make sure it's reasonable well if
you go and want to spend 25% of the IT
budget you're going to get some looks
and make it sane and you may make some
compromises in before you talk to them
but have a plan in place you can just
say I have a solution trust me all we
need is you to go uh-huh
sign here done so the final group of
people who can help you get what you
need are your customers and business
partners this is dangerous
but it can be very helpful so they can't
have a lot of influence one of your
customers says we want this thing
well this customer said we want this
thing because there's an either are we
may walk we may not Rio we may not use
you for everything we were going to use
you for it's tricky to work with because
you can't admit too much case in point I
have a I had a client at a previous gig
who had um they did no automated testing
of their application their model was we
peer reviewed it and it was like so
really it's if it compiles is good well
yes but okay and they had cook they had
a one of those make-or-break
kind of clients a client that we will
probably be sixty percent of your
revenue if we sign so the salespeople
like I really want the sale and you can
tell because I look on the sales persons
laptop and they're pricing out
boats that's a sign that says someone
things a deal is in the making like all
yeah and they're not small boats they're
like 45 footers like you Oh someone's
someone's get something's making some
serious cash okay I see now why you're
asking me can you change this in the
vendor assessment document I'm like I'm
not going to lie I mean I will give you
the best version of the truth I will
answer the question but do you do
automated testing of the application I
can't say yes if you're not and we had
this conversation of the client and the
client said look we really want your
application we want this tool we have an
app scan license we will scan your
application for you and I'm like an app
scan license this syria's cache so
you're gonna - so we can check yes we do
automated scanning you're gonna pay for
it yes we're willing to do that like I
take the money and run and do it that
was the way a very carefully because I
didn't want to say no we don't do that
well how do you know it how do you know
your codes not vulnerable like no would
you like me to lie and say it looks
secure for where I'm sitting but instead
it's to say you really okay you want
this I'm willing to overlook I'm not
willing to overlook it I'm willing to
help you meet our standards and so
that's where we got to right they offset
costs we we want you to do things this
way well that's more expensive fine
we'll pay or you know we love your
product is it HIPAA compliant no and
sometimes that's a well thank you for
your time we're going and sometimes the
customer may say what would it cost to
make it HIPAA compliant okay twenty
percent more okay you're still cheaper
than competitor X okay now you're in
your business guys here you now have you
know the healthcare client now you can
sell more of them and sometimes you go
and you use that for
client to then go back to your
management and say look it's going to
cost us this to ramp up for this new
market but the enthusiasm of that
regulated client because none of the
other tools they have that are HIPAA
compliant do they like maybe let's you
can sell this that we're going to spend
on on making it compliant is worth
getting into the market don't view it as
it's going to cost us X amount of
dollars to do this client think of this
it's going to cost this X amount of
dollars to get into this market and if
we get another healthcare provider it's
half as much it's all about how do you
characterize the expense we have to do
this thing we're not in no way did we
say yeah we're help we're HIPAA
compliant and not do the thing we're
figuring out a way that we can offset
the cost and sell it to our own
management to say we're going to do the
thing here's a way of making it
stainless so building coalitions
recognize these may be temporary
alliances HR once a thing and you want
to think you can get together and say
look maybe it comes out of both of our
budgets
maybe groups together can go petition
the powers-that-be
and get the buy-in we need the problem
is is that just because you're working
together on this thing maybe you also
want to do more restrictive policies and
a charge like nope so you have to
recognize we want this thing together
you're now you opposed us on this other
thing so coalition's are shifting
alliances this isn't Game of Thrones but
this is instead a you and I want this
thing we will work together on this
thing we will reserve that other
conflict for a later date
[Music]
fragile connections though sometimes can
make the this this a little ugly where
you decide that maybe maybe the other
side wants something that is really
really really inefficient or is bad or
broken or it's not the tool you would
ever suggest are suggest to your worst
enemy
and they're fought on it maybe you just
let the coalition die and don't get the
thing you try again later
decided to not rock the boat can make
the good pretty damn bad I'm thinking of
a client of mine this was act we came in
after and they had bought like the wrong
product for 2fa and it didn't work for
about 30% of their environment it's like
well who bought this well we fought it
and they went ahead of when did it
anyway it's like so now we have to make
it work for the remaining 30% of our
environment oh this is ugly but they
screwed up they basically let the
coalition broke and the coalition kept
running with it so takeaways people
generally want to do the right thing the
promise they have their own priorities
they have their own budgets they have
their own interests and often times they
will serve their own interests before
they serve yours and they will just let
your interest security fall by the
wayside
however skills learned here once you
learn these skills you can apply them
elsewhere so questions you bring that up
when you've actually rolled the product
because I'm thinking of the people I
know who have said that and I'm thinking
of an old co-worker mine who one we
don't need to buy this enterprise-grade
product we can roll our own
and two and a half snows a year and a
half later we finally rolled our own
custom coded DHCP server and I'm still
wondering like why did we roll our own
DHCP server that cost us we initially
budgeted twenty thousand it was like two
hundred and seventy-five thousand
dollars because we didn't want some
enterprise grade one so you can bring
that up when you're done because you're
open-source or your I can I can make
something else work for cheaper and
better only works that that argument
only works when you've done and like
look I shipped it and even then the only
people who really care will be your
fellow techies and maybe some maybe
you've been able to liberate that budget
if that bullet point goes on your resume
and you sell up a net for in eighteen
months when you go for another job has
saved my company a lot of money yeah
have you been asked yet
okay because the you your initial
initial you have to gain their trust and
the way you do that is by being
approachable because usually usually
I've helped people get back from after
they've done this the wrong way the
wrong way is to say no that yet the
words
that's stupid um you're wrong are should
not be in your vocabulary there's a
better way to do this I think we can do
I think we can meet all of your needs
and make it secure security is an add-on
like a paint job we know what isn't but
them you want to make it like look we
can do all the things plus this one ways
if you have the time is help them solve
their problems and just slide security
in do you need help evaluating those
vendors I found three vendors for this
that fit our budget and seem to be well
regarded and you pack in the security
capabilities you like in there so that
way you are being helpful to them you're
helping them with vendor selection and
you're adding a condition is one way the
need for security to be involved early
is I've another talk about this because
it's the idea of hey we bought this now
secure you're like ah that's the last
time I could have been of help and said
you want to be early in so you're
talking like hey let me help you do
vendor selection let me help you get
requirements and you so that way your
acting is like a general purpose IT
person and most of us in security can be
a general purpose IT person let me help
you figure out what our requirements are
in needs are if you like I'll go talk to
you know say for example it's like a
finance for cat you know a finance
application if you like I can go talk to
finance and see what they liked and
don't like about their existing product
and now what you're doing is you've
you've a part of a solution and do
things you're doing one is you are
taking stuff off of their plates that
isn't security related you are showing
that you are open and available and you
are showing that you're a part of the
team right I'm being helpful I want to
help I want us all to succeed and you're
not mr. no that's it's it's
also the whole bit like I thought you
were busy like not too busy to not screw
this one up you know yeah if you come to
me was like I got that virus again now
I'm too busy but $800,000 spend on a
finance package or I want to be at least
at one of those meetings they're not
pulling away yeah okay um it depends
because sometimes I found this is that
you don't know what that other person
does until you absolutely need them I've
been both the guy who said why is that
jackass around and I've been watching
people like playing me going why is that
jackass around see if you can cuz if
you're the managers see if you can put
that that the questionable person in a
position where they have to perform and
if they succeed you get to share the
rest of team like see Janice you thought
all you also thought Janice was was you
know not competent see how she pulled
that out of the fire and you're like oh
wait a minute be like oh are and that
could be something that's like exactly
her specialty like yeah I reverse --is
malware like it like a savant and but
has that you know can't can't like fix a
tcp/ip problem you're like okay there
there's a piece of malware why does it
do the thing that does and you know when
eight hours later she pops out a report
it's like say like oh that's why we have
her go to her for that thing it's that
it's that like showing everyone else's
skills and if she falls over you go well
that's now a learning experience for her
to go like see you're not pulling your
weight maybe you should figure out
something else you can do
to pull the weight can't like put people
to the test
not in an artificial mean way it's not
like hey you got to go pen test the
system where's my laptop oh we found you
a special one best in 1999 there babe go
like oh gosh yeah you want it you want
to put them make it make them work there
so that way they prove the rest of the
team that they're competent or not let's
decide it for time cool thanks so much
[Music]