okay I'm just gonna go hello everyone
welcome thank you for being here how's
the conference going so far I missed out
the morning good quality I see couple
thumbs up nodding the free coffee house
right good job Tyler so so I'm here to
talk to you today about measuring up the
casinos real-time intrusion detection
systems so what does that really mean so
I'm here to talk to you today about
measuring the efficacy of real-time
intrusion detection systems so what does
that really mean
idf's is actually not a new technology
right people here have heard of snort
and I could do a quick Wikipedia if I
leave it up for somebody here in the
audience to do that but it's been around
for a while I want to say since at least
the late 90s early 2000s honey net honey
would net project has been around for a
while too and so those two specific
domains all about looking at network
traffic right what's going on in the
network and obviously that matters to us
because we have information systems that
we need to protect we live in an
increasingly connected world it seems
like it took a while for news media to
catch on and a lot of people usually
reference target or even Sony but since
some of those major attacks happen on
name-brand
stores that we take advantage of every
day through commerce it seems like every
couple days on the news whether it's
reddit the register even the Guardian
New York Times Wall Street Journal you
name it some venue out there is covering
some sort of cyberattack and nowadays
folks don't even go to media outlets for
the insider information or to get not if
I quickly go to Twitter right and we
follow folks in the field one person I
tend happen to follow called malware
unicorn was recently listed as one of
the infrastructure professionals to
follow
and the reason why I follow her on
Twitter was one of her tweets was egg on
a long flight home
I created a packet analysis coding in
Python on a plane so these are the
people that are actually leading the
field right and these are the people to
pay attention to and why is that because
these technologies that have been around
for a little while
may not necessarily be keeping up to
date with the evolution of attacks why
is that data everyone's heard the term
of Big Data before and what does it mean
data is contact space right so in other
words the value of the information you
have from the data depends on how you
look at it and what's important for you
and of course how you analyze it so
we're going to talk a little bit about
that today and the application of
machine learning techniques to data to
better detect analyze and ultimately
prevent network based attacks
this is important because it's no secret
that there's a shortage of information
security professionals out there and
even if you were to throw a whole bunch
of people at the problem which is great
because then there's jobs and you know
salaries increase as well right based on
demand it's a market solution we all
know that attackers out there are
becoming increasingly automated right I
would argue that attacks nowadays don't
really happen in isolated pockets they
obviously do but increasingly we're
seeing patterns of automation and an
assembly line approach to cyberattacks
and so as cyber security professionals
our jobs to try to analyze the data and
come up with actionable intelligence as
quickly as possible and in a relevant
manner so that we can better protect the
business
so a little bit about myself I do not
consider myself to be a programmer
though I'm familiar with scripty
technologies my bread and butter is to
be presented with a business problem and
then solve it I'm that guy that figure
stuff out how many of you in here is
that person I would argue that everyone
is that person in this room otherwise
you wouldn't be here at this conference
I'm just lucky that you happen to come
to my talk but the reality is and this
is how I view information technology and
securing information systems it's kind
of like a game like a board game
if you ever sit down and try to play a
game I picked up Skype on Kickstarter
it's a great game if you haven't heard
of it look it up and when you first look
at this board game or any board game you
see the board the way it's laid out some
of the artwork maybe some colors and
then you start to think about it
like what's the objective of this game
what are the pieces involved what are
the mechanics right and then you play
the game once you get your butt kicked
right like it was kind of rough I kind
of don't get it then you play the game a
second time and a third time and it
starts to click it starts to make sense
you start to see maybe how you lost and
why you lost
maybe search strata yeah strategize a
little bit and before long through
practice who starts to become an expert
in that system in my opinion this
applies to my person from information
technology and how most people approach
information technology but the tricky
part is because of data how do we do so
in a manner where we can react quickly
to the emerging threats that exist out
there and the state of change so a
little bit about myself I'm currently
the chief information security officer
for the Department of Financial Services
a state government agency has anybody
here had experience in the state
government agency or currently works
whenever contracted with one how quickly
do they adopt to change numbers pretty
accurate
so DFS has been on the news lately for
passing a reg requiring regulated
financial entities to have a dedicated
security program and one thing that they
realize is that the house needs to have
one as well so that's what I got hired
to do and so being at their government
agency they're not in the forefront of
security and not actively looking at
project products out there and the
trends about what's happening and so
with 16 years of IT experience 10 years
of InfoSec for a number of local
companies it's only recently that I went
to New York City I've had my finger on
the pulse and so when I was at
University of Albany I applied for the
PhD program and I had a very specific
research idea in mind in this
presentation and paper that I wrote is
about this research idea it's a little
bit of background so we're concerned
with the confidentiality integrity and
authorization / authentication of
network communications so making sure
that information systems that exist in a
business are available function as
expected and of course with idf's
technologies right understand detect
record any attempts to circumvent
controls right so some businesses
especially government agencies may or
may not have a policy in place
fortunately there's an enterprise iso
office Navis civil policies so it
becomes a starting point from there we
develop standards procedures and you
bake that into a technology to derive
value right because it's an investment
typically I t's a cost center so we want
to maximize that investment in other
words IT isn't cheap especially you're
paying for support or contractors and
obviously we know that firewalls work
pretty well
Check Point has a wonderful firewall
system I'm familiar with that because I
used to administer it for the Public
Service Commission they even make it so
simple there's a GUI I don't have to
play around on the command line like I
used to do back in my Albany med days
where everything was just one line
scripts and you would feed it through
so as things have changed over time we
have wonderful GUI systems that also
means that if you have port 80 open for
a web traffic and communication
obviously that could be a potential
exfiltration point how many of you are
actively monitoring web communications
all right and so we typically rely on a
managed service provider to do that for
us but if someone we're browsing the web
for say Sourcefire and an activity
occurred where the onu is switched is no
longer Sourcefire right that could
potentially bring you to a different web
server would you be able to detect that
would you be able to respond so the
reason why I bring that up is because of
the final bullet context aware computing
so the ability to discover and detect
changes in the environment and I would
say unexpected changes in the
environment so you probably have a
background on this there's a lot of text
on this slide but we're concerned with
Network protocols right TCP specific
sequence that were communications
redundancy checksums
user datagrams we don't really care
about the data being sent out and back
to us in the order right video streams
things of that nature and of course ICMP
I frequently find in environments where
I've been an administrator in security
administrator that ICMP is often not
configured to be either rejected or
controlled in a specific manner so ICMP
is more than just a packet most people
are familiar with that from a ping
perspective it's actually an entire
protocol suite that could potentially be
abused and often is so for this
particular research idea I want to look
at these three protocols some more
definitions in background intrusion
detection where you spoke about that a
little bit detecting actions a
compromised CIA of a resource right and
most importantly detect actions that
attempt to subvert so that's good but
that's only half the pie right
and so let me know if this situation
scenario is familiar you're at a company
and they know that having IDs be able to
detect often a networks a great idea so
they go through a list of vendors right
and maybe they're going through several
vendors and have some interesting demos
and dog and pony shows and after
listening to how they describe the wares
and how the offerings will work in their
environment they end up management
executive management ends up making a
choice based on the cheapest priced
supposedly 24 by 7 availability of
support supposedly ease of use because
the demo always works right and of
course the best company t-shirt design
who here whenever you see the Splunk
booth always runs for the free t-shirt
pretty good right marketing works so
finally the company picks an appliance
event or whatever and so the question is
what now what do you do with that can
you set it and forget it oftentimes the
company will simply outsource it because
that's the easy answer so what if
there's more to it and how do you even
know that the chosen ideas partner is
effective so four main areas that I have
found in my personal work experience
tend to be overlooked so a policy that
actually dictates effective monitoring a
response so are you actively looking at
the traffic what do you do when you see
something interesting how do you
prioritize that and respond
appropriately is there a definition of
an incident and once that threshold has
been reached how do you act on that
assuming that you've defined what it is
that it is and are taking steps to
handle it what's the forensic analysis
and data retention how's it being
handled and of course reporting how
useful is the information right are you
just simply getting an alert in a
mailbox no joke I used to work at a
company that I was added to a mailbox
and I would always get alerts that the
system was down
and I was like wow this seems like a big
deal you know look around the room and
like why isn't why aren't the system's
people running around like chickens with
their head cut off it was actually
really puzzling so I simply asked a
question like oh yeah it does that what
do you mean it does that
yeah our server monitoring just kind of
sends out pings and like whatever
somebody so how do you know if it's real
or not well if the users call and
complain literally that was their answer
I won't disclose who I was working for
when that happened but that's a true
story
so why did it go that way turns out that
they didn't train their people so there
wasn't people dedicated to actually
tuning the the appliance and I don't
think that's unusual I think a lot of
organizations do not actively invest
enough in training for folks to actively
realize the value of the systems they
put in place literally set it and forget
it so what are the different types out
there network based this is what this
talk is going to focus on but there are
others out there some that resided on a
post an agent that's configured we have
some examples up there and also you have
physical systems as well often will kind
of take that for granted anybody here
have an ID card you just hold up to a
door right anybody staying in a hotel
room tonight
right all examples even your wireless
key entry for your car but oftentimes it
may be the car is a bad example in that
regard oftentimes those systems have
monitoring in place right to detect
unauthorized attempts I can't tell you
any place that I've worked that where
they actively looked at locks to see hey
is there a regular instance of people
trying the store or trying a key I'm
pretty sure a place that I worked out
before name withheld had office services
out sort of cards and I'm convinced they
didn't even ask for the cards back I
know this because I still have my card
so you can't just set up the system
there has to be follow-through so what's
the next step beyond detection obviously
prevention
so we're talking about network based
attacks a network-based intrusion
detection the next step would be
intrusion prevention so hey we detected
an attempt at an intrusion compromise
let's prevent it from actually affecting
the host and of course like it so with
some best practices for this information
the monitoring is a big piece of
effective incident handling you have to
determine who's monitoring the systems
is an internal external if it is
external people doing the brunt of the
work is there a relationship with folks
on the inside internally is there
communication set up our emails being
sent
but being ignored and of course what
will you do once you get the alert and
who's going to fix a vulnerability it's
not good enough to still be alerted
that's to be a process and a flow that's
cyclical the handles us note that these
bullets aren't lists this type of linear
thinking in and of itself what actually
gets you in trouble I'll talk about that
in a couple slides and unfortunately
that's where the buck stops because why
bother detecting an attack in the first
place if there's not going to be
anything done about it it's not even
good enough just to mitigate the
vulnerability how do you learn from it
so it's not an action that's repeated so
you're not wasting time and resources I
don't know if any of you are aware but
time is not a renewable resource and if
you figure out how to make that
renewable you'll be rich
let's talk so it's important to know or
rather to determine how it's going to
happen establish a process to avoid
further exploitations understand how to
escalate and of course avoid further
incidents assess impact and damage and
of course recover appropriately and
finally update procedures as needed how
many of you walked into a workplace and
asked to see a knowledgebase article and
saw that maybe there were four or five
years outdated
anybody work into a support area and
they're like yeah we don't really know
how to help people when they're out in
the field so we kind of give them the
admin password that happens and so if
that happens how do you effectively
detect if someone is doing a privilege
escalation or for a regular end-user is
logging into a local machine and abusing
it you can at that point okay good so
how do you deal with this all it's
important to have an effective security
incident response ideally in a team
right where there's a team response
dedicated people who are not only
analyzing the data but are building
those relationships active documentation
meaning that there's a minimum quarterly
review why quarterly because it keeps
everyone on the same page as people
leave the organization and come into the
organization oftentimes they see that
information management is very tribal
maybe you have a really awesome manager
that says you know what you guys just
came on board I'm going to have you sit
with my senior people over here and
you're going to learn all the cool
things that doesn't happen as often as
it could be usually it's like hey here's
your desk figure it out
it's also important to have instant
coordination so that when people are
multiple people are trying to make an
interpretation of policy standards and
procedures
there's uniform application to an
incident obviously for forensic purposes
preservation and data is super important
and ultimately this comes through
experience you have effective
prioritization of a response and you're
aware of both internal contacts and
external contacts last week I was in New
York State cybersecurity conference and
if you attend that as well a handful of
you if he it was actually really solid
this year and I have a 10 in the past
three years and I don't say that every
year I'll just say that up front this
year the focus was actually quite
interesting I tended a presentation
that's
that incident response is actually 50%
IT the other half is a business that
starts to make sense when you start to
think about okay if there's an incident
and you find that a data breach has
occurred who do you contact first your
office of general counsel your public
information officer how do you contact
them how do you deliver that information
are they going to know what you're
talking about are they going to take you
seriously maybe they start freaking out
oh my god this is crazy
well yeah they got the USB key but it's
encrypted do they understand that right
there is a control in place so and of
course can you tell them specifically
how it happens to prevent in the future
so this is all part of an effective
security instant response so let's get a
little bit more so that's pretty much
all background let's a little bit more
into the the nuts on the boats nuts in
the bolts here so there's two main
detection techniques these are academic
terms right miss Houston anomaly but
really we know them as rule-based or
heuristic based right rule-based we know
what it is and so we have a signature
that can detect it and we're good
antivirus software works that way Auto
updates all the time anomaly based isn't
quite machine learning it's just looking
at patterns of behavior right like okay
given a set of executables on your
machine is one example let's detect for
buffer overflows right if data is being
inserted before after a boundary write
it is not a machine learning technique
but it's a heuristic looking at behavior
those are the two main technologies
they've actually been around for a while
but the interesting thing is they depend
largely on the people who are developing
those technologies there's no substitute
for human mind but recall that early on
this presentation one of the problems
that we have is a lack of trained cyber
security personnel and that need is only
going to continue to grow
whoops so try to make the text a little
bit big here this slide is actually kind
of important and actually grabbed it
from a blog when doing some research and
it really stuck with me it stuck with me
because often times we actually think in
lists right I have my to-do list over
here I've got my system of notation over
here sometimes it'll be a little bit
different maybe in the course of an
implementation you'll have maybe a Gantt
chart perhaps is put together by a
project manager hopefully you had some
input into that one implementation
schedule but attackers are unique breed
in their way of thinking and I would
argue and machine learning does this as
well depending on the algorithm I'll
talk about that in a couple more slides
graphs the Fenian graphs is important
and I don't mean graphs like a chart in
PowerPoint I don't have a chart here I'm
thinking more like graphs the
intersection of multiple points right so
here's an example so an attacker is much
more likely to attempt to attack a
domain controller associated with a
workstation that's already been
compromised and rather than one that's
in an off network segment so if you have
a remote access Trojan or maybe simply a
keylogger over time you just start to
collect the data right and then you
don't do anything with it for a while it
just so happens that often sensor your
way but then an attacker will start to
look at that data and we'll look for the
interesting nuggets right I need a
better example or simpler example is if
you have perhaps a single terminal
server with hundreds of users a terminal
server in and of itself isn't going to
give you a ton of access in the network
but if you start to be able to record
and actively collect credentials on that
terminal server you have a goldmine all
it takes is one privileged account and
you're good to go and so that's that's
not a new situation right because
they're just simply sitting and waiting
and then leveraging privilege
escalations go to the next step but the
reason why it's important to make this
point is attackers don't initially know
what they're going for
they know what their end goal is right
to compromise the network siphon the
data perhaps sell in the black market or
embarrass a company working for a for
whatever reason bragging rights
hacktivism you name it but the realities
are looking for any opportunity they
don't have a list of prioritization
right they're just going to try some
things out and see what works but
they're very disciplined in that
approach so they're not random so I
honestly can't take credit for this
quote browser browsing the web and I can
find out where it is but the point here
is with all that's going on it is super
important to automate as often and as
much as realistically possible to have
the computers do the work for you right
who here has used the lazy system and
website or any website when you're
looking for scripts bash PowerShell I
feel like you have some since I'm an
experienced your hands gonna go up even
if it's a little bit like this so if we
to grab coffee it's free but I wanted to
make this point because often times when
organization executives who don't have a
mind for the stuff and I'm not saying
that to be insulting I'm saying that
their priority is somewhere else in the
business right so so to ourselves
ascetical professionals whether were the
consultants ourselves or working in that
shop to make this point that it's worth
the investment and worth tuning that
investment so we realize that value
let's see so let stands for a literature
review I know this is Amanda's favorite
word so how do we measure efficacy right
measure is a key word so in the
application of testing something out
right we need something that's a
standard the knowledge knowledge data
knowledge discovering data mining
conference in a national conference back
in 1999
yes that's 18 years ago in conjunction
with the US Air Force simulated Network
attacks Oh
a nine week period and generated over
seven million events and not only do
they generate all that traffic all that
traffic every single packet and every
TCP stream is tagged and documented for
what's considered normal and what is
simulating an attack so what that does
is it creates a baseline super-helpful
now there's some issues with that I'll
talk to I'll talk a little about that in
a couple slides the glaring part is
obviously what happened in 1999 does not
reflect what's happening now 2017 but
it's still super useful and there's four
main categories that the stage is set
falls into so when coming up with the
new technology in understanding whether
or not actually has a positive impact
that's to be able to measure it so this
provides us a baseline in the standards
to do that so obviously with a denial
service unauthorized access either from
remote machine or through privilege
escalation and also the types of attacks
such as buffer overflow and probing
whether it's scanning a service on a
machine or scanning an entire subnet so
it is actually the current standard
believe it or not because there's
nothing newer to replace it so so when
you should make a phone call to air
force general I think to have the Air
Force Research Lab over in utica they
came to the conference last week in
cyber security so we should have had
that conversation hey guys let's update
the stuff the data side collection so we
have so I mentioned a couple attacks
earlier forming categories but there's
39 over all different types of attacks
but 22 are focused in a particular data
set over seven of the nine weeks so in
other words you want to look at seven
out of nine weeks worth of attacks to
standardize and see if you can catch
them and then there's two weeks of that
subset that is randomized so it provides
the dependent variable for the
independent variable there's also 41
different types of attributes so like I
mentioned they're all tagged
so why use it even though it's 18 years
old simple standard and you can measure
it but there are problems some features
actually have no relevance to intrusion
detection today for instance most people
would say hey we don't use FTP anybody
here using FTP maybe you are that's
right you don't you don't have to like
out yourself you don't want to say that
but most people are probably using SCP
or SFTP that's my point
anybody using telnet I hope not because
New York State Enterprise Information
Security office said if still it was
enabled on Cisco equipment even though
they had a patch out you're vulnerable
to an attack last month but you
shouldn't have telenet of available
anyway right because everything happens
in Playtex but you guys already know
this so so my point is some of this
information is included in that data set
that we would just say you know what we
have a policy in place no telnet in our
environment
no STP in our environment everything's
using either a secure channel
certificates IPSec whatever and of
course some of the features that they
have they're like number of file
creation operations you probably don't
care that file is being created right
you what you care about is to detect
that unauthorized intrusion before a
file was created whether that's an
executable being unloaded or data being
access to whatever and also some
features have grown in sophistication
and aren't being used anymore so
apparently they featured a piece of
malware called where's master
waa are easy and where's client I can't
think of anything in the recent past
that has featured that type of exploit
can you obviously some of the problems
with something 18 years old so will
benefit from from a serious update also
nmap so they actually have nmap scan so
nmap was being used in this data set 9
to 99 give up for nmap I don't know if
you saw that on Twitter they recently
updated it in time for the summer
code right and they were proud of
themselves because it was in time for
DEFCON so people can play around with it
I love nmap and what wasn't around in
1999 that is now is n Maps tcp/ip
fingerprinting technologies and
techniques which have been around for a
while but not eighteen years ago and of
course the nmap scripting engine and
wood modern IDs is IPS is be able to
detect that I don't know maybe but it's
tough to know for sure without a
standard data set that you can measure
alright and so I use it at all it's
because data classification matters so
ideally have online and offline network
intrusion detection we'll just assume
all online ideally what we're looking to
do is detect misuse and anomalies in the
network traffic with the tags you can
actually map those map those attempts so
let's talk a little bit about machine
learning a little bit of background the
algorithm that you use matters right and
the approach to the data that you use
matters you have Monte Carlo simulations
you have decision trees you have
supervised learning where people are
looking at the results of the algorithm
being applied and then tweaking it
accordingly you have unsupervised
learning where you just let the Machine
figure it out
right and you know good root world
examples are anybody watch any YouTube
videos of google's deepmind project
beating a go champion i think in the
past three months was its young Chinese
person to use nineteen years old I
forget his name and he was expected to
win and that didn't happen and notice
this trend over time right in the late
90s it was I B M's deep blue that one
chess right and I forget the number of
combinations of moves and chests
something like in the order of millions
but I know go is literally an order of
billions so it's really more complex
than chess and so in our lifetime this
is actually an important point in our
lifetime they did not expect artificial
intelligence to master a game like go
but that happened and that happened in
two years ago when they were proving it
out and happened more recently I think
in January this year with the go
champion so there's a benefit here
there's a huge benefit here to
understand what's going on a network and
prevent the bad guys from getting in so
here's an example of one technique
called information game I have this
example because this is the one that I
want to start with there's a reason why
the data doesn't decrease over time it
increases all day every day knots
oversimplification but there's actually
a mathematical formula do you guys
remember because you were in the Class B
for 412 last fall Ethernet right so if
you were to scan all or retain data from
a 100 megabit port for 30 days how many
gigs of space does you need
do you remember I don't look at my notes
before that and that's one well I think
one port is a neighborhood of Giga bytes
but an entire network was in the
neighborhood of terabytes so if you're
and that's not even a large network
we're talking probably small to mid-size
business if they were to retain just 30
days of network data they would
literally need terabytes of free space
today
it's the example that I'm bit on
remember off top my head comes from the
network security onion book published by
no starch press highly recommend that
book it's awesome and it actually gives
you a great introduction to ids/ips
technology because the distribution
network security onion is free and not
only can you set it up in a lab
environment but I encourage you to play
with it because it has Python baked into
it you can apply machine learning
techniques and you can also set up
sensors on the network and forward it to
a central server
so it's a free plug for that book but
it's worth your time to check it out
if you have been exposed to it before
and so the reason for this particular
algorithm is to look at data over time
as the information set increases and
continually look at patterns so the goal
is to determine how relevant each
Network feature network communication
network port is when using the junction
with data classification so that implies
that you would actually set a series of
rules kind of like okay we know this is
going to be okay we're okay with web
traffic out importing as one example so
no it's not a substitute for web
filtering but the goal is to determine
okay we know we see web traffic being
browse from our and user network but
maybe one day the system will catch web
surfing traffic or an attempt to connect
to a domain over port 80 from a server
that hasn't done so before in the past
30 days so as the best practice the
system admin shouldn't be serving
shouldn't be browsing the web for an
application server that could happen
maybe he forgot between the remote
sessions or maybe it's an attempt at a
compromise who knows an idea system
today may not actually catch that unless
you were to build some sort of rule in
place to do it specifically here what
I'm advocating for is that the
technology learns and says this is
abnormal behavior I haven't seen this
before snag it and alert as you build
confidence with the system you flip the
switch to prevent and so we take what
what was created with the kdd set and
build your own template for a list of
attacks and apply the machine learning
techniques to the data classification
and so I framed this in the form of a
research question because like I started
this presentation before this is an idea
for my PhD which I suspended to get this
wonderful job opportunity in New York
City but I hope to continue one day so
given the model for information gained
can we determine the efficacy today
using the KD d99 set and can we apply it
in the future and so I'm looking at
three different methods can we detect
the DDoS attack can we detect standard
usage of the Metasploit framework right
using modern-day vulnerabilities because
we know that using data from 18 years
ago might give us a baseline but is
inadequate and ultimately can we look at
12 different variables in a packet
header and determine if techniques are
being used that abuse whether it's that
abuse the network whether it's
firewalking
whether its port scanning things of that
nature and of course there's certain key
metrics to look for because we've got to
make sure that not only is it effective
in analyzing data but that the system is
reliable so looking at things such as
network performance whether knots
dropping packets CPU memory utilization
things of that nature
there's no point designing a system that
is a reliable and so for those of you
that spend a lot of time doing data
analysis TCP dumps things of that nature
this isn't new for you but this is a
visualization of a packet and each of
the components as they're built and so
ideally the system would look for each
one and that's possible because at least
with the IP protocol suite TCP UDP and
ICMP thanks to the RFC's that exists out
there everything is standardized how
does how do we go from a communication
here over to France well we can do that
because the network communication
follows a standard right the iso
reference model things of that nature in
the RFC
anybody here actually read any of the
rfcs handful of you would expect this
road to raise their hands because it was
assigned reading in spend fall ah anyone
want to take a guess the year that TCP
was released as a standard excuse me
1984 I actually don't know the answer
off my head but I know it was an early
eighties but that surprises people
because people are like not the internet
happened in the 90s and now networking
is happening prior to that and even
before email was a system they created
the Protocol SMTP to send messages email
as a system came after SMTP SMTP the
ability to send a message was literally
just a message like on your screen prior
to the email system that are also
predates to 90s there's a reason I bring
that up I encourage you to do it's
freely available it's actually just text
files as a library out there that IETF
publishes take a look at some of these
RFC's there's some good technical
information in there and the reason why
I mention that is because in those rfcs
or rules for how data communications
occur so if you know the rules of a
system where I go back to the game
mentality what can you do you start to
maybe play with those rules right maybe
see where things can be meant maybe see
how a system expects the communication
to arrive and how system expects to
receive it and of course how they
respects to send it and that's how you
manipulate it right so anybody knows
that well I shouldn't take for granted
I'll take a step back who here has ever
used a command line to send an email
message and actually type the SMTP
commands a couple hands cool I remember
when I first did that it actually kind
of blew my mind away because I took for
granted the fact that I would use an
email client a piece of software that
did it for me automatically
big fan of pine in the UNIX system and
when I did this simple exercise
2000-2001 way back in the day you guys
even born that eyebrows raised um it
blew my mind that this is what actually
happens behind the scenes and at some
point that I'm trying to make nowadays
everything is a screen everything is a
presentation right so what happens
underneath that presentation in the
layers is super important and I would
argue for the audience here most of you
are very comfortable getting in the
weeds but I think as newer generations
of InfoSec professionals come up through
the ranks
it's a crucially important to encourage
them to have that kind of exposure right
so beers is a hacker conference and if
you visit in the hacking lab today today
or tomorrow all right see a couple hands
I'll be honest I expected a couple more
hands to come up if you didn't have a
plan to go there go there and just ask
somebody have a conversation hey mind if
I check out what you're doing over here
and just see how they're manipulating
the data in the command line because
that sets you up for success not only to
understand what's happening behind that
presentation layer but to understand how
the systems are interacting so we'll
drive a little bit deeper so we saw this
is a visual representation of the TCP
packet here's the actual data points and
so these are bits and so there's
basically a numerical rule set that
creates these boundaries so these
boundaries are for us as human beings to
read this stuff and make sense of it but
it's literally bits zeros and ones and
it knows because of the RFC where the
boundaries start where the boundaries
end and how to make sense of it source
port where the traffic's going oh no
source port where the traffic started
destination port where it's going the
sequence number important for TCP things
of that nature so the goal will move
forward for a little bit is to look at
these twelve variables these components
in the TCP packet to see how the TCP
data stream which is a conversation from
start to finish
it occurs and if there's any abuse
happening between the line and if it can
learn this with a high degree of
confidence in a low enough error rate
have it take action on your behalf and
of course log it presents it to you
things of that nature so once again
Wikipedia is a great resource actually
probably half the definitions probably
have this presentation actually came
from Wikipedia just being honest but
it's a great resource for this stuff
I'll also plug YouTube how many YouTube
videos have I signed in classes at
UAlbany
and note pretty solid the gradual yeah
it kind of was well guess what to be an
intersect professional today you don't
need to university of albany probably
they're going to like this you don't
need to actually pay for very expensive
education you just have to have to drive
the desire and expose yourself to the
technologies out there udemy is a great
resource now you won't get a four-year
degree from udemy comm but they have
experts in data mining data
visualization hacking programming Linux
you get the idea here and some of these
courses you can pay for 10 50 bucks at a
pop and they have that trust system
right 7,000 people rated course XYZ
Python machine learning four and a half
stars all right maybe I'll learn
something here take my ten bucks and if
you dedicate six weeks to your life
you'll probably learn a thing or two and
the reason why that's an important thing
to say is because in places like the
Ukraine Estonia or parts of Brazil right
where people might have access to maybe
a computer that's ten years old but can
still function and there may not be a
lot of job prospects but they love this
stuff because it's fun and it's a game
for them and they like to learn um
they'll use the community the internet
community to help each other out I still
remember when I went to IRC back in the
day I don't know if there's a statute of
limitations in digital piracy but let's
just say I got very comfortable in
finding anime back on my new albany days
and that was my first exposure RC and
then from there I got more exposure to
script kiddies and techniques are being
passed around
free all I had to do is ask some
questions don't put some channels and
that was it
so back to the topic at hand
people out there are becoming
increasingly better equipped to scan and
attack our networks and so using an
effective algorithm and looking at
specific key variables in a packet I
don't know how all this Lots allows you
to build a system this is a network
diagram for potential system that starts
with an Ethernet port at the top and now
there's a boundary for online data and
you have a pre-processing phase where
you've sent the packets extract the IP
features look at TCP bless you look at
TCP UDP and ICMP packets why those three
packets because of the RFC there's a
different rule set and looking at those
packets you collect all that data and
parse it and separate the data in
records to be analyzed to look for those
twelve features those twelve key
variables so that's at the end of the
pre-processing phase once you've done
that and then you move on to the next
step which is classification so I'm
looking at all these packets and have
the entire conversation the TCP stream
or does it fit is this a normal traffic
is this a scan is this particular attack
vector whoops that was too fast I try to
scroll down and just advance the slides
and of course once it does a data
classification run the algorithm to
learn over time log it and then you have
the post-processing phase where over
time it starts to that little box that's
cut over in the bottom that's my pointer
right there starts to rate the
confidence right because the idea is at
least when the system is first designed
you're going to have to help it move
along as with any system I have still
yet to run into a piece of technology
that works straight up out of the box
even this Dell computer that I'm using I
didn't get paid to say that came with
you no bloatware I didn't want I also
had a configure window so wasn't giving
out all my crap you know with Cortana
I don't need your Cortana I like you're
there but no etc so the concept still
applies even here because as you look at
the data streams and classify it you
want to build your confidence with it
and so why does it matter so I'll say
this you guys would be like oh I usually
wait until 48 minutes in to say this
this idea or this concept isn't super
new anybody here heard of silence
alright anybody here heard of Verona's
Ronis looks at unstructured data on your
network helps you auditing things of
that nature they also have a PCP product
that they're plugging out I don't so
much about it silence is probably close
to lines what I'm talking about here
here's the deal though silence is an
enterprise product right you buy the
appliance it's a virtual machine since
on your network looks at all this stuff
and you know looks at the data it makes
intelligent decisions how many of you
have the budget of an enterprise
organization I saw two hands sweet I
didn't expect that so you might be able
to afford silence it might work great
and they keep and that is what I love
about the product actually they keep
bringing any attacker conferences and
encourage people to hack against it to
make their systems smarter
that's effing brilliant because people
are like yeah I'll do the challenge and
they're basically training their system
for free how many of you have a
smartphone pretty much everybody right
and even your mother maybe your
grandmother has one now right you've
been like you're rid of the flip phone
go to the iPhone we can do the FaceTime
and now you became their ad-hoc tech
support
are there any products that exist out
there for stuff like this for you and me
for Grandma who might fall for that
phishing email or that website that says
hey pay your 9mo bill for $250 and if
you don't I'm going to cut it off now we
know that happens sometimes in phone
calls and stuff for that but does
happening emails as well so my point is
you and me to average Joe person we
doesn't have the budget the two hand
is in the room do not have access to
stuff like this I would love to see a
product like this available for the
average Joe user they'll actually learn
and get smarter and better over time by
the way and I want to make it a point
about privacy the KB 99 data set is
anonymized so if a product like this
were to be developed and commercialized
maybe one day that'll happen for me I
don't know where my future my path will
take me yeah I would totally write that
into the privacy policy and say up your
data is anonymized I just want the
system alert smarter there's enough big
government out there and big industry
right especially now knowing that our
search histories can be sold right for
data I mean if you've got a VPN
subscription once that law was passed
yeah I'm sorry I went out for free yeah
yeah I don't trust it either I don't
take ahead of anything to hide but you
never know so anyway I guess that's
about it so that's my contribution I
love to present something like this
awesome for the average Joe person
because antivirus and malware detection
is pretty good but it's not going to cut
it over time so thank you I'm sorry for
board you in the first half but always
like to start with definitions and a
build-up to get to you know the meat I
don't want to lose anybody the process
any questions
that's a great question
I actually don't do not actively play
with existing technologies now I do know
that there's probably a lot of spunk
users in the room ish I'm a big fan of
spunk and it actually has to be tuned so
Splunk lets you build up obviously the
intake right and helps you standardized
an intake but I found that it's very
clunky to use and you can actually tag a
lot of the data and build dashboards so
basically it's not machine learning
because Splunk isn't getting smarter
over time but it makes it easier for
guys like you with me to look at that
data
so yeah I detect something weird here
because it matches the dashboard rule
right maybe it's SSH probing right maybe
it's maybe it's firewalking is there an
IP address doing sequential scanning you
know things like that so is there an
off-the-shelf product that does that now
I don't know once they're in the system
that we said they're not can we using an
exploit then I would say makes gotcha
then I would say make friends here in
the conference or maybe one of the
vendors let's have an incident response
team contact and that's valid and I
encourage that as part of the playbook
it's not only is it important to have
your team trained in to tune any
appliances you may bring in or
technologies you're using now it's also
important to communicate internally but
also to have those relationships in case
an instant response is necessary then
maybe outside the realm of what the or
where the team can handle
I hear Verizon has a pretty good team
they only put out that report once a
year so any other questions or even
comments
which that's something off you like free
beer ice cream but once again there's
free coffee everyone thanks for your
time appreciate being here this is great
[Applause]
[Music]