okay I'm a Ronnie ball I'm going to
present - I'm an the middle attacks and
virtualized environments if I don't take
out the screen first how many you guys
operate data centers in here or host
things in data centers in the cloud okay
quarters few of you good
how many vaccine variations in this talk
before I've presented this at Def Con a
few other places okay so I got a lot of
students in this room who've been there
kind of through the paces here a little
bit about me I have a PhD in computer
science from Clarkson University
actually the previous speaker was my PhD
advisor Gina Matthews and she's done a
lot of this over overseeing of this work
with me over the past four years so I
appreciate a lot of what she's done for
me I'm an assistant professor of
computer science at Utica College I
specialize in networking systems
administration information security
virtualization Linux UNIX and
voice-over-ip
I'm also a co-founder I remember the
board of directors for the central New
York hackathon which a lot of the people
in this room were participants of each
year you can get more information on
that see my hackathon org and I also am
the owner of principal consultant of
Adirondack IT solutions which is a small
independent consulting company for IT
work in the area also I do a lot of work
for the Air Force I love a research that
kind of stuff okay so a publication
history of this research goes all the
way back to Derby con 4.0 started when I
presented our neck flooding attacks did
some stuff with besides rock on 2015
DEFCON two times in a row and then we
had a publication in the journal
detailing the Mac flooding attack so
DHCP scenarios defended my dissertation
on the 29th of September and then
recently in February I was invited to
talk on this talk out in Norway at hat
cat which was a very great experience
and if any you guys get a chance to get
out there it's a conference worth going
out to and seeing and experiencing okay
so the road map we're going to just talk
a little bit about virtualization
multi-tenant environments cloud service
is just a high-level overview what they
are which most you probably kind of have
a good grasp on that by now talk about
the test platforms that were used for
this research
as well as a specific tax and results
we're going to talk about VLAN hopping
today and our poisoning
man-in-the-middle attacks and then
present some conclusions so the key
question we have multi-tenant
environments you're hosting data in
these environments you have multiple
virtual machines hosting these
environments and with that it is a
multi-tenant environment so you and
maybe your competitors are also hosted
within that same ecosystem so it's an
important question to explore because we
had these layer two devices that are
being virtualized and emulated in these
in these networks so layer 2 switches
for instance so do these layer 2 network
attacks that we've known that worked on
physical devices over the past say 20
years or more do they actually apply in
these virtualized network so that was
the basis of my research that was my
thesis question this is very important
to explore because you know all cloud
services that rely on virtualization
could be vulnerable to attacks includes
data centers hosting mission critical or
sensitive data and I found through my
research a lot of these attacks that I
presented over the few years do effect
outside activity on the physical network
itself so not only does it affect
systems in the virtualized networks but
you can use it to leverage to get
outside of the virtual network onto the
actual data structure infrastructure or
data center infrastructure so there's an
old lesson here we're vulnerable to
those that are close to us so if we're
hosted on the same system as our
competitors we may actually have issues
with that so what if this is our basic
scenario we have our host operating
system right
XenServer prax max vmware whatever you
want to use it doesn't really matter
this pit point what this research was
really focused on was the virtual
networking devices so we have
hypervisors but different hypervisors
utilize different types of virtualized
networking devices at layer 2 layer 3 in
this case we're looking at virtual
bridges or switches so some
implementations use the virtual
switching like open V switch hyper-v has
a switch to or we're looking at bridging
so things like Linux kernel bridging
which is mostly used by things like KVM
open source Zen proxmox environments so
as you can see here all these devices
all these systems are actually connected
to that virtual network interface here
and we could have a malicious actor on
that network so what could they do with
that how could they actually leverage
being on that same network what kind of
things could be gathered from the
network traffic
so this research has proved that
virtualized network devices do actually
have the potential to be exploited in
the same manner as their physical
counterparts and like I said before
sometimes this stuff can actually escape
and get out into that physical realm so
consequences what happens if we can
successfully launch a layer to
networking attack within a virtualized
environment we can capture all the
network traffic right redirect it before
men in the middle attacks denial of
services gain unauthorized access to
restricted sub networks by doing VLAN
hopping attacks maybe jump over to a
different view lane or a different
subnet and we can also just play an
effect performance by just cluttering up
the traffic on the network so some test
scenarios and results we have VLAN
hopping I got a few scenario
descriptions and had some demos here we
can go through our poisoning so here's
the old test environment I was teaching
at SUNY Pali for a while and we
developed this test environment of a
whole bunch of extra equipment we had
lying around there so you have a lot of
1u Dell servers in here we have a couple
customized servers as well we can see
the specs here basically every single
major hypervisor platform at that time
was was tested and used in this
environment so we set these all up and
we tried to keep the hardware similar
but it's important to realize in this in
this research the hardware really didn't
matter because we were looking at the
networking devices so we were really
testing performance and I shouldn't say
that because we did test performance in
the Mac flooding that was about the only
time when we were looking at how the
flooding affected the performance the
network and in that case a faster system
with a faster processor could have
handled that traffic a little bit better
but for the most part we're testing VLAN
hopping things like that we're just
looking at the networking devices but we
still tried to keep things similar so
here's after $30,000 of funding when I
moved over to Utica College all brand
new super micro servers wired up nice
and pretty you know we did quite a bit
of work here to get this thing looking
nice each individual system has
identical hardware so we're looking at
1u super micro servers with Intel Xeon
x3 1240 v 3 quad core processors 32 gigs
of ram each they each had a 500 gigabyte
Westar Digital hard drive and 4 onboard
Intel gigabit network interface card so
that was nice when I wanted to set up
different networks
that I could set the vm's on to do the
different attacks reviewing hopping
stuff you can also see when I move to
the new environment
I upgraded all the hypervisors to the
newer versions that were out at that
point in time this was because we
already did a lot of testing on the
previous versions so why not see if
either a the problems we found with the
vulnerabilities found still persisted in
new environments or B if they were fixed
so we found a lot of stuff just kept
persisting through there was really no
fix when we move forward except for with
the net flooding when we actually
submitted the issue to open V switch and
were it was validated and we actually
got a CVE for it for and they submitted
a patch so that was the time when
actually they get fixed in the newer
versions of open V switch okay so let's
talk about VLAN hopping so this is an
attack used again unauthorized access to
another virtual land on a
packet-switched network so basically
what we can do is jump from one VLAN to
another and depending on the type of
attack we do either switch spoofing or
double tagging we can have one way or
two directional communications between
that network so a little bit about
virtual LANs you have Ethernet frames
that are modified for VLAN traffic and
what we do is we're just going to take
that normal Ethernet frame we wedge in
this extra VLAN tag here it's for extra
bytes of information with this we get
this VLAN ID and that tells us where
that packet belongs on that network so
here's a CV that was published
describing the switch spoofing of
vulnerability and Cisco switches
basically telling us that Cisco switches
allow an unauthorized user to gain
access to a VLAN by pretending that
they're basically another Cisco switch
so they're spoofing the CDP or Cisco
discovery protocol messages so the Cisco
discovery protocol basically allows
Cisco devices to talk to each other and
tell each other about themselves what's
your operating system oh my my operating
system is this what does my networking
look like what are my IP addresses my
routing information so these are how
routers can talk to each other how
switches can talk to each other we also
have things like VTP for the VTP domain
so we can push that out to all the other
switches on the network to actually
configure our VLANs
ok so
a couple more switch spoofing
vulnerabilities released so the 2900
virtual land switches allow remote
attackers to inject 802 dot1q frames by
forging the VLAN identifier in the
truckin tag so if I can get on to a
switch and spoof it and say I'm I'm
another switch and we're trying to make
a truck connection as long as I can fool
it to think that I should be on that
same VLAN I can start passing
information bi-directionally and
directly from Cisco DTP dynamic trucking
protocol if a switch port were
configured as DTP auto or will receive a
fake DTV packet it might become a trunk
port and it might start accepting
traffic destined for any VLAN and DTP
auto is the default setting on most
Cisco switches this might be changing
now in the newer versions of Cisco but
most of the older stuff you're seeing
out there
geeky Fiero is still the default setting
when you take it out of the box okay so
the dynamic trunking protocol is DTP
we're talking about it's a proprietary
Cisco layer 2 protocol allows the
automatic configuration of truck porcine
Cisco switches so when we're talking
about trying to exploit switch spoofing
we're talking about Cisco environments
right because this is really proprietary
to Cisco it provides negotiating of
trunking method with neighbour devices
so the consequence is if an attacker can
actually spoof and actually say hey I'm
a switch I have a trump connection to
you let's let's make things happen they
can generate frames for any VLAN that's
supported over that trunk so there could
be multiple VLANs that they can actually
get access to they can communicate with
any device on those associated VLANs
bi-directionally and also allows
attackers to Eve drops on the traffic
within that target VLAN because they're
already on that broadcast domain if they
want to listen to broadcast messages or
demand the middle attacks they're
already positioned okay so here's a demo
basically the setup this was actually
from the research environment so this is
a proof-of-concept attack we have a
attacking machine which is a sitting
there on a virtual switch and bridge
right so this is just a virtual machine
over here we have a regular 2950 cisco
switch
physical switch now this is set to
dynamic desirable by default out of the
box we plugged in the virtualized
network into the switchboard just as a
basic communication that were to get the
virtual machines online not changing
that port to a trunk port which would be
considered best practices to make that a
trunk 4 so
just seeing if administrator took the
switch out-of-the-box plop it down
plugged in the virtual network what's
going to happen over here we actually
have a set up correctly we have a trunk
link between the Cisco 2950 in the
virtual switcher bridge so this is it
actually set up for best practice we're
supporting VLANs 1 and 20 over this and
then we have a virtual machine sitting
inside here on the the virtualized
network that's sitting on VLAN 20 so we
have an attacker that's out there he's
just sitting on the default VLAN trying
to get in try to negotiate that trunk
link and seeing if they can actually
send data to the virtual machine let's
check this out ok so what we're doing
here is we're using the vSphere
environment and I have the switch over
on the side so we're going to show the
interface we're connected to so we're
showing into FA 0 21 so it's the twenty
first port and we're just checking the
status and we see it's connected so that
Luminara is the ESXi server right and
it's connected it's not VLAN one just
standard connection there so let's see
what happens next
we're looking over here on the
properties and we see that we have this
test VLAN setup I don't think you guys
can see that it's kind of small
over here we're showing the status of
the port that the system is connected to
except for not nan trunking so this is
the attacking system port and it's not
set up as a truck right now so over on
the test adapter for the target VM we're
seeing that is set on that VLAN test
network over here we can see that we
have a tow 2.1 encapsulation set on that
2421 but again is set for not trunking
so that's kind of key because this the
switch spoofing depends on that vent
truckin mechanism okay so down here we
have the Kali VM we're looking at we're
looking at the properties of that right
now and we can kind of see there that
it's set for no VLAN so this currently
is set with no VLAN tags so this is on
our native VLAN so this is for the
attacking system
to counsel on that so now what we're
going to try to do is from the ESXi
virtual machine the machine located in
that environment we're going to try to
send a fake DPP spoofed message to the
Cisco switch on that fourth is set to
non trucking and we're going to try to
change it over to a truck port going
through the virtualized environment
through the virtual switch so we're just
going to fire up your Cydia and we're
going to send the DTP packet so just
choose the dynamic car key protocol and
then it's going to send out we're just
going to choose 0 here to send the
packet and then we can see it was
originally set for access desirable and
then it immediately turned over to truck
auto so we were able to successfully
change it to a trunk port and now here
you can see the line went down for the
interface and it came back up and if we
show it status on that it is now a truck
port so that went through the virtual
switch from the DM through the virtual
switch into the physical network and it
was able to change that physical pour on
that switch to a a trucking port and now
you can have access to any system on
that network so why does this work and
what else did it work on let's get this
background work ok so I found this
worked on any virtual network that was
using bridging if you were using a
switch like open V switch or the cisco
nexus 1000v or the hyper-v standard
virtual switch citrix xenserver uses
open V switch and implementation of it
those were not affected because they
were actually blocking that DTP packet
from going through it wasn't necessary
the reports didn't even see it it didn't
acknowledge it however anything that was
using a mode of bridging our physical
colleague 2.0 control system so we
actually tried it with just a basic
control using physical systems to see if
we can actually put the switch into
trunking mode before attempting it from
a virtualized environment then we saw
that it would actually work from
anything we're breeding so the open
source them with bridging ESXi server
basically acts as a bridge it's not
using a
so we'll switch implementation it's
using a virtual bridge implementation
and then proxmox using bridge mode as
well so it just basically acted as a
pass-through and loud that DQ packet to
go through that virtual network and
affect the physical switch so mitigation
disable any unused switch ports disable
CDP and DTP or use on a per port basis
right if you have two switches that
you're connecting on a specific port
then maybe you can enable that stuff on
there but if you're just leaving open
port set to D key piatto that's a pretty
bad practice limit VLAN access on trunk
force so only what the connected
segments require so if the trunk only
needs you know one in 20 or 25 and 30
for that particular network don't give
it every other VLAN just to have them
all on there you're opening yourself up
to attacks so configure all ports as
access ports no trunking with no access
to the native VLAN disabled ports too
right you're not using so just down the
port security let's talk a little
tagging now so this is an 802 1q VLAN
protocol it allows remote attackers the
bypass network segmentation and spoof
VLAN traffic via a message was to 802
dot1q tags so we call this double
tagging because we're trying to take a
frame and we're adding an additional
VLAN tag to it to try to get that frame
to jump over to a second VLAN and
there's an actual specific purpose for
this is a part of the standard of 802
dot 11 or 802 dot1q standard um this was
designed to actually work this way so
what we're doing is we're exploiting the
way this thing was designed to our
advantage to get packets to where you
want them to go so here's how basic 802
dot1q tagging works we have two switches
and between them they have a trunk link
and in this case we're supporting VLANs
1 2 & 3 we're VLAN 1 is that native VLAN
if you LAN 2 & 3 or access VLANs we can
see systems on each end of the switches
there that are connected to VLAN 1 VLAN
2 or VLAN 1 2 & 3 respectively so let's
just send a basic tag v layer VLAN
packet over right this is your normal
traffic we have from the start machine
it's on VLAN 1 it's tagged with the 1
and it's going to go through that first
switch and then it's going to go over to
chunk light because it wants to go over
talk to the system over here on the
other side on the m1 so we go over that
trunk and then it just forwards that
packet under the cracky Lane right
pretty simple it sounds supposed to work
so double tag
we have our normal Ethernet frame up top
we saw this before where we wedge in
this extra VLAN tag here right to show
that we're on that VLAN network for that
segmentation
but down here this is what a double tag
frame looks like so we're actually
adding in an extra VLAN tag today
Ethernet frame okay so here's how this
process works that first system is going
to send out a packet now but it's going
to have two tags instead of one so we're
going to be tagged four one and two
notice here that it goes down here this
is on VLAN two it's rejected because the
first tag is one we've only gone through
the first switch it reads that first tag
it doesn't read the second tag so it
cannot pass that packet over to that
second machine down there but what
happens is when we go through this first
switch that first tag is stripped off
before it hits the truck port and now as
it goes over the trunk port and hits the
second switch the second switch only
sees that second tag and this is how the
deal and hopping attack works so what I
did is I stripped off that first tag now
that packet goes on to or that frame
goes on to this machine over here
located on VLAN two it no longer goes
over to VLAN 1 because that tag was
stripped off pretty simplistic stuff and
this was done by design so that you
could move things between packets or
between between networks I'm sorry so
now we just have another example 1 & 3
same difference just we're just shooting
over to a different VLAN to a different
target system now this is a one-way
attack we cannot get information back
right because we're a target we're at a
core system targeting somebody else in
another VLAN we're double tagging a
packet and sending it across that
network to the other side in order for
them to send a packet back to us they're
going to have to do the same process
right they're going to double tag the
packet and send it back to us because
when they try to reply to that packet if
it's a simple ping or whatever it's
going to try to go back to that other
system on that other VLAN and it's the
systems currently in a totally different
broadcast domain so it doesn't know how
to get that traffic to where it needs to
be ok so like I said target system
cannot respond back now to good attack
for eavesdropping because you're just
sending information you can't listen to
stuff on the way back and forth but it
is an excellent method for denial of
service attacks right because I can send
Pakistan systems at other VLANs from a
totally covert VLAN that I'm on another
side and then it's very hard to track
where these things came from so I could
be sending malicious packets over it can
also be used as a one-way covert channel
maybe I want to send information to
another system on another VLAN and do it
covertly I do it this way okay so I got
a few demos of this a couple different
scenarios here this first scenario was
more of a control scenario so I have an
attacking system that's on the physical
network and what we're going to do is
we're going to try to send a double tag
packet between two Cisco 2950 switches
both with these trunk links with VLANs 1
and 20 supported and then we have a
virtualized environment here connected
to that last Cisco 2950 switch over that
trunk link and this is best practices
and had these trunk links down there if
you read the documentation they want you
to set up trunk links and then here we
have an access link on VLAN 20 in the
virtualized network so this is going to
be a physical attacker on Kali to
physical Cisco 2950 switches and then a
target VM on the proxmox environment
that up here in this first window we
actually had the two switches you can
see two tabs there so I'm showing the
configuration of the first switch and we
can see that first port we're connected
or on VLAN 1 and that's the port that
the that the attacking system is
connected to here we're showing it's not
trunking but it's using that 802 dot1q
encapsulation now a show port 24 which
this is the trunk link between the two
cisco 2950 switches so the first switch
was a 24 ports which the second one was
a 48 ports which and we can see that set
up for trunking and we can see that it
is supporting VLANs one in 20 which are
listed here actually has one cat and 20
on there but we're really concerned with
VLAN 20 so if we go and look at the next
switch which is that second 2950 switch
we'll just check the interfaces on this
one cuz we want to see what the
connection for the trunk looks like
between the two switches and then the
trunk link between the switch and the
virtualized environment okay so port 29
we can see the system is Fisto on there
ahead of Star Wars kind of thing going
on except for a trunk port it's
supporting the truck the same trounces
the original one one two ten and twenty
eight oh two dot1q encapsulation and
then we'll take a look at the
virtualized environment of supporting
although this is the connection between
the two devices and we can see that
they're connected there's a trunk port
there between 448 and then back to port
24 on the other switch and that's
supporting the VLANs as well using 802
dot1q encapsulation so in the middle
here we just have a terminal window on
the physical cally system it's going to
be the attacking system and then here's
our target system on the proxmox
environment which is just not a
colleague system sitting over there
so what we're going to do is we're going
to use the Yersinia utility again to
launch the v/line hopping attack on the
V physical system and then we're just
going to use TCP dump over here to
actually monitor to see if we actually
get those packets set across the network
so it's going to take a few - to get
this set up here so just doing TCP dump
over here - VV and then we're just
grepping out for ICMP in the middle
we're just gonna run your Sydney on - I
for interactive mode setup the interface
now this system had multiple interfaces
on it so had to choose basically a
default one there
the one that was on the correct network
in this case it was e - to do these
attacks from so now on the bottom
there's settings so when you go to
launch you're going to pick the DT or
the 802 dot1q attack here and on the
bottom it's kind of hard to see but
there's a bunch of settings down here we
had the source VLAN the source IP
address which can just be spoofed to
whatever you want to set it to in this
case I sent it to 192 168 0.5 I believe
and then the target VLAN is VLAN to that
you want to set which I just set to 20
since that target VLAN systems on and
then the destination IP so what is the
IP address of that system I'm trying to
hit so down here I'm spoofing the IP
address of 192 168 0 to 5.5 and I'm
trying to go to 192 168 1 that 1 1 1 is
the target system so totally different
sub Network different VLAN and we can
see here that our target system is in
fact sitting there on 192 168 1 dot 1 1
1 so we're going to start launching the
attack from your seniya now now I found
that after you can stay here and watch
this and I'm launching the attack and
it's sent off the ICMP packet you can
see there was 118 168 5.5 destination of
1.11 and the ICMP on e 2 right so we're
sending that up but we don't see
anything over here yet it takes it took
a little bit of time I had to run this
attack a few times just launching it
running it like this just keep keep
petting it I'm like aw man
is going to work this is going to work
I'm not gonna get my PhD this sucks and
then all of a sudden things start
happening so it was successful so I'm
giving this talk in Norway and I do this
and there was a guy in the back and they
warned us that Norwegians are not going
to talk when you're in the conference
and they don't like to speak until
afterward but he actually raised his
hand he said you know why that's
happening you know why you're getting
that delay and I'm like you know I've
been trying to figure that one out he's
like you're doing DNS lookups on your
tcp dump still so we would have seen
this stuff a lot quicker if I basically
turned off the flag for DNS lookups on
there so I was like oh thank you I'm
trying to figure that one out for a
little while now it's just a stupid
little thing to overlook right so when
you're using TCP that's a good lesson to
learn if you're getting some sort of
delays and you're waiting for something
to happen maybe turn off DNS if you're
not trying to do - yes you're just doing
IP lookup right it's basic stuff but
when you're doing complicated stuff like
that sometimes you overlook the basics
so good lesson learned
okay so that was that we've proven now
that we can go through two physical
switches and actually do the VLAN
hopping attack as intended right through
those two switches from a physical
system and we actually made it into the
virtual machine to the virtualized
environment so that was our control
let's strip away one of those physical
switches right let's actually see if we
can do this from a virtualized network
through a virtualized switch into a
physical switch out the other end into a
virtual switch and then hit another VM
on the other side on a totally different
network in a totally different
environment right so in this case the
attacker is a Zen server virtual machine
and the target - fox max virtual machine
I'm not trying to beat up Fox max
actually love proxmox it's a great
environment so don't get me wrong here
but and all these videos are available
on you
- there's a lot more to of the
progression there's I have stuff up on
there for the max loading attacks you
guys can look at if you want to okay
same scenario we've got our physical
switch over here that we're looking at
we have our Citrix XenServer VM here and
our proxmox target here and we're
looking at the whole dump here we have
Fisto which is the proxy box server set
up with the trunk port best practices
our Citrix server was Maul and that set
up as a truck port as well and then
we're just verifying the stuff just to
make sure that all the settings were
correct again and you guys see most of
the stuff probably for the interest of
time jump ahead a little bit
eatle - on a capsulation okay so here
we're looking at the networking for the
VM in Citrix environment and now the
heart of this attack is having access to
that admin or native VLAN on the switch
right so I had to make sure that here
we're tagging the proxmox 420 we saw
earlier there the the Citrix VM had no
VLAN tag associated with it that put it
on that native VLAN if you try to tag it
with one it's not on the native VLAN
anymore according to the Tao Citrix is
actually doing their networking so
you're trying the stuff at home set it
to nothing just disable Vee landing and
it will be on the admin VLAN again over
here we're just using TCP dump graphing
for ICMP again without DNS turned off so
we'll have a little bit of a delay and
then over here we're just gonna launch
you're seeing it and run through the
attack again so this is very systematic
you can see as I was doing the research
I was approaching as well can I do it
how you're supposed to do it then can I
take away something and do it the way I
think I may be able to do it and I'm
keep taking away stuff and keep trying
different things and what we did at the
same way every time right so now I'm
setting the settings on the bottom here
I'm going to launch the attack and then
we'll actually see what happens so again
for time I'll just scoot forward here a
little bit or setup that attack here we
see we're sending that packet again
across the network and then we start
just jamming those those attack packets
then again I'm like Hoss
but after quite a while it worked right
so again different environments
now we're going from a virtualized
environment through a virtual switch
into a physical switch out the other end
into another virtualized switch into a
totally different VLAN on a totally
different environment so this gets kind
of scary right now I'm going to take it
one step further and let's strip it all
away let's see if we can really just go
from a physical attacker through a
single 2950 physical switch and actually
have this be that second hop and strip
it off right because before I had two
switches before or I had you know two
physical switches before I had a
physical and a virtual so really you
could say that all you didn't really
make it into the virtual switch before
you already made it to that bad deal and
when you hit that second physical switch
you're not doing anything special but
when we took that first physical switch
away now we were going from virtual to
virtual now we're taking everything away
we just have a physical switch in the
virtual switch to switches ones physical
ones virtual can we make it over here to
the end so we have attackers physical
Kali and in this case I tried to step it
up a little bit we've been pickin up
racks match but let's go super
enterprise-level
hyper-v guest with a cisco nexus 1000v
how many guys have tried to configure a
cisco nexus 1000v he's laughing yeah
he's not laughing he's pretty serious
back there but he knows pain you go
through configuring this thing anyway
let's see what happens let's just go
have it down
Sam setup right but
case I have two tabs over here now one
is our physical switch the 2950 again
we're going to look at all the same
stuff the other cab though is we have
our configuration for our nexus 1000v
let's just verify this stuff for sake of
completeness
so our attacking physical system which
is in the middle is connected on VLAN 1
the target systems over there on the
other side we want to check our status
of our port connected to the virtual
switch of the Cisco system so here's the
hyper-v we're set at the trunk port on
that connected to that cisco nexus 1000v
and the trunking information there in
this case the VM was on on VLAN 10 when
it set it up on the Cisco what we're
still supporting all the same VLANs that
we were using before
ok so let's jump up here now we're
looking at that cisco nexus 1000v he's
probably shuttering there I don't want
to see that again so we can see again
we're set up with a trunk port here
connected to VLAN 10 right for that
network connection the eath one is the
one connecting back to our actual switch
physical switch okay so the attacking
system and the target system we're just
going to the same kind of setup again
TCP dump wrapping for ICMP and then over
on the other side running our your Senia
and we'll just kind of fly through a
little bit more setting it up okay over
here
looking at the IP so let's see what
happens when we start launching this
thing okay so there's a package
again we're just kind of jamming it away
don't see much on the other end and then
oh there it all is so yeah even even
Cisco couldn't stop it
it went through so this worked across
every platform it's just the way the
protocol works and you can exploit it
however you want the utilities are out
there to do it and it will work in
virtualized and physical environments
and allow you to cross between both
worlds so protect your data centers so
double tagging results just a high-level
overview here over here results of
attacks single switch double switch so
we can see this work pretty much in
every single environment right the
double tagging attack for both looking
at a single person on virtual or a
single physical switch or a double
physical switches it did not work in
Microsoft standards working on virtual
switch why not
why is Microsoft standard V switch in
Server 2012 stopping this from working
you really think that would not be the
one but actually is the outlier in this
list but what they actually did is in
Server 2008 they started putting
something into their virtualized
networking that basically blocks any
kind of Maps back spoofing so where we
can see with this VLAN hopping attack is
that your spooky spoofing your MAC
address when you're sending out the
attacks so by spoofing your MAC address
the virtual switch is actually catching
that and it's blocking those packets
from going through so that actually
prevented it from occurring now if you
start looking through a lot of the forms
and stuff out there on why they did this
it seems like it just kind of ended up
getting in there by somehow by accident
by the design and now you start finding
a lot of threads out there of people
trying to figure out how to disable that
feature so Microsoft if you try to go
out and try to look up you know Mac
spoofing protection virtual and switch
you'll find their basic kind of what is
it promo material about the the server
why it has that but it doesn't tell
anything about it and then the only
technical details you can find about it
our third published details on how to
disable it then once you disable it you
could do this type of attack
so don't know that's kind of backwards
the other side can I launch the attacks
from the virtualized environments right
when we had that virtual switch we were
coming from the virtual switch going
into the network's
could it be launched from them and we
can see the yes it could from the
different bridged areas proxmox
XenServer we tried again standard switch
stopped it from happening
Microsoft Cisco Nexus 1000v stopped it
because there's some pretty strict VLAN
controls on there when you're trying to
access other VLANs going outbound on the
prevent of the attack from occurring and
ESX I didn't really figure out why that
prevented it from occurring but it
wasn't able to go out from the SSI
system ok mitigation do not assign any
host to VLAN one of that native VLAN
disable VLAN one on unnecessary ports
maybe even change your native VLAN to
something more obscure right restrict
access to switches by MAC addresses so
we're seeing a lot of physical layer
actual physical system security here
because these virtualized systems are
connected to your physical network
eventually and we can see that these
attacks are actually affecting that too
so you need to protect that stuff how we
do it on time ooh ok I have a whole
other section to go into or at 350 your
choice I don't mind I'll keep talking if
you guys want me to
is it 340 ok then my clock is wrong so
let's keep rolling and any questions at
this point on the stuff I've already
presented yes
you mean just basically connect to
virtual environments with a crossover
cable and try it that way I never tried
that I was trying to go for the bigger
stuff right but that that's a good
question
that is a good question so that's hope
that maybe you could try right and then
and let us know it's a I'm kind of I'm
kind of at my end I've done this stuff
for four years now I got a PhD out of it
and this is kind of my last hop I'm
moving on to bigger things I'm letting
my students now talk right you guys did
a great job on there stuffer stuff let's
talk about the auction moving with that
that is a good question maybe I'll have
some students work on that one at some
point yeah eating your Chinese food okay
ARP address resolution protocol so each
system item Network maintains this art
cache right and it's just translation
between your layer 2 addresses in your
layer 3 addresses so the system's know
how to communicate with each other and
they're in a single broadcast domain our
caches will differ between different
systems right because not every system
on the network needs to communicate with
each other they don't need to know about
each other usually art broadcasts happen
when the system wants to talk to another
systems they say hey who's got this
address there it is tell this at this IP
address right tell me who has it so then
we get this MAC address back from that
system that actually has that on the
network so it's just a broadcast out and
there's a unicast back so only the
system requesting it gets the answer
back and then populates it our cache
with the update so this allows it to not
have to do this broadcast later on in
the line if it needs to communicate with
that system again it already has that
table so it knows what the translation
is so how can we break this our spoofing
is a pretty well-known attack right
basically what we did is we did this in
the virtualized environment so we
created multiple test errors we had a
router virtual machine going out the
physical network interface card of the
the virtualized environment and then
going out to the cloud right so we're
just plugged into the to the data center
at that point and then we had that
target virtual machine and then we have
a virtual switch so in this case we're
trying to do our spoofing like you asked
within a single environment right to see
if it actually works
so this is not a multi-tenant host so
what we do is we pop that attacking
virtual machine down there on the switch
and then we try to redirect all the
traffic through so the virtual the
target virtual machine is going to end
up sending its traffic because of the
MAC address spoofing and the ARP
spoofing to the attacker virtual machine
because it's going to think that it's
sending it to the actual router because
the attacker spoofed
it's a dress to make the target virtual
machine think that is the router and it
also poisoned the routers information to
think that it is the target system is
trying to send the data through so we
have a nice little man in the middle
there so we have a quick demo on this
one the attacker is a physical collie
system and the target system is going to
be VMware ESXi okay so over here we have
our router and we can see the ARP cache
on that router we're showing the MAC
address of 22 and 21 and these are the
virtual machines here 22 or 21 and 22 so
this is our target VM this is our
attacking VM Kali one Kali 2 and we can
see the ARP caches are all correct right
now they're all pointing to the right
locations right we have 21.8 22
correctly we have one pointing to one
correctly different areas the router
knows which one each of the Cowley's are
correctly in each of the Cowley's know
what the router is and it's other VM on
our network so what we did is how many
guys have read the blackhat Python book
anybody so my student
we took the plan well we found out that
we had a class that if you saw the stuff
for presentation that's kind of where
that came from and the black cat Python
book was the book that we use for that
class now these guys will tell you it
was a fun class wasn't it yeah so the
black cat Python book the code is quite
broken so we spent a lot of time fixing
a lot of that code and the art poisoning
code that was in there was what I use
for this attack but it was slightly
modified so if you get the black hat
python book you can kind of read and
understand it's art poisoning script a
little better so here we go we're
setting this up and then an attacking
machine we ran the script and what it
does is a poison as you can see by
showing the art cache now the router we
look back here
both those MAC addresses are the same 21
and 22 so the router thinks that the
attacking system is the target system
if we look on the target system we can
see that Wow well the router is now the
MAC address of 22 which is the attacking
system right it thinks it's the router
so now we're just paying Google from the
attacking or from the target system see
what's going on and over here this the
script automatically sniffs the first
hundred packets of writes into a file so
we're looking at that where we got it
down to dump dot pcap and then it
restores the art cache back so after I'd
sniffed the traffic in the virtualized
environment I'm going to go ahead and
remake everything back to nice so all
the back addresses and translations in
the ARP table are now reset they look
the reset back to what they should be so
the router knows the correct systems
there and the target system should also
know the correct systems so if we look
at the dump file now I basically just
wrote a little TCP dump script in this
case to just parse that dump file and
here we go we could see all the
information that we gathered while we
were pinging Google from the target
system is now on the attacking system so
we're able to successfully perform the
man-in-the-middle attack thank you
through the through the virtualized
environment so this was contained within
a single ESXi environment and it worked
and this as we'll see here in the next
slide was not stopped by any environment
so there's no default protection against
this so in order to protect yourself
against our poisoning or spoofing you're
going to need some sort of third-party
application or some other feature in
there to and on top of your virtualized
environment until you know these vendors
start getting on top of things and start
building in these controls for us our
blotch is a linux utility very useful
for detecting problems with ARP tables
on the network so this is one that could
you know trigger basically if there's
some sort of strange thing going on with
the ARP traffic on your network it will
send you email alerts to let you know
pretty much instantaneously so this is
something may want to start implementing
if you're running data centers and you
kind of think you might be successful in
this kind of attack start implementing
something like ARP watches for work we
also have in Microsoft environment you
have different ways of looking at our
cache or poisoning too you also have
ways to validate our pre quests on Cisco
switches physical switch
so dynamic ARP inspection those things
will actually help you out as well if
you're running a cisco environment a
DHCP snooping which is a prereq to
dynamic ARP inspection so conclusion
virtual eyes or virtual versus physical
really our results show the virtual ID
that were virtualized networking devices
can have the same or even greater risk
of being vulnerable for these attacks
right than their physical counterparts
with physical devices we have a lot more
levels of control built into them to
actually prevent this stuff from
occurring like basically port security
things like that that are in these these
virtualized switches so really there's
no one best system after looking at all
the environments that we tested
there's not one really high performer
that really was more secure out of all
of them we saw the hyper-v environment
did block a couple of techs just because
of that a little bit of maximum
protection I had in there but how's the
usability compared to other environments
you know you have to weigh that into
effect as well so lack of sophisticated
layer 2 security controls similar to
what's available at enterprise grade
physical switches greatly increases the
difficulty in securing virtual switches
against these attacks so like I said
these virtual switches aren't really up
to par yet with their physical
counterparts that have been out there
for 20 years have been redeveloped and
you know enhanced with new firmware
updates things like that with new
greater controls so unless the vendors
start getting on top of this with the
virtual switch implementations we're
still going to be at their mercy or
having to put other solutions in there
to prevent from these kind of attacks
from occurring
so bottom line single blushes malicious
virtual machine has the potential to
sniff all traffic passing over a virtual
switch and can even affect that physical
network as I've shown so you can go in
and out significant threats to
confidentiality integrity and
availability of all data passing over a
network in a multi-tenant environment so
what can users do if you're a user
having data in these multi-tenant
environments you can basically start
questioning your hosting provider what
kind of security controls you have what
kind of access do I have to actually
implement things that help my network
and my data be more secure
maybe I just start using encryption for
everything right so that if my data is
compromised it's still encrypted so it's
hard for harder for the attacker to get
a hold of threat detection and alerting
all this stuff can be questioned ask
your providers make them start answering
these questions when you start paying
those
what are you doing to secure my data not
just how much is it okay here's my email
contact information and get me through
my Clarkson email I'm also at Utica or
my businesses Ronnie double Adirondack
IT solutions com
all the links to my publications
presentations are all found in my blog
you can get my DEFCON talks there Derby
con talks all that stuff is there
special thanks to dr. Gina Matthews who
was the presenter before me she was my
PhD advisor and all this and as well as
a lot of students a few of them in this
room that have helped me along the line
setting up these environments and
maintaining them and help me run these
tests so any questions no questions
that's a good thing thank you anybody
else can't be around later if you guys
want to stop and talk to me individually
or whatever that's fine but thank you
for your time yes uh well okay that
right so I I have been over the past few
years I've been in contact with AWS
people because you cannot do pen testing
vulnerability assessment work on their
networks without going through a lot of
paperwork the right channels and getting
the approval right so I could have but
I'm trying to do this research as a PhD
student not is just some black hat or
grey hat so I had to do things you know
systematically so I've been in contact
with them we've had meetings with them
talked with them quite a bit about
trying to do this it's there's a lot of
roadblocks to getting in the Amazon I
think Shawn was just a CCDC with us our
team exited very well there we ran into
the guy that runs the data centers for
Amazon there so we're trying to really
start building more of a relationship to
get students doing these tests
in those kind of areas however he did
tell us that this stuff is back go to
work on Amazon
he said he that I mean I can't really
get into the details but he did say that
they are doing a lot of special stuff
behind the scenes as proprietary that
prevents a lot of this stuff from
occurring now we're getting there things
like OpenStack a lot more complexity
which could introduce more
vulnerabilities right and then we can
start talking about Sdn all we want but
then you can talk about you know how
those controllers can get compromised
and your network is just a bunch of
published rings all over the place so if
you go and dot you can download my full
dissertation here as well and read that
and I start talking about things like
you know using Sdn and the complications
I've actually wrote solutions that make
Sdn solutions much more simpler so I
just wrote Python scripts to fix some of
these issues as well as a DHCP text I
proposed you could have done with Sdn to
fix them but I wrote simple Python
scripts instead to show that you don't
need that overhead right so there's
there's a lot of questions you'd and a
lot more exploring we could do with this
and we're trying to develop research at
the schools two at Clarkson and Utica to
kind of go further a work with industry
partners to to keep moving forward on
this because it is important as he said
the other yes yeah see I couldn't I
couldn't do a dissertation on theory
alone I'm a practical person I need to
do hands-on stuff so I had a break stuff
that was very lucky to be able to do
this and break stuff you know it was
great so I'm very gracious for my
advisor for letting me pursue this and
yeah without without the demos and the
actual real prototypes and then proof of
concepts this research would not have
been worth even sitting here and
listening to in my mind so I appreciate
all your time anybody else okay thank
you
[Applause]