yeah so this is debugging electronics
you can't handle the ground truth my
name is Daniel my handle is tense future
with the three so disclaimer these are
my own opinions and I'm not endorsed by
any manufacturer or supplier I'm gonna
be talking about some gear and it's
usually just stuff that I've used over
the years and has worked for me but
nobody's really paying me to say this
so who am i I've got ten years of
engineering experience I spent four
years at startups and then the last six
years have been basically building other
startups so I do product design and
engineering and you know process design
business design market research stuff
like that for a company called motivo
engineering so the last three years I've
been a senior engineer and now a manager
for the electrical and software teams so
I've spent a little bit of time
mentoring engineers and so this talk is
really prompted by seeing less
experienced engineers and the pitfalls
that they usually hit and yeah I'll talk
about more more about that later the
commonality between all the places I've
worked is that we're always on a tight
budget so it's like there's a sweet spot
of useful hardware at decent prices
before you get the thousands of dollars
equipment that's not gonna offer you as
much value over my career I've probably
worked on between fifty and a hundred
PCB designs so I've debugged a lot
caveat here's that I've got no
experience giving talks so this might be
a train wreck let's see that's my
twitter and you can check out my
soundcloud I do work on music a little
bit here and there
you may recognize me from one of the
hackaday badge life documentaries I
think was last year year before and Sean
and I who's in the front over here we
made the maneki-neko badge and it was a
little cute badge with some cool artwork
we got another friend to do and it had a
little servo on it that waved its paw
and blinked its eyes we like to few
people did to who am you you are an
entry level person excited
tinkering with electronics you could be
a new engineer you could be just an
enthusiast and I'm mainly gonna be
focusing on you folks a lot of
intermediate and experienced people get
something out of this too because you
probably forgot a lot of the strategies
if you haven't debugged something in a
while
so what is this I got to go fast
I've got like 60 slides to get through
so this is gonna be very much learning
by firehose I'm gonna be around the
whole rest of the of the day for the con
so come and grab me if you have
questions about something if you see me
wandering around in the back grab me to
help you debug something I'm happy to
help all right how do you debug you get
someone else to do it it's hard it sucks
thank you for coming to my TED talk just
kidding so why why debug well it's a
necessary evil if you're working on cool
stuff if you're working on challenging
stuff you're gonna make mistakes and so
you need to debug in my opinion the
electrical systems are the hardest to
debug you can't see the electrons you
have to measure them indirectly software
it's easy all the talk all the data is
in one place you just use the right tool
and you can see the data mechanical is
easy you can like feel it and see it and
hear it and smell it and taste it maybe
some combination of those climate
systems a little bit harder maybe I
don't know we haven't figured that one
out and so an electrical basically the
way you do this you have to measure some
some physical property and directly so
that means you need the right tools so
what does this talk for nobody really
teaches debugging the the engineers who
go through school and get their degree
the the experience they have is usually
out of necessity it's like you're doing
a lab or you're doing a project and you
got to make it work and so you start
testing things almost an art so much of
good debugging just comes from doing it
a lot so keep building things and you'll
gain an intuition for how to do it the
Internet is magic and when I say magic
is entertaining but it doesn't do
anything for you you can't copy paste
from Stack Exchange it's not gonna fix
your problem so the power of Google is
limited but sometimes useful so for
specific problems like something with a
specific device that people have run
into left and right you might be able to
find a forum thread or something like
that where people have found a fix most
of the time you're gonna have to read
those stories and gather clues and
really internalize how people have
solved problems and then you know absorb
those and treat them like they were
yours and like eventually you'll build
up this toolkit or of strategies for
yourself that you can use on your own
projects every problems a unique little
snowflake so I could tell you up here
like Oh on certain type of circuit you
should try this in that well how many
different circuits are there right it's
like infinite permutations of them so
really the best thing to do is
strategies understand how to use the
right tools and you'll be able to string
together measurements and string
together things to test to to come to
your your right answer or your solution
yeah so most strategies just means using
the right tool at the right time like I
said before this talk will be for the
beginner mostly but intermediate
intermediate and expert level debuggers
should actually also gain something out
of this beginner intermediate and expert
really correlates to simple to extremely
complex or difficult problems and
usually that means more expensive tools
for the like really crazy stuff if
you're doing anything in RF or other
high frequency stuff you're gonna need
you know tools that that can actually
measure those types of things all right
so what are the actual steps general
principle get to ground truth as quickly
as possible you don't want to just keep
trying something over and over and
iterating small things and seeing if it
works the next time like don't change a
variable in your code recompile the
whole thing and try it again it's not
gonna work that way
or at least not as quickly for me the
thing I recommend to most of the people
on my team is just measure it like
measure it as closely as you can
or as accurately as you can and keep
notes if you are in a multi-day debug
extravaganza you will forget what you
did the previous day or the previous
hour even alright so what are the real
steps prerequisite assume nothing check
all your stuff first reproduce and
isolate the problem second measure stuff
that's around that problem three add
people like get more ideas into the
problem and then profit so how do I
assume nothing check your equipment so
the easy stuff is like power supplies
are they putting out the right voltage
are they current limiting check the
noise on them I would not trust like
cheap bench supplies they put out a ton
of noise and they can affect your
circuit and very crazy in unexpected
ways
checking your multimeter so that's
another common thing everybody's gonna
have on the bench it's hard to like
check it you have to send it in and get
a calibrate and that's very expensive so
the cheap way to do that is get another
multimeter and check them against each
other see if they see if they agree on
what you're measuring check your
oscilloscope there are test outputs on
most oscilloscopes that'll give you a
little 5 volt square wave and that lets
you check probes to like are you probes
working correctly and then check obvious
things about the power source re the
device you're debugging so power supply
is it outputting the correct stuff
temperatures are nominal is there
anything heating up that's actually one
of my favorite things to look at first
is like is there part of my circuit
that's heating up too quickly or is it
heating up to a point that like I wasn't
expecting most stuff should run cool and
if it's not then you've got a problem
there's stuff like the processor clock
oscillation source like so the crystal
or the RC oscillator
that's an oscilloscope measure
over/under shoot on data signals so I've
seen sort of badly coupled or data
signals going between chips where
there's a huge like spike up each edge
what does that mean that's there's
problems with your circuit and that
could be affecting the device on the
receiving or the sending side causing
all sorts of weird software issues and
then checking that your data package
structure is correct so like is the data
format coming out like you would expect
so we'll go over the test equipment that
actually checks these types of things in
a bit so the real step one reproduce and
isolate the problem if a bug happens
once it is not a bug it is cosmic rays
and if you can't find it you can't fix
it and is it really broken or did your
finger just touch something yeah this
one's gonna be difficult to sort of
generalize because it's gonna depend on
your circuit obvious stuff is like
toggling the power on and off the one I
like is for microcontroller type of
stuff writing test code that just like
isolates the the part of your code
that's causing issues what that lets you
do is measure it on your test equipment
faster or more often and sort of try and
see some patterns or gain insights about
like probability you've gotta isolate
the problem start removing parts of the
system until the problem goes away
so each circuit board has you know
multiple subsystems this one does video
this one's the micro this is power
supply this is your analog front-end
start pulling things out and pumping
test signals as much as you can see to
try and isolate where the problem is and
then start adding things back in until
until you get the desired effect the
main thing here is don't fight multiple
problems at once across coupling of
issues is really gonna hurt you in time
time spent figuring out what the what
part of your your design is going re so
there that sub circuit and measure
seriously just pull out your D mmm pull
out your oscilloscope and keep good
notes on what you find so touched on
this before for the beginners voltage D
mmm digital multi
voltage over time oscilloscope current
under 10 amps DMM I would actually limit
that to like seven or eight amps a lot
of DMMs will start on fire by the way
I've done that so try and keep it low
current current over ten amps or over
time so current clamp you can or current
probe you can actually just clamp on to
the the wire and hook it up to an
oscilloscope and see what the trace
looks like gray house key coils are kind
of cool they've moved really really fast
so if you're measuring fast AC signals
that's the right tool to use for
temperature some kind of thermal sensor
we'll talk about the different kinds in
a bit and for data you want a logic
analyzer or side channel data port so
I'll talk about what side channel means
in a minute how to add brains so I go
through an escalation series at the
individual level
I am reproducing the problem taking
notes googling stuff checking data
sheets app notes errata stuff like that
if I'm totally boggled in like my brains
fried and I can't figure it out bring in
one other person hopefully like the most
expert person you know show it to them
let them ask questions explain what
you've tried but be open to like ideas
that contradict what you think you've
tried and then if that doesn't work
bring in more people so more brains
equals more power but only if you keep
good notes so keeping good notes
don't keep stuff in your brain you will
forget stuff you did an hour ago
write it down the the reason I like the
strategy is it kind of like gets my
brain thinking about the patterns that
show up so if you've been debugging
something for multiple hours or multiple
days you you have recency bias and
you're only gonna be thinking about the
results that you got in the last few
tests if you go through maybe the next
day after you're refreshed and you read
through the like chronology of your
notes you're gonna be like oh like
there's a pattern that is occurring here
and I can narrow it down a little bit
better so where do you find some brains
sometimes that brain is a duck
there's a concept called rubber ducking
that is used in the software industry
we're basically give it an inanimate
object and you explained your problem to
that object and by verbalizing it it
actually gets your brain to like think
in a different way often and it'll pop
into your head I actually have a really
hard time doing this so I just like have
someone like even non-technical
and I explain it to them so that there's
like eye movement and stuff surprisingly
it works really well
sometimes that brain is another person
look at all these people in the room
everybody is willing to help you debug
so go talk to people hackerspaces meetup
design labs conferences college
professors local professionals people on
Twitter you know reddit
sometimes that person's future you don't
underestimate the power of like a
20-minute nap or a quick break or
something like that and yet again if you
if you can find the people with most
expertise so let's talk about tools for
a little bit what equipment do i buy so
you can buy a multimeter for ten dollars
you can buy a multimeter for $1,000 does
that mean the thousand dollar one is
worth it well I'm gonna tell you that
there's a best bang for your buck
there's a sweet spot right in the middle
for most for most devices start with
stuff that you're gonna do most often so
if you don't have any equipment you're
gonna start with something to measure
voltage something measure current
something measure temperature and maybe
something to measure simple data streams
talk about those so the first thing
digital multimeter slowly reacting
voltage so like power supplies is you'll
use this to measure so the the weaksauce
stuff gets something cheap on Amazon
again you can buy multiples and sort of
check them against each other you can
get DMMs for crazy cheap I wouldn't
trust any of the cheap stuff to anything
but volts and ohms not even current
unless you're measuring really small
currents their current measurement
circuits are typically pretty trashed
right in the middle slot there's a B&K
precision in extech I've used their
stuff quite a bit I use a B&K precision
at home
and it cost me like 70 80 bucks that
step up like I'll have that that meter
forever right that step up really helps
and then in the high-end fluke tends to
be like the de facto standard for
professional use you can get those from
between 150 to 500 look for used they
tend to hold their calibration really
well over time here's all the things
that you're looking at for a multimeter
so like I said amps micro amps frequency
is helpful sometimes measuring diodes
help sometimes like to see if a diode
popped or something and then let's see
DC volts AC volts
ghost detection really important
oscilloscope or just scope user older so
you can go to your second-hand shops for
electronics and find like nice beefy 80s
HP or Agilent equipment and it's gonna
last through the apocalypse harder to
find though and actually you're not
guaranteed that it's like working and
good so have them demonstrate it for you
this there's a recent trend in USB scope
so it's like the whole visualization
thing lives on software on your computer
and you plug it in and you can get like
lots of nice functionality Pico scope
has some I've used them they're like a
hundred ish bucks
or higher and you get a lot of like
features for the money next I would
recommend actually Rygel there's also
one had some bad experience with them
and past but like they make some decent
stuff in terms of specs the Rygel stuff
you know hackaday is written a lot of
articles about them because there's nice
unlocks let's say the high end you're
talking about Tektronix or keysight's
but those really start at like 8 9 or a
thousand bucks and up again they're
gonna be like the thing to rely on but
it's crazy expensive so yeah the main
thing you're looking for is like voltage
and time and like a nice trigger setup
so you want to be able to like catch the
right signal at the right time and be
able to zoom into now resolution
understanding that is out of this scope
but look for the highest resolution you
can afford effectively sometimes they
have all kinds of goodies in like sub
menus where they can do math like two
signals subtract from each other or
counting frequency or looking for rise
time things like that get one with a
candy dispenser if you can so thermal
sensor how do you tell if this is my
favorite one how do you how do you tell
if something's going wrong like feel it
like is it is it overheating that
probably shouldn't like put your finger
on it was free well not totally free the
next thing I use a lot is an infrared
thermal gun so there are these little
guns you get from Home Depot they're
like 15 bucks they like shoot a little
laser and like you measure the IR
reflectivity they're better for big
things are gonna be really hard for like
circuit board level stuff for big stuff
you can get the temperature pretty
pretty readily the ones I like are like
FLIR and seek and fluke makes a couple
ones I think they're using clear modules
and it's basically like a thermal camera
right and and you plug it into your
phone and your phone is the display part
and they're pretty decent I'll show you
what a picture of that looks like and
how it can help oh man and then there's
the standalone so you can get them for
roughly 500 bucks they're not great at
that level but yeah these all-in-one
packages like have the same kind of
features and they're a lot more
expensive but yeah the sweet spots right
in the middle there the little plug in
things for your phone so this is what
I'm talking about when like the type of
output image you would get so I don't
know let's look at the bottom or middle
right there there's a chip that's you
know 48 degrees that sound rides that
supposed to be heating up that much I
don't know how fast does it heat up like
watch the video streaming if it's going
from like room temp to 48 in a second
you popped something time to replace
that chip so on the left there there's
the
little $10 gun from Home Depot in the
middle it's the plug-in modules from
FLIR and on the right actually have this
model at work and it's like glorious to
use from fluke and it like records video
and audio and like you can all sorts of
settings current sensors so DMMs low
refresh rate so you're not going to
catch spikes or anything you're gonna
catch like DC level current but you got
a DMM already and so use it in the
middle sweet spot there's current clamps
between 20 and 100 50 bucks for actually
like nice ones at 150 and those have
functions like min max so you'll be able
to like actually catch spikes but it's
just a simple readout and then there's
current probes so that's just like
basically an oscilloscope probe that
measures current there's Rogowski coils
which are like pretty fancy and it will
measure like really high frequency
current current measurements so if
you're measuring like a switching power
supply or something so they all operate
on similar things the the interaction
between electrical and magnetic waves or
fields the current clamp like this fluke
one is super nice and it's like a
hundred fifty bucks you don't have to
spend that and get something decent
there's current probes and there's the
Rudovsky coils they all they all work
the same you run the wire through them
not multiple wires like not opposite
currents just the one that's carrying
the current you care about through
through a loop and it'll measure the
current for you so logic analyzers these
are if you're measuring data streams so
is your data stream actually coming out
of the chip like you software is written
or is there another function before it
leaves the chip that's modifying it and
like in ways that you wouldn't expect
check your scope some scopes have simple
logic analyzers built into them and so
then you don't spend anything I've seen
these like software compatible clones so
they like use the the expensive product
software but they're actually like cheap
knockoffs that you get on
and stuff I've never used them though
but they look pretty intriguing and then
don't underestimate like a scope and pen
and paper I can't tell you how many
times I've debugged like Ken busts
traces on a on a car just by like
writing it on a whiteboard totally works
in the middle it gets a little bit
expensive there are some options out
there that I'm not totally familiar with
but sits out gosh Sally Sally Sally
has stuff for between four hundred
thousand bucks it's it's really really
nice stuff I'll show you their software
in a minute I think you get best bang
for your buck there there's also comers
like didn't I can remember the product
they make but it's a little less
expensive I think it's like 100 to 200
dollars and at the top and you get
really expensive with keysight in second
Tektronix at the thousands so what is a
logic analyzer it's basically a scope
all the inputs are digital and it has a
ton of channels so between 8 & 7
bazillion and the the software that
comes with it is meant to like group
those bits into bytes and convert them
into the protocol that your speak you're
trying to speak and like give you some
words you know towards the top that that
makes sense for the protocol okay so
other stuff I'm going to breach through
these really quickly if you get into the
advanced areas the this stuff is like
mmm anyway for specific types of
applications so if you're trying to
measure resistance under one ohm for
instance you have a really thick power
cable and you need to see like how much
are you how much of voltage are you
losing in that power cable there's think
that's thing called a micro ohm meter
it's like a multimeter except it's like
usually in a box and it specifically
measures things under 1 ohm really
accurately usually two like three
sometimes five six decimal places
checking your design for high voltage
safety so if you work in I think high
voltage you want an insulation meter or
a high pot tester sometimes it's both in
one device checking for sensitive and or
high voltage circuits isolation probes
so basically this is a
probe with a circuit in it that like
that makes it super high impedance and
it doesn't affect the thing that you're
trying to measure and actually I talked
about a little bit later to measuring
high voltage circuits as well a
battery-powered scope is nice because it
doesn't let you like short and blow
stuff up
let's see objecting signals without
having the right code so if you're just
trying to pump in a pedo PWM signal
somewhere function generator those tend
to be a little bit expensive but there's
some DIY options out there measuring
analog or digital signals over long
periods of data loggers so if you're
measuring like mm battery discharge
curves you're gonna it's gonna take days
or whatever and so you're gonna want to
put something that can measure maybe
every second for a few days
rotational speed teka meter and those
can get be fairly cheap it like an auto
parts store measuring light intensity
also fairly cheap called a Lux meter or
a light meter on Amazon they're like 25
bucks
measuring specific characteristics of
power delivery this gets into like power
supply design it's called a power
analyzer it'll tell you more than just
voltage and current they'll tell you
some crazy stuff about the power signal
going through it and then measuring in
tens across frequency spectrum analyzer
it gives you a nice little plot of like
how your antenna is reacting to a to a
signal checking continuity of lots of
conductors cable testers usually its
manufacturers are using this to like
plug in both sides and test that they
didn't break anything but for DIY your
your DMM is gonna be enough to it's
called the beep test or continuity test
communicating with standard
microcontroller protocols there's the
bus pirate the best pirate I think I
wrote that on a previous slide did I
know I didn't so I would have put it in
the middle here or here the thing about
the best part is that it'll work only
when your signals are properly formatted
so otherwise gotta pull out of scope and
really count those bits and see if it's
coming out right communicating via a
serial to a microcontroller everybody
knows about the little like USB to UART
cables
those can be had for really cheap and
then testing power sources electronic
load so these things look kind of like
power supplies except that their sinks
so you can do like constant voltage
constant current constant power constant
resistance I'm sure there's others out
there anybody got one that they like
Finch it's a pretty pretty big bench if
you got all those tools for your own
designs more test points test points
freaking everywhere there's two kinds
that I like there's these clip kinds you
can get your scope probes on they're
easy and then there's these sort of
pokey kinds just a little pad they don't
take up a lot of room on your circuit
board test early do bench tests I don't
do PCBs right away I get demo boards and
link them all together for the
functionality I need I'll see you cereal
side channel so it's if you've got an
extra you are on the board break out
those pins and like spit debug data out
of them constantly and you'll get some
good insight there ways to break
sub-circuits apart so I talked about
isolating circuits every power supply
design has like a fuse or a zero ohm
resistor that I remove and see if it's
doing the right thing you need to gain
buffer amplifiers so if you have an
analog circuit and you have an extra op
amp somewhere like tie it to something
or don't put test points and solder
wires later and like LEDs everywhere
more of them all of the time all right
lecture mechanical stuff I got to go
quick through this so basically an
electromechanical system is a fancy way
of saying the system probably has a
motor you debug with your senses that's
a nice thing your eyeballs
or or a camera of some sort
cheap endoscopes on Amazon things that
you're watching for are like circular
things that are out and around and like
oscillating or you can also measure
current so it's a certain part of the
cycle if you go high current then you've
probably got like something binding up
use your ear balls mechanics stethoscope
is 10 bucks and it'll get you to like
really isolate where that squeak is
happening use your fingers they are free
the other thing is I've done something
with like an IMU and Arduino to make
like a little like vibration sensor
basically like read the vibrations dump
them out to Excel and then create a bode
plot and it tells you like where that
frequency is especially if you're having
that's the bad frequency and it can tell
you something about like okay so it's at
that frequency is that because I'm
rotating at a certain speed
is that a bad speed to be rotating at
smellivision
just kidding these are done lick it's
good systems taste like umami seeing
dead people some people have that sense
that's a good one to use
so debugging for more in software this
could be its own talk and I'm sure it's
been done a zillion times
the big things to look for here is like
chip emulation can you does your dev
environment for writing code for this
chip like have an emulator that means
you don't have to flash as much you'll
have to go and measure things as much
getting the right programmer and
debugger sometimes you can buy a generic
or clone that works as well as the like
manufacturers one sometimes you can't
and having a debugger just in general is
gonna save you tons of time let's see
make unit tests so right code this is
really a software land now like right
pieces of code that check that you wrote
functions correctly basically and this
can be like a totally different piece of
software that's probably for another
talk and then yeah like I was talking
about the serial port the extra serial
port for debug it doesn't have to be
output only it can be input as well you
can inject variables into your program
with a with a debug port on the outside
write a script for it and you got a
fancy like like hardware in the loop
unit tester when not to debug if you
have lots of Units they were inexpensive
and only one of them is freaking out
don't waste your time move on and get
back to it later if that thing is worth
your time well that being said can be a
great learning experience if you do have
the time okay so conclusions I just
wanted to like put gifts on slide
and then share some of my knowledge with
all of you debugging is an art like
skating is an art there's a muscle
memory to it or like a brain muscle
memory just got to do it a lot and
you'll know the right tool and the right
way to use that tool later everything is
experienced so just keep doing it
utilize the people around you this
community is like the best for finding
the people who will help out debugging
your circuits so like I can just pull
somebody aside pull me aside check all
your assumptions be methodical use the
right equipment
someone quick plug we're hiring I run
the electrical and software teams so
like we work on crazy stuff at motivo
like I'm not joking flying cards
autonomous vehicles AG tech like
planting harvesting processing personal
mobility custom factory automation all
this crazy stuff and like I'm always
looking for enthusiastic people right
like we'll teach you a bit about how to
do the stuff like I want enthusiasm and
passion anyway that's all thank you
[Applause]