hi everybody that was a great
introduction so I think I can just dive
right in and start talking before I go
if anybody wants to like ask me any
questions it's no big deal raise your
hand I'm happy to chat about any of this
but to start we're gonna talk about
scrounging which is figuring out how
you're gonna power your system sipping
it so once you're at your powered system
how are you gonna just take as much as
you need and no more and then the third
thing which I think is most important is
seeing power so how are you gonna
validate your system to be sure it'll
always work instead of like I hope I
have enough power from that solar panel
in there to make it run the big thing to
remember here is its architecture it's
all about architecture if you have a bad
architecture it doesn't matter how nice
your switch mode power supply system is
running I don't care if it's 98% if you
got another chip in there that's
consuming like a milliamp all the time
with no sleep function it's game over so
you have to make sure that as you're
picking things out at the beginning of
the design phase you're getting it right
and that even comes down to the type of
power that you use so just like being at
the bar at 2:00 a.m. the fact that
they're serving beer at 2:00 a.m.
doesn't mean you necessarily want the
beer at 2:00 a.m. you might want to wait
on it it's just like that with with some
alternative energies will start with
wave energy
everybody likes wave energy because it's
like all the rest of the power sources
we're talking about it's free so you can
grab it from waves you can grab it from
people spinning dynamos you can grab it
from people biking but you want to do
some back of the envelope calculations
before you dive into this first because
it's a lot of moving parts and it's
annoying and expensive second it's
really not a lot of power so if you have
somebody saying they're turning a crank
that's like 10 Watts turning a crank for
six minutes to get one watt hour it's
like that's not a good deal you don't
want to be doing that so another way to
consider it is the wave energy equation
or the kinetic energy equation we have
here if you put something on the ocean
and you expect a linear charger so base
coil wire on the outside and a mass on
the inside with a magnet that one-half
MV squared is what is operating on your
little tiny mass that's going up and
down so if you calculate that like okay
my mass weighs this much and it's gonna
go this fast because the waves are going
this fast how much energy that is it's
usually not a lot especially relative to
the entire contraption that you're
running and what you might want to think
about is maybe I should just put a giant
battery in there because the chances are
you're gonna be designing a circuit
that's so low powered that you could
service that battery every 10 years so
do I really want to spend the time the
money and all the risk associated with
these devices so that I can say I'm
running on wind or wave in this case
it's not always a good circumstance so
in other technology I want to talk about
is thermoelectric if you have a
situation where you've got a ton of heat
and you can grab that it'd be great to
run on power forever
volcano suite engines awesome they're
really great but the trick is you have
to get that heat out all these so I gave
an example of a part that can generate a
little over half a watt but that's
assuming you have a sixty degrees C
temperature differential and in order to
maintain that if you have something
sitting at let's say 150 degrees you
have to get the other side of the
thermoelectric generator down to 90
degrees so now you've got to dissipate
all that heat on something that's this
thin and transferring heat from that 150
degree C side out the other end so now
it's not a circuit question it's a
thermodynamics and a mechanical
engineering question how are you gonna
get that heat out how are you gonna keep
the cold side cold the other thing is
it's not only if you messed that up that
you don't get the power you were
expecting but they have a thermal limit
to these devices so if you design
something in that's sitting on 150
degrees C engine or whatever and it's
got a 200 degree C absolute max before
it starts to get damaged so if your
engine overheats what happens have you
been able to keep it cool enough are you
okay to keep running on this system so
you want to consider very carefully is
this really the right choice for me or
should I go with another approach
usually the way people go through things
it's like the most sexy covered in news
alternative energy to the least so I'm
kind of following that track the next
one is solar and solar is wonderful
because it's more reliable than the
other two like you can generally figure
out what you're gonna have I went on the
EU runs a delightful website where you
can go on and you can tell it for this
location and my solar panel is gonna be
at 30 degrees or zero degrees how much
power should I expect and they give you
this graph in like five seconds I put
the link in so if you get the slides I
would anybody that wants to use solar
power grab this graph and it's striking
how little power exists so I live in
beautiful Rochester New York and I
pulled up what a six watt panel would do
for me and it turns out its point it's
four point one one watt hours for a six
watt panel per day so that means it's
the same as if you put it in full Sun
for 45 minutes that's a lot to think
about when you're saying do I really
want to have solar power running here
you're gonna be generating tons here all
summer long not so much in the cold cold
dark winter of Rochester so another
thing I want to talk about with solar is
MPPT so maximum power point tracking and
it applies not just to solar but also
thermoelectric and you want to focus on
this maximum power point where the solar
panel sits it'll be in the spec sheet
like we would like you to be at five
volts in order to get the specified six
Watts out okay great so there's lots of
chips some of them you can program like
I want you to regulate your output
current so that your input voltage stays
at five volts that's called maximum
power point programming and then there's
maximum power point tracking which you
set that and then it did 'old its input
voltage in case there's like a cloud or
the sun just rose or whatever it'll find
the maximum power point at that time and
that's Malick's and power point tracking
so this is like amazing and everybody
that I talk to says we got to have it we
got to have MPPT
because we're running on solar and
that's the way to get the most energy
out but all the chips that run this
unless you wanted to roll your own
solution with the microcontroller all
the chips that do this cost between five
and twenty five milliamps to run that so
if you're doing 30 watts it's like sweet
run it and PPT hundred percent got to
have it but if you've got like a 1 watt
or a 3 watt panel sitting on there now
all the sudden your efficiencies are
getting killed by that offset and even
worse in the morning you might be using
more energy than you're getting because
the Sun just rose and you're chewing up
twenty five milliamps but you're only
getting five or ten so it's a bad deal
in a lot of cases to the point where
putting in a linear charger and dealing
with all the heat loss is a preferable
solution not to mention like a tenth of
the cost so make sure that you're
considering all these fancy devices they
have relative to what your system
requires here's a couple pitfalls that I
just wanted to note it's around the fact
that a solar panel could be at zero
volts and it could be at seven point
seven volts while I keep giving this six
volt panel this is the specs of the 6
volt panel it's got an open circuit
maximum of 6 volts all right I'm sorry 7
point 7 volts 6 watt panel 7 point 7
volts open circuit there is a supplier
that sells that panel with this charge
chip with an absolute maximum rating of
7 volts that's probably not good it's
probably fine if you're just like
building one or two but if you put that
into a product that's going to be sold
that's probably going to be a mistake
you'll get your nail by that so you want
to be mindful of the large swings
similarly a lot of these places depend
on you having this huge open circuit
voltage in the case of this is 36 52
this is one of the MPPT chips this
bi-linear they need seven and a half
just to get started so they show you
like in their app note or their design
notes like here we have our six watt six
volt panel running with this chip and
it's like well yeah but until we get a
sunny day to kick the thing off it's not
gonna even start running so you might be
11 o'clock in the morning before you
start capturing an energy so you always
want to be mindful of like
this could be almost no voltage or a lot
of voltage it could be a lot of current
or almost little current alright so
that's how we got our power there's
there's plenty of power for what we want
hopefully if we did our calculations
correctly so we're gonna move on to how
we're gonna use that power all right LED
debug LEDs the last guy was talking
about debug LEDs they're awesome when
you're plugged into a wall burning fuel
to run your system not so great when
you're trying to count micro amps so
there's two design goals that inevitably
come out of the situation and every
design will sit in one of these two
places all the time you either have a
ton of power like to the point where you
could use more if you had more things to
do it's free power it's there your
battery's full your system can pull
energy out of the environment faster
than you can use it or you've used it
all up it's the dark cold winter and you
don't know how you're gonna get through
the rest of the day
both of these scenarios happen all the
time and you get to pick when you're
deciding how the balance between how
much power you use and what generation
system you want to use you to pick how
much time you want to spend in either of
these environments but there is no
situation where you get to skip on both
of them which brings me to my next point
the be my if you ask my wife how we
track our finances in the house she goes
mmm that's the B we don't talk about the
B it's the budget that you have to run
for every system as you get generating
power using power and with alternative
energy you have to calculate multiple
different iterations of it back getting
back to you're either starving for
energy or you've got way more than you
think you could ever use so if you're
running your low power mode maybe you
slow your data rate down what does the
power budget look like in that use case
or if you're gonna say like alright we
got to run firmware updates because our
battery's full and we got tons of
sunlight let's run firmware updates what
does that power budget look like how
much time can I run that firmware update
before I start to deplete my battery to
a point where I have to worry about
breaking my device so there's all these
different considerations that you want
in the the power budget is really what
comes down to and you want that
documented and I'll go into why in a
second and validation phase another
condition that you have to consider
you're here when you're running your
power budgets is the shipment condition
so you put you design this product
that's beautiful it's wonderful it goes
on a boat and it's six there for three
months and it probably sits in a
warehouse for six more months what's it
doing how much powers are consuming when
your customer opens it up is it gonna be
dead how pissed would you be opening up
your $200 device and you get an opium
like please put in the Sun for six hours
before you so it's like I live in
Rochester but I can get six hours of Sun
until May 6 hours do you want to be
mindful of all these conditions that
come up all the time the other thing you
want to consider is over discharge
situations so inevitably what your
customer is going to your clients going
to do or your end-users gonna do is
they're gonna take the device they're
gonna use it for however long they're
gonna use it they're gonna deplete the
battery till it shuts itself off and
then are sticking in the closet for six
months or 12 months so what's your
device doing in that scenario are you
gonna self discharge the battery to the
point where it no longer is a battery
it's just a big lump of nothing all
right so there's things you can do like
putting in protection surgeries
absolutely cutting everything off before
you get to the point where the battery
cuts itself off so that you could have
you know six months 12 months 24 months
before the battery actually starts to
DES
kill itself because it's been sitting
there doing nothing and the last piece
is you always want to see if you can is
there a way to get wall power to charge
your device inevitably
somebody's gonna want that like all the
time somebody's gonna want that so if
you can put a little charger in there
even if somebody's got to take apart a
panel or something it'll win every time
otherwise you're gonna have a lot more
returns from the customer saying hey
it's broken and I'm not gonna wait six
hours and son to get to come back okay
so we've got our power we're using our
power we have our power budget we think
we have a product we got a product we
feel good everything's running the way
we think it should run what are we gonna
do about seeing it and validating the
power I have this
axiom that my clients both love and hate
they love it when I'm trying to get a
jobs like if I don't see it work it
doesn't work they love hearing that
until it's time to release the product
and they're like what do you mean you
can't release it yet you're not done
testing nope haven't seen everything
work and I would encourage everybody to
take that approach especially when
dealing with these weird power
situations because there's so many
opportunities for people to put
themselves in a situation where the
device can't bring itself back to life
so here's for a long time I was using
this really nice source/measure unit to
do all my low current testing and then I
got to the point where I had to count
like nano amps so I put together this
this device and I thought it was trivial
but to the point where I after I started
using it I hit myself in the face me
like how did I think of this sooner so
everybody here might have thought of
this but I wanted to make sure that I
put this up anybody with the DMM can do
low current measurements if you put a
very large sense resistor in and then a
switch that you can flip for when the
system boots up and then once it goes
into low-power mode so you'd like have
an LED and your firmware turn off when
he goes in a low-power mode you flip the
switch and you start measuring the
device really simple I hope I'm not
boring you but I've used it so many
times that I think it would really help
people out
all right so there is a special warm
warm feeling I get when I can validate
that my system uses the to my cramps or
the one my gram or whatever the the
budget says and I see it on my readout
like oh that is nice but there's a
firmware exercise that's even better
than that and that's stepping down the
power by turning each chip off one at a
time and then you can validate your
power budget at each stage so I know
that my LED driver chip turned off I
know that my Wi-Fi chip turned off I
know that whatever chips are going
shutting down and watch each one because
you could be in a situation where even
though you're getting all the way down
it's not as you expected and you've got
to reconsider all of your power budgets
because something well everything
together works it might not work the way
you expected and it'd be worth checking
out and then let's say you don't get
that warm feeling and I this I swear to
god this happens every time you plug it
in you get it so that it's running and
you're using more power than you thought
I hate that so you got it you got to
find the leak right and so the firmware
test where you step it down is a great
tool especially because it doesn't
involve a soldering iron but I just
start ripping stuff off the board I mean
KCl matters so you can pull stuff off
the board like okay here's a note of
current I'm gonna take that branch off
I'm gonna take that branch off while
watching the current and seeing what
Falls and then you can figure out what
part is consuming stuff so I've got an
image there of like I just ripped all
that circuit up with a hot air pencil
you know heat it up and push it off and
you can take it to the point where you
can see what each part uses it's very
common to do things if I if you forget
to connect like a solar panel believe it
or not your circuit can consume more
energy than if it was not there because
it was expecting a load at the input of
your charge circuit and wasn't there and
so you're using more energy than you
thought I mean by like micro ramps but
it's still enough to get you running
around your lab for a couple days
wondering where the hell all this power
is going
mmm I love this slide because it usually
frustrates firmware engineers to no end
I so in the release package for firmware
I have ADD
many different power tests because as
I'm sure anybody who's done low power
systems knows you can make one very
small change to firmware and have a very
large impact on power budget and usually
what it is is the changing of how often
the thing wakes up so if you went from
waking up once a second to once a
millisecond that's a big power
difference and so you can quickly throw
it on the scope and just verify you know
are we getting the ticks that we were
expecting are we seeing all the power
jumps that we thought we would see and
if you can check that then you can be
comfortable about releasing the design
okay and the last piece is validating
all the possible use cases
so a typical charge/discharge curve I
had to I designed a system here that was
charging and we had if you look the
green is voltage and it cut off charging
I'm sorry the green is current it cut
off charging before it was really
supposed to and so it gotten in this
motorboating condition where it would
the battery would relax after it didn't
get that whatever current I was giving
it yeah I was getting like half an amp
after it stopped getting that half an
amp the battery voltage would relax and
it would say oh I got to charge it again
and you charge it again and then it
would come back down and it would charge
again the reason being the cutoff
current of the constant voltage phase of
that charger was wrong and so you got
into this that that situation and so
you're not getting as much energy as you
should
not to mention that doesn't look very
nice so you want to validate that by
just watching it on the scope set your
scope to the slowest way and just let it
do it slow curve up and watch the
current fall just like I have here the
other thing that you got to be very
mindful of is a cloud event so in solar
clouds come how's your system deal with
that it's all happy running in steady
state and then a cloud comes in the
entire front end of your power system
has got the feet knocked out from under
it what are you gonna do about that so
you want to make sure that you can
handle that it's you can use just like
newspaper or whatever to simulate that
it's really easy to do it's not a big
deal but you don't want to get into a
situation where it just shuts off and
gives up until it goes totally dark and
starts back again which somehow some
charge chips do so you got to be mindful
of reality coming and hitting yet
motorboating motorboating on weak power
input so the Sun rises every day and
delivers power to your solar panel in
very small amounts and it ramps up
throughout the day that happens every
day if you have a chip or if you have a
battery that's like I don't know way way
down if a chip would wake up it would
say you need to get energy but you only
need a little bit because if you're in
an under voltage protection situation
like if your battery cells at two point
six volts on a lithium ion it says you
really shouldn't be getting our full
charge current until you have two point
eight two point nine something like that
so I'm going to give you this really
tiny amount of charge current so it will
hold there for a little while and if you
I'm sorry I'm doing the back from dead
scenario I I'll do that in a second so
the motorboating on weak power input is
the Sun comes up it's just a very small
amount of power and the battery says
great I need tons of power give me
everything you got and it shuts down the
solar panel like it just collapses it it
says oh I guess the Sun went away and so
it sits there and does nothing and then
after it gives up on charging it tries
again and it realizes that it's taking
too much power and shuts down tries
again and again and again and again
again this whole time you're not
generating energy and so we're back in
the scenario where it gets a little to
11 a.m. and you haven't saved any power
in your battery in your whole budgets
way off so you've got to be mindful of
how you're gonna handle that now back
from dead if you have this system that's
way under charged and you don't give it
enough power to get through that under
voltage protection then you can be in a
situation where it never comes back does
it make sense
I have no idea why I wrote that inside
last week so I'll just skip back so
that's everything I really wanted to go
over