[Music]
welcome back our next speaker really
caught my eye when she started building
amazing art pieces around old cathode
ray tubes but she doesn't work in all
kinds of mediums in wood in metal even
in human bone
she's gonna tell us how she pulls off
these amazing projects today please join
me in welcoming to the hack at a super
conference stage
Emily Velasco hey everyone how you doing
you excited you ready to get weird I
don't know
are you guys ready yeah all right let's
go okay so my talk is why you should
make ugly weird and annoying things
because that's what I do and I want you
guys to do it too so um yeah let's get
started here that's next okay so why
indeed when I was putting this talk
together I was sitting around my house
and trying to think like well I want to
encourage you all to make weird annoying
things but like I found myself at kind
of I was I was kind of stuck I was like
well why like I hadn't honestly thought
about it like I do this but like why do
I do it like I do it because it's fun
but like if I'm gonna make a case for
all of you to do it like I need to like
use my words and like talk and explain
things so um you know for the longest
time like as long as I can remember I
have enjoyed weird things I like where
music I like weird clothes I like weird
architecture
I just really love weird stuff and um
like but why like what is it about it so
I thought about it some more and it was
like well I don't know that I can tell
any of you why you should make weird
things but I'm gonna tell you why I like
to make weird things and maybe you'll
find that you agree with some of these
things so um
yeah that was one of my recent projects
this was the Dethklok and the idea
behind that like this was honestly
project partially borne out of spite I
was asking people for ideas my friend
Roger and I Rogers here in the audience
we were we were doing something with his
vacuum for us and display and we wanted
to make something out of it and I asked
people on Twitter like what should I do
with it my all said make a clock and I
was like no there's a million vacuum
fluorescent display clocks out there but
they are all like make a clock and I was
like fine I'll make a clock I'm gonna
make a death clock so what this does is
when you touch the little capacitive
touch sensor it kind of reads reads you
and then it tells you when you're gonna
die it gives you a day at a time stuff
like that sets the stage for like just
this is like the kind of level of weird
stuff I work on so as I said like I
really have a good time making weird
stuff like it's just it's not the
ordinary and it really kind of like
gives me something like to kind of
stretch my boundaries with so you know
how like for a lot of people there comes
a moment in their life when they when
they discover something they see
something that kind of opens their
horizons it kind of opens their mind
they have like a dawning realization
about something that like really feels
right to them so for me that moment came
when I was 12 there was a movie that
came out this that year that really
liked it there was there was something
in that movie that really clicked with
me and I don't know if you guys you
might you might know where I'm going
with this yeah so uh
Toy Story came out in 1995 I was 12 and
said our good friend sit here
he was he was undoubtedly the villain of
the movie right like like the toys we're
trying to rescue it was woody I think
that you had woody right and like he he
turned those toys into like these mutant
monster toys and like maybe he was a
villain because like I there's probably
some consent issues involved there with
those poor toys but honestly like the
things that he made in that movie were
so much more interesting than anything
else I had seen in my life and like much
more interesting than anything else in
the movie like I like those mutant toys
way better than like the good toys right
I I can imagine right that was probably
their excuse to work some weird things
in the movie right so like there's
probably some kid roots for its there um
and they're just great like you have a
baby head on like a mechanical spider
and you have like there's there's the
fishing pole with the woman's legs and
there's like the the montt the
bodybuilder with the duck head like
they're so good like they're a mishmash
of parts they're made of things that
like don't belong together but like at
the same time they go really well
together and like you know the other
toys were afraid of them right like
these were the monsters they were scared
of them but like kind of the moral of
the story is that it turns out that
those like scary monster weird toys like
are their friends - right like so that's
the thing that I really like about
making weird things is like you can make
something really weird and really ugly
and really kind of like off-putting but
like making something with a lot of love
and so that like someone looks at it at
first and they like kind of cringe and
they go what did you make that for but
the more time they spend with it like
the more they start to see the charms
and that that's one thing that I really
like about making these weird things is
that like you can make something that
like on one hand like violates all kinds
of aesthetic sensibilities but on the
other hand is just so freakin cool
so let's go through some definitions
real quick I know that's boring but like
if I'm gonna be throwing around these
terms like ugly weird and annoying like
we should talk about definitions
definitions so ugly um yeah it's just
pleasing to the eye not aesthetically
pleasing displeasing to the ear or some
other sentence like okay that's pretty
straightforward
weird having an unusually strange
character or behavior deviating from the
normal bizarre let's remember that point
like deviating from the normal and then
annoying causing annoyance annoyance
that what's your nose like okay great
alright let's forget that okay so the
one thing that all of those three terms
have in common is that their value
judgments right like these are opinions
like someone says something is ugly
something someone says something is
annoying something says someone says
something is weird like that's their
judgement of that thing but they're just
opinions they're aesthetic
princess-like what one person thinks is
ugly you might be really beautiful to
someone else and like if you have
different experiences from someone what
you think is normal might be different
than what someone else thinks is normal
right
and even like something that's annoying
it might be annoying to you at one time
of the day and like great at another
time of the day like if it's a hot day
and it's afternoon you heard the
ice-cream man like yeah like it's
ice-cream man right but if it's like
2:00 in the morning in the ice cream
man's parked out of your house like
that's the worst so yeah so it's all
contextual it's like what is the context
in which you're observing these things
experiencing these things and that's
another thing I really like about making
things that are weird there's like
there's a context to all of it and and
and it changes for people all the time
it's fluid and it's dynamic and there's
a really great quote by this composer
named John Cage that touches on this
point and so he says the first question
I asked myself when something doesn't
seem to be beautiful is why I do why I
do not think it's beautiful
and very shortly you discover that there
is no reason and that's that's really
true like we a lot of times like it's
the old saying like don't judge a book
by it's cover
and like we immediately make a value
judgment about things when we see them
but like if we take time to experience
them and like observe them and interact
with them like our experience can change
and like the way we value them can
change and you know that that really
that's another point that really like
gets to the heart of what I like about
making weird ugly and annoying things is
that like we can we can change that for
people and what he's saying is like you
know you know think critically about
what you're looking at and like
experience it for what it is don't just
like rely on your first judgments and
because you know you might be missing
out on something that you could
otherwise be enjoying you know if you
just say like oh well that thing is
awful and then you just want to walk
away like you might be missing out on
something so like what I want to do with
making weird things is like letting
people experience these things and and
and reassess what it what weird is to
that reassess what is nour abnormal to
them
reassess like what is this that
we pleasing to them so you know
sometimes when I made something well not
sometimes like always when I made
something and I show them to someone
like they always like they there's a
reaction like usually it's like well why
why did you make that what is that
supposed to do it's off-putting and so
one of these projects here this is my
circumvent noise box after I made this I
took it over to my parents house when I
went for a visit because I have a
gratuitous need for affirming approval
and so so I took it over there to show
my parents because I'm not 36 years old
and like my own person right so I took
it over and I turned it on for them and
my dad rolled his eyes and he groaned
and it's like oh god what is em doing
now like what is that awful thing but I
handed it to him and I told him to try
this thing out and so he did and he took
it and he started pressing some of the
buttons
[Music]
and he started twisting some of the
knobs and then he started pressing the
body contact points and like the noises
he were making were just terrible to
everyone else right
he had hated the box until I gave it to
him to try and like it became a thing
for him to control and a thing for him
to play with and you know what like five
minutes later he was still playing with
that box and he was annoying the hell
out of everyone else in the family but
you know I he was sitting there on his
recliner and he was laughing he was like
just totally into this box and just five
minutes before he had just thought it
was the worst thing he had ever seen and
he was totally into it and that's that's
what I mean when I like to talk about
context is that like if you can change
the context for people then you can
change their experience the thing that
like was so annoying had become fun for
him and I make weird things because I
want other people to enjoy weird things
as much as I do I want to share that
with people like I don't know what it
what it is about like the way I formed
as a child that said like I'm gonna like
weird things but like I get such joy out
of weird things and I really want other
people to be able to experience that
with me too and I think that's maybe
becoming a little bit harder these days
because we live in a world that is like
so much is polished by like Biden design
committees and polished by focus groups
and by marketing teams and strategies
and like the things that exist in the
world around us like all of our products
they're polished and polished and
polished like rough edges get smoothed
down like weird things get sounded off
like everything is made to be
inoffensive to the senses before it
leaves the drawing board
right well most of the time right like
don't look at am i who don't look at an
eye so um who here remembers Calvin and
Hobbes can I give show hands okay so I
had to joke about being an old
millennial but I'm not I guess I'm not
that old so yeah there was this this
strip there was a whole series right and
and it was like a like a side plot and
Calvin and Hobbes go digging for fossils
and they just got to the woods and they
dag and all that they ended up finding
is a bunch of like rusty cans and like
old cups and like a coke bottle and some
old silverware but like Calvin is
convinced that like they're gonna go out
there and find fossils and so like to
him those are fossils they're not trash
they're fossils and he takes them back
to his house and he's convinced they're
a dinosaur so he assembles them into
this dinosaur and like he's given them a
new narrative and like you see here like
Hobbs draws it for him and it's it's a
weird like kissing dinosaur but like
that that is the essence of like what is
great about making weird things is that
you can take things that don't belong
together and put them together and you
give them a new context and give them a
new narrative and like that's not trash
anymore right
like that was just trash that was
littering the forest and now to him it's
a dinosaur skeleton like he has
transformed those things into something
else and I love that because like that's
what I work like the things that I make
I make them out of stuff I find you know
I have I have like these bird skulls
here like these I found on a beach in
Northern California with with the bird
still attached they were not alive at
the time okay so but like I can take
like parts of animals that like have
deceased I can take old cigar boxes I
can take out funnel I can take another
like wooden box hiding inside of here is
like some cheap children's toy I found
at the thrift store this is another
cigar box this is a knob I found it at a
at a scrapyard
there's a piece of metal here that I
found on the side of the road like I can
take all these things that I just find
out in the world and like transform them
into something new and like I give them
new life and they're not ending up in
the landfill there and and not only are
they not ending up in the landfill
they're like taking on new meaning and I
think that's really cool
because you know a lot of times when you
work on a project you can start with raw
materials you can go to the store you
can buy wood you can buy like angle iron
you can buy glass and you can make your
project exactly the way you wanted it to
be you can have a vision in your head
and you can create that
exact thing which is a good feeling like
don't get me wrong but when you work
with materials that you find you have to
let the materials partially direct your
creative process like they join you
they're part of like this design
committee and so like you might have an
idea about what you want your project to
be but then you take ugly weird and
things that you found out in the woods
or on the side of the street like
literally these joists these buttons
these arcade buttons some went through
an arcade machine out of their truck
next to my house and it exploded on the
road and it got run over by cars and I
took as many parts off of it as I could
but when you do that like you're
allowing your project to go places you
didn't expect maybe and honestly like
most of my projects like I have an idea
but then I start working with my
materials and then they end up going
someplace that I didn't expect and
usually they end up weirder than I
thought they were gonna be and that's
really refreshing because it's kind of a
surprise it makes you work your creative
muscles a little bit more to work with
the materials you have and then you end
up with something that not even you're
expecting to see and that is such a fun
feeling so in conclusion like there's
nothing wrong with normal but there's
nothing inherently right about normal
either
and when we would decide that one thing
is normal and another thing is abnormal
we're setting limits on ourselves we're
saying like these are the things that
are okay and these are the things that
are not and I don't think we should be
limiting ourselves you know like you
don't want it like why put all those
things like in the closet and say like
those are not okay like no like there's
a lot of stuff in the world that like is
overlooked and is forgotten and like
that no one wants but those things are
wonderful for making your projects and
they will bring such like a different
flavor to your projects
we live in this world with this pressure
that everyone experiences to be normal
like that's like if you've been through
junior high like you felt that like like
don't do anything weird because like
you're gonna be the outcast you know
wear normal clothes like get a normal
job like go to normal places and have
normal hobbies but that's very limiting
and I don't want you to be limited
because you you're all creative people
you're here you're creative and I want
you to be able to like stretch your
creative abilities
as far as they can go so like next time
you think about something and you think
like well that's weird
like you see something and think that's
weird like ask yourself why is it weird
and ask yourself if it's really weird
like what makes it feel weird to you and
maybe you'll find that that weird thing
isn't so weird after all and maybe
you'll find that you'll find some
weirdness in your own life to enjoy so
thank you