[Music]
all right everybody ready to go was that
very sleepy from after lunch I can't
hear you all right
all right so our next speaker is a
writer who contributes to the tindy blog
popular science hackaday among others
and in his spare time he embraces his
inner maker by posting videos to YouTube
about his latest project he today he's
here to take us through his this guy his
little personal strand beast so please
welcome to the heck at a stage
Jeremy cook well thanks so much for that
intro Brian I guess I'll let my strand
beasts I called the clear crawler
introduce it to itself all right so
there's my little clear crawler just
crawling around on the garage floor my
garage
it's 15 a half inches in high about 150
rpm motors various things like that
controlled by Nanna off 24 l01 remote
control and lots and lots of bearings
lots of gears so
so that being Selma going through how I
made this
all right there we go so my talk is
called stron beasts from impossible bill
to dominating in my garage and these
these beasts have been in my garage for
probably six years or so went from kind
of a kind of a project that I thought I
would never be able to do to something
that well I've made at least six of them
at this point so you know as far as
media like Brian said I'm engineer
experimenter technical writer somebody
who has a kind of a hard time telling
people what I do when they ask me
feature in a hackaday and I've written
there as well and most importantly for
year I love making things the first
first step in this was I got inspired
somebody sent me a video of a guy named
Jo Johnson which he made this incredible
strand bisa talked around on the beach
and I just thought you know I saw that I
thought well you know I can I can maybe
maybe do something like that right I
thought basically I thought I'd never be
able to do someone like that and as I
thought about it more and more I decided
to just just make one one linkage one
leg and the way these work is that
you've got one one linkage on the on the
center that actually it's all these all
these legs through just linkages so if
you've got two two motors one on each
side you can drive it kind of like a
tank and what's shown here is is four
four legs and mine uses eight because
with four it just tends to to buckle
back and forth quite a bit it this it's
not really that smooth but um you know
like I said I tried it I thought well I
can make one one leg you know that
wasn't a big deal then I thought well I
could make a base for this and I could
make three more and then well like I
came to this and as you can see this is
almost the size of a golf court current
I never got this to quite work correctly
you know part of the reason I didn't
have pick enough motors on it lots of
friction and it just you know I was just
trying to do a precision instrument with
very imprecise tools which makes
tellenson his beast you know he made it
at a PVC pipe which I still don't know
how they did it I mean it seemed amazing
to begin with but now that I've built
several it just seems almost impossible
especially under wind power but this one
see
little bit too big and so you know what
did I do it and set it four legs I made
it with eight legs and here's me and uh
my my cousin trying to try it out and
push it across the the garage
it broke soon after this so it never
quite worked the way I wanted it's a cut
out of MDF and it's very very heavy yeah
and after that I decided to scale it
down made someone gonna call this the
stron - mouse this actually worked
pretty well it's got a a quadcopter as a
controller so you know as quad copters
are steel or seared differentially so
you can power all the motors up in the
same at the same amount and it'll go
forwards but if you change how much
you're you're giving to each motor that
thing will steer like a tank and this
did work for for a while until it fell
apart everything was it was kind of kind
of glued together so this is you know
the other two are too big this is maybe
a little bit too small and then after
that I made one that was just right and
this one to this day it'll still work
it's got a great linkage system the
middle it's got gears so all that torque
is transmitted down a central shaft
rather than using like a camshaft
mechanism like like Talos and got to
give a shout-out to a Joe who goes up a
hobby engineer he he I think he's the
one that came up with this central shaft
mechanism really really good design and
after that I decided to scale it up
again made something out of clear
polycarbonate called this one the clear
Walker really beautiful never got it to
work quite as well as as tailee onsen
would you know as his beast but then I
tried to actually make a kit this one
rot launches rockets which was that was
a lot of fun and then finally I came to
at the clear crawler this one
somebody geek mom project she came up
with the name for this I asked about
that on Twitter and shout-out to her too
but this one is clear polycarbonate so
it looks has the same look as it big bit
clear Walker but it's you know small
enough that I can get it to walk around
really well which I'll demonstrate in
just a minute
not since
learned through this whole process you
know bigger isn't always better
Big Brother cut off switch which I'll
show that a little later is awesome I
had a couple of those lying around and I
made that a big priority than this
design which is maybe a little bit
superfluous I guess but it was really
fun
differential steering not just for tanks
and then barians bearings bearings
bearings bearings you need all kinds of
bearings for something like this just
the the torque the the friction just
adds up just astronomically after a
while so this whole thing it's got 88
thrust bearings 11 per leg and it could
be a kid even you some other bearings I
mean you could probably put twice as
many bearings on it make it even better
if you want to do you know controls wise
it's very simple it's just two motors
one goes for the other goes forward or
whatever and yeah so that's not so toes
there's that big red switch I was
talking about really love that and it's
functional too because you turn it on
and the the driving motors can go and he
turn it off and everything else is on
but the driving motors there's no power
to them so you can diagnose stuff
without having to worry about it
crawling off the table on you and if it
does crawl away you can you flip it off
so that's that's nice there's the
differential control method you've got
the one one motor on the left side one
on the right you know just like a tank
both goes both go forward it goes
forward both back both back or then some
combination will go left and left and
right there's another picture of the one
of the the leg linkages that's it's
basically acting as a central rotation
there so you've got four of these per
side and then four legs just going going
on and on yeah I think the clear
polycarbonate really really shows it off
nicely and this is all cut on a CNC
router designed in the CAD system like
like AutoCAD oh I guess I'd knock off on
okay you call it yeah 11 thrusts barians
there's another shot of that and yeah
now it's time for the other demo so
let's check it out
so you can see there one thing I've got
I've got to pivot on it goes left and
right down up and down and then it's got
a little little um beeper on it - what
you I guess you can hear it so yeah and
then if I press forward on the control
goes forward backwards and then I can do
right left and then let's see if it if
it goes forward too fast it has a hard
time because the legs tend to jam up a
little bit so let's see if I can get it
to not walk off the table there we go so
yep there it goes
yeah it almost did that you know I get
asked the question sometimes is this
good off-road and it's it's very much
not it can simulate a wheel pretty well
because the linkage system is designed
in such a way that each each foot will
travel up and then go just down flat for
a while so I've found that for four legs
in each side will simulate I guess two
wheels just like a car pretty pretty
well but one is not enough and three I
haven't tried because that's just you
know the work just adds up master anomic
lee after a while so yeah I guess do you
guys have any questions about how I made
this or anything about the design
anything I can answer yes or yes
let's see it's kind of the unauthorized
collaboration okay so so he he came up
with the linkage lengths for each of the
legs like like that's entirely his
design although I guess I did maybe make
a few modifications but he's you know I
give him all the credit for that the
where I kind of came in was making the
actual design on cat and adapting into a
motorized system rather than a
wind-powered device so yeah that's the I
guess that's the extent of our
collaboration so there's another
question over so polycarbonate the legs
themselves they're made the quarter-inch
for the main parts of the legs and then
some of the supporting members you know
the the part on the top like right right
there that just kind of first strut kind
of to support the electronics that's a
of an inch and then the the larger gears
I believe that's just under half an inch
I made these pretty large so that the
the gears on the the driving gears
wouldn't kind of fall off if that makes
any sense I I tried that before in fact
on the bigger clearer Walker they didn't
have that problem my name later would
just kind of if the gears in and mess
just correctly they'd kind of fall off
of each other so yeah so that was that's
answer that yes
sure I mean I'd say the biggest thing on
this the question was how did friction
design our patter friction affect my
design choices I'd say the biggest thing
was just adding bearings after bearing
after burying it it um yeah I mean that
you know that adds up price-wise for
after a while when I made it out of MDF
I actually put some carbon powder on
some of the gears which which helped it
help to reduce friction on that I could
probably use that on this too but so far
it's yet to be yet to be necessary then
I guess I the more friction I can redo
this the smaller motors that can use to
so faster would go I guess yeah anything
else I can answer so yeah well thanks so
much for watching hope you hope you
enjoy the presentation
[Applause]