[Music]
hello welcome back everyone our next
speaker is a designer maker who has
invented holographic user interfaces
designed Electric skateboards for cats
and even created his own light field
camera he worked as a design lead for
Microsoft's augmented reality headset
the hololens
and currently leads aero Adobe's mobile
AR app for creatives in a spare time he
creates short films using abstract
effects and unique filming hardware his
talk this year takes us to experience
building cameras for the immersive
future please welcome to the hackaday
super conference stage Kim Kimble
[Applause]
hello has everyone had their coffee got
some energy back yeah
alright so hi I'm Kim this is me 10
years old with family camera at the
oshika 35 millimeter so old-school film
you know the physical stuff before we
just had cameras in our pockets I think
most of you will remember that and I'm a
camera geek so I've been using cameras
for over 30 years and enjoy using lots
of different types of cameras as I got
older from point-and-shoot here with
questionable rave attire to more fancier
35 millimeter with nicer optics that a
you know bought on eBay and then in my
college years
my first nicer Canon DSLR that my wife
got for me thank you and all this time
learning and experimenting about cameras
and learning how they work and getting
better at shooting how to frame
something that was good for me was not
having a lot of money so it really
forced me to sort of have a one shot one
kill mentality where I would like spend
a lot of time framing an image and less
time just shooting a lot of pictures so
I could really hone how to take pictures
whether it be on a medium format later
in life or a 35-millimeter or a
point-and-shoot there's one camera in
particular that really sparked my
interest and this is a stereo realist
from the 50s and this thing is a 3d
camera shoots on 35 millimeter film and
interleaves the stereo frames on a piece
of 35 millimeter film and you get these
side-by-side stereo frames like this and
this was shot on a on a camping trip and
when you flip them or look at it through
a 3d viewer you get this kind of 3d
effect so you get the 3d visual right so
it feels like you're a bit more there
you get a sense of the volume they're
just kind of fun you could see it
through those old-school you know like
if you master slide things so
a stereo viewer it really caught my
attention I like exploring new ways to
see and this was really a neat way as
someone who is learning about
photography to see in new ways I also
like playing with lenses so macro lenses
are also really interesting so this is a
feather up close and also not just
capturing things that I've found but
also creating new imagery so this is a
mishmash of like Elmer's glue and food
dye and printer toner and soap and then
letting it dry and then you kind of
create these 3d structures that up close
in macro scale just look really
interesting so I took these photos and
took my photography and started doing
frame by frame animations and making
videos from them and they actually got
some traction online and really spurred
me to to do more so this is bubbles with
ferrofluid passing through fluid
dynamics and liquids and just playing
with abstraction and visuals that tell a
story through through powerful imagery
I've also explored light paintings so
that's leaving the shutter open on your
camera and then waving lights in front
of it and it captures the path of the
delight over time and so you'll get from
this type of motion something it's
really graceful and soft like this or
you can capture geometry with
overlapping colors like this it was very
flat and 2d also played a lot around
with making it volumetric so this is
kind of one of the vessel series that I
made so this is using a technics 1,200
turntable in a very unusual way putting
lights on top of a record player and
spinning them around started playing
with this technique combined with
Arduino 'z and electronics and servos to
have them move while spinning on the
turntable
[Music]
really well online collected and viewed
it you've got a staff pick on Vimeo and
at the time that I was working on this
and sort of
Adobe and I was combining my passion for
computers and photography working on
this app called revel at the time which
was basically like Google photos but
from Adobe it doesn't exist anymore but
it was it was really exciting to be
working on this kind of intersection of
my two interest computers and
photography and so while I was on that
team the creative director from
Microsoft reached out
required me to move to Seattle Cisco and
I said that sounds really intriguing
after lots of interviews I'm very but it
ended up being this which is the hollow
ones which is a head-mounted augmented
reality computer this is me wearing it
and so basically this is you know
putting virtual things into the real
world the first type of computer like
this in around commercially available
and so I worked on the operating system
the Start menu how it appears the
gesture the team did a lot of work
around how to manipulate objects in
space and move them and place them on
physical surfaces so you're combining
the physical and the digital here and
this was you know pretty early days for
AR and VR the oculus rift dubbed kit
hadn't I think it'd just come out around
the same time so this was a brand new
medium that people were still learning
about and in terms of my interest with
cameras there was another product that
came out around the same time so this is
the the Ricoh theta s which is a 360
camera so this is one of the first 360
cameras and basically it has this really
big wide angle lens on both sides of the
camera and captures a 360 sphere and
show you the most most of you have
familiar with that and those cool you
could like scroll around on your web
browser and look at different angles of
the image but it really worked well with
this product which is the oculus rift
dev kit that came out around the same
time and let you see the world kind of
like around you right like you're inside
of it and that's not a big surprise new
thing today but back in you know the mid
to 2010s it was a pretty innovative and
new so that was cool you could like be
inside this photosphere and look all
around but something that was missing
for me as you saw in my images I like to
focus on a subject right like when we
take a picture if I take a picture of
the crowd here I'm gonna point my camera
this way I'm gonna frame you over here
right I'm not gonna point my camera this
way and hope that you look over it like
you look over there so one of the
challenges with 360 content is sort of
providing context and framing and
directorial view on what you want to
show right you can't control the the
person's physical turning away from your
subject and so I was curious could you
get something like this the feeling of
being immersed and being inside the
image which this kind of does for you
right like it gives you a little bit of
a sense of feeling like you're inside
the image and I was curious could you do
something similar to this where you
frame a subject and really provide a
vision on what you want to show the
viewer and so I started thinking about
John Gaia's work from ILM and he worked
on the bullet time from the matrix and
that's basically a massive array of
cameras that are spread around the set
and you've got Keanu Reeves here doing
his thing and you're just switching from
camera to camera and you get this kind
of like the bullet time effect right
like we're probably all familiar with
that
and so I was like well could I take the
whole idea of a 360 sorry a 3d image
where instead of just having two frames
having more than one frame basically
like creating a horizontal rail
something that I could carry around so
that was kind of a design goal for me
was to make a portable camera that I
could bring to places so I started on a
project I knew nothing about how to make
hardware or didn't knew little about
electronics and I just know then by
getting some rails right you want to
make a linear rail system you need some
rails and and where do you go to buy
precision metal rails for your precision
camera home depot so so I got some
shower curtain rails and I was like well
these seem pretty straight wall curved
but precise and the reason I got curved
rails was because I was thinking about
the the notion of a focal point so what
is should the focal point of an image be
when you look in like through a window
you're kind of like looking like to a
focal point right and if you just go
parallel it kind of does something
different and so I did some proof
concepts with us basically a horizontal
slider and decided to go with the camera
roll which turned out to be a real pain
in the ass because there's so many
things that I had to solve that were
different that hadn't been done like
this and I didn't really know about a
lot about how this all works
everything from how to attach the rails
together and make sure they're like
vertically stacked just right so that if
I made some bearings slide along they
would slide accurately and precisely
using the wrong design tools to design
the carriage that rolls back and forth
so this is cinema 4d which is typically
used for VFX not for manifold 3d
modeling but I made do with tools that I
knew and was able to make some carriage
components here so here you can see some
iteration on the carriage that slides
along the rail on the right you can see
I sort of have the like I'm using the
red filament actually as the bearing
catch and then over here instead I'm
using some nylon washers to have a bit
more what's it called less friction and
so the carriage would roll along the
rail like that and basically be driven
back and forth by a belt system as you
do with most linear rails but since it's
a curved rail I had to sort of invent my
own rail system which was another real
tricky thing to figure out but basically
the the rail the belt rails slid in
between the two shower-curtain things
there and I could tune the thickness
using some pieces of card stock so
really high-tech right I'm like this
camera is going to be terrible and
obviously you want to use a DC motor
because that's completely precise and
accurate but I didn't know anything I
didn't know what I was doing I was just
interested in this idea of capturing
from multiple angles and so you probably
ask yourself and I know now maybe I
should have used some more precision
like RC you know system or an O Drive or
something that didn't exist back then
but you know I was using a DC motor
trying using the tools that I knew and
what kind of sensor should I use how
should I capture the images well I
wanted to be able to capture in the
frame of mind of the bullet-time idea
right capture high speed and so I used a
GoPro Hero 4 that could do 120 frames a
second and the concept here was to you
know slide it really fast and freeze
time because I was kind of in this like
bullet-time way of thinking
and I used Adafruit components with
Arduino to connect with Wi-Fi that was
also really hard to do because I'm not
really a programmer so lots of learning
here and I ended up with this system
here so you have GoPro sitting on top of
the carriage that slides along the
curved rail that hopefully stays
straight straight but curved aligned
okay well how does this work in practice
and I got it working and I was really
proud of it and it's it's kind of a
death machine camera it goes really fast
and it captures 120 frames a second but
one time I got to put my finger inside
one of those little holes on the rail
and it went at the same time and like
that really hurt so it's a little bit
dangerous don't do not recommend and
then also this is a this is slowed down
and you can see the amount of shake
that's happening here right like wobbly
wobbly wobbly and it's not really kind
of staying level so I did some tests
this is my wife Sophie she spoke earlier
she's also doing with abalone for
wearable projects and you can see that's
really wobbly and shaky and really not
ideal so I spent a whole lot of time
going down the rabbit hole of
stabilization and using kind of
different types of was it durometer 's
of material to try to stop it from like
you know bouncing around like that and
remove the shake and I used everything
like I'm obviously not from the right
world to be figuring this stuff out like
these are ear plugs
that's like household weather stripping
this is like packing foam so I think on
the right there's actually some proper
like shock absorber like 50 durometer
stuff even looking at like drone
stabilization techniques there so after
a lot of experimenting with stuff I knew
nothing about I was able to make it
slide pretty smooth like removed a lot
of the shake but what you'll notice is
that it's still kind of like dips down
in the middle right like as it's sliding
back and forth it's not staying level
it's not staying horizontal and I still
had in my mind
3d image pairs so I wanted to pair up
like the 3d camera the the film one I
wanted to pair up alternating frames so
that when you viewed this in VR AR it
would actually show you you know
stereoscopic images but since the stereo
pairs were could be lopsided since it's
not staying level well there was a Zola
wash I decided to like get rid of all of
this work and kind of start over and
this was a big learning for me and what
I did was actually found a camera that
was more suited to the task and so this
is a fuji film w3 stereo camera that has
two sensors built on it and so the idea
here was to just capture in stereo
natively so that when I played it back
it would actually be nice working stereo
pairs and this is the type of image this
is the kind of image that that one takes
and it's really fun to see all of the
midde
water splashes super cute dog and cool
space stuff the problem was is just like
the GoPro I didn't know how to make it
trigger easily so that was a whole
rabbit hole of trying to figure out how
to hack and reverse-engineer this
consumer camera they're hard to come by
and I had to basically take it apart and
do some stuff with voltages and traces
that also was very fraught foreign to me
and you can see my I think it's like a
spark fun board here that I'm trying to
figure out but I was able to get it to
trigger so I was able to remotely
trigger this camera I was like yeah
that's awesome so I got my test rig
going here I got a little table dolly
with a stepper motor pushing the wheel
and capturing lots of frames and
actually worked really well so I was
like this is awesome this is going to
work so I can like start to figure out
how to change my rail system to
accommodate this new design this new
element so I switched from a DC motor to
a stepper figured out how to drive it
with easy driver board attached to the
Arduino in all the ways this reduced the
complexity of having to control the
GoPro because the GoPros not made to do
this and so I can have a lot more
discrete control as I'm sure you're
aware of and then just simple things
like being able to catch the being able
to catch the
the carriage at either end so that it's
not you know just sliding around when
I'm hand-holding it adding a screen in
the back so that I could have some UI to
control the exposure time and how many
pictures it's taking so all of this
stuff needed to go into a housing
because I did want it to be portable and
it seemed to be working out in terms of
the capture so you know super low fiber
auto typing with cardboard cutting out
of wood some different wood layers here
to to make into a frame so obviously not
the most lightweight thing but it's that
the tools that I had available and the
tools that I knew how to use in the shop
how to make a curved back to this camera
was also a challenge so I actually did
some like dado like slicing in the wood
so I could curve it of course they
didn't have a dado blade so this was all
just like manual multiple cuts which let
me bend that over the back of the camera
and make a nice nice case for it
so this is kind of where it ended up in
terms of the basic build so wooden
housing you've got the shower curtain
rail with a stereo camera sliding around
give it a coat of paint this is the
basic idea here pop that in there plug
it into the hack hacked camera and it
slides back and forth and captures it
actually captures the video as it goes
back and forth and so it's getting about
a hundred stereo pair frames as its
going back and forth so this is the the
final build here and you know definitely
portability was important to me because
I wanted to go out and shoot so this is
out in the field and it can sit on a
tripod so I can actually carry it it is
a bit bulky but you know it is
technically portable out in Seattle had
fallen to your Park shooting and so this
is the type of stereo pairs that the
camera captures so this is just a still
just a side-by-side and this is what it
looks like when it's capturing the the
sequence so it's basically you know
capturing video and every one of those
frames is unique stereo pairs so when
you're wearing one of these or a VR
headset this is kind of what it feels
like
like looking at it with your eyes and
it's really hard to convey what this
feels like it's like trying to explain
to someone we're at a 360 image in VR it
looks like because you're in it well
this is like looking through a window
and as you move back and forth you're
looking with stereo inside a portal
basically so it's kind of like a portal
photograph and I was pretty stoked with
like how it came out and it in a lot of
ways it was technically imperfect but it
really satisfied my desire to make this
kind of immersive camera that was about
framing a subject and providing depth
and like looking into an image so so so
goal achieved after about a year a lot
of mistakes this is a lot of my learning
here so this is all the prototype parts
that I used when producing this and lots
of 3d printing on a MakerBot 2x lots of
learning about different subsystems of
the camera and how they did and didn't
work so this was really interesting but
it's also just as unapproachable as the
the 360 stuff if you don't have a
headset on so I was thinking about like
what if you took this concept and
applied it to technology that's
available today right like what do we
have in our pockets we have phones so
what if you made a phone that instead of
a single light sensors like a lens at
Circular imagine if this strip across
the back of a phone is actually some
kind of new optics that can capture
multiple points of light across like a
strip and so taking the idea and
conceptually applying it to what that
could be as a new type of sensor that
doesn't exist yet so you know wanted to
be handheld and just look like a regular
phone and so this is just made out of
acrylic and a lot of sanding and
polishing and some laser cutting and I
just this technology is roughly called
light field technology where you're
basically capturing light from multiple
angles so there's a company light road
that actually has been doing a lot of
work in this space around light field
technology and light field cameras so
this was sort of like okay I pulled off
the 2d 2d immersive framed image but it
was bothering me that you could only
move left and right to look through the
window board if you like moved up and
down right like I see just see different
things when I move
up and down as well so I started
sketching ideas around a 2d rail system
to do the same thing and then looking at
how to build that so this is basically a
CNC machine but I was calling it the
creative CNC so using it as a creative
tool instead of a machining tool and
basically putting a camera inside there
so we can capture all of the X&Y
coordinates of a plane so that any move
that you make when you're viewing the
image will show you the right
coordinates so this was this is not
finished yet this is still in progress
and obviously probably not technically
the most sound build because there's a
single z-axis rail and there's a lot of
weight on the front but it did it does
work and it's getting there and I'll be
replacing all of the laser-cut wood with
lumina m-- and probably adding extra
extra rail so I really like this idea
because it touches on a specific science
fiction film that I that I like I'm
actually wearing a Blade Runner shirt
today and we've probably all talked
about the the enhanced moment of Blade
Runner where the camera is like looking
behind things and around things and
actually that's totally possible with
this if this camera you know got built
because you'd actually get image data
from lots of different places right so I
like to think that you know I was able
to do this like enhance Blade Runner
moment with this with this camera so and
I think it's the November 2019 is when
Blade Runner happens so it's I think
it's kind of appropriate for today's
super gone so that's about exploring
capturing a framed image with immersion
but I was also continuing to think about
like what if you wanted to do 360
captures but instead of it just being a
flat bubble you wanted to have 3d and
maybe you wanted the camera person to be
not in the frame so one of the things
that's a problem right now is someone
who's capturing a 360 image they'll be
in the image if the cameras on a tripod
so they all have to like run behind
things and like hide when
they want to capture something so my
wife was working on something some
wearable projects and we're gonna go to
the Seattle maker fair so I made this
fun concept headset here where you are
the camera person you're capturing a 360
image and you're also wearing a
basically an AR visor that lets you see
you know the the content that you
capture so it's kind of an all-in-one
package and you know just like the the
rail system you know go high-tech or go
home this is a embroidery hoop with
circular playground express to power
some lights basically they're not
sensors they're just lights and this is
some LEDs just around an embroidery hoop
and make it look cool
and so I was a little bit like am i kind
of crazy this is like a totally crazy
idea right but apparently I'm not the
craziest person so this is from Jesus VR
the film Jesus when they did the VR
version and he's got a galaxy VR thing
that he's looking at the content through
that's captured with this and kind of
crazy like I think it's a military
helmet with some cameras strapped to it
and this is an interesting version from
like they from the 80s maybe don't know
where that came from
but this is not so far-fetched there's
actually a lot of products on the market
that are 360 camera solutions from San
Samsung from China from GE and this kind
of weird hexagonal one over here but
they're all trying to capture 360 images
and that extends to like full 360 like
up and down left and right all around
and these allow you to capture stereo
pairs so you've got 3d vision but 360 as
well so what about the crazy CNC camera
that I built well that's not not so
far-fetched either Lytro has actually
been building these concept cameras and
this is a huge machine from Lytro that's
Appling optical an optic camera that has
a whole bunch of lenses that it captures
images from each of those lenses
separately to create the light field
that lets you basically capture lots of
angles instead of just one even Adobe's
played around with this that the company
that I work for with these different
cameras that do multi optic imaging you
can actually buy these in the store this
is the light
l16 which is a camera that has 16
sensors on it so this is all still you
know like optical image capture right
it's just capturing at the image and
something that you can play back in a
device but what about new ways to
capture such as Microsoft tears doing
reality capture where they're actually
digitizing what they're capturing with
all these cameras and they're converting
it into digital so this is what you get
out of it you get these you know kind of
low poly but still really interesting
like 3d recordings matter port is doing
it for a real estate so they're scanning
entire buildings or homes and something
that you can like jump around in and VR
and you know when you're wearing the
headset you can you know be in there now
all of this data is pretty heavy there's
so much data right like it's like really
really high polygon there's a lot of
textures a lot information headsets are
getting high-resolution this is a 8k VR
headset looks pretty rad yo and then
we've got rendering quality as going up
people expect like really high quality
renders and they don't want to be
looking at cartoony stuff anymore so
that's a challenge and so the compute
needs is just like skyrocketing if you
want good quality immersion and so it's
interesting to think about like what is
going to be needed from computing to
really drive this we have GPUs that are
getting faster and faster and are able
to keep up with what we can output today
but I think something like extreme
ultraviolet lithography when they bring
down like the nanometers of like itching
the the silicon will really like give a
huge boost to some of this emerge
immersive tech and maybe even this type
of like nano scale technology will allow
us to create new optics like the light
field mobile camera where you are
capturing not with a big you know round
sensor but actually kind of like a
diffraction grating almost okay so
you're in the VR and you're like
immersed in this like 3d space where you
want to walk around right so now you're
capturing and you want to you're in the
image instead of seeing the image and
you want to walk around you want to
touch the wall how do you touch
the wall well there's these vests like
the haptics vest the null-space VR vest
is um which gives you some senses like
if you're in a game you can only get
shot and feel the hits well that's only
one part of your body but what if you
want to touch an object in that virtual
world now you're like engaging with the
virtual stuff well you've got companies
like dextra robotics that let you have
this force feedback glove while you're
wearing the headsets and also haptics as
well as playing with that lets you feel
things like you know objects in your
hand so you're like you're like in this
place and like you're in VR but you
still react like a real person right so
in this next one a bus is coming at this
lady and she's like holy and she
like plows into the wall and in the demo
space right like that sucks like okay so
how do we solve the locomotion problem
in VR well this is not new this is like
from the 80s and it's just reimagined
for today and it's these fancy
treadmills and you're like going around
looking at the arcade right and that's
cool but like it's only flat what if I
want to move up and down well you've got
these crazy experiments where you can
like go up a step with this wild like
it's def lifter thing right okay so
obviously it's really difficult to like
get around in VR you're like you're
stuck on one level you can't really
touch things you can't really feel
things that well I mean pretty soon
you're like in this kind of thing like
what is this ready player one dystopian
future that we're in so pretty soon
you're like here and you're wearing some
skullcap and it's like sending signals
to your brain and valve has even been
playing with this this is an
experimental headset and like pretty
soon you're like in this computer like
in this world right and you're like oh
this is not the future that I
wanted like whoa like hold on a second
like the matrix is not what we wanted to
do right here you know like this is not
what we expected so you know I'd like to
look at this and laugh because Palmer
Luckey facepalm but when it comes down
to it none of you here probably has a
headset on you we have these things
right in our pockets and we have these
things
bags and we look at these things at home
and they're all flat and they're all 2d
that's the technology that exists today
so how do we make the rectangles more
immersive less flat well we're getting
there
and there's the cool-looking glass
display this is a 4k holographic display
that you can actually look at from
different angles and it's stereoscopic
3d so very much bringing that immersive
feel to a rectangle and some of the 3d
technology the 360 technology is being
used for more approachable purposes
today so this is the insta 360 1x that
captures 360 in 4k or maybe 6k and
actually takes from that a 1080p
stabilized tracked image that you can
use for your you know YouTube or for
your family images or pet videos so it's
basically extracting useful 2d stuff out
of a 360 sphere we're seeing more and
more lenses appear on cameras I mean on
phones
so there's Yami Note 10 that just got
announced has 5 so we're starting to see
more and more lenses more and more depth
perception many people might have this
and you have this three lens monstrosity
on on the iPhone and what's really cool
is that you know you've got your we're
starting to ease into this sort of
immersive future where we're using
machine learning and algorithms to infer
depth
we've got depth sensors on some camera
on some phones and we're able to do a
lot of like in-camera processing the
Google pixel does amazing stuff with
nitesite and it being able to capture in
low-light conditions and so when it
really comes down to it the the
immersive cameras in the future may not
be that far away but they're also kind
of difficult to figure out and so 10
year old me is pretty excited about what
we have in our pockets and the camera
tech that we have today and so I think I
would like to wrap up by taking a
picture because I think that's
appropriate or just take a little selfie
here with everyone
thank you
[Applause]