[Music]
hello gun I've been really lucky to work
with this next speaker for the past five
years
he's an orchestra musician in a symphony
by night he finds time somehow to work
on the production of the conference
badge this year in many of the past
years he is also the editor-in-chief of
hackaday let's welcome to the hackaday
super conference stage Mike's dish oh my
gosh
super Khan number five how is that
possible so first of all thank you for
being here I know Sunday morning is a
hard time to get out of bed because I
had to do it myself and I said oh my god
I got to give a long long talk today but
this is the most exciting time of year
because so many people that I love
seeing a love hanging around with and
and inspired by end up at the Super Con
and it's really special to be seeing
behind the scenes what happens we have a
wonderful staff of people there isn't
necessarily one central command but
there's a lot of people who know what
they're doing and when problems come up
they know how to solve them and have
made this every year even better than
the last I'm going to just give a round
of applause for everyone that has helped
organize and run super Khan this year I
[Applause]
have two identical-looking controllers I
think this is this one all right so I
have the pleasure of talking about
hackaday a lot and has anyone here ever
found themselves struggling to explain
to someone what a kadai is like it's a
weird thing right so I often go for
hackaday being a tech news website
because I'm really invested in the
writing that we do I'm editor-in-chief
of hackaday comm but it's so much more
than that and sometimes we talk about
hackaday being like a global virtual
hacker space so a place that you can go
and meet with a lot of other technical
people that are doing things that are
the same as what you're doing and doing
things that inspire you
helped you learn other things you could
look at as a project hosting website you
could look at it as a place that we go
and congregate around on different ideas
I really like to think of it as like
through the ask hackaday articles if you
need to know like collectively what do
we think about something like what are
the different ways to look at this that
I'm just not seeing what are the common
ways that people overcome it I think
that's a really interesting thing to tap
into oops oh I just gave away that I
give away the reveal slide so looking at
the ability of people to build really
high-end things I think can be really
inspiring and then going and seeing that
they're having the same problems that
you are and they were walking the same
path and that these things don't just
magic themselves into existence I think
it's you know the social media culture
it's really easy to look and see like
amazing project after amazing project
after amazing project and not see all of
the stuff that went in in behind that
and so I really like being within the
hackaday community and telling that
story like oh this thing totally didn't
work and I wasted all my time on it I
had to spin boards five times it was a
lot of money and the project came in
five months late and oh that totally
happens and so looking into this and
explaining about hackaday is I think
Elliott Williams has the best quote
which is that hackaday is the common
link in the collective brain so whenever
there's something that needs to be done
and you need to find a way to get over
this problem that you're having
oftentimes you're gonna find people are
have cross roads that go through
hackaday like you end up finding a new
part in you're like oh this new parts
awesome but I can't get it working and
you go and you google it and you're like
oh there's a heck of a article on it or
there's a heck of a project on it or
this person that I meant to the super
con wrote about it on their site or they
work for that company and I can actually
have the inside track to it
so I really look at hackaday when you
describe what it is it's a community
that already existed it's the community
that's right here and our role as
hackaday is to not screw that up to
facilitate that and to say let's
celebrate all these people and move them
forward and let's do it in a way that we
can all get behind and that welcomes
more people into it
I think we've done a lot of great things
this year and I wanted to go over a few
of them before I get into the bulk of
the talk possibly the thing I'm the most
excited about is we have a mobile view
that is totally awesome for reading
articles so where before we had the wide
view and you'd have to double tap over
here and it would it would get really
big now we have a responsive view I
spend the majority of my time reading on
the back end editing but whenever I'm
not there I'm on my phone as are like
more than 50% of our traffic and boy
having a mobile view now is is an
excellent excellent experience I'm very
happy about that but not just ahead get
a calm we have a mobile app for haka
data i/o as well and this is super cool
because I've actually stopped traveling
with the DSLR at this point because the
camera in my pocket is just so much
better and so I'm sure like all of you
when you're sitting at the bench and
working on something you're snapping
pictures constantly and then you have to
do this dance of like how do I get the
picture from my phone on to my project
and it's you know you could use a USB
cable and if to figure out the image
that has the weird name on it and you're
like which image is it or you can do the
other one that I often do that I hate
which is okay this got uploaded to the
cloud right didn't it didn't it and then
you go and look and you're like why
isn't it uploaded the cloud so you can
snap images you can put on captions on
them and upload them directly your
hackaday i/o projects I think the
biggest power of hack at i/o is those
project logs so you can document it
along the way because once again I like
to not just see the finished project
definitely check that one out
Oh as my cursor been going crazy the
whole time you're welcome
all right I think I turned the cursor
off ah has anyone here heard the hack in
a podcast whoo so elegant and I did this
really foolish thing at in December were
like let's do a Year in Review podcast
and it was it got a lot of warm response
and I thank you for everyone that has
encouraged us through it we committed to
doing a podcast every single week and
we've done it I think every single week
but two weeks is Elliott here right now
he was here before he's looking around
somewhere
Elliott spent an amazing amount of time
editing this thing and he has a really
good ear for the audio side of things
and so it sounds great because of
Elliott's hard work we're publishing
about 300 articles per month it's
difficult to keep up I love doing it but
I understand there are other things in
the hackaday in your lives this is a
great way to spend about an hour a week
catching up on you know a dozen 16 17
ish articles and just kind of looking we
go over the things that were written
about a hackaday but also just the wider
hacker sphere what's going on and really
love doing that the pac chats are
something we do weekly on hackaday i/o
and we bring in experts from industry to
talk about what we do what they're doing
and I think it's really special because
often times you just don't get this view
this under-the-hood view of what people
are doing and some of the my favorite
ones that Dan Maloney lined up this year
Dana Lewis came in and hosted a hacked
chat she is the one who launched the
open sorry its hacking diabetes so it's
the open artificial pancreas project
four people are type one diabetes that
need a insulin pump and need better
options and more options that might be
available commercially there's a great
one on photography there's one on cube
SATs Quinn dunkey if you know her from a
few of the articles that she's on a
hackaday also has a fantastic channel on
machining a youtube channel and
machining came in and talked about
setting up machines in your shop I know
Dan's always looking for people to host
that so if you have ideas or if you are
interested in hosting please reach out
to him it's I'm gonna give your email
address out dan I'm sorry Dan Maloney at
hackaday comm hope they're he's right
there he's a great guy I talked to him
on the phone there also we
wonderful contests we have this really
big contest you might have heard of last
night called the hackaday prize which
but what wonderful winners last night
but we we run other projects our other
contests throughout the year and two of
them that really caught my eye and did
way better than I thought they would
really amaze me where the circuit
sculpture contest and the beautiful
hardware contest so the beautiful
hardware contest I didn't think it would
be very interesting because the
constraints were so simple it was like
okay take a cool picture of your
hardware like that's just I mean how do
you even start there but of course there
are people who are trying to take
amazing images and so these are three of
the winners from that contest this is
look look at that that's electronic so
this and then these are from the circuit
sculpture contest and that's Kelly
Heaton and I see Kelly right there and I
mean it's just amazing we take things
that could just be really boring Green
Square circuit boards and turn them into
something that far transcends what their
original use was meant to be of the
original design was meant to be and I
really love those so go check out those
two contests let's see alright well
let's go to that slide so I would like
to talk a little bit about all of the
editorial we've done this year and all
of the 15 years of hackaday but one
thing that keeps striking me is the
amazing growth that we've seen and the
ability to just pursue our mission a lot
more closely over the last six years and
that started when supply frame bought
hackaday and started making it a making
real point of supporting the community
so one of the most important things to
me is that supply frame is safeguarded
hackaday editorial independence so we
are we have all the freedom that we want
to pursue topics in the way that we
think that they should be pursued and we
don't feel pressure there and that
should not be understated that is
something that is a very special in the
world today but the other thing is they
have had amazing support for the
community from building out the hackaday
i/o website so we have a place virtually
to get together to launching the
hackaday prize and other contests that
try and promote engineering and
making it a priority to have live events
like the hackaday super conference
events all over the world and also by
sponsoring events that supply frame
doesn't produce the also support the
community and I just wanted to take a
moment to say thank you to supply frame
for that everything the hackaday has
been doing the last six years wouldn't
be possible without it so let's give
them a round of applause okay so this is
this might get a little long because I
went back and looked at all the articles
we wrote for the last year and it's
amazing so the first thing is if you
haven't been reading the Friday 7 a.m.
Pacific article slot for the last 15
weeks or so you should because Jonathan
Bennett has been throwing down an
amazing series with the weakened
insecurity I think as I don't know what
you want to call this computer people a
lot everyone in our lives looks to us to
explain the things that they're hearing
about and a lot of times it's these
security vulnerabilities and they're
wondering like what is that and the
thing is we need to be informed about
that and it's hard to keep up with this
is a really good consumable way every
week to get like the little overview
like what do you need to know and I mean
Jonathan's also really good at putting
the breadcrumbs in there like if you
need to know deeper about this where do
you go for it
so I think that's excellent take a look
at it our editorial goals this year one
of the biggest ones is to take a look at
what the wider media is covering and
pull out those engineering stories that
aren't being told I it's happened to all
kinds of times this year but I pulled
out one that kind of starts at the
beginning of the year you may have heard
that the media was talking about these
hypersonic weapons and they're saying
hypersonic they're saying scramjet
they're saying all these words and they
weren't really explaining any of it and
Tom Nardi took got onto that one and
wrote a really long article and realized
that all these terms were getting mixed
up and they really didn't have anything
to do with each other
so you wrote this story which is really
about like a projectile launch that it's
put out from from high altitude and can
be guided and is a hypersonic craft but
then also realized that the scramjet is
a completely different thing and it's an
engine style that operates at really
high speeds so high you can't really
have a turbine in there and it's like
the
geometry of how the air path moves makes
it work and so he looked at the history
behind that and and why it's so hard I
thought that was a good engineering
story and then you may have heard of
radiation alarms going off from some
accident in northern Russia and people
are guessing that this is actually a
flying missile that is powered by some
kind of nuclear reactor and again I
think this is yeah this is also Tom so
when Tom started looking at this he
realized this is not a new idea this has
been around a long time and kind of dug
up the story of testing after the Second
World War in the United States and and
how they figured out was probably a bad
idea to have a flying reactor and then
if you think about things like the
Fukushima disaster there's a lot of
question marks that came up about like
how are we monitoring ready radiation
how can we be sure that we're getting
the information about it and so Lou and
des picked up on this and said oh we've
seen all of these air quality monitors
and environmental monitors and radiation
monitors systems being put out on the
Internet networks that people can build
and put their own nodes out and so he
went and looked up all of the networks
that he could and and found that what we
were at least from these networks they
confirmed that what was being reported
that this was not a hazard in places
outside of the immediate area were true
and I think it's just an interesting the
first time at least that I've seen that
these that we've had a problem and these
open source networks have been used to
kind of confirm that the official
information that we're getting is right
and that's that's kind of a powerful
thing I like that of course looking at
things like this car is no longer being
sold how interesting is that well not
very interesting except for the
technology that went into it and the
choices that went into it should have
made it a really popular but I guess
yeah all gasp alternative and Roger
chick dug into that and said what
choices in the design and what choices
in the way that was rolled out and the
time period it was rolled out made this
successful or not successful dan Maloney
has been doing let the $50 ham column so
if you're into amateur radio he's trying
to build inexpensive on things that let
you kind of like level up your skills in
amateur radio and while he was working
on this this story in Ohio came out the
whole neighborhood couldn't get the key
fob to unlock their car to work he's
like what's all that so you think about
it okay well there's our you know
somebody's jamming and that's regulated
so you should like roll up to their
house and slap the handcuffs on right
well first of all whose house is it and
the municipality was thinking about like
shutting off power to like one block at
a time
to try and find out where this problem
was and of course the the great story
here is the amateur radio community is
self-policing
so a ham got out and basically did like
a fox hunt to find where this
interference is coming from ended up
knocking on the door of the house and
the guys like oh yeah I I built my own
home automation system I didn't know
that it was a problem and and the ham
goes and says well look this is this is
what's wrong let's pick this fix this
together and you know instead of going
to jail you have people who are now you
know able to say oh watch out for this
this is an issue and it ends up becoming
a public service rather than you know
chasing after problem children I guess I
don't know if you heard of this guy Elon
Musk but he makes really big claims and
he he said I bought this company and
it's gonna let you compete control
everything with your mind and Maya
posture is like whoa whoa whoa whoa
let's let's just unpack that for a
minute and she went and looked at the
company and and the technology they have
for brain computer interfaces and said
there is novel things here but let's
really talk about a serious time line
and you know let's kind of ground to
these claims so that we don't have
unrealistic expectations and I think
controlling those expectations
especially you know wider consumer
electronics market is really important
Ted yopo Ted are you here right now I
think Ted's badge hacking this is an
insanely good article this may be my
favorite article of the decade go and
look at this actually it's not his next
one might be so if you remember when LED
light bulbs came out I was not a huge
fan of complex arresting because you
know they feel like warm up and I'm like
LED they're on immediately they're great
they're low-power they're wonderful and
they last a hundred thousand hours it
says right on the package and then who
here had a light bulb burn out in like
six months or a couple years
like everyone and you're like ah I threw
that package away how am I gonna get
this so he dug into it and said why were
they making those claims what's actually
causing these light bulbs to die why is
it when I put a new light bulb next to
one of my old light bulbs they're not
the same brightness anymore
kind of unpacked some of the marketing
BS that goes into those and and gave us
a dose of reality they're still great
use that use these bulbs don't go back
to incandescent he also did another one
that said I had these 30 year old roles
of SMD parts and I can't get solder to
reflow onto them they just kind of like
jump off the board and did a bunch of
side-by-side testing some of my favorite
things of these types of Ted's articles
and figured out you could sand the oxide
layer off of the solder and get it to
work just by rubbing it on a piece of
paper so as long as you don't have
hundreds in used to populate you can
hand rework and rework them we've been
following stories that are near and dear
to us so a lot of raspberry pie stories
did anybody here have a 3.3 volt rail
died on their Raspberry Pi 3 plus no
nobody that's great so it turns out on
the head on the pin header if you
accidentally saw it or if you
accidentally shorted two pins you'd kill
the 3.3 volt rail and I think the cool
thing about these next few slides is
raspberry PI's been really cool about
acknowledging this and talking about why
the design is wrong and what they're
going to do about it so another one is
they had the Raspberry Pi 4 came out
this year and they said we started
hearing these reports that if you used a
charging cable if you used a really nice
expensive charging cable it wouldn't
work and Maya posture dug into that and
we looked at exactly the USBC spec and
said oh it's these Emaar cables where
they actually have a chip in either end
of the cable and they don't work because
the specification is not right and Roger
change I've done that and said oh you
know what it's not just the Raspberry Pi
like this is a really hard specification
to get into and the reason I'm not I'm
not trying to drag Raspberry Pi through
the mud we love raspberry pi it's really
cool to have inexpensive single board
Linux computers but I think the fact
that USB C is what we're moving towards
and that it's hard to implement so hard
that an established company that has a
lot of products out in the
field is you know fell afoul of it means
we need to tell a better story of like
where are the tested and proven designs
how do you test your equipment to make
sure it's compliant and can we make
these things available so that we don't
just make this mistake over and over and
over again and I think that's one of the
places that a kadhi can really excel is
by highlighting proven designs and
promoting you know sharing your testing
protocols openly I think the space race
is one of the greatest ways to get
people excited about science and so I
like to see that going on again we've
been doing a lot of coverage of that I
hope you're enjoying that I certainly am
it's not the first time we've had a
space race though we had one you know a
half a century ago and there are still a
ton of stories to tell about that I just
pulled this one out we've continued to
do our profiles in science which are
finding you know technologists and
mathematicians and chemists that are
that have moved technology forward this
is a great one about the v2 rocket the
Redstone program which could not have
gotten into orbit without a new
formulation for fuel and it was a person
from my home state of North Dakota grew
up in a tiny town I don't like 25 people
that came up with this formulation we
are really happy to have a ton of deep
experience on hackaday and so every time
a new programming language comes out I'm
like okay who has some experience in
this programming language I can dig into
it and tell me what it's all about
because I you know I'm interested I
don't have the background and so if you
want to use V who's heard of V a few
people but now you can learn a lot more
about it because of Ben James it's not
just that language my Epoque she must
have my number because I've committed
all of the sins on buffer overflows and
C that you could possibly commit I don't
know why that that termination character
in the C string arrays it gets me every
time but if I switched over to Ada it's
so tightly tight typed so tightly typed
that it would never let you do that you
can't buffer all of overflow on it so if
you have problems and C and you want the
compiler to really rein you in Maya will
convince you that ADA is the place to go
and the new C standard has been
formalized do you all know what that
means
no I'm sure not so go and check out Sven
Gregory he said hey here's the new
things that are interesting and some of
the things that aren't interesting but
at least you can stay in the know we
have a lot of writers writing every
single month and I really like that
because we have people that are experts
in certain different areas and allows us
to really for them it's just normal
stuff but for us we don't get to look at
it very much and so uh Brian field
actually works on power grid and did a
bunch of articles this year just looking
at like for this this one's like what
are the poles made of what why are they
as tall as they are and how do they
leverage insulators to keep the high
voltage apart what kind of equipment
they used to step up and step down for
those transmissions but also when
current events things happen like there
was a huge power outage in all of
Argentina and also part of Paraguay and
Uruguay and the reporting the official
announcements of what happened coming
out there were like really sparse but
because of his experience he was able to
like fill in all the blanks on it really
tell a comprehensive story once again
something that was reported you know the
wider news but it was reported as there
was a power outage and now there's not
and he actually looked at it and said
this is um you know things like cold
starting facilities like how hard is it
to start up power generation once it
stopped like that's a really interesting
story and we're happy to have him write
about it alright I probably have like 10
more slides on this but I'm going to
move on just for time oh yeah we have
plenty of time don't worry so
PACA Day started in September 5th of
2004 was the first article published on
hackaday and I think it's amazing to
look back we wrote an article and
unfortunately you just cannot cover in
one article all the things that happened
in 15 years so I thought hey state of
the hackaday I'll cover all the things
that happened in 15 years no that's
really hard too so um being someone that
is always jealous when speakers have
really good stats and graphs and stuff I
was like I can pull some stats so I have
I have a fun little sad thing so five
and a half thousand days we wrote almost
35,000 articles we've received over
900,000 comments it's amazing and I'm
always floored how many times we write
something and some will be in the
comments that said
I worked on that program I work at that
company or that's what I do in my day
job and gives all kinds of interesting
insight to that I'm going back to my you
know the wider hackaday community is
there just waiting for for some way to
cross paths and you know when you know
something you want to share your
knowledge I think that's really cool one
of the things I do hear from people
though is like oh you know back when
hack edebe wrote one article day that
was the real hackaday and so I looked
into that and I said how long was that
when did we actually write one hack it
because it certainly has not been for a
while so I pulled every single day for
15 years and you can see the most we
ever published was 16 in one day and you
know we had a good run here but there's
there's some noise in there so this is
the one baseline we get a little bit
above that so I thought okay if we do
months by year instead we get a little
better thing there and then I say okay
years so we do have a pretty close
baseline there on years and I said all
right well let's actually look at the
number of distinct days so this is 1070
three days out of that five and a half
thousand days we published exactly one
article and you can see this is more
what we're at right now we publish eight
every weekend and we published somewhere
between ten eleven or twelve on the
weekdays and it's kind of the modern
hackaday but still didn't quite mean
much to me as far as the stats go so I
looked at baseball and they have a they
have an on-base percentage right and so
that's really what we need so I put
together the solo hack percentage and
you can see that in 2004 we had a
perfect solo hack percentage every one
of those days September through December
exactly one hack today if per day but by
2015 less than half of the days were one
hack day so our solo hack percentage was
very low and by 2009 it's almost almost
gone so we like to write articles I
started reading in 2005 and I read every
single word in the hackaday article and
I clicked through and read every single
word in the articles that they were
running and I learned just a ton from
that and yet I was still left wanting
more and so I think if you're into you
know hardware especially but really just
the wider technology in general
you'd like to be entertained and you'd
like to find things to write and so
that's why we're running more than one
hackaday is people are interested in new
stuff going and looking at the number of
authors I think it's no surprise that
them as we published more articles we
had more authors at this point we're up
to about 20 to 30 maybe 25 to 30 authors
per month to give us that wide different
background but what was really
interesting to me and Ellie and I
disagree on this I think this is a
really low number but in 15 years
35,000 articles we've only ever had a
hundred and fifty-seven published
authors that's really incredible
and these people generally have better
things to do with their lives they have
really interesting jobs they're doing
important things and they make time to
write for hackaday because they also
come from the Hackney community and they
also know what it is to have on this
form of entertainment and this form of
Education and really want to give back
so I just like to recognize these 157
people and give them a big round of
applause
[Applause]
so in looking at our 15 years the thing
that really struck us is the way that
the technology especially the hardware
has changed so it used to be a lot more
difficult I'd like to say kids these
days have it so easy except for it's not
just kids we we all benefit from this it
changed so quickly that it didn't take
an entire generation to get to this
point but if you go back to 2008 which
is still not even when we started about
four years later and look at what it
took to build a little robot with Wi-Fi
who here owned the wrt54g here hacked on
it at all in some way shape or form
right so if you're someone that hacked
on it you will recognize right here the
serial the DB DB 6 DB 9 DB somethin
connector that breaks out the serial
port that gives you interactivity with
it but you had to have a whole router on
there and then I means you have to power
a whole router and there were just a lot
of problems that went into it you go to
2009 and this is a Arduino form-factor
Wemo board so it's a esp8266 I believe
you get it for a few dollars it's gonna
have the same kind of motor driver of
course motor drivers are easier to get
these days
but look over here you have an entire
user interface that you don't have to
build yourself that your outlet that
every one that you could possibly put
this robot hand into already has and in
this case if you look really close on
the screen it's using the Google
assistant voice commands so we have like
a voice controlled robot over Wi-Fi for
way less than we did when we were
putting a router on it
unbelievable of course isn't just Wi-Fi
that we're interested in people wanted
to put cellular on it and that goes way
back as well but it used to be you had a
whole cell phone so you'd put your whole
cell phone on the robot and then of
course what's the problem with putting a
cell phone in the robot how do you
connect your hardware to it right and
who here really misses the days of USB
on-the-go oh what a horrible standard I
mean there was some good thing I
remember I had the yo-yo board that you
could connect to there like broke it out
and that was okay but it still was just
a fight to get that stuff to happen when
we fast forward to 2019 and carry sharp
glass wrote an article called choosing
the Goldilocks cell module and so it
not just like here's the thing to put
sell on it but it's like here's all of
the different choices that you have that
you can buy right now for it's still
pretty inexpensive and get it to work on
your device
that's an amazing chasm to come in just
11 years this one is an autonomous robot
from 2006 so they did exist before you
know.com 4.0 or whatever rat some of the
things interesting about this look at
all of the batteries I guess it's really
low resolution in there I mean cameras
weren't that good in 2006 either this is
crazy
alright so there's just a ton of
double-a batteries on this thing all
over the place and then I'm pretty sure
this is a GPS module I'm not sure this
is maybe Wi-Fi something anyway it's
difficult to do these things this is the
donkey car I saw this at Maker Faire Bay
Area in 2017
it's an autonomous driving vehicle on
powered by Raspberry Pi 3 so like $35
Linux computer right it has this camera
right here which the board is made to
work with the camera this car is
actually looking at the track ahead of
it on the camera and making driving
choices based on that on this little
computer I mean I know you live in the
same future that I do but it's
incredible to think about how far we've
come on these things the other thing is
look at look down here you got rid of
all of those double-a batteries and you
just put a tight little lithium pack on
there and so you have to look into it
and say alright that the 18 650 that
cell that we love to use for lithium
batteries these days that I went and
looked it it started being produced in
the 90s and being put into laptop
batteries and so we do see a ton of
projects but they're usually pulling
laptop batteries out and then you have
to be like okay how am I going to not
blow this battery up when I charge it
and how do I charge it and like you
spend half your time on your project
getting the battery to work and you know
now we can just go because of the RC
field and buy a drone battery that you
know has all kinds of power density in
it and you can buy a charger that you're
pretty sure is not going to catch it on
fire and in general be be a lot safer
than I have been around some of those
boosted boards or the the electric
skateboards when somebody punctured
themselves that's some scary stuff watch
out for that alright and who
thought you would have been able to
build your own machine tool like that is
something ten years ago I mean really
ten years ago you would have thought I
can't get into that that's too tough and
well I guess more than ten you somewhere
in there
so we at RepRap come along I rep rep
really revolutionized that and said you
know what let's put motors on stuff and
let's make it possible for people to use
them and build high precision precision
things but still you know you had to
like get into that community and hope
you could convince someone to send you
the original parts or you could do I
think they call them rep straps where
you try to like hand make those parts to
the point where they could then print
something better and build build your
machine well now I hope you've seen Josh
Joshua Vasquez is Jubilee tool changing
application we have experienced linear
rails something like this precision
rails right there you have the ability
to get very high power and high
precision motors for incredibly low
price you have good examples on 3d
printed connectors for them and 3d
printed jigs and how to how to build
that it's like not just the hardware
that goes into this but like the entire
ecosystem of how do you build things
that are gonna work well and don't have
backlash in them and don't have flex
it's really amazing to see that it's
come come so far I am looking at where
we're going from here and it's hard to
imagine because these advancements seem
to keep keep accelerating but I think
the place they're at right now is kind
of like I was walking here this morning
and talking to someone about robotics
they were doing and I said it's it's
kind of like hash include' robot look at
that point it really is is getting to
the point where you like have an
existing design and you you wish it and
you wish it to be part of your project
and it can this is one of my favorites
you can find on hackaday oh these are
time-of-flight sensors so really
inexpensive because of economies of
scale and they've put three of these on
this little piece of circular PCB that
spins and created a very low cost but
still totally usable lidar called X
lidar that's incredible
I look at what we're what got us to this
point and it was good ideas so you know
somebody spent a lot of time just making
this AVR chip talk to this existing unit
and you can bet that like getting the
libraries to work on this was
non-trivial but everyone looked at it
that's what I want I want GPS on this I
want a a geocaching box remember those
geocaching that was a good time I want
to do some geocaching and I need GPS on
that and boy I wish I could do this but
that seems like a lot of work and so
someone comes along and says that is a
lot of work maybe we should make that
into a module and you can just slap on
top of your microcontroller breakout
board and oh we'll also give you a
library that will just work when you use
it and decade of that does align and
brings us really a long way to the point
where we're getting there in software as
well if you think about what Arduino did
Arduino came in and said you know you
shouldn't have to be a tool chain expert
you shouldn't have to be able to write
your own make files in order to do
something on a microcontroller and you
shouldn't have to be you know a computer
scientist to connect a temperature
sensor up to something and then be able
to echo that out on the serial port and
a lot of people said oh you know this
isn't real embedded systems and you
should be counting cycles but the thing
is it opened up the economy to a lot
more people who wouldn't have gotten
into it and what that does is you
identify people who are going to be
microcontroller experts then maybe
wouldn't have been exposed to it and
they those people come in and are like
oh this library is kind of janky I wish
it was better and then they contribute
back to the open source and so what we
end up is getting like exponential
growth on the ability to build good
products and to make them work for
everyone I think we're getting to
another kind of fast-forward moment with
that and I think it's in the micro
Python and of course the circuit Python
which is based on that lineage because
when Arduino first came in it was
running on like the 880 mega 8 it wasn't
super fast it didn't have a ton of flash
space but then the embedded systems
caught up and now like the teensy 4 was
released as like a 600 megahertz clock
in there like it's amazing and so you
don't
notice any kind of like wrapper overhead
on that anymore now micro Python it has
a definite speed hit to it but think of
how many more people have been exposed
to Python than have been exposed to C++
and so I just took two examples open cm3
is like an open source library for the s
am 32 and a lot of other controllers
this is an example that you can't read
at all sorry about that
of using a USB mouse and USB keyboard
with those devices and there's like a
bunch of magic numbers in there so like
GPIO numbers and you know just stuff
that you're like what is this okay I'll
copy it and make it work and micro
Python comes along and they're like oh
hey here is CD CHCs and CD chid it's
like one-liners that turn those on to
turn those off and somebody else is
taking care of all those magic numbers
under the hood that's really
transformative because it is like
software include to make your hardware
work and I think that the future is
gonna see that just about anyone who
becomes a hardware person and and just
about any hardware person becomes a
software person I think these are
benefits for all a microcosm of this is
the badge that we saw at the Hecate
super conference so it's based on an
FPGA and as you can see the FPGA becomes
whatever Hardware you want so there's a
couple of risk 5 cores you throw them in
there you do your risk 5 stuff you don't
really think about it once it's up and
running you can make the interface any
interfaces do you want to work on that
but even beyond this it's only becoming
I think widely adopted at this point
outside of just industry that's building
products that has FPGA is in it because
we have a fully open source tool chain
on that and I think the work that has
gone in by the people that are
contributing to those projects cannot be
understated with vendor tools it's
difficult to custom hook them into your
own process these so if you want to
script things if you want I mean if you
want to do anything other than what's
traditionally been imagined on the FPGA
it's difficult to do with vendor tools
when you open it up to the open source
tools it's your playground you can do
whatever you want get it under the hood
and build that and that's just gonna
allow people to innovate and I think
we're gonna see these in a ton more
our products because of it and I'm
really excited about that you shouldn't
be locked into whatever your product
functionality is just because it was
shipped out the door we have the ability
now to change things in the field and
and and that's where we're moving the
other thing on the hacker new super
carpets badge is distributed engineering
team and I was particularly happy to
hear the axiom team accept their award
for the hackaday prize last night
because they said this is the first time
the three of us have met and I knew I
had I knew I had this slide in here and
I'm like I hope I'm not just full of BS
but this badge team is from all over the
world and we put together a how could a
project on hackaday do that had a chat
room in there and you go and look at
people getting to know each other and
working through problems and talking
about what's going on with all the code
if you're working in an office with
other people chances are you're already
interacting with them virtually you're
on a slack channel or a discord channel
and yeah you do see them in person but I
think the default is I can always get to
them through the screen in the keyboard
and so to remove the the close proximity
physically I think is not as foreign as
it was five years ago and definitely not
as it was 10 years ago and so hackaday
i/o is a great place to work on these
distributed projects and find people um
from your own teams but I think just in
general look outside of who is right
next to you or who's across the street
from you because I know my next-door
neighbor doesn't want to talk about
watchdog timers but I want to talk about
watchdog timers and so I'm always
looking for someone I'll be out back
after this if your watchdog timer
aficionado so let's talk about the the
threats the the the things we have to
watch out for moving forward into the
future let me just go back if you show
someone this and then you say you should
try build your own electronics - oh boy
this is not that hard
that is not easy and so when Arduino
came out and we're like you can blink an
LED and someone looks at a blinking LED
and says I can do that and even if
they've never you know touched a c-plus
bus before like they can figure out how
to do it if you say you could put a risk
five core on your Gameboy shaped badge
and
you can make that work that is a much
bigger hill to climb and so we need to
be very careful that we're not making a
may magic and amazing things look like
that's the only thing you can do and
this goes back to my earlier comment and
social media and always seeing finished
projects like celebrate people blinking
an LED celebrate people writing their
first line of code make sure we're
telling that story that you can get into
it and that things like this hack of a
badge are easy in the way that a lot of
people before us have proved every step
along the way and what we can do is go
and gather all that stuff up but it
doesn't have to be that big of a thing
for you the first time out of the gate I
think we really need to normalize the
the fact that this can be entertainment
you don't have to do this like oh are
you doing this in order to get into
college are you doing this to get
funding for your startup it doesn't have
to be I'm doing this because I don't
want to watch the horrible talent show
at 7 p.m. on broadcast television right
like I'm getting to the point where I
can't watch the TV anymore because it
doesn't entertain me and so I think a
lot of people argued at that point too
and so let's tell the story that you can
entertain yourself learns maybe learn
something the same time but have some
fun and don't put the pressure on
yourself that I have to achieve all
those shiny pictures on Twitter or even
finish the project like just playing
with it and figuring out is it the thing
for me is worth it it's worth your time
and I've said this before and I'm happy
to say it again as we level up in skills
and as we learn things and get better at
things we have a higher and higher
obligation to pass that on and to share
that with other people and make sure
that people feel like they're being
welcomed and that their each small
achievement is being celebrated so be
inclusive with your knowledge pass your
knowledge on publish it openly and make
it something that everyone can benefit
from I think that's what hackaday is all
about and that hasn't changed over the
15 years except for it's become easier
to share those things it's become easier
to get people excited about it it's
become easier for each and every one of
you to have an impact on the world and
on individuals and I we're gonna keep
doing that with every waking breath and
I hope you'll join us thank you so much
[Applause]