okay so our next speaker is a software
engineer who fuses her work with
painting coding and VR to create
artistic escapes that envision the
future of how we could how the world
could be her talk today is going to be
focusing on a novel application for
on-body haptics so please welcome to the
hackaday a super conference stage sarah
Bulmer okay so one little correction not
a software engineer just learned how to
do that so what I'm here to talk about
is sort start off with an adventure in
sensory perception and how to sort of
combine different senses and sort of
authoritative I guess performances that
we do and so we're looking at connecting
haptics maybe to light sound body
sensing all types of these these ways of
kind of communicating different sort of
experiences in a performative context so
what I mean by that is let's say we've
got maybe four or five of us that want
to put on a show
and we would do it in terms of having
body sensing or biosensing maybe on our
hearts and we'd have that connected to
someone else and they would be able to
feel what the other person's feeling or
maybe the lights or something dictating
what's happening on your body if the
body just you're tracking that sort of
thing as well and so because of this
then way they're doing performances we
got to really switch the gear around
pretty easily so I really give it to you
you give it to them and if there's a
flow of people coming through so what
happens as we kind of we wanted to wear
wearables I need to put some kind of
haptics into the systems but because of
that they tend to be like the specific
to one person and then we can transfer
them easily so I was thinking about what
I could do and one of the things I was
looking at was maybe we can have some
kind of modular you know pieces I could
transfer around and so the first thing I
came up with which was a great fun as I
thought that maybe I could connect
things with a lilypad arduino because
then we could wear them on ourselves but
that involved a lot of so
and I wasn't good so that was not there
but then I end up with five with his
left over so at five of those I need to
connect into something so I connected
them with a Bluetooth obviously HCF iho
6s okay so we got modules there and that
was cool but they they kind of fell
apart but they did work the one time and
so after that I'm thinking what else can
we do with these so I then started
looking into what else was there and I
realized first thing I want to do
obviously was come up with a new way to
connect things so how about it so we'll
talk about later
those are circuit boards PCBs we got
them set and so this here is what have
now got called the octopus here and if
we got eight different haptic centers on
here and so what how it works is we've
got one main module here okay
connect it through to eight of these
other sensors know you could have eight
three two one it doesn't matter that's
kind of the point so what I can do then
is you can easily you can easily pull
them on and off switch them around and
give them to other people
and so the point of that was that we can
either wrap them in an arm wrap around a
leg rabbet on your back neck etc it's
sort of transfer these systems um this
guy so all of this actually is online so
you can grab that if you want to um I
don't know can I play the movie or
tonight is there a movie I can put on
now yeah where we can just gonna do that
cool okay so um so what I just there's I
put together a couple things here so
taking this now into live performance
fine but I work in saw a VR do you like
building a world building in VR maybe
like last happier just started there and
so I'm interested in sort of your
sensory perception within VR okay so
looking at what's real it was not real
virtual obviously versus reality virtual
reality
and how can you transfer that sort of
information when you're in these worlds
and whether or not you know it's done
through sight which is obvious in VR but
how can you transfer other senses right
so haptics smell sound to these types of
things and so I've taken some of these
systems put them into there there's a
giant module with gloves and haptic
feedback that way and all kinds of parts
your body going through this and we're
in a position now to sort of expand to a
new idea and that's sort of doing a like
a silicone I guess I guess printed
silicone sort of knobs from your fingers
but in that context I'm looking at well
let's see you know everything else is
sort of big and clunky and so I was
talking with an artist friend of mine
and we're looking at perhaps starting
with the concept of aesthetics first and
so looking at the things like rings and
bracelets and instead of you know
starting with these giant electronics on
you know making them work that way and
like well maybe there's a way I could
force them into these smaller sort of
pieces and so that is in the process
we're halfway there but I've got just a
quick little clip here of sort of seeing
some of this in action within the VR
spaces I guess I'm so just hit this guy
think hmm so this here is just showing
yes so this is just streaming we're
getting the connection going from the
other so this is our lab there on my
work University or student there and so
this is the bounce here that I was
talking about just now so I just go
backwards a bit here I'm as you can see
here what we're doing is just
transferring obviously content so I'm
gonna can't say that clearly but it's
just looking at YouTube others so we're
doing through open sound control which
is just the way of sending signals that
you can allocate to each one and here he
goes we check it cleared out feeling it
make sure it's working belts on cool and
so in VR though I need to find a way
obviously to activate the boats so here
whatever so I've set up and HTC vive in
the sense and what I've got is the HTC
vive sort of camera fries they trigger
you know by just by sight for that one
to see whether or not I've got the
haptics on and what it can generate from
that and so when they camera
gets near the HTC vive trackers so
that's what I considered the hands here
when you're in VR when you notice those
when it knows is that that it triggers
the haptic response and so that was just
you know one way to sort of go about
that also we're thinking of you know
putting it in place around your body so
maybe you're in a world and a creature
comes up or something happens to you and
you can sort of sense that within your
the space you're in and coming in cool
you still going all right this is it
yeah so I think this is no this is not
the VR when I'll be our worlds were in
some just gonna let that one run here no
others know you're not but so it's kind
of just an interesting space to be in
and so here our hands I've tracked out
so these are gestures strictly to
someone's hands so when they're in this
space their their whole hand is now
mapped out that's coming through and
I've now connected both there's haptic
gloves and then haptic components to
them also you can see the one-to-one
ratio and so within that space there you
can kind of play around grab things they
haptic sort of with sense different
parts of your body we've got it in the
sense that you can also have your
gestures sort of trigger haptics on
other people um so that's sort of a
component as well as looking at world
building but in a collaborative sort of
co-creative spaces and that way you've
got multiple people in there so we're
also creating with you one example we've
been working on in the lab as well is um
modular synthesizers but in VR and then
morph multiple people can be playing at
the same time and so looking at you know
obviously you're trying to grab for your
articulated gestures with that so what
can we do to improve that so obviously
using hands maybe haptic feedback etc
that's was playing here I was wrapped up
quickly then so this hand here is my own
but what this started off was was our
new idea that we're thinking of with the
Rings and stuff so we're like there's my
new prototype here's on my hand and
where we're at is looking at it this way
so that's the content of talking about
in terms of having like a bracelet first
around your rings and wrist here and
sensors and things on your fingers and
so the warned constraint though is
obviously to have it all in this very
small aesthetic sort of pleasing let's
say wait and see if you could it could
be done
so I'm in the process right now sort of
figuring out this printing out some
different materials
firstly I'm 3d printed like silicone and
that sort of thing and seeing if that
would fit it would be easy to transfer
between people I'm also looking at
within the pads themselves so just also
sensing things hunched that way also
tough pressure in them so maybe being
I'll to inject some kind of an air or
liquid maybe that works that way and
also having some kind of electrical
sense as well so beyond it kind of zap
things that part your around your body
and so we're going with that and that's
kind of where I'm going and that's about
what I've got today
[Applause]