[Music]
welcome back our next speaker during his
time at SpaceX worked on the Dragon
Falcon and StarLink projects but now
you'll find him over at wei MO as a test
automation engineer but today is talking
about putting technology in control of a
very important fermentation process
please welcome to the hackaday super
conference stage trent fowl thank you
all for having me here and thanks for
that introduction I'm here to talk about
a solution that I developed for a
problem that I had in the kitchen for
those of you who are involved in
sourdough baking you'll be familiar with
some of the constraints that are levied
on the sourdough starter which is kind
of the seed that you start your
sourdough baking from it needs some
tight temperature regulation and there
really isn't a good device right now for
regulating that there are some products
out there that primarily are for heating
but depending on the time of the year
you might actually need to cool the
sourdough starter depending on the
temperature outside depending on your
regulation of the temperature inside
your house and being an engineer and not
seeing the product that I really wanted
after some discussions with friends we
came about a product that we believe was
a little bit better
something that heats and cools and that
was kind of the differentiating factor
that we thought would be helpful here so
the solution was to put a Peltier cooler
on the side of a chamber Peltier coolers
depending on the direction that the
voltage is applied can pump heat in one
direction or the other direction so we
saw this as a really simple method of
having both cooling and heating for a
device like this and so there's a fan on
the inside and the outside the outside
is for wicking away heat
the inside can be cooler and the inside
is for distributing air inside the
volume and so like I mentioned if you
just switch the voltage there then you
can change the mode of operation and
it's something that's pretty easy to do
with in each Ridge so here's the block
diagram of the the device that we
actually have here at the table it's
based on a Raspberry Pi zero and then
the meat of it is kind of up there on
the top left where the Peltier cooler
and the fans are but there are some
buttons to control the temperature
setting and a display to show you what
the temperature inside currently is and
so I have this I have this running up
here I'm not sure if you can see this
through the from the camera up here but
there are a couple buttons where you can
increase the temperature or decrease the
temperature and then the Peltier cooler
responds it will either change the
heating or change the cooling and it's
as simple as switching the voltage
applied to that Peltier cooler so I've
used this at my house already I've
gotten a pretty good performance out of
it so I've gotten up to 82 degrees
Fahrenheit and down to sixty degrees
Fahrenheit depending on the depending on
the exterior temperature and the fans
that you have to sync heat you can
achieve a greater temperature range but
I found that the way that I have this
currently set up was sufficient for a
lot of the baking and kitchen needs that
I have and then this isn't just good for
sourdough you can use this for pickling
that's another fermentation process and
then mushrooms also a fungi just like
yeast is also has similar temperature
constraints so there are things that you
just can't do with appliances that are
on the shelf right now like switching
the temperature between what your
starter needs at certain times of the
day at night so this is a pretty
powerful device to take into the kitchen
and then I've got a couple ideas for
improvements here that I haven't gotten
to yet but it's definitely some small
things that could improve the
reliability or the performance and I've
kind of put this project on the back
burner it's in a working state right now
so I can make use of it but if anybody
was interested in developing this
further definitely feel free to reach
out to me I'm happy to pick this back up
if there's interest in it from the
community and I know that I've talked to
some of you guys already today and it
does sound like this might be something
that could be used by other people all
of the all of the code is on github
there and the hardware ended up being
very plug in play there's modules for
the H bridge circuit that just connect
to the Raspberry Pi the display has a
module and then there's just a power
supply that's mounted to the top of this
fine chamber that I got from McMaster so
that's my demo thank you all for coming
[Applause]