I think we'll make it we can start and
hello everyone my name is for Microsoft
scheme and today i'd like to present and
say couple of words about testing iOS
applications
already not working nice i was working
but ok about me
currently I'm working as web and mobile
applications esters ninety percent of my
time doing mobile and ninety percent of
mobile time I'm doing iOS has my
presentation
I'm previously I've been working on
couple security projects i'll spend the
building and different i idn't access
management systems housework and also as
a system administrator and I'm working
an offensive security testing
applications and ok so I'd like to know
better the audience that we have here we
are not so many
but do we have any iOS developers hands
up up
one good and do develop and Swift as
well
our objective c only objective c cool
and do we have any pentre source and I
have that we have
ok quite a few perfect perfect guys
and many people related with Android
developers testers
cool cool right
ok so a couple of words about what we
will cover and what we won't cover the
presentation is about application
testing so will give a brief
introduction to iOS itself and then go
through objective-c runtime will set up
a testing environment and we'll go
through very basic and simple life cycle
for the dentist on giving some real life
examples and things that you want you
won't see here is slow level staff men
the jailbreak development
we also want cover Swift as quite you
and there are still many changes
I think that new version is coming
we also will focus on black box
assessments and I think it's most the
most frequent case where we do
dentist of application and we don't have
access to the source code and also i
won't cover things like classical web
testing which I assume that the audience
here
ok so about is itself in its a mobile
operating system from apple
it's unix-like with X a new kernel it's
in general is called source with some
extent exceptions
you can see up well you will see a link
and open source apple com there are a
couple of libraries that you can look
into and the applications are written in
mainly in objective-c and very recently
in Swift as apple introduced in the new
language and coach is the main API
handling all the touch events from from
the user and all the user input and due
to the system and just a couple of words
about the security model
what you have to understand is that iOS
is basically the entire ecosystem
starting from hardware to software Apple
controls vast majority of the hardware
from cpu bootloader
TPM up to the software with its own
operating system and applications and
though unfortunately won't have time to
go into details of those things
just a couple of words first of all
those are security features of the
operating system itself
security with changing that in the CPU
itself in the in the silicon there is
apple CA certificate and all the code
that is being front and that's being
clouded by the by the system by the
device is being checked if it has known
and good signature security life is
basically a TPM for mobile devices
it's it's included in all of devices to
adopt after our iphone 5s
I believe encryption and the protection
and starting from iOS 8
all data on the device is encrypted
even though you don't have passcode and
the data is encrypted obviously prevents
only it protects only against offline
attacks but all data is encrypted and in
I devices there are no SD cards so we
don't have problem here
trusted code execution is a bit related
to secure boot chain meaning that only
able sign called can run on devices and
also all third-party applications have
to be signed by by apple
it's it's a bit of the shortcut thinking
because there are some exceptions but in
general we can we can assume so
and network security also worth
mentioning is that starting from iOS 9
on the TLS is a connection are allow
that
if you want to connect a resource over
HTTP it must be whitelisted so
ok and the key chain was kitchen kitchen
is also a security feature is basically
a sequel I database which stars also all
sensitive information like passwords
stock and tokens and applications can
access the items in keychain and only
that they can read the items in the
kitchen
only for the for the same a keychain
access group so 2 applications cancer
items but they must belong to the same
access group
and the war mentioning obviously kitchen
can be can be read on the jailbroken
device so it can be fully dumped with
reading my tools applications and books
so it's compared to android and hear it
it looks a bit different so we have only
two users on the system you have a
mobile android user and all the world
third-party applications they run as a
mobile user and they are in some book
which means that they can access only
their own data they can share explicitly
data with other applications and also
compared to android wear the IPC model
is very very broad and here I pieces are
very very limited again we hope we don't
have time to discuss them but in short
and only pieces are only by our of
hundred handlers and and baseboard good
now
objective-c a couple of words of
objective-c it's a it's an objective
language based on
it's basically a superset of C and which
means that you can use objective c
compiler to compile C applications and
you can embed it C code in your in your
applications as well and it is a couple
of interesting features and we'll see
we'll see a couple of details on on an
example
so one of the features it is infix
notation so you can see that
first of all use square brackets and
when you want to call a method on a
particular object you have object that
method and then after a call you have
arguments
so if you want to initialize instance
offer and a string class with string
confidence 2016 you call you pass
actually a method street with string
with a parameter this is actually a
string with that sign
simple as that in objective c you have
two methods you have class instance
methods and they already know that this
is the interface interface
of their of the class and you have two
types of methods one which is a class
method and you can see the pass on here
and one which is an instance method and
you can see the -
and the difference is simple you can
call the class method on its own
whereas in order to call air an instance
method you first have an itch
initializing out an object actually
allocate more initialized and then you
can call instance method on the
particular instance of an object
this will be useful later on during our
application analysis
ok so it's interesting what happens in
the hood
mm in objective-c because you don't
actually call a method in objective-c a
actually passed you passed a message
the method and what happens on early
food so in objective-c runtime you have
a function called object is to match
this message sent and terrorists an
example for from John John skis book and
when you basically do something like
this with with Objective C so you have
say something method on say something
object located in July's you call you
actually pass the net force a width
apart there hello world and then you
release the object
now what happens under the hood it's
actually gets translated into pure see
calls and you can hear see and mr. chain
or more of gyp the objective c message
sent functions and finally and the gap
on the object is to get class say
something
okay and then we have something called
NS sector from string
so basically objective-c message sent
takes two parameters versus the pointer
to an instance of an object on which we
want to pass the method and second is
selector selector is basically a c
string with the name of a method
registered in their own time and so then
you might think how the call graph looks
looks like and it looks like this
so are those are basically this is the
almost the same faction object to see
message sent with small variation
in class from which inherited returning
current structure and and normal
function so we don't have much
we don't have much information from
what's going on the application just
based on the call graph it will be very
useful to see what happens when we
actually went this objective c message
sent function is it's cold and you to
this
due to this property of the language
that have we use this objective c
message a message sent object is a
message sent function and we their
implementation of the method is a result
i'm dynamically which means that we can
change in American implementation during
the run time and this feature is called
methods whistling and it's actually not
the back it's a feature and we'll have
we use it in testing and i'll show you
how i also included some links i highly
recommend because the runtime itself is
very interesting it's written C and
assembly
it obviously must be very efficient and
i recommend the game - it's more
ok so we're very very quick introduction
to the arm to the system and to the
programming language that's used will go
to the actual meat of this presentation
so application analysis
ok so first of all what we want to lose
you would need
so for starting binary analysis of
classical idea pro is very useful
however hopper is also nice you can get
quite far with hopper
it's a disassembler and the compiler
which is very interesting and the prices
are comparable
I mean proper cause something like a
hundred dollars or make yours I think
we're either pro is itself is I think
$1,500 process x-rays for the compiler
and also when you buy x rays you have to
buy separately for 32 and 64 bits and
hopper has has all of this in in in one
license at constant visit tool that will
allow us to to as see what methods are
in the binary what what methods are used
and how interface far interface files
look like from vary from the binary
auto will give us some information about
the binary itself and strings all know
from from unix systems
ok in again in iOS compared to android
we have we rely on runtime on your
manipulation which means that we do some
static analysis but mainly with play
with interact directly with the
application and we'll see how in a
minute
and what those who would need out there
are two widely used tools one is secret
it basically injects into the running
process into the running application and
it gives you an interactive console and
you can interact with the application
from the console you can call them that
you can actually cut all of us messages
to methods with this comment line and
free does something similar however and
completely different way and the main
difference for us is that freezer can
inject to the hook into a starting
process
so let's say that the application using
labor a detection and closes immediately
you don't have time to hook into process
with secret you can do it with free that
very useful very nice to documentation
is a bit a bit lacking and debugger
obviously the burger is very important
so some time ago Apple move from DC to
lv m and subsequently from GDB to LD be
as a debugger and GDP is fully supported
on the iOS 7 for those people who are
not into iOS now we have conversion is I
think not . free . something so we have
already two major reasons that are
without gb and from iOS 8
we have LD be as a default debugger
which is working and however some some
pictures are still missing ldb and it's
not
well it's fully functional but some
useful stuff is missing for us
ok so you want test application what you
actually need
unfortunately no simulator as in case of
android so you have to have filled
device to do meaningful testing
i recommend getting a bit older maybe
device with a bit older iOS because you
have still a bit more tools than four
muir iOS's and but make sure that the
IRS that you're using has available
jailbreak so that you can actually
jailbreak it because we first think
about Drake doesn't quite make sense and
if you want to test any legacy
applications you need another pair of
devices and my my recommendation is to
use two devices / iOS version of a
broken non-jailbroken because it happens
that developers are giving you the
application to be tested you launch it
on jailbroken device and doesn't launch
you see anything
well it might be some tricky jai bri
detection function what's happening so
we start debugging the button bugging
and but when you check it on laundry
broken device you see that the
application is actually not working
so yeah and it can save you some time
and OS X and X code is very use force
you don't have to have mac to test iOS
part it's useful to compile your own
code and and check also and check also
maybe to some proof of concept and
attacks
ok and and and all
if you basically jailbreaking device
requires a exploiting it
and you have ready-made jailbreaks for
some iOS versions but obviously not for
all iOS versions because as soon as
jailbreak is released a couple patches
the vulnerabilities and and if you fail
to jailbreak the device you can restore
it with itunes but also upgrade to the
US version
you can't restart to the previous
version which is obviously a problem
because then it comes to bracket there
is a handy tool called semi restore
which you can use and it happened to me
that jailbreak failed in a in the middle
and then I couldn't launch the
application and and then the stories
handy and save me 11 ipod and again no
possibility to downgrade iOS version so
again if you also buy a device and also
especially used one make sure that it
has iOS with currently available
jailbreak
ok I jailbreaking as such in there are
already Drake's release is very
straightforward usual you just read next
next next next done it reboots couple of
things and then it's basically all
and what jailbreaking does first of all
it doesn't break the application sandbox
it allows to run unsigned code for party
cold and it also gives you shell access
to the device because normally there is
no termina or such thing on iOS and also
it will install the city application
store from which you get and other
useful stuff like openness age or
aptitude and this is how it looks like
this is a screen shot forum of the
street city application first thing you
do is you install aptitude and you
install openssh you have those two users
by default on is we have fruit and
mobile and default password to SS ages
alpine and I list that the some tools
that i usually installed directly on
jailbroken device that then are useful
to for testing
ok free . i won't spend time on this
very straight forward to go to that
website you install one part on your
workstation and the second part on your
iOS device an agent very straightforward
nothing fancy there now we have tools
and we are we're not focusing on the
application and on Android as some of
you know the applications are packaged
in apk files and in iOS this is IPA file
IP is simply a zip archive just rename
it or you unzip it and you have all the
bundle you have application binary and
all the static data is required for
application so graphic certificates any
other code and i always use this Mack OH
binary format
and usually binaries contain when you
want you and you see a binary usually
contains - lets a sub binaries and this
is called fat binary for different
architectures
so the way up the the device can install
can choose the proper binary for its the
cpu ok and now we have we have our
device jailbroken
we have installed our tools from the
list that I shown and now we have a tool
called install a pump when you use -
well at least you all the third party
applications you use the eye on the
application this QR code reader and you
can see that here it gives you free
folders and the applications are
installed into the into the unique
folders will bundle ID so it's a
convenient way to check where the
application was already with or also
actually installed
ok so how will test
well usual test approaches like this
first you get the IPA file from
developers from clients from the store
as well from the apple app store
depending on you and then the
application might actually prevent you
running on jailbroken device because
well they break
maple some risk for the end user if he
doesn't know what it really means and
what it really does
so some especially financial
applications they prevent running on
jailbroken device
so we have to bypass it because you have
to actually analyze the application and
it's not really a vulnerability himself
if you can bypass the break detection
it's not enough on our ability but you
needed for testing right then the
application is if it's not a standalone
application and then it will probably
contact with a backhand server and it
usually does it over https good and and
the application may actually use
certificate pinning certificate pinning
is actually prevention against the road
CA and the application has this server
certificate bundled into it and check if
it if it will fit is correct and so even
if you install your bed profile on the
device and still the application one
trusted
so again you have to bypass this
and then you expect the traffic use you
do usual web start this
nothing really consider and then my open
most interesting part is this one abuse
application logic
I want a manipulation and you can also
remember forensics the attack vectors
are now very limited and some other
minor things
checking local storage client-side box
and other minor checks
ok and now the binary encryption so
actually apple and this applies only to
the binary star to download from apple
app store because apple app store they
they use the parade erm which means that
the binary something are encrypted now
obviously if they run on device they
must be somehow decrypted so we can get
them but if you download the IPA from
app store
you put the binary into hopper idea pro
whatever you'll get garbage because it's
encrypted
now there are some tools that do it for
you just put their name of the two which
is called clutch the binary and equips
it
alternatively you can use the debugger
and i recommend doing on your own
I won't go into details because it's
probably documented on the Internet
no point in repeating it here ok so we
have unencrypted binary and how we can
start analyzing it and the binary is on
iOS have free security features set to
by the compiler and you're in compiling
time
automatic reference counting counting it
counts the number of locations and the
allocations of objects to prevent more
corruptions start canary to prevent
buffer overflows and pi which is
position independent execute execute
table and this is for a sol a sol are
for the binary you can check those
features
by the way this is how you do on the IPA
file . vulnerable iOS application will
use it here you can download it from the
internet and you can train your skills
on it basically and you go to the
director and the news this auto and it
gives you actually this is this part
binary
so you can see that you have one output
for architecture rb7 once if you
and second one forearm 64 and here is
the Frog pie so all is good we have pie
enabled find you know similar without
two words that you can see we have
32-bit addresses 64-bit addresses with
likes it up everything is good and I
think really complicated similarity with
automatic reference counting
I just lifted for for brevity but we
have our binary binary features to the
checked so now we can set up the
environment again
nothing for the fancy lunch burb in the
settings Wi-Fi you go to the Wi-Fi
settings you put your burp and one
remark on babe just remember to listen
on all their faces because you you
listen on the Wi-Fi obviously two
devices are on the same Wi-Fi network
now we have everything that stopped
we want to launch the application and it
happens that the application doesn't
want to lunch because there is a
jailbreak detection before we can buy
passes let's talk about how it's being
detected
usually that through the checks are
really trivial so first of all checks
for existence of additional files that
are installed during the day breaking
which is like -
and it also can check for api calls for
King is forbidden Andre broken degree on
the non jailbroken devices system
normally would yield you the currently
available shell and also city I URL
handler it is this third party app store
and it checks if they're your skin is
register
I also include to an article for
reference want to read more
ok now we want to bypass it how we can
do it
obviously lazy people they invented the
tool for it to make it automatic and
this is called ex-con you can download
from cydia but it doesn't work always
and then you need to do it manually and
i usually do using one of those tools
which we already discussed and now we
see how we can get it to how we can do
it in practice on the example of this
tumblr bio is application
first of all what we have to do we use
the Aleppo is the common to only make
Finn binary from the binary so want to
extract only one architecture and then
we use cause them to and it's tipped and
we usually check for strings like
jailbreak detection route check things
like this and developers are pretty good
on giving us hints or where to look at
so we can see that it has to class
methods app is cracked devices
jailbroken they divide they return
bullying
perfect we launched our binary inhale /
on left hand side of the hopper you have
the search pane and you start taking a
break right so you can see that it but
it turns out that there are two classes
as a fun and I power CJ protection bc
you can also they compare the class it
also gives you their return type and so
we can see that there are couple of
methods use their ok good so we know now
the probably some of those methods are
used to date into that detect the
jailbreak
I still have some time
good and so in in this application you
have basically two buttons one for
jailbreak last one to break this to they
and employ two different methods so try
to bypass this when you click it
obviously says that the advice is
jailbroken want to bypass this
so we launched the secret that p and
this is a process ID and remember that
this SF anti-piracy is jailbroken
this is class method we can call it on
its own right so we do it here and
returns through device is very broken
right
and now we want to call the second
method that this drug detection bc is
very broken right so this is this one
and we can see this - so this is an
instance method and now inside cup you
have function called choose and choose
will go for the heap and it will look
for signature of this particular class
and it will return you an array of an
instances of this class so you could
choose and there is empty are a no
instances and actually this is because
we haven't tapped the second button yet
the second test after we did it
we do another choose the object was
created we have the address and then we
can call it is jailbroken
so this is the main difference between
an instance method in class method in
instance method
you need to have a particular instance
already created in the memory
good now we want to bypass this right so
we see that probably if this returns
through our fall so it's pretty trivial
to patch it and to return to turn in
those case force and the device will be
broken
indeed you can do it very simply with
secret you just used a prototype is
jailbroken and you replace the
implementation of the function
this is actually pure JavaScript so you
just put function return false
you call a method this returns false and
device not a broken
this is very trivial example but you'll
see that in real life developers they
didn't don't do much more than this very
often
ok a second tool and to be honest free
dies
my favorite tool and I'm a big big fan
of dynamic instrumentation and free
basically requires you two things one of
the first thing is you start on on your
workstation second think you install
install it on your idevice use USB
connection not by five and we'll use a
tool called for your praise & what r
your praise that is basically you launch
an application and you pass an argument
the name of the method that you want to
trace this is very very protection bc is
very broken and this will create and and
I Oh with callback functions on enter on
and the only again this is playing
javascript and this will enable you to
see what arguments were passed to the
function and what values were returned
from it
so will basically replace return value
and change it to 0 with all three plays
0 and we'll see what happens
we launch the application this you do
all your work station and it says
instrumenting functions or good started
creating one function it detected it all
good
and then you also see time we click on
the button to jailbreak and it was some
somewhere after seven seconds or after
launching the application
and block us on the output ordinary
returns is your one changing the return
value to 0 0 and indeed it work - to
bypass the library detection and and you
also can see that was quick for a second
time obviously it also work this
this tool is also extremely good if you
want to press what's happening in the
application sometimes you have
applications that use application and
that tried to scramble things and
quipped things and this is very very
useful when you trace the methods
not necessarily for debris detection but
to see what happens in the application
and you can do during some cool stuff if
you if you are lucky to get an
application that and the best things
like this
good so we bypass the driver detection
which by the way is not vulnerability
itself
at least I don't think that this is just
like crew detection on Android but still
you have to do it to test meaningfully
then you test for certificate pinning
and there is also a tool called SL kill
switch which tries to automatically
disabled certificate pinning and first
thing you do is you make sure that this
too is not enabled and you don't have
your butt profile installed on the
device
if it's not installed and you can see
the traffic in birth it means that the
application doesn't do certificate
validation at all
so basically like if it if there was an
HTTPS then you install the best profile
and if you can see the traffic that it
means that there is an opening so it's
less serious but still
then if you enable for instance slq
switch and you can see the traffic from
there on it means that the cervical
spinning and all is good
however if you still don't see the
traffic it means that we have a problem
and you have to buy posit and again this
is not a vulnerability but you need to
be able to inject into the traffic to
test a test for box like in the web
applications and then you have to do it
manually and there are there are there
is very good to reference in iOS
application security book
and on the implementation with with iOS
API you basically also look for three or
four strings in the binary like x509 or
search
you also look for api calls and then try
to see it on your own
recently also developers started to use
openssl directly
and using openssl has one more advantage
that you have to turn of your product
traffic on your own because openssl
ignores your proxy settings in the
device right now more tedious part and a
bit less interesting but still you can
have some good findings herb you're
checking for local storage and
applications heavily used sequel
database to store data and you can often
find there are some configuration
information personal details
financial information so it's very good
to look into it
you have also something called police
tis property list
it's apple format for binary xml files
you have a tool to look into them and
there are also sometimes interesting
things start application screenshots
webview cashing those are all minor and
more tedious things pretty
straightforward and my favorite report
approach personal is this forensic one
and the basically what you do is you do
LS on the root directory with full time
then you play with the application
changed a bit interactive it and then
you do it once again and you do differ
on both and you see what the and you
look what what has changed like this you
can see if there were any that there was
an internal written to the local storage
if there was an integrated into the
keychain things like that
also one hint databases use something
called right ahead log which contains
uncommitted transactions which means
that something might not have been yet
committed to the database itself but
it's been waiting to write a headlock
and there there might be also some some
useful stuff
ok - tools that are very briefly mention
is one is I Explorer you can use it on
non jailbroken device as well
now with some mutations and you can look
into the content of
of your iDevice by the way is violent
and so I think
iOS 4.2 but you can also look into
backups itunes backups
because when you plug the USB cable
today I device into your pc then
automatically back up so late i'm not
use a second - it's still working i
checked it on iOS 8 . something i don't
recall now which one
it's kind of like freedom you install an
agent on device you create it in an
application and then on your workstation
you have nice web interface with prices
- some functions
it's not obviously as flexible but
that's not something nice gooey and you
can still see a lot of lot of things
going in the application here
ok and some some closing thoughts from
from my side is that still server-side
box are most impactful because the
platform as such is its maturing it uses
encryption it uses TPM
so there are less and less scenarios for
getting the data from the device itself
I'm not saying that it's not that that
is impossible but it's getting harder
and the issue might be for instance when
users choose week Pascal's like one two
three four four zeros and it obviously
happens and good practices also - why
device after 10 attempts
then you are you are less even less
lucky and the interesting stuff that i
got from apple app store it's from march
seven this year and this is partitioning
of iOS in on all idevices and if you
have the image in your head
how it looks like on Android and this
actually ranging from Android two points
something to android 6 and this is one
of their well advantages and
disadvantages of the platform of
unification but you can see that the
security is much more common control in
this scenario like right from my
perspective I start with web application
testing and really
well after some time you probably
getting bored if you don't touch the new
technologies but if you're testing
company like I'll see all the
applications so mobile mobile for the
mobile stuff is fun differently and the
platform itself is again solid but the
barbers obviously will do
implementation errors design errors they
will try to implement homegrown crypto
and this will remain from again from my
perspective moving into mobile is good
in a sense that if you want to get
closer to negative security to reverse
engineering
you'll start touching things like this
you start reading api documentation and
you'll start reading assemble your start
using these assembler it's stuff that
you really want want to use your web
tests and also they give you a chance to
I mean they apple if your chance to to
constantly learn because they introduce
new technologies now
things like Apple pay or health kit and
it needs you to be on your toes all the
time and also your theories of a few iOS
and they release new iOS and happened
half of your tools that you are they are
not working anymore
so you have to rewrite or maybe a
transcript of your tools and also from
my my notice is that there are a lot of
tools for iOS smaller than eight but for
recent is meant to they don't work
and this is why i try to your eye on as
staff which is as simple as possible
like debugger like freedom which is
basically an engine very very rough
engine
and and in this way you
you are pretty much sure that you will
be able to test the next generation of
devices
obviously unless there are jailbreaks
developed in the same basis to iOS is
because otherwise we don't have job and
yeah
and so I think I said everything this
homemade crypto security by obscurity
developer software assume that
well no one can change the request made
to the server so it must be trusted
right and you find sequel injection you
find privilege escalation stuff like
this
right so that's all from my sight and
questions from the audience
these weights
obviously the future with April
improving the protection from jailbreaks
implementing touch ID
how how to test equipment we look in the
future
well I believe in history Charles event
with release of iOS 9 and rootless
system and daybreakers prove that they
can still do their job pretty good and
they are still developing great breaks
its getting harder and harder you can
also see it in bug bounty programs like
zero do
how much they pay for a full day break
on on recent iOS's but also introducing
new technologies introduced larger the
surface for attacks and possibly more
holes and on the other hand there were
like many discussions about the
jailbreak developers they just burn
exploit too fast
they just released the exploit that
released the you know the jailbreak tool
Apple immediately patches it and they
release a couple of really neat and very
good exploit that could be used for a
bit later to to keep their you know
their that debris time for jailbreaking
the newest version longer but i believe
that for us future third day breaks will
be developed questions
was
expect good one hello very interesting
talk
I have a question about the jailbreaking
detection do you think we can automate
it so maybe we can imagine someone
making them aware that that I'd as a
bank application that Detective that try
to avoid the gel gel texture and then
you know the user is numb p and sell it
and then you get to the account again
and the scenario of installing the
application and user device is kind of
limited as is opposed to android you
have only the official app store
you have two other methods of the . the
applications one is a talk without her
certificate but you have to plug it into
your ex called pocket with the USB cable
and deploy it
so we just can't send the file to
someone hey install this file like with
ap case right
this all the malware on Android this is
where it comes from and on iOS it's just
basically goes through the vetting
process which is by the way a perfect
now the second more viable attack
scenario is stolen
MDM profiles companies use MDM to push
applications and then if you are able to
talk
over server then are able to still
certificated push the applications and
then this is viable but you can already
start our yeah obviously Jerry detection
can go very far and they can try to
developers and you can try to obfuscate
they called they can also provide an
anti debugging techniques things like
this so but from my experience they
never did it
so it's simple and it's like going
through the state detection error
I mean I as a user I should be warned
about the implications and then it's my
choice
I run the department question again
but there is one more risk involves the
exploitation of application already
installed for instance the web browser
if you found find a remote code
execution in the web browser or iOS you
can run a code that will take a break to
this is not exactly i mean for
jailbreaking you have to have multiple
exploits
first of all as applications are in
sandbox
okay if you get code execution then our
students and box then you have escaped
from sandbox ok but you are still in use
Earl and so we need to have a colonel
exploit
there you go it colonel so then you have
to push the boot wrong but what room is
actually signed so we have to find the
holder and also putting processes like
multi-step process
I have some additional slides so this is
how booting process looks like you have
this root CA lie down in silicon then
you have lb you have I bored you have is
Colonel and os itself and what
jailbreakers they do they usually
exploit this or that this will probably
give you via turd daybreak which means
that you have to have your iDevice part
to the pc and once we rebooted to lose
the jailbreak and this is what we call a
Break normal here like uh theatre which
means that you reboot your device and is
constant and jailbroken
so in short words it's not one exploit
it's not as simple as that
and this is also why the prices for
exploit our delhi even reading the
write-ups I must admit I tried to read
the right house for this
if you are not very into the platform
it's extremely hard to understand what
they're doing
thanks question on back
hi
I've got a question from a bit different
perspective because you said I you
believe that the platform itself is
pretty solid
I'm not actually much into apple but I
think we've all heard about rumors about
back doors that Apple leaves
intentionally so could you shed some
force experienced on on that topic
I'm not allowed by our advertiser I'm
running Android by the way and you know
it's I think if you have other problems
if your if your enemy is NSA or another
security agency you have you are in much
bigger trouble
I mean everyone is now picking into your
privacy
that's true if you are afraid of
backdoors well might be but you have any
specific buyer in mind that word it was
detected
yeah i mean not please wait
yeah i think that everything is possible
i mean it's only software and hardware
right so it can be also my point was if
if you actually come across anything
like that or is there anything really
substantial you could find in the
internet well media media says that
Apple is being pushed to really you know
install backdoors it was pushing the
past and there are two speak discussions
and their PR says or their mind fashion
is that they refuse to do so they
haven't done this if they did that the
if they have done this or not I don't
know but again like big platform
hardware software it gives you a unified
attack surface you own one
you own all of them right now
on the other hand you can control
security a much better so it's always a
trade-off