ok ok
hi I'm going to talk about zero
knowledge work
what to trust the cloud or crowd with
and whatnot
or how and I call the talk lessons from
vanity
we'll see why am I work for high
solutions in Berlin security consultancy
specialising in and technical topics
like fantastic forensics are also hiring
so if you want to move to billion i
passed me a note
I live in or so and i'm interested in
the the edge cases of information
security like ICS where it gets very
physical cloud where it gets very
virtual or crypto this is where I come
from
today it's not about ICS but about the
other two cloud in crypto ok as we all
know as you know more and more and more
processes are transferred into the cloud
or thrown at at crowdsourcing my don't
have to name all the examples you you
know them
why is this happening you can make a big
analysis
the short one is things are being
networked more and more so it's possible
there's some efficiency gains division
of labor capital and sent intensity is
not specific to cloud this is happening
in other parts of economy as well and
then it's also a kind of fashion or bars
so everybody thinks they they have to do
they have to sell their to be part of it
cloud and crowded said what is cloud you
can make it complicated definitions at
different aspects and so on for us today
it's just somebody else's computers &
crowd is other people's computers as
it's not the same in cloud you think
more about someone who owns a lot of
computers and in crowd you think of a
lot of people who owned one computer or
a few computers each but
in the end it from the from the
confidentiality perspective
it has a lot of things in common you
give away things that should be private
you want to be private to someone you
don't know perfectly you cannot control
and so on and so are outsourced to the
cloud or crowd security relevant
processes for example back bounties is
where you tap into the the power of the
other crowd to help you find bugs and
also security relevant calculations for
example has tracking you can buy that as
a service in the cloud and this is only
the beginning and more there
more will come and my first question is
is this a good idea to to outsource
security relevant calculations to the
cloud
do you think good here no good idea
depends on the criteria of course
so i made a simple chart
it's too simple so it's not true but
there are things that that you could
cool could call a good idea like
likeback bounties they they have a lot
of advantages for the father 12 -
running them and all sometimes also for
the people participating
there are some things that are
definitely bad ideas like their services
where you can order
handmade passwords that were handcrafted
specifically for you didn't bring the
switches but it really can buy these
things or explicit password checks like
sending your password summer and ask
this service is this a good password
because what do you do when they say s
you don't know where it went and what
was gonna what else is going to being
have been done with it
then there's a lot of things where it
really depends whether it's a good idea
or not storage is such a thing
depends a lot on your on your
requirements if availability is key and
confidentiality doesn't really matter
then the more store to get the get and
the more distributed the better than
cloud is certainly a good idea for you
has cracking depends on how much you
trust the service where you got the
house from what you will do after they
have been correct or they couldn't be
incorrect and and so on and also with
entropy you can you can gather entropy
for a lot of sources
this can be a good thing but you have to
be careful how about creation of a
symmetric key pairs so as a metric
cryptography usually have a key pair a
private key and a public key and they
have to be linked mathematically so they
usually are created together in some way
should you outsource this to the cloud
or crowd know the name private key says
it basically it should be private
this is why it's called the private and
that's maybe the worst idea of what you
could outsource to one of the worst
ideas what you could outsource there's
it's easy to come up with a bunch of
examples where it's safe two outs or
something but they're not very
interesting like you can just ask for a
passport at some service and then not
use it or use it for something that's
irrelevant
ok trivial you can request some
randomness and in corporate in in in
your state that is already a good
random state and and not not not break
that state that can be okay
you might even now it's getting more
complicated
make it password hash it with the
cryptic art cryptographically secure
hash function so one that can certainly
not be reversed and maybe even takes
some time to calculate to make a brute
forcing harder
send it to and database and ask has
somebody already use this password or
this hash before but you should only do
this if you're really sure that you pass
what is not proof possible so not in any
word list not too short not and so on
and so on
and if the hash itself will not do any
harm
because sometimes it's enough for people
to have your hash for some attacks so
you might take another has fractions
that use the nowhere else and and and so
on and so on
so there's a lot of ifs here so it
quickly gets complicated a more
interesting example that i stumbled
across a couple of months ago is the
creation of vanity Bitcoin addresses so
there's three terms in here
what is Bitcoin was a Bitcoin address
and what is vanity address
bitcoin are ok you can say our that's so
2000 a tour 2013 or whatever depending
on when people came to the topic of of
Bitcoin and it's true
and this is not a talk about Bitcoin i'm
going to take in something from Bitcoin
to show another . but for that to
understand I need to show you a few
things about Bitcoin that you might know
or not now
here for example is the development of
the exchange rate or wait that the lock
scale
this is the better one that's the the
the real scale
yeah it has a long development
a lot of money was made and lost with
Bitcoin it's still alive people say it's
dead
it hasn't made its way into general life
so it's used worldwide but not a lot
so transaction numbers as they are
ridiculously low compared to other
payment systems but it has it was the
first with a lot of interesting ideas
and it's still the most used and so for
for for some reason the most interesting
cryptocurrency not technically
mathematically made but for the whole
ecosystem and so on
so what's Bitcoin in october two
thousand eight
somebody called satoshi nakamoto wrote
an email to the to the cryptography
mailing list that he came up with
something new with a paper is the paper
first page
it's just nine pages so if you interest
it really read it read read the original
papers it's it's worth it
and the main properties of this Bitcoin
that he invented are listed here and we
don't really need most of them today so
I'm so i'll be just very short so
digital currencies in a are easy in a
way you can you can build some parts of
trust with digital signatures but
information has one disadvantage or 11
different station from physical
currencies like gold
you can copy information almost for free
so when you spend a coin some buzz
somehow it has to be prevented that you
spend it another time because you can
just keep a copy and nobody would trust
the coin if they wouldn't know if they
had been spent or not
so you need something to keep track of
what was spent or not he proposed a
peer-to-peer network
so you don't need any central authority
those central trusted party or mint
anonymity is possible and you need a way
to introduce new coins and he used the
hashcash algorithm for for that was
invented in two thousand and two
thousand trees out there and one as a
proof of work so this is one of the most
interesting ideas to create coins you
need to work to calculate a lot and
everybody will believe that you did this
calculation or did did the amount of
work
statistically at least so that so that
you earned this
this coin and the the likely the most
the most genius idea it was to use this
coin generation process at the same time
to solve the double spending problem but
about this on another day
this hashcash what is it it's a it's a
it's easy and nice nice thing you take
some random thing as string number and
hash it you have to happen to agree on
the hash function before and just check
if it starts with as specified substring
for example with with zeros with a
certain number of zeros sometimes will
this will happen by chance and usually
not and they the probability that it
will happen depends of course on the
length of the substring that you that
you demand and it is a good hash
function
there is no no shortcut you cannot
calculate
a string that would have to something
like 0 0 0 in an efficient way other
than brute force because if so the half
function would be would be broken would
be a not not premature resistant so this
is X exponentially expensive in the
length of the of the substring so not
only more expensive but to the power of
the length so means significant links
are intractable you can only do it for
very short length and this can be used
as a proof of work because it's a lot of
work to calculated and because it's
scalable
so you can you can set a certain
difficulty and make people work for it
and you can check whether they achieved
it or not
ok you can use this hashcash or similar
schemes for four different things
the original idea was to use it for spam
protection so before you are allowed to
to send out and an email on smtp server
you have to prove you did a little bit
of work
this will make it very expensive to send
very large amounts of emails
it wasn't really implemented for and
practice for several reasons
you could use it for cloud performance
assurance
that's another subject of research that
some people are doing so you can you can
try to track if your cloud provider
where you where you are renting a
certain service like number crunching is
really doing a lot of work for you like
you're paying this is also not what it's
about
today because we're not about
performance where about confidentiality
and of course you can use it for the
mining so for the creation of new coins
and and mining is basically this thing
anybody can look for for some randomness
you don't start with 0 but you have to
include the last block and this will
develop we will become the blockchain so
that people know where you are at
what you're what you're signing and then
you when you find the the bit of
randomness that that brings everything
to the 000 difficulty length then you
are the one who remind the coin like
mining you found a bit of gold and then
it's worse
something that is defined in the
standard like 50 bitcoins 25 bitcoins so
quite a lot of money but doesn't happen
so often
ok we haven't said what a coin is a coin
is simply no it's not that simple is a
chain of digital signatures so we saw
how coins are created and then a coin
can be transferred from one owner to the
next better to say from one address to
the next and and the owner and order
means the one who knows the private key
because he can sign for digital
signatures you need to know that the
private key and he can sign the hash of
the previous transaction and the public
key of the next or so the one
it's supposed to be sent to and this
will be appended to the to the coin and
the wood and then the coin basically
tells everybody i went there and there
everybody can check the whole chain
because the public keys are public and
they are known and the
and the peer-to-peer network so the coin
we said signature what kind of signature
is that digital signature of course and
in Bitcoin it's the the ecd is a
algorithm the elliptical curve digital
signature algorithm
there's certain reasons why they choose
this signature scheme
one is that elliptic curves make keys
shorter so for the same security level
you need for turkeys and that means sort
of addresses and so on and they picked a
special curve because to do elliptical
curve calculations you need to agree on
a curve so a mathematical structure that
you do calculations like additions and
multiplications in that work a little
bit differently from standard numbers
that we usually use this is what makes
them more complicated but and what makes
them harder to break in and in a way to
reverse certain operations in and them
and they picked one that was not in the
and the
in the list of usually recommended
elliptic curves like from from the
American standards institute missed but
one that was in a deterministic
deterministically constructed so when
somebody gives you a curve
they might have built a back door and it
so they know tricks how to move around
how to calculate it
calculate faster within it and you don't
want that
and this this curve here as the nice
property that everybody can see how it
is developed and it's an easy process
there's basically not much not much room
left
- - to hide the back door and it's also
quite efficient to to calculate on
certain process architectures and so on
so a private key in bitcoin is 256 bits
and the public key
you just calculate so you pick a private
key for example Byron random and then
you just calculate the private and the
public key by multiplying the private
key with something called the generator
of the of the elliptic curve generators
basically one element that allows you to
to move around all the points of the of
the elliptic curves and it's always are
because it discreet always more modulus
modules some parameters it's not really
important here to understand what we are
going to okay now what is the Bitcoin
address
we're almost there a Bitcoin address is
basically a
public key mmm there's something some
steps in between it is hashed and
rehashed again and it gets the prefix
- - to convey some more information and
then it's encoded in days
58 we'll get to that so this is one
example
this is my address my just means that i
have the private key for this on my
laptop so i might transfer the money
that gets there somewhere if I don't
leave loose the private key anybody else
who steals the private key or can guess
it can also also owns the money in that
way
so what is this phase 58
it's those characters to see what what
what they are
isn't that pays 64 what's the difference
anything missing anything too much in
there something that should be missing
missing what's missing
so that the two special special
characters off base 64 of haha
/ and or or plus are missing but then we
would be at 60 days 60 - what else is
missing a high why is that ok ok so it's
just a 64 you take away the the special
characters
+ + / and also the ambiguously looking
characters 0 a call
l and what's the other
I capital I and and L
yeah so you get to two x 26 that's the
alphabet + 10 digits
+ - that's the special sauce that will
be a 64
- those six soul 58 how much information
can you can you put in there almost year
of 5.9 a bit spare character
so that's only a little less efficient
than base64 if you get too long numbers
for forbid feels som something like that
it's it's not a good because it doesn't
it will align with with with with bites
ok it's not only used in Bitcoin also in
other places sometimes in little
variations so and the the third we had
Bitcoin we had Bitcoin address and we
had vanity Bitcoin address
I just
copy the the definition from from
wikipedia what is vanity
the excessive belief in one's own
abilities or attractiveness to others
and then it goes on that reduce not to
be so negative like it like it sounds
today and just mean futility
so in vain you still have it in in vain
added in vain
I didn't it didn't have any fruit and
there was vain glory an old term because
vein was not negative but the the glory
had the boosting part I in it
ok you can make some some pans all of
that i'm skipping those and their the
seven deadly sins last gluttony greed
sloth wrath Envy pride and hope knows
we're already at seven so there was no
space left for vanity but luckily Pope
Gregory said that vain glory is a part
of pride
so we're we're talking about a partly
deadly sin part of a daily thing
now seriously vanity address is just a
nice-looking not really rememberable
because they will still be a little too
long and complicated will see why but
still nice looking address with a hint
at something like the owner or the
organization this defeats one of the
aims of Bitcoin because we wanted
anonymity or at least pseudonymity and
if i call my address
I don't know 1.high solutions something
then part of the anonymity is gone of
course so you have to think about that
but you can have example x1 pay me and
then it goes on goes on with some human
readable substring after the leading one
you always have a leading usually one
can be something else and the beginning
can be nice looking that's a vanity
address
and why should you outsource this what
why would you get the idea because
pretty addresses like like this
they need to be calculated this is this
trial and error thing we talked about
that's exponentially expensive like
mining so it makes sense to give this
task to those who have the right
hardware in place to do it efficiently
and nowadays or for mining nowadays who
need a special hardware a 60 and and big
big big installations of them and here
depends on the length of the of the
vanity address if you can do it with the
with a standard computer or not
okay there's tools for it
vanity gin for example open sores
here's an example to generate something
that starts with one boat
it took around 10 seconds on a standard
pc thats also versions doing the
calculations on the GPU obviously a good
idea
still you still much less efficient than
been a six but better than cpu and
there's a vanity miners that that
automate the process of outsourcing this
to the crowd
now we're now we're getting somewhere so
my private key in the cloud
hadn't we said that was a bad idea
because it coins have been stolen
really for fallout of reasons of course
stolen ki stolen wallets like that's the
the standard thing but also from from
things like brain wallets or poorly
sourced randomness
what is the brain wallet
the brain wallet is the attempt to to
store bitcoins what you need to store is
basically the private key to a coin in
memory human memory that therefore brain
brain wallet because as long as the key
is not recorded somewhere else
the coin exists only in the whole his
mind
meaning that there's unless bitcoin is
seriously broken
there's no way to transfer the money
away from your from your coin from your
address has some drawbacks of the brain
wallet is forgotten or the person dies
or the coin is lost forever so them the
the money
the the coin will have the amount that
it got forever unless bitcoin is broken
or somebody changes or the community
changes the protocol early brain wallets
just took a pass phrase and hashed it
and there they have the private key or
sequence of private key if you want to
make a whole wallet
you need more than one key because you
should you should really use addresses
so basically we need one address for
every transaction and this was not a
good idea because as we find again and
again
humans are no good source of entropy and
this really hurts
in this in this case and
as as we speak if you make a bread and a
brain wallet out of a pass phrase that
is in some dictionary that is too short
too easy
your money will be taken away in minutes
it will be gone because some people it's
not a lot of them maybe a dozen people
were bright they they specialized in
just draining stupid brain wallets and
somebody wrote about those for God's
sake don't do it you may think you are
smart enough
so did everyone else who got robbed
humans are not a good source of entropy
you have a scheme haha space of all
schemes are likely to have probably only
has a few bits of entropy a random
phrase in a book
there are only about 30 bits of sentence
election in a library or no you're not
listening to me re oh oh crap
you think that eight characters and one
from each character class applies here
website security might have to deal with
a thousand attempts per second but some
dude with the fpga farm is probably
pretty computing a billion brain wallets
per second
just stop No ok so i really don't do it
brain wallets it still can be done if
you take the entropy from somewhere else
or some some clients allow you to to to
try to translate a random a good
random address into a series of random
words that you might be able to memorize
but that's something at 13 words upwards
or 20 words
so a lot of remember a lot to remember
and the other example was a poor
randomness
it happened for example in 2014 the
service blockchain in for one of the big
services in the whole ecosystem
they they run the tool where can one of
the tools where you can look at the
whole history of the blockchain its
public so everybody can look at it
everybody had can have it on their
clients
but they make it easier to look at what
happened in Bitcoin and they also offer
on online wallets
it's another question if you want to use
online wallets because one of the ideas
of Bitcoin was decentralization and if
you outsource the operation of the
wallet to some party and part of that is
is gone and they use the for just a
little while poor randomness and because
of another property of the little Kirk
repository photography those private
keys could be recovered and cons of some
hundreds of users were were stolen
luckily it was a good guy
people don't have a percent agree named
BTW see robin hood and he tried to give
back
people their money I didn't work all the
time because often it's hard to find the
owner of their address because of the
anonymity thing but at least a part of
the money was returned and some people
said that's a really new level of
security as the servers if somebody some
Robin Hood makes tries to make you
secure by by by getting at you and
making bringing your money to a safe
place and then inform you about the
about the vulnerability
maybe we can learn from that so really
cloud cloud vanity that was a question
and there is services for that like the
Vanity pool
you see appspot it's really cloud cloud
cloud and they have priceless and so on
you can you can you can order your
vanity address there
here's the list of orders and you can
also help in
that's why it's called the pool help in
mining those on calculating those and
you get to reward for that
this is examples of what people were are
looking for
yeah and why can this be a good idea
we're talking too much about why you
shouldn't do it was insecure
it can be secure for one trick and this
was in was invented by by joel cuts one
of the big names in the in the in the
Bitcoin ecosphere 2012 already and this
is the may be the most complicated slide
for for today
so what do you do you generate a random
private key a so this is not the private
key that you will later used to to to to
pay to to sign but like you would create
a private e week cried private key you
create this random a this should be good
randomness and then you compute the
public key public key and elliptic curve
we already headed
it's just a multiplication with the
generator so this is easy to calculate
it so efficient the other way around is
it is not possible if if this team isn't
broken but this we can do and we publish
our public
p so now anybody who likes to can try
random bees people log into the pool and
get the task and they then their start
trying random bees and what they
calculators
now it's a little bit long because
they're more steps to the address
we already said in the end you need the
base 58
if we leave that away there's some
hashing in between we can leave that
away so they basically calculate the
the the public key that you gave them a
times g plus the public key of the be
that they just invented themselves so
they they calculate their own public key
and then they give you back the result
the result means the be that leads to
your vanity address something that
starts with the right sub string and
what you can do and they cannot and
that's the most important part you can
compute a plus V and this is the private
key of the vanity address because an
elliptic curve cryptography three
it's the same calculating a plus V and
the public key of that or separately and
adding them
that's one mathematical property of the
of this scheme
so you can get to the to the a plus B
and they cannot because they never got
the a from you
you just gave them the a times G and
there's no efficient way for them to get
from the eight times G from the public
key to the a to the private part of it
because if the whole thing would be
broken
this is not reversible
ok so if it's done right and of course
there's a lot of points what can go
wrong for example there could be a fake
website pretending to be a pool using
this mechanism this trick and they're
not using it or there was even a pool
that did it all the way all the way all
the way all the way all secure and then
in the end they said and now please
enter your part of the private key so we
can conveniently give you the final the
final thing and boom
yeah you like it was ok until in the
last step you
you gave him use your secret money was
gone so can we use it for other things
secure cloud computation
unfortunately not so easily because this
is very special for certain types of
schemes that we that we have this kind
of calculations so it's kind of zero
knowledge work in this case somebody
works for you but they don't get to know
the the secret part
this is basically a special case of of
homomorphic encryption special case
because in your mama hawk morphic
encryption usually have a secret message
you don't really have a secret message
here but homomorphic encryption is
calculations that can be done purely on
cipher text and if you can do that
the holy grail of cloud privacy
insurance because you can see crow
securely have calculations done in the
cloud with privacy kept assured
unfortunately they're no good
homomorphic encryption schemes that
there are part of a few partially as
homomorphic schemes with we're only a
few very specialized computations are
possible
like the example we saw or in RSA
without padding and the fully
homomorphic where you can do all kinds
of calculations like searching filtering
sorting are heading multiplication and
so on
I still being research there either very
very very slow or very inefficient for
from from memory reasons very
complicated but research is going on
just google it today so things are being
at our are advancing here
ok model ability i will skip now because
of the time because you must be hungry
yeah okay in the end coming back to the
seven virtues of our our vanity that we
want is a part of the pride so we're in
the in the last line and the the good
thing is for every advice for every sin
there is a virtue something that can
that you can practice that you can use
against it that that stands against it
and for pride there's humility
so maybe maybe that's if you want to
model for this talk humility
be careful with what you outsource and
to whom it's possible but with a lot of
ifs and the thing I like most year that
the greatest and the most important of
all they're just said to be charity
generosity and I think this is a nice
model for for a whole profession
so give back to the community - good
stuff
don't be evil and so on and that's my
talk
thanks thank you for him