i have not
the degrees of separation are not there
all right
so so i have
two kind of pre-alpha topics i could go
through
uh they're both gonna be bad so fair
warning gonna be a terrible closer but
then you're all gonna wanna after party
so it's perfect
um so show of hands who wants me to talk
about like
behavioral economics topics and how
communication is important because we're
tech people when we suck at
communication
that's one that's one i see i see some i
see some
the other option is uh it's probably
shorter so maybe that's a benefit um
it's like the best lessons that i've
learned myself
and that i uh and that people that have
worked for me have learned from me which
is kind of cool because i texted them
all in a panic
this morning when rocky was like oh you
might have to talk so
uh so i could go through that one too
and i want to make sure i reached out to
people that
uh i worked with in the past because i
might think
that stuff is cool but it's actually
stuff that benefited them
so if there's like more juniors i'll
talk about that if there's more seniors
i can talk about b or economics
both that is not in the card you didn't
pick my name twice
what do you want what do you want what
do you want
oh god i hate all of you all right
we'll do uh we'll see we'll see if one
of them sucks interrupt me and like
whatever both in a suck if one of them
sucks really bad interrupt me and i'll
flip to the other real quick
let's start with lessons because it's
shorter
all right all right i'm counting on you
to do that again as soon as i start the
other one then i'm done
all right lessons i've i've stolen and
i've given all right so
first one in big one uh probably more
for some of the juniors um
be first and make waves right so
here's the deal if uh if if you're not
i started my career uh at deloitte and i
was
super intimidated out of the gate by
like the quality of the brains in the
room oftentimes
i thought there was tons of super smart
people it's like you're kind of trained
to do that oh it's a
great internship in college whatever and
it was it was i'm not
i'm not trying to disparage anyone here
but
it was intimidating right and you come
out and there's people that have been in
the industry forever
uh and you know what you end up finding
is uh i'd have a thought in a meeting
i'd be like oh why don't we just do this
but i didn't say it and then i get
really pissed off 10 minutes later when
someone else said it
and i see tons of people nodding and so
if there's anyone here who hasn't
learned that lesson
say the stupid thing first
also make a ton of jokes
make a ton of jokes and here's why so i
i remember having this uh
two reasons one it's just like good
personal stuff and
like what we do is way more people than
technology i do not you will not
convince me otherwise but you are
welcome to try
uh it's way more people in technology
but make jokes it's good from a people
perspective but also like sometimes you
make a joke
and i remember one of the best managers
i've ever had we're sitting in a room
again the late days and uh and i make a
dumb joke
and uh and everyone's like um
that's how people laugh at my jokes
mostly it's very polite and i appreciate
it
uh but but uh
like so people laugh and then someone
like starts another half sentence and
the senior major goes wait
say that again and i say the thing again
and then no one laughs because no one
knows what the hell is going on
and he goes well wait no no like we
we could actually do that thing and the
point with that is
like typically good jokes have a colonel
i'm not suggesting it was a good joke
but typically good jokes do have a
kernel of truth to them
and if you're telling jokes all the time
you're thinking differently you're
interacting
um oh man now i'm gonna get real
confused
gonna start to veer into my other talk
um
but like people are a lot more effective
when when you're playing
when you're having a good time when
you're interacting right and there's
a ton of stuff and it loops into stuff
we heard before about improv
in a million ways right getting out of
your comfort zone enjoying yourself
that's why
ir works really well when it's gamified
like jeremy was talking about like all
this stuff right
so the point is make jokes
play have fun and this job you guys all
know
gals will drive you absolutely bonkers
if you don't
so do your best to have fun but be first
say the thing
think a little bit differently and then
don't be afraid to joke around because
it's going to come up with uh
with cool ideas this is where i look at
my notes so hang out with me for a
second
rocky sing a song while i'm looking at
notes
that was a b flat from rocky uh thank
you thank you rocky
uh so um so i guess it's kind of a
semi-related lesson i don't have a story
for it
um but uh is first just like being
as far as being first goes he who's the
most prepared wins
right so i use this all the time i don't
really have a single story because it's
crazy important if you haven't done this
yet i highly advi
suggest it if there's like a plan on the
horizon like you know a decision needs
to get made whatever it is
and you're like someone who might have
some influence and there are other
people that might have some influence
maybe you have no influence right but
you know decision is going to get made
in a meeting
build the plan and guess what will
happen
when you advertise that plan in the
meeting they're gonna do your thing
because there's gonna be one plan and
everyone else is like well i came to the
meeting to talk about the plan well now
they're talking about your plan and you
get it your way
i cannot recommend enough pre-planned
stuff
and then it'll get done your way um
so yeah probably 30 stories but i'm not
going to tell any of them but
pre-plan and you'll get your way because
i'm a brat and i like getting my way
um solving
problem-solving strategies again this
gets like being personal with with stuff
but um
or being personable with people um
worst experience in my in my career and
i've been doing
it stuff for like 21 years and securing
compliance for like 17 years
absolute worst experience i don't know
if any and i will name names with this
because this pissed me off
um anyone have experience with a product
called sand tap
yeah none of you it's trash it's not a
thing anymore
it caused i'm glad it was havoc um
so we were doing a data center migration
san
tap and basically it's hey you're
dumping a lot of data to
to a sand and uh yeah
let's you're moving data center so let's
just kind of fork the data
and it'll go yeah sounds like a bad idea
because it is and that's why no one
knows about it
um long story
medium long what ends up happening is
we end up with a one week long
rolling storage outage in our data
center
and no one can solve it no one can solve
it
it was stupid and bad and
uh but the cio at the time we have this
big-ass war room and he pulls everyone
in the war room like
40 people in there and he goes hey um
so i know everyone's really upset and
like on date on day two or three
it was like people are gonna get fired
if you don't fix this
day four the tune changed right like
he's like okay
i really just need help
but a really cool thing happened a
really really cool thing happened
and it kind of happened organically but
i'm never gonna forget it
um we had exhausted like every kind of
root
cause triage framework for figuring out
what the hell is going on
and then at one point uh one of the
managers goes
i i don't know i'll put five dollars
on it being this thing and he writes it
on the whiteboard
and someone else like no that's dumb
it's not that thing if it's anything
it's this other thing
and then 20 more people do it and all of
a sudden there's like eight avenues that
we never even explored
and this gets back to the power of play
because once all of a sudden we weren't
using a formal framework we weren't
trying to figure it out we weren't
trying to do something in a very static
way
people were like thinking differently
and guess what like number three on the
list was that santa
sucked and uh and and that better be a
thing
uh related story um on the tale of that
was the
prop maybe one of the best moments in my
professional career which is right after
the cio is like
okay everyone cooler heads are going to
prevail whatever
our our storage manager uh was like five
minutes late because even up till like
four a.m or something it's like an 8 a.m
warrior meeting
he comes rolling in and on the way in
there's like a little side room
and uh for various reasons
our email administrator was on the phone
with uh with the storage company
and uh and he goes oh i think someone
deleted some luns
and our in our uh and our storage
administrators walking by and he hears
this
and goes completely ballistic so the
thing about our war room that you should
know is a big long room and there's a
door in the front a door in the back
so our cio is like oh yeah cooler heads
are going to prevail blah blah blah blah
and literally five seconds later
our storage like uh lead storage admin
comes in goes who has
access to and he starts swearing and
he's like i'm gonna remove
i will murder all of you and
i've never seen it before and this
dude's the cio and the chief procurement
officer and the chief
operations officer because like there's
a whole bunch of stuff going on but he's
like
definitely number two at the company and
number one's in san francisco and we're
in pittsburgh
and and like and this dude's had a bad
week right he's had a rolling storage
out here for a week no one can fix
and we just see the cio stand up
and quietly back out of the back door
because what's he gonna do
he's not gonna destroy the dude that's
been working his ass off trying to fix
this thing
so anyway there's no moral to that
second one but it is hilarious
um
wow fair enough fair enough now it got
fixed later that day because we did the
betting poll
and whatever but and again i i cannot
stress this enough sand tap sucks
um it was actually sand tap was a swear
jar for the next three years at work
um all right so
do what else uh another kind of funny
story although it's sort of short
um probably anti-climactic but i will
remember in my last gig and some people
know this dude
ron beckman um he's like one of my very
favorite people
um he uh i walk into work one day
and i see ron who's our cio uh
carrying chairs and we have like kind of
a big campus
right there's like a like a five
building campus and there's a couple
acres and all this stuff
and he's literally carrying chairs from
one building to the other in the morning
and this dude gets up early and he like
works on a farm and stuff so he's like a
hard worker
but um he's carrying chairs one building
the other and uh and he's doing it and
then i wait till he's mostly done like
hey can i help
um but
but actually like what are you doing
what are you doing and he goes oh well
um we uh we're trying to hire some
people
and uh we've been asking facilities to
renovate this this space for a while and
facilities at this company reported to
the cfo um
and uh i was okay well what are you
doing he goes well
i'm moving all these chairs okay well
why are you moving the chairs oh well
i asked facilities to do it a week ago
and they didn't do it
like okay but like the storage
building's in the other direction you're
walking towards the executive when you
say yeah
what are you doing he's like i'm putting
all the chairs from this part of the
office
into the cfo's office i'm like wait
what like yeah i'm piling
56 chairs into the cfo's office
it's like oh okay uh i don't want to
help you anymore
because that sounds like a dangerous
career move
and uh and he ends up doing it
and uh and i remember being in his
office when he got the call
from the ceo and the ceo is like what
the hell are you doing
because oh i moved he's a very honest
dude ron if you know him
oh i moved 56 chairs into the cfo's
office and then the cfo came along and i
had to stop
and uh he's like well why he's like well
we have to do this thing we could go
whatever
but the point is um again in the concept
of making waves
the next day the very next day
that entire part of the office was like
done renovated facilities did their
thing
so take no is the point right take
no and if you need to piss off a
few people
there's such a thing as good pain right
um
another related story same company
and i don't know if you and bollinger
and the rest were there at the time but
there was a
horrible couple days where we due to
some compliance
reasons had to roll out multi-factor
authentication in three days to a global
organization and it
sucked i think it was after you left
it was yeah oh it was it was after that
but it was uh
yeah it was due to a lot of money that
we would have been left on the table if
we hadn't done this
thing in a terrible way oh god
yeah it's a worse it's a it's a terrible
real life scenario
but the point is we uh we did the thing
like we built the plan
and like like half a day we had the plan
we communicated the organization and we
gave everyone like
the ability to self enroll and and all
that stuff and in three days
when like only 80 of the company had
done the thing
uh folks on my team were freaking out
right they're like oh my god we've been
doing like 20 hour shifts
getting mfa rolled out to everyone
because we were on top of it because we
knew we couldn't be the hold up
right if that was on us we'd be gone
later that week
so we uh
ultimately what happens so 80 of the
company enrolls that means 20 percent of
the company
one-fifth of the company that's a lot of
the company uh isn't going to be
enrolled in mfa
when we flip the switch and make it live
that's going to be a problem
but it's not going to be my problem
because here's the thing we gave
we we gave everyone a path we let them
self enroll we
every single day we were hounding people
on on stuff to do now
i will say it was not our problem that
night it was our problem the next
morning
but i was not going to work overnight
yes
uh manufacturing and services
yeah yeah yeah uh people were pissed
yeah
right and then i forwarded them all
three emails
like we had a we had a boilerplate all
three emails of what they had and i
would copy their manager on it
yeah take no but here's the thing
the concept
the fact here is there's a concept of
good pain right people are
super super super change resistant crazy
change resistant
if you give them a path and they still
don't do the thing
that's not your emergency that night
it's potentially your emergency the next
morning i made no
one work that third night at all but the
next morning
we got everyone set up and things were
fine and the next time we had to do kind
of an emergency rollout
wasn't an issue people listened they
knew we were gonna do the thing
so highly recommend it and you know but
a little bit of pain is a good thing
because people
are gonna be resistant to it
um what else oh i'm gonna tell the story
now about how i
took money away from my wife
it was before she was my wife and she
still married me which means i must be
cool
um but how much time do i have left all
right we're still okay
um
oh god we're gonna bring drinks up here
if that's the case
um so so
uh this is several jobs ago we have a uh
basically there's a dude on my team
that's super instrumental and
this dude's awesome and i try and poach
him every single job i go to
because he's just fantastic he's in my
rolodex and i'm really upset because i
recently reached out to him he's like oh
no my new company's treating me really
nice everyone has that voice when i'm
mocking them by the way
um but the company's really i'm happy
for him but i'm
also like a little bit pissed off he's
not gonna come work for me again
regardless
um he's awesome and i can't do my
thing without him and this dude's like
look man i just want like
two or three grand more a year just get
me to like an even number
do the thing off cycle raise and there's
like a lot going on he's done a lot
recently i'm like yeah i'll go to bat
for that
and the company's like nah not gonna do
it
um i guess long story short i throw a
complete fit
um not knowing that my wife my current
wife who
worked there at the time was on deck for
a raise and money
is a zero-sum game
so i throw a fit and uh end up
basically getting well that weekend
i get a call from the ceo which i did
not expect so like
i was very lucky i get a conference call
hey we're gonna give you a little more
money i'm like that's cool but like
i'm not gonna say no but i really need
like my buddy to have some money um in
the way i threw the fit before i guess
this is an important component
i said take it out of my salary because
you might as well
fire me right now if this guy isn't on
my team
and all he's asking for is two or three
grand so that resonated
um which was cool and you know if you're
willing to go to bat for your people
like that
they're gonna stay in your rolodex it's
a fact
i'll tell you i've made that threat
twice in my career
20-year career i really don't want to
ever do it more than once every 10 years
but i highly recommend you pull out that
card if you truly believe in a person
because it'll really send a message and
if they take it from you look you still
kind of win because they're the person
on your team is going to get what they
need
um and it also will tell you a very
important thing about the company you're
working for
but both times i've made that threat
i've uh
i've been successful this time ceo calls
me on the weekend hey we're gonna give
you some more money okay i need money
for my buddy okay my buddy's gonna get
money too i say buddy he worked for me
it doesn't matter
um so
what i find out the next day is some
promotions were delayed one of which was
my wise
promotion and i hear about that all the
time now
whenever we're gonna buy new things
anyway
that's a story but the point is go to
bad for your people
um but also kind of be aware of some of
the unintended repercussions when you
really throw a fit
because you might get what you want
but it might you know it there's gonna
be potentially some political
consequences you need to be willing to
pay for them i still think it was the
right thing i just think
that the company didn't really tell me
they're gonna take money from someone
else
uh what else what else i'm like
i have a couple downers i'm not to bring
the room down too much
talk to me over beers if you want to
hear other good lessons but they're sad
oh me oh how many people here think
meetings are the best tool for getting
things done i see one
no one else
things done and get things done in
general
so this is why meetings are my favorite
tool for getting things done because
in all my meeting invites i say by the
way if you do the
before we have the meeting we don't have
to have this meeting
and you know what always happens the
is done before the meeting
occurs
not a huge lesson but it is a trick i
use literally always
and i highly recommend others use this
trick
dude threats work well you have to pick
your
yet it's a generous threat it's
charismatic evil
you gotta like you make it sound like a
favor
right because you've already like the
the secret you've already taken their
time it's already scheduled on their
calendar so now they're like oh i
don't want to do this thing
you've already done the bad thing you're
giving them a
path out of the bad thing so anyway
highly recommended
yeah extortion works yes yes
uh c ransomware conversations earlier uh
all right we talked about that we talked
about that we talked about that um
[Music]
oh hire lazy people
yeah hi lazy people so um
brutal um so
i mean there's like a bill gates quote
about this but i actually didn't know
the bill gates quote like before i
was like talked to a bunch of people
about this but the point is like lazy is
basically
the the bad connotation of efficient if
you hire some smart people
that want to do not a lot of work
they're gonna find a way to do not a lot
of work and that usually means creative
automation that usually means
cool process changes that usually means
a bunch of
neat things that like you might not have
thought of because
hopefully you're trying to be lazy in
your own way um
so hire lazy people i think that's like
all the good stuff i have i can keep
going but
that's it goodbye
keep it going for ricky hoco
all right we're good at this point hey
first of all
i want to thank everybody for actually
just coming out
give yourself a round of applause
i want to thank snow and alex cott for
for coming in and uh
and doing our keynotes round of applause
for snow and alex cot
i want to thank for everybody i want to
thank everybody who
you know i was probably a little annoyed
with me for pulling their name out of a
bucket
give them a round of applause for
actually doing it
[Music]
i want to thank our sponsors trusted sec
presenting sponsor ethical intruder back
there
crowdstrike and garticore for making
this happen
for making this weird little event
happen
we think we that we know yeah you know
maybe
the first in-person b-sides yeah since
the pandemic
so um what we're gonna do now is if
everybody could just kind of help out
uh pick a couple of chairs fold them up
and we're gonna take him over here where
the shirts are kind of hung over there
and just
you know get a couple of volunteers to
help stack
see rick fold
and then uh everybody who wants to hang
out you know for another couple hours
we're gonna get some food
uh downstairs we're gonna we still have
some uh i believe
we still have some of the keg uh open or
not open but left
and uh we're just gonna chill out for a
couple hours so
thank you everybody for coming to
b-sides cleveland 2021