i have no idea what i'm doing
it's all right i do i just switched to a
mac i had to be cool right everyone in
infosec needs a mac right
uh and i just gotta do that
it's right there
ladies and gentlemen jeremy mio
don't worry i'm in i'm in management so
i don't know i don't know what's going
on
do i use this or is that the mic set up
too hey adrian
why does this thing work yeah i move
around and i
i might hug people during it
i'm really trying to delay this if you
can't tell
huh sure not that kind of friendship
check check check
let me get
there you go all right
kind of attaches to this thing oh yeah
cool all right i assume i just do that
that works oh whoa
look at that cool welcome
my name's jeremy mio if you didn't get
that already my name was called
and uh i lead uh
coyote county's uh cyber security
program
i also do a bunch of train stuff with
this crazy person
uh sitting in the front row
[Applause]
not crazy for the record just a joke um
and uh we give uh hands-on
instant response tabletop exercises we
use a d20 system
so we use rpg style gaming to get people
out of their element
and to really go through a lot of
scenarios that they might see talks on
or might hear of and never actually
get anything this looks usually a lot
better uh
online but it is hands-on instant
response there's a lot of slides here
you can just right there just me it
doesn't work with the projector
and um this is usually a three hour
training we give
uh so i'm just gonna like blow through
some of these slides
uh there's a lot of demos that are in
here yeah yeah
no i'm going to give this in like 15
minutes i
exactly five minutes for questions so uh
we're gonna go through a lot of just
about tabletops right so
a lot of people there's look at that
agenda so we're gonna kind of
no polls because we're not online uh
and just overview of table topics how
many people have been involved in
tabletops
great all you can come up to this stage
and you can give this presentation
and uh we go over a specific style of
tabletops we do
uh it's a really this is like it's a lot
right
above much
is that better no
was it good before top of the cleavage
right here
okay
[Music]
so we we use 15 minute table tops um
and it gets into about an hour of
tabletop with a team
it's built to be within uh like a
technical
or management so you can actually
understand and get a lot of action
after action reports this isn't working
well
can i just hold it i can just do this
is that what it is okay all right
so um we go through goals and objectives
we'll go through tabletop stuff and
importance of after action reports
uh so when you go through these
15-minute tabletops they're very easy
scenarios
uh they have discussion points so you
can focus on specific
items compliance frameworks miter attack
or anything that you want to focus on
uh again goes over through like what
table tops are
right discussion based scenarios um
and i can't see anything through here so
there you go you can read that um
i'm struggling right now uh so
the goals and objectives right so you
want to break uh table top scenarios
into meaningful
learning points uh you want to make sure
that
you're not going to have any scope creep
in your tabletop scenarios a lot of
people might
conduct tabletop scenarios and
and uh they'll they'll kind of go
through the what if scenarios
and they'll go into this what if rabbit
hole right so you don't want to do that
you want to have some type of focus you
want to get everybody
on the same page and really go and have
a goal and objective of tabletops
and uh you always also want your
tabletop discussion points to be
based on your instant response framework
if you don't have an instant response
framework
you can use any one of the either sans
or nist
so you want to have just basic like
identification detection your
containment
eradication and your recovery and post
stuff right so you want to always make
sure you have
you know some type of objectives with
that communication is big
a lot of tabletop scenarios will start
um in pro
in and companies will have tabletop
programs
where they don't have a really mature or
developed cyber security program
and even if it's communication you might
start there there's a lot of places that
don't even have who to contact or an
incident who is
the point of contact for these systems
who are these system owners right you
can start there you don't have to
get in all of the crazy you know edr
containment stuff you just need to start
with
knowing what you have and who to contact
to find more information during some
type of scenario
there's do's and don'ts here
you can't really see that but uh you
know again
break it into meaningful points some of
the don'ts
one of the main ones person right you
don't know who that person is you're
that person
so uh there's always going to be that
person that either
has the what if all the way until like
until death or they're the person that
always says they can do everything they
have all the logs they know where
everything is or the person that
is that knowledge holder that keeper of
knowledge you don't want to
you want to get that person to not only
be involved into these even if they are
that person you want them to
see if they can have some type of
resolution with that
back online technical difficulties
oh it is the next slide look at that
yep just keep going you don't have that
much time all right so
um one of the main things that you want
to have in a tabletop program and
is another reason why we cut everything
down into 15 minutes which really is an
hour right so it's 15 minutes for
discussion and
uh one hour overall um for the whole
tabletop
you but that you want to build frequency
right so you want to be able to do that
weekly um would be nice but even monthly
so you can have a monthly table top it's
one hour get some uh technical folk you
also get some management in there
and maybe you bring in legal uh and you
just put it through a scenario and these
scenarios are very basic
uh but if you just get your legal in
just grab them and just
um or or tell them don't grab your legal
teams but
you can get them in and
uh review uh table tops with them and
then just continue that on that path
especially if you don't have cyber
insurance you don't know how to use your
cyber insurance
if you have cyber service you've never
talked to your legal team get them into
a tabletop scenario
then have them bring the cyber security
uh insurance information in there
because there's a lot of clauses and
there's a lot of stuff that you're not
going to understand a lot of stuff they
might pretend to understand but if you
don't know that stuff or the all the
clauses there's a lot of stuff with
ransomware
that um your insurance might not cover
anymore
uh it's a big deal to understand that
stuff build the program out six months
if you're doing monthly or
you know uh even i wouldn't even suggest
doing quarterly tabletops at this level
that's why you want to do
monthly you might do larger tabletops
for a quarter
so you might have you know executive
management you know all the teams
all the business units in there do some
crazy like one day or
one week tabletop but you know those are
good things to get to but you can start
out like
again 15 minutes um
one hour
next slide creation process i'm not
going to go into this
but you can build tabletops we're going
to go right into a tabletop
right charters are important right so
you want some type of charter if you
don't know what a charter is
um essentially a document that defines
whatever initiative or project you're
doing
um i'm not you know some type of you
know crazy uh project manager or
anything like that
so i didn't use a lot of charters until
i was in fortune 500
and it's good to have some type of
simple charters that have your purpose
your goals
your members decision guidelines are
good and also communication
communication is good not only for um
you know how you're going to communicate
the general program that people are
involved
but also every quarter after you do all
your monthly weekly table tops
you'll want to let the executives know
hey we did
tabletops this quarter we had 25
action items and we completed 10 of them
that helps a lot not only for executive
management
it also helps a lot uh
for when if you get audited or when you
have cyber insurance
uh findings or cyber insurance claw or
cyber insurance incident that you have
to get your cyber insurance on and they
have to show that you did some type of
uh due care or diligence you can show
that right and you can show that
hopefully in other ways but this is a
basic way as well
you can crosswalk these crosswalking
them is you know taking
all your you know nist miter cis
controls
uh you could even use uh the get gooder
program which i
uh learned about this morning so shout
out to
alex wherever he is and uh you can
crosswalk these right so
this is just a crosswalk and you can
have these specific
items inside your tabletop so then when
you're trying to
understand your gaps you can at least
tie it into some type of compliance now
like earlier client compliance isn't the
end all
but it's something at least you can tag
and be able to understand
any type of gaps you have and it's
easier for the business and others at
the end of the day
as much as we might complain about
compliance it's what they understand
and it's what they're going to tie it to
regardless if we want to change it or
not
so it's good for us to try to get other
types of frameworks in
but we have to ultimately bubble that up
the compliance so
we can make all of the uh executive
suits happy
after a tabletop you always want during
this tabletop
you want some type of after action
report these can get
all kinds of praise you have lots of
pages but you want to have some
main points here you want to have
obviously who was there what the
scenario was
but you also want to have strengths and
weaknesses it's going to be a pretty
depressing scenario
all the time and it should be that
because you're trying to get gaps you're
trying to understand
uh all your areas that could be improved
you want to put people in uncomfortable
scenarios
right like talking randomly out of a hat
or a pumpkin box here right now
i know right so but i'm in my comfort
zone so
i might start dancing here get some
music on um
so you want to have those those goal
there are those strengths and weaknesses
uh you always want to have some type of
strength
right so you want to find something even
if it's you know hey we're in the room
we've never been in the room before
um i've tried to get people that have
never been in one room before together
and do a scenario and it's been really
interesting
um so that's one thing to have the other
things are recommendations right you
can't see it but it's short-term
recommendations long-term
recommendations
you have to be able to split these out
you want to do if you want to mfi all
the things
that's great you definitely need that it
might be a long term goal
short term what can you do well let's
mfa the privileged accounts right let's
mfa these uh critical business uh
units right let's see how we can do that
let's get them
involved let's get all the executives
mfa's right with some short-term stuff
and there's other things you could too
and make sure it's signed off have these
things signed off
um and you know have hopefully you have
in your charter right and you have your
stakeholders
and you can get these uh things signed
off and you have these stack of papers
and you you solve all the cybers with it
q and a
whew
this is technically the first break in
the training so um everyone can grab a
drink
cheers cheers
do we want to go back wait well let's
just try to find one scenario and i'm
going to call on people it's going to be
fun
boom look at that
um look at this oh an employee in
accounting it's called a security
department
you got a security department so you're
uh reporting a wire transfer
right their wire transfer endpoint
has a splash screen with a countdown
window displaying information about how
much to pay in bitcoin
how do you respond all right nope come
on
do i see anyone else over here anyone
else
this gentleman over here
all right all right val please
that's right cry
please miss bats thank you you're the
a floor account
that makes sense 2fa on the coinbase
that's good good practice okay
yeah cool great nope
response
make sure it's not scareware what is
scareware
what is scareware what is scareware
what is scareware
how many people have gotten a help desk
or service desk ticket that says hey we
got
ransomware then like what we don't have
all of our edr and ai systems don't tell
us we have ransomware
what is that and they're like no they
said it's ransomware so we just like
destroy we just we deleted the network
and it's like why did you do that
did you have any other information nope
but it said ransomware the employee said
i saw the splash screen
it was there yep yep they just
everything gone right cut wires so
done ransomware
scareware right so
no class ball oh well here's the class
poll right
so this is like you know contain the
host
unplug send right panic
right hey coinbase number one
right attempt to remove nah oh
right exactly that's the whole point
it's the intern
fire the intern right hbo max it right
so
uh contact my iso so right so you want
to have your learning points right so
you have you know do you pay it
you know sometimes you might you know if
you're a large gas company things like
that
or you know uh hidden supply chain
issues
too soon um so
you know you have to do some type of
triage you want to validate right you
want to validate you want to see what's
going on
another point with these tabletops is
look you have these little
nice little nist functions right here
you can tag them and then you can have
a whole tabletop program and you can
have that build out and tied in this
functions and your tabletops don't need
to be
more complex than that right so you can
have the base scenario
someone gets something that looks like
ransomware what do you do
you'd be surprised a lot of places that
don't know what's going on with that
right and then you can have some
discussion points have in your after
action report
you can have that in about you know 45
minutes to an hour
and you can take those after action
reports and you can
attach to some type of management
meeting you can have that stack of
papers go over the statuses
maybe some of them get put into projects
maybe you get you know some more
charters
and you can develop a lot of material
that executives understand and say oh
we went through the scenario we
discussed it with management we wouldn't
be able to respond with
uh um you know well we don't even have
the documentation we don't even know
who's who would contact during this
uh during anything right so you could
have one focused just on
a law enforcement something happens you
have to report to law enforcement what
do you do
it doesn't matter what it is it just
matters that you had to report to law
enforcement how do you do that do you
have contacts in your local field office
do you have
um contacts with other federal agencies
for wire fraud right do you have your
contacts for your secret service field
office the fbi field office
and if you have the contact what do you
do with that uh right so you want to
build that kind of stuff
and that's why i'm going to go back to
now q a so we just like inception that
back
all right and that's why i'm here
question
really do you give this as a training
anywhere
do i give this as a training anywhere i
do we i
i am a part of a training that an
amazing person named amanda berlin runs
and uh we give not only
uh tabletop trainings but also instant
response
trainings that have hands-on demoing as
well as
a really good role-playing game
that is the last day and you get put
into
different organizations you get
different types of super cool skills
and you get all kinds of different
titles so you might be
the coolest crazy red team pen tester
person
hacker you might be put at the legal as
legal counsel
or a ceo right um and you'll have to
work through that and hopefully you
survive it and not blow up the world
because
two teams have blown up the world in our
scenarios
um and uh that's not good you don't want
the world to blow up
question okay so we take this training
class
will we be able to map what happens in
our scenario
so uh will if you we take this training
will you be able to map it
to the to the get gooder uh so we
might have a you know a a close
partnership with
the get gooder framework and that might
be mapped we currently do crosswalk to
both
cis the nist and um and miter but i
think the get gooder
is going to grant a lot of traction and
we're going to map to that
we will crosswalk yeah it might be a
skip
so
oh is that a drink
next question
sir do you have a question over here
dance question
dance uh we do not have any current
scenarios that cover dancing
but we can we can try to crosswalk that
we might do the electric slide
[Music]
yeah any other questions
also bands now no
yep jerry mio everybody
alrighty