Thanks so yeah I'm camp cannon I'm from
bae and I'm going to talk about
intelligence-led pen testing but in
specific the use of reversed malware in
live pen tests so one of the challenges
that spawned the cbest program and star
was that we were being asked to make
things seem more real to to look more
like attackers and less like pen testers
fantasies like you know their own idea
of what attacks are like and we use our
own tools and our own techniques each
time and really what we're doing is is
attacking as ourselves not as another
person so here came the the threat
insurgents requirement of see best so
yeah it is the core messages that you
know we need to replicate attacker is
not just just do our own attacks and
it's a sort of the reverse of what we
been doing the pentacene team for quite
a long time we we've had tools created
for testing purposes getting reused by
malicious attackers in the wild but what
we want to do is use the tools that
Milosh malicious attackers have made for
themselves repurpose them for testing
however being the risk-averse types that
we are we had to consider potential
pitfalls etc etc what are the technical
issues whether it's actually going to be
useful and whether this is a legal
issues whether we could be breaking the
law I don't want a malware developer
knocking on my door saying hey you owe
me money for using my kit without my
permission and what are the safety
issues could be actually compromised our
client security so I'm going to go all
the way through the issues with that
ordinarily i'd have adrian nish the the
famed threat intelligence master with me
to do the threat intelligence side of
things and i'm a layman at best at
threat intelligence but unfortunately
he's somewhere exotic right now doing
something far more interesting as usual
so it's going to be me before I get into
it talking about the mail whether we've
got one of the questions I had
previously I kind of want to frame to
talk with this because it was pretty
fair was most of this just sounds like
buzzwords it's you-know-who star testing
or red teaming from from yesteryear when
we've done is repackaged it and real
able it and I that is a fair question it
was a bit of a brutal question from from
cross corner and it threw me
but it's it's legit and what I'd like to
say is that it's very similar to red
teaming we use very similar techniques
but we refine them we're much more
restrained and we try to mimic attacker
behavior rather than saying I'm a pen
tester I know how to do red teams and so
I do the red team's that way I think
that's the big difference so just put
that in mind cool so threat intelligence
side of things Adrian will tell you that
over the past couple of decades the
cyber threat landscape has evolved quite
considerably back in the 1990s when he
was testing and I was not the sort of
threats that concern people with a kind
of loan hacker breaking into systems the
kevin Mitnick and people like that doing
freaking and earlier they were the
hobbyist occasional made money through
sort of you know winning phone
competitions and cars and things like
that but it wasn't really a big big
financial gain for them their attack
vectors where what we described now is
the front door so defending against them
was reasonably straightforward making
passwords more complex moving away from
through character passwords that kind of
thing putting firewalls in and improving
sounded stuff and then over the the turn
of the millennium we enter what adrian
has referred to as the virus era he got
some very grand Wells terms computer
viruses did exist before 2000 but two
things changed around this time there
was a huge increase in connectivity
thanks to the internet and expansion
features in windows pcs and servers to
exploit so yeah you know we start having
the big name viruses coming out it start
to become more of a market to make
malicious code and release it into the
world not just for fun the virus era
apparently ends around two thousand six
but this isn't the end of the story what
happened was a code is found themselves
being recruited into the offensive
security market by criminal groups but
also by nation states and other people
and we started seeing more more well
developed to malware and this is when we
start getting interested in saying hey
okay this isn't just I exploit a
vulnerability I get a shell and then I
Exel trait to another place it starts
being sophisticated it starts being
interesting and we start going okay this
is a proper zero-days let's start
reversing them and turning them into
exploit code for our kit and then what
we're in now is more the professional
era a nation-state attacks and obviously
they're not all highly sophisticated
we've seen the comment crew and they're
very basic attacks and that kind of
thing and I I don't want to want to use
the term
et but I think that's probably how most
people feel about where we are now but I
think the audience understands the
challenges in keeping out the term
anniversary using a bespoke toolkit over
a long time period so let's let's look
at some of the stuff that we've found so
we're going to use are going to go
through some real examples that we've
seen recently and they're kind of a line
to the basic attack model of star
assessment or red team so infiltration
evasion after getting a foothold and
then establishing a commander control
channel to move data backwards and
forwards and send commands so let's look
at the okay the first one we're going to
talk about is a watering hole attack
it's most by far the most common
technique that we've had now it used to
be email and web compromise but it's now
more specifically a watering hole attack
whilst email is still very popular with
actors using additional services to
trick users we've witnessed a big rise
in the watering hole style of attack
over recent years and you can see I mean
there's no dates on that because
Adrienne doesn't like to make firm
statements it's easy for me if you laugh
when I make jokes s this makes it much
easier so basically the tactic behind
watering hole attacks this is a much
more technical crowd than that I've
previously presented to so I'm just
going to skimp on this bit but it's
basically you you compromise the site
that you know users going to use you put
some export code on that and it
redirects you to somewhere that you can
put some proper export code or you just
exploit them on site so in attack you're
interested in compromising a government
agency would place their religious code
on sites such as embassies think tax
researchers and technology websites
think tanks specifically have been known
for being seen by us to be exploited
regularly so yeah they do this
technically by creating an iframe link
on the type the target website this
specific example that we've seen often a
single line of code just to force the
browser to load external content often
as well it does checking at this point
to make sure that the targets going to
be vulnerable otherwise it just leaves
you on the normal site yeah so then our
attacker on the other hand has some
malicious code that they've hosted the
iframe redirects you to it and they hack
it oh I used to be animated it's not
animated anymore I'm sorry some
attackers are now adding IP whitelists
into their watering holes to ensure that
a very narrow set of targets but the
high-value ones the government agencies
and so on so forth so they get
compromised
us the hobbyists the people who like to
go and hunt these things and kick them
in the teeth I'm actually going to go to
the place where the payload associate so
we won't see it this is a bit more
sophisticated targeted attack and we see
these things make ok we are we still
looking at a group of individuals who
are just motivated by ideology or by
mainly financial gain or possibly just a
bit of fun are we actually looking at
someone now who's saying right you know
I'm going after this government and so
on so forth I'm going to void using
specific country names because i have a
a contract of my head that says I can't
use real names so doesn't require any
zero days and it's just cleverly crafted
social engineering to run something that
he didn't realize this actually malware
oh it is animated okay fair enough so
yeah I'm going to go through the pros
and cons of like doing a watering hole
attack but I think that's kind of basic
what I really want to talk about later
is the pros and cons of using somebody
elses watering hole attack let's move on
cool so DLLs sideloading we saw attack
and we were asked to come and respond to
attack in in the energy sector in 2014
it was there was three files that were
dropped and they were a side loaded by
antivirus which was pretty cool that
said I'll H dot exe is a legitimately
signed binary the dll was the only bit
that was different and it loaded the air
we go and it loaded the data from at
file so the as far as the system was
concerned that's a legitimate fall
loading in a legitimate dll but because
there's no restriction from dll's of
being run it where i absolutely fine and
i run our data or the email us users
data and it caused some big problems
there we go Xander's Little Helper does
that LH i think is what we've called it
i'm not entirely sure of the country of
origin of this product but they are
there we go it's a sign binary it isn't
malicious and that is encrypted it took
us ages to go through it and yeah it
cannot be addressed directly windows
without breaking expected functionality
instead it requires developers to ensure
they code secured library loads AK
that's not my problem and finally
the last thing we can talk about is
commando control and doing it through
JPEGs now yeah I'll talk about some
anecdotes around this later because this
is kind of a basic attack that I've seen
quite a few times and I think most
people can see it as being a standard
method of doing things but we were going
off to a one specific group and they
were using legitimate content on
compromised websites to hide what they
were doing but one of the obvious ones
are the one things are doing a lot with
JPG files let me go so yeah / espionage
actors and they could update this in
real time so we were seeing the website
watching over time and seeing these
pictures changed nothing else changed so
we pulled down the the JPEGs and classes
Adrian slides so yeah basically it ran
commands and what exle trade data
through the JPEG and then get its new
command from the next jpg and pull it
down the malware itself was just like a
standard exe it wasn't that impressive
but it was just kind of an entertaining
way like a diversionary way of doing
things that was a bit more distracting
than what we usually see there we go
Rose cool so yeah this is a redacted URL
from the campaign we saw I was going to
take this out but it's a u.s. politician
who is runs his campaign from this
website we'll just call it Jim's website
but yeah there was a contact button I
was really basic it was small in the
corner I think it just said something
like go and inside that they were
providing the me encrypted data that
they'd actual treated so there we are
you look at it in in hex here the
highlighted bites they denote the end of
end of file delimited 4.jpg so what's
the rest of that afterwards I don't hear
you ask but you would ask if we were
having to want to want the render will
read down the bites until it hits this
paradise and then display the image and
then after that it would it would just
do nothing so this is where they were
hiding that code so we perform basic
flip flip turns into a ski and it looks
like bay 64 but it's also a simple
vizionare visionnaire our ground SAP
cipher on top of it this is a real
example and it just returns an ID from
the command but standard windows come on
there we go so that's the the code we
had their to reverse it it's pretty
basic
and there we are so sent the command and
that's the name of the machine there
don't go googling that you won't find
anything I'm promise you cool and yeah
there's another example basically that's
that's what it looks like once you
reverse it in Midway so when we run the
malware executable it now talk so what
we did was converted it so we would talk
to a server rather than their original
one and since we knew the algorithm it
was running we just started sending
commands to it to see what it was going
through and we worked out way of
basically using it for ourselves running
on our own service and so on so forth
and these are all examples from the
cases that our team our intelligence
team have done instant response for and
also hunted down over time and the
actors behind them aren't always elite
stupor hackers or whatever but they've
spent effort creating capabilities it
will compromise and remain undetected
almost enterprise networks we can
certainly both tuned penetration testing
to maps their capabilities closer but
also gain inspiration from their
techniques or potentially repress the
tools they've created poop right that's
all the torrent elegent stuff done
that's the stuff I know nothing about
which is great cool so yeah practical
considerations whether we can actually
use these tools that we've found in the
wild and whether we should just draw
inspiration from the more that we can
actually reverse them change the IP
addresses to our and once it is what I
want to talk about on us I think that's
what the important thing is there so
let's talk about that watering hole
attack the most primary that one of the
primary compromised methods we've seen
delivering a water and all the time
makes sense for majority of curve for
companies doing pen testing because it's
a broadly applicable tool the issue lies
however in delivery so I mean let's look
it from a practical consideration if
we're doing a pen test on a specific
organization unless we comp one of their
websites that they're using maybe a web
portal or an externally exposed homepage
that users are likely to be using it's
not going to work right because we can't
just compromise arbitrary sites that's
out of scope so we now need to then
contact them all saying oh hey do you
mind if we contact your third party and
then we need to include them in the
contract and it becomes more and more
complicated so that's a bit of an issue
of using watering hole tax unless you
want to come up with some fancy way of
doing things and so a solution to do
this would be tying it with a phishing
attack and domain squatting typo
squatting kind of attack but then we're
moving away from a pure watering
attack which a an attacker would
actually use so we're having to to adapt
the attack that that we want to
replicate because we're incapable of
doing it within contract limitations so
it doesn't really work however it does
straddle both a user and attack and a
browser security attack so it's social
engineering but you can also use it to
attack a browser so we're doing multiple
things there yeah it's it's it's not
ideal and then the biggest drawback of
this is collateral damage because even
though we can whitelist IP addresses we
don't know that those people that we're
attacking within scope and generally
speaking we attempt as pen testers to
avoid attacking users directly it's
difficult to to repudiate in those
example in those situations and you can
often end up in as I said collateral
damage or attacking third parties or in
scope employees when they're on their
own systems at home so it it's not a
controllable thing however we took one
of the tools to certain point where we
could use it ourselves and that's the
this is the the command screen of it
it's pretty cool it was PHP so it was
like trivial to reverse and it
redirected everything back to our code
within a very short period of time and
you can run it from any web bailable web
page it comes with broad range of
functionality unfortunately you know as
I said using this in anger using this in
a pen test is quite difficult and the
biggest problem we have here as well as
it looks exactly like a real attacker
because it belongs to a real attacker so
when we see something from metasploit or
something like that I meterpreter shell
running on a system and they reported to
the ciso and they go oh yeah that's fine
it's likely to be depends esters when
they see something that looks this doll
gee if they do and report it back it's
actually you know are going to take that
step to go or maybe I should call the
pentacene company or immediately go
that's probably not then that doesn't
like an established all that's call the
police it's not something to write off
entirely but it's difficult implant
correctly or effectively in a test there
was a source of inspiration to design
better implants and explore alternative
methods of exploiting a malicious file
upload vulnerability for example it's
perfect and dropping the shell but
perhaps doing some sort of you know PHP
function
messing around with it might be a bit
better than dropping this kind of thing
so the dll sideloading replicating this
style of attack yourself given that as
far as I'm aware the actual code for
this Salva tak isn't in a commercial
product at the moment I'm reasonably
sure that's the case is definitely not
in cobalt strike or your standard
metasploit we would want to use the code
that we've taken and reversed instead of
trying to build it ourselves which takes
a long period of time or attempting to
find some alternative some corporate
alternative that would do it works
pretty well though bit and evades
antivirus so excuse me it fades host
defence evasion antivirus and white
listing so it's very good and it will go
through where meterpreter won't however
can we trust it and on the negative side
if we want to reuse the three file
technique we need to reverse the dll we
need to reverse the exe to work out how
that's calling across and then we also
need to decrypt the DAT to make sure
that all matches and the chances of us
getting it wrong first time second time
third time increase you know it's not
it's not straightforward activity and if
we are to get round a well implemented
application whitelisting on a target
system then we need to understand which
applications are available in that
system prior to doing the test and it at
that point if we already know that then
why are we doing this attack in the
first place I mean this is this
technique is well known in pen testing
community dll site loadings been around
for ages last time we did this talk
somebody came up to us afterwards and
said oh yeah saw that in the 90s we
still talking about that but i'm saying
ya know gives us something to do so the
the JPEG stego the back and forwards a
friend of mine from the community who
shall remain unnamed I was plead for
themselves a few weeks ago for putting
together an impressive pngs they go see
to channel and it was it was pretty cool
unfortunately when I told him that we
reversed one about six months ago that
it was an artist were too much much
better he was a bit upset about it and
he didn't shed tears but you know but
the great thing about it is that the
code is really really straightforward
you know implementing hiding data and
PNG is something we
courageous and making it look like memes
in the case of this one or you know
standard upload buttons contact buttons
really basic forward stuff it's it's
trivial and using it using your own
methods of doing things to do CC two
channels during a pen test shows to your
your client that you can come up with
inventive ways of doing things but it
also evades it also moves away from the
standard attacker right so if we're
using the one that we've got its
assigned or not assigned binary but it's
a recognized binary by antivirus
everybody on you know understands and
season it has seen that attack when we
go and build our own one in Python or go
and builder and wanna bash or PowerShell
suddenly we've gone around that and
maybe we're predicting what's going to
happen in the future but we're certainly
not replicating the attacks that there
are around now which is the whole point
so yeah I mean as i said before building
something like this is pretty
straightforward why would you use a
dodgy sourced one instead of your own
and we're aiming at sock and mitigation
focused pen tests then you know we need
to we need to make sure that we're
replicating the attack in itself not
just replicating something that we know
is going to go through antivirus because
no one's ever seen it before yeah so
yeah we picked this because it was
something we'd seen recently and it was
from one of the infamous apt groups
which was attributed publicly to a
government in the Far East last year and
there's a lot of case history available
that can be used the game buy-in from
customers which is what we're looking
for because we want to make sure its
real and other attack vectors other
networks defense teams face you know we
want to replicate all of those and it
has the benefit of being HTTP base which
means it's very straightforward and
often people or socks are tracking in
detail http-based traffic it's hard for
ids IPS to identify because it just
looks like normal images and if you
don't do what our intern did which was
just make an image which had the hex of
party THC in it and tried to just put
that straight through and didn't
understand why just putting headers and
footers of PNG file and I didn't get it
through AV yeah I've on the con side of
things even though the binary hatches
may change it could still get picked up
by AV for users with this real one and
as further risk here that the malware is
associated but
known high-profile threat groups though
we could attract additional attention if
load uploaded to a online malware
analysis site by the network defense
team which is standard practice and you
know we don't want for letter agencies
suddenly jumping on us and say or
suddenly jumping on the case and saying
okay this is attributed to a government
in the east and why is a suddenly off on
the cut on this network we need to go
investigate this and it could be a very
career limiting conversation to explain
to somebody why are we using their tools
and why it's turned up here cool so yeah
whilst fully was falling out of favor
with the security research community for
misleading people into thinking they've
seen a threat actor apt style attacking
an organization is pretty bad it's
probably not as bad as causing a
national security incident and we could
do this as some code is attributed back
to a foreign intelligence services and
we it shows up on the networks of
commercial organizations to UK and you
know if this is a CNI company is where
we working with a lot it could get
escalated quickly but I think just as
born is that do we fully understand the
the malware that we're trying to use in
these tests have we fully reversed it
and if we go and use in a live attack I
mean we're obviously liable for the kit
that we use and whilst we have a
world-class reverse engineers who can
pick apart malicious code like you know
before they have their breakfast there's
always the possibility that some
low-level functionality exists which may
produce unexpected behavior and we could
actually backdoor a customer's
environment if you think about how we
were getting malware through bouncer on
the Google Play Store and that kind of
stuff and you just leave it for a
certain period of time and bounce
wouldn't pick it up because it lonely
it's watched it for a short period of
time it's the same kind of thing we can
only watch malicious code for so long
before it becomes a waste of time you
know if we're using the code from six
months ago yeah okay that's pretty
reasonable but if it's a year two years
and I mean is it is reasonably
far-fetched to think that malware has a
command and control channel built into
it will only kick off after two years
but honestly I don't know I I can't say
in earnest that there is no
functionality on here that I have not
detected and therefore you know I'm
worried about using it
another issue worth considering is if we
use malicious tools for Penn tests the
the malware that we've that we've
reversed and we've put into our own tool
kits we probably won't want to release
that out to the community we'd want to
keep it to ourselves to give ourselves
an edge in doing pen tests and I think
one of the best things about this in at
the infosec community is the openness
and people talking to each other and the
organizations that put out the white
papers and say here's the code here's
how you exploit it this is the way you
mitigate it and and use that to improve
things I think this could reduce a
collaboration by us attempting to use
those binaries and then secure it to the
company's when we're bidding on C best
engagements and things out and saying we
have 30 days that no one's seen they
replicate your attacker and we're not
going to release them until we accuse
them on your system that's actually
that's quite bad yeah and finally out
there I anthr about this earlier every
interesting this that to see where if we
do start doing this whether a hacker
could claim intellectual property rights
or a piece of code they've created and
use maliciously I mean they're already
in prison they could pretty much make
any case they want to at that point and
it's self incriminating to admit it but
you know if they're working for the
government at that point or legally
covered to build and deploy them are
where then we could get into a new
uncharted territory for international
law and be a lawyers would go nuts yeah
so in summary we discuss the problems
behind intelligence pentesting looking
at using malware in pen tests we talked
about what is being targeted how it's
being targeted and why and the latter
isn't important for the traditional IT
or network defense team but it is
important for the business to understand
why people are attacking them and
whether they should change their
behavior while rather than change their
their security there is a lot to be
learned from certain telligence and I'm
really happy about the the see vast
scheme coming forward and the
environments in those fields generic
techniques attackers using but
potentially also looking at deeper some
of the specific cases and tools
recovered and reverse engineered
Adrienne's team track over like a
hundred threat actors using capabilities
subotu what they said it or what I said
earlier so you know there's a lot to be
learned from those people and close to
work with them could be better and yeah
I've spoken about the practical and
ethical considerations of using
malicious code
pentesting ultimately we're not going to
say whether you should or shouldn't but
I think it's something that we need to
have more discussion of because you know
we are pulling code out of malicious
malicious binaries we are replicating
them and honestly can you look at the
security tools that you use and say that
you put in anywhere near the amount of
due diligence into those than people do
in to malware my reverse engineers will
spend ages and ages and ages going over
a piece of power whilst we do review the
kit that we use I think that the the way
is definitely in favor of the reverse
engineers for how much time they spend
on one specific binary and I understand
those way better than I understand some
of the kit that we use so yeah there are
practical advantages but there's
significant risk my marriage and my
presentation today was more about
getting discussion going rather than
advocating particular approaches so
don't shoot me yeah and some significant
ethical and legal issues exist cool
that's the end of the talk happy to take
any questions I got some really brutal
questions last time so if you can beat
that I'll be really happy