okay hi so welcome to my presentation so
this is a joint research by me and my
colleague from securing her but she
could not attend this time so we are pen
testers yeah well this is some corporate
blahblah ng I have to say so we do
security assessments of applications of
networks and all of different system
which also contains some devices and
actually this talk will be about weird
devices which connect to the internet or
to the networks through proprietary
network protocols so I will show you a
few case studies which we found during
our penetration test so we are talking
about home automation pool printing
solutions some forex trading software
and remote desktops I've got a few other
examples if I have enough time and i'll
also like to show you some cheat sheets
or of how to develop proprietary network
protocols how to do it properly and
securely okay so what probably some of
you are pen testers have you encountered
a proprietary network protocol during
your nutrition test any okay great so
it's obvious you don't know how to
create requests with this proprietary
network protocol you don't have
documentation and you cannot connect
well-known local properties like burp or
sub box or whatever which works with
HTTP right so you have to do something
you compile the client may be searched
for some tools maybe Google for the
documentation of a closed protocol maybe
just watch the rope pockets so let's
give it a try the first example is is
with home automation device so it works
well just like that you have to buy the
appliance the appliance is just the box
which you connect to the internet and it
has the output and it collects the input
from your smart home additionally you
get a mobile application for example for
Android from which you can control your
smartphone and during this test we found
some proprietary network protocol which
is working from the mobile application
to the server to this box and I would
like to show you the wireshark capture
from from this box so so the client is
actually the box and the server is the
cloud service which is provided by the
appliance vendor so the authorization to
this device is just the password without
any user name or something please leave
yeah well so obviously all of the
requests from this box contained
contained some some similar fragment of
the packet right well what we first
tried to do was changing the password to
this appliance so we took three of these
passwords and actually only this 10-part
10 bytes changed so well obviously do
you know any 10 bytes hash function or
something like that well probably it
will it was cut or something like that
so let's let's give it a try let's
disassemble this protocol and and try we
actually tried to brute force actually
find all hashing algorithms of this
password trying to solve this and so on
and we found that it is md5 but only the
first 10 bytes of the md5 of password so
actually what was possible it was
sniffing the traffic and actually
perform active man-in-the-middle attack
and collect the information and actually
break the access control because you
don't need the password if you can just
replace ok well the vulnerability
here was not very stronger or not very
complex but I would like to show you
what was the process of getting vendor
to fix this yeah so these were the risks
so as always we try to contact vendors
and we wrote him a report that he's got
some vulnerabilities in his appliance so
he said okay I will patch it by su as
you said I will Padgett biases help so
in the mobile application the new
version that that was in the Play Store
there were new four lines and does
anybody see like vulnerability here in
the ssl connection yeah yeah well the
trust manager is empty so the server
will actually accept all of the
certificates any any certificate so the
man in the middle is still still
possible right okay it's a funny thing
so my friend who is actually building
his own smartphone didn't want to buy
big appliance which is which was very
expensive actually this box just cost
about like 1,000 pounds and he emulated
everything that was in this box by a
simple raspberry pi connected to his
sensors and everything in a smartphone
and writing one line of bosch code which
emulated the first version of the
software and after adding the ssl it was
actually still one line of code but
little bit longer so so this is how it
works okay now let's move to the example
that is a little bit more complex we
often see that in proprietary network
protocols the outer layer is very
obscure like I mean
it's hidden and you don't get
documentation but underneath there are a
lot of vulnerabilities connected to
access control like a function access
control of data access control and I did
a big research on pool printing
solutions which I probably you know how
it works you don't print directly to the
server to the printer you print through
the top server and you collect these
things at the printer by swiping your
card or entering your username and the
printer requests the job files from the
server yeah well it's very it's getting
very popular right now and actually the
big biggest risk in pool printing
solution is stealing confidential data
right like I getting the queue of print
queue of a CEO right so the biggest
risks for a proprietary for a full
printing solution is sniffing the
traffic from the server to the printer
also from the user from the user
computer to the server getting to the
other print queues tampering the
accountability because in some companies
you have right to print like let's say
100 pages a day and not not some more
and also stealing users data and users
credentials so let's see yeah well so
sniffing is done here access to the
other print queues here you got the
vector attacks okay let's move to the to
the vendor claims before the test will
really like to open the vendor website
and see what is he claiming so this one
is saying that he's got roots in
education and he understands that
college kids like to hack so they are
focusing on security and they ensure
that it's completely secure and
documents are printed only when the
collecting user is present we always
like to verify vendor claims so let's
see the binary protocol in this
printing solution so here is like
quality analyzes of this protocol of the
pockets of the robe pockets on the on
the cable the print server sends a short
hello message after user swipes his card
at the printer the printer sends his
username the server responds with some
token the printer sends a hash of these
passwords in token the server verifies
it and the printer set sends a message
to release the print queue of this user
and also let's say charge me for
printing 100 pages take it from my
balance and the server responds so I'd
like to ask you workwear where is the
point that we will attack here which
pocket is the most interesting yeah ok
let's let's see how it works how it
looks on the cable so the blue
communication is from the server the
server sent some permissions about the
user to the printer so for example that
he can only he can print color pages
because some of the users could not so
our first idea was to change the data
that is about about the permissions and
it actually worked so after changing
this value well previously it was Kent
or there was no color copy so the user
could not copy in color we change it
that he can and after this a printer
sends the file it is printed in color
and the server does not verify if really
this user can print in color it was only
changed in the user interface on the
printer so what the world the attack
that you mentioned here you've got begin
device transaction of the guest XYZ and
actually the user was already
authenticated in the previous request in
the previous communication so what is
the point of sending username here well
the point is that well we can change it
now on the cable we did it and it worked
so actually we were able to release the
print queue of other user and what is
even more funny the account that was
charged for for printing these pages was
his account because later there there
was there was another transaction for
charging user account for printing these
jobs so actually attacking this protocol
showed us that all the key risks were
broken here so we could sniff we can
print the other print queues time for
the accountability and actually get
other users data and communication with
this vendor was very nice I mean this
happens not very it's not very common so
he gave us access to his knowledge base
and the other version versions of his
software because on his website there
was one only educational educational
version of the software he got some
enterprise full printing solution for
big companies and she also wanted to see
if it's secure so we also found some
vulnerabilities there and he really
liked that that we pan tested him I
don't know if it happens to you if you
pen test vendor like completely black
box without without the the order or the
request they vendors don't look happy to
be fantastic today okay now let's get to
another example which is quite more
complicated and very funny for us we
tested one of remote desktop protocols
these protocols are optimized for for
the latency our front for the data
amount of data that is
sent for the cable so the vendor claims
that his his solution is very secure it
is really we've seen this in one of the
bank's it is used for critical business
operations and they claim that they are
validated with the F IPS norm which is
quite strict and they provide end-to-end
a data decrypt encryption so let's see
if it's really end to end encryption so
the communication was for the first look
it was very simple the client sent four
bytes to the server several responded
with four bytes and there was a big load
of communication which was actually ssl
so if you would tamper these requests
where would you tamper where would you
change anything
okay well so first idea was to change
these values but actually it didn't
change anything the government the
communication was was still was still
this way but when we tampered this value
which is 0 B which stands for 11 right
we change it to just 01 do you have any
idea what would happen yeah well when we
read like 500 pages of documentation of
implementing the solution in the
corporation we found that it is
backwards compatibility because some of
older versions of the software are still
used in critical business infrastructure
it's unlikely to be updated so to be
backwards compatible they just provided
an option to connect with an old version
of protocol and his old version of
protocol didn't didn't support ssl so
first of all the men in the middle
attack was possible in the communication
we found the username and the password
which was encoded so we took we changed
the password to a long one it's the
ascii hex of this password on the cable
we got this encoded password so like the
first thing you would say about this is
the hash of hash function of of this
password well not really because the
length of this is is the same of this
right so any other encryption algorithm
oh well I've heard somewhere sorry right
so you know how saw works right you
serve the password like the plain text
with the key and you receive the this
ciphered text but if you soar ciphered
text with the plain text you'll recieve
the key which was actually this is
redacted it was actually actually the
name of the company communications
limited so and actually in the binary
executable file of this solution you
could actually find find this data to so
all the communication was the password
was encoded with weeks or and this key
okay so let's focus on the ssl ssl
version of of this solution the default
configuration was like that the client
connected with his cipher suits the
server responded with with no
certificates and this cipher suit so
what's what's specific about this cipher
suit yeah it's anonymous so whatever you
you do a man-in-the-middle attack and
you put any certificate you don't have
to do this actually because the server
does not send any certificate okay it
was default configuration there was an
option in this software to switch to the
certificate version of SSL yeah well did
this was you won't think so this time
certificate responded with some
non-animal cypresses and there was a
certificate pinning implemented so for
the first connection the server stored
the client certificate and on the
following connections if you try to do a
man-in-the-middle attack with wrong
certificate it alerted with with
a terror so what would you do why don't
I yeah okay well well what we did was
trying to not do this like the server
wanted it to do but be backward
compatible with the first one so even
that the server sends not unknown animal
suits we tried to connect with with no
certificate so this time if you connect
with a wrong certificate the server
responded with an error but if you
change the communicate from the server
to the client and client thought that it
should be anonymous suit and the client
responded with no certificate the server
responded okay let's connect so yeah a
lot of backwards compatibility
vulnerabilities there yeah this
communication which this vendor was was
really hard we tried to send them our
report and we try to encrypt this but
they didn't know PGP and they asked
asked us to use a zip file with cos name
as a password but when we opened their
website there was five CEOs in this
company okay so finally after like one
month of doing some phone calls sending
emails and so on we achieved like a
proper encrypted channel and they
respond the day sorry we do not plan to
solve these issues they completely
ignored our emails they said that
they've got so many clients that
updating all this for their customers
would be impossible so we disclose it
publicly completely on the full
disclosure list it was about like
one half year ago well and the fury few
weeks later the full disclosure was
closed I hope it was not because of us
okay another example is also encryption
vulnerability in proprietary network
protocol so the vendor claims that this
printing solution safeguards document
confidentiality blah blah blah and
provides airtight security when I see
such claim I take out my laptop and try
to hack the vendor ensures that like the
old key risks of this solution it's not
possible to break them because
everything is confidential it's safe
anytime and anywhere and it's get secure
okay so the first look of the
communication was the old communication
was on to TCP port there was no ssl like
for example the Wireshark did not
recognize it as ssl but it seemed to
follow some scheme and i would like to
show you this scheme so this is a
quantitative analysis of the traffic
from the print server to the printer so
first like a free short communicates
then a lot of small communication and a
huge amount of data so if it's like
whole communication is one point one
megabyte and this is one point oh five
megabytes so what is it in printing
solution files okay so more quantitative
analysis the first communicate was
always constant 263 bites look like that
there is some crypt so probably there is
some encryption the second one was some
padding on the end also some padding and
this was X bytes this X was 512 when the
when the indie administrative interface
there was an option of RSA 512 bytes so
what is it probably a public key well
actually not a public keyboard like
exponent of public key right
okay always different 40 64 bytes so if
they are trying to do something like SSL
probably if this was a public key for a
symmetric encryption outside this is a
encrypted with this public key the token
key for a session key for the symmetric
encryption inside right now we've got
this huge amount of data and in the
wireshark capture we've seen that there
are many many identical 16 bytes blocks
and I would like to ask you how must
have been this file is encrypted that
they were the these are many identical
box anybody yeah well so if you encrypt
for example a bitmap with an ECB mode of
encryption electronic over break you
still you cannot get the right colors
but you probably will at least know the
shapes so the print files are actually
quite the same these are post script
files which are text files and actually
you cannot get exact words of the print
file but you can get some Sun scheme so
we can probably you can crack it okay so
this was some kind of a hello message
than a Hello certificate session key for
the symmetric encryption side and these
were the PostScript print files
encrypted in ECB mode of encryption it
was a very bad idea so we found in the
embedded software that was installed on
the printer hard called adores a
certificate on the server there was no
trust or so the many of the middle
attack was possibly just by changing
changing this this 512 bytes nonetheless
what was the key size if it was two
thousand bytes or more yeah so the same
as we found the same protocol in the
urban interface so we could do also
dominating the attack for the
administrator of this device of course
the consequences of this attack are
pretty
the same all of the cure risks for a
full printing solution were broken we
can we could do actually all of the
attacks and okay how much time we've got
so we tried to notify this vendor and he
responded that sorry many of the devices
do not have the CPU power and we like
features small latency and speed then
security does it happen to you well they
claim that changing ECB to CBC mode of
encryption would cause slower
performance and their customers are very
reluctant to see it implemented right
well actually on one credit processors
changing ECB to CBC mode of encryption
does not cause a slower performance and
and actually they told us that now sorry
you we've got no vulnerabilities you
could not find vulnerabilities because
the system has already passed some
internal audits in big companies so yeah
a very very hard vendor to communicate
and to achieve like a proper patch for
the for the report okay now I want to
present you the most interesting example
from from proprietary network protocols
we had possibility to test a trading
protocol for the forex industry so
actually the software that clients log
into and put some real money take big
risk and win or lose rather lose so it
was an online application but it
communicated through a proprietary
network protocol it was binary to
minimize the delays and it was actually
TCP in the SSL tunnel so we had to do a
man-in-the-middle attack first there was
some pic the awesome pinning it was not
possible to do a man-in-the-middle later
on the other customer on the other
client but just in the in our lab we
were
able to do a man-in-the-middle attack
and tamper the communication inside so
we've been sitting like few days on the
world wars in the inside in these
communications sitting the next day the
next day next day and we didn't find
anything until one day when there were
some HTML fragments and on the next one
we've seen something like this which
closer looks like that it is a soap
communication right soap message
response from the server now we can
let's say suppose that this is the path
for the web service and the method is
this cluster right so we tried to
brute-force other methods in this
communication we found some admin
service but but there were some
exceptions after doing some brute
forcing we found the method which was
called register user why it was in the
client interface not only in the admin
interface we don't know so the answer
for a empty request with the method
register user was incorrect login so
what do you do you just add another
entity with with the login right and the
response which incorrect password so we
put a password in this in response with
incorrect first name actually all of the
form form inputs were responded as an
error so we put the first name and it
responded that group with name new does
not exist if you would like to choose a
group for your user in the forex trading
software what would you choose admin
admin does not exist other administrator
reset does not exist any one route and
the answer for changing this
was so this was an installation of forex
software for one of the banks so the
banks in forex industry are like there
are some groups of banks and if you can
imagine like the whole amount of money
that is on the forex software this bank
could do transaction about like one of
thousands of the whole amount well it's
still enough it's still enough okay so
it was it was very epic fail the user of
course had all the administrator rights
I could put false money on the accounts
and so on and completely tampering the
accountability of this system when we
contacted the vendor actually the bank
contacted the vendor they could not get
how we hacked this solution because
they've got the firewall and they
thought that we physically went into
their location to their server and put
the cable here and i'll drop a drone
with Wi-Fi hard hacking tool or
something and it was very hard to
explain them that we just tempered the
proprietary network protocol which was
coming through the firewall because it
was the accessible way of contacting
this okay so okay ten minutes I would
like to show you some cheat sheet if you
are owner of such solution if you are a
buyer of solution which uses proprietary
network protocol so first of all get it
pen tested verify vendor claims and ask
how do this vendor address
vulnerabilities which could be found by
any any hacker or somebody see how
previously found bugs were addressed and
if word
past of course and if you are developer
of that solution well remember security
by obscurity doesn't work so use a
proper encryption and don't try to write
your own encryption algorithm because if
you are not a specialist in that field
probably will fail so remember about
that the protocol is only the outer
layer maybe it's impossible to do a
man-in-the-middle attack of the outer
protocol but in the lab you can you
could do a men in the middle attack for
yourself and tamper the communication
inside and of course we were the
backwards compatibility as in the
remotest protocols the question is
because like I think that most of you
are pen testers or specialized in that
field how to hack protocols there is
actually I found that there is another
presentation about proprietary network
protocols at Infosecurity Rob I
contacted the guy i think it was Daniel
Monday who is creating a log key
software which works somehow like Escape
key to escape you for proprietor yeah
well well these are some ways for
example for me if I was trying to hack
these protocols we escaped he probably
it will take me twice more time that I
did it by myself just with small Python
or PHP scripts well so like the funny
thing is that you should really google
for it we found some unofficial client
just in the internet but really funny
was finding on google and actually in
the Russian internet the documentation
of the proprietary network protocol used
in the forex trading software which is
actually unacceptable if you handle with
such amount of money and software which
handle such amount of money okay so of
course you could decompile the client
it's well if it's an Android application
without obfuscation it's it's very easy
right or dotnet application but
sometimes it can be really
time-consuming and the time consuming of
that will be not will be not really good
used right so well our approach to
testing these protocols is actually
actually watching their own pockets and
trying to think what developers could
write about this solution that it looks
like this on the cable well try to spot
some scheme so we try to use some
machine learning to find a scheme in the
communication but actually it does not
work like we invented more with our
brains than the machine learning thing
well of course use for this research we
mostly use wireshark TCP dump ssl down
and our own scripts in Python and PHP to
intercept traffic on the TCP layer yeah
well well I think I've got a few more
minutes I would like to show you some
some more examples of proprietary
network protocols so once we tested
industrial systems for tracking error
feet tags so there was some appliance
with with access to the internet and
with modbus tcp protocols well this is
some interface web interface of this
solution whether it's not very
interesting what is interesting there
was error feed reader at the gate of the
company and its read all the graffiti
attacks which were on the tracks and
automatically open the gate so this box
had some open ports in the documentation
of this we found that sending an error
feed to this box is also possible for
telnet on the port 4007
and you have to put these these raw
values on the cable so of course we
connected with this and we could open
the gate just from the actual um network
of this solution but the proprietary
network protocol is it's not very it's
not very complicated here okay and here
in the hex dump of this communication we
found the araphi tax identifiers but
actually should we worry about this like
what what is the problem even there was
a physically physical security guy over
there so he could watch if we are
entering with a wrong car or not with a
truck but there is now it's a big hype
on Bluetooth smart IOT things which is
cloud computing and so on and so well
there is the slides about bluetooth but
i want to show you this funny thing well
there are some for example NFC tags
bluetooth tags in the museum so you can
see what is what is on the image or on
the picture that is in the museum well
that's not very interesting but there is
a thing called cruise control for
pedestrians anybody heard about this so
this is a Bluetooth device which
contacts which contains some electrodes
you put it on the legs with wine does it
move work
okay and from the Bluetooth from the
mobile application you can move some
somebody's leg right so if you hug this
this communication this protocol on the
wire it works like automatically yeah
that's that's what they're climbing so
our first idea like what would happen if
you hack this solution right all this
okay well there there are many different
devices like there is smart cup which
tests what is inside the drink and it
communicates with the mobile application
through bluetooth and actually bluetooth
is well it's not it's not proprietary
network protocol there is the common
tation do you know how many pages is the
Bluetooth Low Energy documentation to
actually create pockets and understand
what's going on there you have to read
3,000 pages so we call it proprietary
and well in my city there was a hacking
competition by startup which invented
appliance in the car which connects with
a mobile device and you can open your
car with a mobile application and
actually we hug this competition even
though somebody told them that it's
unbreakable because the you use of AES
and actually it the topic of connected
cars is very is very big now like BMW
Audis and Volkswagens are implementing
all they're connected car devices which
which you can open the car with the
mobile device you can control the air
conditioning well well I've got some
funny stories about that when i entered
the volkswagen dealer and tried to hack
this connected car but okay maybe that's
for the after party okay I would like to
really thank you for attending my
presentation well my company invented
some like think for a better world we
provide free consultancy of security we
spend one hour per week for a free
consultation see if you have any not
only business like we have private
concerns about security you can ask this
well the link is in Polish but if you
send me an email actually I can send you
the english version sorry and if you
have if you have got any questions you
can ask me and leave your business card
if you want the presentation or my other
presentations