good morning I realized that I do not
look anything like the picture in the
program as you know being in security
ages you I've I've been at this for
about eight months yeah eight months and
look at me now no actually I am very
very happy to be here in London again I
lived here 20 years ago I was brought in
to work on the security aspects of the
merger between swiss bank corporation
and SG Warburg if there any of you who
remember that and you never really take
full advantage in hindsight of being in
a place like London until you've left so
I'm very happy to be back here again
having everyone asked me you're not from
here all you and having it having all
the the wonderful food and the people
are very uniformly nice especially in
the security community here everybody's
really some of the nicest people that
I've ever met and don't tell the people
in this wait this is being recorded by
tripwire isn't it oh crap okay so I'm
going to talk about how Google turned me
into my mother I'm going to talk about a
problem how many of you are caring for
older parents or relatives in the
audience there's everybody too young for
that okay you'll have to take my word
for it then people who have children
minor children that they're having to do
things online for and everything there's
a large problem that I I don't think is
being adequately addressed yet and it
has to do with proxying and delegation
and a lot of you who have worked in
identity and access management know that
this is this is a pretty common issue
but the thing is it's different for the
enterprise and I think this is going to
have larger societal implications as we
go along so it's sort of a definition of
proxying you know as you know generally
a proxy will say you know treat me as if
I were the thing that you were talking
to and I will do all the conversation on
their behalf
we'll pass it back to them and so on it
has legal implications which we'll talk
about any of you who have had to do a
health care proxy for somebody else I
don't know what the legal ramifications
are here in the UK but in the United
States again under certain circumstances
if someone's in the hospital and can't
speak for themselves you would help make
the decisions for them and those are
some well obviously they have
life-changing ramifications for those
sorts of decisions that you make for
them and a durable power of attorney
again forgive me I don't know what the
legal terms here are in the UK but
generally you can administer the assets
of a person on their behalf whether it's
real estate transactions or managing
their bank accounts signing legal
documents on their behalf and so on now
in the United States in general there
are two ways that this document can take
effect either immediately as soon as the
person signs it or upon incapacitation
now the legal definition of
incapacitation is very difficult to
establish and incapacitation isn't
always just being unconscious in a
hospital or whatever especially as their
aging seniors in particular tend to have
waxing and waning cognitive abilities
some days they will be very on top of
things other days especially if they get
a fever or any sort of thing they enter
a state that's the medical profession
calls delirium where it's you know they
may have trouble communicating having
trouble putting a sentence together
they're not sure where they are they're
disoriented it's not dementia which is a
much more long-term gradual thing but it
can look just like dementia and so in
fact one of the classic signs that I
mt's look for if they're called to a
house and there's a senior citizen
especially a woman who is you know not
communicative is very out of it they say
backed a urinary tract infection because
those are very asymptomatic for older
people but it immediately results in
them just being completely out of it my
mother for example when she had one
drove home pulled her cart into the
garage and immediately fell asleep at
the wheel so that sort of thing so that
there are some very difficult problems
with getting someone declared
incapacitated for this reason if you try
to go to an elderly relative and say I
want to take over everything for you
because you can't do it anymore you're
going to have words with that person
it's a very long difficult psychological
struggle for them to start losing the
agency in their life and the ability to
do things and many of them will not will
not accept it or acknowledge and you
know all the way to the end so it's a
very difficult conversation to have and
it's sort of talking between proxy and
delegation it's the you know the
difference between root and soodhu but
the problem is that in real life none of
this is logged when you take this over
on behalf of somebody else it's on you
to be financially responsible to be very
clear document everything that you're
doing on their behalf you know
withdrawals you're making from their
bank account bills that you're paying
especially if you're reimbursing
yourself you have to have a very clear
documentation trail as to why you're
doing it there is there are a lot of
problems especially with seniors being
taken advantage of by the relatives my
my half-sisters half sister-in-laws
father had all of his assets taken by
one of her half-siblings when he became
to some extent incapacitated and the
bank accounts were emptied and you know
that those funds will never be recovered
so you have to care a lot about that too
when people are at that very vulnerable
stage of their lives this is a
depressing talk isn't it I'm sorry
so I've talked about this before in the
past that role based access control that
doesn't deal with this or with anything
else will really know our back has its
time in place but generally they're
dealing with bundles of entitlements and
if you are delegating access to somebody
else it's usually for a very specific
reason it might be time limited you
don't want them to have all the same
bundle of entitlements that come with
your role but if it's too confusing to
sort out if your system is not granular
enough to give just those accesses that
you want them to have you end up just
giving them the whole bundle you know
because you can't be bothered and again
you know I'm out for the next week then
raywood is going to take my place but I
don't want them getting into the silver
you know I want them to be able to do
some other things on my behalf and our
back doesn't doesn't deal with that too
well so the old sort of old-style our
back is that you have a group of
entitlements and they map to your
position in the organization so if you
are a research director here is the role
that you are given and it had it comes
with a static bundle of entitlements and
you know this is what you should be
doing you add more roles and
administrators get all the roles because
it's easier that way and that's it
that's the way it works now first of all
even in an enterprise this assumes that
you're either a customer or you're an
employee and as you know there are many
many different roles in there for
example QA testers QA testers have to
have all the roles when they're you know
testing something in an application an
administrator of an application should
not be an administrator of the operating
system just to the application it
doesn't reflect different axes of
governance you are doing this on behalf
of this department you're doing this on
behalf of an external customer or
another agency this is particularly
difficult and complicated in the public
sector for government because your sin
citizens are not your customers that
they usually don't want to do business
with you they have to and they may be
using roles themselves and dealing with
you for example it's time for the
monthly reporting you know I don't
really feel like logging in and doing
this can you do this here's the password
which is another reason why two-factor
authentication doesn't so sara lee work
that well because they'll just hand over
the token and say can you log in and do
the reporting to the state thank you and
it doesn't support context switching and
I'll show you what I mean first of all
if you're working for more than one
organization or Department when I worked
for the state of Texas for the Education
Agency we had many teachers for example
who worked for they moonlighted for more
than one school district there might be
legal requirements or separation of
duties so you cannot give out a union
set of entitlements you may be working
on behalf of one insurance broker and
then you have to log back out and log
back in on behalf of the other insurance
broker to do that work so these sorts of
things are just not and general not
handled very well I had to replace a 10
year old custom single sign-on system
that fronted for about 60 applications
that were used by a statewide external
base of about 50,000 users in higher
education school districts campuses
nonprofits you know any agency that had
to do something with education and so I
had to try to migrate that to Tivoli and
i can tell you i made the IBM engineers
cry because there was just so much
complexity in the business rules that
had to be built in and it was a multi
year long project so let's talk about
context plus government of plus
governance there is usually an identity
Authority who says yes you know I've
looked at your your picture ID and I can
vouch for you that you are who you say
you are but you also need an access
authority somebody who
is responsible for the data that you're
going to access and has to give their
permission for you to access it which is
not the identity authority this is where
you end up with long forms with multiple
signatures on it because everyone has a
particular area of governments the
governance that they are responsible for
administering and they have to sign off
on your accent your access so they have
to say both who you are and why you need
access to this so again at the State you
might have a superintendent who says yes
this staff member at the district works
for me they are in a role of reporting
on on the free lunch program for poor
students and you know therefore they
should have access to this system only
and then all that ends up in a bundle of
what your entitlements would be so again
somebody validates you as an individual
somebody says here is you know who who
you are in the context of whatever it is
you're doing I I don't know what this
gentleman here's he's kind of dodgy but
he's he's waving an ID card so he must
be all right or you know you're a
medical professional in the Internet of
cows somebody will validate that you are
a cow so it's it's not just about who
you are it's about what you can do so
you will have a function to do you will
have a scope within which you will do it
on behalf of an organization or only
until midnight or only on these days or
only with these systems and all that
will turn into your your authorization
so it's very much like a game of Clue
you know it'll be professor plum in the
kitchen with a lead pipe or maybe with a
candlestick or in the library and this
is more what a you know enterprise roles
and entitlements look like and in fact
it can get even more you can get more
complicated because you're really adding
different sort of functions you're
either killing or you're being killed
in the kitchen with a lead pipe or you
know whatever so that it's that
combination especially in a dynamic
environment that is going to make
Identity and Access Management very
complex so here we go you know things
all the combinations that are possible
out here you know this is this is what
people have to deal with in real life I
don't have to tell you this with a no
date in the library in the shared
library so again this is this is really
how it should be working and it should
be working this way in the consumer I
want to say consumer world but it's like
in the real world the non enterprise
world somebody vouches for you and if
you own the data you approve the access
to it by this organization and by those
authorized individuals and by the way
this is another reason why full
Federation doesn't always take on
because a lot of organizations don't
won't just accept somebody else's word
that they have an employee who needs
access to the data for for legal reasons
they still have to have the final step
of approval and again that this can lead
to a lot of creative solutions
especially in applications I once found
out that because my organization
required so many signatures for legal
reasons on forms for every access that
somebody had externally and these things
had to be processed on paper and it was
very slow i found that developers were
just creating these nice little backdoor
urls that they were handing out to users
to say just just click on here and
you'll go straight into the application
and see what you want to see and so that
that happens a lot you are a bunch of
these things a bunch of these roles a
parent and administrator a customer a
subscriber and you could be all of these
things at different times and the
functions and the scope are different
one another really big problem that we
have in the enterprise today is
it used to be in the past that
enterprises had used a completely
different set of software from what you
would use personally I mean nobody uses
an ERP system for fun right if you do
raise your hand and we'll stage an
intervention but nowadays you may be
using Google Docs you may be using
Dropbox there's so many different types
of software that you can be using at any
given time either on your own behalf or
behalf of the organization from the same
device during the day and the
implication of this for the enterprise
is that they cannot tell what data is
business data anymore they can't tell by
which application created it which
device it was created on where it's
being stored in which format where the
user was when it was created what time
of day none of that matters anymore what
matters is the actual content of the
data and you have to look at it very
closely to say does this belong to us is
this part of the e-discovery you know do
we have to go look at everything that
this user has ever touched because they
may have something that's responsive to
this request that this is why things
have gotten you know to the state that
they are in now so let's talk about
consumers or normal people as we may
call them one example is minor children
I don't know what sort of arrangements
you have here again in the UK but for my
met my prescription insurance provider
informed me that as soon as my oldest
child turned 13 he would need to have
his own login into the online system and
he wouldn't even need to give me
permission to manage his prescriptions
for him and I'm not sure why it was 13 I
don't know if there was some sort of
anyway something very strange then there
are incapacitated adults now you may be
hit by a bus or it may be a periodic
illness you could be on really good pain
pills I know
that has happened to me I've actually
written reports under the influence if
you read some of them you may be able to
tell which one's those were but assuming
this role takes a lot of time in
bureaucracy I know someone gave a talk
at i think it was besides atlanta about
how somebody a spouse suddenly passed
away and they just could not get access
to their accounts even though it was an
emergency so think about this for a
minute if you walked out of here and you
were hit by a bus who would pay your
bills for you and how would they do it
how would they have access to it so
going up to the official route you have
to be able to prove that this person is
incapacitated just saying that they're
in hospital well how long will they be
in a hospital oh I don't know two weeks
four weeks well you don't need to take
it over well yes there are bills that
are due tomorrow it's a lot of
bureaucracy and then as I mentioned
convincing somebody else that they're
incapacitated especially as they get
older it can destroy your relationship
it's just horrible nobody wants to do
this so as I mentioned they said you
know you're 13 year old has to have his
own account and you he has to give you
permission to administer his
prescriptions for him and I said okay so
i created a second account for my 13
year old with one of my other email
addresses because i knew they would
check to see if they were unique so I
used a second email address gave myself
permission went back to work obviously
this is not in the spirit you know that
they had set this up in but they really
did not have a you know a good answer
and the only authentication that was
done is demographic data and you know
I'm the mother of course I know when he
was born and you know all these other
things I forget what they were asking
for but just that sort that level of
knowledge I could do everything online
and nobody was the wiser
another example was when I had to take
over one of my parents accounts and I
could set up the debt or another medical
online thing and I could set it up
online and nobody was the wiser I set it
up as my mother and they said if you
want to revoke this you have to do it in
writing like what who thought of that
business rule who actually walked
through this and figured out that this
you know made any sort of sense so the
authentication mechanisms for online
registration and delegation and so on
they end first of all you need to know
what your the name of your father's
first pet was which you may want to go
home and ask if you don't know you have
to be able to navigate online which
again is not necessarily given there are
still many non-technical people out
there or even if they could at some
point you know maybe they can't navigate
anymore now so they can't set up the
delegation for you anymore if they could
they wouldn't need it this is something
that you know people are not talking
about it they assume that you have
standard IDs as people age in the United
States especially if they can't drive
anymore they won't have a driver's
license it's too difficult for them to
get some place to renew that driver's
license sometimes they give you a state
ID card instead so that you can go vote
but again going through that if you're
mentally not you know really competent
enough it seems like an insurmountable
challenge to find out what you need to
do what you need to sign who you need to
go see they always assume that if you
have a different email address you're a
different person which is pretty silly
they assume that a phone number
especially for two factor authentication
belongs only to one person which again
if you have children who want to borrow
your devices all the time you know
that's not the case and there's no
cleverness in the security challenge
questions they assume that you are not
trying to be tricky like
you know british airways is ridiculous
as the answer to you know what's your
pet's name they're assuming that when
you are are setting up those challenge
questions you're not trying to be very
very clever the problem is if somebody
else is trying to be clever and you have
to figure out the way in which they were
clever because you're trying to
reconstruct their account later you're
going to be in trouble so this is
another thing that really bugs me about
security challenge questions there are
many many systems out there where they
make you change your password regularly
because of regulations but they don't
make you change the answers to your
security questions so as a result there
are some systems where I don't bother
remembering my password I just reset it
because I will always answer the same
security challenge questions and if I
only have to do this you know once a
quarter that's what i'm going to do so
you will always fall back to the one
factor that you can rely on that is
static that you can easily remember the
this is another gap that we are not
dealing with too well so this is my dad
this was his first email address you can
see this is an old UCP format he was the
one who was responsible for getting me
into this whole computery thing at the
age of 12 I made a mistake of telling
him that I was bored never do that never
tell your parents that you're bored he
threw a basic manual at me and said go
make the bell ring on the teletype over
there anybody know what a teletype is
it's like you know yes okay I'm not
alone so he did that he wrote one of the
first Fortran compilers so he started
very very early in this business you
know so nobody can say he wasn't
technical he was a nuclear physicist
without a license he was an astronomer
he did a lot of hacking on his own and
in fact he wrote a story about the
elegance of programming back in the days
when you had to fit it into very very
tiny spaces and so you may want to read
the story of Mel it's also in the back
of the hackers dictionary out there so
he was the one who really got me started
on
this but the problem is as time went on
he was a total command line guy he hated
windows with a purple passion he would
not use it at all he only agreed to use
linux because he could go back to the
command line so there got to be a point
especially as online things got more
complicated that he just did not want to
deal with them anymore he was you know
kind of mentally stuck in the 80s maybe
the early 90s so even for somebody like
him who had been in on the ground floor
things have moved to the point where he
could not you know really keep up
anymore so it's a really good thing he
didn't believe insecurities because when
he had his stroke I had to he was the
one who was paying the bills I had to
break into his banking accounts and by
that time he was too out of it to be
able to help me luckily he had cashed
his gmail password and if you know that
you know that if you want to break into
any count all you have to do is get into
their email and then you can reset
everything from there so that's what I
did you know and there's another thing
we you know we have a lot of stock
photos really horrible ones of evil
hackers that are male why don't why
don't we have any good ones that are
female you know I that this is the only
one I could come up with you know that
and mrs. Roberts I guess probably I'm
closer to mrs. Roberts now so I had to
break into all of his accounts and if I
had tried to do this can you imagine me
going to google and saying well you know
my father is had a stroke yes he can
speak no he really can't tell me how to
login anymore he can't he certainly
can't go to his bank and explain
everything to them he can't walk and in
fact a lot he sleeps a lot of the day
and you know trying to go to the bank
and saying I really need to take over
his accounts for him it was easier just
to do this all online and just not tell
anybody now this is a problem if you
have to take over somebody's accounts
and work on their behalf so do you for
example go to the bank and do you log in
to their
bank account or do you try to convince
them to set up a delegation account with
your own login and just delegate all the
functions to them do you change their
passwords to something you can remember
so that as a result they don't know what
it is and they can't get in or do you
try to remember their passwords yeah I
know there are things like LastPass and
one password and that sort of thing but
when it's an emergency and you're trying
to figure out what you should do these
are questions you ask yourself do you
reset the challenge questions is it what
was the name of his first pet or what
was the name of my first pet wait a
minute which one did I set and again you
know you're in a crisis you're very
distressed because your parent is very
ill you're trying to make these
decisions do you use your phone an email
for two-factor off if they didn't have
it set up it's pretty easy but if they
had been using it do you want to make
them feel better and feel like they're
still in control by letting them keep
you know the email and phone and so on
if they ask for a phone number you have
to try to figure out what that
institution is going to use it for if
they're going to call my mother and say
you've got a problem with your bank
balance you may want to leave it with
them if it is for password resets and
you live five miles away or a thousand
miles away and you're trying to do this
for them then maybe it should be your
phone number sometimes they won't let
you set to so there are these sort of
logistical things that have to get
sorted now the arguments were using
their for using their accounts and just
logging in as them is that a lot of
institutions still aren't ready to deal
with this in doing it in the form in a
formal way requires their cooperation it
requires that they are emotionally ready
to say yeah okay you know i'll give you
the passwords i'll let you do this even
assuming they can remember where they
have accounts because a lot of people
don't again it requires mental capacity
mobility it requires a lot of paperwork
for every account most of this has to be
done out of band notaries public
and it requires a lot of time now that
another advantage for doing it is that
you have an ostensible separation of
duties in in some cases now against
using their accounts if they catch you
they may block you I was administering
my mother's accounts and I actually had
a login of my own but there was one bank
account that for some reason the bank
would not let me see in my own account
so I just used my mother's account and
depending on where i was at any point in
the day some caregiver needed to check
and I didn't have my mother's set of
checks because I didn't want to take
them from her house because then she
would get upset and want to know where
they were so I would write a check and
then I would transfer the money from her
account to mine and I guess the first or
second time I did that from my mother's
account they said Oh fraud and they
blocked it and I called them and they
said well your mother has to go into a
bank branch and show ID and explain to
them that no it really was okay and
again my mother's very very limited
mobility this would be taking you know
the better part of a day to get her into
a bank branch she would be exhausted
afterwards that you know this is not
going to work so I just went okay and I
logged into my account and finished the
transactions so again this is not a
great solution and again especially if
if they're sort of wavering if your
parents are wavering there's maybe some
days where they're perfectly fine with
you helping out and other days when
they're not and all of a sudden they
will say what are you doing you're
messing around you know with my things
and the right there absolutely right so
now we're getting to the good part of
the story this is how google turned me
into my mother so i have for gmail
accounts on my laptop i have a work one
i have my personal gmail and now i have
my father's and my mother's
so what happened was when I was going
through and setting these up and turning
on two-factor off because again my
father did not believe in security and
doing all this I happen to put in my
personal address and added it to my
mother's gmail account as an alternate
email address and then I forgot about it
because I was doing a lot of different
things what happened was I started
getting email address to me Wendy at
Nathan com except they had my mother's
real name attached to it and that was
really creepy I joined the board of a
nonprofit organization they added me to
their mailing list and suddenly it was
coming to me under my mother's name but
to my personal address and I thought
what is this what's going on here and it
was anybody who used gmail at all and I
found out what actually happens is that
Gmail will very happily add very
helpfully add the primary account
holders name to whatever alternate
address you're emailing now why is this
a problem let's say you're Superman and
you're setting up gmail com and you're
setting up an alt email anybody now who
uses Gmail who emails Clark at Kent com
even as their composing it gmail will
say oh you mean Superman so this is yeah
this is kind of a problem so I reported
this to google and they said no this is
functioning as intended so I was like
okay all right you don't mind if I talk
about this then oh no that's fine okay
that's good so how do we deal with this
the problem is that especially if you
add a delegation account to anything
that's very important finances or school
logins or everything if you imagine
everything that you are doing in your
digital life and having to delegate
somebody else to help out with this
first of all adding another set of
credentials doubles the attack surface
right there
it's bad enough that you're you know
your mother's account could get hacked
especially if she doesn't choose a great
password or he doesn't believe in
security as my dad didn't how do you
monitor for fraud properly how do you
tell the difference between me
reimbursing myself into my bank account
because I was writing checks for my
mother as opposed to I'm draining her
account drying and again a lot of banks
have not sorted this out yet they are
still thinking about only about external
attackers and they're looking for those
patterns of fraud they're not looking at
oh you know Wendy Mather has the same
last name has a delegation account if we
set up the delegation account maybe this
is okay well you know for what she's
doing how does revocation work if
they're no longer in a state where they
are able to manage their own affairs how
can they revoke this we don't have a
good mechanism for that if it's out of
bandits to owners for somebody who's
disabled especially if they're
cognitively impaired so they really
don't have any protections themselves if
they want to do that so that's these are
you know societal problems and this is
going to get worse as the baby boomer
generation ages because right now
everybody assumes that all these older
people they don't have accounts anyway
they don't know what they're doing but
everybody in the boomer generation you
know is living living a digital high
life you are all living the digital high
life but we need to talk about this so I
hate presenting problems without
recommendations so I'm just going to
throw a few out here but I think it
would be worth having a great discussion
if you guys ran out of things to talk
about out there over the club met a
first of all wherever possible in your
life right now go get those pieces of
paper when I had the discussion with my
attorney I went out you know after this
and i got i gave a durable power of
attorney to my husband and i said i
wanted it with immediate effect and my
attorney setting sure you want to do
that and I said well if I'm going to
trust
then when I'm incapacitated I'm going to
trust him now so I recommend you do that
because it was much easier once I got
this for my father to say do you want me
to just take care of this one thing for
you today and he'd say yes and I would
go do that it wasn't a binary thing it
wasn't a you can't do this anymore I'm
going to do this for you you know
because that's what they will resist do
you want me to just help you out sure
that's great that's the conversation you
can be having and then just you know put
it this way if you needed me to pay the
bills for you how would I go about doing
that should we just set this up now just
in case that this is a much better
conversation than saying here's a legal
document saying you're incapacitated you
really don't want to do that so do this
in your own life but what we really need
are standardization in online systems
around these sorts of rolls these
dynamic rolls temporary rolls personal
proxies and delegates both for minors
and for people in their majority who are
temporarily incapacitated who are
periodically incapacitated or who are
suddenly and irrevocably incapacitated
we need better integration of digital
and legal and physical world
authentication we need ones that take
better that acknowledge better the very
complex issues around people who are
disabled people who are economically
disadvantaged and have no transport
especially in the united states that
have no transport to go to these offices
or can't afford to take time off work to
get these sort of legal documents
executed they are they also cost money
in a lot of cases and we really need
identity authorities that operate in the
rest of the normal world that can help
vouch for these sorts of roles the same
sort of thing that you would have inside
of an enterprise except it has to be
something says yeah I know I know Bob I
know where he lives I know that he has
these roles in the community
and I know that this is his son his son
you know has the authority to do these
things on behalf of his father the son
also has two minor children and has the
right to do these things online on their
account but it needs to be better
coordinated and then in general we need
better adaptation for all sorts of
disabilities not just visual impairment
for example but cognitive disabilities
and we really need to find a way to
solve this in the digital world because
otherwise your disenfranchising people
for no reason other than you know they
have a high fever or you know they've
been used to running their lives but now
suddenly they can't and then ultimately
if I had all the free time in the world
I would be setting up some sort of
service that would help mediate these
things help choose the right digital and
online solutions for people at different
stages of life different stages of
technical knowledge ability awareness
you know circumstances relationships and
so on because somebody needs to help you
know sort this out at assisted living
centers now sometimes they will have a
consultant who comes in and shows these
older folks how to use a computer which
is very nice but again it doesn't deal
with a lot of the the complicated
logistical things in their life
especially financial and legal
transactions whenever I would have to
check my parents into a rehab center for
example if they had a fall there would
be a stack of papers this high to admit
them and I would end up signing them all
because again whichever parent it was
was in no shape to sit there in a chair
and sign so I would you know sign these
things over and over and over and over
again it was the same if they had a fall
every month you know or every three
months it would be going through that
again at the hospital in the emergency
room for the insurance you know all
these sorts of things being able to
stream
Linus and put this you know in a way
online that can be much more easily
executed over and over and over and over
again is something that we desperately
need if I had all the time in the world
I would set that up maybe somebody else
would be inspired to do that but I can
tell you that having this sort of
digital concierge would be a really
great thing so that's my speech and I'd
like to know if anybody has any comments
that they'd like to share with me