we have Lois from pentester lab so I'm
pretty sure he doesn't really need an
introduction I'm about 95% sure everyone
knows who he is but for those who don't
Louie is a security engineer based in
Melbourne Australia
he's the founder of pentester lab a
learning platform for web penetration
testing so Louie it is all yours mate
and ute can people hear me I guess yeah
you don't get any yes we can hear you
okay perfect so I was not sure about the
background I've put something pretty
simple for now unless you like this one
guys got my favorite one so far and this
one I'm gonna try to check the question
as well I was a convict on I would say
five question you can interrupt me at
any time
yeah so let's get started share my
screen and can you see my slides now
like
yes we can my liking it I can hear
Andrea laughing in the background at
your back your previous background as
well yeah so M so my name is Louie and I
work for doobies Fink open test lab and
I really enjoy bugs and I'm kind of CV
Conway sir and so that's my talk code
that gets you pone you can see the
regular expression in the title because
we're going to cover a bit of that as
well if I get factoring moving yep
so my job is basically to find collect
and study bugs and put them together to
help people learn how to find fix and
exploit bugs on their own so I spend a
lot of my time picking bugs basically
saying like oh this is interesting
this is pretty boring this is the same
kind of bugs of this one and trying to
find things that are really interesting
and that will really help people get
better at finding bugs and I exploiting
bugs and so we're gonna jump right in
there so I'm gonna show you some example
of Venerable source code and then you
can spot the bug so if you find the bug
you can put it in config cone slack but
I'm gonna go through the code because
it's pretty hard to like do it straight
like that so first here we have a little
function in golang
but is used to approach five so we can
see on the second line what we're
getting a five from the HTTP request if
there is no file we generate an error
and we return a very is a file we first
create a defer to close the file in the
future when we don't need it anymore and
then what we do is we're gonna create a
temporary file on the file system in
/tmp
and use the file name as the pattern
used for the file creation for naming
the file then if there is no error we
iver is an error we return and print
their otherwise we'll read the file we
got from the request and again we manage
our so that's what is annoying with
golang is that you spend your time
reading like error
management then we write the five we got
from the request and put that on the
file system in own temporary file when
we closed the temporary file and if
everything goes well we write
successfully uploaded the file not first
if you're not for CTO see us playing at
home he's pretty good at cut review is
touching it you should check out this
training is pretty good as well so the
prime here is a run-time file so ten
five takes two arguments first the
directory where the file will be created
so most of the time you're going to use
TMP or something like that so that's
where you want the file to be located
when you create it and the second one is
a pattern that pattern is used to say we
want to fight to look something like
that
we want the file to look something like
louie dot some random number dot take
stay for example all dot jpg or
something about and that looks pretty
safe to use like that but the problem is
that what happens if you start using ten
file and in the pattern you put a
directory traversal and usually that
shouldn't that five should still be
created in slash temp right and
unfortunately what the golang does is
that it's going to traverse directory
even if the pattern even if the file
should be created in /tmp and because
it's just going to concatenate /tmp
we've the result of the pattern so if
you have a directory traversal in the
pattern you're going to have a directory
traversal and so 5 will be created
something somewhere else which can be
pretty surprising and can probably lead
to cut exact if you can for example
upload GSP or PHP shell or something
like that and so that's something I
reported to the coaling team and it took
here why because I had to argue with
them but it's probably not super common
but it's gonna be something where people
are going to shoot themselves in the
foot and so I reported it I fall to like
two algobit with
purrs and to get people to help me out
with the developers but at the end it
got fixed recently and I think it should
be in the recent version of Galang if
you do that it shouldn't matter you will
still be in /type
yes really good comment in the chat you
to check it out so what happened in -
the same exact thing so in Python you
provides a directory and you provide a
prefix and if this prefix as a directory
traversal in it you're going to traverse
directory and go here you even if you
want to create those five in slash times
you're going to end up in Slough root
and you have the time file in / root so
which is kind of annoying and unexpected
Ruby does it better so if you provide a
temp file if you use time file dot new
and you provide a pattern at the first
argument and then you say I want this
fine in slash time Ruby will do the
right thing and we remove this - and cry
to your file in slash temp so that's
kind of something you need to be aware
when you're doing Roderick code review
because it's not really obvious like
you're creating a file in temp which
time file it looks like something that
shouldn't be dangerous and it actually
can be now let's move to something else
so here we have a little application in
Python and we're using multiple
libraries and what we do is mostly we're
using a URL to fetch a webpage and since
we probably ate like a pen test or bug
bounty before we don't want to get on so
we restrict the fetching to pen tester
like on using HTTP because we love
things to be secure then once we so if
the URL starts with printer.com we fetch
that URL and when we return - camera in
the page so what's something people
often do to download images or to create
like a proxy to bypass the same origin
policy so yeah so what looks pretty good
we're using starts with so it should be
sighs so prime that starts with is
really it's a really bad way to make
sure something is actually part of a
trusted list so for example if you start
with HTTP colon slash slash trusted you
can see that HTTP current such as
trusted dot Penta solid dot com starts
with trusted and something if you do add
in telecom the promise well is what you
don't do canonicalization before before
doing this starts with so if you have
another bug like a file upload on open
redirect or a header injection you can
use okay trust we starts with trusted
/gw KS and then dot slash and go to
another page on the website and that can
potentially create really bad behavior
and you can some time home people thanks
to that especially if we've the open
redirect because you can use that open
redirect to go to a third parties
website and therefore you'd completely
bypassing the usage of starts wait and
that's pretty common in going Python
Java every application and we're gonna
see some even more craziness if you look
at my background this one is pretty good
we're coming very soon ish so uh already
we're so this is in c-sharp
and he vista we're just not gonna make
sure but the URL starts with HTTP colon
slash slash and as you know like
sous-chef dotnet now works on linux and
windows and the behavior will be served
simon linux and windows for bad back so
you can think of okay we have a
server-side request forgery
we can access any web server but starts
with HTTP or we can even try to do a pot
scanner by just changing support as part
of the URL but bad bug is actually even
worst if the URL starts with HTTP colon
slash slash and when you do the start
and you go for example on linux to et
Cie passwd you're gonna get the content
of et Cie passwd and the craziness is
that the dotnet framework mimic the bad
behavior of windows for directory
traversal on windows if you have this
kind of path you don't care because even
if a sh t TPS : / - doesn't exist
it's tickler returns the value 1 because
windows Agha is gonna ignore it
Linux dotnet on Linux will do exactly
the same thing and return it
suppose WD even if HTTP colon slash
slash does not exist so we took the bad
thing from dotnet on Windows and poured
it to Linux
so yeah directory traversal in dotnet is
pretty cool and like here you using a
web client and you do like you don't
know the URL which is a string but yeah
you don't know the URL and you end up
with a file from the file system so
that's pretty crazy I love that bug
another one is again in golang yeah CTO
is adding back to his training so here
we have a simple URL that a simple HTTP
handler but we take a file name from the
URL it's going to open though it's gonna
clean the path because we want to make
sure that everything bad is remove some
of the path when it's going to open that
file and then if there is in there it's
going to defer the closing of the file
for later and when it's gonna if there
is an error it's going to return a for
for otherwise it's going to copy the
file handler from so fagged we just
opened to double user response via for
like the to file under would be
connected and it's going to copy
everything and so far will be echoed
back in the response few seconds for
this one so this one is as well pretty
surprising so let's look in the fat path
that clean soap after keen returns the
surest path name equivalent to the path
by purely lexical processing and that's
the golang documentation and go line
documentation is really good because you
can just run the code on the website so
that's what happened when you run it so
it's gonna do okay if you do have that
kins of a dot slash e you're gonna get a
slushie if you do a slash slash C you're
gonna get a slashy slashy slash dot
you're gonna get a slushie when we
arrived to the store but you think of
when you're doing directory traversal
when you one of the bad guy
imagine you to start the dot slash AC
it's gonna return slash a Sashi if you
do slash dot dot slash a slash B
is gonna return a /e so it's cleaning
pretty good right and as a developer you
see that when you're thinking that's
exactly what the security guy told me
about I need to remove the dot slash
part of clean is removing the dot slash
for me thanks golang you are an amazing
language turns out what the
documentation doesn't uncover is that if
the path doesn't start with a slash and
we have thought that such that such that
such /a b we are gonna get the same
exact result because he's trying to find
the shortest path and it's not gonna
remove also dot slash bad things because
it doesn't start with a slash it's not
canonical is irish it's not doing any
canonicalization because you can't do it
here and as a developer that's a really
really surprising behavior and a few
people got owned by that the thing pub
that he'll will clean up everything for
them but it doesn't now another one so
that's pretty common when you doing
you're dealing with rackets and hostname
so here we have an event listener so
basically when two HTML pages need to
speak together they're using events and
what the first thing you need to do when
you do events like that and but
everywhere in the mozilla documentation
is you need to validate the origin of
the event so here what we're doing we're
following the documentation and we
validating but the message comes from
10.com since we want to make sure that
we don't have these starts with issue we
putting like a dollar sign at the end of
the regular expression so all the events
will come from Pentos rob calm and when
we do something sensitive with the event
or though otherwise we don't do anything
the premiere reyga's and dot pen test
lab Khandala is that WWF intercom starts
we contain much whisper gaps but wwz
Penta solid calm still match it because
the dot ins that looks good in the
domain is actually a wild card for
regular expression so it's gonna match
any characters so invert works as well
for WC Penta solids e-comm
so here's the primary that as a
developer you need to remember that you
need to escape doubts in regular
expression because they are wildcard
we're not a separator between a hostname
and domain and a TLD they actually have
meaning in the regular expression
okay so let's move to the next one and
we're gonna go a bit harder so that's
maybe one sieve you won't find
so we have this little java application
we have a list of domain that we allow
so example.org gmail.com google.com and
we have a fetch content function and
when we retrieve when someone access
fetch function we're gonna verify that
the domain parameter is part of allowed
domains by using include so basically
we're gonna search in the list of domain
to see the one if the one provided is in
the list pretty simple nothing is right
so and that looks pretty good right the
prime is right here we have this request
queried domain dot to replicate and
that's going to bite us because we can
use a Douglas RI which is often using
Turkish and to you pack uppercase and we
get an actual I so gmail.com with a
Douglas I if we do to upper case will be
gmail.com so we have a bypass just by
registering the domain and that's
something that happened to github
recently where as part of a password
reset and that's a really good blog post
that got me started in looking at what
in more depth and as part of the
password reset functionality github was
matching like that and then using the
email provided instead of email that
matched and that was used to bust path
by path the password we set and that's
really really interesting and from the
same blog post you should read it and
someone linked it on the config con are
you slack channel you can see that all
the other characters badges but actually
behave weirdly when we go to a podcast
or when we go to lowercase
and that's something that a lot of
people get bitten by because no one
knows about that or very little PR
developer a very little number of
developers know about that yeah and the
crazy part is that you like oh my god we
see some we are really stuff we see this
is some weird javascript stuff and
that's what I thought at first and
that's actually not the case it's
actually part of the Unicode standard
and part of the implementation
implementation guideline
so what happens is that if you ever are
if you in normal which is like
everywhere everyone except Turkish you
go from I to uppercase I and you go from
dot less I so I don't know if you see my
mouse but here to the uppercase high
here
and that's what is happening here what
is this even more surprising is that if
you're local on your system or on your
server system are define in Turkish the
behavior would be different so a
lowercase I would become a uppercase I
with a dot I because I with a dot and a
lowercase dot less I will become an
uppercase highest here so you have all
these weird mapping but actually some
classic behavior and most languages that
don't follow this behavior do that
because they don't have implemented VAT
Unicode support well enough so that's
actually something that should work this
way so if you want to play capture the
flag I got two challenges right I'm
going to keep running for the next I
don't know 24 hours or something like
that so you can play online capture as a
flat a G one two three four five six
seven eight yeah I bought an amazing
domain and I'm pretty proud of it so
yeah so check this out you can scan the
QR code on the video and I will leave
them running and that's exactly was two
bugs so we talked about two things
regular expression and we talked about
Unicode what happened
if we mix the two thanks yeah pretty
good log domain so yeah what happened so
if we do a regular expression to try to
see if dot less I mat cheese i and in
Python 38.1 it doesn't match so okay now
let's add ignore case to the game and we
can see that Douglas I will match I if
we ignore the case so let's say you have
a rely expression to match your domain
all and you're using ignore case you're
going to get bitten by that so you
shouldn't use in no case when you're
doing that thanks Evo so same thing with
I same thing with the letter the Latin
long s that looks like a weird F and but
it's gonna match s if you have ignore
case and same thing for the Kelvin sign
watching is gonna match okay if you
using ignore case again yeah so let's
see other languages in Ruby the I dot s
I will not match I and with not much
upper case I ever despite the fact that
upper case the of dot si is still aya as
we saw before but the Kelvin sign will
merge K and so the zero means that it
matches the near match means that it
doesn't match and come in sign will
match the K as well as the lowercase K
so that's yeah
Calvin symbol sorry anyway and the same
thing for the Latin long s it's gonna
match the s so so I doesn't match but
the F or the s and the K do so that's
pretty weird behavior and but that's
something but we have as well in golang
so in golang zu modifier so ignore case
is put at the start with bracket
question mark I bracket but you can see
here so it's not gonna match the dot
less I and it's mark is gonna match K is
gonna match to come inside
as it's gonna serve Latin long as it's
gonna match s so yeah pretty weird yeah
in c-sharp
we got behavior different a different
behavior as well so the data side
doesn't notice I I doesn't match total
Assad doesn't match
I Calvin sign match is K but long Latin
long s matches doesn't match s so again
like it's very much language dependent
and as well version dependent it's going
to change between the version of the
same language depending on where support
for Unicode and regular expression what
is interesting in c-sharp is I think
because Microsoft had to deal with so
many issue of Unicode we have this all
this way to do ends with and do string
comparison with managing case and you
can see that they are invariant could
you ignore case ordinal ignore case was
probably the most expected behavior with
the Swiss where int matches i NC first
one being without the dot and depending
like you have always different way of
doing string matching and you probably
want to use the first one in violent
creature ignore case just to avoid this
kind of bugs now let's look at open JDK
and I did the same with Oracle one I did
some testing with just a record one and
it works in the same way so dot si is
equal to I I is equals dot as I if you
do a course in no case same for Calvin
sign in case and for K and Calvin sign
same for Latin long s and s and same for
s and Latino as they all match however
when you move to pattern matching I
doesn't notice I doesn't match I Latin
long s doesn't match s and Calvin sign
doesn't match okay so that's yeah very
very weird behavior compared to what the
Equality no case gives you
and why you bother by that
so let's say you have an application but
something with okay make sure that
domain match something with a I and
we're gonna use in no case or makes sure
the domain match something with s and
we're going to use ignore case with that
you can register domain like instead of
attacking if you are taking domain dot
all you can register domain dot all with
dot si and you can bypass this kind of
protection the same thing kind of work
for us you can VIN sign but the point is
that register it's considered like an
uppercase G so it's character so it's
really hard as far as I can tell to get
a domain which is a revert or even
impossible the same thing happen if you
do an email address or you gonna
validate the email address but since
some people we put characters as
uppercase into the domain or as part of
the email address you're gonna match an
ignore case and you're gonna run into
the same problem the same as well can be
the case with course cross-origin
resource sharing in that if you match
the host name using case insensitive you
can run into the same thing but it's
most likely that your browser will not
send the right value because it's going
to encode the domain as pretty cold so
you unless you have an equipment that
does the translation the decoding back
from pinnacle to like a Unicode string
it's unlikely but it works for calls but
still interesting to look at and that's
it so basically to conclude I know
that's really hard like I guess
computers are really hard and you have a
lot of details to look into and I think
this but really I'll add our like some
source code can look clean and maybe
dangerous even if it looks perfect like
the example we've got like and path dot
clean looks pretty nice and pretty safe
so example with Unicode looks pretty
good but you need to remember what any
modification of a string can
of impart don't make any assumption yeah
like yeah and that's it for me so thank
you for your time and if you have any
questions make sure you stay home and
stay safe and yeah yeah thanks if you
have any question I can say on a
frequent question or if the end were
wants to jump in yes so thank you very
much Louie I will be a hundred percent
honest I don't understand half of that
anymore because I don't do so for
engineering anymore it's just it's just
a black art to me but um I know there's
been a lot of chat about the guys trying
to guess what the bugs were and of
course we had certain people getting
them much quicker than others but yes
now that was awesome thank you very much
you