good morning when I started preparing
these I didn't realize it's gonna be at
8:30 a.m. so brace yourselves this is
gonna be tight okay quickly my name is
Hakeem I teach computer programming I
live in Finland
that's my vlog and Twitter this is the
company I work now at the moment it just
started not much there called expansive
calm the plan we want to talk about
quantum computing and how it applies to
cryptography but to do it we have to
build the base a bit so we're gonna
start with the computer and how to build
a computer and then move to cryptography
using regular modern computers and then
learn a bit about quantum mechanics so
that we are able to understand something
about quantum cryptography and the ways
quantum computers break modern
cryptography so computer made of bits
and all that could be 0 1 it's not a
physical thing it's just an idea I can
be a bit so I can say this is me 0 this
is me 1 and now I can encode something
as long as we all accept this language a
light bulb can be a bit a electricity
could be a bit like low voltage high
voltage that's how your processors you
actually use bits it could be physical
like in a laser Compact Disc you see
these nice colorful things they are
there because the surface of the disk is
not actually flat it's flat and has so
little bits and they don't directly
correspond correspond to zeros and ones
but they are technically like bits so
you can use something to encode
something into bits as long as you'll
accept the rules now when you have bits
and then you combine them into logic
gates any programmer knows logic
operators like and or again this is just
an idea and if you have again I can be a
and gate like give me two bits I'll give
the answer you can implement them or an
or gate you can implement them using
something physical you can probably
train a dog to be a logic operator
because it's not not much there to learn
here's an n-bit implemented with
Domino's this so this guy pushes two
things which means one one and the
answer is also one falling down means
one but if he pushed only one left one
or the right one the answer would be 0
because 0 + 1 is 0 the way logic gates
are implemented in modern computing is
with transistors those on the Left
they're built about coin-sized big from
about 50 years ago and then you see they
go smaller and smaller and that's
basically an electric switch and your
modern CPU has like billions of those
why well if you combine them in somewhat
complex ways like here you can make math
because if you combine gates like this
and you put some input bits you get the
sum of those bits and that's the full
adder that's how it works in action as
long as you keep adding stuff you can
get more and more complex math because
if you have addition you have
multiplication and if you have
multiplication then
you can have everything because
multiplication is the key to everything
and here's by the way a nice sci-fi book
I read recently highly recommended
there are multiple cool IDs in this book
one of the ideas is there's this
civilization they don't have computers
or electronics but they do have a notion
of computing so they use soldiers to
implement logic gates thousands and
thousands of soldiers and they have this
rule that flag down means zero flag up
means one and then they arrange soldiers
and they try to compute some hard
mathematical problems so if you have
bits and you have logic gates you have a
computer now this part is of course the
most difficult and I'm skipping it
because we only have so much time and
this is similar to this it's like you do
something and then magically you have
the answer but if you're interested in
those hard bits if how do you go from
beats to modern computers then I also
highly recommend those two books by the
same author one of them on the left goes
from light bulbs to modern computers and
the second one talks about the
scientific paper by Alan Turing that
started this whole thing alright so we
assume we know how computers work that's
how they basically work you are here we
are now ready to talk about cryptography
as you know cryptography is a way to
make information secret to hide
something so that only specific people
can read your messages so one of the
simplest and most obvious ways to
encrypt a message is to just shift it
within the alphabet we done it as kids
probably and Romans did it thousands of
years ago and if you just take some say
English text and shift it by some number
like three you get this and if you're
not from Hungary this is not Hungarian
although sorry I had to do it
so Romans use it about 2,000 years ago
and I guess it worked for them because
they looked like that and their enemies
looked like that so not much to hide
there but today that won't work it's so
easy to crack it you
can just guess you can look at and the
worst case scenario you just try all the
combinations and in English there are 25
different options so this is the idea
behind the simplest symmetric encryption
and up to about the 70s that's all we
had this is the top of the symmetric
encryption machines the Nazi used in the
World War two
it's much more complex than the simple
simple shift because for single letter
they used different combinations every
time and they changed every day and then
every month but it's still something
that first year computer science student
can crack in about 50 lines of code
today that's symmetric encryption where
you use the same key to encrypt and
decrypt and now your problem lays in
this communication of the key because as
long as someone has the key they can
encrypt your message so this is not
perfect this is why from about 70s we
have a much better idea of asymmetric
encryption and the idea there is let's
say this on the left is me on the right
is that's my sister as you can see we
are related I don't have a key she has
both the key and the lock and the lock
is public she gives it to everybody when
I want to send her a private message I
take her lock and I include my message
with her lock and give it to her
only she can unlock it because only she
has the key she never shares the key
that's the basic idea so it could be
done with locks but we only have
computers that can only do math nothing
else so how do we do it with math well
we need something that is mathematically
easy to kind of lock one way but hard to
unlock if you don't have the key and one
of the things that works in math like
that and it's called a one-way function
in math he is multiplying large prime
numbers if you just pick two prime
numbers you multiply them it's easy you
can do it on your computer even if the
numbers are really really big but if you
have that number n it's really hard to
find what prime numbers were used to
produce
so how to apply this idea to encrypt
messages oversimplification again but
this is how the RSA works basically you
pick two prime numbers let's peek really
small ones two and seven you multiply
them you then find a special value
called 5n there's a whole bunch of
number theory in it we won't cover it
but trust the system this is the formula
you use and you get six and now the fun
part you pick a number E which is your
encryption key and again you have some
constraints you don't see it but there's
math not number theory and math there
but you have few choices when you have
large prime numbers so I pick five
within those constraints and then I also
pick D which will be my decryption key
the secret key again I have some rules
to pick it but I have some choices and I
choose 11 now we have the kit we have
the public keys and we have the private
key so my sister generated all that I
want to send her private message so I
take her public stuff the 5 and 14 and
now let's say I want to send her a
simple message c letter c i convert it
to a number anywhere i want maybe UTF
like a unicode or whatever i convert it
to number 3 because c is the third
letter of the alphabet
and then i take 3 raise it to the power
of that e5 and see the result mod 14 and
mod 14 is the remainder after integer
division so we have 243 we divided both
by 14 we get the remainder 3 oh sorry 5
5 is the secret message this is the
thing that I'm gonna send her and she
can see now she has the private key and
she has the encrypted message she does
the same thing but with the private key
so she raises it to 11 she does mod 14
she gets 3 and that's how it works
basically there are more layers to this
but that's the idea behind much of
modern cryptography so you see the
problem here is it is hard to guess
those numbers and it is hard to find
with large enough prime numbers it will
take billions of billions of years on a
regular computer to just find those
prime factors because the basically the
only way you have is to try all of them
alright we have the idea behind
computers and we have some ideas about
cryptography now to talk about quantum
computers and quantum cryptography we
need to have just a bit into quantum
mechanics so remember in chemistry
classes in in high school we talked
about those covalent bonds like you have
a ch2 which is two hydrogen nucleus
connected like sharing an electron and I
could never understand like sharing an
electron is it like going around two
nucleus at the same time is it like
running around because I have this idea
and many of us do this is the atom right
it has the Nicholas and it has electrons
like planets running around them and
that picture is nice it's easy to
understand but it's wrong because
electrons actually are not those balls
that could be anywhere the idea of
asking where is this electron at the
moment does not make sense because if
you don't ask that question if you don't
look at the atom it's not anywhere it's
not in any particular place so it's not
like that electron is running around the
nucleus it's a probability around that
nucleus and it has some probability of
being here and being here so it's a
cloud of somethingness and when they say
two hydrogen nucleus nuclei sharing an
electron that means the electron is at
both places at the same time it's with
that new clay nucleus and with that at
the same time it doesn't make sense it
shouldn't because quantum physics is
like that it's counterintuitive we hate
it because it it doesn't fit the way we
think about the world naturally so for
the longest time scientists scientists
were asking a question what is light you
know this probably from from physics in
high school is it a wave is it apart
chuckle and the problem with that
question is if you are into waves you
can produce experiments that will prove
it's a wave if you are into particles
you can produce experiments to prove
it's a particle so it's hard to guess
it's hard to find out and one of the
ways to think about it is well if it's a
wave then it should behave like a wave
so if you have like a wave of water and
you put two slits in front of the waves
then on the other side you should see
this interference pattern like here's
the screenshot from a video on YouTube
where a guy pushes two balls onto the
flat pond of water and produces two
sources of waves and those waves collide
into one another and they produce these
flat pieces where waves like high point
of wave with a low point and they cancel
each other and at some points they
amplify each other this way you have the
interference pattern but if particles
are shot through the same double slits
then you should see just two lines right
they go through left one or through the
right one like it I'll switch it to this
one okay so the problem with this is if
you look at particles like photons or
electrons like that then you do an
experiment and you should you should
electrons or photons through double
slits you still get an interference
pattern as if it's a wave and okay well
that proves it it's a wave then but they
think okay maybe it's not a wave but
there's still like little balls of
things that collide with each other and
produce this interference pattern so
let's shoot them one by one just one at
a time and if you do it you still get
the interference pattern like one thing
it goes through something like the left
or the right slit and then it lands on
that side as if it was part of a wave it
doesn't make sense and the only good
explanation to that is it's doing
it's going through both slits at the
same time you should one-electron it
goes through both things at the same
time with some probability and then
collides with each other on the other
side and produces the interference
pattern but if you put detectors on the
slit and you want to see is it going
through the left one or is it going
through the right one you'll see the
answer like this one went through the
left one but you won't see the
interference pattern anymore on the
other side you'll see two lines as if
doors
those were particles so the fact of
observing the answer collapses the
answer to one thing and it's not like
our minds controlling the universe by
observing it it's because at this point
observing means interacting you cannot
observe a photon without touching it
like kicking it and by doing it you
collapse it to one possible scenario
which is left or right so things on this
scale like photons electrons even small
atoms behave like that and they could be
in for example two states at the same
time they could be at two states at
separate times so with things like
photons on the right side there is a
property called spin which is a bit
harder to get at this point but we can
just think of it as a photon looking up
or looking down so it could be in one of
those states and you can apply some
energy and move it from one state to
another state which means you can use
them to create bits just like you use
light bulbs or electricity and at this
point this is no better than any regular
computer you still have bits you'll have
two states distinct this discrete states
but those quantum objects as I said they
can also be in both states at the same
time with some probability so we could
have an electron that looks right sorry
left so it's kind of somewhere between 0
& 1 with 50% probability and that's what
they call a qubit it could also be like
this way and technically you can have
many many more possible
and technically infinite number of
different states between zero and one so
if you have computers with bits and
logic gates then quantum computers are
quantum bits with quantum gates the
gates that operate on those qubits and
again this is the long part which is the
most difficult now if you google about
quantum computing and look at popular
articles or lectures or stuff like that
there are a few levels of the way they
describe it and one of the first levels
is some journalists might say well
quantum computers have more than once
and zeros our regular boring computers
only have 2 bits 0 & 1 and these
powerful quantum computers have more
than 0 & 1
that makes them really really fast which
is again not really true we could have
more bits than 0 and one is there's not
like a physical limitation to that and
there are actual computers with trinary
systems where they have 0 1 & 3 or 0 1 &
2 & it's not that that gives us power 2
bits is enough for all the power we need
another level they might describe it is
well the bits can be 0 & 1 at the same
time this means this computer is
infinitely parallel like this quantum
computer does something that a classical
computer does but it does it in infinite
many states at the same time so it's
like a super parallel computer which is
technically true but effectively isn't
because if you look at this and you
think a quantum computer is just a bunch
of classical computers working at the
same time it sounds really good
but the problem is they do but at some
point you want to get the answer out of
those you only get one one at random so
it's not really it's it's not helpful to
think about quantum computers as
computers classical computers that work
in parallel it's like a superposition of
multiple classical computers just like
a photon on an electron could be in
superposition of different states so if
you are looking for factors of n like
those prime numbers then your machine is
in different states of looking at
different numbers at the same time but
then you want to see the answer and it
gives you the answer like it says this
number is not a factor well that's not
helpful I could have done that with a
classical computer at random just pick
random numbers and see if there are
factors or not so it's kind of similar
to this to a gaming die when it's in the
air it's in like superposition of
different states but it's not helpful
because you want to see the answer and
you put it on the table and you only
have one answer it collapses to that one
answer so you keep going and you say
okay this is also not a factor and if
you likee then at some point you get
okay this is a factor again you could
have done it with a classical computer
at the same speed so this particular
property of quantum computers that's not
enough to solve that particular problem
of finding prime factors but they do
find trying factors by changing the
problem by taking advantage of these
weird quantum properties because if you
switch from the idea of finding prime
factors to a problem of finding a period
of a function which is again provable by
means of number theory that you can kind
of rearrange the problem into finding a
period of some function and then at some
point get the prime factors then your
answers are still random but then less
random than that they are less random
than a perfect die they are more likely
to land on a particular value which is
the correct answer so you might repeat
the same thing multiple times and then
you see the answer is X is more likely
to be there it's statistically more
likely and it's like gaming die which is
crooked like it it's not fair maybe it's
heavier on one point if you do if you
throw it multiple times it's more likely
to land on one side
and this is the idea behind many
algorithms in quantum computer quantum
computing this particular one is called
Shor's algorithm and the idea with other
algorithms as well is that you make the
problem so that you play with it so that
it's more likely to not give you a
completely random answer but more likely
to give you a correct answer and with
with repetition with enough tries you
just look at the statistics and this top
answer is probably the correct one this
lower one is probably the wrong one so
this is how roughly you get about
solving problems in cryptography with a
quantum computer now the idea there is
you have a problem designed for a
classical computer and the problem of
finding friend factors is really really
hard on a classical computer it could be
somewhat easy on a quantum computer
we're not there yet
well the problem with quantum computers
is you need something to have those bits
you need those atoms or electrons or
photons and it's really hard to control
them because if you put them in some
states then basically any fart can
change them anything like a smallest
smallest interaction with a particle
flat or temperature can change them so
it's really hard to make this computer a
stable computer this is why those fancy
quantum computers are so big most of
that space is it's basically a fridge
that you want your quantum computer to
be at about absolute zero so that no
jiggling no temperature affects it but
at some point we will get there probably
the Shor's algorithm was implemented
before was like written before quantum
computers existed and then it was
implemented with one of the first
quantum computers and it produces the
answer that 7 is a factor of 21 which
which is good we're getting there but we
need now to scale it to like billions
and billions
but this could be a race with no end
like we could create new algorithms that
are harder and harder to solve and then
maybe come up with more quantum
algorithms to actually solve them so
what can we do to guarantee that we can
create some cryptography that is
unbreakable by even a quantum computer
and this is the area of quantum
cryptography actually using these weird
quantum properties to create new
algorithms based on quantum properties
to encode messages and we're gonna jump
right into it again this is an
algorithms algorithm called BB 24 and we
are back to the end of symmetric keys so
the idea is we want to share the same
key and use it for encryption and
decryption but now we're going to use it
quantum way so those balls again are
let's say photons and it can look up it
can look down it can be in one of those
positions and then left and right and
you have detectors to detect what
position is it in if you use the correct
detector like if you have up or down
photon and you use the vertical detector
you get the correct answer you get 0 up
1 down but you also have a horizontal
detector and if you use the horizontal
delayed detector on the vertical photon
you get a random answer 0 or 1 so you
basically have like the correct
detectors for a photon and the incorrect
detector for photo so my sister
generates a series of random bits should
be big enough but in this example it's
is small just at random
she then picks random detectors for each
bit again completely random and based on
those she produces qubits she produces
photons of the correct orientation so
that if I were to know the detectors if
he gave me the photons I could produce
the same bits
but she doesn't tell me the
configuration of the detectors she only
gives me the qubits so I get those
photons in some configuration and that's
it this is our first point of
communication and this communication is
done on a quantum Channel on a channel
that is capable of sending qubits in
this example we are using photons so we
could use something like a fiber-optic
cable that is capable of basically
moving a photon from one point to
another without changing its orientation
its state so this is still communication
and this is still like some cable lying
around someone could listen to it right
so let's say some evil person listens to
the to the communication that's my go-to
evil person all the presentations I use
the problem there is it's a quantum
communication with quantum bits and if
Hitler listens and tries to see what
qubits are there he needs to use
detectors but he doesn't know what
detector to use if he uses the wrong
detector for a qubit it will flip to
either 0 or 1 at random by doing it he
might change the qubit so when I
received the message after listening
after Hitler listens to it I might get a
different message and with the long big
long enough messages I got I am
guaranteed to get the incorrect message
and you'll see how this works in our
favor so let's say I get the message I
then also pick detectors at random
because I don't know the correct
configuration of detectors so I just
pick them at random and I produce some
bits by applying them to the photons if
you think about it you can see that
statistically I will get 75% right
because 50% of the detectors I will
choose correctly and out of those 50
incorrect choosers
I will get 50% at random correctly so
I'll get 75% of bits correctly then I
just call my sister on a regular
unsecured line like a phone and we just
compare detectors we don't talk about
bits we don't talk about
photons I say for the first position I
chose that detector and she says me too
so I see okay then my beat should be
correct on the second I chose this
detector and she says no I chose that
detector and I say okay this bit is
incorrect then I chose the wrong
detector so I just discard the wrong
bits comparing them and again at this
point Hitler might be listening to
because it's now just a regular phone
line so he listens and he says okay he
now knows the configuration of detectors
that we used but he doesn't have the
photons in the same state because if he
had then I would have gotten the wrong
message so after doing this we just
discard the wrong bits and now we have
the share key and it's all about
statistics because with message small
enough like this Hitler could be lucky
but we need to produce big messages and
then we are guaranteed statistically to
be safe and there are also ways to
detect if the message was listened to
because we can also detect changes in
the state of the qubits this was really
fast I'm not sure if this is enough it's
a really quick overview there are
resources that you can get into to learn
about this is fascinating and this was
the theory for a few years and then they
actually implement it and all over the
world in multiple places they could
create a secure Channel by doing this
quantum encryption and actually if you
drive from here for about two and a half
hours to the east they did one of the
first demos in Vienna where they created
a secure channel of multiple links and
it works it's amazing so even though
quantum physics is this weird
unpredictable randomness which doesn't
make sense to us because we want things
to be not random I want things to make
perfect sense we want to predict
outcomes
it turns out we can use this in our
advantage so this fundamental property
of the universe of not being sure about
itself can be used for example in secure
communication so if you want to learn
more about this there are a few
resources that I recommend there is an
interactive essay and there's this blog
by quantum scientists and he also wrote
a book called quantum computing since
Democritus and there are a few channels
on YouTube I particularly recommend this
frame of essence channel which describes
both quantum computers qubits and
quantum cryptography using this
algorithm that I described and some
other algorithms those links will be on
my website at this address feel free to
ask me questions or anything I'm not a
specialist in this area at all I'm just
really curious about it I think it's
quite amazing and thank you
[Applause]
[Music]