alright so today I'm gonna talk about
return oriented exploitation on arm so
first of all I'm mine so my name is
Tommy Turkish I'm a 15 year old iOS
flashback USD before and I'm interested
in arm bar security and server
exploitation for about two to half is
now also a continues to work in some
private older Gerak's because my focus
and kinda an iOS and is jailbreaking
process but the main focuses of this
talk is to cover the basics of Army
seven an army research and also I'll
show you a couple of differences between
Army's abandoned army eight then cover
defendants of robbed exploit techniques
and in the end I'll show a demo exploit
so let's start with the Army seven so
army 7i k IA r32 army seven has a fixed
size of 32 bits and there's a 16 bit
mode available known as some mode and on
number 7 we have a 15 general-purpose
registers and these are labels from are
0-2 or 15 and from R 0 to R 12 ok Ramar
0 to R 12 these are the general ones and
from our 13 2 or 15 those are the
special types of registers so R 13 is
the stack pointer which is always points
to the top of stack or 14 is the link
register which is always holds
everything address from for example been
a function call is made and I offered
our 15 is the perma carrier which is
always holds the next instruction to be
executed now I'm rate on the other hand
is armed 64 or AR 64 we have a lot more
registers so like 30 general registers
and these are labeled from X 0 to X 1 9
and on 8 supports only 7 fullbacks
backwards compatibility but when this
mode is enabled the upper 30 bits or
note and the register names are actually
changes a slight bit so it's changes
from X to W and so yeah we have from X 0
to X 2 now in the general ones and we
have the same special registers like an
army 7 so X 30 is a link register the
stack point is its own register so also
repair this ax 31
the program counter here is not directly
modifiable means for example if you're
writing you know in our in arm assembly
or number seven you can just use our 15
just got a as a program Cara but none
are mate
so army eight supports expression levels
as well so from our r2 r3 and this is
kind of a physical separation of levels
even the kind of like rings but that's
actually be a might up now there's a
couple of differences so you can see
first of all the register name so like I
receiver and X 0 then instruction thanks
I like move the W and Army 7 and the
written instruction so like on Army 7 we
branch to link register and an army 8 we
just write which is basically the same
thing just with a different name so yeah
here's a difference is when adding items
to the stack so an army 7 we have a per
instruction which adds many saw
specified registers to the top of the
stack and on our mate it's actually I'm
subtract from this sack minor so it's
actually manually courage to stack
because and here is actually the stack
is first up exact opposite way waiting
so it's actually grows downwards and
then we have another instruction so it's
actually stores a pair of register at a
specified location now absence force so
ever since for return-oriented
programming and this is a modern ask boy
technique the old-fashioned way was to
actually use a child kid do you execute
your malicious code but not it's
actually you would change gadgets do you
actually I executed or malicious code so
here's what we artists are so Oh Rob
gauges are found within the tech segment
so the code segment and these
Trowbridge's has students with our
return instructions or right instruction
we obviously that's how you can can
chain them together and even though how
this gadget could change the gary if
their program how is you so here's a
quick diagram of gadgets were so you see
where we have this a return address
that's where we override the perm
carasau and repeat our first get it
address there which I was getting
printers first get it then once it's
executed it's gonna jump back to the
back to the stack and it's going on like
with the kitchen to dress and so on most
of all the old box / cooler abilities
are different and sometimes you only
have one gadget worth of execution for
example when you doing with an on-site
based function and there's a solution
for that and it's called a step pivoting
and the stuffing is type opening he
create a fake stack and to be able to do
that you need to control the stack
pointer and to be able to control the
sacrum here you need a special type of
gadget called people get it seriously an
example of people get this side it's
very simple so I just actually actually
removes the value of x1
Digitek minor so it's just basically
over right here and the last instruction
just like X 30 and return so here's how
kind of I'm stuck pivoting a stack
pointer works so we have the memory and
we can see that stack pointer now points
to zero are see it means it's gonna
execute from there so like 0 x4 even if
you get an instruction to move down than
our pop we can see is now the second I'm
going to print points to 10 and 0 x4 one
does not doesn't need to be cleared
because it just doesn't count as a stack
anymore now if you actually can control
this set corner by our people get it you
can actually move there and we can
control the whole stack so you can just
basically execute our rope chain so
here's a stack based attack style the
very basics on our stack buffer
overflows and these types was targets
the sack and the main goal is to
override function pointer if it's a
thicker control data all right so this
occurs when program is run out of space
and you essentially start of writing the
function bars
the aim is to control the program camera
so here's some actually diagram of
flavor so you see at the first picture
is nothing delicate in a stack the
second one you can see a few years okay
and a third picture you can see an
outflow and we can control this because
we actually of wrote
the Purim Caribee days our don't think
this will work and when his sons because
most winners some have protection
against these over plays and Marisa's
have a slower and definitely ruled as
well so yeah I'm boys a large so well is
a lessons for address space layout
randomization
I just basically renamed is I or
addressing run time so I can see the
first time it was a 0 X 16 at the 0 at 7
9 0 and the second one was 16 half the e
7 7 9 0 so the two addresses are kind of
different so what is a lot of 4 so it's
a lot for making the prim can control
useless because even if you can control
the program Cara you just can't jump to
any bird because you just don't know
where anything is so it's also for
preventing shellcode from being
successful because it's just you don't
know where anything is Chris there are a
few ways to defeat al salar so I wrote
down two so the first one is a brute
first thing which is not very practical
because if you take a lot of time and
the second one is an info week we shall
talk about a little bit so the web basic
info week one is a format string
vulnerability and this is due to using
printf in a wrong way so you can see the
ethic can enter basically anything even
percentage peace to leave the data from
the cycle so if we actually try to
compile that program the compiler will
show some warnings so without the form a
string is not a string literal potential
integer and underlines the format string
which is in the wrong way so you should
actually use a form a cease-fire and
then put the for machine so not this
thing this app is our binary we see what
we entered so we entered high and here's
what the program printed out for us so
it's basically simply high
now I'm also a form and specify absorb
is a percentage so what happens if you
actually enter percentage high so here's
what we entered and here's what the
program print out for us some real a bit
because it's treated the percentage as a
for misfire so a percentage P purpose to
print upon your relief and if you
actually enter
person in trees we can see the premium
printing out for us some stick burners
so yeah and usually one pointer from the
stack is enough to defeat the whole ALR
but finding the function in this is this
slumber and compared to League dress
what we actually just and then compared
to this tactic address in this is lumber
and the difference will be a slower side
now anytime you want to jump to an
interest from now what you want to do is
usually get the interest where you want
to jump to and at day slow slide to it
so yeah um here's some heat based
techniques so on the heap you have
basically dynamic allocation and you can
allocate by Mulliken specify the size
and you can delegate by free and specify
the pointer so the first technique is
actually heaps way and he doesn't
actually exploit any security issues so
it's like can't really be fixed by an
updated for program and he's praying
attempts to put a certain sequence apart
is at a pretty terminated location by
allocating a large memory blocks on the
heap and you want to kind of think of
history as you would spray up with paint
so here's a diagram how it works I mean
say before the spray basically nothing
allocated on the heap and off the spray
you can see all of knobs located and
then our shot code see when we went to
put consecutive knobs or no operations
buzzer track code use not touch the
program to move on to the next
instruction and this will happen until
we actually reach our jacquard and it
will essentially execute it who executed
series I'm something show you so here
Frankie you actually carefully place
objects in the memory and repeating our
allocations and we will have on
consecutive memory blocks and after that
the allocation
Kempo calls so here's our generic hip
area so you can see the orange is in use
and the gray is a hole so we see we
actually don't know how the hip look
like so it's just like some of them are
in use and some of them are actually our
holes
and now let's do the first up so
allocation is repeated often enough so
ovals will be close so let's just do
that and I'll kidding a bit more and we
will have consecutive memory blocks so
now we actually kind of put our data to
it so we kind of know how the heap looks
like now and now they are kidding can
poke holes so like we put the holes and
essentially next location will be into
our hole and so by this a buffer
overflow can be controlled because if we
actually control the data or between
roof right after these the data before
the new allocation we can essentially
control this buffer or Floyd so ease of
free is a free occurs when a program can
use a pointer after it has been freed
and we often call this dangling pointers
and this could lead to your code
execution
I think this source code from iOS 9 pin
0 is a kernel a current extension and
what you want to care about is the if
the device is not know then what will
does is caused wise terminate and this
course OSE release function and pass an
argument as a device yeah so the OSU
Feliz is the unsafe function is if you
actually check out how Apple actually
find it we can see the actual business
at ends to know so I thought you user
Feliz know oh yeah they actually cook
with patch this by setting device and
also a bit of shame so yeah now here's
the demo so the target name is bi sabe
and vulnerability is our use of free and
the architecture which available on his
army 17 army 8 so every time we went to
exploit any upon your application we
kind of always have a checklist so first
we went to find the real very the
vulnerability killer her and then find
the addresses for a rope chain and in
the end we're going to call up the
exploit and tested sir is the first
stage so by running the program you can
see if you have actually six options
we're interested in five because the six
is just basically access the program so
option number one we can basically
allocate so you can see the program
tells us to enter some data to our kit
so maybe if we want to actually check
this function because I'm a buffer of
will make you Decker now I have access
to the source code because I wrote this
program but you could get this by
decoding from Ida or hopper so you see
we have by often number one we actually
have a function called allocate object
by user and it wasn't our argument as
input for our look so I now check this
function you can see at the scanf it's
actually kind of safe because I put like
a percentage 31 s which means this will
only scan up the pilgrim bytes and we
need plus 1 for the new termination and
the buffer is 32 bytes ID is perfectly
now I again use the safer function the
storing copy not the store copy but we
actually have a objects idea so you
actually want to check out that Samina
see it's actually defined by struct
object and this object and here's a
stroke how it looks like so this is
basically a struct and what you want to
know down is that we have to function
pointer sitting there all right so now
choosing option number two you can see
it's actually opens at fall
option number two we can see that the
program is actually waiting for an input
from the user
now let's actually enter a party for a
file to basically test this function and
we can see that printout the data was
created with how it besides with this is
a test and if you actually check what
the file contains it's basically
contains the same thing but the program
print ad for us so let's check option
number two so we can see it's actually
caused a great deal object-- so let's
check this function so first of all we
can see that it's basically allocator
and your bytes in the heap now this part
is just for scanning apart from the user
and opening the file and we have the F
read now have you done a turbo I've
freed
sync tax it says post in programming
arguments and cannot be interested in
and now the in the first one and the
first one is a pointer and it says
where's reference of an array or
structure where the data will be stored
off the reading so it means it will
store it to object data which is on
Hiep so let's continue our journey so
you see I'm by ocean number four you can
see that I should actually are kids
twice yeah and we get a message that
device was located so checking this
function again which is basically what
it does this all kids are two function
pointers on the heat dart so yes again
it's an instruction so now to actually
free a data we actually need to allocate
first um if we don't do this we might
end up in a double free so yeah in
theory this option number four is only
free data what we entered by option
number one but in reality this basically
what we can see here there is a check so
if the object is known oh then it's
cause a function called terminal type
check and is passes argument as object
and the terminal objects just simply
free a struct so now we actually know
very deep own ability is because it just
I use of free because the terminus
object frees the object but it doesn't
set know so checking the he player
before executing option number three
you'll see the there's nothing on the
heap and continuing forget the message
that device is all okay and let's see
that our two function pointers are there
so it's just basically allocated our two
function pointers if you actually call
number four or the term in it we can see
that a few addresses are masked so I
like three ones and three tens but most
importantly our two function pointers
aren't there so it means we can still
somehow reference to these dresses and
kind of overflow with a bit opening a
big file bigger than 32 bits right so
yeah we actually have this first part
because we know where the vulnerability
could occur now we want to find dresses
so this is the name of the binary so
this is the secret code now
hey yeah so sucrets starts at zero X
zero zero zero zero be 950 so yeah we
can just jump there and be done but you
can see if we actually jump to cigarette
we have a check here which check
wearable is if a check variables is your
equals to zero then it's gonna print out
for us that we are inside secret and
terminating 10 minutes so checking out
you see we have the check variable and
it's set to zero so yeah now checking
this variable in this is number if you
can see it's in the day section which is
good for us because it means we can
actually write it because if this would
be in the text segment you can write it
because the text segment is a executable
part not writable but this this is
segment segment is not executable pop
writable not actually a place directly
to be in the data section
anyways so this means that we actually
have to write a rough chain to modify
the check value and then jump to secret
with holding check the correct value and
you won't even know that it also means
that we actually have to execute more
than monkish so here's what we know so
far so first we need to find a set up
credit to set up our registers then we
need to find a correct correct it to
write the correct values to the correct
address then we want to trigger the UAF
mark and then execute our obtain here's
the first part so we want to find the
set up and the right get it
so I actually post these gadgets into
the banner because just to be easier to
find it and yeah so we can see it's
actually pops or 0 and R 1 R 2 and 4 in
Haribo
this means that we can control our 0 and
our ROM so we basically have this set up
gated now here's the bracket is what we
can see here is the storage of all we
find inside or 0 to a memory location
pointed by varam
now this is perfect for us because as I
said earlier we actually can control our
sewer and our pond bellies so we have
put of them are set up in so
now
remember we are actually working on the
Heath and we have won gauged worth of
execution so we need a solution and that
is stack pivoting so now we need to find
a pivot good
so I actually placed this aside in time
I bury on each side you can see it just
basically moves the value inside phones
inside are to the the stack minor so it
just basically alright so now we have
all the gadgets set if so we can see but
we can see that this is the secret code
again this is the code man if it will
check which equals to zero it's gonna
jump here and it will exit now you're
probably wondering why not June jump
just here and skip the check oh that
would be too easy and I wanted to demo
how food chain works so yeah now we have
churches now we need to occur up the
exploit so here's how the exploit looks
like so we are basically the search
device which will essentially fill up
the heap and this will overwrite our
first function pointer and yeah so if
you go we can beat the Phillip filled up
heap and this is where we override the
first function pointer and this is
actually pointing to our paper credit so
after executing the pivot gettest will
actually jump here and this will this
will the set up get it so this is the
side of greatest address and now we will
load 1 1 1 into R 0 and we will write
the address of check into R 1 so now
your some drunk characters and here's
the dress with the bracket it you can
hear some John characters and here's the
address of the secret so after executing
this exploit we can basically have full
control over the program so yeah now all
the checks are done and here's a test
yeah so my in the pantry which doesn't
really matter what we entered our
reallocate device and I just called up
to number five to just show you that is
just basically print out that first
trick was done in second request um yeah
so this is the correct order and specify
the path or exploit file now coding
option number five we can see that pond
and huge shower and is executed you name
that recommend yeah the expert is
complete and here's some useful wing so
if you want to learn more bomb on
exploitation so the top one is
especially good one and the last one is
my github prepared where you can
download this challenge from and you can
try out yourself so yeah this is my tree
handle if you want to follow any of my
work or if you have any questions later
you can DM me but if you guys have any
questions are feel free to ask and I
will try to answer but that's a good
thanks
[Applause]