good afternoon everyone
this is probably one of the largest
crowds I've seen at the end of Nanog
meeting and that is a compliment to the
program that there was something enough
going on that was valuable that people
wanted to stay so at kind of a round of
applause for the program committee on a
wonderful program
so first up election results the bylaw
amendments for 2019 were approved are we
I want to give special thanks to our
retiring board member will.shaw nock he
was serving as our treasurer will as a
stand-up guy
I really appreciated him on the board
he's kind of has this no-nonsense
approach to things and so greatly
appreciate him and he will definitely be
missed for new board members we have
Benson's slicer I hope I said that right
and Patrick Gilmore will be returning
and the board we've also selected new
officers Shawn Kennedy will connect
continuous chair Tina Morris is vice
chair treasurer will be David Siegel and
Susan forming will continue as our
secretary I'd like to give a few
thank-yous this meeting that you put the
see put on requires a lot of bodies and
forces to make it come out and we have a
plethora of people who pull this all
together so first of all I'd like to
thank our hackathon sponsors of Facebook
and to sudo and our connectivity
sponsors AT&T and especially our hosts
sponsor extreme networks and thanks to
our premium sponsors Netflix our diamond
sponsor AWS Equinox Kintex
Microsoft and Oracle as our platinum
sponsors and fastly qts Knapp Telstra
and Verisign as our gold sponsors and
then thank you to all of our mini event
sponsors
and then also thanks to our service
sponsors and then a very special thing
through our members our board of
directors our staff Valerie Deshawn Lee
Claudia and brandy all are helped me and
a daily basis to help deliver and make
this happen I have an amazing team and
I'm very very fortunate to have them in
addition to our contractors up with this
meeting together
there's charity experiences our audio
crew line speed events who put out the
network for us and Cascadian who handles
the webcast and also the ladies from
Hamilton group Christian Michele and
Sabrina all are just wonderful they're
an extension of our staff and to make
this all happen for you
meeting statistics little numbers so we
had a total of eleven hundred and
sixty-four attendees a members
unattended for 360 for student
registrations nine speakers 37 college
immersion 15 women in attendance 153
which is 13% which is a number that's
writing so I'm glad to see that and
countries in attendance 30 top
organizations I'll let you see them
there
and organized organizational
demographics
members our members are very very
important to us members are a collective
that help us pull this all together
their collective expertise help direct
our organization help Shanna shake Nanog
and help service its mission members
directly support our mission critical
critical incidents such as educational
outreach natox platform content
programming and empower our community
and help to inspire change I hope more
of you will consider being members
within our organization the expertise
that you deliver to us helped us achieve
great things we're looking for more
people to get involved membership is
about community it's about changing as
restructuring the organization is
helping to drive us forward just
recently I've submitted a draft
strategic plan to the board and the
board is critical in helping me pull
nanog together move it into a future as
we move toward change that the request
is required for any organization as it
moves forward so considering becoming a
member because consider becoming a part
of our organization helped guide us into
a future that benefits all for next
event 978 I'd like to announce our
keynote speakers there'll be a man V dot
well fellow engineering fellow and vice
president of Google and Picasa Kohli
executive vice president and chief
technology officer for Juniper Networks
the program committee has a subcommittee
which is called our keynote committee
and they've been focusing on getting
better quality keynote speakers for this
event and this one we had Paul vixie and
karabakh both a result of the efforts of
our Subcommittee on keynotes so I
appreciate what they're trying to do and
the program committee itself is trying
to get content in too early so we can
build the agenda earlier so we can help
provide a an event that is beneficial to
all and again having this many people
here on a Wednesday is evident that what
they're doing is starting to invoke
change in the organization so with that
I look forward to seeing you all in San
Francisco thank you
[Applause]
you