hello welcome to the Nanog tutorial
track like to welcome Damon Garros we'll
be talking about getting started with
modern time series databases in grow
fauna thanks hi everyone
very excited to be here and so yeah it's
just for seeing where the topic today is
ready to talk about you know how to get
started on on monitoring telemetry and
all of that and I've been working in you
know telemetry sync for last four or
five years when I was I started that
juniper started working on the first
implementation of photometry streaming
and then I got a chance to move to two
customers actually implement a lot of
that in the real world and approach
environments and now I'm with the
network to code and we're working with
our customers we're a consulting company
and working with our customers to help
them get started into a network
automation so what we're going to do
today show you the end is really going
to show you how to be all you know -
ball like this one and there's a lot of
informations and we're going to impact
but you know what we're seeing here is a
lot of information we have at the bottom
like visual representation of statuses
of interfaces and and bgp session like
actually look at the right of the screen
the different colors are representing
the different statuses of some BGP
sessions and on top we have some you
know traffic informations that have been
aggregated they're per device per roles
that are providing some very meaningful
signals you know that you can action and
alerts on on your topology so that's
that's awfully you know what we will
have at the end of the session but we
have to cover a lot of things so have to
cover you know how to build those
dashboards we're going to talk about why
times three databases are and you know
those technology should be part of the
toolbox of the network engineers I
understand a lot of you are not software
engineers they're Nazis that means
you're not you know going to deploy and
manage those databases but you're a user
of them and they offer a lot of very
interesting capabilities so it's very
important you know that network engineer
get involved in those discussions and
understand how they can use them we're
gonna you know talk about how to track
interfaces and BGP that
is in a time series database we'll have
a little very short introductions about
GMI which is a new telemetry streaming
interface the goal of this presentation
today is naturally to go deep on jean-mi
it's really about databases but that's
what we will use to extract the
information from the device I'll show
you how to install a time suite database
called permit use how to collect
information with a collector called
Telegraph and then we will also explore
graph anion how to hook that together
most of the sessions will be actually
live demo just going to go through some
slide at the beginning to make sure you
know we've never said we have an
understanding of where we're coming from
where we're going at and all that but
hopefully very quickly we'll get into
into the demo parts so where are we
coming from you know in terms of network
monitoring and and all of that in the
network industry so I will bet that most
of you today are in this you know
situations where we hope you have what
we'll call a legacy network monitoring
solutions you have all in one server
that is pulling information from the
device network devices using SNMP
collecting some traps and everything is
happening on this server the collections
the storage and the visualization what
you may not realize is that all of those
solutions whether they are you know open
and open NMS collect the observable
cacti mrtg
all of them are through using a single
component the same component at the core
which is called Rd tools you know that's
what is generating those various query
graph that we all have seen and honestly
this tool is has been amazing when he
got introduced in 1999 yo for some
capabilities that were you know
unprecedent back then but nowadays it's
it's very outdated tools like the issue
is it's a storage system but it's not a
database you actually store a lot of the
information and you also visualize them
and it doesn't really give us any
capabilities to explore the data in what
a new database and that's we're going to
talk about today can provide like there
is no query enjoying the data retention
is really bad it's very inefficient
nowadays and really there are some
amazing
system out there that can replace that
that will offer new capabilities the
issues as network engineer we are used
now to not have those capabilities so
we're not asking for them but if we
realize what we can do with those new
system then we can really do some
amazing things in terms of you know
retention and then sampling I don't know
if you realize but usually those are Rd
graphs they always come in batch of
three or four and you'll have like one
day one week and then a month and it's
because the storage engine is actually
very quickly losing data in down
sampling you know you have this you
store for a day with some precision and
then very quickly you actually sample
down and you only save you know less
information for a week and then for an
ounce which mean if you want to go back
to the data you already have lost a lot
of very critical information the new
data base is that we're going to explore
they are way more efficient and they
don't have all those limitations and you
can actually store in a more efficient
way you know a very high granularity
systems and data that's one part and
also part of the network industries
we've been talking a lot of that we got
a call kil SNMP we've gotta move to time
interest streaming everything is gonna
be open configure everything is gonna be
Gena my and personally I feel we've been
kind of lost in this discussions and we
probably is focusing on the wrong
problems like all of that is about how
do we actually extract the data from the
network there's very little discussions
about how to actually consume those data
like there's almost nothing out of the
box that can consume telemetry streaming
today like it's actually super hearts
you know people don't really talk about
that and at the end of the day it's not
really about should I push or should I
pull honestly it's a non debate like
outside of our industry people are not
so opinionated about that if you need to
build a Sdn controller yes you need push
you need to have sub seconds you know
information coming to you but in most of
the other use cases it's actually not as
the big of a requirement so we should
not spend so much time you know like
sing oh I should do streaming or I
should do SNMP personally I feel again
it is the wrong debate and there are
places for for both of them depending on
the use cases
so how are other doing outside of the
network industry and I usually like to
look at the you know several
infrastructures and see how you know in
terms of automation and monitoring they
are usually a couple of years if not
more ahead of us so on the server world
the way it works is you know usually
have an agent running on the server that
will be in charge of collecting the data
and then you will have a data store and
you'll have another system that will be
decoupled from that that will be used
you know to visualize or to do their
learning system and what we're seeing is
also we have multiple data stores based
on the type of data that we are actually
we don't collect and we want to
visualize where this one's because the
type of data are so specific that we
have very specialized data store today
and in terms of how do we get the data
from the server actually there's as many
push and pull solutions like there's
actually one of the most popular
monitoring solution that we can export
to the primitives is using push pull
sorry pull from the device it's just
it's doing that in a way that is way
more efficient than what we're used to
so we can you know pull a lot of
information from you know thousands or
tens of thousands of endpoints every ten
seconds or so without scalability issues
so again depend on the tools depend on
the use case that's not really the part
that we should focus on so what we would
to look at that we will really have
desegregated the stack we have a
collector we have the database and then
we have the visualization and shinin
each one is really focused on on its
system if we look at the data it's
important to understand what are the
type of data and what are the different
you know their specificity so on one
side we have the metrics or the time
series which the time series and metrics
are really applied to anything that is
about numbers counters you know CPU
value number of peers number of routes
anything that can be represented with
the numbers will very well fit into a
time series database and that's
something that you usually expect you
know coming constantly to you every
every few seconds every 30 seconds but
something that you always get and then
on the other
that we have deluxe you know in the
middle the logs are structured data more
or less structured actually mostly texts
you don't can really predict when they
will come so you know there's completely
different type of data that requires a
different type of you know databases and
an ensign actually to process that and
then the last one are the structured
data which really don't fit in any of
those more complex structures like the
ARP table my cable routing tables all
those tables that really don't have a
standardized way and and each of them
requires a different pipeline different
data base different storage and join the
one we're gonna focus on today are
really the metric and the time serie and
you know so the starks is only covering
that part there's a lot of open source
projects that are very active in this
space I just wanted to give you some of
them you know in terms of there's a lot
of collectors a lot of databases a lot
of system you can use for learning or
visualization I just wanted you know
please let's not be caught up in the
tools like honestly if you can if you
get started with any of them you cannot
go wrong like any of them will provide
amazing capabilities compared to where
we are right now and there's a lot of
the same concept and notions across all
of them they have their own you know
variations on the implementation side
but you know it's it's this presentation
is going to use Telegraph as the
collector primitives as at times three
data base and you know graph enhancer
visualization but it's not so much about
those systems and I hopefully you know a
lot of these things we will discuss in
this presentations are also applicable
to all of them like all of them are
actually very very good and very popular
a little bit more about Telegraph's so
Telegraph is the collector that's the
part that we will use today to actually
extract information from the device I
personally call that the the Swiss Army
knife because it's extremely poor fall
he actually has this very flexible input
and output plugins where you can collect
data from hundreds of different systems
and different formats and it can you
know and you can also talk to many many
different back-end and data bases so in
this case we're gonna use it for
Prometheus as a back-end and we're going
to use a specific plug-in that what
developed by Cisco for 14 mi if you're
not so much into building your own stack
and managing it and you know your want
to focus on your core business is
totally fine I particularly a lot of the
things we discussed today can also be
applied in more of a cloud-based
solutions what are using can take or you
know that a dog or any of those
solutions we can provide like basically
cloud base time series that is solution
where they would like to replace the
database the visualization in all of
that usually you will still have an
agent either generic one or their own
running on your site to collect but at
the end again a lot of those concepts
also apply in those solution so now
let's look at how is it going to look
like if we actually want to you know
implement that on a network vault so we
will use the same data store same
database same tools to visualizations
and an alerting and really the part that
will change is the collector or the
agent so first use case if you have a
Linux based nas most likely you can
pretty much use the same agent that they
have on the server side so if you have
at least a cumulus or an arts lab but
that can be any other system that lets
you install something on Linux you can
install those agents and you will be
able to extract a lot of information out
of the box pretty much have don't have
to do anything special here then there's
what I call the legacy device the one
that only hex books for example SNMP so
those agents like Telegraph they also
have the ability to connect information
for example through an MP and they can
run outside of the device they don't
have to run on the device itself so you
can have an agent that will collect this
information from SNMP to a lot of device
that's actually probably the most common
use cases where people get started into
the network world and using those new
databases with SNMP and with traditional
devices and it works great
honestly again SNMP is not perfect but
it's not something that should prevent
us from moving forward in those
directions another solution that I've
seen I personally implemented that works
very well is you can build your own
collector you know in Python and go
whatever language and just connect to
the device through there whatever API is
they provide you know all the modern
devices have
advanced api's and so if you're working
on the Juniper device you can collect a
lot of information with net comp at a
pretty high rate and you know export all
those information to the to the database
and then the last one I which considers
our you know the device there are
telemetry streaming and so for those
there's a new generation of interfaces
that are now available couple years ago
every vendor was coming up with its own
interface like I'm personally familiar
with the one from GE protocol GGI
there's a typo on the screen Cisco had
also their own interface and nowadays
all the vendors are trying to actually
implement a standard interface for
telemetry called gnm I and so we also
have a you know multiple collectors that
are available on this field that can be
used to to store all of that so we're
going to have a quick descriptions but
specifically what is interesting about
those those times the database and then
we'll move on to the land so the the
time three database really I mean it's
really something and my perspective they
start around you know 2013 really came
instrument 2016 a lot of different
projects you know started to be very
focused and dedicated and how do I store
and how do i process and consume you
know those specific derive of time sorry
but about counters and integer and all
of that and and all of those system
actually have some specific some
similarity in sense that they all come
with a very powerful query enjoin and
they lets you completely de correlate
how you store to how you visualize and
how you consume and that's what we're
going to explore today they actually
have the ability to and it's something
we are not used to in this industry like
we can store all the informations about
the XE the interface counters and then
we can actually visualize them and
represent them in dozen different way at
any point of time just based on how we
are acquiring the data so it's it's very
interesting those databases are very
different than the SQL databases in
sense that there's usually no schema
there's usually more read more writes
where we constantly writing data to it
then read
but that's why also we have such a
specialization in this space for those
specific type of data and the way
usually the data will looks like in the
database will looks pretty much like
that so you have what some of them
called a measurement name or Surrey
which is really defined what is the type
of data so here that will be let's say I
want to be you know interface output
bytes and then you have a set of tags or
label they all have crawl differently
but what it mean it's the contextual
information on width in which context
this information was actually captured
and so if I'm talking about interface
counters the minimum I need to capture
is the name of the device and the name
of the interface but the idea is that
you can have many many more contextual
information that will actually let you
query those device and that's again what
we'll be exploring in the other part of
the talk and then usually you have a
value so really all the data that we
collect have kind of these specific
formats and I'll I'll skip to the labs
but we'll explore life you know how to
create that and how does that looks like
so the lab so I created this lab based
on six different devices three different
nas iOS 6 RG no cos it's basically
explained leaf topology with 4 spines to
leave a couple of servers to generate
some traffic and what we'll have is we
will have a server where we will install
the x 3 database the visualization it
will install one telegraph agent for
every node in this Telegraph agent we'll
use G nmi to connect to the device
queried information and it will expose
that to primitives and again all works
with that for information is to polish
is running in the cloud in solution
called pseudo there's a github repo that
actually has I think all the
instructions to recreate that and the
pseudo provided some coupon if you
wanted to recreate this topology on your
own after you can come see me and you
can dis if you have some sandwich sure
to spin that up on your own and try at
home
so a little bit about jean-mi if you're
not familiar with Ginny my Gina is the
new standard that has been you know in
for telemetry streaming you came out of
the open config working group and it's
really actually an interface that can be
used both to configure the device using
open country beep and also collect and
subscribe to the states and the counters
in the open config formats so both of
them in this specific case I'm not using
it for configuration just to collect the
data nowadays it is supported by most
vendors so the latest release of you
know Gino's or Arista or iOS 6 are for
example support that and we're just
saying you know the first generations of
collector in these specific fields
coming up so actually I think I I I
wanted to explore this idea so I
actually managed to get you know this
multi vendor environments working I
think we're still at the beginning of
that you know hundred percent is not
with the compatible between all of them
yet but I think it's heading into the
into the right direction so and the way
it works is it's using gr pcs transport
and the collector needs to open decision
so it's initiated by the collector and
the collector then will subscribe to
some of the data and tell you know when
he open decisions what he would like to
receive and that the device would like
to stream the data after that and I'll
show you some of that but again if you
have information about gnm I am very
happy to talk about after the
presentation this is not so much a
presentation about jean-mi I guess you
know people could do a full tox of a
Hauer on it but that's what I just for
just to explore that I decided to use
for a for this presentation and
specifically I'm using a collector
called Cisco telemetry jean-mi that has
been provided by contributed by Cisco to
Telegraph so it's part of the main
Telegraph release it's 1.11 and I
actually was successful and be able to
use that from 112 to on you know other
devices like carrot Stein and juniper so
if you want to try and if you can just
download the the base image of Telegraph
and you will actually get that and you
will be able to use that last slide
before we actually get into the demo a
little bit about theory about primitives
so prometheus is at I'm sorry database
that's what we're gonna use for this
presentation and it is really focus on
on the storage and the query engine and
you can see there's a lot of things
around it but the usual component that
will see is that first you usually use
an external system for visualization so
in this case we're looking at graph Anna
that's we're gonna use Prometheus also
has the ability to generate some alerts
based on the data we are not exploring
that today but it's actually very
powerful capability is very interesting
and usually relies on an external
component called the alert manager that
they're also providing but it's it's
used in many places to to generate alert
and and provide some insights on all of
those data and then on the other side
what we have is really how do we get the
data so as I told you earlier
Prometheus is about pulling the data
they call that scraping and so usually
we have endpoints that will actually
expose those data and I will show you
later how that works
in a specific formats in the expose
that's through a web UI and then we just
give this list of endpoints to the
server and the server will automatically
scrape them on its own and you know the
format's make it that it's it's very
efficient there's also a way using what
they call the push to get way to be able
to get some information that are not
able to expose this longley interface so
we have way to collect those it is
usually common to deploy those system
coupled which they call service
discovery mechanism so that the
primitive servers will actually
automatically discover those endpoints
through some you know centralized
service catalogs or things like that so
that you don't have to manually update
and keep track of all of that but it's
it's an all different topic some of
those service discovery for example will
be like it's naturally integrated with
the kubernetes for example so that's if
you have service training in kubernetes
you can automatically be discovered and
monitored with primitives you know some
are some of the typical use cases what
all keeps things simple we're not gonna
use service discovery today we're gonna
try to export the basics and hopefully
you know show you how that works and how
you need to think when you approach that
in
to work industry so let's get to the
demo unless there's a couple of
questions but what we're gonna do is you
know we're first gonna set up telegraph
which permit use clients to expose the
data in a GM I on the other side to
collect the data from the device then
also we have all of those telegraph
agent and we're collecting the data from
the device will set up from E to servers
and what starts to you know consume and
and scrape those data from primitives
explore some of that stripper Medusa
next start exploring some of the query
so let's get started with that if you
have questions please just go to the
Nikon and we can now so I have a project
again I have actually written some play
books to help me deploy those Telegraph
agents I'm just gonna run that and
explain what's happening in the
background why it's running but what I'm
doing with that is I'm actually starting
six telegraph agents on my jump host or
and on my train post right now if I look
at darker I don't have any image running
so I'm gonna have in two minutes I will
have six images of Telegraph one for
each of my devices and to show you some
example of the configuration this is how
a telegraph configuration looks like so
we have the ability to define what are
the output plug in any input public
anyone we use so here I say I want the
output plug-in to be Prometheus probably
cannot try to make that bigger and then
I want to say I want to use the input
plug-in I want to use the Cisco
telemetry Gina and when I was talking
about and then I will have to provide
where's the device login password and
then the rest of the configuration is
really about what do I want to subscribe
to and here just because I wanted just
some data I'm subscribing to the
interface stats that's what I have here
/ interfaces / interface which is how
things works in jean-mi has subscribed
to a specific path that represent a
specific data that is defined in the
open config data model and here I'm also
subscribing to
the BGP information in the States now
what personally I really like Chris
Telegraph is they are they provide a
very flexible system so that I can
process the data before sending it to
the database to make sure it looks
exactly how I want so for example what
I'm doing here is I'm telling it you
know what I'm gonna get from my
interfaces I'll get a lot of counters
we'll also have some states I will have
some information that say my interface
is up or my interface is down if you
follow the the process you know time
series database are really about
counters in numbers not so much about up
and down so what I'm doing is I
converting on-the-fly
those those still those statuses up and
down into integer like one for up to
four down so that I can actually keep
track of that in my tensor database and
I'll show you later on how I can revert
that back in and represent that and I'm
doing the same for my bgp session i'm
saying you know if it's establish a sign
1 if it's active a sign - if it's
connected sign 3 if it's a less than 4
and so based on that I can now keep
track and alerts on those specific
States you know inside my might I'm
sorry database so that's something that
is done at the at the Telegraph layer so
now that everything is working I should
have 6 Telegraph agent running each one
is actually exposed on a specific ports
so if I go now to my my server on let's
say a specific port slash metrics I can
actually see all the data it looks very
nd just oh so beyond that it's not meant
for us to actually look at it's just
more of a troubleshooting exercise or to
understand how the workflow but we have
actually here all the information and if
I try to get one of them let's say admin
status what we can see here is here it's
actually exactly what I was doing
earlier I have the name of measurements
and then I have a set of tags that are
defined the tags that define the name of
the device I have a tag that define the
name of the interface here I have other
tags that are provided that I may or may
not use I'm using one to insert the
the role of the device is part of it and
then I have an integer then that
actually define my adenine status which
is up here so I have all those
information that I expose for each of
them
so now let's move on to installing
prometheus
so usually you won't stop permit use as
a as a long-running system you will
install that as a as a proper service
here I'm just going to do the basics and
the simple installations where I
download the binary lettuce 1 I unpack
it and I just basically extract so sits
it's to go process I actually don't need
much all I need is a process each cell
call Prometheus and if I start that I
will have time to a database you can run
on your lap on a Mac on Windows you can
run anywhere that's the beauty of go all
I really need is a configuration file so
the minimum configuration files you can
have will be this one that will
so if I that what I really have here is
that just tell it like every five
seconds I will delight you to scrape
yourself actually extract the
information about yourself because you
know as a as a database works you want
to get some metrics and some
informations about it now if I start
that I actually have a tank sorry
database running that will get you know
some information by default for me
choose expose everything on ports 9090
so if I go here actually have the
interface you know there's some
informations we can go to can see
actually what systems are getting
scraped and what is their statuses and
some information we also have a very
simple query enjoin that we can use so
for example if I wanted to see you know
how many series and data's are actually
collected I can have this information
here so you can see here right now I
have you know about 500 kind of metrics
and series that are extracted from the
database itself so but right now I'm not
wearing any information from the network
so let's update the the configuration to
actually collect the information from
the six collectors that I have running I
go back to my system I stop the existing
one update my configuration what I'm
going to do now is I'm heading those new
job and I see now I would like to scrape
every 30 seconds those six endpoints
which are representing the six Telegraph
agent that are running everything runs
on the same pool so everything is
localhost but that's that's what it
meant if I restart the database now and
I go back to the UI I will be able to
see now I have all my additional
endpoint and you know they are slowly
coming up and now I can actually go in
my in my graph and I can query those
information so for example if I wanted
to see my counters that will be
interface States counters in octet so in
this case that's the ingress octet that
I'm getting per interface and as I run
this query
what I'm seeing is I'm actually getting
so we were seeing the data point here
it's very very it's just coming up but
basically I have one you know series of
counters per interface for device so and
now it's all about how do we actually
query dance so let's explore some of the
things we can do like for example I can
filter and say I don't want all my
device only one of the device that are
called at the tag name device of type
device that has a value of Amarillo and
if I do that now I only have six
interfaces six value which really
represent the six data and getting from
this specific device now what I have
here is technically the absolute
counters of those interfaces it doesn't
really give me the rates of traffic on
those interface you know if you see here
we have sixty million so it's not very
interesting to me what I really want is
I want to have the database to calculate
for me the instance rates over you know
a period of 60 seconds for each of those
interfaces on the fly and those systems
are you know optimized for that so now
and since there is no traffic it's it's
very straight and boring but you know
now I actually have you know some
information and actually have the rates
I can actually do some mass here you
know if I say I don't really want the
octet I want the the bits per second
then I just have to multiply everything
by eight and now I actually have my you
know bytes per seconds per interface
that's just a very simple query now
let's say that I am not so much
interested about every single interface
but at some point I'd like to have a
query that tells me what is the
aggregated throughput for this specific
device so I will be able to say now what
I would like to do is the sum of all
those interfaces group by device and in
this case what I'm getting is I'm
getting one line for my device where
have all the interfaces that have been
aggregated together and you're saying
it's very fast the database are really
optimized you know for us to dynamically
calculate those things on the fly if I
remove the filter here and I say I don't
really want to get that just for this
device I want to that for all my device
and I want to group for all my device
based on the tag device then now I can
execute that and I can see I have
actually one
you know graph per device you have six
devices so that's that's what I'm
getting here so you can see you know
it's uh it's pretty powerful let me just
start up some some traffic a little bit
in the background so hopefully we get
some more interesting systems later on
so I'll just start some of that while we
are exploring those other systems so now
I don't know if you actually notice
noticed that here I'm actually getting
sis interfaces and only two of them's
our data plane there's actually the
loopback interface the management
interface so I actually don't really
wants to aggregate for example those
management interfaces I'm on maybe to
just look at my my data plane interface
so I also have the ability to filter on
that and I say I wants my name that only
start with G for example and then now I
only have two interfaces which are my my
data plane interface so now we're
actually getting into situations where
I'm actually limited on what I can do
here because if I want to only get some
specific interface I have to know their
names I have to know that this specific
interface is an uplink or this one is
connected to a server and you know and
that's like the the physical
implementation of my my system actually
getting to my queries and if I wanted to
do that across multiple vendors that
will start to get pretty complicated so
that's where I you know we really need
this very important that when we insert
all those data into the database works
we insert the right tags like because I
don't have a tags here that tells me
what is the role of my interface I'm not
able to make a query that's they only
give me my interface that are part of my
data plane but hopefully because I have
this flexibility I can actually do that
and that's where Telegraph and it's
flexibility is very interesting is I
actually adjust a flag that I'm gonna
regenerate my configuration for
Telegraph I'll show you the difference
but what I'm doing this time is that
will actually insert
some specific rules for each device that
say if it's interface one I know this
one is a roll-up link so actually
automatically insert a specific tag for
this device if this interface is you
know interface - I know so that's we
have here for example on this specific
device used on I know that Enterprise 3
is actually facing your server so I'm
going to insert a specific tag on every
single information associated in this
interface and I will get populated into
my database
I'm also inserting here the information
about the neighbors so I'm able to do
that because in this specific system I
actually already classified everything
that's actually what I used to generate
all those configuration I use in Siebel
so I have everything that is classified
in enamel and I can reuse the same
information I used to configure my
device to generate very specific
configuration for Telegraph and make
sure that inserts all the right tags all
the right informations before I actually
send everything into the database and
because I have those new tags that will
be able to you know to make some more
interesting queries and and really focus
on on the role of those components and
not so much about their names themselves
so now where are we my six collectors
have been restarted and automatically
this should have been picked up so now
if I actually reacts acute my query it's
not yet coming up what I'm seeing here
is now you know where I used to have two
results now I have four and it's
actually considering them as different
because every time we have a different
set of tags it's considering them as a
different search that how it works so
but now what we're saying is the new one
they have this interface role tags that
here is defined as leave they have this
neighbour tags that actually keep track
of what is the name of my neighbors and
because I have all of that inter
database now I can use that as part of
my query so instead of saying I want to
see only my interfaces that have a
specific name I'm going
say I want to see only a specific
interface that have a role that is
called leaf and now I'm just getting
that and since this role is applicable
across multiple of my system in
respectively of which vendor I'm using I
can actually do that across you know all
of my device so now if I do that I
actually get all the interfaces on my
spine that are facing my leaves for all
of my my my spines and if I actually go
back to my query earlier and I see now I
want to do this um by device but just
for the interface that are specific role
for each of those device then I will be
able to have an aggregated value of my
scruples per device only for the data
plane interface on my spine
so I hope you really understand how
important it is to have the right tags
in the right labels in those places
because one mistakes I was doing when I
was at juniper is we're all focusing
about getting the data as fast as we can
into the database and we didn't really
focus about that part like it was just
about minimum number of tags that we
call set but honestly I think that was a
mistake because if you don't have those
specific tags you will be very limited
on what you can do now that I have that
I can you know and I'll try to show you
I can do some some very interesting
query so now we're going to move on I
mean this interface is more
troubleshooting exploring the data have
some information most people really
don't use that you know when we want to
visualize the data will usually go with
more of a dedicated solutions like
Ravana so now we're going to move on and
explore that part of the of the
presentation again if you have any
questions please feel free to go to the
mic and ask them
so here again I have just prepared you
know the command I will go vis the very
basic of installing Ravana just
downloading Debian package installing it
I will also install a specific panel and
I will go back to that earlier later and
explain but basically I'm installing a
panels called discrete we'll explore
that and then now I'm just starting
graph Anna so with that I have a graph
on a server running on my jump host and
usually Griffin has torn on port 3000 by
default unless you specify otherwise
first time you connect its admin admin
and you need to specify it your own
password and then now I have you know
functioning graph on a server the first
step is to define the data source
so Griffin out of the box works with
many many different type of databases
the one we're using here is Prometheus
so if you select Prometheus we need to
provide some informations about where's
the server and in this case the server
is on the same host in exposing every
single port 99s which the default
configuration i didn't provide any
authentication so we'll just save that
and it's selling me everything is
working in actually tested the
connectivity so now I have a data source
configured once I have that I can really
move on into building a dashboard so
going into this plus sign I can start
creating a dashboard so dashboard in
graph Anna is really a collection of
graph that are called panel and so we
can start we know rebuild the one we
were building earlier it's very similar
technically to the interface we had
earlier it's just we have more
flexibility to make it looks nice so I
can now you know again call my interface
state counter octet for example and I
can say I only want the one they have of
roll leaf and I want to calculate the
rate on that because I'm not so much
interested about but the absolute value
and again if I do that you automatically
show me all of my counters in my rate
for my interfaces of a specific specific
role now where Griffin and provide more
is you know we can actually tweak like
for say the legend like here what I
really want to see is just the
information about what is the name of
the device and one is the name of the
interface which is associative the label
called name here if i do that now i can
see that i'm building a legend that you
know start to make more sense to me i
can also define for example the dimetric
here so on the axes what I can say is
here I'm actually visualizing
bits per seconds so I have some specific
information I can define that my legend
I want actually to be as a table on the
right with some data for example by the
the current the current data so you know
now I actually start to have something
that that speak to me and I can say you
know its interface traffic blinks so
that's one graph I can move it around
and we have the ability to select the
how many how much data we won't see how
often we want to you know refresh those
data so that's things like refine our
provider out of the box
so now let's explore this author plugin
I install let's say I want to start
monitoring the state of my BGP session
so the state of BGP session doesn't fit
as a graph as as a line so in this case
that's why it's called is a describe
plug in the screed plug-in that
personally I found very interesting to
to save that so the way it works is I
still have to do a query and in this
case my query will be you know I have
those information about the states of my
system that are saved as BGP neighbor
session states and if I query that I can
see here actually have a bunch of one
and two which represent if you remember
the actual state like one minute
stablish and all that so here what I'm
gonna do first gonna produce a little
bit the size of those lines we'll get
more of them and then this plug-in
actually let me do the mapping reverse
so here I can say now the value one
actually mean established the value two
was
what was devoted to active value three
mean connects and four is idle so I'm
doing the mapping reverse and I will be
able also to do a mapping based on on
the color so your established will be no
green
I'll have connects active
an idol let's say Idol is it's gonna be
blue and active is gonna be orange
that's it connect it's gonna be you know
darker orange so now I can actually
visualize this information I can give it
name for example and I can also assign a
legend here which will be in this case
what is the name of my device and I
believe here it's pure IP
stroke metrics name that is not Jerry
Payne
that is
actually I can get it here
the GP neighbor neighbor address that's
what I was looking for
so now because I have that I can
actually see exactly which piece
appreciation we're looking at and I will
be able you know to visualize all of
those for right now all of them are
established so it's just shut one down
so that we have something a little bit
more interesting so I'm going to go to
one of my device is actually one of my
leaf
neighbor
so we have all of them here and I'm just
going to shut down one of the interface
so that this you know one of the
interface will go down we'll be able to
follow the states and to bgp sessions
will go down as well so you can see you
know we're starting to build those
dashboards so now you know we can have a
lot of information on the dashboard one
thing that I usually do is I have two
dashboards when they will have a global
view of the network that will provide
some aggregated value between multiple
device and but what's usually also
stolen art is will have a dashboard spur
device and so the way it will work so
let's see here we have you know 10,000
feet view dashboard and we'll also have
one per device so I'm gonna clone this
one and I will call it device now since
I want that per device and I don't
really want to create a dashboard for
each of my device what I'm gonna do is
I'm going to create a variable that will
dynamically let me choose which device
I want to visualize so here I create a
viable I give it a name and I say I want
to dynamically query the value of a
specific label from and I give it the
name of specific measurement and I say
for all the tags that are value device
so here trim you preview like that's the
six five device they have right now I
think one of them is not properly
reporting those dos session and and so
now I have actually you know I will be
able to choose and I have a variable
that can dynamically take the name of
you know another device
so first what you're seeing here you're
actually seeing you know those bgp
session that went from idle to active
for example on on on the spine side
where the device the interface is now
down so you know we had this rotation on
the other side we actually devise a
since the interface is down the BG
position is just in that i don't know so
now if I just wanted to represent for
some device I will have to update my
query
we'll see here I only want to see the
information for a device that actually
map with my variable here so if I do
that automatically
since my variable is defined here I can
do that and I will be able to switch you
know between my my specific devices and
in this case it's I'm just looking at
one device every time I don't really
need to put the name of the device but
just the name of the object here and
then I will do the same for my
interfaces here actually just looking at
the device that are matching my specific
specific device in here if you look at
that I actually see you know have some
specific information define so now I
have a dashboard that is dedicated per
device and I can start you know having
some some specific information on that
any questions so far I'm actually
surprised hi
Reynaldo cheese from Oracle can you
elaborate a little bit more how you
collect the metrics from the devices and
you scrape from tomatillos yes so in
this specific case I'm using Telegraph
so I have one Telegraph process running
per device and I have an example of
configuration here and that's where for
each device I provided how to connect
and what to collect using the path so
the pass is something specific to Gina
my so telegraph opener gmj RPC sessions
to the device and when you open decision
say I would like to receive the
interface stats and I would like to
receive the BGP session stats and so
telegraph get those information and
since I defined telegraph and I say I
want you to expose everything in the
Prometheus format on a specific port
then I get that something like that for
each of my device so each of my device
actually expose those information and
here I have you know one ports per
device so nine thousand two is one nine
thousand one is another one and that's
how I get all my information from my
device on the primitive side I created
the configuration to match those so here
I actually you can see that Prometheus
is actually scraping every 30 seconds
all of those in point and I was showing
you and the format is actually you know
an agreement between the Prometheus
client and the server that as long as I
expose the data in a format that match
primitive specification then the
Prometheus server will be able to scrape
that and every service they can see will
go and they will get all of those
information
does that answer your question perfect
so let's start a little bit more traffic
maybe so now there's actually some very
interesting we can do online like we've
just been scratching the surface here
like for example since I have all of
those data and all of those capability
into database that starts to explore for
example what else we can do so let's say
that now I'm not so interested about so
let's say we're looking at at the leaf
so that will be done as for example and
let's say that here we're actually
looking at either uplink or leaf so what
we can see here is there's three you
know not a really good load balancing my
AC NP is not working very well now if I
look at it I can see it now what's
interesting with the system is that it
they have a lot of functions and math
and all of that they'll actually let me
define and provide you know metrics or
signals that will be able to alert some
so for example there is a functions here
that will let me automatically calculate
what is the difference of rates between
my interface which will be if I say I
want to calculate the standard
deviations between a set of you know
graph I will get one line as a as a
response that actually indicates and
expectations that if my if my ICMP is
working perfectly the deviation between
all of those should be zero because they
will have exactly the same traffic on
all of them but now I can see here for
example that my ICMP is not working and
so I have a deviations between my four
uplinks there's actually pretty bad and
so I will be able for example using
graph on ax or using
Prometheus itself - to set up let's say
an alert so if I wanted to say now
actually want to set us ritual as 1000
so I know based on my previous
experience that if my standard
deviations between all of my link and a
specific spine mean that I go over
specific thresholds either it mean I
have some very balanced traffic and
maybe my system is not working properly
or maybe I need to remediate or maybe
there's something else like maybe
there's actually some specific errors
and my interfaces that are dropping
packets on one of the on one of the
paths though there's many multiple
reasons but having that will be able to
actually you know provide some some very
you know specific and actionable metrics
so that's just one example another
example that I like to explore is if we
go back to the global one let's say that
now I would like to see for example if
one of my devices actually dropping
traffic one of my spine so in this
specific case I have all the information
so that my my spines and because I have
all of that I can say I would like to
configure the aggregated value for each
of my spines by device so here I see you
know the aggregated value of ingress
traffic for only the data plane
interfaces for each of them and I would
like to subtract the same value of what
I'm getting for incoming for egress
traffic and so basically the idea is
that everything that is not zero mean
that I have more traffic that is
incoming my device then what I have that
is actually leaving my device so as a
spine that's actually a signal that
something is going wrong so most of the
case you could expect to have some error
counters that were going on that week
also show here but you know in some
cases if you have a big chassis that
could actually have some drop inside the
line car some PFE
and a lot of other places that you might
not be able to see you know have with
the specific counters than being able to
dynamically measure everything's coming
in everything's going out on some device
on your network you will be you know
very quickly able to identify and I can
say here that in this case this specific
device Amarillo is dropping some traffic
where it was not dropping anything
before you know and again that's
something I can you know now visualize
generates and alerts understand and if I
look at my device my my 10,000 feet view
I can actually see that and I can drill
down and and go back on on one specific
device and start investigating and
getting faster to my my root cause
analysis so we're almost at the end of
the session is there any questions and I
hope you know we were able to cover all
the objectivity of the sessions now you
have a better understanding you know
what are those times to database how to
set up you know some collection with
Telegraph how to do the interaction
between the collector and the database
and the database and graph fauna and you
have you know some of the basic
understanding of how you can use Griffon
a to start building some dashboards to
give you your some insight and again I
think if there's one takeaway is that
what's super important is to have the
right labels on your data and if you
don't have the right labels when you
insert them in the database you won't be
able to do as many interesting query so
it's very important because those labels
really are reflections in some way of
your network design so as a network
engineer it's really important that you
get into these conversations with the
people setting up the pipeline to ensure
that they have a way to get those
information to insert them and to work
with them to make sure that because for
them otherwise it's just going to give
you a device name and an interface name
and very minimal informations and you
will actually be very limited later on
on what you can do in explore in your
data with that
I'll take any questions otherwise I
think we're done
thanks again if you're interested to you
know set up the topology at home there
are some vouchers as provided by a
digital the cloud providers that you can
use to set up your topology on your own
you