hello ladies and gentlemen my name is
Alexandra ribbon and today we'll be
talking about impress in data centers
just before we get started just a few
words about about Yandex so what is it
the annex is the biggest IT company in
Russia and one of the biggest largest IT
companies in Europe so the annex is the
huge digital ecosystem of consumer
services the services like Alex George
which is the which is the leading search
engine in Russia I mean with with the
leading market share
there are also services like an extract
which is the largest context of the
TASMAC network in Russia there are also
services like ionic taxi car sharing
food delivery just name a few and
recently Yandex has launched a new
service annex public cloud where we're
in I'm in charge of network
infrastructure so in Palace and data
centers in Palace in other cells I know
that sounds slightly untypical
and extraordinary and I'm kind of
feeling that for those of you who have
ever build data center networks or
operated them in possession data centers
more likely sounds weird or or even
insane and why is that that's probably
because Impa less is perceived to
something which pursuits like something
from service providers like central
complex and and indeed all that stuff
like a GP + LDP there I'm sure you know
the problems with synchronization and of
course RSVP on top of it for traffic
engineering all of that is slightly
complicated and given us that the
question is who might be that crazy to
want to bring compress into data center
networks and yeah well the reason I'm
here today is to show you that in place
and data centers can have nothing in
common with complexity and be an elegant
solution on the contrary the solution to
many differences in
and and that in Peleus in can make
things easier or more manageable to want
a better world
so let's take a look
button yes let's take a look at this
slide there is a typical data center
network depicted it has close topology
or excuse me according to us wide it has
claw topology but yeah anyway it has it
consists of several layers like leaf
lettuce wine level and an export that's
what our data center fabric network look
like looks like in the data center
network we have the different protocols
we have AP before for the Overland
Network and the primary usage or the
overall network is to provide our
customers with their own virtual
networks where they can run virtual
machines and so on so forth we also have
ipv6 for our core cloud components so
basically every core cloud service like
metro block storage object storage
databases any service uses ipv6 and by
the way the bottoms of ipv6 traffic
exceeds those of AP before and of course
we've gotten palace which is the topic
for a discussion it is also worth
noticing that in the data stand the
fabric we use on the commodity network
years by commodity network years I mean
general typical layer 3 switches based
on tomahawk or Trident chipsets basics
so let's finally take a look at the
first implies neighbor scenario I mean
the scenario where we fully employed in
place it's delivering packets to the
Internet and and back so when a client's
virtual machine sends a packet to the
Internet the packet passes the overlay
Network and enters cloud it way cloud
gateway is the special network appliance
which bridges the gap between the
overlay and underlying networks cloud
gateway
receiving the packet received the packet
and with with the help of route of route
reflect knows what a particular border
routers it needs to send the packet to
so it imposes
transport label and send the packet to
the fabric fabric I mean those commodity
natural gears performed trigger smoke
operation until the packet enters until
the packet gets the edge of the data
center network at the edge an additional
transport level imposed in order to send
the packet over the backbone and that
packet with two levels and post level
packet travels the bevel network and few
hops before butter router all those
transport levels get stripped and the
purity packet is sent to the internet
through the butter router the reverse
path is pretty the same it's simple as
that
however let me shed some light on on the
detail details well just remind you that
in Peleus is not complex as long as you
don't bring those protocols in your
network especially in data center
network so we didn't either instead we
use on the BGP and BGP level and cast in
particular to carry level billing
information then network appliance we
use the already mentioned cloud gateway
is our internal development it's a key
component of cloud network ecosystem let
me say so and and it is based on EDI
your vector packet processor for data
plane and go bgp for contra plain we
also have load balancers which just
another type of cloud gateway based
based on cloud between
we also have very large reflectors
throughout injectors filter noise
management nodes and so on
cloud connector cloud connector is
another key component of our network as
you can guess cloud connector connect
the data center network to the backbone
network on the backbone side it has a
GPL dps appear all that stuff on the
back when a drug has on the bgp level
unicast so cloud connector is that
device which imposes an additional trust
level in order to send packet over the
back one
well cloud connector is is the same
commodity not forgive so the same layer
3 switches the layer of the switch we
use everywhere in our network couple
words about the backbone network so
that's a typical region depicted our
backbone Network intercom
availability zones and points of
presence it will build two zones our
data center Skousen thousand sellers and
points of presence that special
technical sides with the only network
that took equipment so through bits of
bandwidth minimal latency it's all about
the backward Network and now how routing
information is distributed it's it's
slightly messy site but yeah I hope I
hope it's visible though so what I
wanted you to see is that BGP label
unicast
is used only to distribute label
buildings only to look back interfaces
of network appliances those network
appliances which need to communicate
with each other every Network appliance
establish direct connected external bgp
level and concession with fabric device
and overall bgp and impalas himself
first a very teeny transport system for
us Tina transfer system over the data
center networks and over the bamboo
networks bubble network
so after distribution all those after
distribution all of loopback stability
information those network appliances and
actually not only network appliances but
routers for example so they can set up
their own BGP session on top of that
transport system and exchange their own
routing information and then send
whatever type of traffic they want it
might be purity before you know people
6n or even impalas
so it doesn't it doesn't matter that
sort of flexibility which in place gives
us is very appealing what is also
important
that's all keep keeping the network
beneath absolute unaware of any of that
moreover the beauty of in polis is that
we can seamlessly integrate into the
backbone network so it t need data plane
just stack of levels
very simple minimalistic contra plane
bgp with minimum minimum amounts of
lubricant ounces and very very little
state in the network and speaking of
state there is actually no additional
state into the bible network because
cloud conductor because of cloud
connector cloud connector with the help
of level unicast throughout reflector
with record in this case imposes that
additional transport levels well I hope
you more or less firmer with the key
idea and let me show you some impetus in
blessing able scenarios to go on now we
can in such cool way delivery package to
the Internet and back but that's not
enough for our customers they want more
and they asked for some sort of disaster
recovery and the best way to do it is to
is to deploy groups or machines in every
evil build to zone and the regional
level or balance eludes us to distribute
to deliver traffic to them the idea is
pretty trivial with the tab load
balancer notes in every evil bill to
zone and those load balancer nodes start
and not seen any car through stupid
routers then butter routers butter
rotors even the distribute imbalance in
cannon from the internet traffic over
those it was built zones over load
balancer notes and now if a customer
solution machine Kapil today one able to
build his own that's not a problem
anymore because law Donna's not just
withdraw the asana cast announces and
and that's all so traffic will traffic
is distributed to the other
availability zones but what what if a
loaders no dice that's a problem that's
a problem because every load bones not
represent represent itself and next up
entering in and but routers for those in
the cast routes and if butter routers
are not consistent fashion capable and
they're not in our case removing just
one entry oh just one extra entry leads
to all flows to be rehearsed
for example TCP sessions get redirected
to the wrong destination and eventually
dropped
so the feller only one load Bono's not
in one bill to zone affects all the
traffic or the traffic in the whole
region that that's quite a big problem
but what can we do about that hopefully
like many problems this one can be
solved by adding more layers so we
basically we just have pre load balancer
so yes moves we put in additional box in
the middle be named at pre load balancer
and these pre load balancers
re-announced roots from load balancer
nodes to butter routers and they and now
next hope entries in butter outers
unlike load balancers which under
development and constantly receive
updates sometimes feathers or boots pre
load balances stays almost untouched and
because they were rarely receive any
updates these pre load balancers keeps
the next hope list in Albury routers
very stable so now what happens in
availability zone a stays in
availability to zone 8 so that's not the
straps or the traffic anymore on in the
whole region so the other zones are
unaffected and even more a lot balancer
notes I can sisters cache incapable
within the region and so even the
failure of one able to build of one a
lot Don's not in one availability zone
never disrupts traffic anymore and now
you may ask me how is this all really
want to impress and the answer is that
because of him police we we were able we
was able to put this provide balance or
not
somewhere in each spot and forget about
them and
as does the rest job I mean in place
interconnects all those preload balances
and load balancers the cool thing is
that we we change entirely nothing
called the fabric to support this
scenario so this isn't this this problem
showed up very just all the sudden and
we can can in week was able to quickly
address it well let's take a look on the
next impressionable scenario cloud
market in Russia is still emerging we
receive new customer requirements on
daily basis and one big customer comes
and says that he wants to consume our
cloud services but he has his wrong data
center he has already heavily invested
in and therefore has no plans to drop it
so basically this client wants a fat pie
between his data center and cloud yeah
that's that's not a problem because
we've got him palestin our data center
fabric to take a look at this slide the
packet passes pretty the same but there
is just additional service level yeah
his edit of the button so in place
enables us to quickly address customers
scenarios with very short the - to
launch new new services bare-metal case
once you started provide customers with
new services you you can stop doing so
another big customer comes and says that
he has seen some pictures of our data
center want grants in one to rent racks
in all of them and that's not the whole
story this customer also wants to
consume cloud services and as a chair on
the cake is wrong that etc and he wants
to interconnect all of that so to
interconnect those regs
cloud and his own data center
we turn some leaf switches into PE
routers in terms of ample s and and here
we go
so those lips which is now PE routers
encapsulate clients traffic in tempo
let's send it to the fabric and the
packets delivered to cloud get away if
they need to get to the the Overland
overlay network or to butter out or if
they need to get to customers on-premise
data center so eternal some switches
into PE routers was the one do we needed
to do to provide our customers with this
with this scenario there remain the the
rest in the network remained absolutely
untouched so this is just another
example how impressed neighbors are so
quickly launch and deliver services so
apparently that's the picture the
customer has seen you can see that our
typical data center point of delivery he
and X builds its own data centers and I
mean from Greenfield and that's just
zoomed picture of Sorek and but by
showing all this I want you I want to
show you another great approach we've
been able to take because of input eyes
now that's a fabric this concept it's
your own the photo decoding what is this
concept about we are true believers in
this concept in basically this concept
means that you should consume the same
product you shoot yourself consume the
same product or infrastructure in our
case you provide your customers with
this is the only way to understand what
what the customer feel about the product
or the infrastructure what is good what
is bad in other words to have the same
experience to have the same pains at the
customer's health and I try to depict
the typical rack layout in in the data
center it's quite schematic but provide
the basic idea
so all the previously mentioned network
appliances are virtual machines
unlike customer sutra machines which
live entirely in the overlay Network
these Network machines I mean network
appliances are directly connected to
their underlying network through wire
srvv functionality so anyway all these
network machines or all these virtual
machines live in the same racks which
customers and share the same racks
there are really literally alongside to
each other in in the same Rex so there
are common components in our there are
common cloud components for instance
cloud schedule which operates virtual
machines common network storage and the
common ethic infrastructure beneath
after all so that all that so that all
that leads to to say all that
infrastructure
sharing common infrastructure sharing or
reusing the usage of the common
companies lowers our costs and all that
leads to firstly our customers benefit
from the reliable infrastructure because
we intend to keep our infrastructure
reliable in order to to be able run our
own critical network appliances and the
second as a result our infrastructure is
so reliable so we don't need to to run
our network appliances somewhere else
but in the same infrastructure so we
don't build any additional parallel
infrastructure to run our network
appliances that lowers our capex and we
don't need to we there is no need to run
there is no need to treat our network
appliances in any special way and that
lowers our maintenance and optics
eventually
and because of impeller so now that is
in the fabric we can run Network
appliances wherever we want input and
input let's simply interconnect them we
are not limited by the size for instance
edge sport where typically network
related stuff allocated so appliances
ran in in points of delivery and what is
also nice that we can easily scale
Network appliances scale them out
whenever we need it when another
workload scan so that's that we can
scale them because they're a regular
virtual machine that's that's pretty
useful and now about some box we we have
encountered so everything wasn't that
shiny we had some bugs in do we have
actually we had a lot of bugs in data
plan we had a lot of bugs in control
plane and I want to show you sound so
take a look at this slide what's wrong
with this impellers heater it's wrong
because it shouldn't be there actually
because it's implicit now so many of you
who could code on Python knows that
explicit null is better than implicit
and apparently our bender things the
same way so implicit node is broken
that's not a problem we don't give up
that easily
let's try explicit no but it didn't work
and I think that piece of hardware just
takes ironic offset and normal packets
turn into garbage anyway those bugs were
sorted just to show you and in the
conclusion so I could have actually I
could have had just only dead slide in
my presentation because this quote from
amazing book navigating Auto complex the
perfectly expand explains the key idea
but then I decided I needed more
pictures more examples so my
presentation to be accepted anyway
despite all the preconceptions we chose
in police because because it's fully
addressed our needs and implants
simplified and actually implies
simplified our data center network in
place is not complex especially the way
we use it but very powerful and the last
the last before before the lunch there
are talks or rumors that in police's
dine already dead it's not in police
lives and prospers and hope it will so
thank you very much for attention and
yeah if you've got any question under
your disposal
[Applause]
anybody questions come on up
hi there Jason Brody Invesco great talk
just curious did you run into anything
with in your when you're always
collectors with a point of view are you
using like any BGP or are like optimal
amount reroute reflection or anything no
we don't have any idea routing
deflections yeah yeah just BGP a BGP for
they are resolution next hope okay
thanks so now I GP at all yeah okay
anybody else going once going twice for
you spasiba thank you
[Applause]
you