software for open networking and cloud
sonic great contribution from Microsoft
in the world of networking but I have to
say they didn't get something quite
right the name in cloud and think
outside of cloud that's the use case for
our talk today
he's Vince from Dell network architect
and me Alan Carr our data center
architect from Comcast
what we are going to talk today a quick
overview so we will look at overview of
Comcast data centers how what's in there
how they look like why we were even
looking for a new operating system
details about Sonic and where we are
deploying it at Comcast and how we are
operationalizing it ok so the data
center footprint at Comcast we have
eight national data centers 14 regional
50 for local a bunch of others total
about like 90 sites the focus today is
primarily on the Nationals because
that's where we are doing sonic in terms
of devices we are looking at about 9500
natural devices just for routing
switching kind of the devices the count
that we know about which gives us close
to 300,000 server ports and we do 600
plus Network changes a month again the
changes that we know about so well so
but the complexity where it comes from
is the rainbow datacenters we build with
multi vendor and all different kind of
hardware's and different vendors there
so we have more than eight vendors for
again not including any server hardware
which brings 117 different hardware
models and 184 different operating
systems management tools are we don't
want to talk
and everything is there so what runs on
that hardware or different cloud
platforms OpenStack cloud the VMware
cloud kubernetes container a Service
Cloud Foundry and no video systems why
systems bare-metal all different kind of
applications so in different kind of
protocols and on top of that we need to
secure that so there's some segmentation
going on in the network which makes it
so which makes it very hard to
operationalize things and scale is still
manageable the difference we have from
the big web scalers is instead of doing
one thing hundred thousand times we do
like 100 things ten thousand times
so why we need new operating system
after having all those different
variations and that comes to like okay
what if the whole world spoke one
language the travels would have been
much easier they will all understand the
same thing yeah they could have
different cultures and different
traditions but I can communicate to them
in one language so the biggest challenge
is the automation if I have these
different operating systems and these
different hardware's I need something as
a translator to give the same command to
all of them and traditionally we have
been building translation layer on top
of the traditional OSS the attempts were
made with DES laughs and we did use
tailor open config is another great one
but we still need something more that we
can talk the same language normalize the
hardware variations so I want all
different kind of hardware versions but
they all need to be on same level ground
and behave the same way the software
Interop is is a big one to give an
example I cannot I I had problem having
two platforms from same vendor and could
not speak eius eius between them because
they are using different packet formats
several days wasted
you know the troubleshooting cases we
figure out they are using different kind
of hello packets and one needed padding
so if the operating system is the same
chances are we won't have these issues
anymore and we could save some time in
the interrupt testing and certification
internally obviously every time you do
something new we need to reduce the cost
and I want something that is cheaper in
I mean software has a cost to support
another big one is break free with the
with the vendor operating systems I have
a feature built by one vendor but not by
other and now I'm stuck I cannot use it
because it has to make business sense
for them
it has to lie on their priority list
which is not always the case
we need multi vendor we need chip
diversity and we want to decouple not
only the hardware software but also
different software components so if I
want I can yank this stack and replace
it or I can upgrade one at a time not
having the traditional monolithic codes
and out of all that wish list I still
want the luxury to be able to have phone
call and have some support on it so
where that takes us is that's that's
served by Sonic
what is sonic wins
so raise of hand before this talk how
many people have heard of Sonic
all right that's a fifth and of those
people how many have actually installed
played with it tested it out all right a
significantly less amount of people I
only it's all about five hands up
so underlying underneath the covers
right Sonic is built upon Linux and with
that you're able to leverage advanced
management tools such that the server
guys that are already used to with a
common CI CD ansible Jenkins Jeff puppet
from the management system so that in
itself is alan carr had mentioned being
able to leverage that for the network
and if we look at the two things there
the OD AB and ASIC vendor diversity as
well as the search abstraction layer
that means what we can do is leverage
manufacturers such as Broadcom Mellanox
barefoot and it's hardware independent
right so what that we were talking about
was being able to use the same software
all the same automation tools to manage
the network infrastructure but the
hardware itself can change we were
talking about containers right
everything right now that's what they're
built on and if we look at how this is
built for example BGP we can take that
stack there and as the operator you have
the option you have the choice of being
able to pick quagga FRR go bgp versus
bgp or juniper crpd and again customize
that operator to customize the operating
system based upon your specific use case
maybe you don't like one stack versus
the other easy to swap out without
unchanging the underlying operating
system
what I'd like to show here and I'm not
going to go through all of it right is
again
in the user space you see all the
different pieces that are containerized
and the ability to maybe pull them out
create your own and then interact at the
bottom level we have the actual physical
hardware right we're talking about the
specific Asics and then the kernel space
where you have all the different drivers
right the switch abstraction interface
sits there to be able to leverage
different vendors and what I do want to
highlight here is in a pub sub model so
again being able to create your own
pieces custom to your environment with
this I'm not going to go through it but
you'll have the slides I'd like to ask
when was the last time you actually saw
a packet walk through from a vendor
showing getting an update and then
programming the fit right that's not
publicly usually publicly available a
little bit about the maturity of Sonic 3
releases a year there's about hundreds
of commits a month
we got about 850 community members and I
actually just checked this morning
there's about 89 supported platforms so
by the time that we had submitted this
until today it's increased in the number
of size major customers that are
actually running this in production
Alibaba
Tencent linkedin dell Broadcom and
Mellanox as far as contributors to the
sonic repository and then there also is
commercial support available for people
that want to run open source but still
need some form of support so the
advantages of sonic again designer
network operating system we saw in the
slide or to go you can change out the
routing stack depending upon your
specific use case that next point there
sonic it's open source so being able to
leverage that with current vendors as
opposed to people with large spend where
they're being able to actually negotiate
rates with their current vendors because
it is a modern operating system we don't
have to worry about monolithic code and
all the baggage that comes associated
with that at some point if there is
looking at Sonic what we mean by here is
building the same layer 2 layer 3 stack
you see all the other vendors everyone
they're building the same feature if we
were able to consolidate on the same
person creating that feature
interoperability and stability would
probably go up in my opinion zero
downtime being able to upgrade the
containers on the fly and then Alan
Carter will also go through a brief demo
of the fast reboot and warm reboot and
part of the CI CD practice is that's not
just for cloud ever anymore everyone has
the ability to do this
okay so where are we deploying sonic at
Comcast we're taking a phased approach
starting from the DC core that we have
in more detail in than the following
slides how the team looks like so five
engineers and that includes our new boss
as well plus 24/7 operations team we do
have plans to extend it in lower layers
and enable more features later
but what's deployed now is pretty simple
we are doing lldp BGP ecmp DHCP LLDPE
the generic management features ECL NTP
tech acts and stuff we do want to get to
some of the layer 2 things next year
including the we explained and a bgp
evpn so high level how the comcast data
centers look like this we follow quad
design which means so the National DC is
divided in quad one two three four
typically if you see on the bottom here
there are racks with top of rack
switches connecting into spines further
aggregated into AG spine going north of
it super-rag and multiple hundred gigs
connected to backbone it's all layer
three ebgp
between the layers now in the center
where it says DC core we're gonna zoom
into it little more on the next one and
that's the area where we are doing sonic
so the DC core is kind of a contained
unit it's like a block that we can
repeat in different quads each unit
looks like 48 so it is 32 spines and 16
tier-2 spines
they are all same kind of switch same
skew tomahawk 3 based 32 by 400 device
and at the end what I get out of it is
2048 ports of 100 gig that I can use for
any top of the rack switches it's a 2
hundred 4.8 a non-blocking fabric we had
a good non-blocking and the leaf spine
taught from Ross white before that this
is one of those fabric design and we are
we are running it pretty lean like we
looked at the features its underlay only
IP v4 v6 fabric by doing this what I get
is for about 40 percent reduction in
cost and that's after we have
standardized on single-mode 500 meter dr
for optics versus what we were doing
before
hey this is sr this is long rage cutting
down all of that just have one optics
overall and we also gain in terms of
latency going from D buffer to shallow
buffer here it's a significant
improvement in latency now the
monitoring part the data collection so
we are leveraging all these different
sources or telemetry gr PC syslog as an
MP CLI and ever flow is something that
we are working on now more details into
the data sources what they are doing so
for control plane and network topology
we are looking at as an mp4 system
events its syslog and various counter
sport counters and the buffer counters
it's using streaming telemetry again our
flow is there in words for packet
telemetry and the tools we are using we
are building in-house in partnering with
its one of partnering with outside
vendors also to build to collect the
data and make some sense out of it
unlike the traditional tools where they
are used just for the monitoring
purposes a up down we want to do
something more in this core few few
things we are looking at or using the
machine learning capabilities for
pattern recognition and drifts
so a few things that we we have as a
requirement or I'm not going to
configure any threshold on any of the
counters they have to be adaptive and
more of like machine learning kind of
you see the pattern let it run for a
week or more and when there is a drift
for more than a certain amount it causes
an alert other thing we want to make get
out of it is to detect the grave
failures which is more important for
sonic the way it behaves if the box is
up and running and interfaces are up but
certainly I drop traffic we need to
detect that and that's not based on any
traditional alert like this something
went down in this case nothing went down
but we are learning it from the patterns
and from the drift the the third one we
we need to look at some of the
correlation pieces so when something
goes wrong I get 30 events and I want
this tool to be able to correlate them
there hey there are all the events
related to one incident so alert me only
once I mean there's detail available but
I need only they are one so I need only
one incident repeatable shot we we did
so this is one of the features which is
particularly interesting to me because
we were looking at traditional vendors
to build us something hey why it takes
so long to reboot and we have been
asking the feature velocity or whatever
never got it and sonic has it now the
fast reboot
I still get messages from the guy
working in lab hey I loaded all the
configs and I rebooted the box box is
going for a reboot and I'm going out for
lunch so with with the fast reboot we
can reboot the Box in less than the
requirements say 25 seconds
conservatively I put here 30 seconds so
we did some demos and I have the
screenshots here to share so on the left
it shows ferryboat loading type and on
the right is over
reboot we are going to look at the fast
reboot today so the the control plane so
the state of the forwarding DB and the
ARP table is saved before before the
control plane goes down and data plane
is not cleared until the control pin has
come back and it's ready to reinitialize
the data plane here's the setup on the
top we have two boxes running sonic and
at the bottom server 37 and 39 running
high power so the top two windows here
are showing those two switches the
steady state and window marked one
showing high power of turning on now if
you could read on the window one is you
a faster abort command and the iperf
doesn't show any disruption there's no
disruption in data plane yet once the
control plane is up the data plane gets
reinitialized
and that's when I saw only 15 second
disruption sonic has open source there's
a lot to read and some reference that we
use for building this slide deck
thank you questions
illegal Dutch telecom looking at the
slides I am
I seem to detect gap in while okay maybe
a roadmap I'm seeing mention of SNMP yes
and G RPC and I for the access to data I
would have expected to see net con for
rest conf somewhere in the picture and
for the data modeling I think I didn't
see anything and my humble observation
is that the data modeling using yang
seems to be a fairly interesting
development and to me it looks like if
you don't have it in your roadmap and
picture you might actually miss a train
that's leaving can you comment so the
open configure supported the other
models are there my the way I'm showing
is like how we are deploying it at
Comcast there's a lot more than this I
am not so sure about some of the other
data models I mean if anyone else want
to comment
Rahul Agarwal Rock Tara we've been
working with Comcast on this so just to
add to what you just said
actually sonic does the poorest comp so
it has a REST API it's a pretty
sophisticated REST API and it does
support open config based models and in
fact what's been deployed does have a
network model which uses rest as well as
open config but of course it comes over
gr PC yep thank you I'll then to mention
we are working with the hall and his
tool on terror to develop the internal
tools okay thank you
[Applause]
you