cryptographic challenge a formal
treatment of repliable onion encryption
my name is megumi ando and this is joint
work with ana licianskaya
suppose that alice wants to send a
message to david anonymously
then encrypting the message can prevent
an eavesdropper from learning the
content of the message
but it won't prevent an adversary who
can observe the network traffic from
discerning that alice is communicating
with david
the adversary can simply trace the
sequence of bits coming out of alice's
computer and going into davis
so what can alice do to prevent the
adversary from learning who she is
communicating with
one practical approach is to use onion
routing
which was originally proposed by chong
to send a message to david
alice first picks a writing path ending
with david
in this example the routing path is the
sequence of parties bob charlie david
then she forms a layered encryption
object called an onion
and sends it to the first party on the
routing path bob
bob decrypts just the outermost layer of
the onion or peels the outermost layer
of the onion
this reveals an inner onion also known
as the processed onion in blue
and the destination of the processed
onion charlie
charlie repeats this process
he peels the outermost layer of the
onion revealing the processed onion in
pink and the next destination for the
onion david
when david peels the processed onion he
obtains a message from alice
now if alice sends her message via onion
routing the network adversary may not
know who her recipient is
for example if charlie receives alice's
onion to david in purple
along with another onion in yellow
then the adversary cannot determine
which outgoing onion corresponds to
which incoming onion
is the green onion the result of
processing the purple onion and the
white onion from processing the yellow
onion
or is it the other way around
in other words onions that are batch
processed at an honest party mix
an anonymity can be achieved so long as
the onions sufficiently mix as they
travel through the network
however using public key encryption to
form the onion encryption layers as
charm envisioned it
is not exactly what we want
this is because the encryption of a
message is necessarily strictly longer
than the message
what this means is that onions with
different numbers of hops to go don't
mix
the adversary can trivially determine
which outgoing onion corresponds to
which incoming onion for the sizes of
the onions
cavemnish and listyanskaya formalized
the notion of onion encryption but by
defining an onion encryption scheme
as a triple of algorithms
a key generation algorithm g
an onion farming algorithm form onion
and an onion processing algorithm proc
onion
they also provided the first formal
security definitions
for onion encryption
onions generated using a secure onion
encryption scheme mixed properly
regardless of how far they are for their
destinations
however the paper by kamenish and
lisyanskaya
and subsequent follow-up work did not
tackle two-way channels
when alice's recipient david received
the message from alice there was no
method for replying to her anonymously
two-way communication is necessary for
most internet
applications for example for web
browsing or for filling out a form
online
so to conduct these applications
anonymously it is clear that we need
anonymous two-way channels
the challenge with constructing a cca
secure repliable onion encryption scheme
is that it is unclear how to do so when
the returned onions cannot be
constructed by any one party
the return path must be supplied by the
sender alice
whereas a reply message must be supplied
by the recipient david
in this paper we formalize the notion of
repliable onion encryption
in this work an onion is a pair
consisting of the header and the content
a repliable onion encryption scheme
consists of four algorithms
the key generation algorithm g
the onion uninforming algorithm form
onion that takes as input the label
the message
the forward path from the sender to the
recipient
the return path from the recipient to
the sender
and the public keys of the parties on
the routing path consisting of the
forward the return pass
and outputs a list of onions
corresponding to the forward path
and a list of headers corresponding to
the return path
the onion processing algorithm
proc onion takes as input the onion to
be processed
processing party and a secret key
and outputs a role in an
output if the role is intermediary the
output is a processed onion
and next destination
if the role is recipient the output is
the message
if the role is sender then the output is
a label and a reply message
so the purpose of having labels is that
the sender can use them to determine
which message the reply message is a
response for
finally there's a new type of algorithm
for reply
for forming a reply onion
it takes as input the reply message
the onion it is replying to
the recipient and a secret key
and is a return to onion
and first destination for the return
onion
our contributions are as follows
first we define the ideal functionality
for repliable onion encryption and
committees uc model or more precisely in
kinetic cohen and lindle's simplified uc
model
we call this f rose for repliable onion
encryption scheme
next we present a game-based definition
repliable onion security
and prove that it is both sufficient and
almost necessary for realizing f rows
and finally we present the first
provably secure repliable onion
encryption scheme charlotte encryption
scheme
security and kennedy's universal
composability model is described with
respect to an ideal functionality
the sukeem obscure the environment z
cannot tell whether it is operating in
the real world that uses a scheme
or in the ideal world that uses the
ideal functionality instead
for onion encryption the environment can
instruct the honest parties to form an
onion to process an onion or to form a
reply
in the real world the honest parties run
the appropriate algorithm from the onion
encryption scheme
in the ideal world the honest parties
relay the instruction to the ideal
functionality f rows
it is a job of the ideal functionality
to form onions process onions and form
replies
we chose to work specifically in the
simplified uc model
first because this choice simplifies the
way we model communication
in the suc model the environment may
communicate with the honest parties by
writing into their input tapes
and reading their output tapes and the
honest parties can communicate with the
ideal functionality via a central router
second realizability of f rows and the
suc model implies reliability in the
full uc model so we don't really lose
any generality by working in the
simplified model
first let us provide an intuition for
our ideal functionality f rose
in order to ensure that the onions mix
at honest intermediaries we want it to
be impossible to match an incoming onion
to its outgoing onion
moreover it should be impossible to tell
whether these onions are forward onions
or return onions
in the ideal world this is guaranteed by
generating the incoming onions and
outgoing onions in an information
theoretically independent way
to form an onion on behalf of honest
party pi the ideal functionality first
partitions the forward path into
segments
where each segment is a list that ends
in the next honest party
here following the notational
conventions of the paper
the honest parties are capitalized
whereas the adversarial ones are in
lower case
so in this example the segments are the
list consisting of p1
the list consisting of p2 p3 and p4
the list consisting of p5 and finally
the list consisting of p6 and p7
let oi denote the onion for party pi
the onions 0102
o5 and o6 are formed independently of
each other
for example
o1 is formed without m or the rest of
the routing path in its input
the first onion o1 is returned to the
sender pi
let o4 be what p4 gets if o2 is
processed correctly
if the ideal functionality is asked by
p4 to process o4 it returns o5
likewise let o7 be what the recipient p7
gets if o6 is processed correctly
then o7 gets processed to m
this is a message that was in the sender
pi's input to form onion
in order to respond to the onion o7 with
a reply message m prime on behalf of the
recipient p7
the ideal functionality first retrieves
the return path which it maintained
internally and then forms onions using m
prime and the return path
this is done using the same approach
that was used for forming the forward
forward onions
of course the full description of the
ideal functionality is much more
involved please refer to the paper for
more details
since it can be cumbersome to directly
prove that an onion encryption scheme
realizes afros we also present a
game-based security definition that
proves to be both sufficient and almost
necessary for realizing f rows
we now describe the salient points of
the security game
first the adversary picks two honest
parties i and s
next the adversary gets oracle access to
processed onions and reply and reply to
onions on behalf of ins
then the adversary picks the parameters
for the challenge onion which includes
the forward path and the return path
the honest party s must be the sender of
the challenge onion and so the return
path must end in s
and the honest party eye must be
somewhere else on the routing path
either as an intermediary on the forward
path the recipient
or an intermediary on the return path
the challenger samples random bit if the
bid comes up zero then the challenger
forms the onion o
as specified by the adversary
otherwise the challenger forms two
onions for example if i is an
intermediary on the forward path
then the first onion is formed using the
forward path up to eye
and the second onion is formed using the
rest of the running path
the adversary again gets oracle access
to processed onions and replied to
onions on behalf of ins
however this time the oracles are
patched in the event that b is equal to
one
in this case
the challenge onion layer for i
processes to o prime rather than to a
message
finally the adversary outputs a guess b
prime for b and wins if b prime is equal
to b
an onion encryption scheme is repliable
onion secure if every efficient
adversary wins this game only with
negligible advantage
in the paper we proved that if the onion
encryption scheme sigma
is repliable onion secure then it suc
realizes the ideal functionality of
ropes this shows that the game based
definition is sufficient
we also proved that
if sigma succ realizes f rows
then it is non-adaptively repliable
onion secure
this shows that the game based
definition is almost necessary as well
our construction is called charlotte
encryption scheme
because the onions it generates are
pairs of layered encryption objects
and so in that respect these onions are
more akin to shallots than onions
for the construction we make use of the
following cryptographic primitives
a cca2 secure encryption scheme with
tags
a message authentication code a
pseudo-random permutation or block
cipher
and a collision resistant hash function
each party generates his or her key pair
by running the encryption scheme's key
generation algorithm
recall that each onion is a pair
consisting of the header and the content
we now describe the steps for processing
an onion oi
which consists of the header
e i
v i 1
b i 2 and the content ci
when the processing party is an
intermediary
first decrypt the first block of the
header e i to get the role and the block
cipher key ki
then use ki to decrypt the other blocks
of the header
and the content
finally to make the last block of the
processed header
decrypt
the all zero string
next we describe how to form an onion
using an example
let the forward path be the list p1 p2
p3
and let the return path be the list p4
p5 p6
first the sender alice who is also
p6
picks block cipher keys
k1 through k6 and mac keys capital k 3
and capital k6
we will use curly brackets to denote
encryption
and reverse curly brackets to denote
decryption
to form the header
to form the header h1 for the onion we
first form the header for the recipient
to obtain b31 we encrypt the aux0 string
under the key k1
and then encrypt the result
under the key k2
b32 is result of encrypting the all zero
string under the key k2
the block e3 is encryption of the role
recipient along with the decryption keys
for the recipient
next we form the header h2 for the
second intermediary p2
the block b21 is encryption of p3
the next destination after p2
and e3 under the key k2
and the block b22 is the encryption of
b31 under the key k2
the block e2 is the encryption of the
roll intermediary along with p2's key k2
we repeat this one last time to get the
header h1 for the first intermediary p1
to form the content c1 we first form the
header for the return onion in similar
fashion
then the meta message for the recipient
capital m
consists of alice's message to david who
is also p3 the keys for replying
the first destination on the return path
and the return header
the meta message along with the mac tag
for the message is
encrypted first under the key k3 then
the key k2 and finally the key k1
the onion for the first intermediary
is o1 which is h1 and c1
to process the onion o3 as a recipient
david who is also p3
decrypts e3 to get the role recipient
and the key k3
then k3 is used to obtain the meta
message m
to reply to the
message with the reply message m prime
david computes the content for the
return onion by encrypting m
by encrypting m prime in the mac tag
forked
finally we show that challenge
encryption scheme is repliable onion
secure
that is we show that experiment 0
when b is equal to 0 in the security
game is indistinguishable from
experiment 1 when b is equal to 1. we do
this via a sequence of hybrids
the high level idea is the following
and in hybrid 1 we form the onion for
honest intermediary eye
and then wrap that onion
with layers of shallot encryption to get
the onion for the first intermediary p1
this produces an onion that is
identically distributed to that in
experiment 0.
hybrid two is the same as hybrid one
except that i's key kj
is swapped out for the all zero key
hybrids one and two are
indistinguishable because of the cca to
security of the encryption
scheme hybrid 3 is the same as hyper 2
except that the blocks in the onion oj
are swapped out for truly random blocks
hybrids 2 and 3 are indistinguishable
because of the pseudorandomness of the
pseudorandom permutation
hybrid 4 is the same as hybrid 3 except
that a second key kj prime is sampled
independently of kj
and the truly random blocks in oj are
swapped out for pseudorandom ones
generated under kj prime
hybrids 3 and 4 are indistinguishable
because of the pseudo-randomness of prps
hybrid 5 is the same as hybrid 4 except
that the all zero key is replaced with
kj prime
hybrids four and five are
indistinguishable because of the cca2
security of the encryption scheme
finally hybrid five and experiment one
are indistinguishable because their
outputs are identically distributed
the full proof with all the details can
be found in the paper
to summarize in this paper we formalized
the notion of repliable onion encryption
we defined security for repliable ionian
encryption in the simplified uc model by
providing a description of the ideal
functionality f rows and presented a
game-based definition that is sufficient
and almost necessary for realizing
f-rows
finally we gave the first construction
of a provably secure repliable onion
encryption scheme
this concludes the presentation of our
paper thank you for your attention