hello everyone uh i'm alex beanstalk and
i'll be presenting our work uh forward
secret and encrypted ram lower bounds
and applications and this is a joint
work with the evgenia dodis and kevin yo
okay so uh what is forward secret
encrypted ram or fse-ram as we call it
uh well it was a extensively studied for
a long time
and the goal was to privately and
forward secretly outsource the storage
of a large data array using small client
storage
okay uh and the adversarial model is
that uh the adversary always sees the
server storage
uh and also we want forward secrecy
uh meaning that the adversary can leak
the client storage and in this case
of course everything that is currently
stored
uh
in the ram is uh no longer secure
but we want everything that has since
been deleted or overwritten
to be secure
okay and we also want efficient reads
and writes and for this
work we'll assume a static number of
entries n
okay and of course uh we want to use
practical
uh
uh namely symmetric crypto
okay so what's the trivial solution
well let's say we have these eight
data items making up our data array
what we'll do is we'll just encrypt
every entry with a single key
okay so we have this key k
in our local client storage and on the
server we have
the encryption of each data item under
this key k
okay but
for security then
we need to refresh the key after each
write
okay but of course then this is
inefficient
because we will need to re-encrypt
everything
okay so
there is also a folklore solution that's
a tree-based
scheme
this is how it works
and the client side we again have one
key k-epsilon
and it
it uh it's the root of this tree and it
encrypts its two children k zero and k
one
and we store these ciphertexts uh on the
server
then each of k zero and k one encrypt
their children
and
uh
at the end we have the leaves are
encrypt encryptions
of the eight data items under their
parents
okay
so how do we read well let's say we want
to read the fourth theta item
then we take k epsilon
decrypt k zero
then using k0 decrypt k01
and finally decrypt d4
okay so this was a login overhead as you
may have realized
okay how do we write
to a cell
well let's say we want to write to cell
for new data d4 prime
then what we'll do is
in addition to the direct decrypting the
direct path
to the fourth cell like we did for reads
we'll also decrypt the copath
okay so in addition to decrypting k0
we'll also decrypt k1
in addition to decrypting k01 we'll also
decrypt k00
uh and in addition to
uh well we actually won't decrypt d4
we'll just
sort of get rid of it
and decrypt d3
and we're left with uh d3 k1 k0 we'll
just forget about everything else
and we'll re uh generate a new key k01
prime uh for the parent of d3
and also
encrypt d3 and this new data d4 prime
under k01 prime
okay then we'll generate a new key at
the parent of k01 prime
encrypt both of its children
and finally
generate the new k epsilon prime and
encrypt both of its children
okay and so you'll notice now
we have forward secrecy because
all information about d4 is gone now
okay so even if uh
the adversary corrupts k epsilon prime
well
uh k epsilon prime and everything that
we can decrypt with it
is totally independent of d4 or anything
that could have previously decrypted d4
okay
uh so what was the efficiency of this
scheme
well we had
uh big o of one client storage we go
then
uh sorry that should be server storage
uh and
we go of n uh overhead for reads and
writes
okay
but we can also further extend this to
have big o of s client storage uh
you know for some s that's not too big
still sublinear
big o of n server storage again
and big o of log n over s overhead
and this is done by just creating
s different trees
and storing in each tree and over s of
the data items
okay now the main question that we have
in this work is
is this scheme
optimal and maybe surprisingly this has
been unknown for two plus decades
and in fact in our work uh we answer
that yes
this is the optimal scheme
okay so for the rest of the talk uh
first i'll give you uh some intuition
for the lower bound that we prove
uh and i'll talk about the model in
which we prove it which is called the
symbolic model
and give you the proof intuition in this
model
okay then i'll give some applications of
fs eram where we sort of circumvent the
lower bound
okay and these applications are forward
secret memory checkers
oblivious forward secret encrypted ram
and forward secret multicast encryption
okay so first let me present to you the
model
before i do that
i just want to mention that the cell
probe model
is considered the holy grail
for
private data structure lower bounds
okay but in this case
it turned out to be too powerful
okay so the cell probe model only counts
cell probes towards the cost
of the protocol itself
so not any other computation just uh
how many
uh server cells that you touch
okay but on the other hand it still
requires any adversary attacking the
protocol to be ppt
uh so in fact there is a trivial uh big
o of one cell probe solution
and this is done using authentic uh uh
sorry authenticated encryption
and the the scheme unfortunately uh for
the upper bound will not be pp uh ppt
itself uh but basically what we'll do is
uh when we go to do a new write
uh we'll just choose a random
authenticated encryption key and encrypt
the data under this key
store the encryption on the server and
just forget the key
okay
now any ppt adversary clearly can't
break this scheme
uh
but
when when the protocol goes to read a
data item
it'll just try all authenticated
encryption keys uh which it can do
because it's it has unbounded
computation and only needs to download
or probe the single cell with the data
item
uh and it'll just uh yeah try all these
keys until it succeeds
okay so
here we've shown that the basic cell
probe model is too strong
and what about other models well there's
also the balls and bins model that has
been used to improve some private data
structure lower bounds
but in this case it's actually too weak
and this is because in this model server
cells can only hold encrypted array
contents and nothing else
okay so namely even the folklore
construction for fseram is not captured
in this model
okay this is because we have uh
encryptions of keys on the server as
well
so the model that we do use in the end
is called the symbolic model
and it's been used uh recently in other
works as well
and it's actually the perfect in-between
of these two models
that i mentioned before
okay so what is a symbolic model
well in the symbolic model server cells
hold strings that are arbitrarily
derived derived from some structured
grammar
okay and so in our work uh we allow for
encryption and possibly dual prf keys
which are basically just
uh random coins
uh
also ciphertext from this encryption
scheme
secret shares
and data entries themselves
now uh note that strings can be
arbitrarily nested combinations of the
above
so here's our grammar
uh yeah it incumb
encompasses uh all the things i said
before so like
keys cipher texts
yeah data items secret shares
all this stuff and in a nested
nature
okay so some examples
well we could have uh random coins drawn
from our uh
uh
set of random strings which is
represented by capital r
uh so we could have random coin little r
or little r prime
uh we could have some encryption uh
under some
prf computation
of some secret share of another
encryption of some data item d1
uh yeah and maybe the other secret share
of this encryption as well
okay so now i'll talk about the allowed
derivations in this model
and what i mean by that is
the strings that are derived from this
grammar
don't actually have any meaning uh so
really like
no meaning and also sort of no
representation
uh
beyond just uh being some abstract
symbol
so for example
there's no bits in this model
it's just uh yeah each symbol is its own
distinct abstract symbol with
no exact meaning on its own
okay but this so-called entailment
relation is what actually captures their
meaning
and it's quite intuitive basically for
example uh you can only decrypt a cipher
text
if and only if you have its
corresponding key
uh with a prf key you can compute that
any output of that prf
uh and so going back to the examples of
the symbols that we had on our last
slide
assuming 2 out of 2
secret sharing
we can derive d1
if and only if we have the following
string strings
r r prime
uh this first encryption
and this uh
secret chair right so what we can do is
we'll uh
compute the prf of r and
decrypt this first ciphertext
to get
now both shares
of the encryption of d1
so we get this encryption and then use r
prime to decrypt it okay
but if for example we were missing uh
the second share of this ciphertext
uh
or maybe our prime then we would not be
able to derive d1
okay so as part of our lower bound uh we
define this key data graph
and this key data graph uh abstracts
encodings of the client and server cells
and the data array itself
okay so for this talk i'll only consider
prf
and encryption for simplicity
so what is the key data graph well it's
a directed
graph at time t
such that its vertices vt are keys that
are sampled and still accessible by the
protocol
as well as the data entries at time t
and then for the edges uh we have one
case in which uh
so for an edge from u to v
it could exist if
v
is
corresponds to some prf computation on
you
okay
or also
it could be that
u
is part of some nested encryption of v
okay
so if we have you know uh encryption of
k1
uh sorry encryption under k1
of encryption under k2 of encryption
under k3
of k uh
of k4 uh then for example we'd have
edges from each of k1 k2 k3
to k4
okay uh and also uh
this edge will exist if
such a cipher text was stored in a
server cell at any time in the past
okay
so of course the folklore construction
is easily captured but it's really much
more general
this data graph
okay so here's an example
we have that k1
is stored in a secret cell
and we also have the encryption of k2
under k1 k3 under k1
of d1 under k2 d2 under k2
d4 under k3
and also the nested encryption
of uh
so the ciphertext
which is the encryption of d3 under k3
which is then uh encrypted under k2
okay so this is what our key data graph
would look like for this example
and you know maybe we also have some
other stuff as well
okay so what happens
if
the protocol needs to overwrite d3 in
this case
well it must forget k1 for forward
secrecy
and then it must also forget either k2
or
k3
right
uh because if one of them is gone then
this the
the
ciphertex encrypting d3
cannot be decrypted
okay so let's say we forget k1 k3
that means that the encryption
of uh d4 under k3
as well as well as k2 and k3 under k1
and finally this nested crypt encryption
of d3 all become useless right because
the protocol
itself also will never be able to uh
decrypt
the ciphertext
since these keys are gone
okay so yeah correspond the the
ciphertext corresponding to these edges
are all gone now
okay so now what's the intuition for the
main theorem
well we have this first lemma
where we say that each data entry
must have a path in gt
from a vertex representing an encryption
key in a secret cell right and this is
because of correctness
we must somehow be able to derive all
data entries and also privacy
uh data entries or keys that encrypt
them can't just be stored in the clear
on the server so there must be
something
in the client storage
okay
and now here's lemma 2.
so this is just a general graph
theoretic lemma if we take any graph gt
satisfying some requirements but very
basic requirements and we randomly
choose
a data entry
then the corresponding path from the
secret cell key
has expected out degree log n over s
and this expectation
is just uh over uh the random choice of
cell to overwrite
okay
and finally
we
have our theorem
where
yeah
just like lemma two if we choose a data
entry randomly to overwrite in each
operation
then an expectation the contents of log
n over s server cells
become useless like in the previous
example
okay and uh yeah the the uh
the contents that become useless
each operation uh are unique across
operations so we're never double
counting anything
and i just want to emphasize that
this this is agnostic to
any
random choices that a protocol makes
because lemma two holds for any graph
okay
uh so yeah uh we can just
uh also to take care of nested
encryptions just take the graph with
minimum out degree paths to each data
entry
and apply lemma2 to this
okay so
now
the main intuition uh for some
applications
uh well we'll just focus on primitives
that already have efficient
uh meaning uh big o of log n
tree based constructions
okay and if we naively compose the
folklore fse ram solution with them
we'd get log squared and
overhead
but instead what we do is we overlay the
fse ram tree with these constructions
uh the trees in these constructions to
retain big o of log n overhead
okay so it looks something like this
maybe this is the
uh
other primitive scheme
and this is fse ram and we just combine
them
okay
so the first application uh
is on forward secret memory checkers
so
recall that for
ford's secret encrypted ram we assumed
that the server always returned the
correct stored cells to the client for
read and write operations
on the other hand
memory checkers which have also been
very heavily studied in the past
guarantee integrity of uh the outsource
data array
okay and for fs memory checkers we
require both
so fs
of the data still holds
and also uh the protocol should output
some error
if some tampering has occurred you know
if the server returns uh
incorrect
server cells
and this should happen even
with client state leakages
and what's the intuition
well we'll just simply overlay classical
merkle tree with our uh folklore fse ram
construction
okay so we'll retain uh big o of log n
overhead which is optimal with respect
to both
our fse ram lower bound of this work
and the most optimal memory checker
construction
and yeah the best known memory checker
lower bound is actually big omega of log
n over log log n so
yeah not not quite tight with respect to
that but it is tight with respect to
the best construction
okay so here's what a merkle tree looks
like
basically we we have the data cells at
as the leaves
uh and
each of their parents stores a hash of
them
uh and we sort of recursively carry this
through to the root
okay so each node stores a hash of its
two children
okay
so how do we combine this with fse ram
well if we look at these two children
here
we store uh an encrypted
uh
sorry to ciphertext encrypting these
data items
and at its parent uh we'll start by
storing the hash of these two
ciphertexts
okay and we'll do the same thing for d3
and d4
and then
what we'll do at
node zero zero and zero one uh
excuse me at node uh
yes sorry at zero zero and zero one is
uh
will have
some key so the key
that
decrypts the leaves
uh encrypted under its parent just as an
fse ram
okay and then at the parent of these two
nodes zero zero and zero one
we'll store a hash of both the
ciphertext of the children
and uh
the hashes of the children
okay and we'll just carry this through
to the rest of the tree
okay and for this hash you can just use
collision resistant hash functions
or if you want to avoid the random
oracle model then you can use woofs
but then yeah you need to also include
the description of the hash function at
each node
and also uh the
word size must be polynomial
okay and also note that uh instead of
using hashes
uh
we can just use fsaad
but then uh
we give up on integrity after some
leakage occurs right because then the uh
the
uh basically the mac key
uh
is obtained by the adversary and so
she can
tamper with anything she wants
okay
so uh
yeah how do readin reads and writes work
well for reads it's just the same as in
the fse ram construction but we just
make sure
the hashes of everything we download is
okay and if not
then we output error
okay and then for writes it's also the
same uh but when we download again we
check the hashes
uh and then when we
uh write the the the new keys and
ciphertext to the server we also
regenerate the hashes
okay so efficiency is nice
uh asymptotically the same as before log
n
and for the security intuition well if
we look at the root key in the hash
then uh
the hash
ensures that we have the right cipher
text
uh so we correctly decrypt uh the the
keys at the children
and we still of course have privacy
okay and then we can inductively carry
out through this same argument uh the
keys in the hash decrypted at level i
uh will ensure that the cipher text at
level i plus one decrypt correctly
and we'll still have privacy
okay
so that's it for uh fs memory checkers
now let's talk about oblivious
fse
ram so fs eram
on its own does not require patterns of
reads and writes to be hidden
but of course oblivious ram does require
this
okay but oblivious ram does not allow
for leakage of client state
so the question we ask is can we combine
these notions
well the strongest notion which
gives
fs and obliviousness after corruptions
unfortunately is inefficient
and we in fact show an omega and cell
probe lower bound
which basically means the
trivial solution of
uh decrypting and re-encrypting
everything on every read and write
is optimal
but
we can achieve both modulo client
leakage
and what i mean is if leakage occurs
then we have fs as an fse ram
but the access pattern is not hidden
if there is no leakage then we still
have that our axis pattern is hidden
and of course we have
vacuous fs
okay and we do this with o big o of log
n times f of n over head
for any function that is little omega of
one
okay and this is almost optimal with
respect to
the o ram lower bound and the fse ram
lower bound
okay so what's the intuition for our
construction
well if we use tree based orams then we
can overlay the fse ram construction on
this tree
uh but of course uh tree based orams
unfortunately require log squared and
overhead
on the other hand
hierarchical orms have recently been
shown to achieve
optimal log n overhead
okay but we can't of course easily
overlay the tree-based fse ram
construction
on these hierarchical orams
so what do we do well we just compose
tree-based orms with hierarchical oorams
we'll use uh tree based orams and
replace the position map in these uh
treebase orms with hierarchical oran
okay so i'll show what i mean on this
next
slide uh so yeah first we have the
position map
uh which uh stores a map
of each data cell uh to the leaf in the
uh
tree-based oram that we use
okay and we store this in
a hierarchical oram
okay and we do this because yeah this
this this position map is what causes a
tree-based oram
to have the extra log factor
okay so then we have our tree where we
have k epsilon stored at the root
and in each interior node
we store encryptions uh under the node
at the parent
of data items uh
whose leaf is in the corresponding
subtree
okay and we
uh pad with dummies if needed so that
every every
bucket has the same number of nodes
always
okay and each of these nodes will have a
bucket with a constant many entries
okay
and yeah so to augment
the tree based orm in the literature
with our fse ram construction
in each of these nodes we also store uh
the the
an encryption of the key at this node
under its parent
okay then we also have a stash
which
stores encryptions also under k epsilon
of at most
little omega login data items
okay so how do we read and write
let's say we're reading or writing
cell i first we just look up i in the
position map which because of our
hierarchical realm has a lot uh big o of
log n overhead
then we retrieve the direct path and
copath of i's leaf and decrypt them
as in fse ram which of course is big o
of log n overhead
and then we retrieve and decrypt the
stash which is that most little omega
login overhead
and if it's a read operation we just
return data di
and then continue
along
the next steps
and if it's a
write operation uh then we update
the data
uh at at i so we we
we say we're going to now store di prime
then
in both cases
we pick a new leaf at random for i
and store it in the position map which
of course is log n because of our
hierarchical ram
then we put it back in the stash
with its corresponding leaf
so the label for its leaf
and
then we greedily evict items from the
stash
to the nodes on the direct path of cell
i in the tree
uh sorry it's it's old leaf in the tree
uh where we put a knight an item in the
node
only if its leaf is in the subtree of
the node okay and since there is log n
such nodes of course this is log n
overhead
and then finally we regenerate keys for
the tree
and re-encrypt the nodes as an fse ram
and re-encrypt the stash which is uh log
n overhead
okay
uh so yeah and then uh obliviousness
follows from previous analyses of the
tree based and hierarchical rims uh
but you know basically of course for the
pmap uh we have obliviousness from the
hierarchical rem
and then for the tree
well we we just
decrypt and re-encrypt a random
root-to-leaf path and copath for each
operation
uh and uh also the whole stash okay so
basically every operation looks the same
okay now for our final application we
have uh forward secret multicast
encryption
uh so what is multicast
well multicast a group manager
distributes keys to a group of end users
and these users can be replaced
at which point
the group manager distributes a fresh
key to the current users in the group
such that the key is private to everyone
else so namely
everybody that was
removed from the group previously and
anybody who will be added to the group
in the future
okay so there's a classical tree based
construction
that achieves log n communication and
computation
okay so our application hopes for
stronger security
and recently
there has
the the community has has desired
stronger security notions regarding
state leakage
uh so for example in continuous group
key agreement
we have the same setting as multicast
but there's no group manager
and this serves as the core of secure
group messaging protocols
and in continuous group key agreement
user states might be leaked and we still
want uh fs and what's called as uh
what's known as post compromise security
okay but unfortunately this primitive
can be very inefficient
big omega event communication and
computation
per operation in the worst case
so multicast
can be useful for the sgm setting
where there's only one administrator
who adds and removes users
because you know of course we retain
this nice login
efficiency
okay so in this talk uh we'll just focus
on forward secrecy for
the multicast group manager state
leakages only and
disregard
user leakages for now
okay and as i just said we'll retain log
n communication and computation
and also uh
aim for small group manager secret state
okay and so the for the security what
what we want is if the group manager is
corrupted uh all previous keys
so group keys should remain secure
okay and this is optimal with respect to
both our fse ram lower bound and
previous multicast lower bounds
okay so yeah here's the folklore
multicast construction
we have a tree of keys
user keys are at the leaves and the
invariant that we want is that users
only know the keys at the nodes on their
direct path from their leaf to the root
okay and the group manager stores the
whole tree
so what happens when we we replace user
3 with user 9
well we put user
user 9's key in the old
leaf
then we generate a new key for its
parent
and encrypt this key to both children so
both
uh to id9 and id4
then uh
sample a new key for the parent of zero
one prime
and encrypt to both children and finally
a sample a new root key which serves as
the group secret
uh
yeah and uh
the users uh that that are in the
subtrees
just decrypt uh
whichever cipher text
comes first along their direct path
uh
to to acquire uh the proper keys that it
needs uh to to maintain this invariant i
mentioned on the last slide
okay so our first step in making this
construction
forward secret
uh is the following let's say we do the
same thing replace user three with user
nine and then uh
yeah
at each node we have in addition to a
key
also a prg seed
and the key will actually be a one-time
pad key
okay uh and so
uh yeah when we replace
nine
uh we have a
new seat and key s3 prime and k3 prime
and
we sample a new
seed and key at the parent
and then we just do a one-time pad of
the new key
at the parent under both children
so really also
we want to be able to uh
obtain s1 prime from these
encryptions as well and i sort of just
swept that under the rug but basically
you just encrypt a seed that derives
both
s1 prime and k1 prime
okay but now importantly
every user in the subtree as well as the
group manager
will just uh
ratchet forward uh
the two children here the keys at the
two children uh using a prg computation
on s2 and s3 prime
okay
and so as soon as a key is used we
delete it so we have forward secrecy
okay
because if a group manager is corrupted
then
all all the adversary sees is uh keys
that have never been used before
okay but unfortunately the group manager
still stores the whole tree
so what we do to remedy this is just
overlay our
fs eram construction
uh on the multicast tree which the group
manager stores
okay so
let's say we have n equals four
so four users in our group
well we have a ram key in the group
manager's secret state so it's client
storage
and this ram key encrypts
both
the ram key at its children as in rfs
erim folklore construction
uh but also uh the seed and key for the
multicast construction
okay and we just carry this through to
the
to the leaves
okay so how does a replace work now
well if we want to replace id2 with id5
uh we just download and decrypt
the direct path and co-path of id2 as in
our fse ram construction
then we generate the new multicast keys
and cipher text for this path and
co-path
and then
we just
do the same
for our fse ram component
where we replace the ram keys on the
direct path and regenerate encryptions
of the new keys so both the new uh ram
keys
and also the new seed key pairs
okay
and uh yeah basically security composes
uh
because yeah so
we have
uh forward secrecy with respect to our
fse ram part of the scheme
meaning that none of the keys at the old
sorry none of the old keys at the nodes
of the fse ram tree can be obtained
meaning when a corruption happens only
the current seed key pairs at the
multicast tree can be obtained
and as i said on the last slide
because the keys
will have never been used that are
corrupted
then we get forward secrecy with respect
to
previous group keys
okay
thanks that's it uh here's a link to our
uh
eprint paper and uh
yeah i'm happy to ask uh answer any
questions over email or in the live talk
all right bye