hi
this talk is about laconic private set
intersectional applications i'm pedro
and this is joint work with navida
lamati niko dotling sanjayam garg
muhammad ajabadi and siang poo
in this work we study the framework of
laconic cryptography which is a special
case of two-party secure computation
here the first party or the receiver has
a long input x
it first hashes the input into a small
hash h
then the sender computes a message m
depending on his input y and the hash h
finally given x and m the receiver can
compute
f x y
in terms of efficiency we require that
the communication complexity of the
protocol
doesn't depend on the size of the
receiver's input x
the electronic cryptography framework
allows for secure reverse delegation of
computation as opposed to fully
homomorphic encryption and allows for
communication efficient secure protocols
teleconic cryptography framework was
presented in the work of show it all
where a laconic oblivious transfer
protocol is presented
this protocol can be based on several
hardness assumptions such as ddh lwe or
qr
later a laconic protocol to compute any
function was presented in a work of
quack at all
this protocol is based on the hardness
of dlwb with superpolynomial modulus to
noise ratio
both of these works use non-black box
techniques
which makes both schemes impractical for
real world applications
this raises two questions the first one
is whether we can build laconic
protocols for other functionalities from
from assumptions other than lwb
the second one is whether we can build
efficient laconic protocols
in this work we focus on leconic
protocols for a specific functionality
namely private set intersection
here the receiver has a large input set
x and the sender as a small input set y
in the end of the protocol the receiver
should learn the intersection of both
sets and nothing else
so what do we know about placonic
private set intersection
we know that laconic function evaluation
implies loconic psi but at the cost of
super polynomial modulus to noise ratio
lwe and non-black box techniques
hence we ask two questions in this work
the first one is whether laconic psi can
be based on assumptions other than lwe
the second one is whether we can build
efficient electronic psi protocols
our results are two-fold
start by presenting a feasibility result
namely we construct the lpsi from
anonymous hash encryption which can be
based on cdh or lwb and garbled circuits
construction builds on the merkle tree
garbled circuit based approach
of dotling at all
showing how to use garbled circuits to
perform binary search on a set of sorted
values
the construction uses non-black box
techniques
so as our second contribution we present
electronic psi protocol from phi hiding
which uses only black box techniques
then we show how to extend the phy
hiding construction into a reusable lpsi
where the first message of the receiver
can be reused across several executions
of the protocol and which is secure
against malicious
senders we do this by relying on the
decisional composite residuocity
assumption the fire hiding assumption
and the subgroup decisional assumption
on pairings
as an additional result
we construct black box designated
verifier nesix for range proofs for dam
guard uric ciphertexts
this allows us to prove
that
the plain text
of a
dj ciphertext is within a certain range
for the rest of this talk i'm going to
focus on the blackbox lpsi from phi
hiding
for a detailed
description and analysis of our
feasibility result please check the full
version of the paper
we now describe our construction based
on the phi hiding assumption
our starting point is the construction
of coil at all for one-way functions
with encryptions from phi hiding
recall that in a one-way function with
encryption given h which is a the result
of a one-way function
applied to a string of bits x
the encryptor can encrypt a message with
respect to a position i and a bit b
the decryptor can recover m if and only
if x i is equal to b
otherwise the message m remains hidden
in the one-way function with encryption
by goyal at all the crs is composed by
an rsa modulus n
and by 2l
uniformly chosen prime numbers
to compute the one-way function on an
input string x
we first choose a random
element r and compute g to the r times
the product of the primes p i x i modulo
n
given h a position i star and a bit p
the encryptor first chooses a random
element rho and computes the ciphertext
which is g to the rho times p i star b
then it uses as the shared key
the value h to the rho modulo n
finally the decrypter computes the key k
prime
which is the ciphertext to the
product of the primes p i x i for i
different than i star
it is easy to see that if x i prime is
equal to b
then k prime is equal to k
our first observation is that this
scheme almost yells electronic psi
scheme as we'll see in the next slide
let's see how we can build electronic
psi protocol using the ideas from the
previous slide
let's assume for now that we have a
universe of polynomial size
we will later explain how we can remove
this
this condition
the crs is composed by an rsa modulus
an element g
in the multiplicative group
zn star
and primes p1
pl each one encoding
an element in the universe
let's assume that the receiver as a set
as r and that the sender as a set
s s
with only one element
the receiver starts by computing a hash
value h which is computed as g to the r
times the products p i for each i in sr
then the sender computes
an element f which is g to the rho times
pw which is a prime encoding the element
w
and
a value r which is a randomness
extractor applied to the hash value h to
the row
it sends the
randomness extractor seed s the value f
and the value r to the receiver
now
for each element in the receiver set the
receiver computes a value ri which is
the extractor applied to f to the r
times the product of the primes encoding
the receiver set element except for the
ith position
if there if there is an element i such
that the value ri is equal to r
then the receiver outputs
the set element i
it is easy to see that the
protocol is correct
and laconic in the sense that the
communication complexity of the protocol
doesn't depend on the size of the
receiver set
however there's a drawback in this
protocol namely
it only works
for polynomial size universes and is
only secure against a semi understander
now let's see how we can prove semi on
the security of
security against the semi on the sender
is trivial since the value h in is
indistinguishable from a uniform value
for security against a semi honest
receiver we first replace the
rsa modulus in the crs
by a nor say by a
value n
such that pw divides phi of n
this change goes unnoticed under the phi
hiding assumption
now we can argue that the value f which
is g to the rho times pw loses
information about rho
this means that the value h to the rho
has high min entropy
and thus we can replace r
by a uniform value
now we can change the
rsa modulus back to the normal mode
and we can conclude that uh
and we can replace f by a uniform value
we now show the main ideas
uh
to uh extend this protocol into a
protocol that supports exponential
universes the main idea is to describe
the universe implicitly via a prf key
this prf should map into the prime
numbers
but recall that in the security proof
for a semi-honest receiver we need to
program one of the primes to
use the fi hiding assumption
for that we'll use a programmable prf in
which we can program one of the outputs
of the prf
we now show the main ideas on how to
extend the protocol to allow for
malicious sender
recall that to prove
security against a malicious sender we
need to extract the sender's input
for this we can use general purpose
nesix
to
guarantee that the receiver's message is
well formed
but this
uses
non-black box techniques
so observe that the res that the
sender's message is composed by the
value f which is g to the rho times pw
and the value r which is the extractor
applied to h to the rho
to prove
malicious center security we need to
extract both the values w and rho
the high level idea to extract
both
w and rho is the following we first
perform a re-encryption step which
allows the simulator to extract the
sender's input w
then we switch to a dom guard uric group
and this allows to extract
both
the value raw pw and check that r is
indeed well formed
finally
we show how to construct range proof
range proof proof systems for dam guard
uric ciphertexts and this guarantees
that the simulator can extract the value
uh with hype with overwhelming
probability
let's let's first look at the
re-encryption re-encryption step
here the observation is that the value r
computed by the sender is uniform when
the element is not in the receiver set
in the original protocol the sender
computes the value f and the value r and
sends both of them to the receiver the
receiver then checks if there's an
i such that r i is equal to r and
outputs the element i if the if this
happens for for for some for some
element
we now modify the protocol in the
following way we had the we had a public
key of an ncpa public encryption to the
to the crs for which the simulator has
the secret key
then the sender sends the value f as
before
but now it sends a cipher text which
encrypts
his
input
element w with the randomness r
the receiver computes ri as before for
all elements in his set and it checks if
the encryption of the value of this of
the set element i with randomness ri
corresponds
is the same as the ciphertext sent by
the sender
in the security proof the simulator now
has the secret key for the public key
and can decrypt the ciphertext sent by
the sender and recover the uh
via sender's input w
as a bonus we get perfect correctness
for our new protocol
and security against
the receiver
we can simply
since r is uniform we can simply replace
the ciphertext by encryptions of zero
now for to prove security against a
malicious sender
the simulator since it has the secret
key of the public key can extract w uh
from the ciphertext as i mentioned
before
but there's still an issue
which is the following the simulator
does not detect false positives
for example consider the case where a
malicious sender encrypts using a a
uniform value r instead of computing it
honestly
in this case the simulator will extract
the sender's input
but
the honest receiver
might
will fail with high probability
so to fix this we need a way to extract
the randomness rule from the value f
from the value f
our our solution for this is simple
we simply replace the uh
multiplicative group of zn
by a dam guard utic group
recall that dam guard uric groups
have a very nice property which is the
following given phi of n we can
efficiently compute
discrete logarithms
let's see how we can use this fact about
dj groups to prove
security against malicious senders
assume for now that we have a reusable
designated verifier nizik
which given f
which is g to the a allows us to show
that the the
exponent a is within some range
for a complete description of such a
scheme
please see the full version of our paper
let's see how the final version of our
protocol looks like now all parties
compute their uh values in the dj group
the sender now sends f
and the ciphertext ct as before but
additionally proves that
the
exponent in
in g
to the row pw is within some range
for security against the malicious
sender we can replace the the element g
by an element
g2 for which we can for each the
simulator can compute uh d-logs
the simulator can now recover a rho
times pw and perform the re-encryption
step as before
to show the
usefulness
of laconic private set intersection
we show that we can use laconic psi to
construct a new primitive that we call
self-detecting encryption
self-detecting encryption is essentially
a public key encryption such that we can
detect if ciphertex is encrypting a
special message
let's see how we can build
self-detecting encryption from laconic
psi
first an authority such as a government
publishes a hash of the uh
special database which can be exam for
example composed by illegal videos
then cipher texts
are
encrypted as
with respect to this hash
that is ciphertext corresponds to the
sender's message in the lpsipro in the
lpsi
finally anyone knowing the database
can perform a private set intersection
between the database and the ciphertext
if the ciphertext is encrypting a
message a message
which is in the database then we learn
the message
otherwise we know we learn nothing about
the encrypted message
that's all thanks