hello everyone welcome to my talk
i am jigar from university of virginia
today i will present our paper
polynomial time targeted attack on coin
tossing for any number of corruptions
this is a joint work with ahmed at sami
said mahalo jifar and the muhammad
mahamudi
let's start a collective coin tossing
protocol is a protocol when several
parties try to decide a bit by each
sending out the message
in the figure we show that there are n
parties each of them send out a message
omega 1 omega 2 to omega n
and the protocol takes all these n
messages and returns the output bit b
the output bit b is either 0 or 1 and it
can be biased
that is
it is not always 50 50 but can be any
probability mu
note that there is also a more general
case
when the parties can send more than one
message but in our research we focus on
the simple case which we will see is
already very general and have a lot of
applications
now imagine an adversary want to bias
the output to the result it desires in
the figure b equals 1 the adversary is
allowed to make k replacement
the budget k is the parameter of the
adversary
the adversary in the figure chose to
modify the messages omega 1 and omega n
and with such modification the address
will successfully increase the
probability that output b equals 1 to mu
prime
we call this type of attack as targeted
attack because it targets to increase a
specific output b equals one
on the other hand on target heat attack
just won't mess up with the output but
doesn't care which direction it goes so
clearly targeted attack is more powerful
here we give a formal definition of our
setting in our protocol pi we have n
parties p1 to pn and at rom i the party
pi sends out a single message of mega i
that can depend on previous messages
the protocol returns a bit b which is a
function over all the messages
for our adversary we consider a targeted
k replacing adversary that aims to
increase the probability that b equals
1.
which of course is symmetric to increase
the probability b equals zero
the address rate at each round system
all the previous messages omega one two
omega n minus one and also the current
message omega i
the adversary can then replace omega i
with omega i prime which is why we call
this replacing anniversary such
adversary is also called strong adaptive
anniversary by goldman sachs at all
the adversary has a budget k which is
the total number of replacements allowed
as a illustration our k replacing
adversary act like the following the
address we want to pass the output one
so at round one party once another
message omega1 and adversary decide
whether to replace it or not
in this case i'd rather choose to
replace the message to omega one prime
at round two party two center message
omega two which will depend on omega 1
and adversary choose whether to replace
it
in this case electricity does not make
replacement
and finally at run n
party and sends out the message which
could depend on all the previous
messages
that there is business successfully bias
the output b21
this is an online adversary which is the
focus of this work
on the contrary
an offline adversary since all the
messages at first and then big changes
so recall that b prime is the output
after adversary
let mu prime be the probability b prime
equals 1 and mu b the probability of b
equals 1
we define our address scheme to be mu
prime minus mu
that is how much address will increase
the probability that the output becomes
one
we can now ask the question
assuming we have an mu product of pi
where the number of particles is n and
the original probability of b equals one
before adversary is mu
then with a fixed value k how much gain
can that really achieve
we consider two cases
in the first case message is uniform
binary for each omega i probability of
omega i equals zero and omega i equals
one are both fifty percent
on the second case
the message is arbitrarily long clearly
the first one is a special case of the
second one these two cases are connected
but also very different
now let's see what our question means by
going over a simple protocol that is
threshold protocol
the output bit of the particle follows
the threshold majority function that is
the output of the protocol equals 1 if
and only if the summation of all the
messages omega i is larger than t
we suppose it takes only uniform binary
messages and the number of other inputs
whose summation of omega i larger than t
is the size of a hummingbird
now this simple protocol is robust why
because with budget k the summation can
only change by k
so adversary can succeed if
if the summation is larger than t minus
k
which is the bigger hamming ball
this code even if the address is offline
and can do the changes at the end
we will come back to it later now our
goal is to answer the question that
whether the stress code protocol is
optimal and can adversely run online in
polynomial time
in this paper we showed that in the case
of uniform binary messages
the threshold protocol is indeed optimal
to show that let beta tm be the
probability of b equals 1 for the stress
of t on the empathy setting
for mu equals to beta t n
a polynomial time online attack can
achieve mu prime equals to beta t minus
k n on any protocol which matches the
majority's upper bound even for offline
attacks
and then for the case with any message
length
the threshold is optimal up to a
constant
for mu equals to omega one
we have a polynomial time attack that
achieves mu prime equals to mu plus
omega mu k over square root of n
here is an outline about this talk
before we go to the details of our
method let me introduce some relative
work and also applications of our method
on the uniform binary messages niche
testing until 1989 shows that resource
functions are optimal that an attack can
achieve probability beta t minus k and
minus k on the weaker adversary model
that cannot see the message before
making changes
our attack on the other hand can see the
current message before making
replacements which is much stronger also
we achieve the bound beta t minus k n
which is larger compared to least
testing paper
on the same adversary kalai at all 2018
proposed a polynomial time
attack that works for large k
which is a bigger root n
and it's optimal up to a constant
proposed for normal time adversary then
with budget k equals to omega root n can
increase from which to approach mainly
one
however their result only works for
large k
where what we want is to have universal
solution on every k
interestingly first work has built a
connection between the targeted attacks
on coin tossing protocols and targeted
poisoning attack on machine learning
model
in the two figures below i will show why
the targeted poisoning attack can be
reduced to an attack defined on coin
tossing
the left figure is the same thing as the
attack on the current housing and the
right figure also looks similar is a
learning problem a machine learner takes
the data set as inputs and returns a
model suppose the data set has n
examples and adversaries inspected and
make some modifications and make the
learner produce a bad model
we can then use that have defined on the
left scenario to write by defining a
collective quantizing protocol based on
the learner and let b equals 1 if the
learner outputs a bad model
attack defined on the left figure can be
directly applied to the right figure
our attack of the coin tossing with any
budget can translate to targeting the
points and attack on machinery models of
the same badges
now we briefly talk about the connection
to the isoparametric problem in product
space on the hamming distance in the
isoparametric problem what we want is to
find a set with fixed size that has
minimum boundary
see the figure on the right side suppose
we have a set markers red that is subset
of this green set i define the boundary
as a set of all the elements that has
hamming distance at most k with elements
in the red set
then the
as a parametric problem asks the
question what shape of the red set has
the minimum boundary boundary is shown
as the brown region in the figure we now
connect the coin tossing with the
isoparametric problem on the left side
we see the quantizing protocol sometimes
returns one and sometimes returns zero
on the right side we define our element
as the input which is a combination of
messages
roughly speaking we can think there are
three type of the inputs there are good
ones that lead to b equals to zero which
is showing the large green circle
and there are also inputs that lead to
output one
represented in the red circle
there are wordable ones that originally
output 0 but they are too close to the
case output 1 so an adversary can make
them bad with at most k replacements in
the figure the brown circle is the set
of vulnerable ones
i should be clear from the picture we
are asking what is the probability being
red or wrong given we already have the
probability being red is the given
property mu proving lower bound of the
probability measure of the brown set is
exactly what we want proving a lower
bound on our risky scheme
now in the case of previous methods from
two papers the budget is large and the
probability of vulnerable brown circle
becomes close to one essentially they
are asking how much inputs are not close
to the bad inputs then by the
concentration of measure the whole
measured space is concentrated that is
close to the bad inputs
therefore only a negligible fraction of
the space are still far away from the
bad inputs then the polynomial time
attacks proposed by those works provide
a computational version of the
concentration of measure so we can cause
their result computational concentration
on the other hand
for the scenario we work on the budget
can be small and the probability of the
vulnerable brown circle can also be
small
in the offline setting
when the adversary gets to see all the
messages our problem becomes exactly the
same with the isoparametric problem
but we want to pursue an online
algorithm which is for normal time and
achieve the same bound
which filter gives a computational
version of the isoparametric inequality
so we can call our goal computational
isoparametric so this is the major
difference between our work and previous
works
in the next part we will talk about the
attack on any message list
we first give a high level description
of our attack
suppose address 3 is defined with a
parameter lambda which we will explain
later and also a budget cake
adversary's strategy is to make a
replacement if first have not make
already
k replacements and the second the gain
is large
namely at run i plus one let alpha be
the probability b equals 1
that is defined over all the sequences
follow this omega 1 to the omega i plus
and we let alpha prime be the maximum
possible probability among other
possible messages at this step omega
star i plus 1
which is also defined over all the
sequences follow that
so if alpha prime minus alpha larger or
equal to lambda
and then our adversary has not made k
replacements yet
the others we will replace omega i plus
1 to omega start at placement
at the high level the attack is similar
to the attack in mahalo g5 muhammadi are
19 and semi at all soda 2020 but also
with key differences the main difference
is that these two papers use analysis
that only applies to large k which is
omega root n what we want is to find
universal solution especially for
smoking there are also in in the
mathematics of mohammadi r19 paper they
suppose alpha bar is the probability b
equals one before the current step then
if alpha bar minus alpha larger or equal
to lambda it will reset the input
message otherwise if alpha prime minus
r1 is larger or equal to lambda it will
do the replacement
so our attack has one fewer case and
leads to a sharper bond even for large k
for the sme at all paper they use the
ratio alpha prime over alpha instead of
over prime minus alpha which leads to a
sharper bond
but it only works for large k omega root
n
so why all these people of choose large
k there's a reason behind that these
three papers share a similar core which
makes them all rely on this omega root
and budget
their analysis goes through the
following two steps first they show a
specific attack with unlimited budget
can fix output one second by relying the
first step they show that this attacks
budget is indeed theta root n
so it can be shown that fixing the
output one could require this budget
root end so you cannot improve with the
sim analysis we need a new analysis
to show how our attack works we start on
the case when k equals one note that
even k equals one is previously an open
question
we can then separate all those inputs
into two cases the first one is the case
when the adversary is budget one make
replacements and the second
is the
adversary with special one doesn't make
a replacement
we can show that in both cases
essentially the adversary will have
large gain
we first show that each replacement made
by this one replacing attack immediately
achieves this lambda game
see the path marked by orange which is
originally getting out to zero
but adversely make a replacement to
divert it to this new parts market with
red we know that adversary only make
replacement when the probability of
alternating one is increased by lambda
so suppose the probability of going on
the original path is p the adversary has
at least gains p times lambda namely
if let p1 be the probability of this one
replacing attack happens and the mu1 be
the expectation of b equals one after
one replacing attack
we then have mu1 larger or equal to mu
plus p1 times lambda so we only need to
lower bound this p1 here
however
now we see that when p1 is small the
adversary still gets large probability
that p prime equals 1. now say this
example the green parts does not change
so k equal to 1 doesn't change and
because k equals to infinity is based on
this k equals 1 attack it already have
the same result and it doesn't make any
change
from a previous literature we know that
when k equals infinity the probability
should go close to 1
which means for this part when k equals
1 it already closed one
namely let this er function be the arrow
of the infinity replacing attack then we
have p1 larger or equal to 1 minus mu
minus this error function then combining
with the case 1 we have mu 1 larger or
equal to mu plus lambda times the y
minus mu mass is the error term
and finally
when let lamb
lambda be the c tan mu over root n
we get this bias omega mu over root n
now we want to extend our k equals 1
result to any k the first approach is to
recursively apply the analysis that we
can apply the one replacing attack for k
times however it is only polynomial time
when k equals to one
now there's approach two that achieves
slightly weaker but for lower time
boundaries to carefully applying
induction
let's attack be the infinity replacing
attack that is cut after k replacements
a generalization of the idea of one
replacing attack show that mu k is
larger or equal to mu k minus one plus
lambda times one minus mu k minus one
times this error term
so solving this recursion above gives
this desired bound and the attack can be
made polynomial time using the same
trick as the mathematician muhammadi r19
paper
that concludes the first case on
arbitrary length messages we now turn on
to the second case when the attack is
applied to uniform binary messages
we start by recording the result on the
threshold functions assume each message
on mega is uniform binary the output bit
of the protocol follows the threshold
majority function that is the output of
particle equals 1 if and only if the
summation of all the messages omega is
larger than t
now
let beta t be the probability of that
summation larger than t
a k replacing offline adversary which by
offline will mean that the address
receives all the messages and then make
replacements can only achieve beta t
minus k which is the size of larger
hummingbird
we ask a question how much gain can
online adversity achieve
what we carry is the online expansion
function which is the optimal gain under
the best possible k replacing attack
similarly we can define an offline
expansion function which is the optimal
gain of the offline adversary
the online expansion function can be
computed by induction and
and the corresponding optimal attack can
also be implemented in polynomial time
if y is given oracle access to the
values of online expansion function but
we do not have it it is because the
online expanded function is in general
very hard to compute
so we propose a piecewise linear
function l
the l function is equals to the offline
expansion function at each having both
sizes beta t
and otherwise it is linearly extended on
all the other points
this piecewise linear function is
inspired by a similar function from for
scania or 2021 paper but the induction
proving the lower bound is quite
different in our
setting here is a figure of the three
functions we described in the figure
x-axis is the mu value ranges from zero
to one the y-axis is the atresia's
maximum gain the blue curve is online
expansion which we want to bound and the
red curve is the online expression which
is easy to solve
because we know that threshold is
optimal
now we define this l function
as the green curve here which is the
lower bound of the red curve
at a high level there exists a recursive
relation of both online expansion and l
function and because of concavity we
then show that air is also a lower bound
for the blue curve online expansion
and because the air function achieves
the same result on each having both
sizes with red curve
the online expansion function also
achieved this game
this leads to conclusion that both l and
online expansion is off by at most one
step compared to the online offline
expansion that is the online adversary
with one more budget
can achieve at least same result as the
offline adversary with the same budget
then we conclude that the threshold is
optimal in this case
recall that the optimal attack can be
implemented in the polynomial time if
one is given oracle access to the values
of online expansion but we do not have
access to that
to achieve upon normal time attack we
define an anniversary that approach
means and uses l instead of online
expansion mu
the induction proof still shows that
using l instead of online expansion
works
let's finish our second result finally
we summarize our findings in conclusion
for uniform binary protocols threshold
majority protocol is optimal for online
offline key replacing attacks and for
any case
and this result can be viewed as a
computational version of hypers
isoparametric inequality
for protocols with any message length
the majority protocol is still optimal
up to a constant factor this result can
be used to obtain generic targeted
poisoning attacks on learners with small
budget kit
where any success of training set
thank you i appreciate any questions and
comments from you