hi everybody this talk is about
ring-based identity-based encryption a
synthetically shortened apk and title
security
the authors are parhadapala from
hollyoak and genoa
i'm parha tabla
the identity based encryption is
generalization of the public encryption
that the encrypted can encrypt the
message under the server's
name or identity
the concept is first introduced by
xiaomir
and the construct first construction is
given by bonnie and franklin
the security is similar to the public
encryption scheme
that
in the ibe the challenge at the
adversary allowed to query
polynomially many identities
and they get the secret case for the
identities and the challenge for two
messages under the challenge identity
which is not created before
and receiving the server challenge
analytics and it gets which
message is encrypted under the challenge
activity
this is a adaptive security notion
the construction under the
standard model
uh in the classic uh
in the classic assumptions there's many
uh
constructions
among them the water's construction is
very simple and efficient they use the
drill system encryption
but we don't know their system from lwe
or postcondom ibs compact selector ips
but there's many tries to construct
lattice-based encryption
that is based ibs schemes uh that's as
compact as the selective secure one
uh the iba
that was a first construction is given
by ibv10 which is adaptive security and
their master publication is
lambda matrixes
the
currently the best construction is given
by yamada and
and the construction needs omega log
lambda
matrixes in the public banking
the yamadas construction is the bank
result
and the design is implicit
the natural question is uh can we
construct a better
uh lattice-based i believe is more
compact temperature and without using
the bearing glycerin
and
of course that's explicitly designed
them for the security for adaptive ip
schemes
there's two techniques to
pre prove the
adaptive security of id ibes the first
is that this artificial labor technique
in this technique
the reduction will increase the running
time by one over epsilon squared
without the artificial technique
the reduction can be removed the running
time blow up
but the advantage is we
lose another epsilon
so another natural question is can we do
better
for these two questions in this paper we
will give a better
ring based identity base
uh ibu is more compact
mbk and the best better security
analysis for both this than the without
artificial approach
that's your first rb design
let's recap the ibb's construction and
in their construction the master public
k is consists of
uh l plus one matrixes a and b one to b
l
uh the key extraction algorithm uh on
input the id and the master
secret k
first computes the fyd
like this and using the sample left
using that ta
the chapter of a
to sample a
a gaussian
distribution vector
and added the skid
to simulate the cajon algorithm dot that
must replicate master secret k the
simulator first replace this bis with a
a times r i plus h i times g
a
a gsw type encoding and compute f id
like this
now from this we can see that
if we let the second term
by a
function function of id and indexed by h
i yeah indexed by l numbers hi
then the computation of hfid is
is
is a homomorphic evaluation of this
function
uh given given the gsw encoding of this
one
encoding of the hash function
the index of the hash function
and computes
this hash function and another require
from this hash function is that
we we want this hash function
part
partition the identity space that means
partition
h id star for the challenge identity is
equal to zero
and for other identities uh the hash
function hash of that id is not zero
to satisfy these two uh requirements a
yamadas
designs the hash function like this a
times id plus b mod a rho
a b rows are omega log lambda bits
and they should and ensure that this
hash function is
a partition function
besides and
but the homomorphic evaluation of this
function
needs varying points 0
so now we show that
improve this hash function we designed a
hash function a new hash function that's
only need omega load one ring vectors
because
the yamaha scheme needs omega lambda
bits and encode h bits
so
the master public gains in yamada's
scheme is omega log lambda ring vectors
or matrix
so improve them
let's see our design
first of all we let's see a result from
fl afl
they said that
if a hash function
satisfies the two probability
properties the first is hash of x is
equal to zero
uh this probability is one over a
and the condition probability for two x
one different x one x two the
conditional d uh probability is equals
uh smaller than one over b where a is
larger than b
and b is larger than q
then
there is a partitioning this hash
function will partition
the x
and the axis in the queue
is a noticeable probability that is a
different definition of the partitioning
so our goal is to construct the hash
functions above properties that means
a
b
is large enough to
larger than a polynomial q any
polynomial q
let's see a basic design
for the basic design the hash of a z the
input c
which might be a
identity in the identity based
encryption
it's a ecc of z which is a vector and we
choose a randomly choose an r first
place
and a minus a beta i random
element in z p
so it's easy to see that for n is z
the probability of h z equals zero is
equal to one over p and the condition
probability for any different c one z
two is smaller than one minus epsilon
where epsilon is a relative distance of
the ecc the error correcting code
it's obvious that
this hash function is not satisfied as
the requirements of lambda 1
because p is very small it's not larger
than any polynomial
so
a
a intuitive construction is that
parallel repeating the basic hash for t
times
so repetitive times we have a hash
function a repetition a repetitional
hash function
which is edge of the repetition of
height function of z is
equal
at z equals to zero the probability is
equals to one over p to t
and the conditional probability also
smaller than one minus absolute t
uh because if we set the t to a large
enough so we can
uh this
uh these two probabilities is satisfied
for the lambda one
but the the vector we designed for the
hash function outputs of hash function
is not compatible uh with the rings or
the design of ibe
so
we embed this uh repetition function
into a ring vector like this we embed
the vector into the
exponent of x
so we just say one to one
and we have a
the probabilities are straight
so it's this embedding is to be embedded
vector into a one ring element with
small coefficients
which is
invertible
by the design
and
this kind of design is satisf satisfy
the requirements for lambo one
and the a this is p times two is large
enough
to larger than any polynomial q if you
said that p is uh almost because to n
squared and the t equals omega one
so our second uh goal is to
homomorphically evaluate this hash
function
uh to evaluate this hash function if we
rewrite our the final
real hash function like this
uh we write the second term to the
to here and the first term rewrites the
first term like this
if j is equals to alpha i then this j
becomes alpha i
and this is equals to this one
if j not equals to alpha i now
then this term is equal to zero and the
all terms is equal and the sum is
uh not relevant to previous one
so now we want to homomorphically
evaluate this hash function
uh if if you are given the
in
encoding of the
index of hash function alpha and beta we
want to homologically evaluate this one
and the z is in clear
so
first of all if we given the encoding of
beta i like this
then we can multiply evaluate the first
term
by the
addition probability of the gsw type
recording
and then and we saw that if we given the
encoding of
this equality test j equals to gamma
alpha i
because i and j is insecure so this term
is in clear so we only need to
homogeneity register
if we give us a homo evaluation system
then we can homogenously evaluate whole
height function
so our goal is to given the encoding of
alpha i which is indexing the hash
function
and j which is insecure
and we want to homomorphically evaluate
j
whether it's j equals to alpha
he calls this the homophobic taste
and
for this goal the previous approach uh
used the bitwise comparison
uh they decompose alpha
as a bitwise alpha one to r5
alpha t
and it was compared with j like this
so this approach needs omega log alpha
for a encoding of each bit of the alpha
for h bit of alpha i including this one
and homophobic evaluate this one and
homophobically compute the
multiplication of jsw type income
so this uh this this approach needs low
load and ring vectors to encode alpha
so
we think we can can we do better
we have an observation for the ring r
because it's a x to the x to the n plus
one
if the a f x a
if f is equal to this uh this polynomial
i want to v to the v to m to 1 n minus 1
if v equals 1 then this uh m terms so
it's equal to m if v not equals to one
then the term is equal uh the numerator
is equal to zero and denominator is not
zero so the whole term is equal to zero
if if we evaluate the the function at x
to the i then if x equals zero which
means x to the i equals to one so the
the function value is equal to m and
if i not equals to i
then v not equals the
one and the function value is not equal
to zero
so observing this one uh if if you are
given the encoding of f x to the alpha
minus j the encoding is jsw encoding of
this one so we can
we can homomorphically evaluate this
polynomial and we got the encoding of
this one
so
uh multiplying a uh homologous
multiplying m inverse so we get
uh
the homophobic testing of j and alpha i
this testing is only needs one encoding
only encoding of this one we don't need
a bit wise encoding of
alpha
so our testing is like this
given the encoding of alpha
which is in the zn
and j is clear so let's first compute x
to the alpha
minus one encoding of this one by
encoding of x to the alpha times x to
the minus j
because j is in secure and then compute
the homologically evaluate the f
function and we got the encoding of this
one
and then we compute the m m inverse oh
that might be m inverse
so here and we got i've got this one
if j is equal to alpha then this term
equals to 0
and the
and the x to the 0 is equal to 1 and the
f function at the
evaluation of f is one equals to m and
the computing by m2 inverse which was
the encoding of one otherwise it was
encoding of zero so we perfectly done
the homomorphic evaluation
so now we finish the homophobic
evaluation of our hash function and the
design of harsh function
so by the way we
we see the
application of this cut this type of
equality testing
given the encoding of x to the alpha we
want to unpack that must be you know
unpacked
for alpha and we get every encoding of
alpha by homophobic evaluating b and j
where j is the
eye speed of j is one
so in this type if uh
if the i speed of alpha is one
then there's one j is equals to
alpha
and we got this homological lesson
equals one and the whole
addition will get the encoding of 1.
if the encoding is with 0 then
each evaluation of this one
all gets a increase of 0 and
and sum equals will get a encoding of
zero
and we get a packing given the encoding
of every rfi we can pack
pack them to get a encoding of alpha
like this
a straight a straight uh application of
this encoding is that we can improve the
mpk size of the ipe in yamada followed
by a factor of load lamp straightly
so this is an another
application so let's see our uh
construction the contraction is uh very
similar to the previous constructions
tryptophan constructs the a and r ta the
triple f a
and then uh
generate the bi
the t and the where's a atom is some
constant
and the t
uh vectors like this
and msk is the ta k generation and
homomorphically evaluates the hash
function this is circuit of hash
function
segregatedly
and then
using sample left
ta is the chapter and you get a r which
is a
uh
let this
uh as a gaussian distribution vector
underline this
and r is secret k the encryption is the
dual regular encryption
that is bi i compute the f id uh in
impression
and then compute the bi bid using a
public evaluation of fid
which is similar to the previous k
generation algorithm
and then i use the
uh dual encryption to
encrypt the message mu a decryption is
similar to the geodragon encryption
so that is our design
next we see our
oh
so over
[Music]
or there's a t is we got the t is uh
equals to omega one so our design only
needs omega one
uh ring vectors so let's next see our
better security analysis
here we recall a bit security framework
of mixing so underwater
where
where we allow the adversary output
a boat
he get aboard the mess the whole
game
which is different from the previous uh
previous security analysis
and uh if that alpha is not avoiding
probability and beta is a
conditional success probability then the
advantage of address every is epsilon
equals to alpha times 2 to beta minus 1
squared
there is a
a
as theorem given
that if
uh which is very intuitively
correct in the
surgical distance
that if we replace a uh
distribution p with a q
then the output
the non-abort probability
is
not affected by p and
uh the success paragraph they are also
very close to the previous beta
under the distribution p
this is very important in our security
analysis
and let's see the secretary first game
one is original game and the probability
is alpha zero for one game one in the
game one the challenger choose a random
partition function h
by random indexing with a
uh
the challenger may use the other
artificial technique or without
artificial eyebrow technique
where the
lambda file is
the estimation of
gamma the gamma is a partitioning
probability
let's just skip this uh analysis for a
moment
uh
for game one the game uh game one to
game three
game two uh we use a
leftover hammer because we replace the
bij with the jsw encoding and which is
statistically the clause
again to the game three we use a sample
left to sample right
because
uh
because we can compute our id by a
trapezo
because we have our rijs
and the hash function
and our five beta the challenger knows
all the all these steps so you can check
about this one and get our id
and compute the skd using champ uh
sample left using the rid which is uh
this is a secret idea for
for for
for the matrix
a chapter for this matrix and we know
that
then the simulated simulator uh can
simulate the k gen without the ms msk
game four is using this rear-end
algorithm
by the
hash function
because the hash function
hash value of
h i d star is equal to zero
and the randomized uh properties of
three rain we can get that
the game's game three and game two is
statistically close
and again because we replace the c1
with a random
uh random element
by the random randomness of real lovely
this game before and game series is
closed so we got game one to game four
is close
so let's come back to game zero the game
one that
that gamma is equals to the
partitioning probability
we get
we have a llama which says that alpha
one which is not about probability at
game one
is larger than gamma mean which is a
lower bond of the estimation of gamma
times a alpha 0 and the beta 1 is larger
than the rate of gamma mean over gamma
max gamma makes the upper bound of
estimation of gamma times the beta 1.
so if that the gamma mean
over gamma max x equals to one over one
minus theta zero over four then epsilon
one is equals two
is
uh larger than epsilon zero times gamma
mean over four
over gamma zero is equal to
2 times beta 0 minus 1.
so we get this one
and
if the challenger uses this artificial
technique and it said gamma mean
the lower bound of the estimation of
gamma equals to 1 over 2 q and gamma max
is 1 over q the greater is 1 over 2.
if we want to increase this ratio to
this one
we need a 1 over delta square that are
zero square samples
by current of bond and which is smaller
than one over the epsilon zero and the
absence the previous reductions need one
over epsilon zero squared so over
reduction if using this uh artificial
bore technique or reduction is better
than previous reductions
if the challenge is without artificial
technique
and set the gamma mean
over gamma max is as it
third zero over four q
then the ratio is exactly what we wanted
uh but the reduction will lose at delta
zero
because
the previous account epsilon one is
larger than the gamma mean times
epsilon zero but the previous uh
coupling with the previous reductions
the factor is
epsilon zero and our factor is epsilon
zero squared so our
reduction is better
so in this paper we give a better
ibs scheme with better
muscle public case
and explicit design and a better
reduction
so thank you
thank you for time