okay i'll be discussing this work called
secure quantum computation with
classical communication
uh and this is a work about the notion
of secure multi-party computation which
studies the setting where we have
multiple parties each with a private
input x i that wish to compute some
public circuit c over their private
inputs um by communicating with each
other and all learning um the output y
okay and so we don't want
these private inputs to be leaked to
other parties and so for security more
formally we say that um
any adversary that corrupts any subset
of these parties so for example uh party
two and party three that they won't
learn anything about the honest party
inputs x1 or x4 except what they
already could have learned from just the
output of the circuit
okay and this is you know
a very well studied notion it goes back
um the study of mpc goes back to kind of
near the beginning of modern
cryptography
and um
you know another notion that's been
studied at least now for a couple
decades is um
uh it's the generalization of mpc to
this the setting of multi-party quantum
computation which is uh where every
party can be quantum
and maybe they each have quantum inputs
and they want to compute a
quantum functionality over their inputs
okay and you can define security in the
same way
okay
but
the starting point for this work is
noticing that so far
npc has really been studied in one of
these two settings either like every
party is classical
or every party is quantum okay
um
but i mean
you know quantum technology is
seemingly quite difficult to to
construct so
for the time being uh it's going to be
the case that there's only going to be a
few quantum computers out there in the
world right so a pretty natural question
uh to ask is well can we um you know
achieve npc or can we do npc can we
achieve any notion of it um when we have
some mixture of classical and quantum
parties right
um so can we do some like secure can we
can we do npc for quantum
functionalities where not every quantum
or not every party has to be quantum
right
so
uh for example
um you could consider the this following
notion where we maybe have one quantum
server uh the party one that's
interacting with a bunch of classical
clients and they all want to come
together to compete some quantum
functionality over their private inputs
okay
and so this is the type of notion that
um i like to study in this work
and so we can again define security the
same way an adversary that corrupts any
subset of parties like including like
collusions between clients and server uh
that they won't learn anything about the
honest party's inputs
okay
um
right so
this is what uh this work studies and
the starting point is some prior work on
kind of protocols that can be uh you
know that can be interpreted as
basically like single client single
server um two-party protocols right so
in this setting we have like one one
client with a quantum circuit
queue um classical input x so this
client is classical we have a quantum
server
and uh you know they interact back and
forth and at the end of this interaction
the quant the client outputs q of x okay
and
um in particular i want to cover you
know mention two protocols that were
constructed a couple years ago for this
setting so mahadev in 2018
gave a protocol for quantum fully
homomorphic encryption
okay
which
basically achieves the cryptographic
notion of blindness in the setting which
means that a malicious server is not
going to be able to learn the client's
input x
while interacting in this protocol
okay
so another cryptographic notion that you
could uh or another security notion uh
that you could hope for is kind of more
of a correctness notion which means that
the malicious server cannot cause the
client to output a false outcome and
indeed mahadevan 2018 constructed this
protocol called classical verification
of quantum computation that achieves
exactly this so i'll call this soundness
where a malicious server cannot cause
the client to output um a wrong output y
not equal to q of x okay you know so
prior to this work there exists these
two these two protocols
uh two different protocols in this kind
of like single client single server
setting okay
but if we want to achieve like the full
full notion of secure computation um or
mpc
it really requires a protocol that
achieves both blindness and soundness
simultaneously parties need to hide
their inputs from other parties and they
need to be
ensured of the correctness of the output
okay so we need kind of one protocol
that combines both of these
okay
so
you know let's try to do that
actually so
let's look at like this let's look more
closely at first this this blind like
qfhe protocol right and so syntactically
what happens is there's only a two
message protocol
you know the client will just kind of
choose a public key um we'll encrypt
their input x under the public key send
it to the server the server will
evaluate the functionality under the
encryption and then return the evaluated
cipher text back to the client which the
client can then decrypt okay
so this is the syntactically what qfhe
is syntactically what cvqc is the the
sound notion um here i'll give kind of
an example of like what a two message
protocol could look like but in general
it could be more than two messages
here we have a client that
you know constructs some public
parameters based on
the circuit and their input and
we have no notion of hiding for these
public parameters they could include
like in the clear descriptions of q and
x right
but
what the server can do is run some like
prove algorithm that that outputs
uh the evaluated circuit q of x along
with uh some proof of correctness and so
now the ver the client can go and verify
that this proof is correct if it is then
they will happily output q of x and
otherwise they're going to abort so this
is this is the um syntactically what the
cbqc protocol looks like
so
recall that basically as a first step we
just want to combine both protocols we
want to get a notion of both blindness
and soundness at the same time okay so
there's a really natural way to try to
do this like let's simply run
the cvqc protocol under the hood of a
quantum fhe okay
so i'll call this like a blind cvtc
protocol and again you know what does
this look like the client just chooses
some public parameters encrypted under
the fhe public key and now this the
server can evaluate the proving
algorithm under fhe give it back to the
client
the client then just does two steps
right first it decrypts the ciphertext
to get to the q of x along with the
proof then it verifies the proof
okay so this seems like a pretty
reasonable protocol that would that
achieves both blindness and soundness at
the same time
right
okay
so let's try to use this protocol um to
you know construct what i you want to
construct one what i mentioned that i
wanted to construct at the beginning of
this talk right which is just a you know
a notion of npc between multiple
classical clients and one quantum server
okay
so let's say we have three classical
clients we have one quantum server
um a pretty natural idea now is to say
well let's use classical npc
to emulate a single client interacting
in this like client this blind cvqc
protocol that i just mentioned okay
so they're going to basically use
classical npc to become a single client
that has you know as input the
concatenation of the three private
inputs of these parties okay and what
does this look like then they can
interact with the server right they can
encrypt these inputs
in the blind cvc protocol the server can
run the the prove algorithm under qfhe
and then they can use classical npc to
kind of uh
you know decrypt and verify the output
and then all these clients can either
output like you know the correct output
or in a book
okay
so
right so this is i don't know
like are we done this is like this is uh
the first attempt basically it's saying
like well let's just put blind cb let's
just put qfhe cvqc together let's put
classical npc on top of it does this
give us actually what we want like a
protocol
for secure npc
um
and so it turns out that it's not the
case there's actually an attack on this
protocol
okay
and to see this uh let's say that like
all buts uh one client are corrupted
okay so the server is corrupted and
they're colluding with you know some
some client okay
so
um
since the server is corrupted what they
can do is they can you know
they can produce a false proof here and
they can do this under the fhe okay so
what is the server going to do
like under this fhe they're going to
compete a valid proof like how an honest
prover would would compute it
uh depending on like whether
like depending on the
uh the input x3 so this is the honest
party's input x3 and the server can kind
of operate on this input under fhe right
so let's say they can compute a valid
proof of x3 is equal to zero and an
invalid proof of x3 is equal to one
but what does this mean
that means that when the clients like
kind of decrypt the output they'll see
the correct output q of x1 x2 x3 if x3
is equal to zero and on the other hand
they'll see a bot or an abort if x3 is
equal to one
and you know recall that like these
clients can see this output and so you
know this means that this adversary like
this adversarial clients
can completely learn any bit of x3 just
based on the output of this protocol
okay
you know so this is kind of an attack
that completely breaks the security of
the protocol any more generally like
kind of any predicate on any honest
party's input can be
can be learned using you know this is
basically what's called a selective
abort attack
okay
um
all right
so the takeaway um is that really if you
just
just try to match together standard
blindness and soundness it's not going
to be sufficient for for building
achieving like the full notion of of npc
okay
in particular what it really boils down
to is that we need this notion of
blindness to hold even if the server can
observe
whether the client accepted its proof
okay
um
like you know note that like what we
just
the problem with what we just saw is
that like the adversary or like the
approver as as soon as like we allow
them to see like what the honest client
or honest client's output um as soon as
we allow that then they could kind of
use that information to break privacy
okay so we need to explicitly prevent
this from happening
um and
this sort of thing can be um can be
captured via you know what i via the
notion of um what i call a composable
blind cbqc
and this is like basically a blind cvqc
protocol that satisfies a or
a particular ideal functionality okay
this ideal functionality is going to be
parameterized by the public circuits
queue
it's going to take a private input from
the client and just a bit b from the
server indicating whether the server is
being honest or malicious okay if the
server is being honest it'll just output
key of x honestly back to the client if
the server is being malicious it'll just
abort okay
and so
so what does it mean to emulate this
like or to satisfy this this ideal
functionality that means if we have a
protocol between a client and a server
kind of like a real world protocol here
where the client you know has some
output y the adversarial server has some
arbitrary output
quantum state psi
then
um
you know this output is going to be
indistinguishable from a execution in
this idealized world right where the
client just all they do is they submit
their input x to this ideal
functionality
there's a simulator that just inputs to
ideal functionality whether this whether
the
server is being honest or malicious and
then the client's output is determined
by the idea functionality
and so we want to say these are you know
these are indistinguishable and this
really captures this this notion of um
the stronger notion of blindness
um really because
note that like basically whether the sim
whether um
the server is being honest malicious or
malicious like this bit um cannot depend
at all on um the client's input x okay
so they cannot um determine whether or
not the client aborts based on the
client's input and that's kind of like
captured within
this this real ideal world
paradigm for implementing this ideal
functionality okay
so
you know the i guess the
the goal of the rest of this talk is to
basically discuss how to
construct such a composable blind cvqc
before i do that i'll just give a little
bit of
you know i'll note that actually this is
this notion has been studied before
so in particular
this work of 2014 showed that um
there are a couple protocols
of
mormon fk 17
that are composable blind and sound
delegation protocols in the setting
where the verifier is quantum but
performs limited quantum operations okay
and these are protocols that achieve
information theoretic security okay so
these are like basically protocols
between a limited quantum verifier and a
fully quantum
server okay and you want to achieve both
like compo both blindness and soundness
and in a composable way okay so this is
this notion has been studied before
um and more recently so gv and 19
actually what they they did construct a
composable blind classical verification
of quantum computation protocol
which is exactly the notion that i'm
interested in
assuming quantum hardness of learning
with errors
except that they do have like their
their security is kind of is
non-standard in the sense that they
don't achieve and they don't achieve
like standard negligible security okay
in particular like the difference
between that real and ideal world is
going to be some inverse like you could
distinguish them with something
responsible probability and where that
polynomial grows with the communication
complexity of the protocol okay and
moreover their their protocol um
is highly interactive and takes part
only many rounds okay
so that's kind of the prior work um
[Music]
so now i can really say what the main
results of this work are
and the main technical contribution is
this are new constructions of this
composable blind cbqc
primitive and in particular we do we
obtain like a four message protocol
that's like fully you know negligibly
secure
from the quantum hardness of learning of
theirs
and we can also compress it to two
messages and even kind of distribute the
setup among multiple parties um
again from
qlwe but um also
operating in the quantum mechanical
model okay
um and so this is again this is the main
technical contribution the main
applications is to show
then how to use like these composable
blind cvtc protocols to construct mpc um
between quantum and classical parties as
i mentioned at the beginning of the talk
right and so our protocols are going to
be
you know
we're starting the notion of like
militia security um although we're going
to
allow
for you know
execution in the crs model where you can
have a a common random string setup
and the functionalities that our
protocols are going to support
is what i call like pseudo-deterministic
quantum functionalities okay so these
are quantum functionalities that have
classical inputs and outputs
and that are like pseudo-deterministic
in the sense that for each for each
input
um
there's going to be one
one output that's output by q except
with negative probability okay
and so
like there's various settings that that
we study so
one setting is where we have multiple
classical clients and one quantum server
and you know they all want to interact
and then all the clients want to output
the result of the circuit and we give a
six round protocol from qlwe and we can
also give like a three round protocol
basically like one round from
clients to server one round from server
to clients and then one round for kind
of a joint decryption um in the in the
qram okay
and then we also study the notion of uh
just this two-party setting with like
one classical client one quantum server
and we give basically what's called a
nisk or a non-attractive secure
computation protocol for the setting
um again from lw and the qram so that
just means basically a two message
protocol so kind of a round optimal two
message protocol for this setting
okay
um
right and so for the remainder of the
talk
i'm just going to be focusing on this um
composable blind cvtc protocol
um and then yeah i would say if you want
to see exactly how
like this protocol is used to build
these mpc applications i'll encourage
you to see the paper for that
okay
and really what uh you know the starting
point of this is is to notice that the
issue
with this previous approach that led to
this kind of abort attack was the fact
that
in the blind cv qc protocol uh the the
verifier when they received the previous
message what they first did was decrypt
and then they verified which means that
like if you if you want to like fully
verify the proof um and be
sure that the proof is being honest you
actually need the decryption key to do
that because you first decrypt and then
verify
right
um and this is
you know what was preventing us from
arguing that like this protocol um
satisfies blindness in the stronger
sense
right so
um
a paradigm that's been useful
uh for getting around this problem like
in the classical setting that's been
used before is you know can we switch
can we first verify and then decrypt
right
um so in this way you wouldn't need the
decryption key for verification and so
like even if the prover can see whether
uh the proof verified or not they might
not be able to break blindness because
the decryption key was not necessary for
for showing verification right so this
is the goal basically can we verify then
decrypt in our setting that means can we
actually use the cbqc protocol to first
prove a correct evaluation of pfhe and
then only after that decrypt the qfhe
okay
so unfortunately it's not actually this
straightforward
and the reason is that um this protocol
of mahadev the cvqc protocol that we're
using actually only supports
pseudo-deterministic circuits q okay and
i kind of explained informally what that
was on the last slide but more formally
q is pseudo-deterministic if for for all
classical inputs x there exists a
classical output y such that like q of x
equals y except with a negligible
probability okay
and so we know how to do like you know
mahadev showed how to do cbqc for such
such uh functionalities
um
the issue is that if like the qfhe
evaluation the thing that we actually
want to apply this protocol to is not
pseudo-deterministic okay
and the reason is that
well
like what happens is that like if you
take a ciphertext encrypting x and you
evaluate it evaluate q on that
ciphertext what you obtain is a
distribution over output ciphertext
encrypting q of x so even if q is
deterministic this ciphertext is
actually a distribution over the random
coins r
okay
so
you know this is this is why it doesn't
like work you can't just like kind of
switch switch these and just like plug
in cv you it to prove the correct
evaluation of qfhe because it doesn't
work syntactically
but
we'll still try to follow this verify
then decrypt paradigm and instead of
directly using you know mahadev cvc
protocol what we're going to do is we're
going to use a
a more recent protocol due to trungath
cllw
that can actually handle in some sense
it can handle like
verification for what's what are called
quantum sampling circuits okay so this
is the high level idea
okay and again this is exactly our goal
is to construct a blind cpc protocol
following this verify then decrypt
paradigm
okay
and before i actually explain like the
steps for doing that let's just
let's just like dive a little bit
um farther into just like mahadev cvtc
protocol okay
and so really
what her protocol is is a combination of
of two sub protocols so one is this fh
fhm delegation protocol and one is
what's called the measurement protocol
which is which which actually makes up
the bulk of
mahadev's work okay
so
this this underlying delegation protocol
that's being used
um considers
um basically a quantum prover and a
quantum verifier
and it supports pseudo deterministic
circuits q this is actually where the
rich just the restriction to c to
deterministic circuits is coming from
um
you know soundness is actually
information theoretic there's no
cryptographic assumptions um the
drawback is that the verifier is quantum
okay and so what happens is it's just a
one message protocol the previous sends
over a quantum state
the verifier
basically just immediately measures this
state in a series a sequence of bases so
either standard either standard hadamard
bases and so this notation is basically
meaning that like for an bit for an n
qubit state psi and an n-bit string h
you basically measure each qubit of psi
in
either the standard or the hadamard
basis depending on whether the bit of h
of i is equal to zero or one okay so
basically the verifier just takes this
the state immediately measures
everything to get a string y-hat and
then apply some classical
post-processing on that to obtain the
output y
okay
and so this is kind of the delegation
protocol that we're starting with
what armilla showed how to do is how to
take um
[Music]
such a protocol and basically outsource
this measurement part of it to the
prover
in the end turning the verifier
completely classical
right
so
you know the a measurement protocol what
it does is it allows a classical
verifier to delegate standard and
hadamard basis measurements to a quantum
improver right so you know now the
verifier has as input it's
it's measurement basis h the previewer
has as input a
quantum state psi and at the end of the
protocol the verifier outputs the result
of measuring psi and h
okay
and so let's you know let's
kind of review the issue with
um
you know this this final protocol is
that this underlying fhm delegation
actually only supports
pseudo-deterministic circuits okay
now i did mention there's kind of a
newer work of cllw what they do
is they
what one of the things that that they do
is they construct a underlying protocol
here that has a couple different
properties it actually supports sampling
circuits q
which are you know quantum circuits the
output some arbitrary distribution over
classical outputs okay
um so that's good because like that in
particular captures qfhe evaluation
but unfortunately um the soundness it's
still information theoretic but it is
relaxed to an inverse polynomial sounds
it's not standard negligible soundness
anymore okay
so
again this is you know um the idea is
still to basically take their protocol
and combine it with the measurement
protocol but we're gonna have to be
careful and try to
you know our eventual goal is to get the
standard notion of of delegation and mpc
with negligibles on this okay
so
um this construction basically proceeds
in three steps
okay so we start with the cllw protocol
okay
and we note that
so in general it only has inverse
polynomial sound as error but if we
apply it to the special case of
verifying a qfhe evaluation
of an underlying pseudo-stated circuit
then actually we can obtain a negatively
sound protocol
by basically parallel repeating it
okay and of course the resulting
protocol still has a quantum verifier
but our second step is then to combine
this with you know mahadev's measurement
protocol to obtain a protocol with the
classical verifier
and right away this only gives like a
one-half sound protocol because of
structure of this measurement protocol
we have to parallel repeat that again
to finally obtain a negative like
finally what we want which is a
negatively sound protocol with classical
verifier okay
right so i'll go like through each of
these steps in a little bit more detail
so first
what we want is a you know
a protocol with negligible soundness and
a quantum verifier so
you know what we're going to do is we're
going to have
the verifier you know take the input x
first encrypt it under qfhe and send it
over and here's where the cllw comes in
what we're going to have the prover do
is you know
basically run the cllw approver
you know to prove
you know to evaluate um the cipher text
to basically an encryption of q of x and
send over a quantum state basically
proving that this evaluation was done
correctly and so the verifier can run
the cllw verifier
to obtain a correctly distributed
ciphertext
right
you know up to some error
you know and the cllw soundness error we
can set to any parameter but it has to
be inverse polynomial so let's just say
we set it to one fourth
you know what this guarantees is that
the ciphertext output by the verifier is
distributed
kind of let's say let's say within one
fourth statistical distance of what it
should be which is an encryption of q of
x so what that means is that when the
verifier then goes and decrypts that
cipher text we're guaranteed that they
decrypt it to the correct value with
probability at least three quarters
okay
so
this is where the parallel repetition
comes in right we have like a three
quarter sound protocol all we can do is
just parallel repeat the cllw protocol
lambda times
now the verifier obtains lambda
different cipher text they do crypt all
lambda cipher text to get a bunch of
like values of y i
and a natural thing to do is just to
have them you know take the majority out
of the y eyes that they decrypt so just
like whichever is the most frequently
occurring y in the set they say that
that's the output and you can show that
basically essentially by turn off it
follows that like the probability that
this output y is equal to the correct
answer is is um overwhelming
um
and i say turn off star because you need
like a little bit
like
um not everything is independent like
um because like for example the prover
could be entangling these states um but
kind of like basically a very similar
argument to just like standard qma
amplification shows that you can
actually get this um turn off
like argument to work
okay and so importantly what we've
constructed
it has a couple important properties
first the verifier like first verifies
right and only once it's convinced that
like you know all these you know all
these cllw sub protocols accept then
they just decrypt okay
so there's no mixture of these steps and
in the end they obtain we obtain a
negatively sound protocol okay
so
if you're called the next step is to
basically make this verifier classical
so let's look at this verify procedure
recall that um
you know due to the structure of the
cllw protocol all this is is all the
verifier does is they first like
immediately measure all the provers
states and some bases h and then they
apply classical post-processing circuits
the results to produce the ciphertext so
this is like the part where you know
we're going to outsource to the prover
using um
uh mahadev's measurement protocol
and syntactically what this looks like
then is that
like mahadas protocol is basically this
forum message like commit challenge
response type of protocol okay
where here so here of course the
verifier sends the encryption of x like
before but then they engage with the
prover in this kind of form message
protocol which at the end of which the
verify either like if their challenge
was zero either just accepts or rejects
or if their challenge was one um
actually goes and obtains like an output
ciphertext which they can then pass to
the decrypt procedure okay
so i'm not really going to go into more
details about how this measurement
protocol works
but this is kind of syntactically what
you get
okay
and because this challenge is only one
bit long
you actually write it like
right now we actually only end up with a
one half sounds protocol okay
so the final step is to boost this
one-half sound protocol to a negatively
sound protocol and again we're going to
do this with parallel repetition okay
and again naturally you know what we're
going to do is we're just going to
repeat this measurement protocol in
parallel lambda times
okay
and so
you know what happens when we repeat it
lambda times how do we define the
verifier well
so you look at all these challenges you
know some of them are zero
if any of the sub protocols were set if
any of the sub protocols um reject on a
zero challenge we just the verifier just
rejects um you know otherwise the
verifier collects all the outputs on
like the one sub-protocols
passes them to the decrypt procedure and
still take a majority of those okay
so again we still maintain this this
crucial structure that there's first
this verification procedure which like
doesn't use the fhe secret key at all it
just like basically uses the underlying
measurement protocol right
it just basically either rejects or
accepts and passes along the ciphertext
and at this point the ver there's no the
verifier no longer has an option to
abort it just simply decrypts and then
outputs the most frequently occurring y
in its set of decryptions
okay
all right so
it basically remains to show that this
parallel repeated protocol is indeed
negligibly sound
okay
and
there is some prior work on showing that
the parallel repetition of these sorts
of protocols is sound
okay and one such work is
is this work of acgh and they gave
basically the following parallel
repetition parallel repetition theorem
okay
they said okay
let's say that your under your single
repetition protocol like over here
satisfies the following property
so the property that
for any you know malicious but efficient
improver p star
if it's the case that they are
almost always accepted
on like a zero round so if you know if
they're almost always accepted when the
challenge is zero
then
uh the probability that they can cause a
false outcome
when the challenge is equal to one is
negligible
okay so it's kind of like if they're
like passing one of these challenges
then they're like um
if they're passing like the zero
challenge with overwhelming probability
then they only have a negative chance of
cheating into one challenge so they're
saying okay let's assume your underlying
protocol satisfies this property
then
in your parallel your parallel repeated
protocol satisfies this property namely
that
you know again for any efficient but
malicious approver
it holds that the probability that the
previous simultaneously accepted on all
zero challenges
and can cheat on all of the one
challenges is negligible
okay so they show that this is this is
going to hold
okay
and so this is actually good enough for
like just basically parallel repeating
like uh
cbqc
but it turns out this is actually not
good enough for our setting and so why
is that
note that in this parallel repeated
protocol if the previous sheets on half
of these one
instances
then i can make the verifier accept a
false outcome right all it has to do is
like change
more than half of these yi's to be some
other zi and then the verifier will
output like a wrong around z right
so actually what we really want to say
is that we want the stronger property
that
um you know for any efficient p star it
holds that they're simultaneously
accepted on all zero rounds
and
can cheat on
like even half of the one rounds still
with negligible probabilities so this is
kind of a stronger parallel repetition
theorem that we want which is what we
show in this work
okay and this is then enough to show the
soundness of this this protocol
and so
i can give like a slightly closer uh
look at this parallel repetition theorem
so
you know abstractly what we're looking
at is is the following situation it's
kind of like a quantum prover sigma
protocol with classical communication
okay so we have a commit
phase like a one bit challenge and then
a response and this prover you know
we're this is all classical
communication but we're allowing like a
malicious proverb to be quantum
okay
and we can set up some notation so
basically the state of the prover after
this commit phase we'll call psi sub p
and then we can associate with this
verifier two projections that would be
applied to size of p which is basically
like pi zero is the projection that
projection onto the space
where the verifier accepts when the
challenge is zero pi one is a projection
onto this onto the space where the
verifier accepts when the challenge is
one
okay
so
what acgh did was they basically
you know a rephrasing of of kind of the
property of the single repetition
protocol that i had in the last slide is
the following
and it's called what they call a
computational orthogonal projector
property
it's if for any efficient p
the you know the expectation of this um
expression is negligible right so
basically that like this prover state
cannot essentially satisfy both of these
projections pi one and pi zero okay
and so this is in particular this this
property implies that the protocol it's
like stronger than saying it's just one
half soundness it's kind of an extra
structural property on on the security
of this protocol but in particular it
does imply that the protocols won't have
sound
and so what they show is that okay let's
parallel repeat this protocol lambda
times so let's sample the challenge um
you know randomly from the space of all
lambda bit strings
then what you can define is a different
acceptance projector for each challenge
okay so now there's like two to the
lambda of these acceptance projectors um
which are basically
um formed by tensoring like all the
accepting projectors of uh you know
for each of the
single
um
each of the underlying single repetition
single instances right
and so okay what they proved is actually
that you know if the single repetition
protocol has computational orthogonal
projectors then all two lambda of these
projectors defined here are all kind of
mutually computational orthogonal
okay
and you can use that to to prove that
the parallel repeated protocol is
negligibly sound
it's not really important to follow
these details but basically
what you
are proving is that basically the
expected value
of you know
of like basically the
um this expression
basically
which represents like the prover
accepting on challenge like
ch right so the expected value over a
random choice of the challenge you want
to show is negligible which you can
basically write out this expression
um kind of square it and write out all
all the terms and what you use is
like crucially what you use is the fact
that each of these cross terms is
negligible due to the computational
orthogonal projector property of the
underlying protocol okay so this is what
acgh showed
so in our setting
you know we would like to do the same
thing the crucial difference in our
setting is that
we have to define these acceptance
projectors for the parallel repeated
protocol slightly differently
okay
we can't just like tensor the individual
projectors together because we have a
different accepting um condition you
know the verifier accepts actually
if you know
um
you know if all of the challenge zero
projectors accept and at least half of
the challenge equals one
projectors except okay and so what this
means is that we no longer have
the um guarantee that all of these like
pi challenges are all mutually
computational orthogonal okay in
particular the prover can kind of pass
two different like projectors
corresponding to different challenges if
the challenges are kind of close enough
and hamming distance
so to very like at a high level
basically what we end up doing is we set
parameters actually we change a little
bit how this challenge is
distributed
and we set parameters basically
so that
it's not that all of the
um
all of these projectors are mutually
computational orthogonal but it's it
still holds that an overwhelming
fraction of them are and that's still
good enough to get the entire get the
final proof to go through and show
negligible sounds okay so we end up with
a situation where an overwhelming
fraction of these pairs of of
projectors are indeed computationally
orthogonal
okay
and so that was just what i wanted to
say like diving a little bit deeper into
the um kind of the strength and parallel
repetition there
um
okay and now i'll just give a quick uh
recap of what i've discussed so you know
the main goal
of this paper and what i was discussing
is to construct a blind cvqc protocol
following this verify and then decrypt
paradigm right
because like this is exactly what's
useful for um achieving what i call this
composable blind cbqc
and you know
such a protocol then has many
applications to npc um in this new
setting this kind of like this new
setting of like you want to compute
quantum functionalities between some
quantum parties and some classical
parties okay
um and so the building blocks that we
use are kind of this qfhe protocol the
measurement protocol and then like
crucially the cllw delegation protocol
for quantum sampling circuits
and again the three steps
were to first parallel repeat cllw to
get a negatively sound protocol with
quantum verifier
then we add the measurement protocol on
top of that to make the verifier
classical um but we end up with only a
one-half sound protocol and then we can
parallel repeat that using a
strengthened version of the acgh theorem
okay and we end up with what we want
which is actually just a four-round
negative result protocol with classical
verifier
um
and that's
that's all i wanted to say here so thank
you for listening