so let's jump right in uh let me start
by reminding you what private
information retrieval is
this is a setting where you have a
server with a database which for
simplicity will think of as just a
string of bits
and a client that wants to fetch one of
these entries in the database without
the server learning which entry was
fetched
and the point is we want a non-trivial
protocol which is better than in terms
of bandwidth
better than the client just downloading
the entire database to get the bit that
it wants
the first solutions were
relied on multiple non-convening servers
but then
just a few years after the notion was
introduced
uh crucial evidence in ostrovsky showed
that you can do that using cryptography
also
uh in the single server setting and
since then there was a ton of work on uh
research and private information
material
in this work we are looking at these
protocols with a little bit of a twist
uh we're looking at the setting where
the client wants any
entry a random entry from the database
not any specific one
but it's still important that the server
doesn't know which one was retrieved
so think of a lottery you have people
registering with the server and
depositing their address telephone
number or contact information then the
client needs to choose a random
participant to get the uh jackpot but
they you don't want the server to know
who was chosen because
i don't know maybe the server operator
will then go and blackmail something
um so this is the type of thing that we
want to do we call it a random index
spiral up here for short
uh why looking at this well
for one thing it's a weaker primitive so
maybe you can think that it's easier to
build maybe you can do it more efficient
or with your assumptions or more
settings and things like that
on the other hand it's also uh
sufficient for some applications
so the
lottery application that i just
described
the motivating application for us was uh
a way to use it in this uh secrets on a
blockchain architecture of the community
from last year's tcc
uh and in this work we did uh two things
that are essentially orthogonal to each
other one looking at rpm as a primitive
in its own right and asking the type of
questions that you ask about new
primitive
and the other one uh looking at how to
use it in the context of the application
to secrets in a blockchain
and i'll say a few words about each of
them
so as a primitive well we provide
definitions but only in the semi honest
it's actually quite non-trivial to
figure out even what is it that you want
uh if you were to define it as a
primitive in the malicious setting so we
don't do that
uh it's not still open
uh we show that it's actually equivalent
to here
so you cannot really hope to achieve it
from weaker assumptions for example
you can build here from our pier
up to a small increase in the
communication rounds
and the bandwidth
on the other hand there are settings
where you can do rpl where you cannot do
here for example one of them that we
show is a non-interactive setting well
perhaps you have a one-time setup
uh before the database and then and
anything else are known
uh but after that every time the server
that server wants to give a random entry
to the client they just send a single
message to the client and that's it
and the specific techniques that we use
have a cute little application to peer
with preprocessing which you can find in
paper
let me give you just a taste of how you
show that rpl and p are equivalent so
this is a very simple protocol for
building full-blown peer out of an rp
protocol
so what you want is appear so the client
has a particular index i that it wants
to fetch but what you have at your
disposal up here so you just run it and
and the client gets some other index j
not necessarily the same as i
uh then it just computes the exclusive
or of the two indexes think of them as
log n bit
strings send that delta to the server
uh what that does is it lets the server
partition the
entries into n over two pairs
and then the server can just send the xo
two bits in each pair back to the client
that's n over two bits and the client
can then get the bit that it wanted
so it adds two more rounds of
communication log n b's from the client
and n over two bits from the server so
it's an already a non-trivial uh
protocol and you can recurse on that if
you want to get better performance
uh let me spend a few minutes say
talking about the application to secrets
on the blockchain so in that context
blockchain is just a code word for a
system with a huge number of nodes
honest majority and a broadcast channel
and in this kind of a setting we want to
implement mpc as a server or vss as a
service if you would
uh and it's important that the
communication is sub-linear in number of
nodes because the number of nodes is
huge
uh so a natural thing to try is to have
the work done by a small random
committee which is sub sample from the
entire universe
but we want resilience against some kind
of a mobile address at least a mobile
fail stop i just say that as soon as it
knows that some node has a role it can
kill it with a denial of services
and the approach is to run a dynamically
changing set of committees
where each committee is anonymous to the
adversary until they do the job then
they broadcast a message uh and then
they're off the the hook so there's no
point in the adversary trying to kill
them anymore uh it also goes by the
code name yoso which was a paper from
crypto this year
uh but when you want to implement this
thing there is a challenge and you need
to
to make it possible for people to send
messages to future committees so anybody
should be able to send an encrypted
message to the if party in the next
committee but without actually knowing
who that is
uh and how to establish these uh
channels is difficult and the difficult
part is to actually choose who is the
target of that channel this anonymous
channel
and the way you can do that
uh
is
you can actually run an rpl under an mpc
so that way you get sub-linear
communication because the rpl has
a lot not a lot of communication
and you get anonymity against the
adversary because this previous
committee was mostly honest and the
other side doesn't know what the
committee as a whole chose
uh let me just mention that here you
require uh
rpo with small client circuit
which is almost the same as a small
bandwidth but not exactly the same but
this is it's a little bit stronger
requirement
um okay that's all i wanted to say thank
you this uh available on it
[Applause]
any questions
okay are there any questions in the chat
no not currently
okay
okay so the second talk is on forward
secret encrypted ram lower bounds and
applications
by alex and joint work with evgeny and
kevin and alex
okay yeah uh thank you for the
introduction uh thanks for coming to my
talk uh so first uh
okay so what is forward secret encrypted
ram or fse ram uh well it's a primitive
that has been extensively studied for
the past few decades
and basically the goal is to privately
and forward secrets secretly outsource
the storage of a large data array using
small local client storage
so what does this mean uh more
specifically the adversary
always sees the server storage
and we want forward secrecy meaning that
if the adversary additionally leaks the
client storage
although everything that is currently
stored will of course be revealed uh we
want everything that has since been
overwritten or deleted uh to be secure
okay and of course we want efficient
reads and rights
and we want to use practical
namely symmetric crypto
okay so yeah there's a folklore solution
that has existed for a long time
uh and so if we have eight data elements
in our array like this
uh basically we have a tree based
solution where
the client stores this key k epsilon uh
at the root
uh and it encrypts its two children
k zero and k one and we store these
ciphertexts on the server
and then we go down the tree so k0
encrypts
keys at its two children as well
until we have basically at the leaves
encryptions of the data
by the keys
at their parents and
yeah basically we store
this whole tree
except for the root on the server and
the client uh stores this route
okay so how do we read let's say we want
to read element four and of course we
just simply download the uh ciphertext
on the direct path
uh of cell four to the root and just
decrypt down the path
okay so of course this is nice
logarithmic overhead
and now how do we write so let's say we
want to overwrite the fourth cell with
data d4 prime
basically we just decrypt the code path
so we get these
green guys here
forget everything else and then just
resample the keys so k zero one prime k
zero prime and k epsilon prime and just
re-encrypt uh uh the two children of all
these keys uh replacing d4 prime uh of
course
okay so of course this is also uh
logarithmic complexity
uh and
of course we have forward secrecy
because
all information on d4 is gone since you
know the parent
the key at the parent of d4 is gone and
inductively up the tree uh everything
along the path is gone
okay so uh for efficiency uh if we
assume we have client storage big-o of s
meaning
the client can store
s keys then basically we can just have
s of these trees and we have big o of n
server storage and
log n over s overhead for reads and
writes
so the main question that we answer in
this work is
is this optimal and this was unknown for
two plus decades and our answer in this
work is yes
uh so i'll give some high level
intuition first starting with the model
that we use
so
sort of the holy grail in private data
structure lower bounds is this cell
probe model
but it turned out for our case
that this model was a bit too powerful
and basically so in this model uh the
protocol
is essentially only charged for cell
probes meaning basically the number of
uh
cells that it downloads from the server
but besides from that uh it can actually
have unbounded computation so
there's like a trivial solution for uh
fse ram
okay and another model that's been used
is the balls and built balls and bins
model uh but it's actually too weak for
us
and that's because essentially it only
allows encrypted data to be stored on
the server so for example you can't
encrypt other keys and store them on the
server
so then even the folklore construction
was not captured
okay so instead we use the symbolic
model
which is sort of a perfect in between
uh and in this model
server cells can hold strings that are
arbitrarily derived from some structured
grammar
so this includes encryption and you know
possibly dual prf keys
uh the data entries themselves
arbitrarily nested encryptions of the
above
and also secret shares of the above
uh so yeah we we
encompass the folklore construction of
course and also hopefully things that
are more general uh and also yeah we
don't allow trivial protocols as in the
cell probe model
okay so some very high level intuition
for the main theorem
uh the first step is we abstract the
keys data in cipher text into some graph
and for this talk i will just ignore
secret sharing uh
but basically the keys and the data
items in this graph are the vertices
uh and let's say we have some nested
encryption
uh of a cure data then basically for
each key that is actually used to
encrypt
uh we have an edge from that key to
the plain text so the data or key that's
the plain text
okay uh and so in this graph we'll have
basically s sources which correspond to
the keys in the client storage and n
syncs which correspond to the data items
okay and so then with this graph we
prove
actually a general graph theoretic lemma
on graphs of this form uh which says
that the expected indegree of a random
source to sync path is big omega log n
over s
i mean roughly something like this
okay and so then the theorem is
basically composing these ideas
and we say that uh every protocol must
produce a graph of this form after each
writes
and then basically an in degree to to a
random sync is essentially equal to uh
the overhead needed to
overwrite a random data element at a
sink
okay so in addition to this
lower bound we also show some
applications which in some sense
circumvent this lower bound
okay and so we focus on other primitives
that have uh efficient
log n tree based constructions and
basically add forward secrecy to them
so first we start with uh forward secret
memory checkers
where memory checkers you can
essentially imagine a miracle tree so
they guarantee the
integrity of the outsourced data right
and we just uh yeah add forward secrecy
to this as well
okay then uh we also have oblivious
forward secret encrypted ram uh where
we hide access patterns to the data
and also add for forward secrecy here
and finally uh forward secret multicast
encryption
uh where multicast is basically a
dynamic group key agreement primitive uh
with an omnipotent group manager so a
group manager that performs all
operations
and we add a forward secrecy
to this primitive as well and also allow
the group manager to have small uh local
storage
and yeah i refer you to the full paper
for details and all those
okay and so the naive composition of
basically just doing our forward secret
encrypted ram on top of
the structures
uh already existing in the protocols
through these primitives would result in
log squared
overhead of course
and so then basically our main intuition
is just to carefully
over overlay the uh fse ram tree
with the tree that is already existent
in the corresponding constructions
to get uh login overhead
so i guess just pictorially
if the red tree is the primitives tree
and the blue tree is the fse ram tree we
sort of just combine them to get this
purple tree
okay thanks that's it for today
[Music]
yeah i mean in fact there's actually
like uh sorry can you repeat the
question oh uh he he was asking if uh
the lower bound can be circumvented
using like stronger primitives um and
yeah i mean
so
for example there's like punctuable
encryption which is like
basically
uh forward secret encrypted ram i guess
like a public key version of it
so i guess we we see
also our result as sort of a lower bound
from you know maybe symmetric primitives
uh simple symmetric primitives for these
primitives as well yeah
any other questions
okay
okay the next talk is on iconic private
set intersection and applications
um
who's the first speaker here
okay um yes so
i'll talk about laconic psi
and this is a joint work with navidad
niko dokling sanjay muhammadin
okay so first what is a
laconic psi
it is essentially a flavor of unbalanced
psi
where we have a small crs
and the receiver
on on the right
starts by hashing a large input set into
a small hash value h
then the sender with a small input y
computes a message m and this allows the
receiver to compute
the intersection between both sets
okay so in terms of security as usual
for
psi protocols we want that the sender
learns nothing about the receiver set
and also that the receiver
learns nothing about the sender set
apart from what is leaked by the
intersection
in terms of communication we require
that the size of the crs the size of the
receiver's message and the size of the
sender's message to depend only uh poly
logarithmically in the size of the
receiver set
and in terms of computation we want that
the uh
key the crs generation and the sender
algorithm to run uh also in time polygon
in
the size of x
so we
loconic psi can be useful for settings
where for example the receiver
is let's say a
big tech company
uh with a huge database and it it wants
to perform
psi with users
non-interactively and with communication
sub-linear in the in the size of the
database
okay so what do we know about laconic
psi
we know that
laconic psi can be built from electronic
function evaluation
but this comes at the cost of efficiency
and
assuming lw with super polynomial
modules to noise ratio
so this raises two questions
uh the first one is whether we can build
volcanic psi from assumptions other than
lw
and the second one is
whether we can do it
efficiently so our first result is a
feasibility is a feasibility result and
here we uh show that
we can build laconic psi
uh secure against semi arms adversaries
by assuming either cdh or lwb with
polynomial modulus nice ratio
so how do we do this
we use a primitive called anonymous
encryption together with this gargled
circuit
on merkle tree based approach
used in many many previous works
and in particular we show how to uh
how to uh extend this garbled circuit
approach to allow for uh
to allow for binary search over a set of
sorted values
since anonymous hash encryption can can
be built from either cdh or otherwise
then so does our final protocol
but the
resulting protocol is not efficient
in the sense that
uh it makes uh non-black box use of
cryptographic units in particular we
need to evaluate the uh the uh the hash
decryption inside the global circuits
so our second result
we showed that uh we can build an
efficient loconic dsi
secure against seminoles bursaries by
assuming the fire hiding assumption and
by efficient i mean that
we only use black box techniques in the
sense that we never go to the circuit
level description of uh cryptographic
primitives
we then uh show how to extend this
protocol into a reusable one where the
first message of the receiver can be
reused across
several executions
and which is secure against malicious
senders by additionally assuming the dcr
and the pairing based assumption
and along the way we show
uh how to build an efficient divi music
scheme that allows us to prove equality
of plaintext across different
cryptosystems in our case the
damgard uric and the bgn cryptosystems
okay to conclude we show an application
of laconic psi by building a
primitive that we call self-detecting
encryption
so essentially this is a public key
encryption scheme with one additional
property
it allows an authority to check if an
encrypted plaintext is in a special
database and we can think of this
special database as a set of illegal
messages right or for example illegal
videos
of course if the plaintext is not on the
database then we want that uh semantic
security is preserved
so how can we build this from laconic
psi
well first the authority uses the
lpsi hash algorithm to compress the
database and publishes the ash
and now every ciphertext
is essentially a
this message in the electronic psi
product
with respect to this hash value
so now the authority can use the
receiver's algorithm to check if the
message is in the database
and
because of the security of the protocol
of the electronic
psi protocol it learns nothing if the
message is not on the database
okay that's it
thank you
any questions
can you repeat the question
so he's asking if um
in the last application
uh
if the last application is secure
against malicious authorities and
you done it just from carbon circuits
like
yeah i suppose so but yeah here it's
really about efficiency
okay let's thank pedro again
okay the next talk is on non-visible
vector commitments via local
equivocability by leo venkil and leo
will give the talk
okay thank you so yeah we're going to
talk about non-multiple vector
commitments and this is joint work with
joe
okay
so vector commitments are essentially a
vector or a commitment scheme that
allows the sender to commit to a
non-vector values and then at a later
stage locally open any of the entries
while
retaining the hiding property for the
remaining entries of the vector
the security property that we want our
commitments to satisfy his position
binding which essentially states that
each entry of the committed vector can
only be opened to at most a single value
so for example the malicious sender
cannot
open the second entry to both 54 and 32.
so this can obviously be constructed
trivially by simply committing to each
entry of the table of the vector
separately
so typically we're interested in
non-trivial constructions that are
succinct in the sense that both the
commitment and the local openings are
size which is sublinear in the number
key of elements in the iron line vector
so perhaps the earliest construction or
vector commitments
are miracle trees that have constant
size commitments this constant in the
number of underlying elements in the
vector
and the openings local openings which
are of size which is logarithmic in the
number of key of elements
more recent constructions based on
algebraic or let's based assumptions uh
can satisfy both constant size
commitments and constant size local
openings and they also enjoy additional
driver properties like updatability of
the underlying vector sub vector
openings that allow you to somehow open
to a sub vector more efficiently than
simply uh opening each of its entries
and more properties as well
now a different
line of research regarding commitment
schemes that has been rigorously studied
for the past 30 years
is that of non-valuable commitments
introduced by the left work and or back
in 91 for their seminal work
so with this work we're interested
mainly in non-interactive commitments so
informally uh non-violability of such
commitments uh states that the men in
the middle adversary that observes a
commitment to some value v
cannot produce a commitment to some
value v prime which is somehow
non-trivial related to the original
value v
and indeed as i mentioned this notion
has been rigorously studied and there
has been there have been numerous
constructions from various assumptions
uh satisfying various security notions
and uh efficiency trade-offs
now what has
not been uh rigorously studied is the
intersection of both of these notions of
acidity
overflow
is the intersection of both of these
notions
which is non-malleable vector
commitments
so specifically
uh the existing frameworks and security
definitions for uh non-valuable uh
non-interactive commitments
uh do not take into consideration uh the
security implications of an adversary
that observes some local openings
for the underlying vector before
producing uh what he hopes is a
commitment to a related vector
um and it turns out that you know taking
this into consideration is quite
important and
it somehow disallows
uh some of the more trivial solutions as
we show in the paper
what has been studied is a related
notion
which is called non-valuable
zero-knowledge sets so informally you
can think of a zero-knowledge set as a
vector commitment
that supports non-membership proofs
so the sender can prove that let's say
32 is not in the underlying vector
and non-valuable zero knowledge sets
were constructed starting from the work
of general and mikali back in 06.
um
but one of the problems of all of these
constructions is that in order to
support these uh non-membership proofs
they rely on some intermediate notion
which is called the multicraft or
mercurial predator commitments
and this is a relatively intricate
notion just to define the syntax of this
notion requires 11 algorithms
and the constructions are
complicated specifically to accommodate
this
functionality of non-membership proofs
so this leads over the question of
can we construct non-malleable vector
commitments that do not necessarily
accommodate uh non-merchant proofs
within a simplified framework hopefully
uh simplifying the construction both
conceptually
and maybe even gaining something
technically
so
in line of this question in light of
this question our contributions in this
work are the following
uh so first we put forth a notion for
normal ability of vector commitments
with the aim of striking a balance
between the weaker notion of standard
non-valuable non-interactive commitments
that do not take into account
uh the notion of local openings and the
stronger notion of the normal level zero
knowledge sets which accommodates also
non-membership proofs which are not
necessary for vector commitments
uh and
then what we do is we put forth a
general framework for constructing
non-valuable vcs satisfying our
definition
uh so essentially we show how to
transform any vector commitment into a
non-valuable one
by relying on a new intermediate notion
that we put forth which we call locally
provokable commitments with all but one
binding
so this is also a mouthful but
[Music]
it is a simpler notion conceptually
than multi-trapped or mercurial
commitments
and
it also admits somewhat more efficient
instantiations as we show in the paper
and an important point is that our
construction essentially preserves the
efficiency of the underlying vector
commitment both in terms of the
commitment size and in terms of the
local openings
so all of this is in the extended talk
also in the paper but not in the
extended talk
are a few additional contributions so
first of all
we consider an extension
of our notion and construction to
dynamic vector commitments that can be
updated
privately by whoever produced the vector
commitment
and we also show that merkle trees
satisfy our notion of normal ability in
the random oracle model
uh which is not the case in the standard
model essentially due to the potential
malleability of the underlying hash
function
and finally we discussed our
applications
both for
cross-transaction independence in
blockchains and for simultaneous
multi-run options
okay so with that with it thank you
could you repeat the question please for
those of us online
yeah so the question was what notion of
normal ability to consider or consider
one-to-one non-emolliability or
many-to-one
essentially
whether the
adversary observes one commitment or
many commitments before producing
their own commitment so in this work
we study one to one valuability believe
over the question of the
many to one
nonverbal future
is that like a reasonable notion of
normal ability for a hash function that
would make like a multi-three
uh more valuable equipment i mean like
some properties
so i'm sure that there is we haven't
taken a look at it but i'm sure that you
can some so the question was whether or
not there's like a standard model
specific property of uh of the random
oracle
such that if this hash function
satisfies this uh specific property you
can argue that the resulting miracle
tree is not vulnerable
so you know my guess is that there is
but we haven't taken it
actually i have one one question um with
the notion of uh non-vulnerability with
these local openings that you define be
non-trivial even if you didn't require
compactness in the commitments
um
so it would be non-trivial also
essentially the trivial solution of
simply
committing to each other on its own
my guess is that uh
you know it might still be easier to
construct but yeah it's not trivial
okay yeah any more questions
okay let's thank you again
[Applause]
the next talk is on vector and
functional commitments from lattices
the work is by chris zach and chad and
chad will give the talk
hello everyone
so today i'll be presenting vector and
functional equipment from lattices
[Music]
okay uh well i didn't uh figure that i
would be going after another talk on
vector commitment so i also have a
description of what vector equipments
are um but just to go over it very
briefly again vector commitments are
similar to a regular commitment scheme
except rather than committing to a
single value you commit to a sequence of
them
uh and then when it comes time to open
uh
rather than opening you know the whole
vector at once you can open it at a
specific position um and receive a a a a
witness that uh the ith entry is equal
to m sub i
um we additionally require uh um for
non-triviality we require the
commitments and proofs are um much
smaller than the vectors maybe the
constant size or or poly liquid like
um
and then there's a we have a verify
algorithm
that checks the opening against the
commitment
uh and then the security uh property
here is called position binding so hbnp
is able to open a commitment at position
i at two different uh message entries
uh and then uh um
additionally an additional feature you
might want from electric moments are
what are called stateless updates so
here uh um say we have a commitment to
the vector m and we want to update the
jth entry um we want to increment it by
delta so delta being the the difference
between the old entry and the new entry
um then we have an algorithm update c to
produce a new commitment
to this new vector
and then by analogy there's a similar
algorithm for updating bruce to reflect
changes in the underlying vector
uh then
as a generalization of vector movements
we have what are called functional
commitments so functional commitments
rather than opening a vector at a
particular position we open a vector um
we can prove um
the output of a particular function on
that vector so you can imagine vector
commitments as being
a case where
a case where the class of functions that
we have a functional equipment scheme
for is um the class of like projections
down to down to single entries um and so
it looks just like a vacuum cleaner
scheme except open takes a function and
then when it comes time to verify we
accept if f m is equal to y
uh and then the uh security property by
analogy is called function binding so it
should be invisible to open equipment
add a function
a function f at two different outputs y
not equal to y prime
uh so as for like the prior work the
existing state of things uh merkel trees
um uh we're sort of
something you might be familiar with
sort of the first uh um you know vector
commitment like thing but that we
they're not statelessly updatable um so
so in other words to get a new
commitment to reflect an underlying
change in the message you basically just
have to you know commit to the new
vector you have to know what the
original vector was or where the new
vector is
um
then uh the statelessly available vcs
sort of come onto the scene based on rsa
and pairings and ly10 and cf13
um that there's as far as post quantum
work um there's a sort of merkle like uh
statelessly updatable vc scheme it's
based on the short energy solution
problem
um it basically is a merkle tree except
uh it takes advantage of some of the
structure of the sas hash function um to
give you to stole for stateless updates
um and then there are numerous
applications for ec schemes like
verifiable outsourcing and storage
you've got a space constrained client um
and uh you know sort of an untrusted
database um and uh
the client keeps a commitment to the
database uh and then can you know ask
for updates or you know ask for
retrieval um
and then can verify them using the
scheme um as far as functional equipment
schemes um so that we there's an fc
scheme for linear functions based on
pairings um there are fc schemes for the
with this paper called sparse
polynomials um and there are many more
than just these two for many other
classes of functions um but one thing
that all of them at least the ones based
on vulnerable assumptions have in common
is that they only work for function
classes that are linearizable which
means that every function in the class
can be broken down into
a linear function operating on some uh
like polynomial time fixed
pre-processing of the message and that
preresting is is um
fixed across the whole function class
um so you can imagine like for for
polynomial evaluation that this
preprocessing would be taking like
powers of the
powers of the message
um so snarks for np let us go further
than linearizable functions um but we
can't do these we can't get these from
falsifiable assumptions at least not in
the black box way
um and then you know and surprisingly
there are numerous applications for uh
fc schemes
um so the contributions in in this work
are we give a new post quantum uh um
stairlessly updatable vc scheme that has
significantly shorter proofs than the
other one the psty um and so in
particular here if we have a message
that's of uh um
length d to the h um then we lose a
vector d uh in the proof size um and d
typically if you optimize these print if
you upgrade these parameters
appropriately d is going to be a small
polynomial
um and this this uh savings and proof
size is sort of paid for by larger
public parameters again by a factor of d
but typically you're gonna have one set
of proof parameters one set of public
parameters and many proofs so this seems
like a worthy trade-off
we also lose public setup
um
and then uh we also give a new sas based
functional equipment scheme for
arbitrary bounded boolean circuits so
this is based on the falsifiable
assumption and it goes much farther than
these linearizable function classes um
that i just talked about
um so it's the first based on false
bible assumptions to go beyond uh
linearizable functions and it's the
first post quantum sc scheme from a
falsifiable assumption
however the sort of downside is that we
have to introduce a new model um in
which the uh the trusted authority that
set up the public parameters stays
online um and clients ask for opening
keys which are these public reusable uh
keys that allow you to open the vector
at a particular function
um
so in particular what that looks like is
is uh
if you imagine the the diagram from
before the change here is that the
permanently online authority has this
algorithm extract um clients go to it uh
give it a function and then get back an
opening key which has been fed to the
open algorithm
then there are a few secondary
contributions which these aren't covered
in the
main talk um
we give a formal definition in the
generic construction what we call zero
knowledge vector equipment scheme and
then we do a formal analysis of sort of
a long-standing folklore
merkel-like tree transformation a vector
from in schemes um where it's basically
a miracle tree but rather than hash
functions all the way down it's a vector
complement scheme and so you don't have
to give sibling information to update um
uh to update uh to um
to open at a particular index
uh and then uh there are a few open
questions that arise from this work so
one is is whether it's possible to get
uh um constant size commitments and
proofs um from uh pq assumption we can
get these from rsa and pairings and some
of the other schemes that i mentioned
before but ours are still um logarithmic
in the size of the vector
and then um the the the other broad
question is is can we get a functional
commitment scheme for arbitrary boolean
circuits from a false level assumption
without this permanent online authority
or whether that's possible whether you
know the the alternative would be um
that somehow you can construct a a smart
friend piece from this in which case it
wouldn't be possible
um but that's my talk so for full
information please uh see the paper
any questions
okay then let's type chat again
okay the last stop of the session is on
upgradable public encryption in the
standard model the work is by your
beginning
[Music]
thanks for the introduction
um so as uh abhishek said this is my
point of data for public key encryption
in the standard model this is joint work
with kenny and daniel um so
okay
ah okay so
um so the broad outline of the dockers
we will look at
uh forward secure public encryption just
a quick recap and use that to motivate
the perimeter and then look at further
about the primitive and the
constructions and so on
um
so fspke there is alice and bob
publishes to communicate palace and
facilitate that alice generates a
publicly secretly paired keep secret key
for herself and sends publicly to bob
bob the public
not can update a message i'm not to get
cipher text and descent
to alice in addition
bob evolves the public key from p k
naught to p k one
uh alice s k naught c naught the math
goes that it gets m naught and then
involves the secret key to sk1 this
keeps happening and note that all of the
conversation is happening in the
presence of an adversary eve and let's
assume that e
as corrupted as k2 the requirement of
fspk is that m naught and m one remains
secured um because they were decrypted
before the compromise happened um and
the correctness requirement is anything
that's encrypted by pki is decryptable
by ski
and uh um so pretty much state of the
art is about with by canada at all where
they build constructions from
hierarchical identity-based encryption
but there's always this gap between
height schemes and pk schemes from
similar assumptions and the question we
confront is can we somehow close the
efficiency gap by somehow weakening the
security definition
specifically we want to use ci to
somehow achieve a weaker notion of
forward secrecy ci
in case you forgot this is just a cipher
text and in this talk we say yes and the
idea is basically
the ciphertext for aid in producing the
sequential change rather than naively
contain the secret key themselves and
the security goal that we want to
achieve is
reasonable security even with
compromised senders
um so that brings us to updatable public
key encryption so what is it upgradeable
public key encryptions
um
the setting is another sequence of
ciphertext that's decrypted uh that's to
be decrypted by the receiver we can
either assume there is just one sender
or somehow assume a serialization
mechanism to make sure that everyone
receives a consistent view
um in a nutshell what happens is the
senders will produce a public teaching
the ciphertext will produce will help
the receiver produce a secret keychain
both the chains need to be consistent
and the fact is that the public keychain
is not fixed a priority
um
um so and what's the security any good
ciphertext and we'll quantify good
ciphertext in just a few slides we'll
restore security irrespective of what
happens between
um so what is the primitive update of
the public key encryption as the name
suggests is a public encryption so you
have the key gen algorithm the
encryption algorithm and the decryption
algorithm in addition we have
an algorithm that is randomized and
we'll take an old public key and we'll
produce a new public epk prime and also
produce the update ciphertext up
updates our secret key will take this uh
update ciphertext up and the old secret
key to produce a new secret key um i
mean the colors are basically indicative
of the fact that they are consistent
um
and uh so what is the security game uh
it's uh within this slide we'll look at
something called as indcrc start i know
this the c r is a new abbreviation we
will explain in a few slides but let's
just look at the game you have
challenger give an adversary the
challenger will generate pk not sk not
keeps a skin out for uh itself and sends
speaking out to the adversary
now the adversary responds with a set of
rise
and m naught star and m one star which
are basically the challenge messages
now this is the part that's interesting
is that the char this challenger will
consume this ri thinking of it as the
randomness for the update publicly and
update secret k algorithm to produce
keys as follows so update pk takes pk
naught r1 produces a new public epk1 and
updates ciphertext up one
which is consumed by update secret key
ah to produce sk1 this happens multiple
times
and at this point you have pkq and skq
now this is the definition of good
ciphertext so the other the challenger
will basically choose a randomness r
start of its choice and update public
key pknot pkq and skq to some values p k
star and s k star
so now
the um
uh the address read receives p k star
s k star up star
and the challenge cipher text
the adversity response with b prime and
vincent b prime is equal to b
now there are some subtleties when the
previous verb are in the definition so
uh the work by um just and others they
did not provide for a malicious
randomness but instead allowed for an
adversity to expose the randomness and
uh just
a pedantic point is that the work by
alvin and others uh included mi um there
which is not our definition so that's
why we don't have mi here
uh so what is this start
so this chosen randomness is what cr
stands for so i've ruined the surprise
uh but the fact is that the adversity
chooses the randomness here
and indc rcp star is the simplified
model presented here because we assume
that the secret key is revealed right
after the message
the challenge space however the more
general version would allow the
adversary to also provide additional
randomness to somehow uh evolve the keys
adversarially before finally asking for
the corruption
and we present this strong
more general version of the pool uh in
the full version of the paper and we
also introduced indcr cca which allows
for uh decryption queries a stronger
security model is something called as a
chosen update where rather than
providing the rise the adversary
provides an update uh which is basically
an update ciphertext and a public key
that's consistent with the update um
and this is a stronger model
and this is also covered in the paper
where we discuss imdc ucpa and the cucc
anyway anyway enough of
the alphabet jargon let's look at where
things stand um so we compare all three
axes efficiency assumptions and powered
secrecy um
public key is very efficient they have a
whole bunch of assumptions and by
definition it's
not powered secure uh fspke is
inefficient you build it from hype uh
again a whole bunch of assumptions by
definition is forward secure
and
the upk that was proposed by just others
is very efficient about our sufficient
spke it's
uh forward secure but it has additional
synchronization as we just saw
and it was uh
proven secure in the cdh assumption
but in the random oracle but it will
hopefully serve as a useful launchpad
and i know i have seven minutes and i'm
standing between you and the lunch so we
all wrap up
um so the upk uh
oh sorry there is a session in between
that and the lunch my mind goes to lunch
my apologies um so uh the upk the
intuition that was discussed in the
uh the
random oracle solution the key idea here
is uh
that say i want to update the secret key
by some factor r1
and somehow the update public key will
just encrypt this r1 to produce the
update ciphertext and the fact is that
we use a powerful home mortgage
technique to just use the public key and
the fact that the update publicly knows
r1 to somehow evolve the public key to
the new public key
so this is pretty much the idea that
people work on but why is this secure
so
this is based on a standard high shelter
encryption
so why is it secure let's take a simple
look at the game where the university
provides no updates so no randomness
from the adversity so it's a challenger
and the adversary the adversary receives
pknot and provides just the challenge
messages m naught star and m one star
and uh the adversary receives p k star s
k star c star nub star okay again uh we
will look at why these terms matter here
and then b prime that's the usual so
let's take a look at sk star so recall
that sk star is nothing but the old
secret key uh plus a randomly chosen
delta star
okay so what this is is essentially a
leakage
on
the old secret tsk
upstar is basically
an encryption of delta star which we can
think of it as sk the oldest case the
new sk start minus the old sk so it's
somehow dependent on the message so
fortunately delta star is random
therefore the leakage is trivial
and the hash function which is modeled
as a random oracle will ensure ktm
security
um so how do we go from here to what
standard mode
ktm security uh allows an adversary to
obtain an encryption of a function g of
the secret piece under a particular
public key uh um so bernard all showed
kdm security for refined functions and
they provided constructions from the ddh
assumption
how we need only circular security that
is an encryption of a secret key
sort of in ask scheme bit by bit and
homomorphisms
so here a secret key is a vector
and we will use both vhs of
cryptosystems and human backup
cryptosystem um and here we will only
we'll encrypt delta a bit by bit
and this seems to be inherent we'll see
why
and the problem now is that leakage per
bit is non-trivial because delta i is
either zero or one and you can pretty
much guess um
recovered so what we need is to show
that the schemes are simultaneously
secure
both
cs and lr secure so circular secured and
leakage visibility um so what is this
security definition for this game that
i'm
throwing in right now the game is pretty
simple challenger adversary pksk is
generated keeps pk pass k for itself
sends pk along adversary provides
challenge messages and a leakage
function l
now the adversary tosses a bit sorry the
challenger tosses a bit
uh and then there's a challenge
ciphertext which is an encryption of mb
and then there is an encryption
of the secret key uh under the public
key which is also provided to the
adversary along with the leakage
function l
and then the adversary guesses a bit b
prime and we want semantic security
so the pro point here is that the
leakage function here um can even be a
probabilistic and just means that
uh there is some amount of residual
entropy that most lambda bits of entropy
are
drained from the system
okay um so
what are our contributions
um so
we present two upk constructions in a
standard bottle
one from the radius assumption which is
based on the ph of cryptosystem
uh where we will update
uh pkn uh encrypt
sorry update pk will encrypt bit by bit
in the exponent as you see over here and
then the update secret key will be in a
position to decrypt it and this is where
the fact that we are in we have a big
string hell comes into play because
delta is either zero or one so i can
take discrete log efficiently uh and one
from the lw assumption which is based on
the dual degree crypto system i just
believe to be post quantum secure and
update public key will now encrypt bit
by bit as such
um and then we show that the two schemes
that we're considering are
simultaneously circular secure and
leakage recipient we also introduce
stronger security models and present
constructions satisfy these models and
there is a possible abstraction here to
go from upk to upke we have identified
some kind of circular security kits
receiving simultaneous security
we need homomorphism and we seem to need
me as a journal of autism uh and our
constructions are all follow the same
blueprint but they're not genetic
construction so there are some inherent
subtleties in the construction itself
which makes it not peaceable to have a
genetic composition uh result
and this is the table so we obviously do
inherit uh some some performance loss
because when we go to the standard model
uh but we do have
both from ddh and lwe
so
on the dot at 12 i'm done that's all
folks thank you
okay we don't have time for questions
that's the end of the session let's
thank all the speakers
i