[Music]
okay you're ready to go
so welcome back everyone so
we have the second quantum session today
and it's going to be a mostly online
session and the first talk is about
secure software leasing from standard
assumptions
and
thank you for the introduction i'm going
to talk about the secure software racing
this is a joint work with the friukki
tagawa and takashi makara from entity
secure software racing is a quantum
cryptographic primitive there are
investors who has a software and lessee
a central authority generates a common
reference string
the lesser generates a protected
software by using a secret key
then the lesser sends it to dynasty
the lessee
can learn the software on the lesbian
legitimate platform that is they can get
an output for an input
at some point the lse returns this
software to the lesser
then the lesser checks whether the
returned software is a buried list
software or not
after the lazy returned this software
they cannot run the software anymore
that is this software must be a quantum
set since we can easily copy cluster
information
there are two security notions for
secure software listing
one is finite time security
in this security game an adversary
receives the protected software
then the adversary tries to generate
possibly entangled bipartite states
both of them can be used to run the list
software
the adversary sends one state to the
lesser as a returned software
and uses the other one to run the least
software
finite time security guarantees the
returned software is not buried
or the adversary cannot run the resource
software on the legitimate platform
anymore
here the adversary is forced to run
software by an honest evaluation
algorithm
the other notion is infinite thumb
security
this is stronger than finite thumb
in this security game the adversary also
tries to generate possibly enzymed
bipartite states
then the adversary tries to use both
states to run the least software on the
resume platform
infinite time security guarantees the
adversary cannot use either of the two
state to run the list software
this is our result and comparison
finance and labor presented the notion
of secure software racing and
instantiate it for subclass of aviation
functions by using public key content
money and elderly assumptions against
quantum advisories
their scheme achieves infinite time
security
some concurrent and independent works of
our work improved the assumptions
but the function class is limited to
subclass of invasion functions
alongside achieve secure software
listing for broader function classes but
they still need public key content money
ours is the first secure software
listing for broader function classes
from standard assumptions
in our paper we give constructions for
pseudo-random functions and subclass of
evasion functions
but our construction can support public
key encryption and signature by
combining the technique by alan snyder
our construction is based on the clean
framework using software water marking
we can instantiate the water
watermarking part with standard
assumptions
alongside concurrently and independently
presented presented a similar technique
based on watermarking
we note that some works achieve security
where pilot software is not forced to
run by honest evaluation algorithms
lastly our construction can be achieved
only with classical communication
that is we do not need to send quantum
states
uh this is our result
now our so our scheme is based on the
scheme by announce announcer and lab
maker so i label it
software is modeled as a classical stack
we somehow generate a protected circuit
in the classical way and connect it to a
public key content money
when we return the list software to the
letter the list checks the quantum money
is valid
then the lesser also checks the
protected circuit part is correctly
connected to the quantum money
if both
are by the return of the software is
buried
when we learn the reasons of their own
legitimate platform the platform does
not
the platform does the same check as the
lesser
it checks both the quantum money and the
connected part
the crucial observation here is the
lesser can use their secret key for
checking the returned software while we
need a public key to run the list
software on the legislative platform
we found that we do not need the full
power of public key content money for
finite time security
so instead of public key counter money
we use two tire quantum lightning which
we introduced in this work this is the
relaxation of quantum lightning
in two-tier quantum writing an authority
generates the public key and the secret
key
anyone who has the public key can
generate a bolt as quantum lightning
there are two types of verification in
two tyre quantum lightning
one is full verification which needs a
secret key
the other one is same verification which
needs the public key
so anyone can execute same verification
however only the authority can execute
through verification
in the security game the adversary
generates potentially entangled two
quantum states as quantum lightning
into tire and vulnerability game one
quantum state is checked by full
verification using the secret key
the other quantum state is checked by
same verification using the public key
two tire unclean ability guarantees one
of the two states with the same serial
number is invalid
we can construct the software racing by
using two tire quantum lightning instead
of public key content money
we also use software watermarking for
the circuit protection part
alexa generates a bolt and serial number
and embeds the serial number and the
public key of two tire content lighting
into software by water marking
so the software is connected to the
board
when a software is returned
the letter extracts the embedded public
key and serial number and checks the
bold part by full verification with the
secret key
when your let's see then learns software
they extract the embedded public key and
the serial number and checks the bold
part by same verification with the
public key
precisely speaking we need mac to
formally prove the security of our
construction by add but i omit it for
simplicity in this talk
we can prove the finite time security of
our construction by using two-tier
unclaimability and unlimitability of
water marking
the adversary generates two states
one is checked by the lesser and the
other one is on the legislative platform
suppose the first one is buried under
full verification and the second one is
valid under same verification
we consider two cases
first if the
extracted public keys are the same in
two states the adversary breaks two-tier
uncle nobility
in the second case if the extracted
public keys are different the adversary
breaks unremovability of water marking
since fire the software must preserve
the functionality of the of the original
software
note that this argument is
oversimplified since we omit the mac
part from this intuition
this is the summary of our work
all building blocks can be constructed
from the ql library assumption
we can also achieve status of their
listing with classical communication
however i omitted them in this talk
please see the video or paper for the
video
that's it thank you
thanks for the talk so i think we're
running a little bit out of time so we
can have the questions for you towards
the end unless someone has a quick
question while the next speaker ombre
sets up so that we can get to the
questions for your talk towards the end
of the talk
with the end of the session
so i was just uh updating that uh uh
umri unfortunately uh called me 30
minutes ago we had an accident
uh
yeah um
anyhow we can now do do you think
we could have your talk right now the
classical binding for quantum
commitments and get to this talk towards
the end of the session yeah so what
we're going to do anyhow because he's
not going to get here is in the hospital
um and since i didn't have any time to
prepare anything uh there's a talk by
michael from qcrip the five minute talk
and uh we're going to broadcast it uh
right now
and uh we already checked that it works
so no
worries i hope umri is
not serious me too
but uh i spoke with him on the phone um
so he's conscious uh he's sort of
walking
or limping i guess
but he has to get a few uh tests done to
know that
everything is fine uh so yeah so uh get
well from uh from here um
everyone on pcc
yeah so uh let me play the video and
i'll be happy to answer questions uh
afterwards
hello hi everybody i'm michael and i
represent uh the following work which is
a joint work with the newbie conscience
all of us are from tel aviv
um
so what we have done we started to
consider the notion of quantum
receivable soundness i don't have that
much time to
uh
recap although it was done in the
classical motion but
what we do is we consider uh resetting
attacks where the prover has quantum
oracle access to the verifier
and
he needs to cheat the verifier at some
session
uh the motivation that we have for
considering such a notion is to follow
this the first one is to achieve such a
security guarantee as was done in the
classical case and as takashi has
mentioned before me uh the notion of
black box zero knowledge is indeed very
important to understand and we hope that
as in the classical case understanding
more more about quantum reasonable
assignments will help us understand more
about the limitation of post quantum
black box zero knowledge
uh again as takashi mentioned we show uh
analog results to their uh regarding
free message and constant around public
coin we show that there cannot be any
black box zero knowledge uh
protocol that is as those are described
here
uh
and we achieve this by observing that
as in the classical case uh post quantum
black box zero knowledge and resultable
sounds cannot coexist together
and using test observation we use the
measure and reprogram techniques to
transform for example pre-message
protocols into classical reset of these
stuff into a recently sound ones and as
such there cannot be both quantum and
reasonably sound zero knowledge with
free messages or public coin
uh this is the first result we achieve
in the paper
the second result is on the positive
side we show how to construct uh the
pull of spontaneously sound zero
knowledge protocol uh for any language
nmp uh our protocol assumes the hardness
of quantum learning with errors and a
quantum polymorphic description the
construction is constant round uh again
zero knowledge is post quantum which
means it is uh
holds against quantum verifiers
malicious quantum verifiers and just to
give a little taste hey our protocol
indeed begins from the protocol of
concentration zero knowledge which is in
the black box from vitamin k but the
protocol as is is not receptively sound
even classically then we need to first
try to think how to transform it into a
classical uh recently sound protocol uh
via the actual document or paradigm and
then try to solve all the
technical difficulties that arise from
the fact that we're dealing now with
quantum adversaries and not uh classical
ones
and the last result we show is again an
analog of the classical result which
shows a connection between receivable
soundness and a quantum virtual black
box sophistication we showed that any
recently some zero knowledge protocol
for np and some kind of hardness in the
post quantum world
for example when we function
implies that virtual black box
substation
is impossible
this
with the construction of the protocol is
an analog result to the possibility
results that are mentioned here and also
i'd like to mention that if we were ever
to construct a better
like weaker assumption protocol
which is reasonably sound we can
immediately imply that resettable
that uh quantum virtual black box
society is indeed impossible and as such
trying to build for example uh public
coin constant from a non-black box
protocol
it will be as difficult as showing that
uh contour virtual background
sophistication is impossible
since we can transform it to resettable
sound
there is sound protocol giving uh
our
our compilers that we have discussed in
the first result
uh
so this is what
whatever
[Music]
okay yeah this was pretty fast i'll be
happy to answer questions now or later
uh whatever the form of this
first of all thanks a lot dear for just
taking care of that if you're having
totally okay if uh yeah we could have
sort of had to stop later but yeah
thanks a lot and yeah best wishes to
omri from everyone at tcc and any
questions from the audience or
i don't think there are any questions on
the chat right now
and maybe i can ask a quick question so
can you expand on the last part that
these better protocols will imply better
obfuscation
schemes you mean quantum complication
skills for quantum circuits
right yeah so uh no not for quantum
circuits so we're talking about quantum
obfuscation of classical circuits
okay let's
whether quantum gives you more power
maybe you can
expect you can get for example virtual
black box
uh for classical circuits but using a
quantum state so your obfuscation is
going to be a quantum state and there
are impossibility results for that uh
from the past uh year uh actually a
couple of those
and they all seem to rely on uh somewhat
strong assumptions for example
photomorphic encryption
and it's not whether this is inherent
right like in the classical setting we
have unconditional impossibility results
and really sort of like the
the main engine there is uh is one-way
functions
um so basically
like the basic question is can you show
impossibility of
obfuscation
using
quantum okay of like obfuscation through
a
quantum procedure um based on weaker
assumptions based on one way functions
or perhaps even unconditionally
and we point out that through this
connection
um
to a
resettable soundness um
you might be able to get like a
different path toward this uh this
question uh in fact in the classical
setting you can instantiate uh this path
but in the quantum setting at least for
now we don't know how to construct like
things like let's say a constant round
public coin uh zero knowledge and stuff
like that uh if you manage to do that
and
naturally it won't involve a
fuliomorphic encryption which sort of
automatically gives you secret protocols
uh then we would also vicariously
get uh stronger impossibility results
okay
okay i see i understand now i thought
that uh you were hinting that there
might be better constructions for
obfuscation schemes from sort of these
new protocols so you're saying no it's
the opposite oh it's more bad news it's
like
okay yeah but from weaker assumptions
thanks a lot me and that's wishes to
hungry
so let's move on to the third top of the
session and uh japan is going to sort of
keep the dogs you can please share your
slides
and the paper is on unifying
pre-sampling via concentration bounds
and the work is uh by ciao go uh
chipping liu uh
zan and uh please rectify uh me in case
i mispronounce anyone's name yes
thanks for the introduction
uh yeah i don't think we can see your
slides yet
okay yes yeah i'm still i'm still
working on this okay uh can you see that
yeah
okay okay great
okay yes uh thanks for the introduction
the work is about the uh unifying
pre-sampling we are concentration funds
so um okay let's start
uh okay
so we start by looking at a famous
example of practical hash function
char 3 and for this function the
building block is a function in the
picture
the function seems very random and
achieves pretty good performance in
practice but however it is very hard to
analyze
even uh for the most fundamental
properties like lesion resistance and
unwillingness
so to deal with the difficulty in
analyzing security belay and rock will
observe that random oracle captures most
railroad attacks and the proofs are much
simpler
but however security balancing idealized
models
uh like a random oracle model provided
essential and heuristic justification
and guidelines for their security in the
standard models
but
however traditional idealized model
failed to capture pre-processing attacks
the obtained bonds in idealized models
are inaccurate or not applicable at all
once pre-processing is allowed
and one famous example is pre-image
finding
well um when no pre-processing is
allowed it is easy to see that it
requires roughly zita and queries to
invert the image and when preprocessing
is allowed the query goes down to n to
the two sets
so let's look at the formal definition
of idealized models which pre-process
so
so when uh
the adversary in the random oracle model
is allowed to do pre-processing we call
such model auxiliary input random oracle
model or
ai rom
there are two phases in the model the
first one is called an offline phase
there's a unbounded adversary can
arbitrarily interact with the random
oracle and making unbounded queries
it at the end of the day it produces a
piece of advice of lens atoms most s
and then
in the
in the online phase another algorithm
tries to win a security game it gets a
device from the offline phase and the
challenge
and then it makes at most t queries and
the goal is to output a valid answer
so the reason to think about this uh
offline procedure
uh is because it captures the more
realistic realistic attacks or enzo in
other words the non-uniform attacks
and another reason is that usually it is
crucial to answer online queries more
efficiently comparing to um
more efficiently so for example a hacker
needs to like respond to a server in a
short period of time the offline phase
is allowed to take a quite a while
because the hash function is public now
and everybody could like spend a lot of
time and analyzing that function
so therefore we define the security in
the ai rom
which is simply um
the security against aspects of a device
and t queries
although the model captures the more
realistic attacks it is usually more
difficult to work with especially to
prove its sc security
so there are a couple of techniques for
analyzing security in the ai rom and as
you may tell from the title in this talk
we were all focusing on pre-sampling
which gives a simple and intuitive
analysis
so the intuition behind pre-sampling
technique is that although the device
can be an arbitrary function of the
random oracle
for now let us assume it is well
structured in other words it only stores
as input as pairs of input and outputs
of the random oracle
and therefore for an online adversary it
only knows this fixed coordinates but
nothing else
and therefore the security is easy to
analyze as long as the challenge avoids
this fixed coordinates
and um informally for example
serum says that the advantage of any
complicated advice is at most the
advantage of some longer but well
structured advice
and and let's look at the same and more
formally
so um we first defined the bit fixing
model well the random oracle is sampled
as follows first the outputs are
arbitrarily fixed on
p coordinates by the attacker
and then the remaining coordinates are
sampled by the challenger or by the
random oracle
and the sampling theorem says that let
epsilon be the maximum success
probability of breaking an application
in the ar wrong
then it will be at most epsilon prime
plus st over p well epsilon prime is a
maximum success probability
in the corresponding p bit fixing
model
and when p is roughly s times t then
epsilon will be at most two times
epsilon prime
and note that usually epsilon prime is
uh much easier to bond
and also um we note that the first one
is additive therefore works better with
indistinguishability game and the second
bond is multiplicative which works
better with
unpredictability games
okay and that's like the recap of the
classical theorem and now let's switch
to the quantum world
so in a quantum world uh random oracles
are the same which is the random
function drawer at the very beginning of
the game the only difference in the
interaction between algorithms and
random oracles
since the quantum algorithm can always
implement a practical hash function for
example a chart three on its own devices
therefore it is natural to assume it
makes superposition queries to the
random oracle
and it's also natural to define
auxiliary input quantum random oracle
model well
both the offline and the online phase
online algorithms are quantum and the
advice can be either quantum or
classical and in this work we're
particularly
interested in the case where advice is
classical and the online algorithm is
quantum
and therefore um
as we have seen the simplicity and
tightness of pre-sampling techniques in
a classical setting we ask the following
question can we leverage free sampling
techniques to the quantum setting
and in this work we answer this question
in three different aspects
first we realize that a
so-called direct leveraging is difficult
we show that if such a direct leveraging
would work that it implies the famous
aerosol and binance conjecture is true
the conjecture research said any quantum
algorithm or unstructured inputs can be
approximated on most inputs by efficient
classical algorithms
the conjecture is still quite open and
the best known bond is still
exponentially far from conjecture
therefore we think it is a barrier
and faced with this barrier we revisit
the pre-sampling techniques in the
classical setting we find that there is
a much simpler proof for the previous
pre-sampling theorem
which will redefine p-bit fixing random
oracle model and work out a simpler and
unified proof
with only standard concentration bonds
this proof gives type theorems of
previous works for both uh ai random
oracle model and a random permutation
model and this is why we also call it a
unifying
approach
and with this new definition of bit
fixing model we adapt it to the quantum
bit fixing model and we show that with
this new definition we can prove a
quantum version of the pre-sampling
theorem and further
it is optimum in the sense that it
matches exactly classical uh the
parameters in a classical bond
and finally we showed the simplicity and
generality of this theorem by reproving
previous bond and also giving the first
uh post-quantum noun uniform security of
a merkle dam got hash functions
and i guess that's everything i want to
talk about today there are a couple of
technical things but we can talk about
that in the in the question session
and thanks for your attention
[Music]
so maybe if i can ask a quick question
and uh
do you think these ideas would be
something i guess would also be okay so
you right now apply these ideas to prove
uh something pre-something theorems for
random oracles from hash functions but
what about some other oracle functions
could be like some cryptographic
articles that you want to say okay hey i
have like pre-processing access to these
oracles cryptographic articles could be
an encryption scheme could be a
decryption scheme and eventually sort of
just say okay hey i'll give you some
polynomial string and then ask a few
questions uh
yeah i
i'm not a hundred percent sure but
currently i think for these idealized
models we can uh generalize it although
we don't know if there's two to prove it
in other words like we we're going to
prove security in the bit fixing model
but then if you're caring about like
other models then you're
basically you need to bond the security
in the in the bit fixing of other models
which i'm not sure if that's uh easy or
or hard but there's like a natural
generalization and you can adapt this
whole framework into other other oracle
models but i'm not sure whether uh let's
argue this epsilon prime is easy or not
okay but uh won't the argument epsilon
prime in those cases be similar to
arguing that uh like here epsilon prime
is sort of arguing about the number of
queries or it's like for each random
oracle query writing some properties
with that
uh yes so so this so called a bit fixing
model would you you need to argue
security in the big fixing model and
that that that makes some difference and
that may seems like non-trivial i guess
yeah okay
thank you
and i would say there were some
questions on this youtube chat for
uh new but i would say we can get to
those all the questions if we have time
towards the end of the session of course
yes
yeah yeah i i i look at these questions
also yeah
as well so let's move on to the next
talk and the talk is on relationships
between quantum cp notions nissan could
you please uh share your slides
uh yes
is that is that okay now
yes could you start the slideshow
yes
is that fine
that's that's great so okay so the next
talk is by son and the doctors on
relationships between quantum ncp
notions and the paper is by torque uh
winston cautions issan ibrahim
uh jello and noel davia dominic andrew
and uh please correct me if i said
someone's name correctly but yeah take
it out uh
that was great thank you for the
introduction and uh
so uh we the full version of the paper
is available at april if this
presentation is really short
so
i will go uh quickly the setting that we
consider here we
we're talking about the post quantum
security in the solar position access
model when the adversary quantum
adversary basically has a
uh has a quantum
uh quantum access to the classical
cryptographic construction
uh so uh
in this talk we are targeting how to
define the cpa notions in this model so
basically the question is how cpa notion
can be defined when that the city may
have us for position access to the to
the encryption scheme and what they are
what is their their relationship between
the notions that have been deprived
so to to define such emotions
we have to fill in these question marks
and how adversary
interact with the challenger
and in the learning phase and the
challenge phase
and the challenge phase is is colored by
the red and the learning face or or like
they don't have a color
so first i quickly go through the
existing seepage notions
before our work
so there is a bonus on this definition
that they consider
like standard oracle access to
encryption in the learning phase
and the
classical access to the encryption in
the challenge fields
so in the challenge phase the
uh basically the challenge after getting
two messages it returned one one of the
encryption of one of the messages based
on the random bit which would be so this
we call it the one ciphertext return
actually
there's another definition that they
consider a
different query model it's called the
minimum query model in the learning
phase and in the in the chat in the
challenge phase as well so the challenge
phase here is quantum and giving two
quantum states row zero and row one the
challenge gets back the encryption for b
uh the third notion is they consider a
real random
type return type in the challenge phase
that
the basically the
queries are implemented as a standard
oracle access to the encryption
scheme so this this phase or
or included as this and then in the
challenge phase the challenger either
applies permutation before encrypting or
it doesn't apply and that the sales goal
is to
detect if this permutation has been
applied or not
so now the question remains or are these
all possible notions
and the answer is no if we
systematically want to answer the
question
so i will go
quickly through the options that we have
so
for the for the query models if you have
four options
uh to consider like the classical query
or standard query model or embedding
query mode or minimal querying module
embedded query model is different a bit
like slightly different from this
standard model in which
the alpha register here
is is said to be zero so the adversary
doesn't have a control over output
register
there's also a different material type
specifically in the classical case we we
have two different notions for this that
the challenger returns one cipher text
or two ciphertext or real random return
type so uh
but in the challenge in the classical
case these notions are all
equivalent
and there are a number of queries that
we have to consider there is a zero one
or a polynomial
so now if we quickly uh do the math then
we can see that in the learning phase
you have five uh choices
and in the challenge phase we have two
times four times three choices and it in
the total we have 120
choices for to define certain notions
and this is huge number of notions
that's really frightening to want to
study these notions
and uh so here we excluded uh some some
notions um
pixel that the notion is that they have
a different quantum queries in the
learning and challenge phase
these are our 36 notions
also we excluded the one time in cpa
notions that is
but basically there is one challenge
query only and then there is no learning
queries so this is the 12 motions
and also there are some notions that are
impossible to achieve it means that and
like any encryption scheme will be in
securing these notions
so if we do the mass we
we can get a 57
encryptions
like security motions
still it's a huge number of
notions
and
one example of such a notion is that
we consider for instance the minimal
query in the learning phase and then in
challenge phase
we we can stereo random return time so
the notion can be defined
uh step forward basically so
this is the new new notions by the
combination
so we started this notion then we
grouped them into the 14 panels
and we also studied relations in
relations between these patterns so the
equivalent notions are grouped
and
we have this this table as a result
and uh so you may see some red none
implication that they left as a
conjecture and some question mark
if
we we assume that we basically believe
the
retinal application as a conjecture
because we believe that this direction
is more likely to happen and if it does
i mean if we can prove firmly that it
does then all the open questions will be
resolved and the table will be complete
so that's that's really pleasant to to
look at them
also at the end of paper this we have a
discussion related to this
so
the conclusion is of the talk is we have
two notions that
implies all other notions
and uh this is uh when we consider a
standard query model with the real or
random return type or minimal query
model with the one side one ciphertext
return type
now we also
we base we present a scheme that's
secure respected to both this these two
notions
and since this notion together imply all
other notions then
basically we have a scheme that securing
all the possible 57 notions that we
consider
and also we
we saw that these two definitions are
not comparable
and this is our opposite classical case
that different
different uh
uh
obviously classical case basically
different quantum cbi notions may not be
equivalent but in the classical case
we
we know that all of them are equivalent
and i guess that's
that's the end of my talk i was fast but
it gets a long time do you have any any
questions
i don't have any questions on chat yes
and any questions from the audience
so uh just to sort of understand the
contributions of this work so do you
think these two uh
what do you mean by they're incomparable
are there schemes that are secure as per
definition one but not after definition
two and the same goes in the reverse
direction
yes exactly
okay
so we cannot relate relate them together
but you have schemes that are secure as
per definition a but not as insecure as
per definition b and same the other way
around so that's yes
yes exactly
okay and do you think a similar
systematic study will be required for
quantum in cpa emotions
in cca emotions uh chosen scientix
attacks well for for the cci notions
there are there there are days which
basically there's
the main challenge to define that sysa
notion is the
when we consider the like the challenge
queries be quantum then
the the challenge here basically we
don't have a way to record this this uh
quantum queries and then later the
decryption basically return curve or
garbage when when that we say something
is query so
uh the recording for general encryption
function general randomized function
is not yet developed so
there's only one definition uh
but there are some attempt to define the
cc nation with with the challenge
queries to be quantum but still
there is not immediate success of that
so i'm afraid that defining the seaside
notion with the quantum challenge phase
is challenging itself
i understand so the question was do you
think the
the lessons that you learned from this
work about definitions about their
quantum nct notions the similar lessons
would also be used when one will be
studying the cca counterparts of all
these things
as assuming suppose we have like a
starting definition where the decryption
oracle query access has been modeled in
an appropriate way
uh sorry it was a bit interrupted so i i
couldn't get the last uh the last few i
think it's just maybe we can take it
offline it's not a very important
question but yeah thanks a lot for the
great i'm sorry i'm sorry i think i
didn't hear
we just have one more talk and we can
sort of circle back to all the questions
for all speakers towards the end of the
session thanks again nissan again for
the talk
thank you
uh can you share your slides
um
yes let me do that
okay just suck
okay you can see it so now we are
the last talk of this session and it's
uh work on classical binding for quantum
commitments and it's a vote by neil
danskins we cover kerosky and me is
going to present
okay thanks michelle uh all right so
this is uh work uh with uh spika um it's
about commitments
and uh
as you all know uh commitments are one
of the most basic uh crypto primitives
uh they involve the sender and the
receiver is interacting two phases right
um in the commitment phase the sender
commits to a message m and in the
opening phase it can open this
commitment
and the basic properties that we ask for
are hiding which means that before the
opening phase the committed message is
hidden and binding which says that a
commitment can only be opened to a
single message
and in this work we're interested in
quantum components
we're still uh thinking about
committing to classical messages but the
communication and the parties are
quantum
and as it turns out for quantum
commitments the question of binding
becomes rather complicated
in particular the the classical notion
of binding is generally considered
impossible due to a simple superposition
attack
so you can think about running down
sender
in superposition over distinct messages
let's say zero and one
and in this case assuming that the
receiver is unitary
the message bit is not really fixed
after the commitment in fact it can be
opened to a uniformly random bit
now of course there does seem to be
an easy solution here which is for the
receiver to just
measure the entire channel the entire
commitment and therefore effectively
make it classical
and this one did worse at least in the
statistical binding setting
so what is the catch
so the point is that by forcing the
commitment to be classical we might be
missing out on features that can only be
achieved quantity
and one known example of this where
quantum commitments are really superior
to classical ones
is that they can be constructed
non-interactively from one-way functions
quantum secure bonus functions of course
and this is not known classically as a
matter of fact there are black box
barriers for this
however
the court's finally quantum commitments
are at the same time also inferior to
classical commitments
for once they satisfy a weaker binding
guarantee in particular the committed
message is not really fixed uh they are
subject to this superposition attack
and this also makes them harder to use
and harder to analyze
and the question is whether this price
is really necessary or perhaps we can
get the best of both worlds
so
in this work what we show is that the
answer is essentially yes we can achieve
the best of both worlds and let me tell
you about each of the contributions
so we first define
um
classical binding in four quantum
commitments which has a similar
guarantee to classical commitments in
particular the commitment fixes the
message
and intuitively the notion we introduce
can replace classical commitments in
applications without really changing the
proof
and we demonstrate this for example in
classical zero-knowledge problems
then we show that we can achieve a
statistically binding version of this
notion
non-interactively from one-way functions
okay so indeed we get the best of both
worlds
finally we also explore a statistically
hiding version of this notion and there
we show that actually classical binding
is impossible
now i have very little time so i will
only tell you what is sort of the the
basic idea behind the the definition and
then the idea is actually very natural
so
basically our receiver during the
commitment phase is only going to make a
partial measurement
and
the rationale is that we want this
partial measurement
to be such that on one hand the
commitment will turn classical enough
for fixing the message but on the other
hand it will remain quantum enough
to achieve the superior features that
we're after
okay
so let me also tell you just in a
nutshell about our construction of these
non-interactive commitments from one way
functions and the construction basically
derandomizes noor's commitment scheme
which as you may know is a two message
commitment
and specifically the basic idea is to
have the sender sending a single message
a superposition
over all receiver messages
and corresponding sender messages
where we derive the sender's messages in
some appropriate way specifically using
a pairwise independent hash function in
order to derive its randomness
now we're going to take this randomizing
build
randomized building block and repeat it
in parallel
many times and in our commitment phase
the receiver is going to measure
some random subset of these commitments
and these are meant to be in our
commitments that fix the value
and in the opening phase we're going to
use the rest of the commitments
in order to test that the actual
uh commitment that the commitment to the
center stand originally was well
structured or close enough to well
structured
um
yeah so this is the
uh the idea of course that analyzing
this is tricky these commitments are
entangled um but you can watch the the
longer talk where we discuss more
details
so i'll end here
thanks
thank you very much so any questions
from the audience about this youtube
chat
i guess not right now so this is uh
seems like a very cool trick so do you
think this idea can also be used for
sort of this uh century could also be
some other primitives because this seems
like a i mean abstract it seems like a
very general idea
fun question um
so
it's an open question and uh we've been
thinking about it and we don't have any
good answers yeah so i invite you to
think about it as well you know perhaps
like uh um a natural uh candidate is for
example zaps right like turned into
exactly absolutely not interactive
one essential difference is that zaps
don't have like an opening phase
uh
and we're using here the opening phase
where there's no secrecy left whatsoever
in a very strong way and and that that
is the barrier there i don't know maybe
there's a way to to circumvent it it's
an excellent question
wonderful okay so if there are no
questions uh thanks a lot near again and
uh
[Music]
so
at this time you would like to invite
anybody who would like to ask a question
in session
and uh so uh maybe i can sort of circle
back to your day if you're still around
i had like a quick question for you
yeah
so do you think uh the quantum lightning
schemes they were initially proposed as
an interesting abstraction to build
quantum money as well and sort of
applications towards quantum money so
you have like an interesting weakening
of quantum lightning do you think you
might be able to
sort of also get one uh maybe not public
or publicly quantum money but very with
very weak unforgivability property
from these ideas because uh your quantum
lightning scheme only relies on
classical assumptions or uh only on sort
of uh learning whether there is an other
standard assumptions can you use these
ideas to also build quantum money
schemes though not fully publicly going
to money but only for a very restricted
class of forgery attacks
uh
yeah
it
may be possible but i don't have a good
idea for now
so yeah it's it's a good open question
to
to find um another application of this
idea like uh tutorial
uh something yeah like
maybe
two different writing might have some
other another application so yeah
but i don't have any good uh
idea so far yeah
okay thank you and still one more
follow-up to
your talk it's just uh you i think you
used relied on and also the other uh the
current work relied on the ideas of
watermarking uh software watermarking as
a particular primitive to sort of
classically bind come into the
uh or classically watermark the the
circuit so but i think uh the the ideas
that over there used were the original
definitions of water marking do you
think there has been recent work in
which the notion of water marking has
been strengthened to a traceability
properties that those particular
traceable primitives can also be used to
prove certain stronger properties about
uh software using if we use those
particular ideas
oh sorry i i didn't uh get to you all
yes so
stroke
so i'm simply asking currently when you
are using watermarking inside your
schemes you're using the the uh the
watermarking definitions that were
defined for the unremovability games
recently there has been a push to sort
of move from watermarking to traceable
primitives where you can have like
stronger properties so do you think if
you sort of rely on traceable primitives
then you might be able to prove even
stronger properties about the resulting
software reasoning schemes or do you
think maybe there are more fundamental
gaps
if you want to strengthen them further
it's a it's very good question so
i also tried to extend the our
idea to the some three for example
printed but
one one uh
obstacle is uh
uh
we
in in the in the
second software racing uh
setting uh
the rest use
only secret key and uh sorry
oh so
the last you cannot use secret key
so it says
i think it is a problem
uh to extend uh our idea to
uh through addressing primitive
but
i don't i'm not sure whether it is a
fundamental obstacle so
uh
maybe we can uh overcome
the issue the issue and uh
we can achieve some
uh
tourist stressing version of the of the
printed so yeah it's a good uh
application i think
great thanks a lot and thank you rio
near japan hassan
and all of you for sure being here