the last day of pcc
uh the first
today we start with the foundation
session and the first talk is on
de-randomizing yao's quick to strong
one-way functions
and uh this is a joy work uh please
boost camp uh joffrey pila and felix and
peter will give the talk
thank you for the introduction
so i'm
and i'm going to talk about the
randomizing yellow suites strong one-way
function construction
and
as we were presented uh this was a joint
work with chris bruce's casual foreign
at least chris is also here in the zoo
so he can help me if you ask difficult
questions in the end
uh all right
so we say that if is a weak one-way
function
if
it can be inverted with probability at
most 1 minus 1 over p of n for some
polynomial p
and we say that g is a strong one-way
function if the inverse and probability
is negligible so this is the usual
definition of one way function
now the theorem by yao says that if f is
a weak one-way function then this g that
takes some long input x one to x n times
p of n
where this p
is from the weak one-way function
definition
then this g feeds these x's into the
weak one-way function and outputs the
results
this g is a strong one-way function
now we are interested in whether we
could have shorter input to g
that is
if you have the yaw construction here
could you add some pre-processing
function such that it makes the input to
g shorter
in particular
if the input to the weak one-way
function is of length m
and this x is of length n
could we have
n equal to some constant times n
now the result of our paper is negative
that is
there is no preprocessing
with input length less than some
constant times p of m
so the input here must be at least
order of this polynomial
more precisely
we show that you cannot prove that such
a short input g is a strong one-way
function
and what proves we rule out exactly
we rule out a big class of relativising
black box proofs
and our proof
is by oracle separation
so first
we have a piece based oracle to get rid
of all possibly already existing
randomness
existing
hardness and then as the weak one-way
function
we have a special random oracle
that
can be inverted on one minus one over p
fraction of random outputs
and then we show that this kind of
short input g can be inverted with
non-negligible probability
the adversary against this g works as
follows
so it inverts each of these y's one by
one
and it is successful in roughly this
fraction of the f calls
so the adversary learns all
but uh this
polynomial fraction of the excise
and now the interesting part of our
proof is to show that when you know
almost all of these
then
no matter what this preprocessing
function is
uh
this x is easy to guess with the b space
oracle
now
this looks a little bit like secret
sharing
you know many shares and you want to
learn the secret
of course in secret sharing instead of
this x we would have some secret and the
dealer's randomness
however there is a result in secret
sharing that says that the randomness
and the secret together need to be long
so we were hopeful that you could prove
an upper bound in our case as well
and indeed we managed to prove that on
average average the hard x-i's
have little entropy conditioned
that you know all the easy exercise
regardless of what this pre-processing
is
this is because
every x i
cannot have a fresh bit of entropy from
a short x
so when we choose a random subset of x
i's then the entropy is gone with high
probability over the choice of the
random subset
and then
uh when you know all of these
uh it is very easy to get this x using
the plus base
oracle i give the details of that proof
in the long talk
and in the long video i also discussed
how this relates to other works
thank you for listening
any questions
okay any question for pila
let's see if there are questions from
the chat
okay so looks like there are no
questions thank you peter this was a
really great talk it was really
enjoyable
all right so
so then let's move on to the next talk
next talk is um
actually do we have children
oh good
um on three with separators and young's
garbly this is a joint work by chitan
karen klein and christoph pietrock
and chetan is gonna give the talk
[Music]
um now we can
yes
yes now we can you'll have to speak
louder
okay
um
uh sorry for the technical difficulties
i'm jaitan
and i'll present the paper entry with uh
separators and yahoo scarbling this is
john wood with current line and chris uh
chuck
um
our main uh result states that for for
the class of boolean circuits of size s
and
tree with w
yar scarbling which we denote by gamma
is adaptively indistinguishable uh with
the loss of security which is
exponential in the tree with uh as to
the of w to be precise
uh so for concreteness if one considers
uh boolean circuits uh that have
constant true width
uh we get uh
uh
adaptive indistinguishability with only
polynomial loss
um a couple of remarks are due here so
uh what is true with uh it's a notion
from algorithmic graph theory
which is uh informally a measure of how
far a circuit is from a formula
and we will come to the the details a
bit later
and uh secondly the notion of security
we consider here is called adaptive
indistinguishability
uh this is weaker than the standard
national security which is adaptive
simulatability
and we will see soon why this is the
case so adaptivity here refers to the
fact that uh the adversary
uh it can uh
select its input
after the fact that it uh it has
obtained the garbled circuit
uh so what was known about uh security
of eos garbling
um
the selective security was established
by link lindell and pinkas
and
this was that they showed that yao is
selectively simulatable and this
implies selective indistinguishability
and
uh this was followed by the work of
obama tall uh who proved a negative
result they ruled out
uh adaptive simulatability of of yao
scarbling
and so this was a a corollary of a more
resol more general result of that which
showed that
if
for randomizing coatings uh which is
adaptively simulatable
uh your
online complexity needs to exceed the
output length this is not the case for
uh yao scarbling
but
uh jaffa golian makes um
so that you can bypass this negative
result by modifying yao's construction a
bit
that is by deferring the
output map to
uh to the online phase
so uh
the the the the state of adaptive uh
distinguishability had remained open and
we
uh partially resolve this um in in our
work we show that it is indeed possible
in some cases
uh uh so i'll briefly describe our the
overview of our proof so we
like in previous works we do a hybrid
argument and we to get adaptivity we use
something called piecewise guessing
and in order to do this formally we uh
uh abstract out the hybrids using
a game so our people game is a bit
different from the previous works
and
this is one of our technical
contributions
and the main technical configuration is
coming up with um efficient doubling
strategies and for this we use
uh trade the notion of three with our
separators so so what does this
translate to so uh uh
doubling strategies are are
by the the second step
they are kind of tightly related to the
hybrids the hybrid argument and and
coming up with more efficient terminal
strategies for some measure of
efficiency they translate into better
hybrids for foreign
uh so
so this is what i would like you to uh
take away from from this talk like the
notion of separator and through it so
this is a very general
uh notion and it is uh it's a it's a
useful uh tool to have and once reporter
uh as to attribute this as as already
mentioned it's a measure of how far a
circuit is from a
from a formula for example boolean
formula by definition have tree with one
and what is a separator a
separator s for circuit c is a subset of
its gates
such that removing this subset s
and the incident wires it decomposes uh
the circuit c into
sub-circuits which are of comparable
size so for example in this figure on
the left you see a circuit c and a
separator for it is shown in between the
dashed lines and when one removes the
gates
uh the the circuit neatly decomposes
into two sub-circuits c1 and c2 which
don't have uh connections between them
uh how are circuits uh how are
separators connected uh connected to
attribute this is why a classical
theorem of robertson and cmr they showed
that
any circuit which is uh which has a tree
with w
has a separator of size
uh which is upper bounded by w therefore
uh this is an existence theorem
and how what does one apply this uh
existence theorem so
so on a very high level what this allows
is
to do divide and conquer uh this is the
main reason is because uh the notion of
qubit is a
is a monotonous property so if you if
you look at the sub circuit of a circ
circuit the tree width can only decrease
from its parent circuit so what it
allows you to do is
you take the circuit c you decompose it
using a separator s then you can keep on
doing this process until you end up with
small enough sub circuits
so if you are if you are trying to carry
out some uh thing for the whole circuit
c you can uh divide the task into
carrying it out
for the sub circuits uh given you pay
for the separator s
uh since
uh so the so since the the the sub
circus that we get is not too olympic
uh the depth of this this recursion is
is also is bounded by log of s
and moreover the amount of resource one
uses per step it's also bounded by the
uh size of the separator therefore if
the separator is not too big one ends up
with a nice divide and conquer strategy
which helps
uh carry out whatever task one wants to
and
that's all
um
[Music]
you can find more details about the talk
on the paper or
you can look at the the full video thank
you
thank you
are there any questions for children
we have one question
from the audience and if you cannot hear
you can speak from that oh you can come
here to watch me okay
uh all right this is uh just a simple
question do both parties need to know
the tree decomposition
um
no no one just needs uh if one has an
upper bound on the trivets
uh if you look at the details of the
paper
it suffices if one we guess like uh the
trivets that the separator and then
one can carry on one doesn't need to
compute the three decomposition
okay
and then uh one more question since
we're already starting with circuits so
they're already um you know dags does
that mean like in general like the tree
width tends to not be
that big for most kinds of problems
people would wanted to do
um
not necessarily so so uh i burst some
things under the hood here trevit is
actually defined for undirected graphs
originally but we use like a definition
which is for directed graphs
um
i don't think so one could come up with
uh with circuits for which like the the
tree width is um large enough there
might be like a small gap between the
the triplets for directing and directed
but it's probably not significant
thank you
other questions for chetan
so i don't see anything from the top
thank you chetan again
all right next talk is um obvious
transfer from chapter permutations in
minimum round
by
arca nicole champ
ripo goyal
hello hi
can you hear me
yes
okay
so thanks a lot alessandra for the
introduction
um yeah so the first thing we start in
this favor is the notion about videos
transfer so i hope all you know all of
you know what is it what it is so
basically we have a sender with two
inputs and a receiver with
with one bit as input and the aim of the
receiver is to get
a cb
in such a way that the sender doesn't
learn what is the input of the receiver
and the receiver doesn't learn what's
the other input of the sender
and unfortunately we know that we cannot
realize this functionality information
theoretically and so what we can do is
to rely on some assumptions in this case
we want to consider the
the setting of computational
hardness assumptions in particular
we um
consider the uh the notion of one-way
chapter permutation
so
one way to describe uh what these are
the is through a set of algorithm so the
first algorithm is the generation
algorithm that gives you um the
description of chapter permutation and
subtractor
uh then we have an evaluational grid
that basically we can use to take any
value x and evaluate g over over x and
we get the
uh the output and this is easy to do on
the other hand uh if we just take a
random element from the codomain and we
want to compute the inverse this is hard
it's hard as unless we have the tractor
if you have the trapdoor we can do that
in sleep
so one property that you might want to
add on top of your one with raptor
permutation is the property of
certifiability where certifiability
means basically that anybody by just
looking at the description of the
function can claim efficiently
whether g is
a primition or not
so
what is the relation between ws transfer
and uh capture permutations so we know
that uh uh in three rounds if the
receiver is seminars and the sender is
corrupted uh we can use structure
permutations to to realize the blues
transfer functionality however as we
will see later
it is required for the traptor
permutation to be certifiable in order
for the proof to go through
and
in a little work of casastroski of 2004
the others show that you can actually
realize any functionality but again you
need to rely on uh certifiability of the
chapter permutations and this result is
in the pre-plane model and requires just
five rounds which is the minimum number
of rounds that you can hope for
this result was later improved by
ostrowski richardson and scafulo where
they showed that the same result holds
by requiring only black box access to
the underlying raptor permutation
and now what we ask in this in this work
is whether we can remove this uh
requirement on the certifiability right
and this is kind of another question if
you look for example in other in other
contexts for example
um we know that to realize
non-interactive uh zero knowledge uh
we just need chapter permutation so a
bellaryum in 1993 show that you don't
need the certifiable property and this
result was also improved later on by um
by connecticut so we asked whether the
same holds in the case of probably
transfer more in general in the case of
two-party competition to realize any any
functionality
so before diving into it
uh i just want to recall how the egl
construction works to realize obvious
transfer so for simplicity let's say
that the receiver here has a fixed input
one
and the idea here is that the sender uh
generates the trapdoor permutation
it provides the description of this
function to the receiver
and now the receiver for the input he
knows he samples a random x one
evaluates the function over x one
and for the input it doesn't know it
just picks the random y okay so the idea
is that he will compute these two values
in such a way that the receiver knows
only the pre-image of one of those
now the receiver the the sender has a
tractor so he can invert
both y 0 and by 1
and so he will use the
inverse of y 0 as a one time key to
encrypt
his first secret c 0
and he will do the same
for the second secret c1 and he will
send uh those encryptions over to the
receiver
well now the receiver if the receiver is
a semi-honest then he can only get
uh one of these uh secret and he is
happy
but what happens when the the sender is
corrupted
so if the function g is a permutation
and the receiver has a way to certify
that then well the receiver will
be happy and he will engage in this
protocol and as you can see if the g is
a permutation you can actually claim
that
the input of the of the receiver is
information theoretically hidden because
the distribution of y 0 and y 1
basically
they are distributed identically
on the other hand
if you consider a function that is not a
permutation and that it's not
certifiable so the receiver cannot just
support um by uh understanding that the
function is not a permutation then you
have a problem and the problem is that
you have some collisions in the sense
that two values for example the
the the function evaluated on two values
gives you the same value
this means that for example
the value y1 which is computed by uh by
the receiver can never will never be
equal to for example b1 or b4 right
because there is no value that is mapped
to from x1 to uh to the domain b1 a b4
and on the other hand
y0 is randomly sampled from the domain
so i mean
b1 might be equal to any of those values
right so and this might give an
advantage
to uh to the adversary
so what do we do to solve this issue
uh we
define and extract an encryption scheme
that takes a simple description of the
one-way permutation and a message m and
it returns a ciphertext
now
if the function g is indeed a
permutation
then any
any any descriptor that has the chapter
of g can decrypt
on the other hand if g is not a
permutation and it has a lot of
collisions then the message remains
hidden
so that's how we modify the protocol so
basically the second round is now
encrypted using this encryption scheme
in such a way that we are in a win-win
situation so if the function is not it's
very bad uh it's very badly not a
permutation the the sender cannot
decrypt but if the function is a
primition then the sender can't decrypt
then we are happy because i mean it's
fine that the sender
sees y0 and y1 because they don't leak
anything about the input of the receiver
uh
as you might have noticed this is not
this is not sufficient to to prove the
security of this because there might be
less than exponentially many collisions
right so
but we show in the
uh and we discussed this also in the
extended talk how to amplify the
security of this problem
uh by using an approach similar to
oblivious
transfer combined combiners
and so we use a similar approach to
realize an optimal
around the two-part competition that
realizes any functionality
in the optimal number of rounds and that
requires only the black box access to
the underlying um chapter permutation
and
this uh this is the end of the talk
thank you very much
thank you we get it do you have any
questions from your audience
and questions
[Music]
okay so maybe i'll have a quick question
um this in this encryption scheme is a
special one
and
and what's the idea
yes so
what's the idea of the encryption scheme
or what city of the
i guess um how do you use the
information about the chapter to decrypt
or not decrypt
because i
if you understand this should be a
yeah so your construction is non-black
books than in the
chapter permutation
no no the construction is black box on
the tractor permutation so the idea is
is that basically to encrypt you just uh
use the
um
you take a value x and you use
you know you evaluate x over g and you
get the hardcore beat of x actually to
be precise right and then you can use it
to encrypt one bit for example okay so
your cyber cybertex is like the arc or
bit of uh
of this value right x and uh you also
send um
you also send one y right and then the
point is that if you have the trapdoor
you can decrypt because
you can right but if the function is not
a permutation
it's ambiguous like how to decrypt it
because you have the value y
and then you try to invert it and you
get two values and then you don't know
what is the right value
that's more or less how it works yeah
but it's fully black boxes and the use
of the
of the permutation yeah
nice nice thank you
all right let's thank michelle
our next um paper is the cost of
objectivity in security games on graphs
and it's a joint work by treeton
karen christoph and michael
and karen will give the talk
yes
can you hear me well yes
okay
thank you for the introduction
cryptography we often define security of
a scheme by game between an adversary
and the challenger
and the current can you speak a bit
louder a bit louder okay or maybe
yeah
so what i said in cryptography we often
define security of a scheme by a game
between an adversary and a challenger
and to prove security of this scheme we
then construct a reduction that
simulates the challenger to the
adversary and tries to extract some
information from this interaction that
helps it
to break some heart problem pi
and such a hard problem pi is very often
defined
through the security of some simple
cryptographic primitive on which the
scheme is built
we then prove that if the adversary
breaks the scheme with advantage of
xylem that the reduction breaks
the underlying heart problem with the
advantage of xylem over loss and clearly
the smaller these losses
the stronger the security guarantees we
obtain for our scheme
in this talk we only consider fully
black box reductions
in many cases it is significantly
simpler to construct such a reduction if
the adversary's choices were known ahead
of time
we call such adversary selective or
static adversaries
in practice however we usually require
strong adaptive
security where the adversary can make
all its choices adaptively depending on
what it learned during the game so far
in this talk we will discuss lower
bounds on the security laws against such
adaptive adversaries
for schemes for which selective security
could be proven only polynomial loss
the games we consider are multi-round
games that capture several existing
constructions where the adversaries
queries can be considered as edges of a
graph
one such game is called generalized
selective decryption and it was
introduced by panjuani in the setting of
multicast encryption protocols
this is in a secret key setting nodes
represent keys and edges represent
encryptions of secret keys under other
secret keys
while this game makes sense for
arbitrary acyclic graphs
in many applications or specific
constructions the adversary would be
restricted to query added paths or
binary trees
the next game we consider is the
security of tricam which is a continuous
group key agreement protocol
that is currently discussed by the mls
working group
this is very similar to gst however in
the public key setting
and furthermore the adversary's queries
are somewhat structured to form a tree
the next game we consider is the
security of the pure random function
based on pseudorandom generators due to
code right called was in micalli
as a prefix constraint to the random
function
here nodes represent seeds and edges
represent prg evaluations
and the underlying graph structure is an
exponential sized binary tree
the last game we consider is the
security of unidirectional proxy
encryption schemes
the nodes represent public key pairs
and edges represent re-encryption keys
issued during the game
similar to the case of gsd the graph
structure is not fixed but in most
applications the adversary would be
restricted to paths or binary trees so
these settings are especially
interesting
for all these four games and various
underlying graph structures we obtain
lower bounds that almost match the best
known upper bounds
unfortunately however in the case of
paths and binary trees
our lower bounds only hold for so-called
oblivious reductions
where we call a reduction oblivious
if it ignores
what it learns about the adversarial
structure
about the adversary strategy and ignores
this partial graph structure that it
learns during the game so it behaves
selective in some sense
in the case where the underlying graph
structure is a tree we do not have to
make this restriction but we obtain
lower bounds for arbitrary straight line
reductions
and our final result for proxy
encryption on arbitrary acyclic graphs
holds for arbitrary fully black box
reductions
while obliviousness is a rather strong
restriction on the reduction let me
mention that all known upper bounds have
been derived through such oblivious
reductions
our main conceptual idea
to derive our lower bounds is to
introduce a builder pablo game that
abstracts out all the combinatorics
behind our proofs
here the builder represents the
adversary and the pablo plays the role
of the reduction
we then translate upper bounds on the
pebbler's success probability into lower
bounds on the security laws using oracle
separation techniques
so we construct an ideal basic
cryptographic primitive in the case of
gsd this would be an ideal ncbi secure
security encryption scheme
and we construct an inefficient
adversary that simulates some builder
strategy within the game
breaks the scheme by brute force
breaking the underlying cryptographic
primitive
recall we consider black box reduct
fully black box reductions so we can
consider inefficient adversaries
and this fact that it can break the
underlying primitive allows the
adversary
to map any pebbles any reduction
strategy into a pebbler strategy in the
buildup publicly
let me conclude with some open problems
first can we strengthen our lower bounds
to hold also for rewinding or
non-oblivious reductions or can we use
these techniques to overcome our lower
bounds
recall that only in the setting of
proxier encryption on complete tags we
have a complete answer to these
questions
second of course it would be interesting
to see which other multiround games can
be captured by our builder pebbler game
and finally
whether one can use our
idea of translating pebbling lower
bounds
into lower bounds and loss in adaptive
security
also in other settings
such as constant run games like abe or
garbling where the entire graph
structure is known in the first round
in the setting of yao's specific
construction for grappling we know the
answer is yes as we showed it crypto
this year however we required very
different techniques there
please let me thank you for your
attention and i would be happy to answer
any questions
any questions for karen
all right looks like there are no
questions in the chat
thank you karen
thank you
all right so
next talk is on concurrent composition
of differential privacy by saliva dan in
taiwan
and
chiang hao is going to give the talk
uh okay um
uh hi i'm tian hao i'm a phd student at
princeton um today i'll talk about our
work on the concurrent composition of
differential privacy
so differential privacy is uh dominates
privacy notion nowadays um the main idea
of differential privacy is to carefully
randomize the algorithm um so that its
output does not depend too much on any
single individual in the data set um
that is um and for for differentially
private magnesium um the probability
distribution of the the magnesium's
output of the dataset should be nearly
identical to the distribution of these
outputs on the same set with any single
individual's data being replaced
and the distribution closeness is
characterized by parameters epsilon and
delta
one of the most important properties of
differential privacy is that it permits
the analysis of cumulative privacy loss
under the composition of multiple
mechanisms if we run multiple distinct
different private algorithms on the same
data set the resulting composed
algorithm is also differentially private
with sound degradation in the parameters
epsilon delta for privacy guarantee
this property is especially important
and useful since in practice we rarely
want to release only one single
statistic about dataset
releasing many statistics may require
running multiple and the different kinds
of differentially private algorithms on
the same database
there are already many composition
theorems exist in the literature and it
has been shown how to compute the
optimal bound for composing
magnesiums
of the existing composition theorems
however focus on or implicitly assume
that the underlying dp mechanisms are
one-shot algorithms that only output one
answer
however many of the useful differential
privacy primitives such as sparse vector
technique are actually interactive
mechanisms which allow one to ask an
adaptive sequence of queries
about the data set
for instance sparse factor technique
could potentially accept infinite amount
of quarries while paying privacy cost
only for quarries that are greater than
the noises threshold
um
so we first formally defined the
interactive differential privacy is a
type of interactive protocol between the
adversary and
interactive magnets
a natural question regarding interactive
vp magnesium is whether the differential
privacy is also preserved under
composition however there could be more
than one composition operations for
interactive magnesiums
the most the most straightforward one is
sequential composition where the
adversary's interactive session with one
mechanism must be halted before it
starts an interactive session with
another mechanism in this case all of
the composition theorems we discussed
earlier still applies
however
a reality strike is that a single
anniversary could interact with multiple
mechanisms concurrently
where different threads of the
interactive sessions can be arbitrarily
interleaved with each other that is
although the response outputs by
different magnets are generated
independently and the adversary however
may coordinate its actions it takes in
various executions of interactive
sessions and in particular its actions
in one execution may also depend on
messages it received in other executions
unfortunately none of the existing
composition
theorems for non-interactive dp can be
directly applied to the setting of
concurrent compositions
to the best of our knowledge this work
is the first to tackle the problem of
the concurrent composition of
interactive differential privacy um here
are our main results
um
we derive a bond that is similar to
group privacy for the computer
composition of pure interactive dp the
privacy degrades at most linearly with
the number of mechanisms concurrently
executed which is same as non-interrupt
dp the proof is based on a hybrid
argument
however for the concurrent composition
of approximate interactive dp
it is worse than even the basic
composition theorem of non-interrupt dp
in the delta term
we then characterize a pure interactive
dp mechanism as a post-processing of
randomized response
which is a non-interactive mechanism and
obtains the optimal privacy bound for
the composition of pure interrupt dp by
taking the optimal composition of
non-interactive differential privacy
since we know that dp is closed under
post-processing
um unfortunately we still don't know
much about the the computer composition
of approximate interactive dp
we believe the bond we got are far from
the correct answer based on computer
simulation we conjuncture that optimal
composition bound
may may also hold for approximate dp
yeah thank you
you can help
is there any questions
okay so we have no questions from the
chat
but i think you can now again
next talk is on the
irreplaceability of global setups
or how not to use a global ledger by
christian baderster
sorry julia jesse in basilicas and julia
is going to give the talk
thanks everybody
okay can you see the
you'll actually need to um under display
settings up at the top you will need to
i think it says reverse display
swap swap presenter sorry
ah
yes how does this look
that looks good for us
okay so now my mouse is a bit gone but
ah okay
can you see the laser
pointer yes
okay awesome sorry
okay so hey everybody um this paper is
about uh pitfalls in analyzing the
security of protocols that run in
concurrent systems
so let's assume we want to capture the
security of a protocol run between
uh alice and carol that requires some
sort of
protocol setup
for example such as a public key
infrastructure
in our work we focus on setups that are
modeled as global meaning that these
setups are not exclusively available to
um this one protocol instance but it can
be they can be accessed by other
protocols as well
once a um setup is deployed in practice
actually it is not well we don't really
have any control over how users use it
for example um
a user might use a private key obtained
from this pki for more than just let's
say ecdsa signing
so to summarize global setups are in
many cases a way more realistic modeling
than than local ones
okay so in
in recent years blockchains have arised
providing us with publicly
accessible or privately accessible
immutable transaction ledgers there are
many applications for this new type of
data structure some more serious some
less serious
and if you check the literature many of
these applications have a
security analysis in a simulation based
framework carried out with respect to a
global ideal ledger functionality
now the whole point of the blockchain
era is to not implement such an ideal
ledger functionality by a trusted
authority but by a decentralized and
interactive
blockchain protocol emulating the
trusted authority right
so if we want to
want these proven security guarantees in
the literature to be meaningful in
practice we need to be able to replace
the global ideal ledger functionality in
these statements by one of these
protocols
so in this paper we uh investigate
whether we can replace a global setup
such as
a
transaction ledger with another protocol
while maintaining
the already proven security guarantees
okay so let's look at
what happens
if we attempt to replace a global setup
let's say we designed a protocol row
for online poker and we have proven that
it securely realizes some ideal
functionality of poker
i'm assuming that the parties have
access to a global ideal legendary
letter here
if we now replace the ideal ledger by
the bitcoin blockchain
for example in our security statement
the following nasty thing happens i want
you to look at the the interface of the
simulator here in the ideal world
we see that the interface
changes from the one at the g ledger
functionality to the one at the bitcoin
protocol right
now the bitcoin blockchain is known to
securely realize an ideal ledger
functionality meaning that there are
less attacks on the bitcoin protocol
than on g ledger
the interface of the simulator under
replacement simply shrinks shrinks here
and the simulator actually might run
into failure
okay so failure of the simulator under
replacement is clearly not a nice thing
right it means essentially that um our
security proof does not carry over to
the poker protocol as we would deploy it
in practice in practice right so
accessing the bitcoin blockchain
okay so this is a problem uh in 2014
canadian uh demonstrated that um
that such simulation failure can
essentially be avoided if the replaced
protocol
is essentially equivalent to the ideal
functionality in particular the
adversarial interface
but of course this has quite limited
applications and for example it does not
work to replace a non-equivalent
um by a non-equivalent uh
sorry the ledger by a non-equivalent
blockchain protocol
so in our work we find essentially more
ways than equivalency to keep security
statements valid under replacement of
the global setup and the intuition
should be quite clear from the from the
kind of animation that i showed in the
last slide
um the intuition is that we can replace
whenever the simulation is not disturbed
by the replacement
okay so our first composition theorem
for replacing global setups works for
what we call agnostic simulations this
is a simulator who
essentially only
accesses the ledger as an honest party
would do right so this means the
simulator of the security proof
for our poker protocol here so this guy
it essentially just transmits um submits
transactions um on behalf of alice and
carol to the ledger right so for global
setups which do not even provide an
extra adversarial interface this theorem
essentially yields black box composition
meaning that we do not even have to look
into the simulator and can directly
replace the global setup with any
blockchain protocol realizing it
um the second composite composition
theorem uh for replacing global setups
that we came up with can capture um an
even broader setting but its
preconditions are more tedious to check
we define a set of so-called admissible
attacks which are attacks that are
allowed on both the global ledger
functionality and on bitcoin
so for example it might be possible for
a network adversary to postpone
publishing of an honest transaction in
bitcoin by one block right
and hence we can unlock this kind of
attack also for our poker simulator
okay so the flip side of our work is
that these theorems these two
already make it quite clear that
replacement of a um
of a global setup in security statements
really hinges on
well on the optimality of the simulation
so to say it very clear a security proof
with a simulator who overly exploits the
adversarial interface of the global
setup will most likely not survive
replacement of the global setup
okay so i hope i could get you
interested in having a look at the
extended talk and also please check out
the paper which is equipped with lots of
fun examples on how to use and how to
not use global setups that you still
have to replace
thanks
um
thank you julia do we have any question
here's some questions
maybe i have a quick question
so
so would you say there is a way to
define the global ledger that is um
safe so that will work for any that
touch of the simulator cannot exploit it
whatever that means
that's that's a very good question and i
mean that's a question that we asked
ourselves um the thing is that you have
there's another side to
to what i just said because you also
need to prove that the bitcoin protocol
realizes that ledger right and you don't
want
this uh ideal ledger functionality to be
really close to the bitcoin protocol
because otherwise it will get like
extremely long right
so you want this ideological
functionality to be some abstraction
of the bitcoin protocol meaning that you
need to allow the adversary for example
to do some reordering right so it's
always there's always these two sides so
on the one hand we want to simplify the
proof of secure realization of the ideal
letter on the other hand if we allow too
much and this is exploited too much
in the
in the simulation of the application
protocol then i mean replacement does
not go through right
and so yeah what you say is is very
valid for the letter i cannot i mean we
cannot really really answer this
question in a nice way because there's
really these two sides
and from from what we um so we checked a
lot of uh um a lot of literature
um and it seems that most of the
most of the application um
applications do not overly exploit um
these adversarial interfaces with only
very few exceptions
okay
thank you thank you thank you again
thank you
my last talk of the session
a polynomial time targeted attacks on
coin tossing for any number of
corruptions
this is a joint work by omit
saeed muhammad
and g is gonna
give the talk
yeah
thank you
so um
hello everyone welcome to the talk uh i
am from university virginia today can
you speak louder or closer to the mic
okay
is that better
slightly better
okay
i mean actually maybe i can increase the
the speakers here
okay try now
okay uh hello everyone
okay let's let's continue like this
so hello everyone welcome to my talk i
am gigon from university of virginia
today i will present our paper
polynomial time privacy attack on coin
tossing for any number of corruptions
and this is drawing work with amir
saying
muhammad this talk is about collective
coin tossing so let's see this example
of for such protocol now here are n
parties and each of them sends out a
single message
and eventually the protocol takes all
these messages and returns the output
bit b which equals one with probably mu
note that although in general parties
can send more than one messages in this
work we focus on attacking this single
message protocol as we will see is
already very general and leads to
interesting applications
here we define the attack model we focus
on what we call targeted k replacing
attacks
targeted means the addresser prefers
output 1 and k replacing means that it
can corrupt and replace up to k messages
within choices after seeing the original
values chosen by these parties so for
example in this protocol at round one
party one gives this message omega one
but adversary after seeing this omega
one decided to replace it to omega 1
prime and add round 2 part 2 prepares
this omega 2 and
it can depend on the previous omega 1
prime but this time the address will
decide not to replace this message and
finally at round n after
party end prepare to send this omega
message
it could depend on all the previous
broadcast messages and the adversary
changes the message to omega n prime the
success of this address is measured by
how much it can increase the probability
of putting one
and more formally
the gain is
mu prime minus mu where mu prime is the
probability of b equals one after the
attack and mu is the probability of b
equals one without the attack
assume we have a probable pie between n
parties and product of b equals one
is mu we now ask the following question
with a fixed budget k how much gain can
already achieve we studied the question
for two classes of particles on the
first class
message are uniform binary and on the
second class messages are arbitrarily
long the first class is clearly a
special case of the second class
now suppose beta tn is the probability
of hamming ball which is simply the
probability of the summation of uniform
binary bits
omega 1 or 2 omega n
for the case of uniform binary messages
make sure that for the original
probability mu equals to beta tn even
polynomial time online attacks can
achieve probability mu prime which is
equals to the beta t minus kl a bigger
hummingbird this implies the threshold
protocol is optimal for hamming ball
probabilities and as a result we obtain
this computational and online variant of
harper's vertex as a parametric
inequality
and for the case of arbitrary message
length we show that polynomial time
online attacks can achieve this gain
omega mu times k over root n and this
implies that this threshold protocol is
optimal up to a constant for constant mu
for large messages as well
and because of allowing these large
messages as a application this result
allows one to obtain this targeted
poisoning attack on deterministic
machine learning learners
with the small budget kick when
that is small end when any size or
training data set
and for the case of uniform binary
messages
as a related work this lead testing at
all 1989 paper showed that the stress
hold functions are optimal for a weaker
addressing model in which the addresses
cannot see the message before
deciding to make these changes
and their attack is not for normal time
for arbitrary messages a series of work
starting with a client or show that uh
how to obtain for normal time attacks
using larger budget which were by large
will mean that this k equals to omega
root n instead uh there are there are
analysis use this works uh lead to no
gain when k is a small or
root n
however know that uh
here we want to understand ultimate
attacks for every part possible k
we now describe some ideas between
sorry we know describe some idea behind
the proofs of our two results starting
with the case of uniform binary messages
now with this describe our first result
in more
details uh suppose the messages are all
uniformly memory
consider this t threshold particle in
which parties let this output be b to be
1 if the sum of the bits is larger than
t
consider a more powerful attack which we
call offline so it will to say all the
messages and then make replacement
it is easy to see such attacks can
increase the probability of the output
one to a larger hummingbird and harper's
vertex as a parametric inequality shows
that one can always achieve the same
gain when the probability b equals one
is the probability of having both
our first result is to improve this
classical result to show that the same
can be achieved even if the attack is
limited to be online so it cannot see
the future bits and runs in the
polynomial time
to gather uh some more details of this
proof here's a figure of the different
adversaries scheme for n equals to 10.
in this figure x axis is a mu value that
ranges from zero to one and the y axis
is maximum gain that it can achieve for
every protocol for given mu
the blue curve is the maximum gain for
the online adversary which we want to
bound the red curve is the maximum gain
of the offline address which is
basically the isoparametric bond we know
that the blue curve is always below the
red curve but we don't know how much
observe that somehow magically at this
exact hammering ball probability what we
prove is always the case
to do so we connect these points on this
red curve that correspond to the exact
hummingbird probabilities using these
straight lines this gives a piecewise
linear function l
which will prove to be a lower bound on
the blue curve as well doing so mean
that this red and blue curve will have
the same
result on this hummingbird probabilities
and to prove that this alpha curve is
indeed a lower bounce which uses
induction and and the
induction crucially relies on the
concavity of this l function
our high level approach here is inspired
by reason work for scanning at all but
the actual induction step is quite
different
now we go over ideas behind our
attacking for the case for arbitrary
length messages
suppose as wrong i every adversary is
given this message of omega 1
and current message omega i and the
address we want to decide whether to
replace this or mika i or not basically
we use this additive game adversary that
is similar to this attack in mm out
making paper which makes this
replacement when the current additive
gain is large not namely at this message
omega i let alpha be the probability
before the attack of
b equals 1 and r prime b the maximum
possible probability of b 1 by replacing
this omega i to any other message omega
s star at this step
so if this alpha prime minus alpha
larger or equal to lambda the others
will replace this omega nito omega star
this paper has proved that the attack
starts to gain when k is large
there is also a multiplicative
multiplicative gain adversary from ad
summing at also that paper that gives
this even shorter bond using this
multiplicative looking adversary however
what we want is to have a tag works for
any k and that's not provided by these
two papers here we show that this
additive gain adversary as opposed to
this multiplicative warrant of this
attack can lead to a good gain
even if we cut this attack for any
number k
we prove this result by using this
reduction induction on this
okay all we need to do is to gain the
pain
case replacement in summary we show that
either this happened or something is
even better happens
so if the case replacement happens
allergies against lambda
so this is only true for additive
attacks with
if the case replaces does not happen it
means the budget of addition is not
fully used
then the output will be
indistinguishable for another attack
which has even better even larger budget
maybe infinity budget and of course it's
a extremely strong one so it's a win-win
situation for the adversary
so we
summarize our findings in the conclusion
for the uniform binary protocols
threshold particle is optimal for online
offline k replacing attacks and for any
k and this result can be viewed as a
computational version of hyper's vertex
as a parametric inequality
and for particles with any message lens
the majority protocol is still optimal
up to a constant factor this result can
be applied to obtain generic targeted
poisoning attacks on machine learners
with small budget
thank you i appreciate any questions and
comments from you
[Music]
thank you
do we have any question for d
by the way am i
pronouncing your name correctly
yes
okay perfect
okay so no questions from the audience
and no questions from the chat
all right so let's thank every speaker
of this session
we