and the first talk is uh
by uh on on the topic information
theatrically secure mpc against mixed
dynamic adversaries the paper is by ivan
damgard daniel escadero and the vera the
virabhi and the via is going to give the
dog
thank you uh so this work is about
information theoretically secure npc
against makes dynamic adversary based on
a joint work with ivan dangard and dan
so let me begin with a quick
introduction to what mpc means suppose
you have n mutually distrusting parties
out of which t
and they want to compute some combined
function on their private inputs and mpc
gives them a way to do so while ensuring
that everyone gets the correct output
and that nothing beyond the function
output is revealed
now in this work we focus on information
theoretic mpc where we assume the
adversary to be computationally
unbounded and this includes perfectly
secure protocols where no error is
allowed and statistically secure
protocols where negligible error is
allowed
now let's look at classifications of
adversary based on the kind of
misbehavior that they are allowed so the
weakest one is the passive or the semi
honest adversary and here the kara
parties are honest but curious that is
they follow the protocol steps but the
adversary can see their internal state
now in such a model information
theoretic security is known to be
possible if the number of passive
corruptions is less than n by two a
stronger model is the active or
malicious adversary where the corrupt
parties can deviate from the protocol
arbitrarily and in this model
statistical security is known to be
possible if two ta is less than n but
for perfect security you require three
ta to be less than n
the third model is that of the mixed
adversary where the adversary is allowed
to make different types of corruption
simultaneously so this adversary is
allowed to make tp passive corruptions
ta active corruptions and tf fail stop
corruptions where he can instruct these
failstop parties to abort but he cannot
see their internal state
so in this model it's known that
statistical security is possible if two
t a plus two t p plus t f is less than n
and there is a similar inequality for
the case of perfect security uh which
has three ta instead
so if you look closely this actually
generalizes the bounds that we saw
earlier for the passive and the active
case and these were presented in the
work of fitsy and others and they showed
that these bounds are also sufficient so
in particular they showed that if you
take a fixed tuple t atp and t f
satisfying such an inequality then there
exists a protocol
now an important point is that if you
take say two different couples
satisfying this inequality then what
their result says is that there exists
two different protocols but what we are
interested in is having a single
protocol that works for any tuple that
satisfies this inequality
and this is exactly what the dynamic
anniversary model is and we want to
understand that under what conditions is
it possible to get information theoretic
security against such a dynamic
adversary
and this was introduced by the work of
hurt and others in 2013 this model of
dynamic adversary and both in their work
and a subsequent work by patra at all
they focused on the case of
computational security and we are
focusing on information theoretic
security uh but even information
theoretic or dynamic adversary has
indirectly been studied by these works
in 2008 because they consider a general
mixed adversary model and you can think
of dynamic adversary as being a
threshold version of this one
i refer to the paper for further detail
comparison on this
now let me list our contributions first
we explored the case of statistical
security where we begin with the
assumption that the adversary respects
this inequality so this is needed even
in the non-dynamic case so it would be
needed in the dynamic case as well so
for this we showed that for sfe
protocols even the strongest guarantee
of guaranteed output delivery is
possible but this comes at the cost of
increased round complexity so we showed
that even if you just need fairness you
still need to incur round complexity
that grows linearly in the number of
parties so this actually shows a
separation between the dynamic and the
non-dynamic case because in the
non-dynamic case you can get constant on
protocols at least for some restricted
trusses or functions
next for reactive mpc we showed that
fairness is possible but it turns out
that god additionally would require this
constraint of r plus f being less than n
where r is the maximum number of states
that the adversary can read so this
would include the active and the passive
corruptions and f is the maximum number
of players that the adversary can crash
so this would include the active and the
fail stop corruptions
next we explore the case of perfect
security and again we begin with the
inequality needed even in the
non-dynamic case so for this the picture
was more on the negative side and
particularly for sfe we showed that it's
impossible and continues to be
impossible even if you just want the
weakest notion of security with the
board and you don't even allow the
adversary to use fail stop corruptions
but
posit on the positive side it's still
possible in some cases for example when
either you restrict pa to be 0 or you
extract tp to be 0.
next we explore the specific reactive
functionality of vss uh so note that the
negative results for sfe generally don't
extend to vss and for this we showed
that geod is impossible even if tf is
zero uh but fair vss is possible and
even geode is possible in some cases so
here we chose to explore the cases when
either ta is 0 or 0 and for each of them
we showed what the optimal bounds would
be but there can also be different other
kinds of tradeoffs when each of tatp and
tf 1 0 so that is something that we are
left to explore in future work so with
this i conclude my talk and refer to our
paper for further details thank you
thank you for the great job so any
questions from the room or
i don't think there any questions
but a quick question so in the case of
uh
computational security you had like uh
the lower bound for information
theoretic security as far as perfect
security or statistical and perfect
security but computational security
what's the what's the what are the
equations i need to satisfy in terms of
datp and fdr
uh so uh in the computational one they
did not consider fail stop corruption
they just consider the active and the
passive one and it was
it was 2 t a plus t p is less than n
that that was what the uh what the
condition turned out to be for the case
of um
yes yes it is also tight yeah so even
for the dynamic case so the first work
had explored they had both the upper and
the lower bounds and the second work
they explored the round complexity of
such protocols
and uh um
any questions or just one more follow-up
so you also talked about trying to have
like a one general protocol that sort of
fits all
df parameters so uh suppose if i ask you
that okay hey you still want to compile
this all these different protocols for
different uh perfect or statistical
security but maybe i give you some sort
of computational tool i give you like a
encryption system then can you sort of
compress all these different protocols
into a single protocol using
computational assumptions i'm not sure
if that question makes sense but i'm
just trying to come up with a generic
compiler for aggregating all these
different templates into one using a
computational assumption
uh so i think that um like maybe some of
the sub protocols you can try to have it
in a hybrid model like in a hotel hybrid
model or something but uh yeah i mean
i think the conditions may change in
that case like i that's actually
interesting but i need to think a bit
more but if i just think of our upper
bounds i think that some of the uh like
the one some of the limitations were
because we don't have the uh
corresponding information theoretic tool
but if we had an ideal uh
call to such a ot hybrid or something
then maybe uh maybe we can get something
or better feasibility yeah interestingly
interesting okay that's great thanks a
lot
so there are no further questions yeah
let's just move on to the second talk
which will be an in-person talk too so
that that's great
okay
i'll do this
okay it's uh great to have an in-person
talk in the online session supposedly
online session with yeah uh so the next
talk will be on actively secure
elementary and pc reductions and the
paper is by benny applebaum and arushi
goyal and arushi is going to give a talk
thanks for the introduction um yeah so
this is joint work with benny applebaum
[Music]
um so this is this is my quintessential
slide on the definition of npc which i'm
going to skip because they already
covered this
[Music]
um okay
so let's start so since its inception uh
the design of npc protocols have quite
heavily relied uh on the notion of
secure reductions and we see that the
task of securely computing a particular
function
securely reduces to the task of
computing a different and a simpler
function g if there exists a protocol
that computes f where the parties have
oracle access to the simpler function g
and given this kind of protocol
uh all we need now is to design secure
protocol for the simple
functionality
uh many classical protocols for example
that by yao and goldright on
essentially construct protocols that can
be viewed as secure reductions to the
two party ot functionality
going the step ahead we say that the
task of securely computing a function f
non-interactively reduces to the task of
completing a function g
if in this particular protocol the
parties only make single queries to this
oracle g and don't interact with each
other at all
in our work we consider the notion of
elementary reductions these are
non-interactive reductions
where the function g is that of a
constant degree and moreover the
reduction is
makes use of a prg in a black box way
this additionally requires that the
function g is entirely independent of
the prg
such black box restrictions typically
make things much faster
and also many classical reductions
already capture this notion of
elementary reductions
which i will go over in a couple of
slides
okay so like to summarize a little bit
about uh how elementary reductions look
like we have these set of parties who
run some local pre-processing functions
in their respective inputs
these be processing functions can make
oracle queries to the prg
the output of these pre-processing
functions are sent by the parties to the
oracle g
and finally the output of this oracle g
is
post processed by the parties using some
post processing function to compute the
final output
note that here both the preprocessing
and post processing functions are
allowed to make oracle queries to the
prg
but the function g is entirely
independent of it and the parties do not
interact with each other whatsoever
okay so like i said many classical
reductions are in fact elementary for
instance the two-party protocol by yao
and the multi-party protocol of beaver
megali and rogue
in the semi-honest setting can be viewed
as an elementary reduction from all
efficiently computable functions
uh in the dishonest majority setting
bieber mcauley and rogue way also had a
maliciously secure variant based on zero
knowledge but that protocol was
interactive i'm sorry that reduction was
interactive and the oracle g in that
case depended on the prg in the
malicious setting however we either know
of elementary reductions only in the
honest majority setting or only for low
depth circuits or only ones that achieve
the weaker notion of security for the
what
unfortunately we don't know of any
elementary reduction uh that is fully
maliciously secure that is it achieves
guaranteed output delivery for all
efficiently computable functions
um
apple bomb at all present a
non-elementary non-interactive reduction
in this setting but the function g in
their case depends on the prg
so naturally the question that we
address in this work is whether an
elementary reduction exists in this
setting
and we show that uh an elementary
reduction that achieves full security in
the setting is unlikely to exist
uh but one that achieves identifiable
abort does indeed exist
uh let me now elaborate on these
contributions a little bit so to
establish our lower bound we show that
uh for two parties existence of such an
elementary reduction
that achieves partial penance that is
where fairness is only guaranteed when
one of the parties is corrupt implies
existence of an information theoretic
elementary reduction for all efficiently
computable functions um in the crs model
with inverse polynomial average based
privacy against passive adversaries
ah and here by information theoretic
reduction i mean that the parties are
not even allowed to make black box calls
to the prg
and while we don't achieve an
unconditional impossibility the
implications of this particular result
statement are quite non-trivial
because they imply existence of constant
round protocols that are far
beyond the current state of the art for
instance existence of this kind of
information theoretic reduction would
imply a two-party constant round
protocol for all efficiently computable
functions that achieves inverse
polynomial average case information
theoretic security in the ot hybrid
model
which in turn would imply a constant
round protocol for three parties
um with inverse polynomial average case
information theoretic security for all
efficiently computable functions
and this is a well-known
three-decade-old problem um although the
original problem was stated for the
standard notion of security
it doesn't seem like this relaxation of
security uh gives us any more advantage
or makes the problem any more attractive
for our positive result we uh
i'm sorry we show that uh an elementary
reduction that achieves identifiable
abort for dishonest majority for all
efficiently computable functions does
exist
and a similar reduction was in fact also
implicit in a recent work
of vomit on
we also show that if the parties are
allowed to interact with the oracle g
more than once um then it's possible to
achieve fairness and finally it's
possible to achieve full security if the
function g is allowed to depend on the
prg
in fact any passively secure elementary
reduction can be transformed into an
actively secure one if the if the
function g is allowed to depend
thank you
[Music]
okay so maybe just a quick question just
to understand you said that you uh get
this three down protocol with inverse
permanent security in with these uh
implications
three particularly protocols so in
encryption and other primitives we know
that inverse performance security can be
amplified to full security by sort of
using secret sharing tricks can you sort
of hope to have like a similar theorem
here that sort of any protocol with
universal name security can be amplified
to a protocol with security independent
of the
that's a good question i'm i'm not sure
so so the only reason we say that this
yeah yeah the reason that we say that
this sort of there is this implication
is that the rest of the reduction
remains the same it's just how you
implement of uh the function g right
using the function j is simple enough
then the function g is a constant is a
constant degree function so that that
can be implemented whatever like we know
how to implement that
but i'm not sure how we can get rid of
like the inverse polynomial uh
dependence uh sorry security that uh
arrives whatever as part of your
reduction
any further questions from the audience
or the chat
i don't think so it's okay so yeah once
again
[Music]
let's just move on to the next
so the next talk is by uh is on
environmentally friendly composable mpc
the brain model from standard time
resumptions
and the result is by brandon rodner uh
jeremiah
measure john muller god and jeremiah is
going to give the talk
thanks for the introduction
so secure multi-party computation allows
material distressing parties to run the
pm to try to perform tasks like secure
function evaluation other parts evaluate
a function of the private inputs to host
the first price bit auction where only
the highest bid and the winner revealed
the intersection of sets but nothing but
the intersection was there sorry but do
you think you can speak a little bit
louder it's
uh difficult to hear you in the room
maybe a little more yes
okay this will be better
of course okay thank you
so much mpc can be used from arbitrary
computations in a secure way and for mpc
protocols we usually require properties
like correctness secrecy or the
independence of inputs
and in reality protocols are seldom
executed in isolation and we thus want
these properties to hold even if the mpc
protocols executed along arbitrary other
protocols
set it differently we want the security
to hold under protocol composition
a suitable notion for the security of
protocols in a setting where other
arbitrary particles may be executed
concurrently is universally composed of
security introduced by kennedy
it can be shown that this strong
security notion cannot be fulfilled in
the plane model where only authenticated
communication and complexity assumptions
are available
instead across the setup such as common
reference string
about the key infrastructure or random
oracle is necessary
as reliance on the setup might be
undesirable there's a long list of
security notions and protocols featuring
compostable mpc in the plane model
without a setup
common to all the approaches listed
above is that the simulation is achieved
by giving the simulator a complexity
advantage over the environment
as a consequence the simulation is not
efficient and cannot be out cannot be
carried out in uniform polynomial time
and this non-polynomial time simulation
leads to a number of drawbacks the first
is limited environmental friendliness
which was introduced by kinetic impulse
very informally
environmental friendliest means that the
non-polynomial time simulation as can be
seen on the right side may affect the
security of other protocols that are
executed concurrently
as an example think of the superpower
normal time simulator creating a
commitment that may have an adversary in
another protocol if the considered
commitment scheme is not malleable
because to see security this does not
happen as the simulator runs in
polynomial time
but there are also there are different
disadvantages for example in the
simulator things for polynomial advice
this advice may contain secrets of
protocols that have started previously
this is true even if these protocols are
secure against non-uniform adversaries
like in the case of uc security
a such non-if non-uniform simulation can
also negatively affect the security of
other protocols which is undesirable
yet another drawback of previous
approaches with limited user usability
support that we construct commercial
commitment scheme that is for example
spseq
because the super polynomial simulation
we can not lock this commitment scheme
into arbitrary uc secure mpc protocols
in the fcom hybrid model because the
simulation can negatively affect
complexity assumptions made inside the
embassy protocol
so the reusability of your z protocols
is limited under
notions that allow mpc in the plane
model
in order to prevent this drawbacks we
use timed assumptions in addition to
polynomial polynomial time hardness
assumptions these timed assumptions can
be broken by a simulator in polynomial
time
as the environment also runs in
polynomial time we can only hope for a
temporary advantage for the simulator in
such a setting
to give you an idea we will use timed
commitments that are extractable for the
simulator at a time and they are still
hiding for the environment
the small advantage is sufficient to
achieve
composibility later on the environment
will also be able to extract such time
commitments
the environment having the same power as
the simulator doesn't have its previous
solutions and has to be account for the
protocol design by transforming a
short-term trapdoor into a long-time
trapdoor
polynomial time simulation doesn't
affect polynomial time hardness
assumptions anymore this leads to full
environmental friendliness currently has
previously started protocols and to use
irreusability
unfortunately we do not achieve full
composibility
by using timed assumptions in addition
to polynomial time hardness assumptions
you can achieve composite embassy in the
plane model with properties that go
beyond the state of the art
our first result is a compositional
commitment scheme in the play model it's
fully environmentally friendly constant
round makes black boxes towards building
blocks only and can be constructed from
standard and center times hardness
assumptions
also the simulation is uniform
within this commitment scheme we
construct a composable general embassy
protocol in the plane model with the
same properties
and by using time targets assumptions we
are the first to achieve these
properties in the plane model
last but not least we also propose
variant of uc security to analyze the
security of all constructions this
notion is called t-lock it's a short for
time lock you see
in contrast to uc security this allows
the use of time parameters like time
commitment schemes
as t-lock is mathematically a special
case of uc security no changes to the
framework are required
t-lock security is fully environmentally
friendly fully use compatible features
for user usability and the single
instance combination theorem
this concludes my talk and thanks for
your attention
[Music]
so maybe a quick question is that or
you can miss the first part of the talk
but what's the purpose of using just
relying on timed assumptions here
can you sort of uh repeat the question
so what's the purpose of just relying on
time assumptions here it's like is the
notion time that i mean because time
assumptions are only known from us very
specific set of computational hardness
assumptions right
um i'm just trying to understand whether
it's like the notion of time assumptions
is necessary to try to rely on other
more general functions um
the use of timeless samples is very
crucial here so we have seen that
disadvantages of previous results for
compostable mpc
are because the simulator runs in super
polynomial
time so to say and this can affect the
security of other protocols but when
using timed assumptions we can have a
polynomial time simulation and we cannot
achieve this using a polynomial time
hardness assumptions so we have to use
something new like a timed commitment
scheme so this is crucial the reliance
on timed assumptions which can be broken
in polynomial time
so basically to get around the
complexity leveraging issue and actually
you don't have to sort of uh break
things into a moment and that's why you
want to sort of rely on assumptions
yes
could there be any other could you sort
of guess that maybe you could rely on
some other sort of type of hardness
because time thing is like one type of
hardness maybe some other source of
hardness like space risk constraints
issues or some other type of hardness
assumptions where you can sort of rely
on some type of other because basically
you're trying to rely on there should be
a difference between what the adversary
can do and what the reduction can do and
that dichotomy can either be well not
superconducting based or in their case
timed assumptions maybe something else
could be sort part of trying to get the
same things uh yes i think this is very
general approach and of course has been
used for many years so you could
of course explore space hardness
assumptions or something
like that whatever you want but i think
timed assumptions have
seen some use in practice for example in
blockchain so there's at least some
practical evidence like people are
betting money on this literally
but timed assumptions seem to work right
now so i think they are interesting uh
an interesting avenue to pursue and in
our protocols what is nice property is
even if those timed assumptions turn out
to be wrong later after the protocol the
security of our construction is
unaffected so the time the sentence also
need to hold
during the particle execution during a
very short
time frame and later on they may break
down and the protocol will remain secure
as long as your standard polynomial
hardness assumptions which you use later
on the protocol remains secure
okay that's very interesting thanks a
lot gentlemen
so if there are no further questions
let's just move to the second or
the next talk of the session
yeah so
um i think um martin is going to give
the talk martin could you share your
slides please
jeremiah
okay
so the next stop is the mixture of the
zone on community
okay so the next thought is on
communication efficient asynchronous npc
with adaptive security
the result is by annex chopard uh martin
hurd and chen dalm and martin is going
to give the
book um hi everybody
so also this is a multi-party
computation we have the usual setting
and
participate parties are pairwise
previously connected with communication
channels and they want to evaluate some
circuit each input is given by one of
the parties and the outputs are given to
the entitled parties
now the setting we are interested in is
the asynchronous setting which means
that messages on the channels can be
delayed arbitrarily the adversary can
control that but you are interested in
adaptive corruption which means that the
adversary corrupts parties during the
protocol executions
and depending of course depending on on
the information gathered so far and the
security level we're going to achieve is
computational security and in this
setting asynchronous channels and
adaptive products are actually just
asynchronous channels the best possible
corruption threshold is t smaller and
over three
so a lot of work has been done in the
a-string chronosetting it all started
with bernoclem arabian in 1994
and lots of protocols have been
published since then however many of
these protocols only achieve static
security whereas we are interested in
adaptive security until you can see that
in the adaptive setting the best uh
achieved communication complexity so far
is n to the four which means end to the
four messages need to be communicated
per multiplication in the circuit
now so far adaptive security and
information theoretic security was the
same that is all the adaptively secure
protocols actually achieve information
theoretic security and the cryptographic
protocols achieve static security and
what we we ask the question whether we
can do more efficient adaptive security
potentially at the price of
cryptographic security only
our results are the following we provide
two protocols the first protocol
tolerates t smaller and over three
corruptions which is optimal and it
communicates n squared per
multiplication this is the same
communication complexity that was
achieved so far in the static setting if
we do not uh consider some automorphic
encryption or fully homomorphic
encryption and then we have a second
protocol which achieves linear
communication complexity
of n per multiplication however this
protocol has a slightly
lower corruption threshold slightly
below and over 3
and it also has lots of assumptions it
assumes securities non-interactive
serial knowledge proofs and it also
assumes atomics and atomic sent means
that the party can send a message to all
parties it wants at once atomically that
is the party cannot be corrupted during
sending the operation during the send
operation it can be corrupted before or
afterwards but not during the sending
how does our protocol work well we
follow the cdn approach which means that
we assume a homomorphic threshold
encryption scheme for example by a
that's homomorphic only with respect to
addition not with respect to
multiplication and we assume that the
secant
key is shared among the parties
and then we use beaver circuit
randomization technique that is in a
preparation phase we click bear
multiplication triples abc where in our
case as we work with encryptions a b and
c will be encryptions and the plaintext
of a and b multiplied to the plaintext
of c
now how do we do the preparation phase
so in the first protocol we just follow
the standard cdn approach meaning first
each party contributes a value for a and
then the sum of these values will be the
relay and then the parties contribute
values for b and for b and c and the sum
of those values will be the actual b and
c and in each step we do a course hit
agreement that is we choose we choose a
subset of the parties who actually uh
correctly provided their contributions
and we only considered those properties
this protocol has complexity n squared
by multiplication and then in order to
bring this down to o of n we use secret
committees the secret committee is kind
of a setup assumption that means uh that
a party knows that it is in the in a
committee it also can prove so but other
parties do not know who is in the
committee and then only parties in the
first respectively in the second
committee would provide contributions
for a respectively for bc
and in the computation phase we used the
multiplication track of uh the public
reconstruction of dunkirk nielsen for
the multiplication
and now how do we achieve adaptive
security so far i didn't talk at all
about adaptive security in the
preparation phase adaptive security is
for free because we only have random
triples the simulator will actually not
cheat the simulator will execute the
standard protocol so there is no issue
with adaptive security
in the computation phase we use the dm
trig that is we assume there is a k
which is an encryption of one in the
real world and and an encryption of
serial in the simulation and this makes
that all the real encryptions in the
simulation will be encryptions of zero
now we need to talk about how to extract
uh inputs from the corrupted parties we
need to talk about how the simulator can
adjust the output to whatever it needs
to be but this
is just standard technique from dno3
so summarizing we have we provide two
protocols in the paper the first one is
n square complexity the second one with
linear complexity where the second one
has a little bit lower corruption
threshold and has a bunch of assumptions
and it's an open problem to achieve
linear communication complexity in the
asynchronous model with adaptive
security in the standard model
thank you for your attention
[Music]
is how can the secret committees be set
up
well
the easiest way is just uh to assume
this as a setup assumption we have set
up anyway right we need a sharing of the
secret key for the homomorphic
encryption scheme so we we just assumed
this as a setup
are there any follow-up questions to
that or is that uh
that answers the questions okay
so one just to understand what do you
think is the uh
what tricks do you need to sort of get
to this open question
uh what are the barriers to sort of this
quadratic blow up with respect to n
how to bring it down well
i mean what do you feel it's like maybe
it's like this is these are the tricks
that one might need to come up with
what's the value
what is i mean
the computation stage we have is linear
time right it's only about the
preparation what we need in the
preparation phase is that the party can
kind of provide the b and c together
with the proofs and
if you just do this
naturally i mean one one could amortize
there this this would be the standard
approach that people in the swim kind of
setting are doing but if you want to
amortize in the asynchronous setting the
problem is that you will have to uh try
two corset agreements in a row which
means in the first crosshit agreement
you go to a subset of n minus three
parties but then you need a second
concept agreement where you have only n
minus two t parties and in the worst
case this n minus two t parties only con
uh contains one honest party and then we
lose amortization
so it might be that for
slower threshold but probably not
negligibly close to hanover street but
the victoria way one could do linear
complexity
we tried
several attempts but
i mean as you can see we could not
achieve without the committee trick
and maybe like uh this might be a stupid
question but can you advertise against
different runs of the protocol can you
sort of just reuse this uh this sense of
preparation phase right can you sort of
make sure that for different runs of the
protocol you can analyze uh you don't
have to just do the preparation once for
multiple different runs
sorry can you repeat the question so uh
i'm just trying to understand so it's in
the preparation phase that you have to
sort of have this
lower priority can this be reused across
different runs of the protocol
we have to in the preparation phase in
our case it's just
once you produce as many triplets as you
need right it's it's it's just once
you cannot reuse but the preparation
phase actually it's it's not it's not in
blocks we don't have segmentation or
something like that it's not needed in
in this case here
i mean in the synchronous setting when
you look at protocols like dh08 or or
these linear time protocols usually they
would work they would work in blocks and
then they do player elimination dispute
control whatever and then in each block
they have potentially less corruptions
so a block succeeds either or if it
fails then next time we have less
corruptions and things like that we did
not achieve to make it work in the
asynchronous setting
okay yeah thanks a lot
so thanks for the great talk
so i think next stop is also online and
uh can you share your sites please
on efficient perfectly secure
computation with optimal resistance and
this is a joint work between uh
abraham
and abhishe
and gilad is going to give the talk
thank you so um i'm going to talk about
efficient perfectly secure computation
with optimal resilience
uh i'm gillard ashraf from babylon
university and this is a joint work with
italia brown and abhishayana
so uh in the setting of secure community
party communication we have some set of
parties which has some private inputs
and the parties want to compute some
joint function of their inputs while
preserving some security properties
such as privacy correctness and so on
um
we know that any function can be secure
securely computed and one of the similar
results in secure computation
is that of bgw from 88 which shows that
in the perfect settings
semi honest is possible with perfect
security assuming that at most half of
the parties are corrupted
and in the malicious settings we need at
most one third of the parties on crop
what is the communication
um
both of the results are tight and and
perfect security means also that that
vessel can be computationally unbounded
and protocols and descendings are
usually also adaptively secure and
secure under
concurrent compressions once they
satisfy some natural requirements
what's the communication complexity of
the protocol so if you want to compute a
function f we first describe it as an
arithmetic circuit c
and then uh the semi-honest case we have
to pay uh the total communication
complexity of the
the old channels the n squared time
uh the size of the circuit in the
militia's case
it entered the form in the optimistic
case and then to the sixth uh time of
the focus in the pessimistic case and we
have two cases because adversary can
slow down the protocol but cannot um
harm security so optimal is when it
doesn't slow down the protocol and
pessimistic
optimistic has mentalism slow down and
pessimistic is in the case it does
succeed to slow down the protocol
our result so we show how to improve uh
the malicious uh cakes
and we reduce the communication
complexity to enter the three times this
has on the salgado optimistic case and
enter the form time seeing the
pessimistic
so we improve both the optimistic
emphasis semester case
if we want to look at another view of
our improvement is as follows so in the
bgw semi honest
the number of secrets people that the
parties have a shell
is n pair each multiplication
so in total we have n times the
communication complexity of secret of
the sql sharing
per multiplication
in the malicious case we have n square
times the communication complexity of a
stronger signal sharing scheme of
verifiable signature when the dealer can
be malicious and partisans can be
malicious
uh in our case
in our results we show our to improve
and the number of secrets
or values that we have the secret shell
during the malicious case goes down to n
to linear till each multiplication
we also have some bonus and this is an
interesting part of the paper so we show
that um
if we have a circuit g that has n inputs
and m outputs outputs of multiplication
depth one
uh in other words we have some
polynomial of degree two
i want you to think about g as very
large why l and m are relatively small
uh to compute such a circuit vgw
requires the amount of vss that is
proportional to the size of the input
plus the number of multiplications in
the cell kg
we show our um a way to do it the way to
compute it product equal achieves
just the amount of vss that is
proportional to the
size of the input and size of the output
and is independent of number of
multiplications in g
uh another this means in particular the
communication complexity is sublinear in
the circuit size
the the technique for that is somewhat
similar to the r1cs in zero knowledge
and for the best of our knowledge this
is the first time that uh this happens
in the perfect security setting
as an example this is useful
look at consider the task of matrix
multiplication
so this is a task where
let's say i have some matrix a you have
some matrix b and we want to compute the
multiplication of on the two matrices
so if we implement this circuit at least
naively
um the size of the input is m squared
for both of us also the size of the
output
but the circuit itself requires m to the
three
and q multiplications
um
so bgw will require n squared times m
cube the communication complexity of the
ss while our protocol is just n times m
square so we both improve n
and this will work for any circuit
and for some circuits we can apply this
technique where when the circuits are
wide enough
where we can actually also be uh
independent of the number of
multiplications and just look at the
number of wires that we have
some related work so selling is the case
of constant run per multiplication with
perfect security malicious security and
optimal resilience
optimal resilience we mean
in the number of corrupted parties in
number three
in that case we achieve this
communication complexity and to the
three optimistic and to develop
pessimistic
and the one complexity is the depth of
the circuit
there are more efficient protocols if
you look just the communication
complexity
but those are the protocols that are uh
based on the player elimination
they come up with a prize
where uh now the round complexity
is also depends on the number of parties
which essentially means that um
for large circuits
large depth circuits
uh this can be a bit pricey
moreover uh for circuits with
multiplication depth one which is the
task which we are focused on
uh we can obtain communication
complexity that depends only on the size
of the input and output and is
independent of the number of
multiplications and it is unclear if we
can act on those techniques uh
those to this line of protocols
uh so formally i would say if you have
this kind of cell kit
our protocol can be
more efficient if you have large depth
circuit then there's no question that
you need to go on this
on this line of protocols
and that's it
for this talk thanks
um
just a quick question do you think uh
is there a way to combine
your protocol and these other protocols
which has the highest long complexity
just get it get the best of both worlds
i i believe you can you can do things
that um
when you get like a large depth
um
you will use the player elimination
technique um
is it as simple as sort of just a black
box combination of the protocol so it's
like you have to know
no this is uh
it should be a future walk i mean it
could be if you actually walk off yeah
to work on the details and
there should be some kind of a shell
[Music]
so any further questions
now let's start the speaker again
thank you
the next thought is in person talk again
[Music]
so
sixth talk of this session is uh
on the topic of communication models and
best achievable security into around nbc
the talk is the paper is by arushi
kuwait
and rajeev
and how is the talk
uh thanks for the introduction uh hi
again um so this is joint work with
abhishek
[Music]
and rajeev
um so the two main communication models
that are used in the design most
interactive broadcasts
are broadcast
uh our is a broadcast channel that
allows the sender to send the same
message to multiple parties and
point-to-point channels that allow
parties to exchange private messages
with each other
these communication models play a
fundamental role in helping decide what
kind of security is achievable and what
assumptions are needed to achieve those
securities
in the setting we explore the role of
these communication models in the
two-round episode setting
two rounds are considered minimal
for npc since one round is known to be
impossible
and in the two-round setting
a lot of recent works have made
significant advancements in particular
these works
establish feasibility of general
computation in two rounds
while relying essentially on minimal
assumptions
in particular the question that we
consider is the following so in two
round npc in the honest majority setting
where the adversary is only allowed to
corrupt the minority of the parties
what security notions are achievable
in the different communication models
and what assumptions are needed uh for
achieving them
in this work we primarily focus on the
plane model that is without any trusted
setup but sometimes we're going to open
this plane model with an untrusted
public key infrastructure also known as
a peripheral
okay so before diving into the main
results let me quickly recall some
standard security notions that are used
in npc so the most basic one
is of course just privacy against semi
honest or honest but curious adversaries
um for malicious security we have a
range of different uh notions starting
with security with the bot that in which
the adversary might prevent the honest
parties from learning the output by
prematurely avoiding
and this notion itself consists of three
increasingly strong variants
uh the weakest of which is selective
about whether it was might selectively
force some of the parties to abort in
unanimous abode the party is all either
abort or they all agree on the correct
identifiable abort is similar to
unanimous amount with the added
advantage that if the honest parties are
forced to output bond they're also able
to identify at least one corrupt party
that costs the bond
and finally the strongest notion of all
is that of guaranteed output delivery
which ensures that irrespective of the
adversarial strategy the honest parties
are always going to be able to compute
we can also consider a variant of
guaranteed operatively that's against
just field stock adversaries as opposed
to fully malicious according where fail
stock adversaries are ones that behave
like semi-honest adversaries but might
pretty much earlier
and so collectively
we get
these two hierarchies of security
notions
going back to the two-round npc and what
is known about existing protocol so
we're going to consider all of the
security notions that i mentioned on the
previous slide and for communication
models we'll look at the broadcast only
setting the point-to-point only setting
a combination of the two and the
broadcast only setting augmented with
the bare bki
um okay so for semi-honest security uh
we have results uh a feasibility results
in all of these communication models
for fail stop guided output delivery we
have an impossibility result in the
broadcast only setting but do have a
feasibility result in all of the
remaining communication models
similarly for selective abort we have
feasibility results in all communication
models except
the broadcasting resetting
and for unanimous about identifiable
aborting malicious guaranteed
operatively uh we again have
impossibilities in some communications
um
and finally for unanimous support we
have a feasibility result in the
broadcast plus b2b and broadcast plus
pki setting
now together all of these results leave
the question of
feasibility of two-round npc in these
remaining
settings unresolved
and in this work we
provide answers to all of these
questions
thereby completing this picture
in particular we show that
any kind of security with the board in
two rounds is impossible over just
broadcast channels and for this we start
by showing that any two round honest
majority abc over just broadcast
channels in the plane model implies a
two message of libya's transfer protocol
uh if you start with the seminar on this
protocol we end up with a semi-honest
oblivious transfer protocol and if we
start with a malicious one we end up
with a malicious photo
and this complication holds both in the
plane model and in the crs model also
this implication helps justify the use
of ot in the work of carcatol and
venomoud oil in their design of a
semanas protocol in the broadcast only
setting
um
next we prove that a two message
maliciously secure ot is impossible in
the play model and these two results
combined show that any kind of militia
security in the broadcast only setting
is essentially impossible
um in the broadcast and p2p setting we
show that even identifiable abort uh is
impossible
and on the positive side we show that
guaranteed opportunity and hence
identifiable abort are both
uh achievable in the broadcast spki7
and so now together these results help
us establish the following hierarchy of
communication models in the two-round
setting
starting with the broadcast plus pki
setting which allows us to uh achieve
the strongest notion that is guaranteed
up ability uh slightly weaker than that
is broadcast plus point to point uh then
point to point and the weakest of them
is the broadcast only setting that only
allows us to achieve the amount of
security
thank you
any questions
[Music]
so maybe if i can ask a quick question
so uh
do you know about the model where
potentially you use the first round yeah
and so what happens to the picture when
you can sort of uh work in these
non-attractive secure computations where
you can dream
does the picture stay the same or does
it mean uh i don't
know
about the i don't think we know enough
about the
the reusable
especially in the two-round setting um i
uh i mean i could be wrong but i don't
think you even know of a just a simple
malicious basic or protocol in any
communication model
i think that requires some sort of setup
in the play mode
any further questions
okay so thanks again
[Music]
can you share your slides
are you can you can you speak up a
little bit
can you can you see the slides yes yeah
we can see the slides okay
so the last stop of this the the npc
session the first piece of the session
is on generalized pseudo-random secret
sharing
and efficient strategies uh resilient uh
secure computation the work is by
febreze
uh need gilbert levy
and uh
thank you thank you very much for the
introduction
so uh
so this talk is just uh yet another walk
on
on the very popular setting of
multiparty computation with an honest
majority
so in this setting we have n parties who
wish to compute jointly some
functionality over their private inputs
in the presence of t corrupted
properties
and n must be equal or larger than two t
plus one
and the reason why this setting is so
popular because in this setting we can
achieve highly efficient protocols that
are either information theoretic or only
make a black box use of cheap symmetric
crypt
which is what we are interested in this
work
now within the
the owner's majority setting we can
distinguish between two sub settings the
weak honest majority setting where n is
exactly two t plus one which is the
minimum number of parties required to
maintain honest majority and strong
honest modality where n is strictly
larger than two t plus one
and the main question that we ask in
this work is what can we gain in terms
of concrete efficiency from allowing
strong honest majority
now this question may sound a bit
strange at first glance because we are
used to think that in cryptographic
protocols will have a trade-off between
security and efficiency
right and so if we reduce the security
threshold we can achieve we can improve
the efficiency
however this is uh this is not true for
the honest majority setting
and the cities consider the task of
evaluating an arithmetic circuit over
secret shared inputs so the best
seminars protocol that we have in this
in the honors project setting
is the damn gonisol protocol with the
communication cost that is that is
shown here
and over the years it was easier to
achieve militia security uh as we reduce
the threat the threshold but recent
works have closed the gap completely
between semi-honest and malicious
security for both the strong and the
weak honest majority setting
so now the
the cost with malaysian security is
is the same or at least at least in the
amortized sense as as for semi on the
security
so now let's assume that you want to uh
to run a maliciously secure protocol in
the strong ones for those descending so
now we have two options one is to run a
protocol in the stormwater majority
setting but the second will be to let
the parties share their inputs to two t
plus one parties and let them run the
protocol through them and it is almost
straight forward to see that if we if we
will use the second option then this
will yield
uh less communication so it is not clear
what do we gain from running uh from war
from running a protocol in the
stronghold is setting
different direction that has been
considered in this in the setting is to
evaluate multiple gates together at the
same cost of a single gate
and this is done
using pac shamil sql sharing where you
store l secrets on the same polynomial
so now
the degree of the polynomial that we use
throughout the computation is t plus l
and which we denote by dn the number of
parties must be equal or larger than 2d
plus 1.
now if we evaluate smd circuits where
you have a many copies of the same
circuit in parallel then this gives an
immediate improvement by a factor of l
for both communication and computation
which is of course significant
rather for evaluating general circuits
or non-smd circuits previous rows could
only achieve asymptotic efficiency but
with high concrete costs for routing
sequence between blocks when moving from
one layer of the circuit to the next
layer
so a question remains still what quick
what can what can we gain in terms of
compute efficiency
when we want to evaluate
in a general arithmetic circuit
and in this talk
we present in this work we present
several techniques for the strong
management setting where we improve
communication computational cost storage
and latency
all of our constructions are based on
zero the random sql shelling prss
which allows us to generate
cellular random chemical secret sharing
without interruption from a set of
replicated seeds that is distributed
across the parties
now while this
method does not require any
communication the computational cost
scales very fast with the number of
parties and therefore it is efficient
only for small values of t
on the other hand it has many
applications beyond the context of
multiparty computation
so um so we have several technical
contributions so the first technical
contribution
uh is um
here we show how to to generate linear
correlations that can support
computation
of uh non-smd circuits over pac-secret
shelling
which is which are generated using prss
and here we
we are cheap to avoid the routing
mechanism overhead from previous works
completely
our second contribution
is a new general prss construction with
reduced number of seats and reduced
computational cost
uh if the polynomial degree that we are
using is larger than what is required by
the security threshold and the packing
parameter
which we denote by by d so in this case
we are able to reduce the storage and
the computational cost and by achieving
this we are able to extend the number of
parties for which the prss technique is
it can be used
and our third and last technical
contribution is cheap struggle
resilience and here we show that if the
number of parties is larger than what is
required by the polynomial degree namely
that n is strictly larger than 2d plus 1
then we can allow the protocol to
proceed even if not all messages have
arrived in each round of the execution
now this is a straightforward to achieve
with similar security but with malicious
security the this is actually uh
challenging and this requires us
required us to deal with the subject
attack due to ital which we call the
double dipping attack and we
and we present some some new techniques
to deal with it
so
combining these three technical
contributions we achieved
the following two results so the first
of those is appearance prss scheme for
sharing degree d polynomials between n
parties with a security threshold t
where we make a reduction from a problem
called coupling designs
and show that given a solution to that
problem of size k
then our plc scheme requires k times d
plus 1 times n minus t divided by n
pls seeds per party
and this improves dramatically over the
classical construction of primordial
when d is strictly larger than
and in this table you can see
the
the storage cost the comparison between
the uh our work and the claim of our
work
uh for two special cases but in the
paper we give many more data points and
show that we can improve dramatically
over the work
when d is when there is a gap between b
and d
and as i said before uh this result has
many applications beyond the context of
general npc for example threshold
cryptography or secure aggregation which
is important for federated learning for
example or even the simple task of
secure distributed storage where a
dealer wants to signature
a secret across multiple servers and
using pls the dealer only needs to
broker to broadcast the offset between
the um
the secret that was generated using krss
and the actual secret
so so using our
technique we we can do it with the
with less storage and computational cost
and our second result
is an npc protocol so given
a security threshold t tagging parameter
l and number of parties n
we can we share we present a new
protocol to compute any arithmetic
circuit c over a final field f with the
s multiplication gates with the
following features
so first the protocol makes only a black
box use of any pseudo-random function
besides that it is the information
theoretic
the protocol achieves malicious security
against key corrupted parties and tau
lost messages in each epoch where an
epoch is defined by two rounds where p1
or any other designated party sends a
message to each other party and receives
back a message from them
the third property is that if the
parties follow the protocol then it
terminates successfully even if tau
messages
chosen adaptively by the adversary
dropped in each epoch and finally the
communication cost is given uh in this
in this expression
and as you can see it
it is
used as l is increased and in the paper
we put in the comparison where we show
that as we increase
l and and t
then we can beat the best previous
protocols
while achieving struggler resilience
and with this i would like my talk thank
you very much
thank you for the wonderful talk i guess
we're just running a little bit over
time but i think that's okay
so any questions from the room or the
zealot chat
questions
so i guess everybody's eager for
breakfast so thanks
again for the talk and thanks everyone
in the session so feel free to connect
the virtual participants should use
europe to connect and sort of ask more
questions the in-person participants can
sort of this year yeah just talk to each
other over here and let's we will
reconvene in about 22 minutes for the
next session that will be on function
encryption and