hi my name is elon yugev this is joint
walk with alessandro chiesa and this
talk is about tight security balance for
mikali snogs
so let's talk and i'll start with a
brief overview of what our snarks
succinct non-interactive arguments in
the random oracle model
so snarks in a row
so this is a proof system so we have a
prover we have a verifier we have some
language and we have this verifier that
is wondering if this instance x is in
the language
the proof is non-interactive so we have
this single message a proof by that
approval sends and the verifier reads
fine and decides if to accept or reject
um the communication complexity
complexity is going to be succinct so in
in particular the size of this proof pi
is going to be much smaller than the
size of the witness of this np language
um and to get succinctness actually we
have to sacrifice something so what
we're sacrificing is uh the information
theoretical soundness and we're gonna
settle for computational soundness so
what is computation sound is in the
random oracle model
so both the puber and verify have a
common resource this is a truly random
function so this is random the random
function here
it
eats arbitrary strings and outputs a
string of length lambda
and the soundness is as follows
we're going to say that the
the scheme has t epsilon security so it
has two parameters t and epsilon
for instance is not in the language
if for any t query unbounded adversary p
so the adversary has the unbounded
competition in power but is bounded to
at most t queries to this random
molecule so the probability over the
random oracle the disproval outputs pi
that makes the verifier accept the proof
i notice that the verifier has access to
the same random oracle is at most
epsilon okay when epsilon is a function
of t and lambda
so t epsilon security means that if you
perform at mostly queries
you can convince the verifier of a false
statement with probability at most
epsilon
so why do we study snogs or in general
why do we study crypto in the random
oracle model so first this is a very
nice very elegant information theoretic
model okay there's no real computational
assumptions here we have a totally
random function and then things are
information theoretic
um and this allows us to
prove a lot of stuff upper bounds and
low bounds and these pulls are usually
very tight you can even get very very
close to the to like very concrete and
absolute constants
it's not only just a general model we
have some very beautiful constructions
of songs in the room
and you can take these constructions and
if you want to bring them back to to
real life you just heuristically
instantiate the the random oracle with
some cryptographic
cryptographic hash function these are
usually considered as
relatively lightweight crypto it doesn't
involve things like public encryption
and
lattices and so on
and it's actually a very efficient way
uh to get post content security
okay so we have all these attractive
features of slugs in the hall and this
is going to be the focus of this tank
um so i talked about construction so
we're going to focus on i would say the
main construction okay the beautiful
consumption of the of mikali it dates
back to 94 it's going to be
it's a construction based on kilian's
interactive version where he
made it non-interactive using the fiat
mirror transformation
and in a high high level overview the
construction is as follows so uh
what we're gonna do we're gonna take an
information theoretic proof okay in our
case a pcp
we're gonna combine it with a
cryptographic commitment scheme okay
that supports
local openings these are going to be a
merkel hash
and
together what we're going to get is now
so let me spell a few more details about
this
so
um i assume most of you at least
saw or heard about this construction but
i want to take you step by step
because we need to see a few details
so the approval is going to start by
writing a pcp for the statements okay so
this is a pcp
that can convince the verifier that
indeed x is in the language okay the
problem is that the pooler cannot send
this entire pcp because it's too large
instead the prover is just going to send
a commitment to this pcp okay so it
computes this miracle milk entry of this
pcp and it computes this mercury using
the random molecule of course
now
um
the verifier is supposed to
pick randomness okay for the pcp that
will tell him which query locations he
wants to read
and we do not allow interaction here so
we're going to let the random oracle
simulate the verifier okay this is
called the fiat trimmer transformation
so the approval is going to query
the route
okay so after he committed to the pcp
he's going to query this vote the
commitment
okay so he's going to apply the random
molecule to the root and use use the
output of the random okay to derive pcp
randomness
okay so once approver has this pcp
randomness he knows what what are the
query locations that the verifier wants
to see and the proof is going to contain
the root
a of the pcp all the pcp answers okay
that correspond to to this location and
for each answer an authentication path
that assures us that indeed
the pcn pcp answer that he wrote here
corresponds to the pcp that underlies
this root
okay so this is the the part of the
of the pool what is the verifier gonna
do well he's to verify that the pcp
answer so it's going to run the pcp
verifier okay on this to to to make sure
that the pcp is fine and then it's going
to check for each symbol okay in this
answer it's going to check the
authentication path to to make sure that
indeed this is what the approval
intended to send
so what is the size of this pcp or
very roughly speaking
it's the number of queue it's the number
of queries of the pcp q okay so we need
to um to open each location
and for each location you have to send
roughly a login nodes okay on the on the
three and each node has a lambda bits
output so this is roughly the size of
the proof
okay
what about soundness how do we improve
soundness of
of this scheme
so again we you use some underlying pcp
okay so suppose you initialize the
scheme with a pcp with soundness epsilon
pcp
okay
the best soundness expression and known
is actually due to bcs a few years ago
and we're gonna denote the soundness
with epsilon arg okay this is the
soundness of our argument scheme
and as we said it's a function of of t
and lambda
so the best sound this question knows is
the following soundness
okay so we have t times epsilon
t times epsilon is it comes from
the arrow of the pcp so a cheating
pooler can just try to convince the pcp
verifier okay you can do this say by
just choosing a random proof and hoping
that the verifier would be convinced
okay and each time you might lose the
probability of lambda and he can do this
roughly two times okay because this is
his query budget
and he can try to attack the random
oracle for example you can try to find
collisions and that's why he's not
really committed
to any specific string
and to rule out this
you have to assume that he didn't
do magical things like find collisions
or inverted random oracle and you use
you lose this probability that comes
from the birthday paradox
okay
and the
main question that we want to ask is is
this tight is this expression tight
okay this is going to be the focus of
this walk and i want to point out that
the negative answer would be excellent
news because if this expression is not
tight and you can actually prove a much
tighter expression
and this intent would yield a small
argument size okay and we're going to
see this
so
this part already hinted is actually
tight
um so the the cheating pool can try to
convince the pcp verifier
roughly two times okay and each time he
might actually lose uh
an error of epsilon pcp
okay so we have like a matching attack
for this expression
for this expression the answer is
unclear
okay
so this tells us that the for example
the cheating pool is not going to find
any collision
but what about vice versa can you attack
the scheme if you are given a single
collision
so i want to pinpoint on this question
and
i want to show you that the answer to
this question
actually depends on the fine details of
the construction
and if you're slightly careless with the
implementation
then
one collision is actually very harmful
okay so let's try to see this so
consider the micalli construction okay
and suppose we have a binary pcb okay so
this is the pcp string here
okay i never really think of padded up
up to length lambda okay because we want
to hash
two lambda bits to lambda bits this is
the milky hash
the medical tree
um
so if this is the construction then we
can reuse a single
zero and one collision okay so you can
find the collision in the leaves between
zero and one
and you can reuse this uh collision
everywhere
okay so if i found the collision here
i can use the same collision here and
here and here and here and so on
so in this case i'm almost not committed
to any location of the pcp
so i can commit to something
random using this collision
and then when i see the
the queries of the verifier i can just
open in a way that makes him
accept
and if this is the case then the
soundness is actually optimal okay we
just have to rule this out and we have
to assume that he found no collision
however
um this can be truly avoided by adding
indexes
so when i mean adding indexes we're
going to add a prefix i j
for every node okay to the value of
every node okay these are like constant
prefixes that
that just mentioned their location in
the tree okay so the leaves are going to
be layer one okay so we're gonna add the
the one and then we have like this is
node the one and this is the first node
in level one this is the third node in
level one
and so on
uh and now you can ask
is the sound is optimal
um
so let me just mention that once i find
that collision here
okay i can actually i can't reuse it
here okay because the prefixes are going
to be different
so collision here doesn't give me
anything here and if i want to find the
equilibrium here i have to walk again
and find the new collision okay so i
cannot reuse my computation
and more importantly i cannot reuse the
success probability so if i had some
success probability of finding a
collision here the probability that i
find many many collisions is going to
decrease very fast
okay so with this implementation in hand
okay with the
with the prefixes i can state our
results so we give a negative answer to
this question and we show that the it's
not tight okay
remind you that negative answer means
good news
okay and what we do we actually show a
tight security bound for mikali
so our main theorem is that the
security expression for mikali is the
following the same t times epsilon that
we had before okay but instead of this t
squared over 2 to the lambda we have t
over 2 to the lambda
okay and we have some other small
expression here that replaces the four
okay c capital c
which depends on l the length of the pcp
and log sigma where sigma is the
alphabet of the pcb
okay so this is the expression we have
and this expression holds provided that
lambda is not too small okay so it has
to be at least 2 log t
we show an almost matching low bound so
this is tight and even inside c this
expression is almost tight
okay so we have a matching low bound
and as i promised this has implications
on the argument side size
so using the previous analysis
if we wanted t epsilon security we had
to set lambda to be log t squared over
epsilon
okay this is what you get if you
require the success probability to be at
most epsilon
using our analysis we can set a lambda
to be the maximum of these two
expressions but you can see that it's
smaller than this expression okay
so let's say that this is the maximal
one depending on the values of t and
epsilon
the lambda has to be only log t squared
and not log d squared over epsilon
and again this gives us a smaller
argument size because as we said before
this is the argument size is q times
lambda times log n so these two things
are like a constant and we we are making
a lambda better so any factor that we
improve here we we
gain the same factor in the argument
size
um we worked
quite hard to make sure that all the
constants and our theorems are very very
tight okay and have a very concrete and
good concerns
and what we show is we get actually
computer efficiency as well so in this
table we're comparing our analysis to
the best pile analysis of mikali so we
took the the same
pcp with soundness and some proof length
okay 2 to 30 and we amplified it and
depending on the tn epsilon you can show
you can see the results here so in red
this is the size of the argument in my
color schemes and in blue it's uh it's
all skin
and you can see that overall depending
on the values of t and epsilon we get a
improvement between
20 to 40 percent
okay
um another thing that i want to mention
this tight analysis actually led us to a
new construction okay so this is a
significant wall that you can
see in the last crypto
and the new construction took the tight
analysis and managed to overcome and
circumvent all the bottlenecks in the
analysis
and what we got is that the the new
construction has a has sound is just t
times epsilon okay with with the same
requirement on lambda
and this actually gives a much better
argument size both concretely and
actually even asymptotically
and i really welcome you to see the
paper on imprint
okay
so now i want to
dive back in to our construction
in the analysis of our construction
so first how the prior analysis worked
okay so we wanted security and we call
it snugs right
what we did usually
is we wanted to say okay the commitment
scheme is really a commitment scheme so
we had to assume
okay or condition on the event that
there are no collision and no inversions
okay and that's why we lost this
probability in the soundest
once we have this then really the
cheating proverb has nothing
he or she can do
except to
commit to some
pcp string and hope that the verifier is
convinced okay so the security from this
point on is reduced to the soundness of
the pcb
in our case
we want the security of mikali snarg but
we cannot just condition on not finding
collisions or inversions okay and we
have actually have to keep showing that
soundness
holds
even when the pool will find collisions
or inversions
okay what we're going to do instead
we're going to score the collisions
joining belgians
okay and we're going to bound the
probability that he finds more and more
collision to inversions
and then given a specific esco
we're going to see
how harmful this disco is okay so we're
going to have some new game that we call
trees on this game
and this game has got is going to have a
specific budget and we're going to bound
the probability of the adversary to win
given this specific budget
and we're gonna um
do this bound using a reduction to
another type of game that we're gonna
call that we call it reverse on this
game
and this game will reduce back to pcp
soundness
okay so the analysis is very modular in
this uh and this approach this game
really describes
all possible strategies that adversary
can do
and this is an intermediate and very
simple game that allows us to to reduce
all these possible strategies to
something very simple in this game we
can like say something very meaningful
just using the pcp service
okay so now i'm gonna dive in
these steps okay to give some additional
details and we're going to start with
the scoring collisions and inversions
okay so we're in this part of the proof
um so we introduce a scoring function
okay the scoring function is a function
of the query traces of the algorithm so
suppose you have achieving prover you
can look at his
it's a query trace okay and then you can
give a score to this square
query please
and the scores are going to allow us to
quantify the soundness even in the event
of collisional intelligence okay so
let's first talk about the skull okay
what school do i give to a specific
trace okay if the trace hack contains
nothing interesting it's not going to
get the scope it's going to get it's
going when i see some rare events okay
so one example of we have two kinds of
irrelevant one the first one is
collisions okay so if i see a collision
i'm going to add one to the scroll
okay and i have to define this slightly
more precisely okay so what happens if i
see a k-wise collision okay these are k
elements that all collides with the same
value it's going to get a k uh a score
of k k minus 1.
okay i'm going to add all these scrolls
so this more or less counts the number
of collisions in a given place
okay the second thing is going to be
about inversions
okay so inversion is another thing we
don't want the adversary to do because
then he can
start by querying the root and seeing uh
and seeing the queries and then walk his
way back and just derive the pcp that he
wants that
that convinces a specific verify
okay
so we're going to count the number of
inversions so inversion is going to be a
response y
okay the hit a previous query x1 x2 okay
so remember that queries are rehashing
two elements to one okay we go with
another tree
um so what we don't expect is to see a
an answer
that hits something that we queried
before okay this is also reverted and
we're gonna
and we're going to count these
and given this scoring function
uh what we claim and what we show in the
paper is that any t algorithm
for any query algorithm the probability
that this that the score is more than k
is bounded by something that
you can already see comes from the
birthday paradox to the power of k
and this thing this thing is not going
to be very small so this thing is going
to be like a constant so the probability
that he finds a collision in our
analysis is actually going to be some
constant okay so we can
most definitely not rule out the
event that he finds a collision okay but
the probability that you find case
collisions this already decays
exponentially faster than k
okay
so before i go into the other parts okay
the three sounders and i think i just
want to show you how
using this and we're going to have a
step that you're going to believe and
i'm going to
show you later okay how i can conclude
the proof okay so this will show why
this is useful
so what is the probability that the
verifier accepts okay suppose that x is
not the language and i want to bound the
sound cell
so this thing i can always do i can
always do this infinite sum and say okay
it's the probability that verify accepts
conditioned on
the adversary okay getting a score of at
most k
times the probability of getting a score
of mos k
okay so this is just a sequence of the
infinite sequence of events and i can
just sum up the probabilities of all
these
all of these things
okay so this is using the scoring
function
so now
now i can focus on one specific k and
ask what is the probability that the
verifier accepts okay what the
probability that the chi chi approval
succeeds
if
i condition on him getting a score of at
most k so if k is three means i cannot
find four collision he has a budget of
three collisions so what's the
probability of succeeding with this
specific budget this is exactly why we
introduced this game threesomeness game
okay so this is really by by the
definition of the three sounders game
yeah okay
now this is a step that of course i
didn't show yet okay
and this is going to be lemma 1 plus 2
okay that we're going to just briefly
see uh and this uh the probability of
getting the scope okay this is the claim
that we we have on the
underscoring function
okay and we're going to see this
expression and just maybe just point out
already that what we see here is this is
actually the cost we get from collision
so we have the same t in epsilon as
before okay as in the original
a sum this expression of mikali but we
pay another factor here of two to the k
okay because if he has a score of k this
gives them a lot of power it gives them
exponential and k
power okay and this is going to come
from the inversions part
but now we can just take everything that
depends on that doesn't depend on k we
can take it out and we just get this the
same expression okay just rewritten
differently
and then when we look at this infinite
sum okay that depends on k and now here
comes the condition that lambda is
slightly more than 2 log t then this
infinite sum is going to converge and
we're going to be left with the
the soundest expression that we want
okay
so really what's missing
is for me to give you analysis why if
you're limited to a budget of k
okay in this three sounds game uh i i
need to give you some bound in the
of the soundness of this game
okay
and lemma one plus two is going to be
about the three soundness and the
reversal
okay
okay so now we're moving on to the three
sounders game
so we introduce this intermediate
information theoretic game okay place on
this game it has two parameters okay t
is the number of the actions okay this
corresponds to number of queries that
varsity has it's okay in the game it's
the number of the actions he can do and
k is some bad budget okay it's going to
be the collision and inversion budget
the game is planed on a graph okay it's
blended it off
and uh
and
in in every you have this infinite loop
where the approval can choose one of two
actions okay the first one is adding an
edge the second one is deriving pcp
randomness okay we're gonna see this in
a second
every time he chooses an action the the
budget t decreases by one okay and when
we get to zero we stop
uh okay so what is this graph
so the graph already contains
all possible nodes
and the what the cheating pool can do it
can add edges from this set
okay so this is the complete
set of edges and you can choose one and
add it to the gulf
so what are these edges
so
remember in the construction we have the
prefixes i and j okay so every node we
know exactly where it is okay so these
are these i and j's here okay so we have
levels
and the i is going to be the
the level of the node
okay so we're always connecting nodes
from level i to two nodes in level i
plus one okay for example here so we
have
this is level i and two nodes in level i
plus one
okay and if you connect it to some
position j and these are the
corresponding positions okay in the next
level
and the h values are just like the the
actual hash the output of the oracle
this is something that he can completely
uh specify
okay
so
this is the complete set of edges and
you can choose from here and add it to
the graph
however we didn't talk about the budget
okay what happens to the budget key
okay so if he just adds an edge let's
say he added this edge fine he just adds
it and t decreases by one okay
what happens if he adds a collision
okay so let's in this example here okay
we have the node u and he added this
this edge here and the v primes okay so
we have a collision here
uh he's allowed to do that okay but each
time he does this the um the collision
budget decreases by one
okay and of course once we got to zero
that's it okay it cannot continue beyond
zero
okay so that was the easy part what
about inversions
uh inversion is
is a the harder part to add okay so the
problem also has a budget of k
inversions
and this is slightly harder to model
because
a single inversion actually
allows him to win
okay so if he can invert something he
can just
er er he can just a a computer root and
then compute the corresponding pcp that
is good for this root and then just
invert back the function to connect the
two
so we're not gonna allow
arbitrary inversions okay or or
something called strong inversions these
are gonna be disallowed okay instead
what we're gonna allow is weak inversion
okay i'm gonna try to um tell you what
is the difference so
a strong inversion is gonna be when i
have some
value y okay and i wanna find some x
such that f of x equals y this is a
stronger version okay i particularly
inverted y
okay corresponding to this function if
what is a weak inversion okay which is
allowed the weak inversion is where i
give you a large subset okay of y one y
one up to y m
and then you're gonna
find x that inverted one of them
okay this is a much easier task and this
is going to be
allowed
and let me show you how this goes back
to the graph okay
so
if the prover wants to add an inversion
okay
so inversion is adding a um an edge to a
part of the graph that's already
connected okay
then he can specify inj
but he cannot specify h
okay so if this node here is already
connected and he wants to add now this
to this edge here connected to here this
would be an inversion okay
so he can specify i and h but he cannot
specify the specific h of this node
instead
h is going to be sampled from the
all possible potential capital h
okay so what is capital h
so
capital h is going to be all the h's
for which this node i i j h
he cannot connect to okay if there's
some h such that i j h is just free and
it can connect to and it's not
considered inversion then fine just just
do that okay you take all the nodes that
all are already connected to some
component and this is going to be the
capital h okay
and now an edge is added only with
probability the size of this capillary
is h over 2 to the t
okay if you're slightly confused let me
give you two examples i think they'll
make things easier so
when h equals one let's say just started
and have only one node that's connected
to something and he wants to do an
inversion
but then sure you can say listen i give
you ij i want to do this in version and
capital h contains only this particular
node okay so this is actually a strong
inversion okay so right this is a strong
inversion but we're going to add this
edge only with probability one over two
to the one over two t
okay and maybe more importantly i want
to i want to mention that every time he
he does this
the inversion
a budget decreases by one regardless of
whether the edge was added or not
okay so you can try to do a strong
inversion but it's going to happen with
very small probability and it costs him
an inversion budget
okay
the other side
he can make h very large
okay you can make h the largest possible
is t okay you can have it most t and
nodes connected because it has to
connect them first
this would be a very weak inversion okay
but it's added with probability half
okay so you can have you can have many
potential nodes and then you're going to
be you're going to add the edge with
higher probability
okay but your edge is going to be added
to a randomly
a node from h
so you cannot really specify exactly
where the inversion is going to be you
have a big bucket of nodes potential
nodes you say i want to inversion with
one of them and with high mobility you
have an edge that connects a random one
okay so this is like the trade-off
between a strong and a weakened version
and of course he can do anything on this
trade-off that he wants
okay so that was the three soundness
game and the threesome's game really
captured all possible
strategies of the adversary and that's
actually what we show we show that any
adversary for the original snog we can
translate to an adversary in the
threesomes game
and now what we do we introduce a new
game okay and i'm gonna present it here
a very simple form of this game called
reveal soundness
and what we show we reduce every a
adversary to the of the trees honest
game to the to adversary to this reverse
on this game so the reverse on this game
is the following it's called the veil
sounders because we're gonna reverse the
roles of
in a standard pcp your first committee
of pcp and then you choose randomness
right and we're gonna verse this so we
call it reveal
songs so the game is as follows though
we start where the game first stamp is
row one up to ot
okay so this game has some parameter t
and these randomnesses these are
randomnesses of the
pcp verifier
okay so we start by sampling randomness
for the pcb verifier okay very weird but
we sample a lot of them okay so one up
to volte
only then okay this is given to the
proven okay and the prover as a function
of these randomnesses he submits a proof
by
okay
but then the game samples a random index
i
okay and the prover wins
if pi conditions the pcp verifier with
randomness or i
okay so we choose a lot of randomnesses
the prover as a function of this chooses
the proof pi and then we choose a random
one okay
and he wins if
if pi convinces the pcp identifier with
on the missile line
okay this is very similar to the
weakened version we talked about earlier
and our main result here is that we show
that
you can reduce three soundness okay you
can do the the successful ability of
achieving improvement in the threes on
this game you can reduce it to the
reverse on this game and then you can
reduce this back to the standout pcp
soundness
okay so let me just specify the two
lemmas
so if we have epsilon 3 that is a
function of t and k okay so you have t
actions and k is the budget
the reverse soundness has only this one
parameter okay t
okay and the first letter says that
uh the winning probability in the three
soundness game is this expression
okay so it's t times epsilon pc because
i can always just try okay and actually
every time i try have a advantage of two
to the k okay these are because of the
collisions
and i have this additional term this
comes from the inversions so i have 2 to
the k power times my probability in this
reverse soundness game
okay and these are the two inversions
and then the second lemma says that okay
what is this epsilon reverse okay this
epsilon reverse actually something we
can bound
and this bound actually just depends on
the parameter of the pcp such as the
the length of the pcp and the alphabet
provided that the pcp that you use had
has a good enough soundness
okay so it's not like a smooth
expression with in terms of epsilon pcp
but once you have this condition we can
bound down the levels on this
and now you plug these things in back in
the original explosion that you we saw
and we can conclude the proof
okay so conclusion we gave a new and a
tight analysis of michael snod this is a
new upper bound and a matching lower
bound
and to do that we had to introduce some
new pcp games which i think is uh
are interesting on under on right in
particular this river sounds game
uh we actually
got something we got a new we got new
and smaller argument sizes okay both
theoretically and practically
um
some ideas for future work first what we
do what we did apply to nikoli snog and
of course if you want something really
efficient and practical you're not going
to implement the mikali that uses pcps
we're going to integrate a new modern
version of it called the bcs where the
construction is a similar in spirit but
it's it's based on iops
okay so iops this is an interactive
version of pcps and they're much much
more efficient in a lot of research
these days than iops
um so the idea of future work is
actually taking what we did for one
round okay i've been calling three and
apply it to bcs
where you have many rounds and in each
round you have this three okay so you
would have to
uh kind of define the interactive
version of these pcp games okay to be
like iop games
uh
second thing is that
as we already mentioned we can take this
tight analysis and this gave us a lot of
the ideas uh for a better construction
with the smaller argument size okay so
future work let's continue this let's
find better construction of snarks in
the random oracle model and i didn't
find this explicitly but there is the
very big open problem of can you achieve
a linear argument size of snugs in the
random oracle model so both the mikali
and the bcs construction have something
called the quadratic argument size which
i did informally
define
but the hope is that the titan title
analysis
could lead us to a linear argument size
which would be very amazing
so with this i end thank you very much