ok hello everyone
saw the title of this talkies arlen
zombie apocalypse by Alexander please
read him in the dark
hi and welcome everybody my name is
Alexander Merkel amateur radio call sign
thanking you for seven times we went
from extreme and today I want to talk
about
automatically establishment and the
zombie apocalypse first let me ask are
there any ham radio operators in the
audience today no yes it's very from New
York nice no Europe your short list the
right ok that's very that's great so
that part of my hobby and I'm very glad
to see you here today of course
statistics with say that somebody will
be a ham radio operator after order to
millions of us know a little bit of a
small state worldwide I think some
700,000 in the us- and I promise to talk
a little bit about in our
interconnection between Meridian the
parking movement
thinking it does have some some
connecting points to but I'm going to be
going to get back to that I promise in
the end of the presentation but let's
start with with this first so the
automatic link establishment of zombie
apocalypse so I didn't want to make it
you know too boring because the usual if
you're getting cold when there are some
unusual things happening for example
flaws which lies to reach must have laws
here and amateur radio operators give
their best to make communication
interrupted
you know we will do our part when there
are some dangers and Unitech a reliable
means of communication so basically when
you have a zombie apocalypse what
happens is that ok so the question of
danger in this hypothetically dangerous
insulation does not come from the
zombies themself it comes from the other
people in a slow they're still be there
is instinctively drive and and you know
to watch for the large numbers large
quantities of them in in the groups but
the largest threat is from the other
people meaning you can have more orders
groups that wants to go to your group
and to take what you have or to pillage
and plunder everything that is around
there is no rules there are no laws and
you are probably going to be with
weapons dangerous so the first thing you
have to consider is how to protect
yourself your small group was up to kill
her family or small group of friends and
you want primarily to defend from the
other people also of course you have to
know the rules of the zombies and you
know the answer is also presented from
them but mainly from the other people so
the people are the problem and we're
talking about the strategy here I don't
mean that by saying that it absorbs
something he does certainly but in this
way I want to mention one of the
curious things about the suspenders you
know if you put it through the city but
not your ordinary regular sitter from
the kitchen but it's actually going to
be a real threat of something like this
silk material separated to a single
cells and what happens then is very
interesting
all those things tend to gather together
and to bring back the sponsor again in
the format that it was so I
civilization is like that so we have a
sudden impact of something which
disrupted the civilization in entirety
meaning zombies and you know the stuff
to do everything communication
connection between people and everything
you know nothing works but just the
initial wave meaning that it has to
settle and then the civilizations going
to present itself is going to try to
assemble itself again so your best
strategy would be too many Kevin already
have a small group you should try to
conquer all of the other groups and to
make europe larger and larger as large
as possible you know and then bring your
old so-called blood see a doctor they
thrown those groups you're not no longer
at War II and you can start rebuilding
the government the civilization and that
the system again so that would happen
definitely so you know like this guy I'm
not even going to try to pronounce his
name but you know he founded the largest
empire that ever existed if you can't
land mass but it did that by conquering
small groups by another one by another
and in the end he created largest empire
largest them prominent part of the 10
imparted ever existed
other questions call to retain that and
how to govern that's a separate question
but that is what you want you want to be
like like him in the case of zombie
apocalypse so let's talk about in that
event of the zombie apocalypse or any
unforeseen event you want to hear
communication which is reliable that is
the top priority so you want to care for
example if you order a new groups like
if you make them like you care of your
troops viewer generals whatever you have
to control them and you can't to convey
the information about commands but they
have to do to them and this is actually
tactical operation tactical sorry
tactical communication meaning that you
have to be able to send the data to them
but let's consider for the theater of
the zombie apocalypse for this case just
to be there in europe not some small
regional something like that not entire
world problems going to happen in Cairo
but let's consider youre so you have to
communicate
large businesses meaning at least 1,000
kilometres more couple thousand
kilometres and you have to have a
reliable real communication of conveyor
orders to troops will do that for
operational communications of course if
you want to run was the best with
communication at all of course it is
shortwave radio 2 Way Radio talk about
key or do we call it also
if you want simplicity for example
tomorrow the guys from my comedy clubs
are going to be here we go to be a
little bit of a horse open you know just
retreating about anything that you want
to know about it we're going to bring
couple of radio stations and do the
digital come radio operation modes if
you want something simple you can't or
more Scott you know because you can
build transmitter for more cool Morse
code which can be heard
15 kilometres something like ten miles
away by just using five elements in 02
of resistors and resistor with general
purpose transistor and remember one
capacity or something like that so five
elements and you can be online you can
just meet you can call for help you can
scavenge for example if your plane
crashes you can skip those parts are
very commonly founded in any kind of
authority can make it through sleater so
but what today is not an operational
communications but on the tactical
communications meaning on the
communication for a long range so let's
talk about that automatically link
establishment automatically establishes
what it is and what it does is basically
started as a us- government and military
standard so it is you know it is open
you can read it you can implement your
own versions and I'm going to take this
opportunity because it's a lot of young
and smart people here so far software
for our government to talk about so
after a little bit later but only for
Windows operating system there is a
fortunately no implementation of four
leanings of our controller so 3
controller so if anybody's interested
you know everything is open you can read
the specification you can read
you can help you know always actually
something which American military and
government use their for example
separate implementation for a marine
corps' Marcella and what it does I know
how much you probably don't know about
radio waves you know how they travel the
problem with a jeffrey delays for high
frequency radio waves is that while they
cannot they can travel large distances
for example my local club here the
connection directly nor direct to a
connection
expedition on the South Pole director
election from some god forsaken city in
this region with the South Pole
expedition without any you know without
any relays without any anything in
between so it can go very very long
signals can travel in two ways so you
hear one component of the syllabus goes
almost straight line and is going to get
you probably some couple of Conduct
record kilometers but what is
interesting is the second component of
the HSE
actually goes toward the space and then
bounces off the youngster so it bounces
maybe a couple of times and it can reach
very very distant lands so easily
the problem with this is that it is very
unstable meaning that it is not like a
telephone you know it depends so many
things and this is what makes a good
home radio operator you know you have to
know all these things to be able to
switch for example the frequencies for
example some of the frequencies that do
not work at night or some of the free
classes for example 21 murders is very
dependent on the solar flares so when
you hear a large number of spots every
11 30 years you have a solar maximum and
then you can talk with Japan using 21
murder hurts like you're talking with my
phone is very very good quality is high
but when it starts decreasing then you
cannot do anything you cannot hear you
just pack your antenna for twenty-five
medical school next 11 years and
remember you could always the problem
the american government wanted to solve
is they didn't want to have highly
skilled operators to depend on them they
wanted to just the media operators and
to empower them to use HFE no reliable
Mandir so if you don't have a reliable
communication however you can you can
communicate over large distances but if
you can do it
reliable than it is so so we're going to
talk a little bit more about how it
solves that the terms but you can of
course be there is we can operate by
voice or text messages or even you know
you hear something which is called pilot
stations which you install some BBS
author and then you can leave messages
for somebody else who use the station
for example nice nice application of
alan was in Sandy's storm and one of the
when everything goes down you know
civilization of fragile very fragile so
when something unforeseen happens on a
large scale you're going to lose your
fault you're going to lose your
connectivity interest in going to lose
everything that you take for granted and
what is left is this you know you can
take your stay connected to the car
battery and operated straightaway you
can move it you can do whatever you can
to communications so yes I'm not going
to go too deep into the tools there is
no time for that but as I say you're
smart people and they're plenty of
information about this just to notify
you that this exists if you don't know
you know it's interesting thing it is
usable and it has a community which
growth meaning in seven years ago there
was a network of global our network is
called a href link it if the target
thing but i think in the end of the
presentation so let's talk about how it
works you have a couple of antennas for
example of per device for example for
714 three and a half and 21 mayor and
the other guy also couple of an illness
and what happens is the software and the
hardware devices for its cold out of
control or if you have a softer
controller it is embedded in the station
itself those very expensive for us from
radio operators prices went down but
still there are not too you know
available usually the government or the
military use them and then you don't
have to worry or you can use and what it
does is this
periodically your station scans all of
the available frequencies and just
leases if there for example I have to
mention this first all of the radio
operators have their cool science my
from textfree and my oldest patient with
Michael sign over the same day as my
station in everyone who wants to contact
their thing and it works like this
my station for example and if for
example your status which could be
killed on 9 November November what it's
just going to remember the frequencies
it was first for example you tell us 43
is going to record in a local database
ok I heard that station on three makers
the nice to see this error issue and I'm
going to determine that was the best
channel to communicate with you just
remember that and just cancel every 10
seconds something like that it does make
contact yet he just makes the basal you
know who is around here and when you
want to call the other station goes like
this for example she wants to call my
radio station just centers
specific types of my callsign side of
the radio station if her computer
connected to the registration and
connected via the soundcard basically
and then she talks in michael c what
happens next
of radio ways and actually going to call
my name my station still scarce
all non-free Chris's and sees the first
two letters from my callsign and then it
stops Kenny and then all of the other
letters are like mark Michael side and
is going to know that some stations ok
let me stop and then is going to because
that her station is going to sound is
called sounding when you win the trust
me so it's going to sound her call
saying also and the stages are going to
automatically do the handshake protocol
established in either operator
even Beshear is going to building and
she can send me message for example
there is a disaster situation and they
have to fight with my crossbow actually
do have a couple of both but not the
crucible and violent fighting them that
message is here with me for me and I
come back I can read it so the stations
are linked and in the end of the
communication when she wants to
terminate that link that communications
and all she has is that so it is not
automatically sending out the former
something you have to click on certain
but so my station is free again for the
other station but it's interesting here
is for example shit is intense I have
three intense for different free classes
and what happens if for example 3 makers
goes down it is very bad reputation for
teenagers to the given time
automatically our system is going to you
know always assess the quality of doing
is going to say ok this is not good
letters disconnect from this dream a
first and let us connect that works that
episode so I don't have to worry about
you know
communications sustaining the connection
that's very important because when
you're doing that LIKE operator manually
you know you always have to agree with
let's go on other cured Ryu other
frequency let's let's let's schedule you
know this for you don't have to worry
about that at all so this allows
operators to do much more things much
more we could you know just manually
this just makes us better meaning that
we can single operator can handle
multiple networks because you can also
make using our that's very important
because of a massive network you have
announced and every node can speak to
each other in if I don't see him for
example through this you know it's very
reserved
resultant rhetoric so it is very usable
in emergency situation and it is used in
emergency situation but this is how it
works and this short diagram showing you
know that you can hear a mobile station
UK stationary station or whatever they
are they all are equal but there are
some of the specific station that they
mentioned already called the pilot
station they have a specific software
install of them on them
which station there are available 24 7
all around the year so you can use them
like you know like you would use any
other node but you can also use them as
a relay race or whatever or the usually
something which is called BBS link
software installed on them so you can
you know you can connect SMS messaging
to them you can send emails by pilot
station even if you don't have the
activity you can say for example jungle
whatever you need to email for whatever
reason and you can do that you can
actually send the information to the
palace station is going to transfer
emails to whoever it has to be just
regular email is not nothing special
just SMTP errors sending something of
course if used that you cannot use it
for spam
is going to be too slow and the other
thing is you cannot use it for
commercial purposes
there is something which is called
products for example of you cannot there
is very interesting presentation from
think it is connected to some digital
modes of communication for home radio
and he's actually just be there it is
interesting but what I wanted to tell to
you is that think about that
products which says you're not allowed
to communicate in cryptography
everything is a plain text and we cannot
encrypt everything so this is the
context of course in the case of zombie
apocalypse
probably bend the rules a little bit ok
so yes this hardware for so is it reads
the most of the radio operators use this
PCR assaulter and it is coupled with the
SSB transceiver
by the sound card meaning the only
interface is you know output input just
sound waves and you connect the mic to
the 22 computer and you connect the
output of the station to computer and
recording and codes and related to it of
course it helps if you have a computer
could get the beach is something which
controls automatically station you know
you can buy click on the button on the
softer that's usually how it works so
here and we which is if you look at
either of the heaviest rain suit for it
it looks very old dated it is in terms
of you know but this multi PSK is even
worse you know you you came as House of
controls and it's very it scales so yes
there are commercial HOF radios Ali
controller already built in it so you
can buy those they're not that expensive
as there are you just started maybe ten
years ago so you don't need to hear the
computer if you have those but you do
like I know one point five thousand
dollars something like that so for
example
one of them those stations i cum 7,000
which is it is I don't think solving in
this case but this waterproof cases
ideal for a case of zombie apocalypse
you know you hear you hear of the
display only thing you hear them
keyboard where you can type in the
messages don't need to have the you know
the computer it is not there so with
this station but of course computer did
so much more freedom and much more
things you can do with it
meaning you can send files for example
during the storm actually one of the
operators communicated across 19 states
with with the families of the people who
are trapped and you know send the list
of the people who are missing or found
in the truth that was the only
communication in the United States
shared for maybe they'll to something
like that and all that is required is
something like this
a little bit of fire maybe I know maybe
twenty metres but it can be anywhere and
you just throw it out the window and
you're good to go to go so just some
agreed frequency going to that much but
just wanted to show that their
agreements on you know you can operate
what you can do and that is also agreed
with the International through unions
you know all sorted out
so this description of our stations are
communicating between there and let us
mention this is maybe the most important
link for our communication it is a chick
flick dot com which represents the
highest reconciling the organization of
all the people using away so it is a
chip network it is I think in USA here's
some maybe fifty to seventy stations in
the region here we do have our network
creation for example in here for some
reason they are not too keen they did
not see the value in there but you know
the neighbors European users so we do
have always station our power station I
think another city he's going to make
power station very soon we thought that
we're going to make it in time for this
conference but not yet what's going to
be operational very solid is going to be
on 10 megahertz and you're welcome to
join in too to see somebody is
interesting from radio is open for
everybody and just to end up going back
to what they promise to you you know
what's the connection between packing
thinking in the ham radio and a little
bit more over history of going going to
take too long you know
well on both sides so lets a subculture
subculture subculture
intelligent people which are driven by
the first thing and on the both sides
have people who are trying to excel and
trying to extend assistance that they
use to make it better to find novel ways
of communication you're very interesting
Communication Workers also interesting
application there is I think / broadband
there is in dire broadband network of
ham radio station connected to Reuters
United States and Europe I'm not sure
but they are in the United States there
is a network of station since meeting
everything over the IP protocols
everything like it should you know just
using the radio stations and so people
who are experimenting who like mystery
for example may be of some of your
current for a number of stations that
something which is not cracked yet you
know there they started cold war-era you
head soviet you hear the German and this
is a test third but if you ask for
details just say something and
moderators what they do is that certain
fratricide certain time over there they
trust me some of those those are voiced
some of those using Morse code and they
do something like this in 0533 2011 stop
maybe 3 33 trust of those and his goals
Lions until tomorrow the other bedroom
number of years nobody knows what they
are you know so there is a mystery there
is a passion for technology for you know
of course we're not most of us rich
people and we have to you know do with
what we have so here you can make your
own just trying to cut the costs you can
make your own and tell us what is good
is that it is interchangeable can be
crossed with all of the other so for
example of a computer scientist and
author programmers who are some radio
operators and they also help you know
this is all so interconnected with the
debt and just going to end with a little
bit of history just bear with me so what
happened is that you know how it became
to be there to stories like a bandit I
don't like that much and one that I like
is it just the first time radio
operators build their stations and they
just the first thing that they found
that was boxer who come which was
usually
box at the times there's the first and
probably unlikely scenario and more
scenario is that a regional telegraph
operators which were fired
telegraphy
just for you know a little bit
professional and the they head towards
the violence operators and they said
those guys did they don't even know
about it called correctly they have a
chance they're good coordination that is
the name radio and to end this also
connected one development of a
disconnect one of the greatest tragedies
in the world which is sinking of Titanic
after the nineteen well before that you
could do whatever you want on the
Terrebonne the 2012 can use whatever
after that
this is going to be a problem people
started to interfere with the
transmission of the other boats of the
government systems everything so they
wanted to know to put the radio matters
aside so they said okay you can use
whatever free courtesy of wavelength 200
metres or less which was considered you
know so they're just going to play and
what happened is that because of him
radio movement exploration of debt
part of the radio spectrum I would like
to think is speeded up and save fifty
years of research in that field because
we do have three million people and who
knows maybe some of you will join the
board thank you guys
any question with us tomorrow villages
be there with the stations and you're
free to work with us to you cannot but
you can see how it goes
all right thank you
my my first question this seems very end
to end you're talking to one of the
stations is there a routing and if not
my other question is what happened to
packet radio I mean operated by using a
packet radio a twenty-five years to
build communication networks including
routing what happened to them so I can
still alive and kicking so people are
using it but the last couple of years is
something which is called 3131 both
speed and BPSK for phase shifting K
you have interesting lecture about that
actually in the sense that they said
about the god speed so yes packet radio
is not that much about the routing
chretien those pilots stations are
something like a Reuters for the network
so they actually build a network so it
is
point-to-point but you can also route
information by those files stations so
this is my best knowledge of course not
work that much but we are just starting
with our club to use that I hope
at least a little bit of information
that is so how can I become operator in
the city
you're from sorry from the side pocket
so there is a travel partner Rebecca I
think it's called club you know that
restaurant just you know there you know
it is there's so I think they're close
to that I'm not in that club but you can
go and talk to the people I'm going to
connect with later on early stage just
for a moment you just go there and then
there is some basic you know that you
prepare and then when you pass the test
you become a licensed ham radio operator
before that you can also enjoy the hobby
meaning you can listen to the broadcast
but you don't have the license to
broadcast yourself so there are some
radio clubs in almost every city a
member of the pop overages Training Club
I'm not member of this club so I don't
know where they're exactly but I'm going
to make inquiries so please by jay-c
uniforms for school Papa deltacom you
should have any from issues become a
member of our club it is not connected
to the city you can be member of
multiple clubs so it is just going talk
to the people and make friends make new
you know point of use anymore sorry yes
way to communicate during disasters
maybe description is not directly right
radio but in the example seal what did
they use for power source yes yes of
course you can use your hand it some of
the stations are very you know you can
vary for example did I mention you're
going to build tomorrow that just may 24
Morris called it can take anything from
one and a half battery to maybe 12 walls
but through something like this I hear
station which I connect to the car
battery so you can use care about the
actual did that you know just connected
to the led to Quran and there is also
some movement inside of the moment is
called cure P which is master of our
commitment so meaning I'm not going to
do one killer to power because you know
I can I'm going to try to use as little
as possible cure appeals five months or
less so with with five votes
all of the European tell us what's up
with this and all of the digital most
use usually about 20 to 30 per hour and
20 volts of power we communicated in
Japan you know light bulb there are no
lie anymore
to because