welcome again this will be the first dog
today is invisible infrastructures by
$100 gift from share from this great
read and enjoy the dog hello everybody
who here feels comfortable walking in
English I mean just said that I know how
fast and how profound how deep can I go
with what terminology do all speak
English good enough
okay great my name is under boutros care
come from share foundation and this is
my colleague planning on also from from
share foundation he's a local hear from
them he said I come from belgrade today
we're going to talk about I hope that
you're all enjoying yourself and that
you like the conference I personally
liked it very much and my talk today are
atop today will be about invisible
infrastructures or as this subtitle here
says postcards from Internet each and
every one of us uses internet daily
basis but not as many of us are aware of
how the internet actually works and even
those of us who know because there are
some here as as far as I know even those
who know how the internet works have
some issues with the physical aspect of
the internet they don't really know the
actual points where their traffic that
this is why we share foundation did a
research to check all the points or the
places where the serbian the internet
believes I hope that you enjoyed this
this presentation it has amazing
visualisations done by my colleague
flooding here and sit back and enjoy
this is the essence of the Internet is
some of you have done this at some point
it's got race through writing
researching is a special service or at
all which is integrated in most sober
operating systems using using ICMP
protocol to to trace the hopes of of
danger and basically it checks were
tracked the package from one point in
the internet which is your computer to
some server or a website so basically
traceroute this quite useful tool in in
network diagnostics but also be used it
as a tool for for research in order to
be able to see the entire the entire or
most of the serbian network I just
wanted make you aware that if you are
connected to a high-speed internet
service provider in serbia chances are
that during the past year or so
mayor of London have knocked on your
router at some point because we took all
the IP ranges that are publicly
available for for Serbia and trades
restarted all of the IP addresses
available so the internet basically
works based on packets IP packets which
are structured in in some logical way
just a general idea is that it they
contain a header or part with metadata
and and content part which contains the
actual content of the packet I don't
know how many of you are familiar with
the term metadata metadata are our data
about data or data that explain what the
actual data is about you can think of it
as as when you send a letter by by post
nobody does that anymore but I'm sure
you remember how it's done basically you
have our letter to try to put it in and
then look and then on the envelope he
writes address is your address the
address of the receiver
some stamps etc so think of of D header
of the IP packet SSD envelope or D I'll
take part which contains the dresses and
some other information that make sure
that the letter makes the right address
or in case if it's the receiver doesn't
want to receive the letter it comes back
to to you that there are many cool
things about these IP packets but what
we're going to talk about this is it's
where this package goal and where the
suspected stored at on this journey from
from serbia to or from the late notice
other ever 22 some server in this case
Facebook server in the USA the first
jump the IP packet makes when it
generated by your browser is your router
at home that's the black or white box
that gives you that gives you internet
then it goes to some local let's say
center that's set up by your ISP that
gathers sold a traffic from your
neighborhood let see and then it just
two days building in Belgrade it's as
baby fell apart this is for a new
high-speed which we base our I mean I'm
in this movie so that's why the new
researches is based on on that provider
anyways in this building all the packets
generated by as BB users are our our
collection afterwards
packet jumps to this building somewhere
in Germany in in Frankfurt more
precisely in in Europe is it's the
biggest internet exchange point internet
exchange point is is a point in tonight
network where many many ISPs
March and all their packets
come to this place and then their route
222 to some some other places so
actually this one of the biggest peering
points in in in in Europe its cool
building with a nice park and its
blurred because it's considered a
building off of national interest for
Germany's so you can't really see all
the sides of the building new churches
have a picture from a partner for this
search by the way Google Street Google
Street pictures afterwards it goes to
Dublin in Ireland in the Republic of
Ireland where it gets copied and just
throw that away there is this cool place
in the UK which back in in today
indicate today's was a really famous
surfing place where people went to serve
on on these boards it's called to check
in in its sandy west coast of the United
Kingdom
this is a cool place because this is the
point where European traffic leads
Europe or it goes to to dus quite nearby
there is this is the hub HQ jQuery
actually the rotors and the servers are
located
this is also a really cool place it's
called GCHQ farm did you see it is I
don't know many of you know the
intelligence agency of the United
Kingdom and it's it's a beauty just a
couple of tens of kilometers away from
scrooge XO
intelligence agency by chance their
biggest their biggest satellite farm
near the point where the European
traffic leaves lives you know I'm sure
after he dies under the Atlantic goes
into dis this fiber cable is going to do
you this is this is in Tuckerton in New
Jersey
the lending point the lending point of
of the european internet basically if
you we have sched equity owner
under on-site that constantly since
packets and receives we have detected
turn in on on the east coast of the USA
that receives European traffic this is
what's known as the first capital of the
internet it's a connects the first place
where huge amount of data was was
gathered but nowadays there even even
bigger ones is it still works I mean
it's it's quite big
you can see by the party by the parking
around and it leaves it reaches the
destination which is the facebook data
center in in Forest City North Carolina
in dus something worth those think about
this building is that Facebook cannot
build it fast enough to 20 stalled all
the servers they they use so they
constantly by new land and build the
place which on the inside looks like
this journal people here they're just
eighty people working in Dec humongous
building that basically what they do is
they change batteries and the change
some spare parts it's there's no light
light automatically turns on if there is
a problem that some some some server so
it's practically it quite to ghost city
to humanize the humanities building not
a nice place to be but it does she
released her facebook photos and chats
and and statuses are so next time when
you type of status or post a photo you
just bear in mind that it it sleep
somewhere around here and i really
important thing to note is that even
when the package died so to speak or
it's it's completed its mission in life
and that's to reach from Novi Sad 222222
Facebook data center in dus it doesn't
actually died goes to hibernate maybe
and its further analyzed
and cloned into future as well for
purposes of data analytics etc can you
give a voice to London as well
22 may be explained in some other way
but under explain now basically
happening in less than one second when
you type in www.facebook.com in this
moment this tiny little packet go is
going through all of this country's is
going through all of these different
great buildings and finishing in this
place at the end and what is really
important for us is that like why we are
not aware of this process because it's
so fast and it's an invisible in our
golden with its research was to try to
understand what's going on behind so
everytime when you type www.facebook.com
this is what is going on and I will
continue further to just a couple of
other details that on the way in most of
these countries the pack it gets copied
and stored depends on the following the
stricken country it varies from six
months to 2222 years that at least in in
the European Union even though the
directive of Deut deal sweet retaining
data or more simple words retaining
information about towards some visitor
from serbia has promised us on the web
even though they were directed to track
least at indy you is is declared tumble
really many countries in the EU that
still do that and and the course of the
next step was ok we showed the road to
the package from serbia to dus now let's
see what's going on you serbia like
we don't really have a map of our own
country representing older servers and
two points in the network of vital
importance we find that we needed to see
who has watched part of the market and
found out as its not really super hard
to find out you just get the IP ranges
and and see who has so many IP addresses
to put things on lower level every
device that is connected to the Internet
IP address ok so this is this
180 point how we can know that those ip
addresses belonged to someone in serbia
because there is like organization is
distributing by countries range of IP
addresses so they're saying from this
number to that number this is all the
devices that will be assigned to the
different hardware computers or Reuters
in serbia and then those number numbers
those ip addresses are separated two
different internet service providers
Telekom Serbia get one range as bigoted
another range orion gets through the
range and so on and then at the end when
you are using Internet basically you are
using one of those ip addresses that are
assigned to the Internet Service
Provider the to those ip addresses from
European register of IP addresses that
way you can maybe you have maybe notice
that are sometimes when you watch
YouTube it says you did video is not
available in your country that's how I
actually did you choose serving knows
that your answer be there also other
ways but basically does the most common
way to to see where you're located
Telekom Serbia has the biggest portion
of the IP address space assigned to
serbia denning says BB and some water
some other providers what you're going
to see now
logical maps during physical like land
map but logical maps of the internet off
of Serbia and what I want you to think
about as concentration of the points of
the host at what we did basically all of
those ip addresses and we created well a
little packets that went to your
computer
visitor computer computer and told us
through each other points this package
came to your computer on the way back we
get information about this dress and
then we use different softwares for data
visualization to make a maps and this is
going to suck and they're really cool so
this is one provider called absolute ok
it's one of the smaller ones this is
already on it looks like space and this
is Telekom Serbia just remember this one
this is the University you use it at
your university is part of the Emerson
introduces the post btw
Bell tel has been one of the second
largest when basically so this is a map
representing each and every one of them
different color represents another
speech so and these points where you
have bigger concentration are there or
more points and during the Middle you
can see the points where they are where
they connect between the internet and
telecom so but OK except of this like a
visual part of the team that it looks
like really cool and the question is
what we can do about that how we can
read those maps the main thing here it's
the two can see for example to big big
bowl and that means that in the in the
middle of those both there is like 10 or
fewer IP addresses that means like
servers that all the day all the other
Reuters our servers that are connected
in Telecom is basically going through
this two points so that means that the
network of Telecom is really high list
and centralized what that means that
means if Telekom Serbia for example want
to filter or block some of the website
or or for example if they want maybe to
read all the traffic and to collect
information about the traffic going on
they will need to install two other
machines near to this points and they
will be able just with those two
machines to get a lot of traffic is
going on on different networks it's a
different situation so for example in in
in because it's not so centralized
network if you want to track what's
going on then you will need to track
here
much easier because it's like
centralized yeah I think that there is
already some filtering in in in I'm
resort on a local level so every
university because every faculty
practically has released to websites
that they block for instance I think
that they don't allow you to or
something like that
torrent on some of the University
what's filtering in general filtering is
controlling what goes to the end user or
whether gender user or you at home will
be able to access some website website
on the on the internet it's it's done in
many countries like Turkey and Russia
India Pakistan and and some other
countries as well under the pretext of
national security or child pornography
one of the most common excuses but what
do you think of Internet filtering did
it it basically is censorship in a way
because government or any government in
the world trying to filter or prevent
access to some websites that are
considered inappropriate for the culture
political system etc there are many ways
to go around these children's but I'm
not going to get it in debt now
it's important why it's important that
the internet remains decentralize
because if you have a network that is
highly centralized and the central point
or something needs some point near the
center gets corrupt in any way gets
hacked or whatever then turn that reduce
compromise because it it in that point
you have everything all the traffic best
trick that point for example in telecom
if you have a decentralized network if
part of the network gets gets corrupt or
affect their mean the remaining part of
the network can't can properly so that
is why it's it's highly important that
we fight for for decentralized internet
and and neutral internet as opposed to
the balkanization of the internet one of
the most sorry excuse for a term which
means that every country country gets
sovereignty over their own part of the
internet which means that for example if
the russian government decided that no
Twitter for russian citizen date date
they have a legitimate right to do that
now that sample so this is the central
point where these providers merchants
quote socks or serbian open exchange
which is the first and as far as I know
the only successful internet exchange
point in serbia it's operated as as as
an organization and they have their own
hierarchy and and way of controlling so
basically you saw the networks
individual in our now those like
validation is going to show how those
networks are interconnected between each
other so that's basically the internet
for example year your friend is on
telecom and your honor's be in order for
you to be able to communicate their
natural need to merge at some point this
is this is basically dead . this and
other important thing for us was to see
what the Serbian citizens actually visit
online there is this website called the
Lex it's run by by Amazon it's it's
owned by Amazon which maintains list of
most popular
websites for a country so we got the
list for serbia we took the 100 most
most popular websites and we want to see
where do where they hosted where they're
actually physically posted so we the
reason for this is that you want to to
just make a route like with it for the
Facebook packet in in in the first in
the first story just see which countries
you go when you're sitting at home and
and browsing some some website on the
internet because we sell them think off
it's really hard to think of leaving the
country when you're in your own
apartment doing something online you you
don't get the feeling that you actually
not only get out of your home but you in
most cases leave your country or even
your continent you go to USC and we are
not really aware of that and it's super
important to be aware that because
changes in in in in laws in all of these
countries affected us affect us really
really seriously so they yellow line we
line which you can see around here is
the national border of serbia old old
the websites that are inside the yellow
line are in serbia and all of them that
are outside our outside of it so
basically on the first view you can see
that most of them are outside but let's
just have a couple of couple of things
around here
centralization of there is a question to
lesion in couple of points in in in this
picture so first of all most of the
websites are hosted in serbia are at one
single provider hosting provider which
is called mainstream its provider from
belgrade so also in some other providers
but just a couple of them
unitarian telecom they have H one or two
or three website so most of the let's
say the representative number is 800 so
we took the hundred most most visited
sites so most of them are outside but
those who are inside our most of them
are with main street and another
important thing is you CDs don't in here
it's again a centralization point
because if you visit any website in
serbia chances are that you're going to
pass through to that point which again
talks about centralization of you talked
about leaving the country there is also
a point which which is highly
centralized and through each you visit
many web sites like this one or maybe
this one here so most of them are
interconnected and and highly
centralized which means that at some
point somebody sitting somewhere 1000
what websites are visited by a huge
number of of citizens of Serbia or
people's lives in serbia at at at any
point of time so as I said I just a
little bit of Statistics again I
mentioned coping detain storing data in
data retention I hope the church leader
with the term but I'm just gonna repeat
explanation once again so that I'm sure
that you know what it is
data retention means that the country
makes the law that as for the ice peace
or the telecom operators that the stored
data about your activity online for a
certain period so that they can use that
data in case there is a court court
process going on and they need some
evidence most most of the excuses are
organized crime smuggling child
pornography and terrorism international
terrorism which are quite a poor excuse
for data retention is because studies
have shown that data retention is not an
effective fighting terrorism or any
other type of crime so to speak so let's
have a closer look at that these blue
points on on the right is your source
computer and on the left the blue points
are the points where the data you
your data practically when the visiting
those website it's it's called peace so
we see a huge concentration of of decent
loop and the White Point Sur where the
website is actually hosted so we have a
huge frequency of these blue dots in in
Budapest Vienna and front so these
points his government's the Austrian and
German government can easily see what
interests serbian people have because
they have all the data are retained in
their points what we can see is that
most or data passes through you and and
into you as just a little bit of
statistics which I personally don't like
but it's useful sometimes only 27% of
websites in serbia are so said
hosting serbia please only for fourteen
of them are posted with with mainstream
which means that I'll 200 or 14% as it's
quite a high percentage for a single
single hosting provider then the entire
you can see it's it's actually 13
because I just tried to do that the
entire the number of countries in which
you good when when surfing calling
chances are it's thirteen or or less
17% of the traffic passes through 17 in
17 cases out of 27 the traffic passes
true salts or serbian open open exchange
65% remains edu 40% is in Germany while
11 this is this is a really fun fun fact
not really relevant but quite
interesting
1111 websites or 11 percent of these
websites are hosted in the Netherlands
that the reason for this is that the
Netherlands Holland has quite a liberal
laws regarding pornography so these are
mostly internet pornography websites 36
percent off all day of 100 most visited
sites in serbia are are indeed you said
this is the map so it's it's also quite
centralized because it doesn't leave it
it it's only in Europe and and in dus we
don't really go to Russia and Australia
Africa South America the serbian
internet or the most popular websites in
serbia can be put in this one box of
Europe and USA countries if not not all
of the European countries but some of
them so
we also can see that the trier quite
centralized and in this way again and
now we come to a really really fun story
you have heard the word case you
probably like eating cookies but there
is also another type of cookies there
are on the internet cookies are pieces
of data that contains some information
that can be related to you in some way
so that the next time you visit your
website you have better better user
experience thats your location
your lets a user name in some cases your
posture also so they they contain them
stated that gives really really
sensitive and important information that
can be related to you most of the
websites use case and it's because it's
it's quite convenient because the use
Google Analytics which is a Google
service that allows the web
administrators to track the number of
visitors see where dear visitors come
from a long day they said on the website
owner information how many claims they
had on on certain links and other
information that information to the
quite useful for them but they're really
intruding our privacy so why should
google know how long do I read a single
tax or why should google send me
advertisements all because the purpose
of these focus is to make a profile of
every user so that they can send them
certain type of advertisements when when
they're online you have certainly noted
when you google something then after
some time you get on your underside of
your browser
advertisements related related to your
search for instance if you I don't know
Google rent an apartment in Novi Sad
then you get booking.com telling you
that there is this nice apartment in
Novi Sad or near Novi Sad
this is based on on on on on cookies so
the business model of most of the
biggest internet companies nowadays is
not making you pay for the service but
offering something and getting your data
which is their currency
entire amount of the value of data on
European level two years ago was 300
interesting billion GBP pounds and until
2020 there is this estimate that it will
that it will reach a trillion which is a
humongous humongous amount of money it's
not the money that you get but its
amount of money that some company gets
for using pure data in most cases these
companies Google it's been deployed in
many websites so these are the websites
in serbia that implement Express has the
biggest number of cookies then you have
to study telegraphy etcetera
so in the middle
we have two types of cookies they they
they they have of course the most common
one is Google Analytics because of the
reason I already told you that we have
facebook facebook cookie doughs in many
different shapes and sizes from sheer
button to LIKE button to Google to
Facebook comments and other content they
they provide they provide
4344 the website to make again simple
you have those companies Google Facebook
and other one really really extremely
rich so they're earning like fifty six
billion dollars for example Google every
year that's a lot that's like more than
probably serbia or more than a lot of
countries in the world and from where
this money is coming from so the only
business model that they have to collect
data about your movement on the internet
and to transform this data into some
analytics that means into some profile
and then they're selling those profile
to people who want to advertise on their
website so the only business model the
Google heavies is that there is nothing
else and every time when they want to
have some new service new thing it's
basically to support this business
models to have more data about you if
it's for example for homes that can like
monitoring your electricity use surgeon
temperature and other things to collect
more data about your behavior that means
that you want to call it means that you
referred to for example if you're
growing marijuana on the
don't do that but if you are doing that
you will spend a lot of electricity no
to put the lamps and 22 heat just go on
and tell them how to do that and and
basically if someone is able to track
how many electricity to use his able to
track you and to find you because of
that basically what Google is doing is
trying to transform this information
about you and to create a profile of you
are you like this deal like that and
then to sell those profile store and I
would an Indian South you don't sell
your boat show you some some
advertisements this thing is going to
escalate escalate to some point with the
introduction of Internet of Things
because then smart houses it is whatever
because then we have many many many
devices that have some different sorts
of sensors for example the refrigerator
that has an IP address and some
interface that collects data on how much
milk you have so many eggs do it a week
etcetera so these teams get more and
more personal by the day it you should
take note is Google implements many of
these many of these cookies but in the
future this number is gonna grow
exponentially at least my opinion just
to have a look at the company's of
course Google Inc is is the one who owns
most of these cookies then we have
facebook and genius which is an
interesting an interesting example
because it's company based in Poland a
thing or two about you
industry Europe anyway so it's the
company offers marketing services for
companies from serbia so it's
interesting for this it's it's really
interesting for this market here because
they have the most personalized data
force of serbian the serbian citizens
day did there is so many companies from
serbia actually go to Jimmy S&S ok I
have this advertisement here just please
send it to people
I dunno teenagers attending high school
interested in sports and then you have
jock or some other sports vision company
that sells sneakers because they know
the deeply football just again something
and then the numbers
decrease slightly ninety percent of the
websites have integrated at least one
Google cokie 46 integrate Facebook cokie
36 jimmy is plenty for Twitter etc
seventeen different Google on seventeen
different third-party applications or
seventeen different types of services
that keep a cookie on your on your
important thing to know is that the
cookie is not on the internet but on
your own computers so they every time
you access the website you send the
kooky along with the requests for their
website and that's called a online sit
there is a hundred and eighteen in the
50 most popular sites and Serbia
integrated Google Google party
applications ninety percent of them are
integrated in 45 of 50 out of 50 what it
means that you even you don't use Google
and that's probably not possible but
even if you're not using Google in
nineteen when you land on ninety percent
of the website there are cookies Delta
googled it you are on the web site and
basically that means that once instead
of visiting one website you on average
you visit 7.3 other websites so because
the average number of integrated cookies
per website is 7.3 which means that you
don't want to visit the website you
actually type the URL address of but you
also visit 7.3 are other websites 08
different servers on the Internet
almost more than eight service on the
Internet
know that you visited a certain website
a certain type that you're interested in
in in in certain think I'm not going to
go too much in detail regarding these
just I think we should we could because
this is an interesting one it's it's due
proportion of where there's companies
that don't the cookies come from so you
can see this big black stripe it's it's
dus course then we have serbia somewhere
in here with this small small stripe and
not many other we have poland is because
genius is is is in poland so the only be
influential actors in in in serbia
regarding cookies to you as because most
of the companies are actually register
their so this is something that is going
to talk about mostly I'm just gonna jump
in let me let me try some code to make
some kind of summary of the things
before first we understand understood
like when we are visiting some website
we are traveling to seven different
countries leaving out of the race and
the way in other countries on the way
can collect the data about us most of
those countries that we are visiting our
across the ocean so it's United States
and the rest of the countries in the EU
so our internet is not so big it's
basically serbia
United States than we realize when
you're visiting some website there are
other people who have information that
you visited that website and then we
realize that this is the main business
model of the biggest internet companies
that exist today in the world so they're
able to collect a lot of information
about you so the players who can collect
internet service provider can collect
information government can collect
information and companies can collect
information and also their
redistributing this information to other
companies
this is some kind of summary of the
things and what we explain now they can
collect information of what we which
websites we are visiting how long we are
staying but what we are collecting what
we are searching on the internet so on
so on and they're using this information
to sell you more thing
but this is not the end of the story
because there is a mobile home mobile
phone is basically the biggest tracking
device that exists that ever existed so
it's the most ultimate surveillance
device has a smartphone so
we will explain why this is the story
number but this is the right number
three or so when you are downloading
application York leaking something like
this except yes yes yes I accept accept
accept and more unless you're you're
never reading basically what you are
accepting so we did some kind of
research so we started the most popular
applications for mobile phones and try
to analyze what kind of information you
gave them permission to collect from
your mobile home and so for example
Facebook what we can see here they can
collect location as the mass media files
camera microphone life connection
DeviceID call information other things
but when you go deeper and more into
details you basically understand that
they can collect more or less
everything that exists on your phone
maybe they're not collecting this way
purpose of tracking you or something but
in any case you gave them a possibility
to do so if they want and this is the
same for example with the Google Google
it collecting the game like 10 different
permissions but for example being
application made from Microsoft for
example that is doing the same thing and
you could see that being is collecting
much less a much less they're gonna
think less things then Google so
basically for the same service they're
not collecting so many things and then
you have doctor logo is basically like
privacy oriented browser they're not
collecting almost entity so then we
start to 22
research like some kind of domestic
application like mostly news
among the public and so on and then we
found like also interesting things that
for example quoted can read sensitive
log data what it means says it is
located that means when did you call
someone who did you call how long
duration of the call and song song and
career one news website can collect
those information about you why they
need that I don't know what they're
doing that but what is also like really
scary on this it's that when you are
buying from I think the electronic
mobile phone application it's already
proving that means that you never gave
them give them approval to do that came
with the phone so this is the things
that you should always have in mind when
you are installing some application
please do read what is written there
because this is the price you're paying
for free so
the most intrusive applications that
there are regarding this permissions are
of course this fiber but facebook
Messenger song every time when you hear
the viper for example it's company that
it's worth of $50,000,000 or sell for
200 million dollars you should ask
yourself based on what they don't
produce they
location is free they don't produce an
offer from where those fifty million
dollars came from in most of the cases
coming from the day today they are
collecting and selling or marketing
purposes or to some other other
companies there is no any other business
model so all of those things with
organizational stuff you can see on its
website that we made for this research
is called labs that address so you can
go in in detail and try to understand
all of this but there are like privacy
oriented or anonymity oriented software
applications for example or bought some
kind of mobile version of tour basically
not connect collecting anything just
what they really need to do to run at
the start up to have whole network
access view network connections and this
is the for example if you are installing
application for example a clean master
that should clean your
from different kind of dumb things you
can also check what they are what they
are doing on the back and you will
understand that they are like collecting
lot of different information about you
so this is basically some kind of
summary of our mobile home repair
missions and now we will this is like we
try to understand like which of those
permissions are our Privacy can harm
your privacy and and basically from here
to here most of those things can be like
have a problem with the privacy and all
those likely
permissions are you can find more
information about this and this is our
last thing it's related to surveillance
and metadata retention infrastructure so
it's basically how the mobile phone how
how they are receiving information from
your mobile phone and how they're
tracking your method eight so basically
you have a mobile phone inside of your
mobile phone have something that it's
called him a number email number
identifier for the mobile home inside of
the mobile phone you have a SIM cards
and most of you to sign some contract
with their sore or so you're giving your
names
your street address number of other
phone call away so they have basically
information who you are then your mobile
phone he's doing three different things
you can do all he can do SMS and he can
do they transfer in all of this is
called GSM communication and how things
are going on around you in most of the
cases you're surrounded with the three
different base stations what are the
basic PlayStation PlayStation sold those
gray around the city
the fields as a matter and most all the
time your mobile phone is connected to
three of them and so when you called
someone this signal is going to to the
base station and then from the best base
station it's going to something that
it's called mobile switching center and
this is where the magic is starting to
happen in this moment which asks enter
the race packet it's the similar to
Internet the packets every call every
data packet content and on the top have
a header headers and headers means
you're calling for how long from which
base stations also on this is collected
copied to something to some kind of
database of metadata in serbia those
companies MPs Telenor and so on
they need to collect those metadata and
keep them for twelve months and then
so you have like alot alot alot of
metadata about each of us so far they
have every time when you called someone
when you send SMS when you move some do
something basically they have some trees
in metadata that you did that and
they're keeping this information in some
kind of database base the main question
is how and who can access those metadata
by our research there's different ways
that how different agencies can be like
to court so all of them can access those
men metadata two different ways for
example how it should be done is that
they are like calling and asking them
ok serious a court order can you give me
metadata about this person this is like
usual thing but it's not the part of the
reality but the another part of the
reality is that they have some kind of
application for direct access to this
metadata and so they can search through
the database by the telephone number by
the location of the base station and
songs so what it means for example for
example the few that have mobile phone
now you are now connected to base
station know if i if i search now
through this database who is connected
to base station in this moment I will
know exactly who is sitting in this
industry and this is the crowd there how
would they are tracking criminals are
attracting doing like lot of political
activist
because there is a different illegal
ways how to access this information
through these applications and so on so
our research told us that like there is
like a huge amount of data that is
analyzed on a legal way that it's not
true this court system and so on so you
can see more I think we are now we have
five minutes so this is basically you
can read more on on on on our website
and you can find out how those different
way behind other people are accessing to
our metadata maybe leave this five
minutes if someone have any kind of
questions about anything related to any
questions
guidance on what to do about it so yeah
about your activity on the internet
being tracked and what you can do about
it
asking from the position of a user how
to protect yourself from
so there is this thing called and luck
plus some of you made it's basically a
plug-in for your websites that blocks d
ads so by blocking the ads in blocks a
huge huge amount of cookies but on the
other hand you can configure your web
browser
especially for use Mozilla or or tour
which I strongly recommend you can turn
off the dakotas it'll be a little bit
inconvenient in the sense that you will
need to sign in everytime you open I
don't know gmail or whatever because you
don't store anything your passwords or
or whatever you use so just turn on the
cookies on your website used at luck +
and most preferably used tor tor browser
which is super easy to download insult
or project though torque download you
said in your pretty much safe I found
out about a nice blacken a similar to
block a bit more user friendly flexible
its privacy from the Electronic Frontier
Foundation its cool and I would
recommend to turn it on and nice feature
of it and you will see the number of
cookies that they detected so you can
see for yourself like the things that
you showed us in this in this
presentation you can see for yourself
what individual sites are ya how many I
encourage you to do so whatever to look
as many kisses as as you can and just
one more comment because I am NOT
security expert I'm generic programmer
and I just
development particularly on Android
finally green so yeah technically if
they are requiring you to do that you
cannot allow something that doesn't mean
necessarily that they are doing that i
mean the the plastic example is for
example you want to make a flash flood
light that requires you think of the
camera axis direction so you see a
flashlight asking the camera for me so
yeah things can exploit I give you the
next release some master stuff in there
but yeah sometimes it is sometimes it's
not so
yeah I mean there is also these good
trend which I'm really glad about going
on that the applications ask for a
permission when they need to do a
certain tests for example you need to
switch on the torch flashlight Danny
test shoot these action asked you to
give her permission to use flashlights
camera whatever and then you give it but
it's not a permanent permanent
permission so these event-based
permissions are much better approach
that's something I S had and that's
something and retool have enduring next
the next edition so things are getting
better but we still need a strong voice
from the community i mean you cannot
blame the developers for asking to use
those permissions you can blame me to
Google on Google India review system
because they they need to review the
application really needs to use older
this all those things so yeah things
things are getting better hopefully in
in debt in in that way
ok questions comments we're kind of
running out of time but maybe one more I
personally
shows also how many cookies and one more
thing about GSM base stations did you
know that we are all base station you
can connect if you choose our network
operator on mobile phone we don't keep
metadata please try to break our deal
with this research was to try to
understand the map system oK what's
going on and what are the different
forms of our behavior and how this
network looks like and basically for
every different aspect you have a
probably different to how to avoid the
problem for example if you don't want to
be tracked locally in your country then
used bpm
browse the internet from another country
if this is what you want to do if you
want to be anonymous settings like this
store network if you want to understand
who is tracking you online use goes to
Rio or or privacy better or something so
we just wanted to somehow map different
kind of problems that we see and not to
give solution but just to do a very
earnest about the things I hope we will
maybe next year to the solutions we also
have also you can check everything on
our website labs or terrace ok one more
thing
did you know that there are two parties
meetings are gathering so you can learn
how to use tools for cryptography tools
for blocking these kind of crackers we
will hear a trip to party here after
after the soldiering workshop if anyone
is interested in so they're learning how
to organize your encrypted protecting
you have that one's own yes there there
is a book up to throw out so it's super
simple super easy and you should share
it among your friends even though as we
had the opportunity to live too
here last night ripped apart this or not
the solution but at this point I think
that the only option we have so just try
to educate yourself as much as possible
about all of this has once again led the
IRS check it out it's kind of cool and
that's it thank you very much