the next thirties Tennessee element of
surprise about technology hardware of
particle accelerator so serious
all right thank you will be hard but i
wanna be your beauty of this summer
so I work at physical research center
and the center is called dizzy and the
place where I work is in the city of
homework it's the second biggest city in
Germany and there we have quite a number
of particle accelerators and I work in
science communication that means I look
at what the researchers doing and I
tried to explain it to the general
public like you people and I tried to
make people better understand about
physics and what is happening so let me
start with an invitation because if you
have a chance to come to the north of
Germany then it's a good opportunity to
visit homework and you will be able to
see all of these things that I put her
on the pictures we have some particle
accelerators there and one that is
especially cool to see is the one on the
upper right this is called the HERA
accelerator it is not in use today but
this means it is an opportunity for you
to go and see it up close it has a
circumference of over six kilometers and
it is the largest accelerator in the
world that is now easily accessible to
visitors so if you have a chance to come
to work then it will be a good
opportunity to visit easy today I will
be talking about particle accelerators
in general and some of the physics that
we do but mostly about the Large Hadron
Collider which is the accelerator in
Switzerland and it's the one with the 27
kilometers of fun and much of the
technology that I will be describing has
also been developed a daisy because it
once not today but sometime ago it was
one of the leading one of the most
important particle accelerator centers
in the world
ok so I will talk about what we are
doing
and why we try to do this to find out
things about physics naturally and I
will be describing some of the devices
and the hardware that we use and there
is also an I T aspect to it because as
we will see there is an enormous amount
of data that is generated and the state
has to be collected and processed
what we are doing is we are using
accelerators in the shape of a ring we
call them storage ring and also impart
some linear accelerators that make the
particles gorgeous in a straight line
and we give high energy to the particles
which is the same as to say that we make
them fast but to say that we make them
fast is only half the truth because at
some point when you get close to the
speed of light then you cannot make the
particle much faster because the speed
of light is the limit but we can still
increase the energy we can double the
energy triple the energy but still the
speed will stay very close below the
speed of light so when we get to high
energies it makes more sense to speak of
just the energy and not the actual speed
and well when we have gotten them to a
very large speed we make them collide
and then we see what happens and
actually this see what happens is
something that is very difficult and
requires quite a bit of detector
technology and I will be talking also
about that so the the basis of this kind
of research that we are doing is this
famous formula which says that energy is
actually the same as mass but let me try
to put it may be in terms that are a bit
closer to someone if you are tinkering
with electronics what if I say that
parts electric parts electronic parts
are actually like the same as a device
that you can build from them and we
might make it look like this so the
parts is really the same as the device
ok kind of you know but not a hundred
percent you have to put the parts
together in the right way otherwise the
device will not work and if you have the
device it's not the same as the parts
because the parts are put together you
connect them
and it's not the same as all the
individual parts so you know the analogy
works a little bit so if the mass can
constitute something that we want to
find out about like for example of the
Higgs particle then how about we just
take the energy and put it together in
the right way and we have exported ko
finished well actually it's not so easy
because we cannot assemble we cannot
just take energy and make the right
thing out of it there is no construction
manual for the Higgs boson so what we
actually have to do is we have to create
the energy in a very messy in a very
unprecedented process which is the
collisions of particles and it doesn't
look like this
putting parts together nicely into a
device is rather looks like this we make
the collisions and the result is lots of
collision products and out of all these
collision products we wonder maybe there
is in sight the divisive advice or the
Higgs particle that we are looking for
but it's a very hard job to find out
from all these things that come out of a
collision
if there really is the right thing in
there and that's what you need detector
for so we need the accelerator to make
the particles fast we need the
coalition's to convert the energy into
something and then we need the detector
to find out if something has the thing
that we are looking for
so these are the three things that we
are using and now I would like to tell
you about the first part of this about
the accelerator and how it looks so
storage ring the first surprised it's
not actually a ring so it's not a
perfect circle it always has some
straight parts and the straight parts
are used to are the place where the
particles actually get their energy now
let's think about how we can give energy
to a particle we do it by using electric
fields but again maybe we can find an
idea that's a bit closer to our hearts
imagine some kind of racing video game
and you have these these booster arrows
on the ground right through
you drive onto them and you get faster
we can do this with charged particles
imagine an electron or a proton is like
the little racing car in this game and
an electric field if the polarity is
correct
can be like a booster so ok what do we
do to make the particle really fast well
we just put a lot of boosters and and it
will make the particle go really fast
well this would mean that we need a
large electric field how large well
really large the energies that we want
to give to the particles like for
example an electron it would need an
electric field off billions of faults so
governments and this is something that
technically is not really possible to do
because you know how what generator do
you need for a gig of alts what
connections do you need what cables do I
need for a gig of its not practically
possible so this is kind of a forbidden
way but what if we could do electric
fields that are opposite to each other
and put them in a row
well it would look like this ok so
here's our our particle and it gets a
boost but then the next field it slows
it down so boost slowdown boost slowdown
nothing happens but here's the trick we
can use alternating current just
alternating like you have from your
power socket and if we alternated with
the right frequency then we can make it
look to the particle like it's always on
an accelerating path so the protocol is
coming and it sees the first
accelerating filled the next one will
slow down but when it gets to this point
we switch all the fields polarity
changes and so the next thing that the
particle seizes also in accelerating way
and this way from the point of view of
the particle it's always just
accelerating and what we do is actually
with which the fields now this
alternating current thing is is not
magic you know
like I said the power socket has an
alternating current of fifty hurts so
the polarity changes fifty times a
second so we can think about what kind
of what kind of frequency do we need to
accelerate the electrons
what we put in is that we have a device
which is about one and a half metres
long it's called the cavity that is
where the magic happens so if the cavity
is about one and a half metres long how
fast as the electron going well we know
that because electrons have a very very
slow small mass and to make them go the
speed of light they just need a slightly
so we give some energy to the electrons
and their speed will be almost the speed
of light and we can calculate with that
ok so it's one of the house meters
divided by the speed of light and the
result is a few nanoseconds so every few
nanoseconds we must switch the field
because that's when the particle exits
from 170 to another and so a field that
changes every few nanoseconds has a
frequency of gigahertz and as we know
electrical fields on the order of
gigahertz also they're not magic they
are like microwaves they're like
wireless just that we need a little bit
bigger of a device to generate the kind
of feels that we are looking for this is
the capital like I said about
one-and-a-half metres long and it is the
device that we used to put inside this
alternating electric field with the
frequency of the gigahertz and the
electrons are rushing through it now if
we have a circle accelerator then it's
ok if we have just maybe not one but if
we had just have a handful of these
devices because the particles will come
by lots of times right we put our
acceleration here the particles going to
circle and so they get an energy kick
and an energy kick an energy kick and
after a while they will have been
accelerated and we don't need many
hundreds of those just a few because
they come by all the time and so this
this thing is about one and a half
metres long is made up mostly of a metal
that is called niobium
I had never heard of this before that so
niobium is the only thing I know
the only thing I know where they used
for these cavities and some things in
accelerators the metal that we use needs
to satisfy three conditions you need to
make it you need to be able to put it
into a shape because as you can see the
shape is very special it looks like
donuts or something and it needs to be
the shapes of the electric field will
fit in just right and it cannot be too
expensive because we need a lot of it
and you need to be able to cool it down
for a superconducting temperature now
superconducting means that some metal if
you some metals if you're cool them down
to a very low temperature will lose
their electrical resistance so they will
not be electrical energy converted into
heat and this is good because with our
large electric fields that change over
time there are large currents flowing
and we don't want to heat up this thing
because it might melt or something so we
just cool everything done and it has
cooled to a temperature of for Calvin's
that is minus two hundred and sixty nine
degrees Celsius it's very cold we use
liquid helium to do this and yes that's
how we do that now the microwave
hurts changing electric field it needs
to come from somewhere we cannot just
connect household microwave because it's
not powerful enough what we use is a
device that is called a clue strong and
a Christian can they build them had two
different frequencies the lower end is
about hundreds of megahertz and it goes
up to two sometimes even more than 2
gigahertz of frequencies and we can see
here that the power which they generated
around 300 kilowatts that is just the
power for the electric field which is
used to to drive the particles and we
don't just used one of those we need
sixteen times 300 kilowatts for the
fields that drive the the particles as
the comparison because this is you know
something like a radio transmitter we
heard yesterday that to have a normal
ham radio conversation from here to
Japan you need about 20 Watts I looked
up the power that nasa uses two talk two
spacecraft out by Pluto they use about
20 kilowatts and here we have 300
kilowatts to accelerate a few particles
so it's it's actually a large energy use
and at these higher energies and that
these high frequencies it's actually
better not to use cables you can makes
these kinds of signals go through a
cable but then you shouldn't let the
cable lying around in a loop or maybe
the connectors filmmaker problem so what
better way to transport these radio
waves of these microwaves is actually
waveguides and you can see it up here it
looks like it's for air but it's
actually not for transporting harrods
hollow metal to you and it's like a
reflector so I have this metals you and
had one and I stick in an antenna and
the antenna transmits and because there
are other metal walls of the thing the
radiation gets reflected around and it
can only move in one direction which is
the direction of the waveguide so to
transport the energy the fields from the
klystron where it is generated to the
actual accelerate we use these
waveguides and inside the fields
propagate ok then we come to the second
part of the actual circle part which is
the curves so we have seen how the
particles are accelerated but if we just
leave them alone they just fly on a
straight line but we need we wanted to
go on a circle so what we need to do is
to put their a magnetic field magnetic
field if charged particle comes inside a
magnetic field it is put onto a curved
path so we need to put magnets at the
right strength into the path of a
particle simpatico comes flying here and
there is a magnetic field and then it
will start to go around the curve the
thing is that we give the particle so
much energy that they need very large
magnetic fields to actually turn them
you cannot just use a small magnet
because it will
changed the way of the particle 22
little and so we have these they're
called cryo dipoles which means very
cold magnet these are also cool to about
minus two hundred and seventy degrees
Celsius and the LHC accelerator users
about 1,200 of them all around the ring
part of the accelerator we are well they
are also expensive because you need the
niobium and everything so some some
estimates were that one of these things
cost half a million Swiss francs a lot
of money and to generate the field we
use a very large currents of its an
electromagnet have two conductors and
you put an electric current through them
and then in the middle there appears a
magnetic field and the magnetic field
should have a strength of about eight
and a half Tesla because of the strength
of eight and a half Tesla it's enough
for the protons that are going at this
energy where we need them to just make
the right the right angle around the
curve
well and because that's a very large
magnetic field we did a very large
electrical current and it's about to
kill em Paris 1212 killer on parasol
12,000 and Paris
power sockets the power connection in
your home I think at least in Germany it
will support about sixteen and Paris and
if you go above 16 emperors then fuse
blows out so that's quite a bit bigger
and also all around the Large Hadron
Collider 600 tons of this niobium metal
is used to make their electrical
conductors that we put the current
through and it's funny I looked it up
the the world production of niobium is
not very much because like I said it's
not used in very many applications and
it mostly comes from Brazil and when
they're rebuilding the Large Hadron
Collider they used a quarter of all the
world production of niobium for five
years so they were like the biggest
the biggest customer for this sort of
metal for a while and well so now we
have these magnets right and be cool
them down so there's no electrical
resistance we put a large current
through and this gives us a large
magnetic field so the particles can go
in a circle and that's cool but if we if
the current is supposed to be constant
then there is a large energy stored and
this energy is actually extremely large
it's on the order of 10 gigot rules and
you can compare this energy that is just
inside the magnetic fields which report
there to be stable is equivalent to the
energy of a train with fifteen thousand
tongues you know like a big trade train
moving at a hundred fifty kilometers and
if you imagine a big freight train
moving at 250 kilometres it could do a
lot of damage if the energy is directed
in a wrong way so the magnets are also
something that we need to watch very
closely we don't want the energy to like
the cooling to fail and then a part of
this energy could be converted into heat
and that would be very bad and actually
we know that it would be very bad
because one time it happened the cooling
at a connection between two of these
dipole magnets did not work right and
saw this super conductivity to the metal
was lost and suddenly the large current
was not just flowing through but it was
flowing through in generating heat in
this heat that was generated by the
electric current made the liquid helium
that were used to cool everything
evaporate so imagine that half cubic
liter of liquid helium suddenly becomes
a gas well it expands very quickly and
in this incident it not only shifted the
part of the accelerator for a little bit
it also filled about a hundred or two
hundred metres of the tunnel with pure
helium just from the evaporation of the
cooling which is one of the many reasons
that whenever an accelerator is running
nobody is allowed near it
the tunnel is closed the doors are
closed there is emergency shutdown if I
try to open the door
you cannot even take the elevator to go
down everybody needs to be away from the
accelerator because of these things can
happen it's not just about radiation and
particles it's also about lots of cold
things and lots of magnetic energy to
put it together we have this ring which
is not perfect but it's actually you
know it has a accelerating pardon the
curve part and together we use this to
make the particles going to circle and
come by our accelerating portion every
few times now if you look at the layout
of the sexual machines you will find
that often they are connected some large
accelerator is connected to some smaller
accelerators and these are called the
pre accelerators because it's useful for
us to put the particles not you know
like energy 0 there standing still
we put them in the accelerator and then
turn it on its better if we give them
some basic energy to say and then put it
in another accelerator which makes them
at a higher energy if you want to a
drive on the output you don't go there
and stop on the output and then
accelerate you know you go before and
there's a little and you match the speed
of the other cars and then you join it
and this is how we like to do it with
the particles also because it gives us a
chance to have a more smooth operation
of the electric fields and the magnetic
fields and you can see this pattern also
in the layout of some real-world
accelerator centers so this is the LHC
these are our 27 kilometers of fun and
as you can see it is connected to many
smaller machines and also here where I
work at easy there was a connection of
this now it's almost like a historical
evolution that all these smaller
accelerators are connected to larger
ones because when all this acceleration
business started about in the nineteen
fifties the machines were small because
you could find out a lot of interesting
things with a small machine but then we
wanted to go to higher energies because
our machine had told us everything so we
build a bigger one and we could connect
the bigger one to the old smaller one
and this happened again and again and
and as you can see here there's at least
1233 accelerators to the LHC which some
years ago where the biggest machine but
then they became just the pre
accelerator for the next big machine ok
now we have all this acceleration
everything is working great and the
particles are going really fast and here
comes the real business that we want to
do which is the collisions the particles
collide so we can find out something
about what's inside or what can happen
with the energy and it is very difficult
actually to make the particles collide
because they're extremely small and
extremely fast so when we try to make
coalitions we make a lot of them and I
will give you an overview an explanation
of actually how many of them will
generate but first we need to take a
look at what the beam looks like so the
stream of particles that we make go
through the accelerator recall and
actually of course there is two beams
because we need collisions
soybean miss not a continuous stream of
particles like you wouldn't I don't know
from science fiction the particle gun
they don't come out in a single stream
but they're also not single particles
like proton proton proton but there are
packed together in bunches and bunches
might look like this so we have a huge
number of protons and it slides through
and then there's a little part and then
there's another huge bunch of protons to
make
single particles collide is too hard we
cannot
the magnetic fields that will determine
the path to have one proton hit one
other proton it's impossible if you
calculated it's like trying to shoot
with a rifle into the air and somebody
else also shoots their rifles into the
air and the bullets are supposed to meet
in the air but if I'm here and the other
person is on mars it's extremely
difficult so we have like large armies
and everybody is shooting towards Mars
and then hopefully in the middle
some of the bullets will collide and the
number of protons that we have in a
bunch like the number like the number of
bullets that we shoot its tend to the 11
so that's a hundred billion particles in
just one bunch so large branches are
made to collide or ima to meet and then
hopefully among all these two hundred
billion protons that meet there will be
some collisions so how many bunches are
there well they're spaced apart by 25 90
seconds so I'm standing next to the LHC
when it's running which is not allowed
but let's imagine and here's a bunch and
I went 25 90 seconds and then there's
another bunch and that means that they
are apart by seven and a half metres and
about not quite three thousand bunches
are in there at the same time and just a
funny fact because it's a lot of charged
particles moving its actually like an
electric current but the electric
current would look rather small because
even hundreds or a couple thousand of
billion protons is actually not a lot of
charge so it's like like one and a half
million pairs as the current we don't
want to you know it's not a power cable
it's an accelerator so that's ok and to
make them collide well we need to make
these beams meet and this is done at
interaction points so at this
intersection points we put special
special configurations of magnetic
fields because the magnetic lenses
and we make the beams meet we make them
intersect and so hundred billion protons
in each bunch and there is two bunches
coming one from each side and the
interaction point the the actual area
where they meet we make it a small as
about human hair is thick hair cut it
and the area that you get if you look on
that is the area where we make these two
hundred billion protons meet how many
collisions are there when we do this
well about 10 to 20 and this is actually
a bit too much for our instruments but
the number that we that we get the
number that we choose because if we make
the number less if we make it only 125
collisions then we don't get enough data
this way we get a little bit too much
data but then we try to choose we will
look at how we deal with the data so
yeah if there is more than one collision
per bunch crossing it's called a pile up
and it makes it harder on the on the
detectors so about 20 collisions one
collision per bunch crossing and they're
a bunch crossings every 25 90 seconds so
that means every second there are about
600 million collisions
600 million times per second collides
with some other protein and the
experiments that we used to find out
then what is happening there but this is
just one part of one of one experiment
so keep in mind how large this is we
have here people and trucks and it is
this part in that experiment and this is
one of the two machines that we have
there and the actual collisions the
actual magic happens inside this tube
it's cut open here so there's one stream
of particles coming from the one side
and the other is coming from the other
side and the collisions happen right
here in the middle and then we put the
detectors like an onion structure inside
on the very inside next to the beam is
the most sensitive detector and then
come other instruments and then the
energy and energy measurements we try to
take very close to the beach we want to
know very precisely where everything is
and then further to the outside we want
to know how much energy there is other
particles just smash into our detector
components and we can find out how much
energy they had so yet the inner
tracking on the inside me want to know
where everything is because of course in
the collision energy is converted into
many particles there can be 20 30 50 of
particles in just one collision and we
need to know where they're all going so
that's why we need the inner tracking
then outside for the measurement of the
energies is the calorimeter this is
Greek for measuring the energy so the
calorimeter as they actually stop the
particles and we can determine if we
stop the particle free sort of catch it
we can determine how much energy it had
by how much damage it does to our
detector not really damaged but still
it's it's a process that changes the
detector in some ways are some parts of
these calorimeter as you want to replace
every few months or years and then there
is also another thing which is also like
a calorimeter but for the muons Iran's
our special part of particles a special
kind of particles that can also be
generated and they go through almost
everything they can go through a lot of
led a lot of other materials so the very
largest part of the detectors is just
for this muon particles and we put them
outside of everything else they can
catch the rest they didn't get stuck
inside these other parts oK so that's
the instrumentation and like this is a
picture of the of the very inside of the
detector it's composed of small small
elements and these elements can see if a
particle went through and well we put
enough of them and we need to put in a
circle because particles can go every
way and we want to catch them in every
direction so that's why these are
arranged in a circle
around the beamline and then we need
triggering because let's think about how
much data is actually generated there
are forty million bunch crossings per
second and suppose that every bunch
crossing inside our detector and we want
to know what is happening
sold the detectors have a large number
of channels you know channel can be a
voltage here everyone everyone of these
small elements will have not just one
but many channels just for itself in all
in one of these big detectors there
might be about 100 million channels and
suppose that every channel has has a
data range of one or something so it
could be anything from like 0 millivolts
21 vault in 1,000,000 bold steps and the
net will be about a thousand bits and
that means that for every bunch crossing
we get about one and a half megabytes of
data that doesn't sound so bad but it
happens every 25 nanoseconds the actual
raw data that is generated all the time
when everything is running is on the
order of many terabytes per second and
we cannot process terabytes per second
we cannot even store these terabytes per
second at least we couldn't do it for
very long so we need to pick some of the
events we don't record everything from
the 60 terabyte per second
data stream which is thick some things
which are interesting but it's very
difficult to find out what is
interesting how do we choose and this is
done by something called the trigger so
the trigger is supposed to choose oh
yeah this is about the reconstruction so
one event right we have a bunch crossing
and there's 20 events and to calculate
what happened in just one event takes
the reconstruction of these experiments
of its couple million lines of C code
that was especially written just for
this experiment and it has to simulate
many objects because of course many
things are meeting in many things are
flying away
and so for every one single event you
would need about 15 seconds of real-time
CPU but with six hundred million
collisions per second you don't have
that much computing power is just not
available so like I said we need to pick
certain events which are interesting to
us so the trigger does and most most
experiments uses several level trigger
system is where we tell the first level
trigger ok you see an event and now you
have 22nd 25 90 seconds of time before
the next bunch crossing
you have this much time to find out if
you think there is something interesting
there and if yes you will put it on to
the next computer or to the next trigger
and if not just throw it away and it
will eliminate more than 99% of all the
event so we are left with a smaller data
stream off about a hundred or 200
gigabytes per second but of course this
is still too much the next level traders
have a bit more time to decide they have
10 microseconds time to decide if that
thing which they got from the first
level trigger looks interesting or not
and if yes they will pass it on
so then in the end we are left with some
hundred megabytes data stream per second
which is okay we can manage that and
store that but then we still have to do
all the calculations to reconstruct what
actually happened in these events and
when we do that we can get some nice
pretty looking graphics which are like
this so this is the representation of
what happened inside the detector at the
very moment of this one collision so
here's a collision and there's some
particles flying outside and some
special particles flying further outside
because they had larger energy and there
is also one here and then if we look
from another direction it might look
like this so if we look into along the
beam it might look like this and then
the particle theorists come and they
look at the date of this event and they
will say oh yes I know this that's what
happened and this then will be probably
very interesting because there was a
Higgs boson there so out of everything
that happened
goes into the detector the data's picked
and picked again and then hopefully in
the end we will have some events like
this that we can show to the theory
people and then the theory people
hopefully we'll say yep that was exposed
so that's what we have to do and to
store all this data because there's a
lot of regenerated there's the LHC
computing grid which has a number of
data centers around the world connected
to each other and these four experiments
they produce about 25 petabytes per year
and the LHC has been running for for now
34 years about so already we have 100
petabytes of just stuff that we record
it happening inside the inside the
accelerator I heard that now I'm not
sure about this maybe some of you know
better that this is among the biggest
data collections that there is after the
end of a data collection and to
distribute all the state and restored
efficiently the year dedicated data
centers are connected with links that
are about as large as gigabits per
second to distribute the data I am I
have one story that I found from the
time that the LHC was constructed so
they were thinking about what we should
build and this was about in the middle
of the nineties so they said okay we
have this detector and admits to collect
the data we put it all together and we
will put 10 Gigabit switch but in the
middle of the nineties there were no 10
gigabit switches so like the financing
committee said well you cannot plan to
build some machine with a device that
doesn't exist they said but we asked
some of the network people and they said
that when we finally get to putting
everything together they will be
attending events which saw no problem
well they kind of managed to convince
everyone to still put the money in and
luckily it happened and the really worse
which is that were fast enough at the
time that they were really putting it
together five or maybe ten years later
so sometimes even have to plan ahead to
use technologies they don't exist yet
because the whole process of thinking
about it and planning it and finding the
money and making the decisions so long
that technology has advanced a lot okay
now let's think about something because
we make the triggers choose what are the
interesting events right and we want to
find out about books about these very
interesting events but we have to find
them in this enormous amount of data and
so if the trigger throws away everything
that we tell it isn't relevant well we
choose what's relevant right so what if
in all this data that we throw away
their something which would actually be
interesting
reprogram it wrong and then we don't
find anything out that we wanted to know
and there is one great example from the
nineteen thirties
about something like this actually
happening of course this was way before
computers but still it's the same
problem in principle so this was when
people used for particle detectors they
used photographic plates you had a
special special kind of liquid or solid
and you put a magnetic field there and
then of particles go through you will
see it on an actual photograph so you
take it to a photography lab and there's
all the chemicals and then you look at a
physical photographing you say yes
there's a particle so here in this
photograph we can see the important
things are here this is a metal plate
and this is the track of a particle that
went through the metal plate and we know
that there is a magnetic field like this
which makes the party cannot just fly
straight but actually to go on this
curve and we also know that the particle
is coming from this direction because
when it hits the plate it loses some
energy and then the curve gets tighter
so you see first is flying like this and
then it's like more like this and that
means that it was coming from below and
hit the play it and then it's flying
above so this is like our event few and
because because we know it's coming from
this direction we can calculate the
amount of energy that it had and the
amount of energy that had lost
and we found out that this has the mass
of an electron but from the direction of
the magnetic field we also know that it
is positively charged we are actually
electron but not with a negative charge
like they all have but with a positive
charge so what's a positively charged
electrons right in the nineteen thirties
they were thinking that this doesn't
exist
you cannot have a positively charged
electrons so some genius found a
solution and he said half the picture
was just develop the wrong way around if
i turn it it's an electron again but of
course this wasn't the solution this
wasn't actually the case because what
they actually found was a positron a
positron is an anti electron it's the
anti-matter counterparts to an electron
but they were not ready to accept this
result because he was thinking well
looks like an electronic but it has a
positive charge so there must be some
mistake when actually it was no mistake
it was just a positively charged
electrons and only much later
months or years later somebody did the
experiment again and they've paid very
close attention to all the magnetic
fields and two other directions and the
currents and then they were sure well
there is no mistake in my instrument it
really is something like a positively
charged electrons and then that was the
discovery of a positron
and so that means only if you can accept
something as a result then you will be
able to publish it and well so you need
to kind of trick yourself because if
there's some result in you think it
cannot be well maybe it can be and so
with this very difficult process of
accelerating everything of making the
collisions picking out the data and then
finally putting it all together in a
theory the LHC accelerator has already
produced a large success story because
you see this this gentleman here which
is Peter Hicks and his colleague
montclair they were honored with the
Nobel Prize in Physics in the year 2013
after the LHC accelerator had announced
that they had actually seen the Higgs
particle and the amazing thing is that
the theory these two proposed actually
was first thought of fifty years before
so it took fifty years from the ideas of
view of these two and actually a third
guy I hope he'll be called but he didn't
make it all the way he died some years
before this discovery but Peter Hicks
and France Moncler they lived to see
long enough that this particle
accelerator really confirm their idea
and it was only possible because we were
always building at the limit of our
capabilities like I said the 10 Gigabit
switch that they thought they needed in
the middle of the nineties but it didn't
exist these accelerators always like the
the most advanced thing that we can
build and after fifty years that was
enough to confirm this series so that
was a success and so from the very start
where we say that energy is this like
the same as mass like parts as a device
we can devise these machines to actually
make the particles go in some packets
and then they collide and there is a
huge amount of energy and if we pick
everything right and if we think the
right way about the theories then we can
actually make some surprising
discoveries and the nice thing is that
when the when the Nobel Prize was
actually announced it was not just these
you know these two men celebrating but
it was actually hundreds of people
everywhere around the world and even
myself I was sitting in Hamburg we were
watching live stream from Stockholm of
the Nobel Prize it was like a football
game and everybody was super excited
when they announced that they had found
the Higgs boson and then later when they
announced that there was the then there
was the nobel prize given for this
theory that was confirmed there so it's
a community work of everybody's not just
the people who think of the theory like
the physical genius people it is also
those who construct the accelerator
those who put it together those who
program the software
a lot of people involved in this very
big process and it can be a lot of fun
when you look at it or when you are a
part of it or just to find out something
about it because it's yeah its
cutting-edge technology and so with this
I would like to thank you very much for
your attention and I will be happy to
take your questions
that are going in the opposite direction
from colliding before you want them to
collide to do it at all
yes that's right so we want the
collisions to happen only in the
collision points and not the other way
around the LHC is actually composed of
two accelerators it is one pipe and
below that is another pipe and they go
in opposite directions and only inside
of the detectors these two pipes so
actually you know one pipe is going like
this
the other papers going like this and
they don't meet but in the interaction
points we kind of open the pipes and
then there's an opening where we can
direct with magnetic fields the
particles to meet and so we determined
by the way that we construct the
accelerator where the interaction points
are and that's where we build the
detectors
so and there are parts of that they are
accelerated in that way that you're
using alternating current are changing
the electric fields are just how do you
prevent well if they're moving in a
bunch how do you prevent some parts of
bills from being slow down and some from
being accelerated yes you need to your
right to need to synchronize your
electric field with the way that the
particles are actually moving because
that's a I want the particles to be
going along this way of the way if but
if they come too early then they will
not hit the right parts of the electric
field now it can happen and it happens
that some particles are being slow down
but then they they are sort of pushed
back into the next bunch it's not a nice
thing but the thing kind of it kind of
balances itself when you have a bunch
and some part of it is slow down too
much then it will drift all the way back
into the next punch and then hopefully
there it will fit right in
but it's not nice of course you want to
have a nice and clean bunches and saw
it's actually a lot of work to tune
everything right so that when the field
is in a special position they bunch will
actually also be in the correct position
so yeah that's difficult thing to do you
write thank you
you feeling paying your taxes then you
have to oversimplify complicated process
when you talk to general population and
thank second question is how do magnets
how do magnets work that's too difficult
to Christian well yes you are right of
course I the presentation as much
simplified from like one guy building
the actual accelerator presenting it to
a bunch of particle physics people there
is almost no formula in this
presentation but I think that if you
want people to feel like they learn
something about an accelerator it's
better to first proposed to first
present a simple principles and then
later if they want to you can look at
all the formula it's all public you know
you can look at the data but if I start
with integrals and differentials and
volume integration and everything then I
think people can lose interest and so i
hope i don't mean to offend people when
a very simple explanations it's just a
way that I think it's good to start into
the topic and if you know already more
than that's great and you can visit
presentations may be at universities you
can read documents on the internet you
can read books about particle physics
and I think that I would like to give a
start
into this process
how do you keep good questions we have
ten billion or a hundred billion
electrons in this bunch right then we
want to make the bunch go through the
accelerator but they all have the same
electric charge they are all charged
negatively so they repel each other so
the bunch actually will not stay in a
bunch it will want to drift apart and
that's bad because our tube where the
particles are actually going is only
about this big so if the bunch drift
apart of the particles were smashed into
the wall and be lost from the reaction
so what we do is we have magnets called
quarter polls they're not just north
pole in South Pole but their north south
another north and another south and the
magnetic field that is created between
these polls is called a quadrupole field
and you can use it like a lens like the
lenses sunglasses can focus the light
these quadrupole lenses can in a similar
way also focused the path of the
electrons quadrupole magnets here and
here comes my bombs and it's drifting
apart but then the quadrupole magnets
makes it go together again and so all
along the path we need lots of
quadrupole magnets to actually push the
particles together even though they're
charged wants to kind of make them repel
each other
iraq's well thank you everybody and have
a fun conference