so my name is Rob and I want to
apologize about the the font I think
whatever PDF reader this is messed up
the fund a little bit but hopefully
every every slide will be readable so my
talk today as the digital cockroach bait
station and the point is to teach you
the basics of how to build spam honey
pots and then also go into a little bit
of information about what data you can
get from from spam and what information
you can get especially from headers and
some somethings maybe you don't that are
not obvious that you can you can gain by
analyzing headers so who am I i work for
threat can act and this is a start up in
Virginia near Washington Dec and I'm
senior intelligence researcher I do
malware analysis and integrations and
just about anything that needs to be
done and this is my twitter handle down
here so follow me on Twitter when you
have a chance so what are the problems
here the main problem is that you need
to have more fresh malware samples you
need to have you know
fresh malicious links fresh advance fee
fraud if that's the type of threat that
you are working on and so the the goal
here is to take from all of these you
know different types of attacks phishing
attacks attacks gaining actionable
threat intelligence and gaining contacts
around what this particular attack that
you're looking at is what is probably
the purpose of the attack who the
adversary behind the attack is which
sometimes is difficult to determine but
all the ultimate goal is to give you
information about whether to pay more
attention to this particular attack if
you have one of your employees that has
clicked the link is this something that
you need to focus more attention on and
do damage control or is this something
that's just you know some sort of
unwanted program which you can you no
reform at their machine and then move on
its not something you know not Chinese
Apte or it's not you know some sort of
malware strain so I'm going to kind of
used to terms interchangeably
I think they're basically the same thing
so is spam trap and a spam honey pot I
will just use these terms
interchangeably but the idea of a spam
trap is a little bit older and
and has been around for years and years
and years but the idea of a spam trap
was more to collect spam on your mail
server and then you know at the same
time block just to be able to block the
spam but the purpose of what I'm talking
about here is sort of another advanced
stage of this type of honeypot wear what
you want to do is gather data out of it
about you know our boundaries malicious
links different types of attachments etc
so this is the definition that I have
spam traps this is from Wikipedia so
spam traps are usually email addresses
that are created not for communication
but rather to lure spam so my concept of
a spam honey pot still fits within this
older definition of spam trap but the
purpose is much more advanced than just
simply blocking the spam itself so I
kind of you know I want to relate this a
little bit because I have I have a
background in biology and so I like to
kind of bring a little bit of biology
into the sand and think of the
adversaries that I am working against as
cockroaches but not all of these are
cockroach traps each one of these type
of insect trap and this one you may
recognize that one is pretty traditional
cockroach trap but this one this is
actually for catching flies Drosophila
flies or very small flies
this is a general this is a general trap
for most types of insects and then this
is another type of cockroach trap this
one is in my opinion absolutely
disgusting because it has what's called
Roche butter on it and so they eat the
rich butter and they take it back and
has poison in it they take it back to
their colony and then they you know the
ones that are around that Roach also
died and then
this one is probably the most advanced
of all of these traps this one is for
bed bugs the way it works it has a co2
cartridge and bedbugs actually are
attracted to your breath
that's how they find you at night so but
moving on from entomology or move back
to spam so I always want to make
everything that I work on very very very
simple I don't want to spend time
maintaining a large system that is
complex I want to make something that is
very very simple and I want to reuse
open source software that is already
been written and is solid and and
trusted so you can choose whatever mail
server you like to use but I prefer
using postfix I would not recommend
using something like send mail unless
you want to have a sendmail honey pot
with with the spam honey pot on top of
it but yeah if you use something like
post pics and then what you do is you
have a Python script and I will go into
the details of the Python script you run
the Python script so that every single
email that sent to this mail server is
parsed and has all of the headers
converted into JSON and then any of the
attachments and any of the links that
are in the body are parsed out of it and
then all of this ends up being inserted
into an elastic search index and this
way you're able to do correlation among
different IP addresses as centers and
you can also do you know you can make
pretty graphs as well
so I want the red doesn't show up very
well in these slides I apologize but so
up here this is post pics so if you're
not familiar with postfix it's a general
generalist mail server software very
solid fairly secure and I personally
recommend running it on FreeBSD or
OpenBSD something where you don't have
to worry too much about the operating
system also being part of your honey pot
so JSON if you're not familiar with JSON
JavaScript object object notation and I
personally prefer JSON over XML and over
Yambol and the other different markup
languages
simply because it both it obviously it's
machine readable but if you if you
printed well with nice pacing human
beings can also read it so you can read
the data you can you can read the data
that's in that interchange format but
XML I just I i cant read XML it's almost
illegible because it's it's too busy and
then elasticsearch you know it's up to
you if you want to use a different type
of database to store your data that's up
to you there's MongoDB there's other
types of no sequel but I prefer
elasticsearch simply because it's very
very very easy very easy to set up it's
very easy to use and all of all of the
text searching and access to
elasticsearch is via RESTful API so it's
it it goes over the same protocols as
all the rest API's so the mail server
configuration again you know we're going
for simple you want to accept all email
from any domain even if the demand that
you have that pointing to this
particular server is a different domain
if someone is going to send you spam
you don't want to rejected for any
reason even if it's for the wrong
man wrong wrong sender anything so you
want to accept all usernames and you
want to accept any domain but one thing
that's very important is that you want
to prevent having a balanced message
sent back out you don't want to run a
spam honey pot and have you you're
attracting all sorts of spam coming in
and you don't want to waste time sending
bounce messages back to all of the is
probably nonexistent email addresses and
from addresses etcetera and so you
basically want to block all outbound
mail and essentially one of the things
that I've done on my spam honey pots is
on top of configuring the mail server to
not send bounce messages or any sort of
return message at all I make sure that
the host based firewall on the p.m.
blocks all outbound traffic on those
certain ports that guaranteed not to
make any mistakes even if there's like a
Miss configuration I'll stick it still
will not send something out that I don't
want it to so this is just you know
anything at anything that's what you
want to accept so what i do is i process
all of the inbound email with a custom
Python scripts and just as a backup
because you know for for any reason the
elasticsearch cluster is unreachable and
you can't send your data they're going
to have another copy of it because you
know you might miss one thing that's
very important so you want to make sure
that you keep a local copy on on the
mail server on the spam honey pot for a
period of time before you know so that
you can go back and we parse your
messages if something messes up in in in
your in your storage and database so
this is just a recommendation and
actually if if python is not your
language you can you could use any
language at all because it's very very
simple simple what I'm doing here
basically parsing each one of the header
fields in bikini value pairs and then
say you know basically X and then
exporting that
as a JSON file and then the body and the
at the body also as one you know key
body and then the value is the text of
the body and then also just as a second
you know so that there's a single text
blob I also save header as a key and
then the entire header not broken up
just exactly as it is in the in the
message as another key value pair so I
prefer Python three point four you know
there's certain times where I have to
use Python too but I tried to move away
from Python for anything new
so and then like I said that translates
all of the emails into JSON format and
then exports them and saves them into
index in elasticsearch so good this is
this is kind of a very busy slide but
we're gonna spend a lot of time on this
one because it's very important to know
what data you can get from spam and I
apologize if you can't read it all read
it out to you but so one of the
important things that you can get is
from the date time zone so if you have
legitimate email coming from you know
eastern standard time in the United
States chances are that's coming from
mail server that you
you might not trust but at least you
know that it's in the United States but
if you have an email
invalid and the the timezone is that a
No in China or in europe you know you
you might actually put maybe you know if
you have some sort of filtration you
might put a you know a +1 as far as like
suspicious Ennis of this particular
piece of email so especially you can
find you know information about where
that mail server or or the botnet or
wherever it thinks it's sending from you
can get some small amount of information
from the timezone itself so pay
attention to the time zone spf so these
next two SPF and DTM these are important
said D cam is domain keys and SPF both
SPF and decamped our methods of blocking
spam so they are there a way to verify
whether the sender of this particular
email is who they say they are and is
coming from the demand that they say
they're coming from so in this case it's
good to it's good to find this
information you can find the forged you
can find forged EMPs also the SPF if you
see spf fail pay more attention to that
particular pieces so another thing this
is this is something that is a little
bit that might not be as obvious as the
other components here so the e EHL Oh or
a cello string this is during the SMTP
handshake when you know when one mail
server or a mail client is speaking to a
mail server it makes a connection on
port 25 and then it goes through an SMTP
handshake so the first thing it does is
it says hello or a cello and then it
says it's domain is supposed to be
so if for example you know I am a male
client and I'm telling the truth I'm not
like a misconfigured mail client I'm not
doing anything malicious
what I would do is if if my mail client
is configured to be at you know Rob at
example.com lho would say lho
example.com the domain that I'm telling
the mail server that I'm coming from so
this one is actually interesting because
let's say that you have a particular
botnet which is standing out you know
thousands and thousands thousands of
pieces of spam
there's only two things that it can do
it's not going to tell the truth so it's
not going to be no its not going to give
you it's true domain because it doesn't
actually have a specific domain but
there's two things that can do it will
have either similar to a demand
generation algorithm like the ones that
you see for.net situ where the callback
to demand generation algorithm so to
have a similar type of algorithm just
generating random or some random domains
or it will just be configured to say the
same thing over and over the same like
hardcoded lho string so you can key off
of that and you can for some types of
botnet you can identify that particular
operator of the bottom because of the
way that they have configured it and so
this is actually an indicator of that
particular type of delivery method so
that one is pretty interesting also
obviously the originating IP originating
IP is not always the source you could
have open relays you can have sometimes
even have a male sorry a web server and
the web server is compromised in the web
service actually sending out spam or
reeling spam from botnet the pit like a
PHP similar to a PHP back door but a PHP
based mailer
if you do if your if you maintain
websites and you have like a compromise
WordPress site you've probably seen this
type of Mahler before so what you can
get from the originating IP obviously
you can get network who is GeoIP ASN who
is and then also this is one that is
that some people don't paid close
attention to but there's our who is so
an ISP will reassign of block of IP
addresses to maybe a hosting provider
and so the hosting providers information
is found in the car who is data so if
you need to contact someone to report
abuse often you can get the the more
specific information from our who is so
the next one
reply to reply to is interesting for
certain types of scams that you would
see in in spam
so specifically these are important very
important in advance fee fraud so these
are the sorts of things where you know
the Nigerian prince is sending you one
million dollars as long as you send the
Nigerian Prince $100 now this sort of
thing that type of adversary needs to
receive your reply so they don't forge
the information here in reply to this is
usually a live address and so you can
use that as an indicator if you're
collecting a set of threat intelligence
so this can be an indicator that you
want to to to save and also you can
correlate across different attacks and
follow patterns as adversaries typically
use their same you know same set of
email address or same style of email
addresses over and over and over the
subject subject interesting the subject
this is interesting in certain ways but
you know when I get down here to this
when I talk about the same hash the
that's where the subject will become
more important
but the subject by itself is until we
get down here and I explained this the
subject is not necessarily that
important at this point the from address
this is typically forged you know you
during the SMTP handshake you can type
as long as you're as long as that mail
server they are sending the spam to is
maybe misconfigured are not configured
very strictly the from address can just
be anything anything you want you can
type in whatever you want
so the from address not necessarily
something that you want to keep as a
specific indicator of a live email
address that you may want to track but
it can be it can be used to correlate
across different different attacks you
can also see you even see if someone is
trying to attack your company you might
even see the from address being an email
address at your company so then the
envelope sender this is a little bit
different than the from address this is
so when when you have an SMTP session
and the connection goes through the LA
show at the beginning and then it says
receipt to and mail from so the mail
from the email address that is put into
mail from is found here in the envelope
sender so this is this can be forged
also but it's actually a diff it can
even be a completely different address
than the from because from is actually
when new when you go past the the mail
from in the receipt to the next step you
enter data and so the from the from
address is actually part of the data
section of an SMTP connection so so
return path this is not not necessarily
an important for me in this stuff but
this part so X mailer and the mail URL
this is very very very interesting so
when you have a compromised website
and the compromised website is being
used to send spam
one of two things can happen one is the
the PHP mailer that's being used that
has been inserted into the the
compromised website as being used to
relay the spam if the spammer doesn't
configure it properly it will actually
record its own path on that mail server
in this X mailer field in the header so
if you want to do some sort of take down
on that particular you know spam stores
you can actually figure out exactly the
file on the server that is that has been
inserted into the server so you can call
the you know hosting company or the
website owner and say you know hey not
only take this file off clean up your
stuff but also can you send me a copy of
this file I want to see like what the
configuration is inside you know what
the the PHP code is for it so the next
part down here this is another not so
obvious but very interesting header
component so the mime boundary string
them I'm boundary string when you have
different types of data in the body of
an email they all have a mime boundary
string around them unless the email is
just plain text if it's plain text there
won't be any mind boundary strings but
if you have HTML or if you have an
attachment
you'll have a mime boundary string on
both sides of that different type of
data and if you look to the mind
boundary string is typically a random or
semi random string of characters but
again because that is you know
you have a botnet and the botnet is just
generating spam
chances are that botnet is the
generating the spam is not using you
know clean good email client code that's
going to generate normal you know a
regular mind boundary string it's going
to generate either the same mind
boundaries string over and over for a
lot of emails or it will use one that
has a certain pattern and so this
becomes its own indicator the origin of
that particular piece of spam
ok now we get down to some hash so this
is this is something that is that I'm
working on right now it's still in the
still in sort of the theoretical area
but some hash is one of the two I know
of two algorithms that do piecewise
fuzzy hashing so piecewise fuzzy hashing
is something that's used extensively and
malware research and what it is you take
you know you take a blob of data and you
break it up into certain known pieces
and then you take hashes of the pieces
and then when you have to let's say two
files that have had a piecewise fuzzy
hash you can compare them and see how
different they are from each other and
if you know one part of it is is
slightly different but then this whole
areas the same you know the distance
between those two files will be very
close so there's two there's two
different to different types of
piecewise for the action that I'm aware
of what is called sim hash and some hash
is actually a algorithm which is
targeted towards text so it's it's
sufficient for looking at two pieces of
text and seeing how different or how or
how similar they are and then the other
type is called S O S S deep and if you
do our research you probably heard of
SSD deep it's more
it's more tuned for looking at the
difference between two binary files
right so the thing that I'm the thing
that I'm working on is to take a SIM
hash of certain header fields such as
the from address such as the the
subjects reply to things that are going
to be indicators you know things that
are going to be indicators of possibly
you know the origin of this of the spam
and then take the same hash of each
one's each one of these and you know in
theory I should be able to get a
basically a distance and a similarity
between one email and another email and
see you know in and be able to use that
in an automated way if I have this
particular you know don't open the door
please open this fax you know and has an
attachment if if the set of header
fields after I've run it through some
hash is close enough I can also say hey
this other email that's not necessarily
asking about the facts might be closely
related to this one because of some of
the similarities in the header so I can
you know perhaps use this to block it on
a mail server or just do it to to to
find you know texas's of different
attacks so that's a that's that's it for
the header and then this is over here
this is this is all the information not
all of the information but these are
some of the major components and
information that you can get from the
body of the email so again
advance fee fraud attacks use phone
numbers embedded in the email that's one
of the ways they get you to contact them
from from my experience a lot of these
are VoIP numbers that are pointing to
another number so that when they get
taken down they can just roll it to the
next one the next most prevalent from
that is probably cell phones but most of
the time it's icy avoid numbers in here
and then of course the attachment
attachment can be either you know it
could be any number of things and maybe
a base 64 encoded HTML it could have a
job it could have a javascript attack
buried in the attachment it could be a
binary it could be any number of things
also you can get a Ural if you've got a
drive-by attack or if you just have like
a regular download some you know I've
seen many many many many malware attacks
where the the the the URL is just a file
click and download the file and then
it's you know it the instructions in the
email please run this year please open
this and it sometimes the fire will be
like JPG
exe or or PDF exe or something like this
and it works I mean it it's amazing it
still works but it does work and then I
down here I have listed to two types of
same hash that I take of the body and
the reason for this I just called this
rendered some hash and the reason for
this is some emails will have planned
tax and then in another between another
mine roundtree they'll have an HTML with
like all the pretty graphics and fonts
and all that crap so what I want to do
is not necessarily take a SIM hash that
includes all of the HTML so what I uses
beautiful soup you can use any type any
type of scraper software but I use
beautiful soup to just remove all of the
HTML tags and then after I removed all
the HTML tags then I take the same hash
of the remaining the remaining data and
then obviously you can get an email
address and then the text of the body so
this is just an overview of some of the
different things that you can get from
an email and you know I already talked
about elasticsearch so now this is the
this is the part where you
alright I'm sorry this these were these
are actually cockroaches those were bed
bugs but I guess the the the the the
picture didn't come through on this
laptop I apologize but this is where you
want to first of all register a domain
another option is to go and look there's
you know there's many many many domains
squatting sites that want to sell you
old demands so you can some of them you
can rank the domain by its age and so
who cares what the domain is I wanted
domain that's been out there for 20
years just existing for twenty years
because it will attract more spam than
others but one thing that's important
after you after you have registered your
domain
make sure if you're going to register it
make sure to turn on demand privacy or
whatever thing that particular registrar
provides or just put fake information in
there must cancel your domain for a year
and still someone complains about it now
the next step is to configure DNS
there's a couple of nuances here for
configuring your DNS it's very important
to make sure that you don't have only
one IP address because you're trying to
simulate a real mail server in a real
male environment in the real enterprise
in a company so no company has 11 IP
address for their mail service they have
a set of IP addresses for the mail
server referring to different ones so
make sure you assign at least three IP
addresses you can pretend because the
the mail server you can only you only
have to set up one spam honeypot 11 mail
server for this but a sign 33 different
IP addresses at least to that server so
that you simulate a real environment
also create a primary and to backup host
names have all of them male one-dot male
one example.com mail to
not example.com and Mail 3 etcetera also
simulating a real male environment so
that it looks right now this last when
this is actually the one that's very
nuanced so you want to have three or
more
DNS MX records and you want to have
differing priorities set to those MX
records we're going to look at a slide
in a minute that shows this but the
reason for this is sometimes the main
your primary mail server is where you
have things like antivirus or some sort
or you're running spam filters and the
protection that you have is on the on
your primary mail server your secondary
mail server or tertiary mail server
sometimes will have no spam filtration
no AV and so i've seen a lot of spammers
will send only to the higher priority MX
records and they will they will
specifically on purpose not send to your
primary mail server because they're
hoping that the primary mail server
trusts mail that's coming from the
secondary and the secondary has no spam
protection on it so make sure you have
three DNS MX records so that you catch
you catch that extra spam and you catch
those other people that are targeting
you know lower priority MX
mail servers so now you need to generate
email addresses to see them out to all
of the world's ended everywhere get it
on every single list and everything but
what you wanna do is you can see them on
your own website put them in you know
put them in metadata put them all over
the place
give them to your friends have your
friends help seed when they you know
write a comment on some website just
have them put the ring this random email
address like in the bottom of their
comment you know why not
but the important part here when you're
seeding email addresses out is
maintained either a spreadsheet or
database or something so that you know
where the email address went where you
put it
what date you put it there and you know
maybe who you gave it to have someone
else is going to see it for you so that
you know alright this place
generates this type of spam so you can
correlate where that email address was
seeded with the type of attacks on the
type of spam that come into that
particular email address so when you're
registering to demand sorry this doesn't
actually didn't didn't wrap properly
with this with this PDF reader I
apologize but there's many free services
out there for registering domains and
they will even let you have gmail email
service on them
the adversary uses these you know like .
TK and stuff like this why can't we use
the same services so just make sure that
you protect your identity by using free
email services
burner you know basically burner emails
and protect yourself with domain
registration DNS service and before you
begins eating before you begin seeding
anything out into the world and trying
to collect
spam look very carefully at your own who
is information look very carefully at
your DNS records look at it very
carefully and see if you made a mistake
and you're leaking any information about
yourself if you left your name or if you
have registered the domain and you
forgot to turn on who is privacy or
something like this and you know there's
some identifying information about you
you want to make sure thats not there
before you begin sending stuff out to to
attract adversaries and also this is
something that's very very important on
the spam honeypot itself there is pretty
good chance that at some point this
server will get popped by someone right
so you don't want to have the admin or
the user name that you're logging into
the spam honey pot as your you know your
hacker handle you don't want to have you
don't want to have any trace of anything
on there just call it something boring
like you know user one and an admin one
so that there's no there's no trace of
of anything that if someone pops your
spam honey pot they could possibly
figure out who you are and information
about that also with things like logs
it's up to you when I when I set up my
spam honey pots the author logs and
incoming IP address logs are all set to
Dev know if the if the box gets popped
it makes it a little bit more difficult
for someone to figure out where where
I'm coming from
so make your username on the new server
very generic it didn't work
ok so this was a screenshot of the DNS
records for a example spam honey pot I
apologize this light doesn't work if any
by the way if anybody wants the slides
just come tell me afterwards I'll give
you a copy of the slides I got them here
in PDF and you should be able to if you
read if you look this look at this you
know in a different PDF reader you
should be able to see this this example
slide so
now you know you have to sometimes have
a little fun when you're doing the sort
of things when you're generating the
email addresses you want to generate
email addresses some of them you might
want to generate them that are just
random whatever but all the other ones
you might want to have something that
looks real you know real names real
names for companies in this sort of
thing so have fun with it so these are
just a few sites that I use to generate
the names so I have you know behind the
name random random name generator name
mesh and these two are you serious
interesting because they make they just
they they they spit out random generic
company names if you want to make a
domain name that's you know based on
something that sounds like a real
company just have have this make a
couple of random names another thing
scrabble word scrabble word finder deal
if you like Scrabble you can increase
your Scrabble knowledge at the same time
as you're making fake email addresses by
looking through all the scrabble word
finder Xin than memorizing the words
that you're using there and just
creating email addresses with it and
then anagram solvers put in a word and
then find all the different anagrams for
it and then creating mode email
addresses for that so now you have spam
and the sorry this this slide also had a
picture it had a picture of probably my
favorite piece of spam I've ever seen
and believe me come come get the PDF of
this it actually has a malicious link
where it ends in main PHP and then it
has a big ass key like finger clicking
the link and it's awesome
by paula jones' the PDF reader on this
machine is not not the best but
thank you this is this is the company's
blog where we publish research this is
my twitter handle and then this is our
company to order handle so please come
check us out and follow me and if we
have any questions what is generating
mailbox names over using a Cattrall
mailbox
what is the adventures of generating
mailbox names on the honey pot over
using a catch-all mailbox so so the
question is what is the what is the
benefit of generating a set of email
addresses over just having a spam honey
pot that that catches everything so you
do want to always have a spam
the underlying spam honey pot is that it
catches everything but the reason why
you would generate I mean generating the
random ones is not the important thing
it's that you have a specific email
address that you have succeeded in one
specific location so you know that if
something is sent to this particular
email address you know where you see did
it and you know perhaps some information
about how the how the adversary is is
getting there are gathering their email
addresses could also you said that you
log when you needed that email address
to a certain form or whatever to gather
spam
you could also log that the email
address it would still show up in the
log of the catch-all email address that
the email that you so I'm now I'm not
following you if you wait so you're
saying you know I think there might have
been a misunderstanding so I'm when I
say generate email addresses all I mean
is generate the text of the email
address
nothing on the spur nothing on the
server that yeah the catch the catch all
will catch all that well I'm gonna ya
what i'm saying generating an email
address I'm just saying you know use
those tools to generate a list of email
addresses that you put in your
spreadsheet or database so that you can
correlate that with the spam that's
coming in that's what I meant thanks
sure well first of all thank you for
interesting presentation I have a
feeling that this is only one half of
the story right so you have a built-in
system which which is pretty elaborate
can track where you've sent to cede it
addresses to what parts are used to
harvest those addresses now what I would
be interested in what most legal do you
have a teacher on the disposal to
actually do something about it basically
you are harvesting a lot of dictating
formation about spammers somebody might
say so what do with it
ok so this is a good question so one
once you've gathered your spam
what can you do with it what what
purpose do you have for gathering this
so there's many different purposes here
but I'll talk about one so specifically
if there is a new a new attack actually
not even get I will give you a specific
use case so after the hack after hacking
team was popped everybody remembers that
two months ago hockey team was popped
and then they had a a set of flash days
that were being weaponized first the
first one that I found that weaponized
it was an angler ek and then you know
rig exploit kit and all the other
exploit kits also used it but there was
also an apt group
which is known by the name wet be so the
wet be apt group began using that
particular / exploit weaponize from from
the hacking team disclosure and so they
began sending that out just as a you
know a shotgun blast via spam and that's
how I caught that so you know the the
way that I dunno gathered the data 222
then look at the flash file you know
reverse it into action scripts find out
what it's the payload binary is that
it's delivering all of this I gained
that knowledge by having a spam honeypot
working and and catching that to begin
with are you also employing something
like legal things is it something you
can do in this global world is it is
running a spam honeypot let's let's
change so let's let's let's change that
question slightly instead of is it legal
let's ask the question is it illegal not
to my knowledge is it illegal so no my
question was not about you being legal
but when once to track down somebody can
you take legal actions think that's
doable let's say so after you know after
you've developed a
you know a set of threat intelligence on
a particular attack and then from that
sort of threat intelligence may be over
quite a bit of time you were able to
perhaps an adversary their persona
emerges from you know from your analysis
of this data typically I did you know
it's it's difficult to to do something
legally against that entity they're
typically in a different country than
the us- however it's still very very
important to know that information so
that you're so that your security team
and your company can make a decision as
to whether this adversary is very
capable or whether they're just you know
some script kiddie that doesn't have a
whole lot of knowledge and is not
specifically targeting you so you'd be
able to divide your attacks between you
know just typical crime where and then
something that's a targeted attack
against you and so therefore you're able
to not necessarily go after that
adversary or that group but you're able
to make an educated decision as to
whether you need to pay more attention
to what just happened on your network or
if you can just use regular procedures
and and move on you know thank you
first of all thanks for very interesting
presentation I really like that I have a
question have you ever thought of making
your honey pot as an openly with one
option is to limit connections which
coming from outside the wall to your
server to prevent exhaustion and the
same time
prevent reflected in our service attack
but it may be a good idea to be
intermediate being one in the middle
between the attacker better than being
the receiver I hadn't thought about that
but definitely we will talk thanks yeah
I think that's a good idea anymore
questions all right thank you very much
everybody thank you