welcome to this year's Belkin we are a
bit late but we already know
be double talk about the power of over
sourcing topic is greg is so please
welcome and enjoy that hello everyone
today I'll speak about grass guess power
of open sourcing and by Tony rather get
and what
but first I'll think about definition
above definition of grass gets glass
pieces graphic resource of my support
system commonly referred as grass keys
that open source open source system get
it published like General Public License
since 1999 then it's a portable
the weekend with the on Linux and other
devices but first British history grass
is was born in the early eighties it was
developed it was a helicopter in america
army
that's developed this got a disgrace
system it was for use to show some
psychological logical system and they
tell us but now there is seven today we
have seven different types of grass
peace now the seventh nationally is
stable version and we can use it now
they it's frightening see language but
version 6 we grasp case came in Python
language it's easier to write and
understand for developers so that was
the best the bus now these days
stable version is grass is available
since 2015 it offers a large data
support improvement topological to the
order to achieve actor and driving
and much improved vector network allows
analyzed the best import the best thing
about certain grass guess seven version
is full-time parole framework and there
we can analyze different different the
images from from two or three types of
time and we can analyze these changes in
thinking been extended many many new
menu options have been added for example
for image processing go we can now we
can now analyze all bids will be on US
soil soil heat flux cause that in fact
are protesting there is faster dating
import we can make creating and new
basically indexes like button for design
vector analyzes there is there isn't so
much memory required for general support
global mobile enabling and it improved
by John P
weekend
read-write grass refers to and from
numpy and we PSU supported that's mean
implemented in part sir like C C++
Python and she'll
question is who is using race as open
source program there is a lot of you not
just in commercial but the currently
grass species used in academic
commercial purposes as well as many
governmental agencies including Norway
USD the CSI and the national parks parks
on this matter where you can see that
uses mostly used in Europe than in
America North America and little bit in
asia now talk about capability can do
with a roster to the factors that Dan
Hauk so support vector network analyzers
support image processing system
we can realize system and grassed uses
linkable two different types of
databases like as well
PostgreSQL MySQL and SQL drunk driver
writer analyze that mean that we can
ultimata crossed the line in the area to
vector conversation than we can but
buffer instructors
profile they took over the weekend we
can put color table in these maps and
then we can director and point-to-point
data format
grass yes we can use different data
types like to the restaurant they take
including image processing trade of
oxidative for volumetric data to the or
3d vector data with apology and
multidimensional
point they roster geometry is presented
the in cell lot tricks with coordinate
the resolution is defined with south so
weird and high resolution can be in
kilometers meters degrees and but vector
geometry is presented like a point
Android line quandary
geometry is true to it really that means
we have XY and that coordinate to
present rector raita
these are some command we can use in
grass keys for example every command
have some preferences
they can for which is specialized for
example graphics demeans is used for
function display that is the command for
graphical output than
fixes for raster function it's for
presenting rather data and the
protesting with then of course we for
red Torin protesting with director data
I will show you some examples with this
with the functions but important thing
to the Marshallese that grass always
import complete map but one we want to
export export we should to cut into area
of interest and with export factor we
always we always get the entire map with
raster we have two different functions
where we can define will we get mapping
orbit room as usual or
resolution current region resolution
these different functions are brought
out the F region is the current working
area and important thing is when we make
some cult calculations with directors
these calculations are made only format
but on roster calculation calculations
are made just on current reader that
means if we are a position on the serbia
these calculations will made just under
serbian not if map is about
dialog box and their way where is data
jews location and maps that are
important to choose because that the
final coordinate system than one week
rules all these last start
and this
windows where we we will display our
data and analyzed
which one will show for example it would
be a location and then ok this is one
example we can make different type of
genetic maps
and on this matter will show railroads
this area for example we can make we can
make some analyzes like alright shaded
relief map it would be tearing analyzes
and here we can see the functions in
squares means that we we are using
raster and and now we can choose which
one of these functions will be used for
our next map for example will generate
contour lines here we should important
last name of the input would be rationed
name of output can't control the levels
that important that we do we must define
these trees for example and right
now we can see all these contour lines
and that's great but here we have vital
shell and what about if we need more
options
look at just for a moment I'll show you
a glass case Architektur and we can see
that as any open source program we can
make some code for this program and we
can make some improvements and on this
weekend see that python is very
important in developing with grass gas
detector pythons cup of tea it's in a
way that started in with 2006 grass yes
grass started with scripting pipeline
because that's easier way to improve
grass gays and lesbians fighting is
default language for creating down there
are too many pipe and I worries included
in grass is but all of them are divided
into two in two parts for raster and
former rector on this two sides you can
find out many of the examples of these
scripts and on this picture is one
simple script for opening Quarian
closing of actor Matt it's true that the
grass is have over 400 different
functions who we can use but what if
there is there isn't our function that
we just need in that moment the best way
ways to write sample script this is
great but we cannot find out in bio
progress library the progress library
have a menu of Germany examples and get
horrible so we can find these python
script that can help us to solve our
problem and shoulders and although it is
implementing grass just $7 where we can
make our model and we can look on this
model in Python editor 404 advanced user
that that advantage because we can we
can make our model and by tonight or we
can make some some changes but for users
who are not as good in programming these
more those are the best way to make
their own
their own function
and make some improvements for in their
analyzes I can show you on grass gives
side there is a programmer's manual with
these libraries we can find out some
codes that can help us to to solve our
problem and make improvements every new
every new Python script will which
really is uploaded on site is will be no
script will be uploaded and every month
we we get to these are the update on
where we can use them if they are if
they are good we can use them and on
that way we improve everywhere journal
for grass case
here we can make it by some some changes
and here is graphic modeler where we can
make some of those commander day and
here is also quite an editor if you if
you don't like to work with model you
can hold here directly and use your
script in analyzed and you can choose
which of this course we want to make
some command the way the model waitress
amanda roster command we choose one of
these want to make me with black door or
database we can use one of these ok
of course there is a lot of tutorials
for learning holding in Python the grass
juice scripting and for a final of Star
Trek there is one way deal from 1987
where Captain Kirk says speaks about
improvements encoding and he says don't
keep your information about soils
vegetation roads or archaeological sites
rolled up in my pubes or stuffed into
drama keep it in the computer so he he
said that we all need to work with maps
if you free work with it that's the best
way on computer and the best way to make
some improvements is to give our
contribution through making some scripts
and coding thank you and sorry for the
inconvenience