thanks shown up
overs as everybody feeling these men are
so let's start this thing that I made my
name is Jared hey I'm a Manchester with
got the digital copy and sends a
previous life as a sysadmin it's really
want to introduce me to use scripting
and moving in Syria and I want to see
that there is a lot of really
interesting stuff going on in the
section related to PowerShell I have
always shied away from defining myself
as a developer but I keep developing
things then releasing them which i think
is by definition what makes a developer
so own up to that label now and along
with my wife I'm the co-owner of a
broken bunny is famous freezer and he
got sick while ago and I was headed
stuck tilted so he looks really really
cute and very very curious at all times
so I noticed Carolina connie is
definitely a a gray beard con definitely
some older folk air some Linux gray hats
so as you start out with a new church
and see what the hell's PowerShell
PowerShell scripting language that
Microsoft came up with a while ago was
built into Windows seven when it came
out and it's this really powerful
language that's built into dieting that
so what makes it cool is outside of the
built-in tools that you get with
PowerShell you also get full access to
everything that's in dotnet and you get
a lot of great methods to interact with
calm and WMI and all these made of ways
to manage Windows it's a object oriented
language so that makes it really easy to
work around the system a great example
of that is they rewritten paying so that
when you do something that actually
returns an object in a little bit like
the response time ttyl all sorts of
stuff that actually makes paying more
powerful the command structure in
PowerShell has a verb now sort of ocular
it makes language really propose but it
also makes it into it for example if you
have get content which is going to read
a free content from the file contents
are you write content to about so it's
going to be easy day into it you know
how to use power show the other cool
thing is the health system is actually
usable it's a lot like man pages from
you know the dude that created our show
actually came from a Linux background so
you'll see a lot of knowledge to letting
scripting to the point that there are
built-in aliases for LLS W get girls
right in our show which is pretty cool
she also has really great to have
completion its type of lesion for
as great a completion for it commands as
well as the parameters for those
commands Wildcats are pretty much
anything in PowerShell you can talk
completed so really great easy language
to use its been used these days mainly
for administration networks Microsoft is
moving all of their management basically
overshoot PowerShell
manifesting itself in things like the
new versions of Exchange console new
versions of the Active Directory
administrative center these are all just
kind of GUI frontend for PowerShell
commands to the point that you can
enable a window that will show you of
the parachute pants are running in the
background
microsoft also is using it for
automation so if you're familiar with
Shaffer pop it
microsoft has something called desired
state config which is kind of their take
on you know popular and people accept a
lot more complicated I tried to use it
as a sysadmin and gave up and just use
it instead cuz actually puppet on
Windows was a lot easier to use than
desired state config any effort sec
community people are just grabbing onto
our show there is really a lot of great
stuff going on in the data forensics or
instant response side of the house lot
of work being done on lay real low level
risk analysis doing since PowerShell is
modern language is very networker we're
so it's really easy to do you like
queries for elective and blogs or W my
across the entire network of his makes
it super-easy to you you know do instant
response to you
investigation cross your whole network
for you no malicious the bands are you
know what have you
there's also a lot of worry I'm not
going to be talking a lot about the blue
team or instant response side of things
but if you are interested in that check
out
invoked ash I R dot com there is a guy
that runs that geriatrics and does
amazing work with our show last time I
checked your blog entry on the front of
his page where is like low-level disc
and analytics for his leg looking at
blocks on a disk using powershell which
is not something you would expect from
justice scripting language but we're
ratings so we're we want to break stuff
so I can go ahead and what can we do
with our shells you break stuff all the
great thing about it is our shelves with
the admins are using to manage their
networks so that means if we get on and
admins box we can manage their network
for them it's also really really hard to
lock down because PowerShell uses this
scary console that you type in windows
admins aren't really aware of it so in a
lot of cases they don't like it down
there not there's just zero wariness of
it what actually led to me
creating pas attack is at a friend that
was on an engagement and he landed on
this terminal server and it was really
well lockdown you couldn't open Explorer
II can open command prompt you could
open power show so we're going back over
Lake text messages back and forth you
know ok try this try to see you know
that means just weren't aware so it's a
great tool to use on the once you start
getting into the tools said some of the
work that's been done by the offensive
community there is a lot of really cool
advanced level stuff going on
you'll see a lot of stuff like DLL
injection or WMI abuse which is
something that
manifestation on twitter has been doing
some work on and what's great about this
is the community is really led by these
guys that they've been doing this for a
long time so they bring with them a very
mature methodology to power show and it
kind of comes from angles so from the
10th I strangle you see a lot of focus
on not leaving a trace or reusing tools
that are already on the box
a lot of in-memory its hacks you know
stuff like that and then on the flip
side more from the development and they
are very big on following the
conventions that PowerShell is kind of
built up within itself so supporting
that health system every man's going to
have like you know it get help he can
get a man page out of it every commands
going to use similar switches that you
see in other you know it's so the
offensive community does a good job of
jurors making in their tools work like
you'd expect a powerful tool to work so
I'll this is awesome but you know I've
noticed that as great as PowerShell is
there is this kind of barrier to entry
that you know people are kind of aware
that there's some cool stuff going on in
PowerShell if you put your standard
penthouse or in front of a PowerShell
console they wouldn't know what to do
with it and I think a lot of that is you
know Windows isn't that cool things like
focus on a really pay attention to all
your cool worried coz and stuff done in
like Python on Linux and stuff like that
developments out of windows just isn't
as interesting or glamour it's
as you know what you would see on the
Linux side and the other side is you
know it's can be intimidating
you know there's a lot of stories that
have a hard enough time doing something
productive with Python you know they
never tell me learn this language that
you know is this Windows niche you know
it's not it's not on their list of
priorities and then you know I mentioned
that the general populace is kind of
aware of that there is some cool stuff
going on in PowerShell but they don't
know the specifics and that's good
there's kind of this like our show click
on Twitter where yeah I mean there's a
lot of course you're going on but unless
you're following that circle you're
probably not aware it like that certain
stuff doesn't kind of surface out of
that you know little tiny click so
that's kind of what led me to build pas
attack so yes attack is a custom
PowerShell console designed for
offensive use it includes a lot of the
best offensive utilities that are
available in the PowerShot community to
rate their embedded into it it also
tries to emulate PowerShell console
experience so that includes using really
powerful tab completion of the man's
you're running in PowerShell commands in
PAS attack so if you are familiar with
our show as it is right now then you can
just can't jump into POS tagging it
going
if you're not familiar with our show you
can come learn get your chops and then
apply those two other instances you know
when you kind of start getting involved
with empire or land out of her shell
prompt that isn't BS attack you'll know
what to do
the other thing that you want to make
the barrier to entry as low as possible
so it is a single executable there is no
set up there is no install you download
this executable and run it on and get
hacking so with India stack there are
over a hundred and ten commands that
cover the entire range of a pen testing
gauge meant so recon privilege
escalation back doors lot of great work
on recon
on that later it includes a lot of
demands from frameworks that you might
be familiar with power tools power
supply teaching is a really big projects
are just these giant Lee monolithic
collections of offensive towards their
awesome also under surface some of the
lesser-known tools NPS attack so it
includes invade which if you're familiar
with responder it's basically responder
but in our show so it can do a zombie
relay can do basically capturing
credentials and stuff by speaking like
the W pad proxy address a lot of really
great work being done there
the other thing includes is Powercat
which is a cat but in PowerShell as
evidenced by its name what's cool about
our cat I found out so like Nick at how
you can do dashiki you know XQ bash and
throw that at a reverse IP and get your
shell will do the same thing except
throws back to our show what's cool
about running power cap with NPS attack
though is the PowerShell session it
sends out has all the tools in PAS
attack RA and so it's like this fully
weaponized shoulder sending back to you
right here it's pretty cool so with a
hundred and ten commands that still
overwhelmingly acres in this problem do
you still have no idea what to do so I
wrote a man called get attack and where
get attacked does is it access like a
search engine for attacked or you know
it's a commands so that's the limits on
the screen but basically you can give it
any strain and it's going to search
through all the commands NPR's tack
every journalist of whatever it is that
matches your query so in this case we're
looking for passwords we could see that
we got mimic as forgot your password etc
countless get through with building pas
attack I wanted to make sure that it
wasn't just for the lab I want to build
something that would actually be used
for OnLive engagements so when the
things I'm doing is
is the payloads these routes are
offensive PowerShell scripts there
encrypted before they are compiled into
ups attack and then when you start vs
attack it takes is encrypted payloads
and decrypt straight into memory so the
decrypted playing sax payloads never
actually touched disc Davies gotten a
little bit better about detecting some
of the more common or more popular
offensive PowerShell scripts like
democrats so this kind of voice that
because there is nothing for a beat the
tax also sends it's it's a custom
console it doesn't actually touch
Powershot exe it's called through dot
net income supports that so in the event
you land on a box where PowerShell died
txt is blocks they can't really block
the dotnet d lolz so this should still
work on her pretty much any circumstance
will be able to execute our show the
other thing is I want to focus on making
sure that this worked everywhere so
pissed at targets done at three top-five
which means that it works on anything
from a clean install of Windows seven
other way up through a fully patched
version of Windows 10 that one
executable run across everything
that's a great question as that when I'm
asking questions short answer and so the
other cool thing is it is just a
PowerShell console so you do have access
to get help which like I said his parish
else kind of me and Paige equivalent any
command in PAS attack a native
PowerShell command or something that was
included by the offensive community will
support get a shop and kinda give you an
example of how to use it if you add the
parameters that except stuff like that
so it's kind of a democrat here and
hopefully it doesn't go well
so in this case we are on a high note we
found it does stop it was unmarked we
had fierce attack on a USB key we're
gonna go ahead and run it good for
everybody waitin back see what's going
on
ok so the first thing to do is see if I
can find some passwords on the network
so I can do here is just throwing get
attack passwords and its gonna return a
list like I said everything that has
passwords are involved passwords lot of
that is he invades stuff which is going
to be able to use of hashes and stuff
like that where we're interested in
though is get upp password password if
you're not familiar so admins in a
Windows domain have the ability to set
passwords through Group Policy they
would do this to set leg local admin
account so you can save passwords
through that or if you have a scheduled
task they want to run under specific
credentials you can use Group Policy to
define all of that Microsoft was for
thinking they were encrypted passwords
strain that get sent out to all the
computers they were then super helpful
and published the encryption strength to
Amnesty yet so
now when you try to do this in a modern
Windows Devaney usually get a prompt
that says hey this is a really bad idea
you shouldn't do this by legacy you when
its demands have a ton of this stuff so
it's it's a great little like kidney
punch to you know get a free password so
it's going to get GBP password so hit
the account name is robot have its
password and looks like this was set for
a scheduled task or something like that
in the network so the next thing I do is
get a little bit more information about
this robot account so I'm gonna do you
search for Active Directory stuff I
agree Active Directory so there is a lot
of recon stuff NPS attack and all that
is really provided by the power of you
module which was written by harm joy I
believe a lot of really grade just ways
to get a fake get figure out what's
going on in the environment are great
tools we're looking specifically for use
a related stuff so we have get a user
information for a given user in a demain
sounds like exactly what we're looking
for is going just you get help she has
ever known get new user before actually
haven't done this demo billion times so
get help
looks like exactly what we're expecting
every user name specified domain so
let's just go ahead and you get a user
per user name
so we get all the information from Ed
login account last time they had about
house where it looks like this is a
service account for stuff what's
interesting to us though is he's a
member of a group called local admin
which sounds really promising so what I
want to do is to find out more about
that group so let's do another search Q
see what we have as far as groups are
concerned
alright so we want to see it says local
admin let's look at local groups on the
computer see if that actually matches
the way we'd like it to get local group
looks good will do it helped so we
specify computer name is one to run
against a computer at school but looks
like we just have to specify like group
name and it should work out just fine so
local group
alright so this is everybody that's in
the local Administrators group on this
computer you have an administrator
account an admin account domain admins
and our local admin group so that robot
account should have local admin on this
box so let's go ahead and restart
pierced acronym run it as local admin
account though
local admin account looking at how it
was you know how that group is set up
I'm kinda suspecting that robot is gonna
have admin access to other boxes in the
network so let's do a search through get
attacked for local admin and see if we
have any sort of Rehan stuff that we can
do here have you mean like called find
local admin access this is going to see
if I machines on local demand that our
current box as local admin on
so it is running back with 16 gigs
around it's not gonna run more than two
boxes lab seven years to you and lets 71
where line 701 so it seemed as she was
in other parts of the network
the other thing I want to do is so we
know that we have admin access
throughout the network computer network
we want to find some domain admins those
who try to ask later privileges so we
can do I know that we have something for
finding admins and here so I can just do
a search for find and return everything
back this is my favorite command average
it's genius invoke user under way
invoke user hundred days is scans
through the network and finds any
computers that users in a specified
group are logged into so let's go ahead
and look at the help for this
this is a mess I don't want to go at
thats like thirty seven parameters so
when the great things about get help
is you have the examples so the examples
is like your TLDR of a man page so here
we have eight examples of how to use
this command the first one is exactly
what we're looking for if I machines on
global demand or domain admins are
logged into you and we can check if we
have local admin rights to it so it's
just go ahead and run that
so we have a domain admin as username is
admin 1 I'm not original and it looks
like we do have local admin rights on it
through this field right here so we're
gonna run democrats democrats is great
if you're not familiar with democrats so
many cats is like this with Army Knife
credentials and tokens in a Windows
environment you can do all sorts of
really interesting stuff like creating
your own tokens of being taken stuff
like that way most people use it for is
dumped in credentials Democrats will run
against a computer and dump the
credentials that be else as process has
in memory
windows after I think windows 8 don't
want it did change things so that only
hashes are stored in memory Microsoft
really helpfully provided a rich kid you
can rebirth that behavior said you have
a local admin rights on the box you can
join us
remarried a way for somebody to log back
in and get their point X crowds sense we
are mimicking a pretty standard
corporate environment here on Windows 7
is why upgrade and what's great about
Windows 7 is many cats works beautifully
on Windows seven other cool thing about
democrats is mentioned reflect a DLL
injection before so that comes into play
with democrats here
way in both democrats does he run it
against a remote computer and it injects
the democrats DOL straight into memory
on that remote computer so it never
touches debts like I mentioned AV is
really good about detecting democrats
this is a way that we can get around
that usage is pretty straightforward we
just need space back computer name and
don't crowds so let's go ahead and do
that
ok so we gotta get back and you can see
we ever have the actual like computer
account which is great we also have the
admin password think that's the first
time anybody's clapped for one of my
demos that's pretty cool right so we
remain friends I want to you know get
outta here so I like here here here here
so what I'm gonna do is dump the Active
Directory database so anti vs.net that
way I can copy it to a USB key you know
the developer may be coming back from
lunch or whatever soon here so it's good
and start up his attack and this time as
the domain admin that we just got credit
for
so here all right so we need to do is
find out what our controllers that's
where anti-assad its gonna get attacked
me and controllers and we have it for
again at the main controller I was just
in return to list the domain controllers
in the network sites we have won again
16 Big Mac and we get hits were all
sorts of information about EDC what is
no rules it has its IP address websites
and and its hostname mixing why do is
figure out what we're gonna do to copy
and TDS I did after this domain
controller so again and get attack and
copy there is a lot of tools for working
with volume shadow copies in the US
attack
shadow copies are really cool there a
great way to get around by logs or
access permissions stuff like that but
we actually with all this going to
handle all this for us to copy what he
does is really really awesome it
actually analyzes the hard drive volume
and then takes that and purses it back
into NTFS and re-creates the files that
way so does like this real real low
level copy desk and watched it back from
there again like not what you'd expect
from justice scripting language really
cool stuff so let's look at what the
plans are for a copy
and I'm lazy senators gonna skip
straight to the examples right so read
NCS from remote server invited to a
house on the local server so we need a
pass to what followed were looking for
Peter name or copying it from and our
local destination
2012 pretty scene we're just gonna go
into the folder that working out of here
this does take awhile because it is
doing such a low level access so it's
expected so we're gonna run well as
because I like that and we got our NCDs
study it
so i think is pretty awesome I think
it's super helpful tool I think you know
it is both useful for people new to
PowerShell people who already have
experience with it but it does have some
short so I think interest in evading an
antivirus just because it's it's an
interesting challenge and so while the
strings are encrypted in PAS attack it's
all the same strengths you know so
whoever downloads from the release page
stacked IKEA see you know you're going
to have the same strength as everybody
else
the other thing is the community is
super super active cities tools are
being improved all the time and he is
Jack naturally because it's a binary is
gonna have you know older tools then
what's currently available so created a
build tool for PSE TAC be built tool
makes it easy to build psh ACK which is
kind of funny because I'm gonna make you
compile stuff on Windows what it does is
it downloads the latest version of psh
ACK downloads the latest rules that it
depends on the crips them with the key
and encompasses everything together so
at the end of this you get a custom-made
console that is uniquely you told the
other day
unique signatures and it's super easy to
use
so this is an example running so we
started it downloads be as tagged
downloads all the tools you can pause it
and kicked out a custom copy of your
stack
things about the bill tool is the
dependencies are actually super regional
you need done at 325 to build psh ACK
and then you need it by hand up maybe
you actually run the build tool reason
you need a three-day visit goes
backwards compatibility and is atrocious
and so I just standardized on that it
makes things easier
you also need a JSON bow card modules
dodges and it's included with the zip
file to download from get her modules
judge a sign it is really just a list of
URLs for the doors they're gonna be
downloading and the cool thing about
doing it with the JSON is if you find
something that you think to see
recording you want in your copy of your
stack it is really really easy to add it
the other thing is you know it helps if
there is a bug introduced in house files
you can easily roll back so it makes it
really easy to make this your own
version of PSE TAC
stacks up on again so that's get out dot
com slash shirt heat or you can get it
from wwe.com along with whatever random
shit I have up on there for the
precompiled versions are available on
the releases tab for both schools and so
that means basically all you have to do
to run these tools is downloaded zip
unzip it and run them neither have a
setup process or anything like that it's
super easy to get involved or get
started so with Carolina commonly seen
version one-dot oh I've had some beta
since release candidates kindly do not
do this but this is the official a hey
it's not a burning pile of garbage
release
but in the future besides the obvious
like a bug fixes and you know can stand
up to date on modules there is there's a
couple things I am interested in
involving with his tax that's better AV
evasion there's console emulation stuff
that isn't quite spot on making it work
on but I'm really curious to see what be
community meets from this to like what
would make things easier for you guys
one of the things they don't want to
work on it is it is an interactive tool
so it doesn't play well with shells and
that's going to be a kind of focus you
know for development for you know the
foreseeable future until I can learn
that out but really comes down to you
you know what do you guys why you can
let me know please download this play
with it and some issues if something is
broken if something doesn't work quite
the way you think it should or if there
is a feature miss seen you know just let
me know I don't don't be afraid to
submit an issue you know and I can
expect you to Lake have a fix for it you
know I just want to get some people if
you don't want you to get home just
reach out to me on Twitter or through my
email I would be at the end but yeah if
you're if you're feeling froggy and why
it's important quest that would
definitely be appreciated this is my
first like Big C sharp project so it's
probably just a mess and I would deeply
appreciate more mature eyes on it let me
know all the ways I screwed up please be
kind
I definitely want to mention his attack
by itself actually isn't that advanced
of it or it's pretty straightforward
what makes it awesome is the PowerShot
unity so I mentioned earlier this hour
show click that you know kind of is
where all this cool stuff is happening
this is kind of the entry to that click
for you if you are slightly interested
in PowerShell an offensive PowerShell
these guys are doing all of the most
amazing work out there you know we've
got people from empire on their
manifestation runs Powershot mafia along
with a couple other guys which came his
way
Paris boy para trolls and emerged into
you
Kevin Robertson did in May and he's
doing a lot of really cool stuff he's
wise he's got an up-and-coming guy just
kind of like a period with a check this
out and is doing is really cool stuff
and an economy that you devious he if
you check out the shower shaving
framework which is why he's responsible
for is a lot of just really off the wall
Lake approaches to you back doors and
stuff like that so I just all really
cool people you follow me on Twitter I'm
incredibly grateful for their work so
there's my email address and my Twitter
handle
if you're in the Charlotte area me and
some friends we meet up monthly for what
we call Charlotte hackers and I'm it's
basically it's where we just talked
about you know read same stuff and then
drink beer and eat food afterwards so
it's called beta shot they made some
good friends were there aren't a lot of
stuff so happily take questions answered
with you as you would ask first question
wise
is it able to evade logging which was
introduced in our shop five so Microsoft
made a lot of changes with our show
version that are good for the end user
and bad if you are trying to develop
evil PowerShell tools so some of things
it does is logging is a billion times
better in power show to the point of Lee
there's too much logging now which is
probably a good thing the other thing it
does is through Windows Defender winners
defender entered into a new module that
sits in front of the Scripting Host
we're like all scripts are on the basic
PowerShell whatever its model basically
looks its roots right before they run
and is herman's hey is this malicious or
not so it gets passed encoding you know
you're past that stage the encryption
their peers attack does all that kind of
mood cuz it's right before it gets
executed its I've already seen the
PowerShot community of it just for that
so what are the things you'll notice
appear on the bill to as i mentioned lee
download some stuff and he might not
like it you know go and disable it
Windows Defender will catch like three
of the scripts that he s attack use its
surprisingly enough democrats is no
longer one of this so they've obviously
made some changes recently that kind of
a pain that and I expect we'll see that
more as time goes on my take on it is
dads right now Windows Defender is the
only anniversary I'm aware of that is
using that model it is open other AV's
can use it but we are pleased to have a
little bit of a window here before AV
started using it you know especially in
corporate enterprises running like a
Symantec Enterprise 11 or something like
that
like you're probably still have a real
good range of success using psh ACK
and an actual environment and the same
goes back to that log in as well
Parish LA introducing a lot of cool
stuff but the windows admins are
catching up you know they're they're as
unaware of PowerShell as like the
secretary is maybe more so honestly so
it still is it still right through the
harvest things are changing so any other
questions
yet they were there is a great idea and
if you would like to submit an issue
that I would really appreciate that
sorry the question why is there a way to
run vs attack without letting it touch
disc and right now just because nature
it is an interactive console it is kind
of how was built but that is kinda
focused you know going forward is how
can I make this work over River shells
how can I make this work without
touching desk so it's coming i hope i
think im so forgot to mention that so
our show has an execution policy so when
you try to import a script that's from
the Internet by the father is going to
say hey this is from the internet it's
probably bad run it and I won't let you
run it so you can change that execution
policy but you were fired by the way
most people change it you need to be an
admin on the box to update it when I
found out in developing vs attack is the
set execution policy command has options
those options are dash current user or a
used ESCO and then you can specify
current user which you don't need admin
rights for his attaches the HKC you reg
key or gosh process we're just for this
process it's going good disabled
execution policy MPs attack starts up
the very first thing it does is just
Sables execution policy for its process
that's very true so another way you can
get around the execution policy is just
basically instead of calling me strip as
he filed you can either just copy and
paste the contents of this crap street
into PowerShell or you can save it
selected text file invoke that text
files so the jeffries over the guy that
creative PowerShell has gone on record
of saying like what this was never
designed to be a security policy but you
know they wouldn't let me name it lay a
decision to fire him security policy so
we get what we get any other questions I
did write all this so it for five months
or so I mean there was a lot of work I
would say I probably put 80 to 100 hours
and it and that was coming out from not
really having any idea what do it seems
sure to this point I did PowerShell is
creating your own PowerShell console is
complicated and not well documented so I
ended up having seen a lot of other
projects to do that
bench and it has the past their crime
work which he created for instant
response teams and it's a custom
PowerShell console and so reference in
the previous talk how to copy and paste
code from Stack Overflow this was how to
copy and paste code from github so there
is i think i understand most of it does
but there is probably a couple lines
that it works
go any other questions
question is where was the hardest part
of writing us and we took the most time
versus time so the hardest part about
writing is actually be typing itself and
there may be an easier way to do this
but my original idea was to use
predefined so if you're not familiar
with scripting or in OC or whatever
reason I'm basically says like hey I'm
going to prompt the user for input and
they're gonna tape and once they hit
enter
I'm gonna take that and put it and use
it so this would be super easy because
you know kato get it dash attack you hit
enter i take that executed as Powershot
the problem was I couldn't figure out an
easy way to make that work with tap and
for me to completion was absolutely
essential for that's so what I ended up
doing is basically rewriting the entire
consult said that anytime you hit a key
I'm analyzing it and like making
decisions based off a bit so all of the
edge cases they're coming out of bed for
a while there are bills were like if you
hit left on the keyboard it just
depended in invisible left character to
be strange so I think I worked through
all that but yeah there is definitely
the hardest part of the easiest powered
was set on any of this was super easy
getting getting the color to blue I was
pretty easy any other questions
so I had to rate the auto-completion I
ended up writing the auto-completion
myself and so about after a node out of
completion is up there and also when the
hardest things about this after I put
like 15 20 hours in auto completion and
other custom Powershot project came out
so airs on ideas like great but it's all
good we can learn from each other I I
got over that quickly in their release
they had mentioned like oh yeah we're
just going to use this chab expansion I
did you are incomplete so it turns out
parasol actually automatically 3.net
will let you use its own tab completion
I'm going to stand by my custom
implementation because between
PowerShell version 2 and version 3 they
changed how it's how completion worked
so if I wanted this to work across all
versions of PowerShell I have to lay
detect what version of Skype completion
it was probably be easier but insulate
the existing tab completion as like it's
gonna work against everything so we'll
just leave it as any other questions yet
I have not because I don't have a
license for global trade so if you'd
like to donate that towards developing
that would be much grateful and I'll
tell me check that out any other
questions I was going to defend against
fierce attack what would I do so there
are and I wish I knew them off the top
man or have references for this if you
go through manifestations Twitter feed
he does he's done a lot of light posts
on here a WMI queries that will catch
like weird movement throughout your
network so stuff like reflective
learning DL else or impersonating tokens
and stuff you wouldn't expect from a
computer you know within your place from
your end users and so that's really I
don't know that there is anything you
can do necessarily I don't know what you
do to protect Pessac from running but at
least detecting it there is a lot of WMI
queries that you could use to do better
you really can't that I'm aware of
because it's part of dotnet so our show
is in just her shutout exe it's actually
like dotnet assemblies so i shud i txt
is doing a lot of the same stuff I am
just better because they're highly paid
developers and I did this my free time
but it's essentially the same thing
they're creating a PowerShell console
that safety net in the background
execute Powershot so I'm not aware of a
way to actually disabled friend that
works at a bank in Charlotte that he
says they've done this and I might do to
get around here stack let me know what
happens and so far I haven't heard back
so we'll see
yeah we would truly be if you want me to
get this running Windows XP let me give
you my card so we can range from God ok
greens any other questions
yeah there was $106 they are awesome
you're going to get go I guess well I
appreciate and