so this isn't a mere talk about using
John I think most people in this room
use it if you don't know how to use it
you know Google and there's tons of
articles out there lots a lot more than
I can tell you so what what what the
topic is going to be about is using the
tool and a corporate environment and
some of the joy that you get pushed back
to you might get from management and
users when you do something like that so
let's jump into it I guess I heard
you're pretty much everything in my
contacts down the bottom until next
Tuesday I'm part of that corporate
finance infrastructure taking a new job
after that so after a few beers I might
be a little bit more honest about some
of the details and corporate world there
are lawyers wanted me to say that so big
surprise I do have a mind of my own to
use it so I saw some of the reasons why
you would want to do this and I kind of
fell into this I wish I would have
planned it more
had a time but it's probably one of the
better ways to check and see how your
controls are working fine as you go
through some of this the first couple of
passes you'll find things that are
misconfigured servers that miss configs
for user habits and as you collect more
data that you may find in this is
something that's been a pet peeve of
mine because I have this love real well
a relationship with auditors and they
push it they pushed the check box and
say ok you're in and everybody I know by
saying this but your minimum password
length is usually a ESA has some
combination of complex characters
whether it be numbers uppercase whatever
that was around when I started and I'm
old
Thank You season and computers are
faster things have changed that it's too
short it's it's not it's not strong
enough anymore so I ended up finding
when I started running this was actual
proof and the heart thing with without
having the proof is if you go to another
and say look I feel that 82 shortly
wanna bump it there especially at like
an internal auditor or third party that
comes in and just doesn't add on your
company they're stuck to the rules
they're like this is best practice so we
gotta go if that's packed this gives you
some data to go back with him and and
argue that point and I think we're gonna
have to start pushing back on some of
these auditing rules because they're
making us less secure my opinion
so is a few challenges that you got a
workout out before you can even start
doing this the first one really has to
come up with a server initially I
thought while I want the GPU box and
deal somebody's declined mining machine
or whatever that in a corporate world is
is hard sometimes there are pushing BM's
it's hard to build one off boxes and a
lot of reasons so I started doing it
with a small machine with just a small
p.m. it's got no horsepower and doing
some simple rules and I was still
popping passwords so what I found later
on was that this was a benefit because
when I went to manage better when I went
to a user I said hey look if your
passwords week and I like that we can
fit the rules like I'm on a little
laptop here and I did it in a couple of
days if I had a really big box I would
do it a couple of minutes you know you
sent me to send me the drag races with a
piano and I so
only old people get that panels were
slow season and so anyways I thought it
was a benefit now as time goes on in if
you start doing more and more machines
especially if you're doing a lot of
boxes that small boxes is going to have
a hard time doing it but initially to
get you going to get that conversation
go on and get the political wheels
turning its get you going and so that
was one one thing that actually was was
a positive that I didn't think it was
and I see some of the other things that
turn more political as you get into this
is who gets to see the raw data who gets
to see the actual passwords obviously
you know some of the admins estoppel
wanna see it or they might be able to
change configuration settings to improve
things but you can't go put it on an
open file share for a home for everybody
to read either and dealing with
different teams like your Active
Directory jeans or Unix and Linux Data
Center dies they may or may not want to
give up access to that information to
begin with so there is some management
back and forth before you get before you
can start all of this
the other thing is to try and build
something disreputable the first couple
of rounds indicted on how I jumped into
a store run and uses a different
dictionaries doing some different
techniques and I get down like look at
all these past few really good shit I
forgot everything that I ran so over
time
scripted it up with with some basic
steps that have repeated over in time
and that makes consistent month-to-month
reports
and I started all of this on the UNIX
and Linux I'd mainly because of my
background and I already had access to
the shadow files and the data center so
I could I could begin doing it right
away and one thing I found in this comes
back to the configuration stuff I was
running across multiple hashing
algorithms so you have a single server
that would have or five different
hashing algorithms could be deposited
could be always up to 255 by 12 as much
as it supports near before five well
when you run John it can only do one of
the time so what ended up happening was
I found I found one account and only had
it crack down half a box as well the
user comes back to me and says you know
that's great but I think your your
script isn't working right because it's
the same password everywhere while 41
that's a bad practice but I went back
and looked and sure enough there was
three or four different I had to enter a
through three or four different times
with different hashing algorithms in
order to get all of that that makes your
process lot longer and the other thing
that happened to me that kind of a long
standing lined one of the audit or
something if we had had stressed that we
should push Shah 512 across the board
while we did that and then my runtime
started to really suffer because it's
got John's gonna work so much higher on
that has to go through all of the
combination and it kinda kicked me in
the leg and I didn't even know it was
common thing but it was a good thing at
least I saw that we made the change and
it was making impact so it's good it was
nice to see the change across from the
from a different perspective and
finally there's a lot of when you start
doing this is a lot of conversations I
have with management they don't
understand the tools they don't
understand
auditors updated a little bit so a lot
of communication has to go with your
upper levels i'm talking like your sea
level
exact type because they're seeing the
reports and you want to make sure they
understand it the other thing is as you
go out to the users say change it they
will push back sometimes and if you've
got that sea-level exact understanding
there really isn't much argument because
they come back and I'll have to show you
actually so again consider starting with
that that small crack and server I think
I think that helped a lot
dad is a low hanging fruit first it sees
it tell you if you got a problem when I
initially the first time that we ran a
tight one little story we had a internal
audit he comes in and he found a weak
password on one machine ended up being
the root password on a Linux box and it
was from the that somebody built and it
had to do follow the guide new root
password 12 p.m. is bill nobody ever
went manually changed it came to me says
you know I found this and so what we
gonna do to fix it and so we started
looking at it goes well how many other
times the day they miss it and we had a
thousand 1500 Linux boxes and I'm like
to check every one of the nice thing we
went check there's like two other ones
so the guys are doing their job he
missed a couple that I got lucky but
still that got the ball
the next when you're setting these up
and started to build these things I
would say that start with dictionaries
the ones on the web are fantastic in tho
get you a lot of hit make your own and
you can start small with it I started
with the John Lewis that comes with a
with the program and then just built on
an overtime because I do the
vulnerability assessments and I'm also
tied in with a pen testing internally I
had access to some of the pen test and
when they found a password or if I was
doing one and I found the password I
just sort of my dictionary and wouldn't
worry about it if it catches it catches
it if it doesn't it doesn't great and if
I am I looking at a machine or something
I find threads in a script I just throw
it in there I don't really worry about
chasing the guy down to tell me that fix
something I worried more that catch it
if that's really valid I'll catch
eventually in this process and that that
seemed to work out well some other
tricks that I picked up over time
use like addresses or river names of the
state that your company is in a where
they're working a lot of people use like
regional areas baseball teams football
teams sports teams that type of thing
but think that regional area that we're
the people are working from that works
well in a corporate world they love to
outsource so for example if if you're
out sourcing teams are all in India or
mexico or wherever it is go out and get
a dictionary for that language Spanish
put that in there just put it in there
just see what happens in may not get it
my and and that'll get you started and
once you have it set you have say he
cracked and passwords with that now you
can look at it and say ok now I start to
see some patents M-eighty they're
putting numbers at the end
humans if they're going to have to put a
capital letter and put it in the front
so so you can run your mass switches do
just upper and your your first character
then maybe do a couple of lower case
man maybe that put a number two numbers
right in the middle and then put the
rest will be all lower-case so you can
do the mask of that pattern only in that
only runs in about 18 hours on a small
box thing just run it and see what
happened try a different combinations
move those digits around there is some
different rule sets from CoreLogic has
won it runs a long time but if you run
it with a different rules that a
dictionary you'll get additional hit
they abandon prepend a time here
want different tricks but by then you'll
start to see more patterns as you keep
doing this over and over again and then
that's it really that is the process to
do that over to do that rinse and repeat
process and you'll end up with a with a
set of passwords and what we we did try
to do in this goes back to the have nots
small server we set a time limit to sell
I said like you gonna give me all the
eighty credentials and that was that was
political to get in first place but
contentious give me 10 days I'm gonna go
on my Pinto and I'm gonna see what I can
get
and then I just go through all of this
stuff and you only gave me ten days and
you only give me a little server I
should really get that much if you're if
your controls are in place and you know
if you come in I usually try to have a
goal like if I can get 30% of what I was
given and I feel like I did pretty good
and if I had a GPU box it would be
higher so that's what we did it's been
working out so far and the next the next
big trick is working with the users to
get things change
so there's a couple of different
messages are very popular for me and
like I said I crop probably fifty or
sixty of them that I was running through
over and over again and I had the luxury
of having two servers so I took some
longer masking selecting character links
and tried those and just let that run on
another server that ran for like a week
why I could merge in back in later why
like the top now there's one little
thing at the bottom because I'm season
and cause I like to get my kids a hard
time words with friends but I found a
good use for it there's tons of sites
out there with all the legal
three-letter words or words with friends
so he could do this with foreign matters
five whatever it so do a little loop
here where where it starts with a three
letter word and then the a is just any
character after that and just threw it
over and over again you can repeat that
for you could put your digits and around
that that was successful
the other thing I'll say to you when you
start doing this you'll learn a lot of
things about your music community
one final story it's fine to me I was
standing on this guy for weeks and weeks
to change his password cuz I kept track
and it finally in the password was fuck
you so I was like ok that's nice and so
he finally changes it and he pops up on
the report the next week and change that
the fuck you with a two at the end of it
so I almost wanted to let that go cuz it
was funny but whatever so that I could
drag you going to do more more drag here
idea
that's why I like my tractor alright so
the other thing and I'll say don't do
what I did and just go all the passwords
I got and give it to the CTO and leave I
i don't i don't know why I was like you
can use Excel you do it that didn't go
over so I went back to school and learn
communication and it doesn't have to be
really tricky but with something like
this we're gonna break it down to him
and this is nice and pretty but it's
kinda what you would expect since you're
doing all those masks rules with eight
you're gonna get the most inundate you
get you started ninth and tenth from
dictionary words and then those John
rules that are adding on to it as you
get higher and higher when you get
really high those are probably from you
know getting them from a shell script or
something like that and there there were
long and complex just happened to steal
it or you ran me the cats or whatever
whatever the case was and I'll tell you
this to people push back our delight
while you find that and you catch that
that would never happen so I'm not
change it like I found it I shouldnt
have so shut up
but anyways this this makes it really
easy for the sea levels when you come to
him you say look here it got there is no
the real date is not here but this is
kind of what we ended up with and like I
said this is kind of light that's
perfect it's easy to explain in real
life you'll end up with little blips so
you might have I don't know fifteen
character spike up or something like
that and they'll pick the spikes and
status and okay we've gotta act on all
of these and get them fix wise 15 so
high you know and I'll start asking
questions so had that in the back here
had before and it's really easy if you
have a spreadsheet all separated out you
know where your counselor what they are
you can take a look at them you know you
could have tons of different reasons why
why why every once in a while you'll
have a spike just know what your data is
before you go in front of the Seas think
there's any other tidbits
for
so well and I did start to use Pipal
what I found it though it was a little
bit overlooked for some of the exacts
they got caught up with all of the
different line items and they didn't
tell the story so this is the other
thing this story that I wanted to get
out of this was we've gotta get we gotta
get that link longer and here's why I
got so all I did was I took all of the
passwords and then I just wrote a shell
script it did work out and I put the
account right now so I two columns show
that into Excel and then just so there
you've got it all in there and then then
it's easy to go you know where my little
blips coming from all of that kind of
stuff that's all there really protective
of that spread she was only 45 people in
the company should have that but that's
it is really really easy as about it or
line shell script it's not so that's
about me see if I can figure out how to
get back to
so
now the now that you've embarrass people
what do you do and and this is this one
I still struggle with because I'm
getting a lot of pushback extending the
eighth nobody wants to do it they're
afraid of third parties coming in and if
your third party's all-powerful gonna
run the show me why i think its it
doesn't even start with a technical
changes user training and you can do
some pretty simple things you know
telling remember remember your favorite
song and pick out the first letters of
each one and don't put don't do patterns
and I was even thinking about running
through one of these in front of people
going here's how easy it is if you don't
put your capital in the first one
don't put exclamation points or special
characters at the end
change things up a little bit and I'm
not going to get it that way
not not through these massacres unless I
get really lucky and you've made it
harder for other people as well so I
really if a perfect world I would say
the minimum length about 20 and drop the
complexity rules all together and and
let it go at that and then do the user
training and then then it becomes really
difficult to do these kinds of tricks to
get very many passwords I just gonna
have a hard time even with a GPO box and
if it's after that may or may not work
politically and depending on your
corporate environment but if you do the
user training because he can improve it
that way
the nice thing we're doing this is you
can measure it now you can just
auditors in management love trending
chart so over time you've got numbers
and sell hey look we've made an
improvement or user training is working
or it's not the other thing that would
help have your Active Directory team
give you a little bit more information
about those hashing about those user IDs
what is issued to they belong in maybe
you have to focus your training in a
certain area or certain region or
whatever but you can use some of the
data that they have put it together and
and make some change out of this and I
think I mean I'm not this far I don't
know if these are good ideas are bad but
I think that is the least I could
measure it
so I don't know what the time as a head
but if you guys gonna literally you'll
hate me these are the two links that I
like lived and breathed when I started
all of this is the first one is from the
guys from CoreLogic they do the crack me
if you can stop in Vegas this PDF walks
through a lot of the masking techniques
plus some other neat little tricks that
I live that document I found it really
helpful and then if you want to expand
Aires school security he's got a time
and you can hold those you begin to play
11 other little bit if you've got if you
just wanna play with this crap at home
and you're just got on your laptop and I
know you're all on Linux make password
is a Unix commands are you can make your
own password hashes and make your own
dictionary make your own files to
practice with i mean obviously you're
making the password you know what's in
there but you can you can play with it
without having to steal somebody else's
I found helpful so it's probably really
early like to be some questions I hope
ya
because I'm seasoned I think that I have
to be honest I pick the tool that I was
most comfortable with long-term what I
thought was I was gonna end up with a
combination of both because I think it
has cat has its advantages in certain
areas and I was hoping to have that
monster GPU box and I would be run in
both in and use them for their
advantages
the other thing gt-r has so many
understand so many different algorithms
and my my long-term another long-term
hope was I'd love to do this on
databases I i know i would destroy them
for a while or you know some of the
other stuff that's out there
ATR's gonna be able to handle a lot of
it so I just kind of started there
now it's something I forgot to mention I
think a little bit I did in my political
jumps I got the houses from a D but they
didn't give me the user accounts and
they did it for a good reason that they
did they said well I can go and change
somebody's benefit information or
whatever and I didn't really need that
so I was just working off the house so I
depended more on my dictionaries and
well being local to the company so
and doesn't think I'm sorry
so the question is maybe I should go and
some of the other if we're going to the
the lengthy reduce the complexity of the
18th team and ask them to set some mass
I'm sorry I'm settings to complement
everything the other thing they just
made me think of two thought about even
extending the the time for changing the
password if we really did see an
improvement
highway 90 days is too short I mean in
in the nice thing with that is you could
go to the users say look I know I'm
making it really long time taken off
some of your other day and make it make
it a little bit more but I think the
user training is going to help that more
than anything else
ya koi mining box
I haven't had one but from what I've
read i guess im video from I was just
looking at pricing things that looks to
be about 54 and you could buy pretty
decent box at that point but like I said
I never even got to play with it with
the big our way
I'm sorry the the question was what do
you recommend in terms of hardware for
those larger boxes and I'm not there I
haven't been lucky enough to work on one
yet
with all the Bitcoin miner has been
going on there's there's another
information about building a box out
there and and he really anything is
going to be a lot better than that small
00 p.m. that I use so it's gonna be a
big improvement I guys I'm sorry if I
ran too short but I'm hungry