hello my name is Casey Smith and the
title of this talk is cyber cartography
how to model cyber terrain this is
recorded for b-sides Boulder 2022 for
the virtual track hope everybody's doing
well and thanks to the organizers for
giving us a chance to present virtually
not all of us could be there but hope to
to meet up with everybody soon
so you can connect with me on Twitter at
sub T thanks for watching uh and or
watching either at the event or later on
I appreciate it and this talk will be
some of it's speculative and really just
trying to drive curiosity and Innovation
so feedback welcome and I look forward
to hearing from you
really three big ideas that I wanted to
cover in this and they are first is our
models versus reality how how are how do
we use models how do they affect our
perceptions or experiences how do they
align with reality how do we update
models secondly uh the idea that defense
and offensive tools need the same
perspective and that makes things better
overall over time
third is combining things and learning
from other disciplines or other domains
so how can we draw from domains like
medicine uh you know meteorology and how
can that inform our cyber security
processes and models
and then lastly along the way some case
studies and references that may be
helpful for you if you like this
so these are some things I've been
working on over the last few months and
so I always like this far side cartoon
where these two spiders have this web
across the slide and they basically say
if we you know if we pull this off we'll
eat like kings so if I pull this off uh
it you will be at a minimum entertained
and hopefully find some useful content
so I want to start with a map so
some of you will recognize when you see
this map immediately where this is or
you may even be able to quickly
translate that to what it might look
like over the horizon if you were to to
be standing at a point on this map and
see it others of us it might take more
context or more perspective so
when you think about Maps we could look
at this and we can see things like
bodies of water uh various slopes or
steepness or grade of the terrain we
could see maybe communities and Roads so
but it may not be enough to help us form
a really clear picture of what this
would look like so we may need
additional context so how about now does
that help at all provide any context
some of you are thinking no not even a
little bit so
you know what about now sort of like if
you've gone to the eye doctor where they
changed the lintus which is clearer so
this is Mount Albert the tallest 14er in
the state of Colorado this is a
prospective uh sort of standing on the
road looking to the West uh just south
of Leadville
and the reason I bring this up is it's
important when we're describing a thing
that we use maps but maps are a
reduction or an abstraction and so the
map is not the territory excuse me and
it may take multiple perspectives to get
the ground truth so the first part of
this is really to drive that point home
how we use these models versus an
experience of a particular thing
another example I want to use is if I
were to present this music to you what
does this sound like what what do you
hear when you read this and I know that
may sound funny but some some people are
trained and can actually instantly pick
this out and hear this playing in their
mind others of us need to need to
actually hear the music and then we can
start to see the patterns in the notes
on the page so I'm going to try and get
this to play real quick and see if this
helps identify this
foreign
[Music]
okay hopefully that helps identify the
song as Thunderstruck the soundtrack for
hacking of course that's debatable but
according to at least one news article
that's fact so anyway the idea though is
some of us can look at that and and see
that I can't but some people can look at
that and and hear that song all those of
us need to hear the song and then we
could recognize the patterns uh in the
model or in the sheet music so music can
be transferred across time and location
by writing it down uh and then I someone
can put that on on a instrument and
begin playing that by reading the music
other of us have to hear it others of us
experience it so again the sheet music
is not the song
the menu is not the meal right so models
are always an abstraction of reality so
they help us describe things talk about
things but it is very different than the
experience itself
one of my favorite examples of this is
from the movie Titanic where early on in
the movie there's a uh one of the
analysts is describing using the model
and simulation how the Titanic broke
apart so he's describing what happens
and uh and then the ship splits and and
sinks and you know and then at the end
he says pretty cool huh he's talking to
Rose of course who was on the Titanic
when it sank and she sees it responds uh
thank you for that fine forensic
analysis Mr Bodine of course the
experience was somewhat different so for
those people who have been through an
incident who have had their organization
attacked or have worked on incident
response they read threat reports very
differently than those of us who may not
have experienced that same situation
there's a lot of things happening that
aren't captured or cataloged right how
were emotions for the team what were
tensions like what was communication
like those aren't always captured and
don't come out as opposed to those of us
who read those Sports and they're like
oh they dropped the sign driver an
elevated privilege is pretty cool right
maybe but if you experienced it and it
affected an outage in your organization
may not be so just remember the model or
map of a threat report there are people
and organizations impacted by that
actual report
so when we look at models from miter
like attack and defend these are a great
way like music to in my opinion to
communicate a taxonomy communicate
things across time so it helps us look
at something and say okay they did a
scheduled task or they did this
particular technique but again think I
think of these as recipes right these
are not the meal these are these are
a way of describing something but there
could be things we learn as we draw
closer to the reality and the whole
situation much like the Mountaintop we
can be looking at a map it's different
than standing at the base and looking at
the actual event
so if you're not familiar with defend
minor defend is a relative newcomer to
matrices or taxonomies for various
attack patterns and defending against
those some of these we would recognize
very quickly like say multi-factor
authentication others of us would be
terrified trying to inventory system
firmware on all these devices and trying
to understand how to defend that but the
idea is it gives us at least a place
where we can work from a measure of the
terrain and know how we can improve so
these are really great hopefully you
don't hear that I I don't like these I'm
just trying to share how I think about
these models sometimes
another very popular model is minor
attack and there's a matrix for various
Cloud mobile these are really good at
describing across the top these are the
goals of the adversary so the adversary
wants to achieve persistence at the top
and how they would do that might be by
going up the stack or using one of the
items in that column to achieve that
particular
tactic so inside of each of these these
are very helpful but again they don't
necessarily describe the way we
understand them when someone's
describing supply chain compromise
I might think about that differently
than you do and so also keep in mind
this is very much like the model we have
for Sheet Music some people can look at
this and just play that attack out in
their mind other of us other others of
us need more context to understand what
happened and to draw a new insight and
observation to what happened
so you might have a situation where on
the left you see these are these are the
directions the attackers went on the
right The Blue Team scrambling or
incident response teams scrambling there
may have been a few points where those
intersected over time where we may have
been able to disrupt or prevent or block
Downstream Effects by the attacker but
overall sometimes they're not things
aren't as neat and they don't resolve
into boxes uh as easily so keep that in
mind as we go through this talk
so you'll see various models presented
for an intrusion
that are well organized and cyclical and
you know attackers don't do uh internal
Recon unless they've done initial Recon
for example so
um that is one way to think about it
another way might be there are a lot of
entry points there's a lot of messiness
to corporate and small business networks
and there's a lot of places attackers
could start and move what's important
though is we have a an understanding or
language this is actually from Matthew
Monty's book network attack and defense
is a very good resource if you haven't
read it I'd highly encourage you to take
a look but a real operation may look
very different from a defender or even
from an attacker's perspective
it's never as clean and easy as a simple
spreadsheet
so that's part one uh really talking
about how we think about models and how
they affect reality you know the map is
not the territory there's a clear
distinction between the two the next
section I want to talk a little bit
about is how offense and defensive tools
need to share the same view and once
that happens both attackers and
Defenders can start drawing the same
conclusions or observations about what's
happening and so if either side has
uh an information asymmetry here that
may help them right they may have a tool
to see something that the Defenders
simply don't or they may be aware of a
blind spot in a tool that a Defender is
not aware of
so I use this example I'll call it
cyberball it's essentially a soccer
field on the left a basketball court on
the right and over on the left-hand side
these are Defender rules there's a lot
of meetings there's a lot of can't pick
up the ball with your hands uh there's
different you know a goalie that's
guarding the the net
but over on the right an attacker has
really is none of these same constraints
they could pick up the ball by their
hands they could throw it around they
could kick it they can uh they're trying
to achieve a different objective than
what's happening on the left side
not a great analogy but this is
sometimes how I think about I see a lot
of attackers playing one game Defenders
playing another game attackers playing
the game of trying to achieve an
objective or hit a Target Defenders
trying to do log searches analytics and
and uh they don't always line up and so
it's almost like there's two different
planes so hopefully bringing these two
into alignment maybe at least is a
theory I have that might help
organizations Better understand and
model attacks and defense
so when we think about an event what
would an analyst need to see before an
event during an incident or after that
could help them understand it better
can we use that information to replay to
learn from for example why did it take
us five hours to get the logs maybe next
time it takes us an hour and a half next
time it takes us 30 minutes
is there a way to pause or look at our
Telemetry rewind even train people on
that so pause and analyst and ask you
know hey what would you do in this
situation uh give them a chance to think
about it and and play it out and see
what happens so that's where I think
models can help us ask these what-ifs
run through these scenarios help people
train
but we think differently about a map
when we're traveling than we do when
we're lost than when we're just sitting
at home uh and so different maps have
different utility or models have
different utility given the
circumstances or the event that you're
facing
as a Defender I want the same map that
the attacker has I want to know what
they're looking at and try and outpace
them or uh make decisions before they
make decisions on the same information
and cut off the attack so I might see
well it's pretty obvious they're going
to go after that bridge so we may want
to defend that area more heavily or
whatever we're talking about but I want
to hear the music I don't want to read
the music I want to have the experience
essentially that the attacker is having
and looking at the network from that
perspective to help inform where I need
to defend so what can they see what can
they touch or access those are the views
that I want so some of you have used
Cobalt strike before very popular red
team adversary emulation tool very
popular with actual adversaries as well
and this is just a screenshot from their
SMB lateral movement and you can see how
an attacker could track which systems
they've compromised you can see what the
Privileges like are they system are they
uh just a normal user
you can also track in the tool
credentials that you've collected over
time and from what source so this might
be how an adversary sees an engagement
and moves through a network and that may
be very different than the way a
Defender might see that same information
uh Raphael has a really good talk called
Flying a Cylon Raider encourage you to
check that out if you're interested
because he describes that sense of how
do I take an attacker's perspective how
do I look at an attacker's Tool uh and
use that to help inform defense so
really good stuff
one of the tools that I like that I
think it represents this really well is
a tool called Bloodhound and I think it
shows
very clearly the benefits of attackers
and Defenders having the same view
same information of a network and so
Bloodhound if you're not familiar with
the tool is a tool that allows you to
model active directory structures to
then find attack paths so maybe you're a
normal user and you want to elevate to
domain admin or maybe you have rights to
this group but you want to elevate to
another group it does it does quite a
bit more obviously so I put some
references here about how this tool has
really changed our industry in terms of
seeing active directory
and really a big shout out to Andy and
the team that's doing this work because
I think
The attacker's View and the defender's
view with Bloodhound is the same so the
idea is we're looking at the same data
and so we can draw conclusions about
what we need to defend and how we can
improve so if I can run Bloodhound as a
Defender before uh an adversary does I
may be able to quickly cut off places
where they could Elevate privileges
weaknesses we might have in our active
directory structure so
or configuration so so that to me that's
an example of offense and defense having
the same view and everyone getting
better over time so another tool might
be something like nmap to do Port
scanning or some some derivative of nmap
we're both using the same things to scan
for open Services try and fingerprint
targets that is helpful to both
attackers and Defenders so trying to
find those places where the tooling
provides the same visibility to both
sides and we're starting to see this
more I really like the team at Microsoft
that's doing some of these
visualizations so here you can see an
attack from ransomware and you can
actually start to see the flow of the
attack mapped to various techniques on
the right
but you begin to be able to understand
okay uh you know credentials cannot be
dumped until security controls are
turned off or until they elevate
privileges so we start to see the
ability to affect Downstream Behavior by
understanding the attack Flow versus
just a spreadsheet or a chart so now
we're starting to look for Trails uh on
the map as opposed to just looking at
the map together
another blog from Microsoft is showing a
similar thing now that all of a sudden
looks a lot closer to the Cobalt strike
view of the network
and we could start to think about oh
okay you know if the defender uh if they
hadn't been able to reach uh node two
then they wouldn't have nothing would
have happened after that so okay lesson
learned how do we iterate and improve so
that I think has been very valuable
for attackers and to finish that the
same view
and so there's some examples of this
that you can use to experiment there's
neo4j which is a lot of the Bloodhound
development
excuse me uh there's D3 for JavaScript
I'd encourage you to experiment and try
some of the different visualizations to
see what is surfaced or what
uh might make sense
there's quite a bit of templates and
models that you can use to see what
would happen and ask questions change
the state ask the question again you
know if we if we made this configuration
change how would that have affected this
incident you know maybe the whole thing
was uh you know predicated on one thing
being true and if that was taken away uh
everything would have collapsed and
that's how we can get better over time
by using these types of models to
understand that at least that's my
theory
so what kind of maps do we have what
kind of visualizations do we have in
other domains in other disciplines
you know how can we learn from those
other disciplines
what are the things that I think is
interesting that other disciplines do is
look at data across time so you
functionally have how could we model a
network or a device state or
configuration
over time and go back in time and look
at State roll forward in time and see
how changes play out
so if you think about meteorology or
weather models and data you can see
the value of these models is predictive
right so I want to know what's going to
happen on Friday so that I can make
plans today and so looking at various
trajectories inputs and knowing where
models work and where they feel so some
of you may be familiar with you know the
concept of long-term weather prediction
it's not possible I can't tell you what
the weather will be like
10 years from now but I can tell you
what it will be like 10 hours from now
so understanding the value of these
models and constantly changing inputs
and seeing how that affects different
things don't I don't have an answer of
what like a weather map would look like
in terms of of cyber security but that's
what I'm thinking about in terms of
visualizations collecting some of this
data and then looking at uh maybe what
it's telling us is going to happen or
could possibly happen in the future
but so a great example of where we do
actually use time and looking at data
across time is time travel debugging
this is my first experience of this was
from a talk by Brett Victor called
inventing on principle in 2011 and so he
was giving this presentation and he was
talking about how he was trying to get
his character to make a particular jump
and rather than trying to pick the
numbers he has a sliding bar but that
was still hard to see so what he did is
sort of turn on these Trails for the
the character
and he could actually by dragging the
trails up or down play out a different
future for the character until he got
the exact amount and so this has been
incorporated into a number of commercial
products I'll show you in a moment windy
bug a t train have both tools that use
time travel debugging and these These
are game changers for analysis because
you can change input you can you can
play out and exploit and roll something
back change the state play it forward
again and see the effect and that is
really remarkable so as we look at
weather and how weather patterns can
change over time we can look at the
state of things even within a system
even within a debugger and see how that
would play out over time so
when you think about reverse engineering
and debugging you know a developer a
reverse engineer they're trying to look
at the same data they're trying to see
the same things they use the same tools
so an exploit developer can use a windy
bug or other tools guidra Ida just like
a software developer could as well so
you can see here's an example from
windybug moving forward going back in
time and I think the real value is
seeing something play out back it up
change the state play it again and see
if it has a different outcome see if it
actually made a difference so
I like this slide a lot this is from
t-train's uh website and they do time
travel debugging and low-level analysis
for like kernel drivers and things like
that but you'll see here they can track
reads and writes of locations to memory
over time you can create bookmarks or uh
snapshots you can then Trace those to a
point in time where a write operation
corrupted something that caused a crash
and Trace that back over time and see
where it came from see that it actually
came from uh the ethernet interface so
these are things we haven't had so these
are new so new models new maps new tools
are going to give us new insight into
how to defend and also how to attack so
I like their stuff I think it's pretty
neat
another example that I've used is API
spy and if you've ever looked at a you
know you're in a debugger and you see a
create file
call and you're not sure what the
function parameters are so your context
switching between the msdn page and then
you know what are the inputs here what
does that structure look like I like API
spy because I can simply hover over that
function call and it will show me right
away oh okay I can see that first
parameter is a pointer to a string or
whatever it might be so that gives us a
lot quicker Insight a develop an
intuition for maybe what's happening as
we're troubleshooting something so some
of the best tools for troubleshooting
and debugging can be really helpful for
informing what we know about security
incidents and situations
how we see things then this is sort of
my point helps us make predictive and
analytical and strategic decisions so if
an attacker is seeing something that I
don't see they may make a different
decision than I might make and so while
there's always that element of human
adaptation and Innovation
um we want to be more informed than the
adversary we want to know things that
they may try we may want to anticipate
or disrupt their attack early in the
chain and we can't do that if we're
looking at a map of Paris you know
trying to defend Texas okay so uh
what we can we can predict where things
are going our models can inform us uh
you know what questions we need to ask
Etc
so one of my favorite tools uh for web
application testing some of you are
familiar with this would be is burp
suite and I love the burp Suite
interface the the plugins the whole
thing it's just very elegant and it
allows me to then see the request and
the response parse the headers look at
different parameters we play attacks
uh fuzz or inject things at a particular
point in time
very very powerful offensive Tool uh to
to go look at and start testing web
applications there are other web proxies
that inspect data like Fiddler uh o wasp
zap proxy uh Charles proxy uh mitm and
in Python
but this is an example of seeing the
data and then that informs our defense
so by running scans and running attacks
you know we might see that oh for this
particular method call if I just count
the Response Code so Response Code 500
means the application couldn't handle it
and something crashed in either the gvm
or the the web server so those are
important and we can see an asymmetry
here between you know get requests
causing a 500 or a crash versus get
request causing a 200 and we may want to
look into that so I guess my point being
here is I would really like my wife to
look more like burp Suite right so if
those are two different tools or
whatever you're using to defend your
website the closer uh the view of you
know can come to looking more like an
offensive security tool I think we're
going to see dramatic improvements and
insights we're already starting to see
that people using application monitoring
data to help inform their defenses so we
could look at got a parameter
over time and say like it's only ever a
date if it's something other than a date
whether it's a semicolon or a apostrophe
just kill the connection because I know
that field should have always parse or
why you know why is it a date 99 of the
time and now all of a sudden it's
adjacent objects or yaml so that tells
me something's happening there either a
misconfiguration or somebody is sending
those events so anyway hopefully that
make you make it gets the point across
like as a defender of web applications
one of the advantages you have is all
testing and all attacks are for the most
part visible if you're have the right
verbosity and logs turned on so you get
to see all the failed attempts before
the attacker actually may succeed not
often but uh sometimes so
another
um example for you just I'll just leave
this up here for you uh to reference
this is a visualization tool using kitra
and it allows this situation the
analysts to really just scan through the
data
and all of a sudden some things start to
to pop out uh as or that maybe that's an
image maybe maybe that's another type of
structure that's just a text string but
then we're leveraging the power of the
you know human brain to see the patterns
here
while the computer can then surface the
data so sort of combining the two
strengths of both the computer analytics
and the human pattern recognition to
find something in a file that we may not
that may have been difficult to to find
otherwise
and if you like adversarial thinking or
red teaming
you can use this same approach as well
you can think about well what does a
Defender see what would they actually
observe and I like this painting called
Another World from MC Escher which shows
three different perspectives the same
frame but it actually takes your brain a
little bit of time if you pause the
video and try and figure out am I
looking I'm looking up but I am am I on
the left or am I on the right and I'm
looking down and am I on the right or
the left and so
those kind of contexts which is slow us
down can slow us down and so how can we
accelerate that but you might think
about as an adversary uh emulation team
or red team like what would a Defender
see here and how could I
either try and camouflage my activity or
how could I you know try and blend in
so when we talk about other domains
disciplines so what what can meteorology
teach us about you know cyber security
what can an astronomer teach us about
cyber security so you think about that
for just a moment some of you will
recognize where I'm going with that the
idea was from the book cuckoo's egg
where Cliff Stole was a astronomer that
was called in to respond or essentially
ended up responding to a pretty major
cyber event in the late 80s it's really
good read lots of good history a lot of
good approach and techniques there but
we can learn a lot from other domains
whether it's meteorology astronomy or
excuse me medical Aviation Public Safety
all those a lot of these problems people
have solved that we may not be aware of
and there may be techniques we could use
and apply to cyber security in the
models we use in the database service
so another reference is Carmen Medina's
talk uh keynote that she did about
diversity of thought and inclusion and
different perspectives on solving
problems and she mentions one of the
astronomers here Cecilia who
by looking at things like photographs
from telescopes was able to infer makeup
of stars and it's really fascinating
look not only at the science but also
just uh you know what she had to
overcome to
to understand and and reach those
conclusions so the way the way we look
at things and understand data may give
us new insights so in this particular
part of the talk Karma was talking about
the benefits of combining
telescopes and photography because up to
that point it was just somebody's
you know uh someone's word that they saw
this thing at a particular time but with
a photograph or a recording they were
able to then other people could study it
and draw other conclusions
so how does that help us with models and
cyber terrain well we may if we think
about telescopes and photography you
know what do we need to combine uh with
cyber so I you know I don't know this is
just an open question but like you know
what how could you combine cyber
security with Zillow or something you
know or or how could you combine it with
a recipe site or drone perspectives or
whatever you bring to the industry and
your perspective may be really valuable
for us because we may be missing
something but things that might help us
think about this be like what takes a
lot of time today what's expensive today
what's tedious or error prone today how
do we reduce that improve that improve
the quality those types of things we may
draw from other domains so
some of you may have heard of the ooda
loop and some of you may roll your eyes
and stay with me but the idea of the
ooda loop here is
observe Orient decide and act and so
this originated in the Air Force pilots
looking at how to become better pilots
and how to win uh in dogfights and how
to gain an advantage over adversaries
and and some theories are a lot of it's
related to like the canopy or the bubble
Pilots had a different view than their
opponents and so this old movie from uh
with Clint Eastwood the original Firefox
if you remember you know he has to steal
this plane and in order to do that he
has to think in Russian uh so pretty
cool you know original Firefox before
the browser but the idea here is
UDA is probably best experienced and
taught it's sort of like trying to
describe to you how to play the piano
versus letting you play the piano and
see what that's like and then you'll
begin to to build repetition so let me
try and
explain that how I think about UDA and
how I think about faster Loops so going
faster from observe to act
is how I interpret that and and that
improves that our Speed and Agility as
Defender so one problem that you might
have is imagine you're a large
organization and you identify in your
proxy server logs a malicious domain was
detected somebody tried to browse to a
malicious domain so now you have a lot
of questions and how fast you answer
those questions May inform the scale and
size and duration of the incident so
once you understand there's a malicious
domain in your logs you have to ask how
did it get there which hosts performed
the lookup
you know was it just a lookup of a DNS
name or did someone actually send an
HTTP request to that domain and if if it
was a lookup who performed the lookup a
proxy server or a domain controller
um there's a lot of questions right and
so then we may want to go back and say
all right now that I know that it was
computer a what was the process name on
computer a that performed the lookup was
it a browser was it maybe just a you
know someone typed something in wrong
was it an injected ad or was it SVC host
what's the user agent if it's an HTTP
request there's a lot of things here
just by seeing a malicious domain in
your proxy logs you have to go answer
and then once you've answered one and
two
you now have to sweep the organization
and answer that for all of your hosts
has anyone else talked to this domain
has any other process talked to this
domain and then you repeat that cycle
and so that's the loop right that's the
observed act and so by doing that in 12
seconds versus 12 hours how quickly can
you reboot eradicate clean up machines
versus something that may have persisted
in your network for a very long time so
by increasing the speed that our
questions are answered we can influence
our ability to defend the organization
so that's how I interpret uh some of the
UDA models and things like that I see
value in it but I see value in it in
terms of
doing it instead of just trying to
describe it so
but
by understanding how quickly you can
answer questions that
makes you faster right so if I can pick
up an enemy uh aircraft 12 miles before
they see me that may change you know
right that all of a sudden you start
thinking of where this comes from that
may change how we react so the speed
with which you ask and answer questions
may affect outcomes of incidents both at
attacker or Defender and asking and
answering faster than an adversary may
be something that you'll strive for how
quickly could we answer that question
what tool do we need what do we need to
turn on in our logging to be able to do
that faster so
so that's Buddha if I think about
observe Orient decide and act it's a lot
easier to do it but also if you break it
down then you can ask how could we do
this faster
so what's an example of this maybe
that's where EDR uh could help you right
so you have a tool that now tracks every
computer every process and every domain
they've talked to and now you can answer
the question in 12 seconds versus 12
hours versus 12 days
so that's where I'm going with these
tools can and models can help us improve
our defense overall
back to earlier when we were talking
about drawing on other disciplines so if
we think about like telescopes and
photography being combined what could we
combine EDR with so EDR by itself could
actually maybe be a force multiplier if
we combined it with something else so
what about fraud analytics and this is
just pure speculation but you could say
like you know how when I buy a credit
card you know buy something and it's not
me the bank calls me or sends me a text
and I say nope that wasn't me what if
that was possible with EDR so what if
you know your EDR system detected wmi
spawning a command prompt and the user
got a push notification hey are you
running command no
how quickly could you then react or
respond check with the user give them a
call so the the data then can be uh
inform us and that model that helps us
get really quick so we can deny the
transaction in a few seconds or we can
recognize this holiday season and yes
that person's buying a TV or it's the
end of cycle maintenance and yes they're
running wmi and we get better over time
but just simply asking a question might
be a way to improve the process so
hopefully that makes sense so just just
combining ideas like that like how could
we you know use a fraud notification in
the financial industry and combine that
with endpoint telemetry I don't know
another thing you might do is enrich the
context or the data that you're
presenting so if you look at a other
graphs you might just see nodes but here
an analyst can actually see a keyed map
and they can actually see
the data oh all right that's a file
right that's a file modification that's
a process spawning a network connection
so by seeing the relationships and
quickly understanding that may help an
analyst pivot to another tool that shows
them oh I need to go look for any exe
file in the app data local temp file or
with the name temp in it or maybe I need
to go look for any executable that has a
single letter so like show me every
executable that has like e dot exe
almost always evil so that is from JP
cert they have a tool called syspon
search that kind of enriches the view so
trying to draw from different
visualizations we've looked at
Bloodhound active directory we've looked
at debuggers we've looked at burp Suite
looking at endpoint data so hopefully
this is connecting with maybe some of
you different visualizations of giving
you ideas
about how these maps and models improve
our understanding
I like this one uh from Edward Tufts he
has a class I'll reference at the end
about data visualization and modeling
and so what we want to teach folks or
what I what I think we
want to teach people is how to react and
adapt to situations and use the tools
that they have so if the thing I like
about this is here here I am looking at
the dishwasher Matrix and I if I have a
number five tablespoon in my hand I
don't know where it goes there's nothing
on this it tells me so what do I do with
this tablespoon that doesn't fit the the
grid and so
that can help us
you know how we're using the tools so I
much more want as a senior or principal
and training new analysts I want them to
be able to adapt and react much more
like
um maybe a surgeon does
where we're training them you know
C1 teach one do one so to speak where
they're getting the Hands-On practice
maybe guided or in a controlled
environment but it's not enough just to
give someone a matrix and just say go
hunt it's just like giving somebody uh
an anatomy chart and saying go do heart
surgery so there's got to be a way to
train people there's got to be a way to
use these models to help people learn
over time one of the books I like is by
Dr Atul gawande who wrote a book called
complications that he actually wrote
while he was a Surgical Intern that
talks about this it talks about the
challenges but we need to teach people
to to do the work and be able to adapt
and provide feedback if the tool is not
working that needs to be something that
they can provide to us so again trying
to draw from a domain like medical
training or surgical training how might
that inform how we train security
analysts we don't just turn them loose
there's more of an apprenticeship and
working together to both learn because
the senior or principal or role can
learn from someone with new perspective
they could be like why it takes you like
seven steps to copy the you know event
log domain into the Sim why don't you
just do this so it's mutually beneficial
so
uh or building muscle memory so if you
remember in the Karate Kid towards the
end early in the movie rather uh Daniel
has been doing all these this work he's
been sanding floors waxing cars painting
fences he doesn't really understand why
he's doing these various things until Mr
Miyagi starts doing punches and kicks at
him and he realizes he's learned by wax
on wax off he's developed muscle memory
to respond and react to these things so
we work on the models we study and
understand but ultimately it's the
experience of the thing that is going to
be how we use these and how they help
make us better and improve our
understanding so
okay so some closing thoughts uh our
tools our Maps our models they matter
we've covered a lot of ground we've
talked about how the map is not the
territory we talked about combining
tools so offense and defense have the
same view we talked about different
Industries at different parts of cyber
security where that's true things like
debuggers time travel debugging uh web
application attack tools Bloodhound Etc
I want to close with this and I think
this is an important concept is that you
get what you measure is a quote from
Richard Hamming and essentially he tells
the story where the fishermen go out and
they catch fish in the Nets and every
they conclude that there are no fish
smaller than a particular size because
they've never seen them in the net and
so the takeaway here is the instrument
affects what you see
the size of your net is going to affect
the size of the fish you can catch
um seems obvious sometimes we forget it
hopefully that's a good reminder and
another quote I like from Carmen Medina
is our ability to know as a function of
our tools for knowing so our ability to
combine telescopes and photography is
going to improve our understanding over
time our ability to take cyber security
tools and models and map them over time
helps us see things so
okay we covered a lot of ground thank
you for uh bearing with me through that
hopefully this was informative there's
some references for minor attack and
defend uh one of the plugins in miter
calderas game board which is trying to
do something very similar to what we
describe where offense and defense have
the same picture and a lot of my
thinking and ideas that around these
visualization came from a class that I
took uh Edward Tufts course on
visualization is outstanding if you want
to take it it's super fun and hopefully
we'll we'll bring new ideas so looking
forward to those of you who are new to
the industry and those of you who are
seasoned veterans how what we can do to
learn from each other and draw from
various domains so thank you for your
time and I look forward to seeing you
all in person and hopefully you'll have
a good rest of the event