rights
our next speaker is Quran duvetti Quran
is a manager or technical lead and the
security team at Google and his talk is
titled clean forensics analyzing Network
traffic of vacuum Bots
please give me a warm welcome
[Applause]
thank you love the energy here it's
still like 3 30 p.m and I was like I'm
the last talk so I need to make it
interesting
um thanks everybody especially uh the
organizers uh Matt uh Punk quarter
everybody thanks for having me here and
lovely audience all right so I'm gonna
talk uh today about vacuum Bots before I
actually you know dive into the
technical content show of hands how many
of you have a vacuum board or want to
purchase one or if curious about them oh
quite a few hands all right how many of
you think they are secure
no hands
all right I like the crowd
so a little bit introvert me uh I'm
Karan you can call me k
um I'm a security manager at Google
uh I'm an infosec alumni from Carnegie
Mellon I spent two wonderful years there
um for fun I write blogs at all
thingspawn.com I mostly write about
security engineering interviews try to
help people land jobs
I also spend time reviewing Journal
papers so some of the research stuff and
it's very exciting to see what's
happening in the field
and for fun I love to travel I'm here I
just flew in last night and I loved
going to the beach so
with that
let's look at some of the things we'll
discuss today right so we want to get
started with why vacuum Bots like why
are we even talking about that right we
talk about iot a lot which is
understandable but why specifically
vacuum watch
with that understanding we'll go into
some of the functionality right how do
they work what features do they have
and you know some of the missing things
that are not so popular
then we'll dive into the interesting
parts right we'll talk about how every
one of you in this room can conduct
Network forensics on your own right it's
not rocket science it's very very
interesting
and then the most interesting part I
would say
um or maybe not uh mostly secured in
privacy issues that I discovered in some
of the Bots
and then for fun I'll also show you the
reported issues so I actually talked to
one of the vendors no names will be
taken in this room I know this is being
recorded and will remain on the internet
for a while so but I'll show you the
communication and I'll show you the
challenges of when you report issues
what really happens right and then I'll
give you time for Q a
if I see the audience engaged I'll end
early I promise
all right so with that and obviously uh
the typical disclaimer this is my own
research Google has nothing to do with
this right so you can blame me
all right
so let's talk about why research vacuum
bonds
and I think if I just leave this slide
and just let it be it speaks volumes but
I'll still speak
um so if you see this trend this data is
taken from grandviewresource.com
um some credits to them
they have shown that over a period of
time since 2016 at least on the slide we
see an uptick in the number of bots
being sold right year over year it is
projected to grow by 23 percent
every year
by 2027 the numbers is expected to be
60.9 million units these are Bots
running everywhere it's like an army of
parts
some of the major players uh let's look
at the market right let's see who was
actually capturing this market so I've
listed on some names on the left so
you'll see uh these manufacturers but
it's not really Consolidated right no
single manufacturer is dominating the
market but also not it's not also
fragmented right so it's kind of like
there are territories and then people
have actually got their territories
right and they marked their own
territories
um
it's kind of interesting and we'll see
why
so with that with that intro let's look
at some of the functionality right what
can you do when you go and buy one of
these
so the most common and obvious thing is
cleaning right but it's not just that
you can have Auto so you can just tell
about hey go clean and it's supposed to
figure out like the area it's supposed
to clean how fast and how much time and
all that on its own
you can tell it to clean its edges so it
can say in this room go around the edges
right just the edges you can also say
hey there's a spot that's dirty clean
that spot or you can just say hey I'm
going to manually control you and you
can control the button through a path
you want
you can also set up schedules and this
is interesting right you can say hey
every Sunday do not bother me 7am start
cleaning right and yeah it will bother
you because it makes a lot of noise at
least some of them do
um some of the fancy Bots have a health
monitoring feature so you can in their
app you can actually see how much you
know life span you have left for the
brushes right how long you have to
replace them stuff like that
here's a here's an example right so I've
taken this in an undisclosed location
here's a bot that's trying to map an
area that I was trying to clean
you'll see the bot is the dot generally
and someone has a zzz probably sleeping
and it's actually mapped this area on
its own right so the blue lines the
solid blue lines that you see it has
gone around and figured it out
the white lines
right sort of gone through it has
followed that path right it's a
combination of from what it seems like
it's a combination of uh breadth first
and then depth first algorithm right
that's what I saw from the lines but
anyway
some of the Bots also give you
um
features for multi-floor mapping so
let's say you have a house that has
multiple stories you can take the bot at
any story and it will map each floor and
sometimes the auto detect Which floor
they're on pretty fascinating right
um only few of them at least in my
research gave you the ability to view a
live stream so technically the bot is
looking around
that makes sense
all right so with that understanding of
functionality let's look at when you
when you buy one of these parts right
off the shelf how do you set it up what
happens
so in this example I've given some of
the you know basic components
you have a phone right you install the
app generally every manufacturer has an
app you can just click and install
um there's a bot and you have a modem
connecting Ur home to the internet
so the the border that you see on the
left the black one is your home network
and anything outside is external
so step one you install the app you
create an account right you enter your
basic credentials your name email stuff
like that and you say hey create an
account for me
that's what happens
in The Next Step you turn on the bot
right
and the app generally tries to search
for that bot right for that manufacturer
it will say hey are you around is
anybody around that I know of and it's
kind of interesting how they have made
it work so it's not as simple as hey bot
connect to my home network directly
that's not what I saw what happened
the app will do a search
and the bot will start up a Wi-Fi
network of its own
and it's going to broadcast it out
so that's another Network apart from
your home network
and it's going to say hey connect to me
I'm here what happens there is your
phone or that app connects to this wi-fi
network and it exchanges your
credentials off the home network
so it's a way to securely exchange
credentials that's really what's
happening in these three arrows and
after that once it's can talk outside
from your home it can say look I know
this person this account
I'm in this house or this this person
owns the bot right let's associate
myself with this account right so that's
the call it makes finally
and now you have a functioning part in
your house house
make sense
I see no it's cool all right
so that's very basic of you know how the
Bots work how you can set it up but
let's talk about how you can set up your
own home network right and this is
something you guys can do or all of you
can do you go back
so let's say you want to look at the
traffic right you want to examine what
is the bot really sending out of your
house
do we know like do we know this yet
I didn't right
so I to to show the point I actually
took a picture in my apartment and this
is how it looked like don't be scared of
the wires I'll simplify them in the next
diagram but the point here is it is very
very inexpensive for anybody to run the
setup so case in point I was able to do
it in around 150 ish right and this
includes my modem right so can be
anything I had a basic switch in the
middle that you see there
um it just needs to have Port mirroring
which is actually a very common feature
these days and then I also have an
internal router and I'll talk about why
and then a bunch of cables you can buy
them all for 10 bucks not that expensive
and at the bottom I had you know a Mac
and a phone to test this out so the
phone had the app and the Mac was used
to look at the traffic
makes sense
all right
so here's the icon view of that diagram
right and this makes it a little bit
simpler I hope to understand what's
Happening Here
so we have the bot right
and we have the cable modem on the right
so let's start from the right go to the
left so it's easier to understand
so from the right the cable modem talks
outside your home network that's your
point for any communication inside the
home to outside
simple enough
the app or the your mobile phone is
connected to that Wi-Fi network it's not
connected to the cable right it's
through the Wi-Fi network of the cable
modem and it's talking out so you don't
see anything this site from the phone
right it's just talking now
the switch is connected to both the
internal router and the external modem
right it's kind of in the middle and
that's for a reason because it has a
mirror port
and what I've done is I've connected my
machine or the Mac to the mirror port
okay
the bot is connected to the Wi-Fi SSID
of the internal router which is then
connected to the switch
so now if you think about this setup for
a second I know that's a lot of words
but if you think about communication of
the bot right let's say the bot says oh
associate account or I'm here
that packet is going to go through the
router to the switch to the modem out
but it will also go through the mirror
port
when the response come back it will go
straight back but it will also go down
because it's mirroring all the traffic
and that's how you can set up and listen
to all the things that are happening
through the bottle right that's the
reason of using the internal router and
the switch
simple enough right any questions here
no all right cool
now let's get into a little bit more fun
part right what did we see or what did I
see for some of the examples that I ran
this through
so let me explain like what I tested
first so with this setup right I tested
several functionalities we just talked
about so what happens when you establish
you know when you set up the connection
when you set up the bot that's case one
what happens when you say oh start
cleaning
what happens when you say move the bond
what happens when you say start
capturing video
I don't know but that's the setup will
enable us to check that data and then I
conducted analysis of okay I see you
know I see this traffic going on what's
the protocol can I look at it can I
examine it and why and why and why right
so here's an example I have not named
particular bots of vendors just to make
this talk a little bit more generic
right
um but I've seen a lot of patterns and
I'm going to stress on the patterns here
okay so the most common thing I saw is a
lot of bots are configured to talk to a
cloud service
that makes sense right they need to talk
externally why not a cloud service and
the first thing to do is hey I want to
talk to this domain I need to know the
IP the only way to for them to know that
is DNS
so we clearly see a DNS response coming
back and I know the Wireshark screenshot
is really really big and I tried to
blank things out you know but
essentially this exchange is saying hey
the first packet out is DNS tell me you
know a particular domain that I belong
to so
cloudservice.manufacture.com right it
can be hosted anywhere and I want to
talk to that IP right
the next thing I saw was once you get
that IP the bot established a TCP
connection
so now things are getting real right
so I didn't put Wireshark captures on
purpose here because there was a lot of
data
and I try to abstract out some of the
stuff that was interesting
and I know people are shaking heads does
anybody recognize what protocol that
looks like
on the right
looks familiar
I'm hearing mumbling but
a little bit louder so I can hear
and it's fine to be wrong it's totally
okay
yes close enough and what protocols use
XML
something over the network
or something like an example
whoever is behind thank you eggs
yeah correct xmpv exactly right so
they are actually using xmpp in this
case
is xmpp secure
it's plain text so no right but we'll
get to that right but it's very clear
when I when I say on the app turn right
what really happens is you see that IDE
and you see a particular atom feed it's
like a published subscribe model right
so it's like chat Bots
a lot of these Bots are chat Bots
they're just talking as a chat app
right and you say Hey you see the action
spin right I don't know what TD is maybe
it's a category of command no that's
that's how they have implemented it but
it says move right and then I get back a
response that says result and a type but
it doesn't say anything it's probably
saying success
right so this is what I saw on the
network when I hit one tab on the app
and it's very fascinating you can map
every feature and you see what's
happening on the network
all right similarly I said start
cleaning or stop cleaning same stuff
just for a little bit more information
so if you look at it it says clean and
there's also extra information like
speed
there's also a clean report coming back
right so all of this implementation
can be reversed engineered just by
looking at the traffic
simple enough right
there's also keep alive so after you're
done cleaning and you're happily you
know moving on to your work the bot is
still talking out maybe
it the Cloud Server might say hey bot
are you alive and it should say yeah and
this happens in your house without you
knowing
it's not malicious but it happens right
yeah
good question right how often is the key
for life is a question it it depends on
the implementation the bot or the
particular vendor and as I said I'm
trying to abstract it out it can be
anywhere from a few minutes to an hour
it depends generally when I saw Bots
cleaning it was more often just to see
like you know things are on track it's
not stuck it can communicate but like
when it stopped and like charging maybe
less right but this was clearly seen on
the network so
and there's a clear giveaway because
there says exempt right so you can see
the protocols all pretty clearly here
authentication we talked about security
right
this this when I saw this
um I stopped looking at the traffic for
at least 10 minutes
there was clearly a plain text password
being used in XMP before Authentication
didn't expect that but you know it's
it's it's also sometimes not surprising
because the functionality you know maybe
people just want to implement it and get
it off the ground and you know get in
the market I don't know how the
development life cycle was
but anyway we saw it there I removed it
from from this slide because you know
the essence is pretty clear here
and then uh it comes back from the
server as an acknowledgment
the protocol actually used here which
was the interesting part was sasm and
everybody here can look it up and read
about it it offers different types of
authentication so you can do a password
you can do sorry you can do a plain text
password you can also have a better
version of the same thing but in this
case it was just plain password
so
in another set of bots so there were
some of them involved but in another set
of bots there was a better version of of
this authentication something excuse me
something called as secure mqtt
mqtt like for those who don't know is
also a machine to machine protocol just
like you know it has a published
subscribe model so the same stuff on the
ground
but there's a secure version of the same
protocol
I saw the port being used as 8883
hmm okay
their status and this was really
unexpected and I'll I'll talk about this
why so you have you have sometimes all
of us look at phones right so we're
looking at our phones like this
literally like this
and you can open an app and you'll be
like okay let me open that we don't
think about it
but when I opened this particular app I
actually saw traffic
and I was like wait I didn't do anything
what's happening
turns out the bot is trying to get the
time
it's trying to get the time
which is correct for itself
and the weight was doing that was by
getting the time from the phone
and the way it was clear to me is I had
to reverse engineer it a little bit but
if you see the bolded line time T equals
something right some big number that's
an Epoch time right so you can convert
it into the current time which I did
here right and you can see when I was
testing this
um and there's also a TZ it's a time
zone I was in California at the time so
TZ is minus seven UTC makes perfect
sense
but is this good
is there any issue with this
you think so
why
location
yeah it does reveal some of the
locations thank you exactly and we'll
talk about that in one of the issues
that I actually ended up reporting
correct
so we saw this unexpected right I didn't
do any action on my phone but I saw this
so with that a little bit of the shock
I'm seeing in this room right now let's
talk a little bit about the security and
privacy issues that I actually you know
collected and then I'll show you the
reporting part as well
so can these Bots be hijacked or
controlled that was my obvious question
when I did the research I'm seeing a lot
of traffic on the network I'm seeing a
plain text password
can somebody just come in and say it's
not your Bot anymore it's not it's mine
and it can be somebody walking into my
apartment
right so there are two parts to this one
is remote can somebody do it remote they
don't have to be a local attacker on my
home network right
this is hard in my experience when I
thought about it I looked at the traffic
it's a little bit hard for you to get
into the home network you'll have to
compromise it but an easier way
is just get control of the app
the app does not have any two Factor it
just has a username and password so you
can set your password as clean me and
really that's the only control you have
or security you have quote unquote uh to
get control of any device through
control through that app
that was fascinating to me I'm like huh
now I need to worry about the security
of apps on my phone
so you see how the thread model is
moving from the iot device to the phones
and that's why it becomes complicated
and we talked about the local one right
so you can replay the commands we saw
play index commands right as long as
there is no nonce value that's saying
okay this is a new command and it
expires after like 30 seconds you can
replay those commands back over the
network
and the bot will do what you say
what about floor plans it's also moving
around just like you it's just another
human because it can also look at live
video
what about the privacy of floor plans so
this is interesting right sometimes I've
seen and this varies so I'm not going to
generalize my statements here but it
really depends on where the floor plans
are stored so they can be stored on your
phone
maybe okay but they can also be stored
in the cloud associated with your
account
again on the network I did not
explicitly find traffic that looked like
a floor plan it's very hard it's very
challenging and I'm being very
transparent about this because I'm not
saying oh this method is like complete
in any way but it gives you a lot of
information
so I didn't find it if you do first
anything else please talk to me
or best to talk to the vendors
course location somebody correctly
pointed out uh the location issue so yes
it's not precise by the way because we
still have a time zone uh I would say an
area of the time zone but let's say I
taking this phone I have I have an app I
have Bots I travel to I don't know
Zurich Switzerland for example right and
I have a bot in California
the moment the time zone changes from
this and I open the app my bot is gonna
think it's somewhere else it's it's in
UTC UTC time zone of Zurich right and
it's going to mess up the schedule of
the bot
so instead of starting at 6am or 7 am on
a Sunday it will be off by seven hours
and I tested this accidentally
I didn't even know about it and it
suddenly started one day and I was just
testing my time zones I just changed the
time
and so sometimes you discover things by
accident as well but it can be proven if
you look at the traffic so it's all
visible at the end
uh this was interesting because you can
mess up schedules and that can have
different human effects
people might be pissed off
video recordings right
um
this was interesting I wasn't very
scared about it after I saw the data but
like for people who spend a lot of time
in what shark
if you see the left screenshot the
screenshot on the left you see almost
equal sized packets being exchanged over
UDP
you know sounds like something that's
not reliable like a video stream
or an audio stream right so this was a
clear giveaway okay I clicked start
video and I see this boom boom on and
it's just really quick because it has a
lot of data right
when I examined the packet
I said hey give me the details
I luckily did not see it being a sum
protocol that I recognized I couldn't
decode it per se but I did find some
metadata right and that's the part I've
highlighted for everybody here so if if
it's too small I'll read it right it
says message type start streaming
so you still get a sense of when the
user started looking at the video
it will also give you a session ID I
don't know what you can use it for that
for for what reason but that's still
data and give me more data I'm happy
right so there is some metadata being
leaked that is you're not completely
aware except you know the stream is just
fine at least from what I saw
all right so we saw we saw the
functionality we saw how to set it up
for yourself we saw some of the issues
now this is this is the most uh I don't
know fear slash interesting uh
conversation so I'm going to show you a
bunch of emails and that's an exchange
with a vendor
the vendor names or anything else that
gives away the name is blanked out so
don't worry but it's interesting
nonetheless
okay so that's me and the part that's
highlighted is the date and time so I
want everybody here to watch the date
and time okay don't worry about reading
it I just put it as a proof that I'm not
bluffing everybody here this actually
happened right I can show you on my
phone later
without blanking out anyway but
um essentially
If You observe the date and time it is
November 18 2019. so I've been doing
this research for about good two years
now and that was the first time I
reported so I said hey by the way hello
XYZ support here's what I found and I
had to write a long one because if you
write a small one they don't think
you're serious
so I completely write down my research
and said hey this is what I found so I
told them here's the background right I
told them issues one by one so I said
hey by the way I see insecure protocols
I see plain text passwords I see
potential man the Millet attack on the
local network right and that's all the
text here
I also see course location tracking
right and for this one I was very
specific because I showed them what I
captured because they won't believe me
otherwise right
anyway
um it was like explaining everything
that they knew but they already knew
hopefully but anyway
and then I finally you know was also
transparent about the privacy of floor
plans again I remember I didn't test
this completely or thoroughly and I
actually wrote that but I wanted them to
investigate and like look at it and say
is this okay are we doing good or can we
change something
who in this room can guess what happened
next
[Applause]
who remembers the timeline what date or
what month did I send this
it was four year four slides ago
November 2019. okay cool everybody's
everybody's awake awesome
I have to do these pop quizzes
all right uh
guesses for what happened next
random guesses
they ignored it
reported you to the police
somebody reported me to the fullest I
don't confidently say on with the
recording on that I'm clean so I'm I'm
still here I'm still here giving a talk
about the same thing so either the you
know I don't want to comment any further
any other guesses before I hit next
later to the day A year later today
awesome
[Music]
they ignored it so whoever said ignored
it was right
um I actually closed the ticket so they
went one step further
if you see the date
if you see the date it's not that far so
I I would have to give give it up to
them for for the promptness
but if you see this part
I didn't click any of those links by the
way
what do you think happens next
this time it's probably on me right well
maybe on them I don't know
public disclosure
good good thinking you're vacuum is
seriously stopped working
I would question my if so the audience
said uh one person said my vacuum's not
working
I would be very concerned at that point
and I would re-examine my methods again
if I miss something
because I definitely miss something but
really good call
all right so what happened was you know
I obviously followed up and I said hey
if you look at the time again it's a
little bit on that side because email
threads right
um if you see the time that kept keeps
me awake so 12 21. I said request to
reopen the ticket number X
because I've not received an official
reply to blah blah blah right and I also
somebody said responsible disclosure
extremely good call because that's I
reminded them of that there is
let's think about this for a second a
bit more seriously
we just talked about the market we just
talked about it's a multi-billion dollar
industry there are millions of units out
there
we should take this stuff seriously
I don't mean to talk anything negative
about this vendor or anything else it's
all for fun right but in general right I
would expect prompt response dialogue
all of that
what happened next
close again that's a good call
fix the issue and gave you some bug
Bounty money
at least at least the latter part I
don't know about the first part right
maybe the issue is fixed uh we'll see
we'll see in Fallen flights but I didn't
receive any conversation yet
so after a while after a while and I say
why because see the date I got an
acknowledgment a good one because I was
following up I again this is all for
humor right I don't mean to demean any
vendor here right just just so people
know but the timeline is pretty critical
right so at after close to a month right
you get a knack and I and I have some
explanation this is good this is
actually good I I wanted something like
this
but look at the part that's red
it says at the end it says yes we
implemented using xmpp which some of you
folks kind of recognized through the
slides says which is an older model
I don't know what's old and what's new
because I just bought the bot and I
wanted it to work the way it's supposed
to work all our new models now use more
secure technology to ensure user
information security
what do you mean by what do you mean by
use more secure technology to ensure I I
don't know I I had no idea right but
that got me worried because what about
the old models what about people who
bought the old model
are and don't know about these
right
I hope people can see the next slide
but what happened next
no guesses tired of guessing huh
sorry what was that close the ticket
um not completely I'm trying to recall
exactly yes they may have closed it but
I have to check my email thread again
um I wasn't satisfied with this to be
honest I love the response I like the
came back something substantial came
back right not just close the ticket but
I personally wasn't happy and I gave
them time so I really wanted to be
responsible and adhere to the
responsible disclosure time frame so I
said look 90 day 120 day whatever you
want I'm cool with that I mean today
it's two years almost
so three months later
I followed up but then I got a response
something like this right and look at
the time
February now we are in February we
started off in November
so somebody said Thank you right
somebody said they thanked you that's
also correct because they did right and
they passed on the team back passed on
my notes around hey I'm not happy with
this we need to CV a sign we need a cwe
something that shows this is
acknowledged right not just that email
I'm passing this note blah blah blah I
was fine I said okay I'm cool no worries
right
what happened next
I bought a new one I was buying Bots
sure
[Music]
sorry
nothing nothing
close enough
all right so
nothing really happened which is right
actually uh so you see me following up
on March 30th so just think about this
I'm not the first person who bought this
bot right I maybe have conducting This
research that's another story but I'm
working with them right now I'm not like
against anybody I'm working with them
I'm reporting responsibly trying to
understand and help out but we are at
March 30th
and I had to follow up a little bit more
strictly
right and say look
is there a response do we have something
assigned is somebody working on this if
so I'm fine I'll back off I I have no
issues right but I want something to be
done
and thank you
sure
find final takes on what happened next
because that's the final guess I won't
ask you guys to guess any further
they tried to run me over
oh my vacuum wow I'm really scared of
that guy now
so I again I I didn't do any public
disclosure I didn't I also have blanked
out their names right um I've done this
on my own no employers involved
I was very honest and transparent and I
reported it for good reason and like
with good faith right and even here I'm
not talking bad just just to be very
clear I'm not saying in a negative
manner I'm just saying this happens with
vendors and sometimes it's some of the
priorities right it's one person
reporting something like it it really
matters how you are responding and
prioritizing so I'm not saying it's all
of their fault but like for some
security issues we should be more
cognizant and that's really the message
right nothing really happened
so I had actually pulled back and I said
hey it's been like a lot of time in
seven six seven months I actually
started writing more emails
um seven months later I did get response
that says yes right and the the part
that I want everybody to focus is the
red part right so there's obviously a
date that's July right and there's
obviously escalations happening so look
I'm not I'm okay with the process but
I'm not okay with no work being done
so it got escalated
I would I would put it in a positive way
the the future Bots with the unknown
vendor here
they were better
right A lot of them did not have those
issues I was happy at the end I mean it
was an old one I understand but it's an
interesting case study you can pick one
up and test this out yourself right
and I didn't follow up after this it was
way too long it was kind of old several
years old I don't know how many people
use it but the objective is today's
awareness and not just raise awareness
you don't have to attend a talk to know
about this you can do it yourself
so in conclusion
I promise to end early so I'll stick to
that promise
um they might use vacuum boards like
other iot devices this again this is
nothing to do with specific vacuum watch
that can this can apply to your fridge
you know cameras anything right by
anybody
they may use insecure protocols
they may use insecure configurations
it's also very challenging for the end
user to get guarantees of privacy and
security I understand their pain points
I get it that's why I'm not complaining
too much about it I'm just saying hey we
can do a better job
the DIY method I described really that's
one of the main takeaways of this talk
is you can replicate this do-it-yourself
talk to people raise concerns I think
one way to really get the industry
moving is more people getting involved
and saying hey we should fix this now
right and finally again not finger
pointing but it's in general challenging
to get a response and also a response
and a fix
it's hard to fix these devices they're
everywhere like how do you tell how do
you follow up with a customer and say
hey like for that bot that you have
you're not going to give you a new one
it's hard to do logistically right it
happens with cars there are recalls but
like for Bots
I've not seen them yet
with that thank you everybody for
listening thanks for keeping it clean
and you can reach me at my website for
yeah I have my LinkedIn Twitter
everything
thanks all
[Applause]
right
any questions I do want to allow time
for questions yes
were they firm or available over the air
so the question was were any of the Bots
firmware updated over there yes uh there
are some and actually that helps a lot
what I didn't do is retest the same
thing so it's definitely possible to
your point and that's why I was not very
negative or like trying to criticize
anybody here some of them may have been
fixed maybe I didn't hear back a lot of
now vendors are following this method
where they say oh look update available
click update and you'll be fine
um I just don't know whether each update
has a security patch or they are just
functionality improvements or bug fixes
that should be another
topic over the year updates that was a
question I that's an interesting thank
you I think I'll think about that I
haven't done it yet
but we could do that sober were they all
plain text uh that's a good question yes
a lot of them uh the question is I'll
repeat for the recording did any of the
Bots use SSL
um I cannot say that specifically SSL
but they were secure protocols in place
for a lot of them so there there were
times when I actually got a bot and I
saw nothing on the network
and it's very sad as a security
researcher
but that's a good thing right after that
sadness passes away you're like good job
so yes
yeah so I I couldn't see that some of
the slides curly enough for those
packets UDP packets the slides which
sorry I'll take you back sorry about
that
was there a lot of UDP that's the one
yeah those are all UDP packets yes those
are not even in fact it's kind of small
that's why I was talking about it yes
those are all UDP packets
yeah
I would be concerned if there were TCP
in using video
that's a lot of bandwidth and
tissues
anyway any final questions
going once
going twice
sold
[Applause]
thank you for that talk it was super
interesting I was