good morning i'm dr mark peters from
tech incorporation i'm here with agile
compliance and risk operations
uh talking about some of the things
we've done to implement devops some
government contractor spaces in the past
uh year that i've been employed in those
areas
i have to remind everybody as i talk
about government stuff that i don't
actually speak for the government uh
program for which i'm employed i'm
speaking for myself and my company
uh these are my personal views don't
necessarily represent any of those other
books along the way
i also mentioned that i do tend to talk
really fast and i'm going to try to slow
myself down to make the time moments
appropriately
but we'll see how it goes along the way
so as all the talks start first we have
to move and
i think i've lost my webcam there we go
and there we go so who am i a quick
introduction
i used to work in air force intelligence
i spent about 22 years working for the
u.s air force i went all over the world
and all kinds of different things
for different people telling them things
they didn't want to know what the
secrets were and finding out the secrets
from the opposite side
of our cyber security working on those
opposite perspectives to get things
through
needless to say working with the
government organization for that long i
got oodles of experience with compliance
practices making sure that the security
was in the right place
that the tools were in the right place
that things were moving from one side to
the other
and that all the information got to the
people they needed to do
so after enforcing those compliance
practices for years and years and being
on the other side of it
i got into cyber security uh and i got
into that practice because i spent some
time at the nsa and worked with some of
their functions i'd work with some of
the other cyber functions and i run a
couple different units doing cyber
things
back and forth along the way at those
times i got to implement those tools at
multiple levels to see how they worked
all the way from
building your own sets and having them
there and
trying to figure out how the computers
work to getting those results out to the
ops guys so that they could use it
effectively do what they wanted to do
in the past year that means what i've
done is i've worked with two different
agile
programs your government programs that
are enforcing cyber weapon systems for
the government
and they're trying to build an agile
transition their programs
for one i worked as the product owner
trying to make their pipelines and their
platforms work better
and for the other i've been the lead
security engineer so implementing
security all across the way
and trying to make those pieces all fit
together in a manner that everybody can
use most effectively
i'm also a devops institute ambassador
if you're curious about devops the
devops institute is out there and they
talk about the three ways all the time
when we talk about flow feedback in
continuous learning so i'll mention
those later in the talk as we go through
uh instant some of my other background
just real quick i'm an avid reader i
read a little bit of everything i read
history i read about devops i read about
business i read about sci-fi and fantasy
so if you've got any good books feel
free to lean out and recommend them
i've also done a lot of writing along
the way i actually published a book
about a year and a half ago called
cashing in on cyberpower where i looked
at 10 years of economic attacks for 10
years of cyber attacks
and how they developed economic
influences all across the world i do
have a doctorate in strategic security
not in arithmetic but in those reading
and writing functions
as we move forward so leaping into
the talk uh the problem was
as we came across as we moved into this
new role here as a lead security
engineer
is how does my security team ensure
compliance enforce the standards
and still remain agile now this remains
a problem for a lot because security is
seen as
non-flexible as we talked about they
look at their own things they don't
expand and they don't make this merge
but we want to be committed to the team
vision and the team organization
in order to do that we have to be agile
across the process and that starts with
looking at ourselves it doesn't start
with pointing the finger at the other
side of the fence
and looking at someone over there and
saying you know what you guys are doing
it wrong
and you need to fix it to do it the way
we do what we want to do is we wanted to
fix ourselves
so that we could be an example so that
we could lean into those things and
provide help to those other
organizations
as the cyber lead as a cyber security
lead in the security team we face this
problem daily we go out to everybody we
talk to everyone we say
you know what can we do how can we help
but we weren't getting there because we
were making the transition with the
government program for what used to be a
waterfall program
what is now said they're going to be an
agile program
and in that you still have a lot of the
old practices and you have the old ideas
and you have the old culture
and you need to move that forward and
one of those biggest challenges is we're
looking at the cyber team
is the government that dod that u.s air
force sector
uses the national institute of standards
and technology and use something called
which i'm sure a lot of you are familiar
with at 853 plus categories and controls
and indicators for doing a risk
management framework or they call it a
risk management framework
because it's supposed to guide you in
doing your cyber security but what
actually happens is you get
19 different families of controls with
over a thousand different controls and
indicators
and the government comes back and says
hey guess what we've got a thousand
different indicators we'd like you to
respond to
every indicator with artifacts and
examples of what you're doing and how
you're doing it
and how we move that forward but we
didn't want to go there we didn't want
to be
that tightly tied we didn't want to be
that tightly tied when we sat down with
the dev and said hey
you know what i need you to answer uh
about a thousand questions on how your
program is going what you're going to do
next
we wanted to be in an agile process
where we're talking about those four
basic principles those four guides to
agile
where we're talking about people over
processes we're talking about working
software
over uh comprehensive documentation
we're talking about moving forward the
whole scope of the things and we're
talking about using scrum and getting
that daily feedback into
something that's a uh a very standard
process
so as we're looking at the problem about
ensuring those compliance and forcing
standards remaining agile
we start looking at the parameters
because the parameters for us are the
things we have to consider
we have to do because we're working in
that government bureaucratic framework
and we've got to make sure that we can
move ahead
we've got to make sure that we can move
to the right places to actually
accomplish this
so we have to meet the standards that
they're laying out for us and as a
contractor we have to meet the standards
that are in our contract
as we move forward we have to be able to
manage risk and we have to be able to
manage risk effectively
because in the end that's what security
is about it's about tying risk down to
the factor
where you can get into the risk and you
can find things and then we had to look
as always at the third option of where
we could buy a solution who could we buy
a solution from
we just hire somebody else to come and
replace us and do the job for us at a
lower cost
i like the tom sawyer thing where you
pay everybody to paint your fence for
you
and then you just sit back and collect
at the end so
and looking at our parameters the first
as always like we said is to be
compliant or agile
now what we see is we see compliance or
agile is the opposite sides
of the room there's no compromise
between being compliant or being agile
and that the places that are inflexible
in their compliance
don't see it any different because we
see all kinds of compliance
we see the legally prescribed compliance
we see the organizationally prescribed
components
and we see sometimes even internally
prescribed deployments what do we have
to be compliant with the standard for
our organization
as we move forward into that setup now
this includes something like fits for
the cryptographic standards the nist
that i already talked about
fisma socks for the stocks and the
credit exchanges
the pci disks for your credit cards uh
the gdpr for
europe the ccpa that they've implemented
in california they're all different
standards
many times a lot of them apply many
times only some of them apply
and many times they're good ideas but
they're not formal practices all these
compliance standards are usually very
administratively heavy there's a lot of
stuff that has to be done
and they're very difficult to implement
and that they're meant to be that way so
that you have experts that come in and
can enforce those
there's a lack of freedom and there's a
lot of blockers in those processes
but it's not true all the time sometimes
it just takes a different way of looking
at it
and i'd like to think that a lot of the
way of looking at that is in those agile
practices as we look at agile as we look
at the
lean scrum and those types of frameworks
that we can get to a devops mindset that
we need to a better way to interact
those things together
and make it more of a loose framework
that leads to our high level success in
getting the job done
but we've got to eliminate that that
whole that back and forth
on those processes so that we can get to
the right area
and we can get to the right place where
we're talking about the things that we
need to do
and we're talking in an effective manner
about those things we need to do
to move forward so we need to be
compliant and we need to be agile in
process
and being compliant being agile gets to
the same spot when you're talking about
security
and when you're talking about getting
security into the practices so that you
can deliver
effectively on the value for the
organization and that means you need to
talk about risk
you need to talk about risk management
and you need to be able to do the math
without numbers
and that's very contradictory statement
because there really is no math without
numbers but at the same time you're
talking about the various elements
of those processes you're talking about
the ability to
talk about those three elements or those
four elements that make up risk and when
you look at a risk equation or a
standard risk equation
you're talking about rat times
vulnerability time or risk equals threat
times vulnerability to exposure
and we want to lower all those elements
but in order to load those elements we
have to be able to talk about those
almost we have to be able to talk
effectively we have to know
what the threat is who's coming at us
where does it exist
and whether that threat is a foreign
malware source but that threat is just a
loss of business right
the threat to us may be that we can't
deliver unless we have that product out
there
the vulnerabilities are those things
that exist in our system in our code
in our culture that may cause exceptions
may cause gaps in the future whether
it's a standard a
cve off the enterprise says hey we've
got a
a break in our program we've got a break
in our code and you know it's going to
be vulnerable and it's going to be a
critical failure unless we fix that
immediately
if we've got a break in our firewall if
we've got
all kinds of other vulnerabilities but
that also leads to exposure
and the reason i say it leads to is
exposure is managing risk exposure is
one of those key things especially in
working with government programs right
but you have to be able to talk about
effective exposure but
if you've only got a small area and that
small area is off-prem
and it's behind the number of firewalls
and it only reaches out through one way
and it only reaches through a vpn
that handling it handling a
exposure on that backend system may be
relatively minimal it may only cause you
relatively minimal risk
even if some other site like a cve or
miner says it's a critical failure
because it's so far behind that that
there's no exposure
to that system that you see so you have
to manage all those risks and you have
to compare between those risks
to be able to manage the structure in a
way that you can effectively present
those results
as you're sitting down and talking to
the devs and talking about your ability
to do your risk operations and your
azure compliance
and that's what we did we said we wanted
to be agilely compliant but we still
wanted to manage risk and we wanted to
manage risk for operations
and to us our agile compliance meant
that we needed to maintain
that compliance without sacrificing
flexibility i think earlier in one of
the presentations they talked about the
inflexible developers
well a lot of times security hits that
same in flexibility as well that we need
to be more flexible
and not all of our guys they were kind
of rooting the process they're not all
good at doing yoga or moving
some of those transitions so the
flexibility was in between
but we did that agile compliance we
worked to get to that agile compliance
and we worked to that at the same time
to doing risk operations managing our
risk
and always talking about risk in the
same manner and being able to talk about
how we were effective in that risk or
where that risk structure
as we move forward
so the third option like i mentioned for
us was that buying a solution
and everybody knows that you can go out
there and buy a solution there's lots of
contractors all over the place
if you've been in cyber security for any
length of time i'm sure at least a third
of your emails if not more coming in are
from vendors
and they offer a lot of good products
and there's a lot of good things out
there
nowadays that you can get in these
product scapes uh
that'll help you and they'll help move
your process forward and they'll make
you more effective and deliver value to
your process
from the beginning to the end so
they fall into kind of different scopes
and the first scope is really a who
wants to sell method
and you get the scaled agile framework
for enterprise it used to be scaled
agile for enterprise now it's a scaled
agile framework
uh for enterprise and the government is
using that they're using it a lot
they've bought this big framework that
goes in and it gives them a structure
that they can use when they start
talking about implementing agile and
implementing a devops mindset to move
forward
but it does cost and it costs to get
trained people and it costs to get the
training experience
and to bring them in and the next step
you get disciplined agile right
discipline agile is from the pmi
institute
uh and i'm a program management
professional so you know full disclosure
there
i've seen discipline agilent's way of
again taking that agile mindset
and building it onto a structure so that
when a big company like the government
comes in and says hey you know what
uh i need something and i need a
framework but i'm not ready to give up
all my culture to get to that framework
to get to that agile compliance
it kind of kind of helped them along the
process then you see deloitte and other
companies who will come in
uh and they'll bring a consultant in the
consultant will tell you everything
you're doing wrong and everything you're
doing right
with more emphasis on what you're doing
wrong and tie you in for a long-term
contract
and it'll get you in the process it'll
get you to agile compliance to get you
to risk operations all along the way
uh so that you can do the right things
uh it makes success and have value in
your organization
you get overlays itel and cmmi are both
great organizations and they both
both offer good quality products but
still buying someone else's overlaying
depending that they're answering the
right questions for your organization to
move forward
in a mix of these is helpful and
understanding all of these is helpful
and you see sre certifications working
with the devops institute
that site reliability engineer those are
good functions and those are good
effective functions
that help people do good things and they
build in value throughout your
organization by having that development
from ops
all the way through security all the way
into depth but you have to be able to
understand what you have to talk about
and sometimes that's working through the
process first and getting to the first
steps
uh before you find out that you need an
actual asberry certification you
actually need one of these overlays from
somebody else
and then you see people who are just
selling experts right i'm not going to
give you an overlay
instead i'll give you an expert i'll
sell you an expert that expert can go
into your organization
and when they get to your organization
they're going to help you fix everything
that's wrong with them
you see this from a lot of staffing
agencies you also see it from government
contractors which i can't complain too
much because we've come in as a
government contractor
although i do have to mention uh in all
fairness as we talk about our government
contract
situation we took over from a previous
set of contracts the previous set of
contracts
for the weapon program we're doing the
cyber vulnerability analysis weapon
program
had three different contracts for three
different companies and they had one
contract doing maintenance one contract
doing sustainment one contract doing
development
well when our company technical
corporation came in we took over all
three of those contracts and blended
them together
which is working for us so far so good
as we'll mention some of the other
slides but better than the previous
three
where none of those contracts were
willing to talk to each other to get the
maintenance and sustainment development
all done
in conjunction in time to get to
something where they could actually have
an agile compliance
and a risk operation along the way
so how do we discover fixes how do we
get there with these problems in this
framework
around what we need to do how do we find
out
what it is that we need to fix where we
need to fix it and find an
effective way to move us forward in what
it is
and the first thing is adaptive
philosophy right it always boils down
vaginal and devops in sre that you have
to have an effective culture
and that means you need to start both
small for the culture from the bottom up
as well as from the top down both sides
have a culture and you have to meet
those cultures in
with our security team when we sat down
to adopt the philosophy i came in from
an outside program
the previous three individuals on our
security team were already there
so they already kind of had a philosophy
from that organization from their
previous waterfall setup
and what we wanted to do was we wanted
to move it into that
that kind of devops agile mindset and
that meant who are we serving where are
we building value where are we
delivering
uh effectiveness into the organization
uh through this value philosophy through
this devops and the value stream that
goes to the devops as we move forward
we talked about first that we have
security user storage who uses security
right
who needs to use our security products
who needs to use those security features
and the first thought is well the devs
are the users right because they
actually have to get the security we
have to convince them to build the
security and we have to convince them to
put the security
both in their products and in their
pipelines uh and in their deliverables
so they're part of the user that are
using our stories when we say we need
this to be effective
because in the government in a
bureaucracy in a compliance if we don't
do all those things that we need for
compliance
and an outside organization comes and
says hey you know what you're not
compliant
they can shut us down and they can pull
it back and that's not good for anybody
most of all the devs because there's a
lot of them and because they put a lot
of hard work in
trying to get the process forward and
trying to make it
work on a daily basis so what do we see
about the devs well the devs
also have their user stories right and
they see security as an enabler
so we have to work through that mindset
that we enable them to do more effective
things
uh when we give them good security we
allow them to deliver more value
uh all across the way with those
effective things
and how do we get them to talk to us on
a regular basis how do we integrate with
them on a regular basis
uh and that has to be part of our
mindset too security historically in a
waterfall
sometimes has a bad reputation or a bad
experience of constantly being known but
being the culture of know that we only
say no
because we're just trying to get
compliant
but we're not really just trying to get
compliant we're trying to do the things
our value for us that our organization
has told us value but we need to
integrate to get past that process
to get into the place where we can do
the good things for everyone
and then we have a product owner store
right the person who owns the business
the customer who's getting that end goal
value
from the entire stream uh and that has
to be the compliance adds value
we have to be compliant to add value and
they have to value the new things of
compliance and the new security and that
agile compliance that comes in through
that security
is just as valuable as putting in a new
feature that new feature loses value
if you don't have the security and
compliance built in all the way across
the process
to get you achieved and we started to do
that when we were thinking about it but
how do we manage risk how do we operate
through risk
instead of just saying we're managing we
want to talk about risk operations
because we want to talk about this
change in the cycle
in this process that goes through to be
able to effectively talk through our
risk processes
with a number of different people and a
number of different factors
so we have to be able to manage multiple
users we have to be able to manage
multiple users all the time in order to
manage those users
we have to be familiar with those users
part of that is integrating into those
teams
and making sure that we had security
reps in those teams
a lot of times i'll tell you about
security champions and using a security
champion
designating someone to represent
security for your team
and that may work as you get larger and
larger but when you have small teams and
only a certain number of deadlines
i think it works better to get your
security team in there every day
i get the experience and get the
face-to-face and we need to be able to
suggest those solutions in those
face-to-face
experiences by uh talking without
leveraging
right we can't say this is what you have
to do and if you don't do it we're going
to shut you down
we're going to cut it down right here
instead we have to listen to what the
developers are putting forward
now what they need to do and suggest
how they can find ways to make that go
through compliance and how they can make
that compliant
in the process and hopefully that gives
us some long-term success with the
short-term compliance
and that having an effective process and
having effective people that are
integrated and they're
talking to deliver functional software
helps us meet the compliance
all the way through so that we can do
this easy things in small steps
and then use automation to round those
up together so we can meet those
compliance standards at the barns
with our thousands and thousands of
controls
so what was our security team problems
and what were some of the solutions
along the way
so with a new contract the first
question was where do i start
right what occurred before we came in we
came into this new government space
in working in the government space our
first problem was access a lot of these
government programs are
blocked when you see that you have to
get access to the government the
government wants certain
things to be filled out before you get
into those spaces you have to have the
paperwork
you have to have what's done i always
say and i always work
that when you work with programs when
you work with software when you work
with any process really in any type of
operation
change creates error but indecision
creates disaster
you have to be able to make the small uh
changes
along the way to do things you have to
make small decisions in small increments
and without the access at first without
the access to the old compliance
standards that was what we did
we went back to the basic security
practices we went back to the basics of
what was happening how was it happening
were we making sure that we were doing
the right things
we have all the users integrated we have
all the users uh passwords
we have the secrets protected we have
our facilities not just locked down but
blocked out in certain ways that we can
make the standards
so we were making these small decisions
into these small increments
along the way uh and then the next step
for us was do we understand the tools at
hand do we have the right
tools in the places the government came
in
and processed it to us that we were able
to do the right things and that
we saw them as effective
in the process so we had to challenge
the old models because the old model was
waterfall
and the waterfall development of being
able to deliver in five years
was no longer affected so we had to look
at the new tools so that we could get
new cycles out we could test the new
tools
we looked at things like di2e which is a
framework of
developer defense intelligence
integration to enterprise uh trello
which is the boards for workflow
clara which is a container standard
sonar cube which is a code scanner a
sas tool a static analysis security tool
on salt stack it's integration
management
we were finding ways to integrate those
we were finding ways that we even used
that we
shifted from a jenkins to a git lab in
the earlier formats so that we could get
more pipeline built in and more that
cicd framework uh built in along the
process
but some of that was learning for us
some of that was learning that the
security team had to go back and
challenge their previous assumptions
and sit down with the devs and say
this is what it is and this is what
we're doing this how we use it i can't
even mention with gitlab that gitlab is
a great tool
we love using gitlab but uh one of our
first debates with the guys over gitlab
was that they said hey we're going to
gitlab we said that's great
uh when you move from jenkins and you're
moving out to gitlab gitlab has these
great security dashboards we want to see
those security dashboards
we want to be able to get those metrics
and look at you
and use those metrics right because
those metrics are great those metrics
will give us so much of the security
compliance information
that we can automate and we don't have
to go bug you all the time for this
information
and the devs came back and said yeah
that's nice but we only bought the
bronze package and the bronze package
doesn't include the security dashboard
so
you're gonna have to wait till next time
uh so instead we have i mean we're still
working through a process
for that but hopefully we'll be able to
get some more success with it along the
way
and at least we've got our pipeline
metrics and with that pipeline we've got
the tools in the process right so
talking through how you get to that
agile compliance if you can go through
to that compliance guy
and you can say hey in that compliance
with the tools i've got
i get every time code gets checked in i
get a number of scans i get a number of
processes
i get that that static code analysis at
the beginning and at the end i get that
dynamic analysis of how it goes into the
platform
and i get the scan of everything that's
matching up as well as i get a stig
which is a government framework for a
secure technical implementation guidance
it tells you all the things you need to
do with every tool
to make sure it's compliant so you use
the stakes did you apply all the stings
affected
we can go and say hey not only is this
being done because you came in audit but
we're doing this for ourselves and we're
doing it every day
uh and i've got this whole stack of data
so that when the auditor comes in
uh i can say i've already got it for you
right it's already there
uh and it's what we have and that blends
into that next part
can you see what you need to do are you
able to work transparently and
communicate often
uh again we see security a lot of times
a lot of old security practices what
happens is
that security comes back behind a
blocker behind wall
nobody wants to talk about the security
nobody wants to talk about the
vulnerabilities nobody wants to talk
about
uh what's wrong we don't see it as wrong
but it is potential for fix
it is potential to improve and to do
better by being able to work
transparently we have to be transparent
about what we're looking for
just as much as we need them to be
transparent about what they're working
on
and what the factors of them actually
working with that process are
and that's part of that communication
often how do we get to a process
where we communicate often enough
um that we get what we need and not only
that
the developers keep thinking that we're
involved and embedded in those teams
and right now we do we have somebody in
one of their teams every day we have
four or three development teams and an
engineering architecture team
and with four security guys we have one
person on each of those teams
uh every day sitting in their screens
offering them advice uh when they need
it
because a lot of times they don't need
it a lot of times they can do their own
thing but then taking that information
back and building a consulate
consolidated security picture of how
everything works
along the way so this leads to the next
step which is it's not just about us
right it's not just about my security
team it's not
just about that development team or this
ops team or that functional underwear
we have to have a organizational
solution
we have to be able to make the culture
change both from the top up in the
bottom
bottom up in the top down to deliver a
process where we can build those good
teams and we need to be able to work
through those
through that leadership structure all
along the way and that's a challenge and
it's a challenge for a lot of people
but if you invest in the people and you
harvest that process you harvest the
good things that come out of the people
because it's people over processes but
you have to have the right people and
having the right people build processes
along the way
you have to take the people first and
know that the developer is important and
that person is important and that lets
you get to the point where you have a
good process
by working through there and building a
team that depends not just on their own
team
but that every other team is functioning
along the same way
so we talk about being able to integrate
we talk about being able to
beat the street right now i say beat the
street because i had a good senior
leader come back to me one time
he mentioned that uh somebody asked him
why he repeated the same thing over and
over when he did talk they said they'd
seen him talk
in three or four different places and he
said the same thing every time and he
said the same three things every time
and his response when he came back was
that ten percent of the people
who hear me hear ten percent of what i
say 10 of the time
they said he figured if that happened he
had to say the same thing 30 times
before he could effectively depend on
one person hearing him once
uh and the same thing applies to
security and same thing applies to
develop
when we go through and we want to talk
about security we need to say the same
thing and we need to be on the same
message
if we're constantly changing our
security message and we're constantly
changing how that security message is
going to affect value
then we can't manage our risk and we
can't be agilely compliant
because somebody will hear a different
thing every time we get there and
they've got a lot of stuff to do
just like we do the devs have a lot of
things that they need to take care of
so if they only hear part of the message
part of the time then we don't get to an
effective security platform along the
way
and that translates into building
transparency as well
having that transparency all along the
way being able to visualize workflow
and be able to go and see what everyone
is doing keeps you from having to track
that person down and say hey i need you
to tell me
because you can see it for yourself and
you can see it from the beginning to the
end of the process
across the pipeline and that's a lot of
what that flow and feedback is in that
devops mode being able to have a clear
flow
and get clear feedback all across the
step and that's what we're working
towards with this agile compliance risk
operations
and then we need to be able to link
items and tasks
you have to be able to take the item and
when you see it know how security fits
it and know that security is part of it
all the time
just like the operation of it having
those acceptance criteria and those
definitions are done built in across the
way that let you get where you need to
be
by linking those items together and
having a backlog of what you need to get
to
sometimes security is not the most
important priority i know that sacrilege
a lot of people on the security teams i
know that's sacrilege a lot of people
have worked it but
sometimes because of that exposure
because of that risk management
you can put security in the backlog and
it can come up the next time
or the time after that or the time after
that it has to be done before
compliance but what is your compliance
framework when is somebody else going to
check
and what is your risk if you actually
let that security go and say hey
you know what we have a ci cd i'm going
to fix it the next time because
it's more important to get that feature
out now and that leads to the
prioritization how do we prioritize
those things
along the way for security so once we
have the organizational solutions what
are those takeaways what are the things
we learned from doing this
uh all along the way as we're moving our
process forward
uh and the first is practice practice
practice right uh
agile is a skill agile compliance is a
skill security is a skill coding is a
skill
uh there's a great paper by a gentleman
named malcolm gladwell who's
written a lot of stuff on the process uh
it may actually be a book called
outliers that was written in the 90s one
of the things he talks about was the
number of times
you have to achieve deliberate practice
to be considered good at something
and those numbers wind up looking like
500 times you have to be able to repeat
it 500 times for familiarity about 5 000
times for
some basic level of competence about 50
000 times for mastery
and it has to be deliberate practice
which means you have to concentrate on
those right things that you're doing
to be able to uh move forward
um and it's difficult if you think about
doing the sprint if you think about
doing your
your basic scrum meeting that you do
every day
you spend 15 minutes doing every day and
you probably do it 280 times a year
if that and if you need to be able to do
that 50 000 times before you consider
you're effective at that you really have
to practice you have to take advantage
of every opportunity
as an opportunity to practice an
opportunity to get that continuous
learning from that third
way and move it forward so we practice
we practice a lot we try to talk about
what we practice when we practice
through our screens we practice through
our retros and we practice through our
reviews of what we're doing
so that we can find a way to get to the
agile compliance and this risk
operations
and then we say through that as we're
learning we never stop learning
we never stop learning about how we
manage our backlog how we prioritize
and why it's important to prioritize and
that's the integration of people
that's the communication along the way
that actual communication that you have
to get there
and value those people over processes
you have to value change over a plan
a compliance is a plan and it tells you
to do one thing
but we want to value the change so how
do we change to meet the compliance
to manage our risk and be able to
prioritize and through that we take the
time to innovate
and adapt our processes so they fit
better the next time and they fit
better into the things that we're trying
to do as we move forward and i can't see
ah there we go and the last one is we
have to advocate i talked about
advocating b will be the street
you have to constantly go out there and
convince others if we're not doing it
ourselves
if we're not enthusiastic and passionate
about the process of our security
then we're not going to be able to
convince other people right because
everybody's passionate about their own
they're passionate about what they're
doing it's building that passion into a
broader view that we're passionate not
just about our thing
but we're passionate about delivering
value to the organization
we deliver that value through convincing
others that compliance is a good thing
that getting to this agile compliance
that it's not going to slow them down
security is not going to break them but
it's going to move them forward to the
right pieces
that they need to deliver success uh all
along the way
uh and with that we have to build
relationships over processes i mean
that's agile one
in pro building those relationships
takes time and building those
relationships in a secure manner takes
time
so that they trust us as experts that
they trust that we're coming to them
with the right things
that we're coming to them with the right
notes and as we have those notes
we're moving forward and doing our
things and sometimes that means doing
the compliance stuff behind the board
right
they want to talk about having a demo
they want to talk about having what the
next functional software delivery is
and all you've done is address how
they've done the controls but when
you've automated those things
you've taken that work off of the
development plate you've taken that work
off of the coding plate
your success is that you've given them
more time to do the functional software
uh and granted that doesn't demo well uh
but it helps to build the relationship
when you come back and say hey you know
what we're good and you don't have to do
it as often
because we've done one of these things
and so
as we move forward from that one of the
things i like to talk about is being
king for the day right everybody likes
to think about
what would i do if i was in charge how
would i make things better immediately
what would i immediately fix to make it
to the next step to make sure that we
were actually compliant
that we managed our risk that we were
delivering effective processes
for the way and here move security
processes
and i want to move security processes to
the left i want to move as much to the
left as possible
and i want to move them to the left so
that i can integrate software so i can
make things quicker so that i can allow
humans to do more human things
because we're automating more things
along the process
and that automation is key in getting
those results
in being able to flood the
uh the auditors or the inspectors with
the degree of data to which you're doing
these things
we talked about being able to do a
continuous integration continuous
delivery but part of that is continuous
monitoring
that everything that comes out of that
pipeline delivers an artifact
and every one of those artifacts has
potential uh security value or not
security value but compliance value
and being able to manage those things to
show compliance
all the way across the process and being
able to understand what's coming out of
your pipeline
to show that process uh to expedite that
security and
onboard the people effect uh
the better i can integrate the better i
can move the security to the left
uh the better process i have in getting
the right data in the right place at the
right time
i had a story that was sliding in mind
but we continue moving that that
pipeline up and
that's the speeds up in the pipeline
to get our our process in the right
place where we need to go
then next we want to be able to move 30
checks to the right
so both as we say move security to the
left we want to move
security to the right because we want to
have
compliance as acceptance criteria right
we want to have
security to the right to the fact when
they're done they're thinking about it
and saying hey i'm done
and this is good because it includes
security it includes security all the
way
all the way is the process is being done
how do we get the the devs to include
that how do we talk to them enough that
they think about security
as part of the process they think when
they want to include something they come
to us and say hey
i need to include this and i want to
have security and that talks about trust
and that talks about people that talks
about interactions
you used to hear ronald reagan talk back
in the 80s you used to say trust but
verify
you have to trust but verify so we trust
all our developers we trust that they're
going to do the right things and we
verify through the tools and we verify
through that knowledge
and we verify through scans one of the
processes we put in is
they do all their scans in the pipeline
and one that when they've done their
scans and when they've done their checks
and when it's all done and it's gone
into delivery we're ready to pull that
into production
the next step is we go back and run our
own scans against it we
run our own scans in the process is it
sitting in production waiting for that
next poll
so that doesn't slow them down it
doesn't stop them but it's a
verification
that we verified that our process is
matched up against their process and you
know what the numbers they got from
their tools are the same as the number
weeks
numbers we got from our tools and that's
how we do things effectively
that's how we do things uh in the right
way so that we make sure that security
is doing the right things and security
is doing the right processes
and those are integrated processes those
processes take everybody those processes
take
uh the right value to build value for
the organization to stick to our goals
to stick to our vision move
uh one of the personal pet peeves i have
is you always talk to people when people
say the meeting is boring
meeting is important i want less
meetings i don't want i don't want to
talk
all my meetings are boring in
a side point i don't think any meeting
is boring
i don't think any meeting where i can go
and learn something from the people
there
and being able to interact with the
people there and create value and create
a process
is boring if you go into the meetings if
you set an agenda for the meeting
or if the person has an agenda set then
you can get effective things done
through those meetings you can get an
effective process and you can learn
about the people and you can get better
interaction
you can get that collaboration you need
you can get that change you need
by talking about effective things and
that ties into the other half of
security that no one's issue is ever
unnecessary a lot of people
i don't want to worry about your issue i
don't want to worry about your issue
just like no meeting is boring
no one's issues are necessary everybody
has a reason they are putting their
issue forward and they have something
they need to get done and something
that's valuable for them
you need to be able to recognize their
value and you need to be able to
prioritize but you need to
address across the entire scope of those
factors
but there are things that we get done
to make things happen in a way the best
measures everybody and best helps
everyone
uh to move forward so we try to address
everyone's security concerns we try to
address everyone's security concerns
along the way
and make sure that we're talking about
how those things work
and what they have and what they need
and what their goals are um
one of the biggest pet peeves is people
will run in and they will go hey we have
this uh this new cve just popped
up and we have this critical
vulnerability on one of the systems we
use and
or one of the systems we're planning on
using and it's back behind all these vpn
firewalls but we haven't we have to
patch it right now
so well if you want to patch it you know
we know what the patch is do you have
any capacity passion
they say no we can't patch it for three
sprints but it needs to be patched right
now and this is a security problem
so well you know we've kind of already
had that discussion if you haven't
prioritized it you don't want to
prioritize it to right now
then it is a security problem let's talk
about it as a security problem let's put
it on our compliance center
but we're not going to fix it for three
sprints and if that's what we work with
you know that's what we work with as we
move forward
so we have to address everyone's
concerns and we can't be uh dismissive
about it
uh one of the other frameworks we have
in that same type of mindset one of the
things that's happened to me on occasion
is our engineer comes up with the same
type of question right he comes up and
says hey
we've got this great big cbe and we need
to fix it we need to worry about it
and you know what uh the security guys
aren't doing a good enough job you guys
need to be out there threat
you need to be looking at the new
malware you need to be looking at how
that stuff is coming at us
you need to be talking about our the new
threats and the new vulnerabilities of
the new processes
uh in our conversation back a lot of
times it's hey we talked about having
these the secure technical
implementation guides right these
basic standards of security that you
need to be able to do
and you guys can't get to the basic
standards and if you can't do the
basic part that we've been asking for
and i understand that you prioritize
we have functions that we need to
deliver but if the basics can't be done
how do we get to the advanced part to
move forward
and that's that deliberate practice
again that's working on those silver
practices
working on those deliberate practices
all through the process so that we can
manage our risk
on threat exposure and not just
vulnerability not just talk about where
it's open
but how do we reduce our exposure how do
we reduce that attack surface that's out
there
so we can manage our threat so we can do
our risk operation so that we can become
agilely compliant
and we can move along the way
so i know i'm short of a little bit
short of my hour time but i do have some
questions
so this is me this was agile compliance
and risk operations there's some of my
contact information
i'll go back and i think i've got
questions in a reverse order as we look
at them
so the first one is any framework
recommendations for standing up an
information security
uh assurance program uh obviously
there's good things for infosec all
along the way
uh being a government guy being a lot of
time in government
let's just move the window and create
christ from the third application
there we go this should be all clear
enough but if there's recommendations
i i like nist because i've been in the
government it's kind of overdone
but at least it gives you a good friend
gives you some good discussions for how
you stand up and how you think about
uh what the risk is and what the
vulnerability is
uh being an intel guy i look at
vulnerability as well and i start with
some of those vulnerability questions
and you start with things about um how
do i know
once you know how do you how do you
prove that if that's true or what do you
see next
and if you see something next uh the
next step is what are the assumptions
that you need to make that true
so nist 853 as i mentioned earlier is a
great one
for sending up that initial information
security assurance program
i'm sure if you look out there there's a
lot of different things sans institute
has a lot of good stuff
about how to stand up an information
security
program and work through so i work back
through
[Music]
questions working security
found tools that assist you in the
process there are
all kinds of tools that will help us
automate sonotype is a great one
it will do things we have been working
with salt to get a demo
extensively because salt will do a lot
of the automation for the infrastructure
and we'll find ways that can
automate the infrastructure but not just
automate the infrastructure but automate
the configuration management
to do some of those tedious processes of
keeping track of versions
keeping track of updates through
versions keeping track of
um
the compliance and the policy associated
uh
and not only that but we've talked with
some of the users themselves who've been
fairly happy with it
and they can put it in and we'll
institute a baseline configuration
on their system and track and return
everything to that baseline
configuration
and once it does if they had a custom
they can move it back and change it back
to what they had as that custom setup
and then you just manage it through that
type of process
um the yeah the tedious security
checklists are long i mentioned
nist 853 there's 19 families there's
over a thousand controls
uh some of it is just being able to talk
and having your folks be comfortable
with you that hey
you know what you really don't have to
answer all those questions or
in looking at those questions and you
being familiar with those questions you
can talk to the security folks about how
do you automate the tools in the
pipeline
they give you artifacts that answer
those tools for you so you can just pump
those
those answers into those checklists as
you move forward
uh quantifiable details in the federal
fiber space some of the kpis related to
compliance risk management
communicating the effectiveness of
scaling agile over waterfall
well so one of the biggest difficulties
in the government space that we see
is that the government
wants to be waterfall they have a large
bureaucratic process and they want to be
agile
when they say hey we want you to be
agile we want you to do this devops
thing
and that means you're going to deliver
our our new software our new functional
software that we're really excited about
and you're gonna deliver in three months
right so sure great
give me a full devops way to go we'll
deliver your software in three months
you give us all the resources we'll grid
they say well that's great here's all
the resources but by the way
here's all these paperwork standards
that you need to meet while you're doing
the resources
here's all these bureaucratic things
that need to be answered
while you go forward so we go into agile
we go into this process for our own
program and they say hey we need you to
be agile
we need you to start delivering we need
you to start delivering good stuff but
one of those first things we need to
prove that you're agile is we need
a 150 page system engineering management
plan that describes exactly how you're
agile
in every phase of the process before you
get a process up and running
so that is difficult when you manage it
obviously the the kpi the key
performance indicator
uh to compliance and risk management
is just that we're doing it that you're
making process that you're getting there
that you're getting things like scans
done that you're getting things like
uh integration done uh i mentioned we
took over from a previous company the
previous company had the contract for
about three years
in that three years they had not
delivered a a single release
uh not one they were still working on
the same version they had when they
picked it up three years previously
in the nine months our company has had
the contract
we delivered our first release our first
update they're not major releases right
minor releases
is what they're calling them uh about
three months in
six months after that we delivered our
second release about
five months uh and we're on our way to
delivering our third release
uh here in the next month and a half um
so while we
gripe about all the small things that we
have and all the problems we still have
the fact is that it has turned into
functional software and in addition to
that functional software
with the compliance we went into the
process where we have scans in the
pipeline
previous was doing development work but
they weren't doing a pipeline they
weren't doing any type of ci cd pipeline
and we're typically doing insect
management
now every time the code gets checked in
it does a full
code check it does that full stoner
queue with that that static analysis
and then we use a tenables a cast
framework to do scans on the overall
integration to making sure that it's
compliant with stigs and cves
at the far end and those scans come
every time
code is checked in and then built on a
nightly basis and then we do those scans
on a monthly basis to go back and check
that what we're building
actually matches or the the scans we're
getting from the pipeline actually match
the scans we've got to build
so those are some of the kpis we use
to move forward
at the fair risk management i don't
think i've seen the fair risk management
framework
um i will uh look it up
and take a look if you want to get me
email i'm happy to give you a response
back
i've seen a lot of stuff and a lot of
risk management boils down to that same
uh for me that that threat versus
vulnerability versus exposure
and there's a lot of things we can do
along the way to get there and a lot of
things we can
look at to manage those individual risks
but when we look at the risks
we still have to manage them effectively
we have to manage them effectively
based on our organization
uh as a devops ambassador i have to say
it manages
value right how do you deliver value for
your organization how do you get
security to a place
where you deliver effective value in
moving forward
okay
so how do we approach organization we're
senior leaderships focused on delivering
agile with no regard how their
organization is currently structured for
delivering software
how do you approach these conversations
uh well when the senior leadership is
your boss obviously
you approach them very carefully um
and that has to be the key and i think
it goes back to being the advocate
and saying the same things over and over
a part of that agile is that
transparency
and you need to be able to approach them
and say hey look you know what this
isn't working
uh and when they're not willing to
change
then you kind of do the best you can
sometimes
uh or you offer different suggestions
i've had a lot of good luck with
boston's in the past
but instead of saying hey we need to
change this and we need a plan for you
or i need an approach from you
is to suggest um you know here's what i
think
here's how i think we should do it uh
what do you think about that can you
give you some
some input on the changes and making
process that way
if you can't
agile should not be as defined by
the organization structure is by the
cultural mindset
if you're talking about how you hand off
information from one to the other
as was a process of reducing the number
of handoffs that you have or the dev ops
process of reducing the
process that you have maybe
one of the suggestions would be if you
look
at a the sre programs or site
reliability engineer to streamline some
of those things
maybe implementing or
enforcing a site reliability engineer
could help you get the champion
to make the changes where you needed to
make the changes uh i talked to her at a
speech last year at devsecops up in
austin
one of the individuals talked about
having a batman having a batman on their
sock team and every time the guy came in
it was bad
you called from the outside to get
somebody you got back whoever was there
for that week was batman right
and it's the same type of thing with sre
that you have an individual
whose job is to make things flow better
and that they do the restructuring they
present the restructuring and they make
sure that things flow through
or they just take it and they walk it
from place to place to make sure that
things get done
and the way they need to get done and i
think as you increase the value
you've gradually convinced the senior
leadership that the agile thing is
better
and that you're increasing their value
when they give you some space to do
these type of things
uh as i mentioned with government uh
one of those challenges is um
when they implement devops for the first
time and i've been in the two different
organizations
i've seen it twice the first thing they
really need to do is they need to say
all right
you're going to be agile we're going to
do this thing and we're going to do this
flow with devops
but here's your first three months plan
your sprints but i don't need anything
delivered right i have no expectations
other than that you build your teams you
do the bottom up organization you figure
out how your teams are going to work and
figure out how the process is
unfortunately a lot of organizations
don't have time for that
but it does speak to the effectiveness
of creating your own dojo where you can
focus on those things where you can
bring the people out for a while or
bring a team out
and have them focus on a very specific
thing which is training
and learning how they should interact
and learning how they need to interact
with other folks
um somebody tell afterwards we uh
i don't think i have any more questions
we'll move things over to the uh the
other track
we'll move it over to track two if
somebody has any more questions for me
i'll be happy to take them there
i'll be hanging out thanks again to
b-sides for giving the opportunity i
really enjoyed the chance to speak
uh hopefully you all enjoyed it as well
um and i will return it to the uh
the present so that he can have control
and he can out the next person get set
up for their presentation
thank you very much i appreciate your
time
you