well thank you for the introduction um
yeah i am uh aaron rubesh my
presentation was going to be all over um
i just kind of threw the name out there
i figured it fit with what i'm going to
present to you guys um
i knew i didn't know what i was doing
but now you do and so the gist of that
is basically i learned security the hard
way
i got into it um
when i was younger uh unknowingly
really and i just started
you know going through online resources
and
going through the the fire hose like
like was mentioned in the previous
prison
presentation and really trying to learn
everything on my own and there is a lot
of information that comes from that
and so i i told myself if i could ever
help
anyone else learn security i hope that
they don't have to
go through the massive amounts of
information like i had to just to get to
where they want to go and i and i hope
that this this presentation
really helps to clear up kind of
what it is that you should know getting
into security
what are some what are some uh i guess
technical
goals that you should try to achieve
um going into your first job or
or going into school or just just
setting for yourself if you just want to
do it as a hobby you know what are what
are some of those technical goals
that you should kind of prepare for um
when you're really trying to get into
this stuff because it is a lot
there's a lot of different tracks in
security there's a lot of information to
go through
and it can be overwhelming to someone
and i i truly believe that if you have
any type of knack for technology you can
do well in cyber security
um but the thing that scares a lot of
people is just the sheer amount of
information
um in the stuff that i guess a lot of
people expect you to know
if you look at any job applications and
stuff out there you see
all of these crazy requirements for
everything and it's
that scares a lot of people off when
when really you you can get by with
with a lot less than what's uh than
what's required
so i hope i hope this presentation
really serves as a is a good starting
point for for someone
getting new into security that wants to
make this their career
um and if you if you've been in it for a
while maybe maybe it'll serve as a
refresher
maybe it will kind of um
remind you of some of those skills that
you kind of put to the side and you
didn't pick up on that that you should
get back into
so a little bit about me
so currently i am a software developer i
am not
in a security role per se but i
previously
was a penetration tester and i worked on
an application security team
i live in houston and
um so i guess one of the questions might
be is why is this guy talking to me
about security if he bailed from
security um
i didn't bail out of security i
whenever i learned security i also
learned programming at the same time i
taught myself both skills
and i i feel like they they really go
hand-in-hand because you wouldn't have
the insecure software if you didn't have
uh or you wouldn't have the security
vulnerability if you didn't have
secure software um people are a portion
of that but
you get the drift um in my in my roles
as a
uh as a corporate penetration tester
one of the things i noticed um was that
the tools really suck
uh well i hated the tools i hated using
the tools and um
i always thought that that's that's some
place that could be improved greatly so
i looked for a
company that was doing security tool
development
um and i joined them and now i'm
helping build uh security tools so still
kind of in security but
more of a software dev now i started off
with security
really before i really knew what i was
doing um i used to play a lot of video
games like like mo
like most kids um and i
really wanted to be better than others
at those games but i didn't want to put
in the work
so i started developing automation tools
um cheats hacks exploits
i started making brute forcers for some
of the games i played to break into
other people's accounts do all the stuff
that they uh that they worked hard for
um yeah sorry if that ever happened to
you i don't do that stuff anymore
um but to do that i had to learn
basically reverse engineering how to
um how to debug an application that i
didn't have source code
for read different variables inside the
memory
uh and then call different things um
that i wanted to do or that i wanted to
automate
and for brute forcing it's same thing as
you know
um john the ripper does or
other other password crackers and stuff
out there um but just developing that
from scratch not really knowing that
that's
you know kind of involved in security it
wasn't until later on when i started
college that i actually
saw those skills that i was using and
said hey this is actually a pretty
decent
um pretty decent career avenue
and so i i jumped on that train and
i got a degree in uh computer
information systems and i focused on
security as like a hobby and
all the tool sets and stuff on the side
and that's where i got to where i am
today
so um yeah so
i basically just want to get into like
the skills that i see that are valuable
for someone getting into security
that i really in my experience my my
couple years of experience
that i see like my peers
insecurity lacking
it's pretty crazy that um that a lot of
people in
in this field now and i know there's a
there's a lack of talent
um but there's a lot of people who who
don't have some of these basic skills
and it's
it's it's sometimes not a tool issue
it's sometimes
just a lack of the fundamental knowledge
um
and it will lead you to less you know
false positives and then better reports
and stuff like that so
uh the biggest thing that i always tell
people
to learn when you want to get into
security is networking
what is a packet how does it traverse a
network
how does a switch switch the switch the
packet to
you know whatever devices how does it
how does a router work how does a
firewall work
um just basic like network plus
ccna level networking knowledge
um it's it's really crucial in this
field um you have so many
so many exploits and stuff that happen
remotely now or the all the good ones
anyway or ones that you can
basically use from a remote perspective
that you can
use to get into something that you don't
have physical access to
and to do that you need to know how
how you know those devices are
communicating on a network level
what uh what type of protocols are being
sent
um what that looks like whenever you
whenever you take a
uh packet sniffer like wireshark tcp
dump something like that
and you export the the pcap and you
and you're reading it you know what is
that what does that information mean
and then how can you edit that
information to get it to do with do what
you want
you take some of the some of the network
level exploits out there right now
um that are just you know uh basically
at the protocol level you know editing
different fields in
a specific protocol that's going to make
something some device on the other end
communicate ineffectively or cause an
exploit
and you you learn how to build that
stuff yourself
so really you know how to read a pcap is
crucial
what the network devices do and then how
do they do them
how does the operating system do
networking
how does your linux machine route
packets how does it
assign ip addresses to different
interfaces
how does uh how does the iptables
firewall work
um if you've used something like pfsense
before how does that stuff how does the
packet filter and bsd work
um and really the best way to learn this
stuff is to
you know try to build your own router
you can do that with just a uh
you could set up a linux virtual machine
set up a couple other virtual machines
with it and you can build your own
network turn on ip forwarding
and there are some iptable rules in
there and you can actually
have a functional router that you built
yourself and
without really needing something else
really getting into the stuff
and actually playing around with it
you're going to learn a lot
and it's going to make you a better
a better penetration test or better uh
blue team if you if that's what you want
to go into about a purple team
player um it's really going to
really going to make you stand out more
when you when you're able to analyze
this information
and and really know what's going on
the uh second second skill set is is
operating systems
um really you need to learn how to
effectively use windows linux
and mac um i used to just
completely bash on windows wherever it
uh wherever i saw it
um i never i never liked using it i
hey i just hated it but really once you
once you really get into it you know
windows is everywhere
and it's something that you need to
learn how to use effectively you need to
learn how to do the things that you want
to do
in windows because you're not going to
escape it
and you really
need to turn that into something that
you could take advantage of
so by doing that you know
you can more effectively discover
exploits on your own you can more
effectively execute
exploits um and execute uh
different penetration tests and um
assessments and stuff like that
so uh along with those skill sets you
want to learn how to like troubleshoot
and inspect the operating systems you're
working on so
just figuring out okay what type of
processes are running on this machine
what type of services are running on
this machine
um what type of uh what type of
applications are listening on different
ports you know when you when you
when you run like an nmap scan on a
a networked device you're used to just
you know
tossing a couple flags into an nmap
into nmap and then running it on a
running it against the machine and then
seeing what
what ports are open what what it thinks
is there right but how do you do that
from
from the inside right if you're already
on the machine you want to see hey maybe
something's listening on something that
i didn't pick up from externally
what what may be listening here that i
can that i can find that i can maybe
take advantage of um how do you find
what tools are available maybe
you are on a machine and you're trying
to find a way to pivot somewhere else
how do you do that without knowing
what's available to you on the machine
you're working on
maybe you have a c compiler installed
maybe you only have bash available maybe
you have python installed
what can you utilize to help get you to
the next machine that you actually want
to get
to um
and that's really the only
there's multiple ways to learn this
stuff
you can go for like an a-plus or
something like that or read through
those books but really
it's going to require you to just
install some virtual machines
or solid on physical hardware if you
want and just
get into it and just start playing
around with the stuff and really
and really learning how all of the stuff
works you know
set a goal for yourself say hey i want
to set up a vulnerable
web server and you learn how to
create a web server or on linux or maybe
windows and you host a vulnerable one or
maybe you um
add some like known exploit exploitable
configurations of that stuff and
you set that stuff up on your own um to
to figure out really how how the whole
process of uh
how that works um
third skill that uh that i see really um
a lot of people lacking is just a
general programming sense of programming
knowledge a lot of people want to come
to security that they
and they don't really want want to
program that much they want to run some
tools
run some
they want to run some scripts and just
analyze some output and that's fine
um if you want to do that but if you but
i feel like if you really want to
want to learn you know what you're doing
learning some programming is
is going to be crucial to that i always
say learn c
and then learn something like ruby or
python
and that's because everything's built on
top of c
operating system kernels are built on c
most of your tools on linux are built in
c most your tools on windows are
probably built in dot net now but a lot
of them were built in c
um and really everything you want to do
on an operating system on any operating
system you can interface it through c
if you want to build a packet sniffer
you want to create your own packets to
send across the network you can do that
and see yeah you can yeah there's python
libraries and stuff available for that
as well
but you have everything available to you
already
if you're using c um
by doing that you know you gain a you
gain a deeper understanding of how
you know other applications on the
operating system are actually using
those libraries as well
whenever you whenever you kind of learn
the low-level programming the system
level programming like that
and you understand kind of the linux
apis and the windows apis
you understand that how how other
applications out there
are always going to be using the same
function calls that um that you would be
using if if you wanted to write a
program that did
something similar right and you can use
that to your advantage you know that an
application that's communicating
to the internet or to some other
networked device is going to have to
create a socket it's going to have to
then send bytes across that so by
knowing that
you can you can understand that um
that if you go in and you actually look
for where it's calling those functions
you can actually see
okay hey this is what data it's sending
this is how it's sending data
maybe if i can intercept that or rewrite
what it's uh
rewrite it what it's sending i could
discover a new exploit or i can
um i can figure out another way uh
to get it to do what i want um it's
things like that that you that you start
to understand that
that software is really um it really is
what
what you make it to be and even if
someone else made it you can still
do what you want with it if it's on your
machine
and this is uh this this leads to a more
easily tran
more easy transition into like reverse
engineering if that's what you want to
do
um preferably that's that's the stuff i
enjoy uh debugging applications finding
my own exploits um
and doing stuff like that is is kind of
what
what i'm mostly interested in and that's
that's where i think uh
you know the low-level programming stuff
really helps that because you're
actually able to analyze
what those uh what those functions are
what they're doing in that application
physical networking and not like you
know just cabling up stuff but actually
growing your community
whenever you have a stronger community
and a larger community of people who you
can reach out to
you're going to just you're going to
have a better baseline of knowledge to
begin with because you have
people who you can more easily ask
questions to that can tell you
either yes you're doing this the right
way or yes you're doing this wrong way
or
you're looking at this the wrong way um
they can help you
uh get out of the weeds with a uh uh
with an issue that you may be
you know uh wrapped around into too much
that's not really going to um
to get you anywhere faster than you
would have done it on your own
um i like to say it's it's good job
security um
and not in a sense that hey you're going
to stay at your current job for
for a for a good long time but it's
better job security and knowing that
you have people looking out for you
i can't almost i mean it's got to be
every day you know
you see on twitter in security twitter
anyway
that um you know someone's saying hey i
lost my job here's a resume and then you
see you know
30 minutes to an hour later people
helping them out and having
four to five job offers in a day i mean
stuff like that that's really
that that you get from having a good
community that you don't get otherwise
and i learned this you know in the past
couple years a lot better than i did
before because i was always kind of the
guy that wanted to take everything solo
i always wanted
to figure it out on my own and really
try and just do it do it myself i always
wanted to figure it out my own
and never and never really take help
from others and
i've had to i've had to struggle against
you know thinking that way and get out
of that mindset and really embrace
um having a larger community and um
really communicating better with others
and contributing back
to communities invest in the education
of others you know
don't just if you see someone asking for
um for help with someone or they or
someone wants um
want some assistance doing something
don't don't think that it's oh that's uh
that's too easy for for me to really
care about someone else will help them
you know
or maybe maybe you're afraid of being
wrong
when you're trying to help someone um
or you see someone just struggling with
a with a certain topic
that you know a little bit more about um
you know just
take five ten minutes out of your day to
just help someone out
help help at least lead them to the
right path um and not just
and not just ignore it it's gonna make
you feel a little better about yourself
and it's gonna help
the community um as a whole um
because we're all we're all a community
we're all
we're all in this together we're not
we're not fighting against each other or
anything
um you know the more the more people we
have investing back into
into the education of others the better
and more uh
more knowledgeable our community will be
as a whole
um radiating on what was said in the in
the previous uh presentation as well you
know attend
ten more conferences attend the local
ones if you have uh b-sides locally
um unfortunately the houston one isn't
that great i don't think
um but uh
but you know attend attend on a couple
uh you know a couple cities away you
know fly out of state and go to a
different
uh go to different conference um go to
go to some of the larger ones go to
small ones
um you know just just find other find
find ways to go out and meet some people
you never know who
you're gonna meet and uh and what type
of knowledge they're gonna have and what
what type of uh what type of
opportunities that it might present you
um another school skill set i like to uh
i like to add in here is don't just
learn a tool
learn how to learn how it works don't
just you know get on a windows machine
and run
mimi cast whatever you want to do to try
and get some passwords right
learn how that tool is actually doing
what it's doing
um because chances are that whenever a
tool like that gets fixed
there's going to be some code changes
around where that
where that tool is hitting and if you
know that code is changing in a certain
area you can also use that to your
advantage of finding
ways to get around what was changed and
by knowing what
what kind of type of areas of an
application you're already targeting
uh it kind of reduces the time it's
going to take for
for like a new x-ray to come to come
about or a new way of uh
or a new way of um of executing and
getting the same functionality
is gonna it's gonna come about so um
you're going to uh you're also going to
discover a lot more ways
of of doing the same thing
um i like to say you know uh
whenever i wanted to get into like wi-fi
hiking and
man in the middling right um everyone
just says okay go go buy like the
pineapple right but
you don't really need that you can do
that with just a raspberry pi and a
uh a wi-fi adapter you can do
all of that you're on your own just by
learning how the tools actually work
um and making you know a more reliable
product or making something that you
know you can rely on your own for
instead of having to rely on a specific
piece of software hardware
it will also allow you to um to
contribute back to other tools
so maybe there is a tool that that's
really popular that you like using or
one that's just you know that's not very
popular that's uh
that you like you lose using and you
want to
help them out and you want to contribute
something that you found
with it you know you can contribute back
to that tool and make it better which is
going to then
go back to making our community a more
knowledgeable
more knowledgeable community
so a lot of uh a lot of people al also
ask me
you know how do you get all the hands-on
experience um how do you go
get the first job that's you know saying
hey i want you to have
uh you know five years of splunk
experience and um
and uh you know knowledge of firewall
systems and um
and different ids ips's and how to write
you know the most
intense uh snort filters and stuff like
that so um you really
it it sucks that that employers would
ask
a newcomer um to have such experience
but that's really unfortunately the
the place we're in right now um
and really i'm not saying you don't
stand a chance if you don't
try to create that hands-on experience
yourself um but it will make
it more likely that you'll you'll get an
opportunity from someone like that
and there are some great there are some
great employers out there that actually
invest in your education
and um and
don't care that if you that you know
everything off the start
but there's also a lot of crappy ones
out there that
are going to want you to have that and
it just
in my opinion um if you're not kind of
the person that's that's
that's going to rely on just the
employer being a good person
um really you know it doesn't hurt to go
out and create your own hands-on
experience and in fact it's going to
make you
a better more knowledgeable security
expert
by doing so so i always tell i always
tell people
you know build out a build out a
full-scale vm network like act like you
have a production environment
that has a you know a database server a
web server a couple application servers
maybe an email server
you can build that all out in vms now on
moderate hardware
and just try to just try to just try to
attack it and see
see what you can find see what you learn
in the process of just setting all that
up it's going to make you it's going to
make you a lot better just
just by going through that process
launch attacks on networks that
launch attacks on like your built out
networks anyway
that really allow you to not not have to
just hit
a vulnerable machine so maybe you were
used to doing like ctfs like hack the
box or
doing uh the vulnerable vulnerable
machines or something like that
and you are used to just spinning that
stuff up
and launching an attack at it and just
going crazy
maybe try putting a firewall or
something in between that or maybe try
putting an ids between that so that
whenever you're trying to attack those
things you're not
just going straight for the vulnerable
machine you're trying to get past
other obstacles along the way
um and the reason i say that is because
of the time it's never going to be as
easy it is
is in a ctf um or
or any of the other challenges out there
like that
there's always going to be some type of
security control well not always there
are some
places that don't have it but it more
just expect there to always be
some type of security controls in the
way blocking your
blocking you from doing you know the
exploits you want a lot of people come
in here thinking
you know i all i have to do is run these
these couple scripts
um i'm going to then be able to
uh be able to you know exfil some
passwords and then
and then i'm going to be able to pivot
on to the next one and you're not
because you're going to have
an entire army of devices actually
blocking you from doing
what you expect and that that throws a
lot of people off
um because they're not used to dealing
with that so actually spin that stuff
up you're on your own and practice it
and then you know
a great way to test if you know how to
harden systems and harden
your networks uh something that i did a
couple times
throw out like a a open
ftp server on the internet and just you
know see what hits it see how long it
takes for malware to get dropped on it
um then try to add like some security
controls to that
and see if you can harden it further and
keep prevent that stuff from hitting it
do the same for like a web server have
some
you know database set up and just
putting it on the internet
is a surefire way of having someone
scanning you and someone trying to hit
you within
probably 20 minutes um i think it's the
longest i've gone
of putting something online and not
having anyone hit it yet is probably
about 20 minutes so
um do it in uh find a find a cheap cloud
hosting provider and you know spin up a
five dollar
droplet somewhere and spin up a server
and just see how long you can go
with uh uh without getting hit or
um and trying to make improvements to
that and try to
prevent that from happening so
you