we're getting started close enough uh
craftsman dan lawrence um everybody
should be able to see my screen
and the webcam right now uh so we can
i'm gonna get started uh we'll give
people one more minute or so since it
still says 359 here for me
oh there we go all right four o'clock we
can get started
uh so thanks for listening to the last
talk of the day my talk on open source
supply chain so my name is dan lawrence
i'm doing a session live stream team
here in
austin texas i'm a software engineering
lead at google
and i've been working in open source for
a long time now
i've been involved in the cloud and
containers um
open source space for a while but before
that i've also been doing open source so
a little close to about a decade now so
open source security and open source
supply chain security is a topic
that's near and dear to my heart and it
really keeps me up at night with some of
these terrifying
attacks uh so recently in open source
i've been kind of working the techcon
convenience delivery open source project
to help start that and i'm still a
maintainer in me today
but i'm also working on a larger
industry-wide effort to help secure the
open source supply chain
uh both of which i'll talk about in a
little bit more detail later in the
presentation
um i don't know about everyone here this
is one of my first virtual events um so
i'm hoping to have a little bit of fun
i'm trying to make it
interactive um we're gonna be doing a
couple of quizzes
and polls later on where i get to ask
you some questions and i want to see
your answers um
in chat in the discord so um there's
everybody should see the discord channel
track two in the clouds
i'll just type there and once we get to
that part
i'm ready to type their answers and
please try to
keep this interactive and be honest this
is the judgment for the
talk
okay all right let's jump in
um so open source is under attack i'm
going to start by covering the state of
open source and
supply chain security um unfortunately
it's not good today
you're under attack i'm going to cover
uh how's under attack
by who and i think you can protect
yourself today
and then at the end i'm going to talk
about some of the larger efforts going
on to help solve this as an industry and
how you can get involved to help out if
you're interested
let's start with the problem with open
source i don't want to batch open source
open source is amazing
most of my career using and building it
i'm sure everyone else here interacts
with every single day
but we do need to face the facts having
a problem with open source
helps our security is not a solution and
it's not how we're going to solve them
i'm going to start off here with one of
those terrifying and depressing problems
today
i mean if you're not terrified by the
time this session is over
hopefully you can re-watch the recording
and to keep doing that until you
get terrified all right let's start out
here with
the first quiz um i don't know if
everybody here remembers what this is
um but this was a usb flash drive
um before dropbox google drive and cloud
storage is how people actually use the
transfer files between computers
um so first question is hopefully people
are
listening within the discord
if you found one of these on the street
would you pick it up and plug it into
your personal laptop
i don't want to answer here zero no
no on the usb all right good um okay
so it sounds like a little bit of a
silly question but let's
go a little bit farther with this if you
found one of these outside of your
office
would you pick this up and take it into
your office and plug into a work
you know um okay even less so
okay start to see where this is going
okay so let's pretend you work in
a data center not even allowed in the
door so let's pretend you work in a
production data center
throughout the server maintenance in
that data center and you found one of
these on the sidewalk outside there you
could take it and plug it into your
server running your databases
hopefully people start to see where this
is going and hopefully people have
received some kind of training
on this from their company and what to
do so everybody doesn't get these
answers on the fly
um this sounds like a silly uh question
but
the reason this has been happening to
everybody so strongly by our security
teams and our
training departments because this is a
real type of attack um this has been
used dozens and dozens of times
even at the international level if
anybody remembers the stuxnet worm
used to disrupt uranium enrichment that
attack was allegedly carried out by
dropping thumb drives near facilities in
iran
to reach an air gap um i even had a
little bit of a run into this once
uh and learned how seriously my company
takes this type of threat
i was living in san francisco back in
the time
getting some people in chat saying they
can't see the presentation can anyone
see it
okay so some people can
alright um
sounds like it's working for some people
okay uh all right sounds like there have
been some intermittent problems
hopefully people can get that resolved
um yeah so i was living in san francisco
in 2013 and a friend of mine had just
gotten
a brand new drone uh we went to fly it
near the bay bridge
in barcelona in san francisco drone
technology was a little bit new at the
time he didn't really know how to fly it
that well so you got a little bit out of
control with the drone
and ended up crashing into a building
across the street and landed on a
balcony of that building
if anybody's kind of familiar with that
area the google office where i worked is
right there
i started looking and realized that you
can crash the drone into my office
so i went in um got my badge and wanted
to look for the drone
but it turned out our security team had
already confiscated the drone
i explained what had happened and they
agreed to give the drone back to my
friend but they were still a little bit
worried because using
pictures or spy on the office so they
wouldn't give it to uh they would get
the drone back unless he showed them
that he wasn't taking photos
uh but and this is the part that really
taught me how
seriously people take attacks like this
is that they wouldn't plug his sd card
into their own computer
that's not scary they were this i mean
him go home and get his own laptop
plug that in and show them the pictures
on it that would have been a kind of
crazy attack vector but
don't plug anything you don't trust into
your computer because the overall
message no matter how you find it
that's how scary this is it's scary it
should be
so what does any of this have to do with
uh open source security what do drawings
and usb drives and or any which would
have been
broken source today all right so time
for the next quiz back to the chat
um what did we learn and what can we
take away from these other examples
what is the difference between plugging
in one of these usb flash drives
am i tying on a sidewalk into your
laptop
and typing this command api install
express
so your npm is that network management
what is the difference between these two
people meant it to plug place answers
see some people are thinking about it
trust in the contents of the files
nothing
not as much as you hope but a little bit
of social care okay
um so here's my answer i think most
people are on track a little bit
um my answer is only one of them says
production when you plug a flash drive
into your laptop it's kind of limited to
that laptop
but if you're typing if you have install
express and packaging add up into an app
that gets deployed to production
it's gonna eventually run with a whole
much more privilege um people will stay
on track though
uh in general we rely on social proof
and hopefully
uh assuming other people have looked at
those files and trust them a little bit
and uh hopefully nothing bad happens
when we take this code that we've never
seen before
and run it on our computers or worship
data centers
um i don't really want to make an npm
here this is a problem with
package manager pretty much in open
source today so let's jump and do
another bit of a demo with a couple more
quizzes
so now i will try to tab away from
implementation and
cool people should see my uh
my id here so uh this is a demo of go
programming which is what i use for most
of my program today
and it suffers from most of these same
problems so i'm going to show an example
here
of how a supply chain attack might get
carried out and how hard it is to find
this is a little toy project it's called
numbers and it tells you whether or not
a number
tells you whether a number is even or
odd so you can see how this works here
go over on main.gov
and we can see the implementation um
this takes the number
as input and it uses this uh percent
sign which is the modulo operator um
to tell if it's even or uh um this might
be a little bit unfamiliar to you
um and my colleagues let me switch
over here um here's the github repo
decided that the module operator was
just hard to maintain
so i got this pull request um to switch
from using that custom logic to using an
open source library here
okay this is what the pull request looks
like coming into my package
um some changes to our go module
definitions
um an import statement and then it
switches over here
cool so this package is called odd as a
function
uh tell us something is even around um
if i wasn't being that
um conscientious i might just merge this
and yeah i recommend it
but let's pretend i know about open
source supply chain attacks and i want
to
take a look here and see
what's in this code before i merge it
i'm going to take this
and open this up on github is odd
so we can see all the source code here
it's got some tests which is awesome
um i didn't have tests before
i'll check out the implementation here
nothing
uh too tricky just calling cannoli
library
is even um and now
if i want to be extra extra careful we
can even take a look at the
xeno library also tests
all right we're being way more careful
than 99 source maintainers probably
would be
we still don't see any problems so let's
uh take this one extra step so let's
actually
check out that branch and run it and see
what happens
and check how to use library now let's
do the same thing
go run go for
oh um see here is princeton starting at
crypto line
so even though i looked at all that code
somehow a crypto miner got bored
how did that happen does anyone have any
guesses in the chat
before i show how this slipped in
and then uh how you might help detect
this and prevent it
let's add crypto code and all those date
units i looked through
where did that come from
overloading synonyms and code stranger
urls imported as a dependency
um i assume i will go to synonyms we're
talking about one of those attacks or
something uses unicode
characters um that's another organelle
that's not what i did
here reported as a dependency
technically
the only two that got pulled in were
it is because it was hidden in a
different version of
the independency so i can show how you
might have caught this
uh there are two main ways uh one
is we just actually go back and look
through here you can see that
we're using this specific version of the
is even library
so when i did my spot check i only
looked at the top
but it was hidden so we can take that
commit
and you can see that that one added a
file to do once you print online
thankfully you left this lock statement
in just if you were able to detect it
it was then deleted right after that so
if you just look through the current
state of the video repository you might
never see these things
to figure out what's actually getting
merged here um i generally recommend
vendoring dependencies
so you can do google vendor
then instead of just the uh descriptors
here or
the urls that are the trackpad and
follow um it actually pulls the code in
it's going to get used so we can go
through here and see
the util file start crypto so that
actually checks these dependencies in
your repo
so if we did that
[Music]
around
and then if we go back to github we'll
review our pull request
even though github hides these gifts by
default if we um they're at least now
part of it
so if we actually open up all these
files we would see cryptoliner in here
that would make it a lot easier to catch
all right so i'll jump back to the
presentation
awesome uh so i just showed drill
modules i've talked about npm as well
this is a problem with every package
like i said um gold modules
aren't all bad they do have some cool
security features um
but they're not perfect uh code review
only shows the dependency metadata
unless you're using vendoring
that makes it hard to detect these
things um
uh and they go to you want a module
proxy to store code
from an intermediate location we were
able to find that in a github repository
that was reserved um if i had deleted
the commit and that repository would
have been even harder to find by going
through there
look at the go module approximate
directory restores things
um and with go and new effect
of an ecosystem number of dependencies
is growing pretty rapidly
um it's hard to take the time to review
each line in a large project
but it doesn't make it so you can skip
you're still taking arbitrary code or
basically picking up flash drives from
the sidewalk and plugging them in every
time you install a dependency that you
didn't look at it
um so to sum up this problem um we all
understand
that software and code review throughout
the software development process is
important because people will know to
take that spirit they've been working on
the team
but we've somehow let open source slip
through the cracks
um in general we hope that through
social trust i'm having many eyes on the
problem that stuff like this will get
caught before it affects us
but that's not always true these attacks
are becoming more and more common so the
chances of getting caught by one is
increasing over time
basically when everybody is responsible
for reviewing open source software
in many cases no one is responsible and
no one's actually doing it
um i showed how to review the source
code for go um and it's easier than a
lot of options
because dependencies and go modules are
just a source code
imagine what that might look like for a
language that packages uh
build artifacts like java or even iphone
or some of the other interpreter
language from the transformation step
between the gear repository source code
and the final thing you download
installed
let's take a look at python and what it
takes to trace something like this back
for a popular python module
so i'm going to jump back to
demo um
we are going to start out with the
requests library
in python forgot the url
if anybody has used python for
a while um you're probably familiar with
the requests library
this is how most um
http requests are made by this is one of
the most popular libraries
so if you go to the python package index
and you type pip install requests
this is roughly what you're going to get
we can look through here this tells us
that the source code for requests
is here on github you can click over to
that to see the source code
but if we download this through pip
we're not actually going to get it
break in this file um how do we
know that what's in this file came from
this repository
um well the short answer is that we
really don't we're trusting the
maintainers of this to faithfully
upload uh the build artifact from this
github repository over to python package
index
um requests is huge and popular
so we'll get kind of a pretty good
feature that's what's happening
if we look inside file
and you can see that they actually have
a script here to publish
a release it installs another dependency
which if you kind of have an adversarial
already had on
you might get a little suspicious but
it's not something called time
of running some build commands you
shouldn't want to upload that
so if you were able to project some code
into twine you actually have a chance to
modify this code before it gets uploaded
how do we know that this is what
maintainers actually ran them we have no
idea
but since it's python we can still kind
of do some basic verification
thumb and download and keep varying so
what would it look like to actually have
to do something like that for python
we've got a couple scripts here so i
don't have to
remember all this bash time as i go but
we can download the source code from
github
um git clone and check out the specific
version we've looked at
open that up um and then we're also
going to download the published wheel
which is what a python artifact is
called
um and explore those and then we can
combine both of these and gift the two
directors
so for this one if we do it hopefully we
should see nothing
too drastically different now
download the source code um and then the
disk started okay so there actually are
uh some files that are only in the git
repository facebook
like kind of overplay it the document
directory
settings and stuff like that that you
don't necessarily need
um the main meat of this is the same
overall request for entry um so it is
possible
to verify these kind of things in python
and other interpret languages
but now imagine what it would look like
to actually do this every single time
you install the package
or for a language like java just get
packaged up into jars which are a lot
harder to
compose and inspect how many people out
there
are actually doing this stuff for every
packaging
and this isn't even really a full demo i
did this for the request package but if
you actually type
installed requests you're gonna get
probably a dozen or so packages the
request depends on
so taking the time to follow all those
packages back to their repositories
the exact versions that they got
downloaded from and comparing file by
file
isn't something that most people are
going to take the time to do
realistically you know each one of those
is a potential attack vector
into your application
let's try to jump back here
so these are all simple applications
that just had a couple dependencies
um even the request itself only has a
couple dependencies
to go from although one of the projects
that i spent a lot of time working on
most people um in the cloud of engineer
space and colleague whoever uses
kubernetes
one of the most active projects on
github this right here
is terrifying monstrosity chart on the
left
snapshot of the dependency graph of the
kubernetes project
taken a few months ago uh kubernetes is
built in the go
like i showed before and it does make
use of vendors it changes the
dependencies get checked into
the kubernetes source management system
um you can see how very deep and nested
all of this gets
in a large project
but even with the kubernetes i think
each one of these dependencies has a
whole bunch of other dependencies
and it takes a lot of time to start to
review these things
some of these are coming from
trustworthy sources and we don't need to
take as close a look
at stuff here from microsoft um this is
just a snapshot of a couple things
to finish
but there's something from a trustworthy
source like microsoft but then um a
whole bunch of basically just smaller
personal github repositories
um that are now being imported by these
treatment service attachments
think about how long it would take if
you just started working on
one of these projects to get um admin or
maintenance privileges
on these repositories where you can put
in any code you want
and wait long enough for the update
picked up and pulled into upstream
dependencies
um and making into larger larger
products
it's another small problem though um
even if we do we say we trust a couple
of these
organizations or large projects uh we
have no way to actually guarantee that
this came from microsoft
it could be making use of one of those
you are also wanting our typo spawning
things
he's one of those opposed actually one
of those unique characters that looks
like one
um there's no kind of public key or
assigning infrastructure for us to know
that these are coming from the people we
think they are
if you uh start to get excited and think
about a red team
scenario here if you just had a couple
months how long would it take you to
get maintenance privileges on something
like this you can merge code and
get malicious code into clusters all
over the world
this isn't really scalable today we're
viewing and preventing these things
new tools new practices and these new
systems to help solve this in a scalable
way across the industry
i'm going to talk about a little bit of
history and why now
open source has been around for decades
and decades
and decades um so why are we only
worrying about this today when people
have been copying around
and using it for so long um
your um overall kind of history of this
uh this attack has been known about
since
at least 1984 there was a paper
published called reflections on trusting
trust
it shows turtles all the way down here
even if you trust all the source code
that's coming in you also have to trust
all the tools involved
i mean this paper showed an even scarier
scenario where somebody
uh they could modify it as a compiler um
source code that could insert backdoors
and everyday programs that that compiler
built
um and there's some really funny stuff
there where they insert uh back doors
into the disassemblers and everything
too
so even if you use the disassemblers to
look for these back doors those
disassemblers have been compromised
they have no hyperloops so it's kind of
troubles all the way down if you don't
know how
the tools you use were built or the
tools that built those tools um
it's kind of a nightmare scenario
uh so people have known about these
attacks forever they have started to
accelerate though
which is the working part um in 2006
i got pretty worried and made a whole
bunch of security improvements
and a bunch of debian and red hat
package repositories were poisoned
people were able to insert malicious
packages right into the places that
everyone installs and their security
tools and competitors from
um 2010 there's a stuxnet where i might
mention before
to disrupt an international scale
um some similar attacks have happened on
criminal.org with one external
development
story and uh even
uh in the new baggage management space
um i
like to call out the docker one two
three three two
one attack um it didn't have a huge
impact
but it is pretty scary when you think
about what happened when docker was
first
gaining momentum and dr hoga was an open
source
uh repository for container it was a
group of people um i don't think they
were ever really
started publishing a whole bunch of
useful containers with
my sql tomcat coming some crypto
uh images were published on them they
did a good job of maintaining them and
keeping them up to date
for years and people started using
stuff in docker one two three three two
one then eventually
um they inserted put the lining into
these
container images slowly over time it
shows that if you're patient
and actually do useful work people will
build on you and
end up you the way open source is
supposed to happen and then you can
reach that trust by using that platform
you've built
to um inject ransomware or crypto mining
or all sorts of terrible things
there have been much others recently
like the webmin attack
that one was the build server compromise
so the ci system was used to publish
webmin
a popular remote administration tool for
servers was compromised
so every release had some code injected
into it to add a backdoor to a server
administration tool
and that was in a while for a while when
you start thinking about you know
resource supply chain um it's every
piece of
the way that this stuff gets delivered
to you it's not just the source code
it's also the build tools and both
systems and every one of those
is an attack factor it's really exciting
if you've got a red team on
uh really scary for anyone else
um some more numbers here just to show
the scale of this problem
um in 2020 has been a year full of
pretty bad news i might need to have
a few solid fire here and scare people
anymore but
uh supply chain attacks this year aren't
looking any better than everything else
um there are 11 million developers
running npm commands each month
grabbing packages from the internet and
installing it
um there's been an 80 percent increase
in supply chain attacks
in 2019 2020 isn't over yet but
seeing a similar increase so far
pretty much everyone is using open
source software whether or not you know
you are
um 97 of the company is using it in some
form
so pretty much everyone needs to be
worried about this problem
um and then there is the scale of code
sharing with things like
github and awesome package managers it
comes
more and more using other people's code
the average node project has 86
dependencies
that's just across all github so it's
small and large
many products i've looked at have one or
two orders of magnitude one
that getting pulled in every time you
add something you need to think about
the different attack factors here
opening up for people into your code
by any interpretation here this is
serious and getting even worse
again why now why are people only doing
this now and why is it rising
well the cost per hack and
the rest of software is increasing all
of us are either trying to protect
systems or doing our job we're closing
all the other doors people stopped
leaving servers just open to the
internet we're all using https um
most of the other common entry points
are getting
tougher so attackers will actually find
the easiest way to
the rise of open source at this point
it's probably the easiest place to
inject things
um not everyone uses uh not all software
is open source
and you have to technically have to
worry about these type of moves coming
in from paid vendors
but that's much harder than open source
so that's the easiest attackers
all right so now if the scary part is
over um
everyone can relax and start talking
about some reassuring things hopefully
um if you want to kind of jump out of
this and start looking at every line of
your dependency code in your application
i completely understand you don't have
to listen to the rest of this
um hopefully this will be recorded and
you can watch the rest later
but now it comes the optimistic part um
how you can protect yourself today and
what we're doing to
make this um harder at manage your level
how to protect yourself um thankfully
nothing here is
too complicated um you just need to
start protecting
your supply chain first you need to lock
down your own repositories
some basic stuff like enabling and
requiring two-factor authentication for
every one of your contributors
if someone you know an employee
intercompany or another resource
container that you trust
on the city of code if they're not using
two-factor authentication they could
have been compromised
so you need to start requiring everyone
to adopt basic security standards
require everything to go through code
review and actually take the time
to review the code that's coming in
whether it's yours or not
um this one is essentially this kind of
painful
reduce your dependencies uh dependencies
are great and
easy to get stuff done quickly but you
need to think about every dependency as
an attack evaluate if you really need
your home
using something great it's in hundreds
of non-great
uh second level dependencies that's a
problem
uh take that into account as you're
evaluating what to build on
then uh the even tougher part um it's
not tough
from a complexity perspective it's tough
it isn't painful
at times you need to audit your
dependencies um
track updates to them but you need to
review these updates just like first
party code
you need to go through everything
this isn't only about people inserting
malicious code
dependencies have bugs too sometimes
those bugs need to vulnerabilities to
get reported
cdus if you're not checking uh your
dependencies you have cbd databases um
then you have
a bunch of different supply chain
problems
then the final piece um making your cict
pipeline
observable so this is not so much about
protection but it's about
mitigation after the fact if you
aren't vlogging every single version and
every single bit shot
and every commit and every digest of
every artifact you're producing
then if something like this does happen
you're gonna have a much harder time
figuring out how
compromised you got um the stuff above
this is about trying to prevent yourself
from having a bad day
this bottom one is about uh making that
bad day not turn into a bad month if it
does happen
cicd system keeps all of these
august and then you can track down what
versions of your dependencies are in
production
and make it easier on yourself later
all right so i'm talking about uh some
stuff that's going on
that'll make these attacks harder and um
identity and software is a big one um
today
uh it's pretty common if you sign okay
commits
github you get a little badge like i
showed here at the top right saying
comment has been verified
um which is great it looks like insecure
but all that really says is this someone
generated
there and signed that it doesn't tell
you who did that
um just as someone did we need to get
beyond
just these signatures without another
source of trust or
pki key infrastructure um that verified
badge doesn't really mean anything um
for maintainers of open source projects
we need ways for them to share their
uh identity in the public keys that they
need to be using um this will help
prevent that tax where people screw for
pretending
but it will also make it easier for
maintainers to know whether or not a
contribution coming into an open search
project
it's going to be someone they trust or
not uh since these people are
overburdened
and barely have time to review the code
terribly hard today but there's a bunch
of work going on in the open source
git project itself to make it easier to
sign commits
today you have to use gpg which is kind
of clunky to generate key pairs
um but everybody already has says h can
set up
and push to github hopefully um and
there's some work we have to make it
possible to sign your new comments with
these ssh students instead of having a
manageable separate settings repairs
um in two factors everywhere thankfully
this is finally originally victory
across the industry almost every service
supports two-factor off
um but it's hard to check to see if your
contributors or other progress that
you're using
are using two-factor author you can
acquire it on your own project
but you can't tell if you're depending
on something that does not require
um if you're only independencies from
people even if you trust them and
they're not easy to factor off
um then that's a problem you need to
make this visible and kind of
sharing the projects with people that
aren't using two factors off into
setting up this basic
security protection and then like i
talked about
uh just a minute ago um better pki
infrastructure so that all known people
can share the public keys that they do
their work
so we can have more trust the work
that's being signed with these kids
moving beyond just that kind of
important verified symbol that doesn't
really give us much information
so i'll next step up from identity who
is typing things at their keyboard
we also have to start uh playing better
ways to trust the source code that we're
using
depending on if you take source code in
a binary form
you have very few tools to figure out
what code went into that binary what
tool is produced
there are some projects that have to
standardize a
software bill of materials s-bom is
that everything to search for their
software build materials
which will allow people to distribute
executables and binaries to describe
all the things that went into those
download random program
you can see exactly where it came from
in a trusted way
um this is coming from me uh hopefully
instrumented build systems that will
automatically generate these standard
formats once the api paper is
um and then tying that source grip back
uh once you can go from a binary to
source code
let's source code back to the identity
of the contributor that's the
federated strong identity programs we
talked about before
and then just looking at source code to
figure out if it
is secure we have security audits
many large open source projects have
done them uh but they're expensive
and hard they don't do them often enough
rather than get one audit every two or
three years
um we need to come up with ways as an
industry to contribute funding
um to these projects that we're all
depending on that aren't being uh
don't have enough intention to have a
refund auditing in a more scalable way
for
critical projects um once we have the
really good data showing
which are going in the contributors are
for projects
you need to start to do more advanced
techniques it sounds like a data problem
um because it is like an anomaly
detection
there have been a couple attacks where
uh somebody
just abandoned a package because they
got maybe with their job or personal
life and handed it over to
another group of containers that we're
willing to take home
if you were looking at the commitments
you might see a huge change in activity
there
to find that profit something we need to
take a closer look at
and then in addition to auditing we can
start to do things like crowdsource
reviews
so if you're on a project with hundreds
of thousands of lines of dependencies
at your company and you want to spend
the time reviewing those
hopefully uh crowdsource that so
everyone out there isn't reviewing the
same
set of lines of code can build up a
little bit of trust
with each other um and flag things that
we've all read to make sure that
many eyes on every line of open source
is actually true
if few more eyes on each one
after the source code course there is
the build process
we talked about the reflections on trust
and trust favor
and the demo i showed with the requests
library
we need to hit ci and build systems uh
to log your activity and make this
probably viewable so that everyone can
trust it
right and if we could actually just see
in a secure possible format exactly
which commands got running
to transform that requests give
repository to the published package in
python
so we don't necessarily have to audit it
every single time
we could just see the scripts that were
happening trust those scripts
and trust that the
cs system will be run correctly
the tool chain vulnerabilities can also
come in
the tool chain level once in a while
there's a bugs out there will come
higher than the results and
uh binaries built with it being subject
to the os attacks for example
um if you don't know the tool chain that
was used to build your own application
and you don't know if you're
subject to those kind of things again we
need ways to
securely log the exact versions of the
tool chains that were used
then the final piece the artifact
manager itself one of this matters if
somebody can just upload artifacts
directly to that or modify the artifacts
that have been
uploaded already um knowing
who the vet and offensive different
people from the maintainers i get
it's a great start here um
knowing whether or not updates are
available to thanks to fixed normal
abilities that's another huge
attack factor that people rarely
consider
if someone cds are out there in the wild
and
trick somebody into not updating because
you can point them at an out-of-date
package or something like that
you can keep them vulnerable and exploit
that later um there are actually some
protocols designed
to help uh flag stuff like this so if
you know updates are supposed to be
available and you're not receiving them
um that completed
and then tampering of course the source
signatures uh didn't come in any
commission everybody
has some experience with already um but
uh
organizations should be signing their
artifacts
unfortunately not every package manager
supports this
um there is improvement happening to
almost every one of these pieces
um especially package managers this is
kind of a time for a whole bunch of
improvements here
we talked about some cool stuff um well
some of the parts that make go modules
harder
to work with securely but they do have
some cool improvements
uh the versioning selection algorithm
info modules
is designed to help prevent you from
upgrading accidentally
of the only upgrade when you need to
and the goatee ones that hit module
proxy server
actually publishes all of these to a
transparency log
which is this type of system that lets
them
log the exact tags and versions of all
the go modules
to the source code so if you and i both
install the same original package
we could be uh be very sure that we did
the same source code
that's something that's just started
rolling out similar to the certificate
transparency program
it's used to secure the way that ssl
certificates get issued
but that type of support should be used
by pretty much every package manager
and then finally cbe reporting so this
is how we report things
that we do find uh this uh process
is still very manual and humans are
actually still numbered
like you have to email someone usually
or fill out a form to get a cpd number
which is great back when you were
talking about operating system packages
uh
if you have uh maybe a dozen or so
install on your computer
but language package managers where
there's um
hundreds of thousands of times being
uploaded each month uh it doesn't really
scale to that process
so it's going to improve the scalability
of cpu recording
so that it will scale to this open
source world where
there are way more packages than
anyone's ever dealt with before
some other cool stuff happening
programming language
improvements um a bunch of kind of the
research
level here it's not as far along but
making it possible to
apply permissions for the android app
store at a dependency level
within a larger program so if you want
to
install something you don't really trust
so much today you're giving
that the same permissions that the rest
of your program runs with
imagine if you can sandbox that
dependencies it's not allowed to access
the final system that's not allowed to
access the network
i'm sure i trust it to do some basic uh
computation
there's also just general hygiene
improvements the bulk stuff i talked
about before
turning out two-factor authentication
signing commits signing packages
all these things that everyone knows are
good um that aren't necessarily taking
the time to do
you do enforce that and that's a lot
easier and kind of
increase the adoption of stuff that
already exists
and i talked about cds
all right i'll end uh with a couple
links to how you can get involved
and then we can go to questions
um overall summary here
uh supply chain attacks are a serious
problem for opens for software and
software in general
i scared everybody a little bit that's a
lot of that
and this is a standards automation and
big data problem that we can all stall
together if you try
um there's kind of a link here for a
supply chain security project in the
techcom
cd open source project that i'm
currently working on or you can see some
information
and reach out and get involved if you
want to
i need some contact information for me
as well as you can follow up after
uh here is my account where you can find
that little crypto liner code both for
you
running um and then my twitter and
many languages that are standouts and
their supply chain support
um from a security perspective
um yeah i'd say um i think go is
probably
done the most with the transparency log
stuff that they've done
to make certain classes of attack
starter um i think one
each package of trainers in general are
all pretty far behind things like
operating system
package managers that have been met this
for a lot longer
but those kind of have the benefit of
usually being
set up and run where only a core team
has access to publish those packages
um and they don't have to deal with the
scale of thousands of people uploading
stuff constantly
i think um learning from light layers
learning from the operating system i
could commanders and integrated basic
stuff like
signatures and some of the tuf or the
update
framework has come up with uh on other
classes of attacks that need to be
prevented with those
uh update notification prevention
attacks i mentioned before
how helpful would virus total be on this
area
um to virus that our approach registers
not to be weak
yeah i think um i kind of classified
that as a dependency scanner
um they're pretty good at picking up um
known cves and their dependencies and
kind of banning you
to update or upgrade github
has some of that data in now or if
you're using certain languages it'll
notify you if there's a security update
you need to pick up but the challenge
there is how few of them
are actually reported uh and how long
to get them recorded and let's see these
file
you