sorry we had this technical difficulties
I was literally looking at my slides
upstairs right before came in and we
just had a hardware problem but we're
just gonna use the backup and drive on
right first of all thank you for
surviving the beginning of the last song
of the day I really appreciate that
John will keep boredom I'm here for
Chattanooga and I'm here today talking
about evaluating injection attack tools
through quasi natural experimentation to
inform risk assessments and policies
that's quite a mouthful there but really
these are just three very simple ideas
put together first of all I'm interested
in evaluating injection and attack tools
particularly the automated ones so we're
just gonna try to figure out what we can
do to defend a system based on the
behavior of the tools I want to do this
through quasi natural experimentation
and quasi natural experimentation may
sound like black magic but if you've had
a statistics class any time in the last
ten or fifteen years you were probably
taught causing actual experimental
techniques as part of the class okay and
we're going to do this to form risk
assessments of policy so I'm a huge
believer in risk assessments and I know
that there are probably a lot of folks
who are working in environments where
risk assessments are check the block
unnecessary performance you have to fill
out now I hope to evangelize you a
little bit and bring you a little closer
to successful policy implementation my
main goal here is to try to drive home
the the answer the question when we're
defending a system with very few
resources how do we know that our
solution is going to work I know many
people who work in InfoSec work at a
large enterprise environments I've
worked in environments where there may
just be one or two computer
professionals on staff and as a result
of that you're the only security people
there so I distinctly remember we'll see
a case situation in our priests
station today where I remember defending
a penetrated system implementing what I
thought was a correct solution and I
knew okay I want to do this I want to do
that one to the other and I did those
things and then I thought to myself how
do I know that any of this stuff just
worked and the truth was I didn't right
if the attacker just stops attacking if
you were just a one-off hit on this
guy's list how do you know that your
solution was gonna work or not okay I
will tell you that in today's
presentation our ground rules are I'm
going to redact a lot of the information
to show you know try to present
information is based on real-world
situations but we're going to scrub some
critical names and numbers so we don't
embarrass anybody in the case of some of
the photos I've taken out some logos and
in case other photos I literally have
blocked what I thought was critical
information rather than show it to you I
use the brain way to talk down into four
main sections here first we're going to
go over a little bulk AB you Larry
because some folks are familiar or not
familiar with risk assessments and
policy what I think makes them
successful I will tell you about this
one situation to change my career and
then because I know the last security
guys are just going to go comatose if
you got to hear about another sequel
injection attack we're going to try to
pick off these techniques and use them
in other simulated situations that might
be might be a little more interesting to
you alright so let's go ahead and take
off get store them I'm going to go over
a couple of these these have been some
of the main references for my research
this is if this is not familiar to you
please raise your hand have you all seen
risk assessment matrices before
all right remind you that probability is
is great at along one axis the severity
is graded along another axis so
hypothetically you should be identifying
what you believe other are the potential
vulnerabilities of your system grading
and evaluating them and then following
that up with some risk
trolls and then reevaluating
reevaluating the residual risk okay for
a language about the threats I pick a
wasp automated threats if y'all are not
familiar with the Wausau made threat
handbook I encourage you to have a look
at it the diagrams in there alone will
make you smarter they break down a lot
of criminal style operations but they
only focus on the automated threats in
their handbook and so I'm going to pick
these up and even when we go into the
other situations I'm gonna try to carry
over some of these definitions so you
can see the analogies and there these
are some of those standard threat
descriptions of course we're going to
refer to this special publication 800-53
or vision for and this is so that we
don't have to invent or make up our own
risk controls we're just going to go
ahead and accept this standard once they
provide now if we go to the website you
go ahead and download a lengthy list of
different types of risk controls
available with some standard definitions
there I want to kind of emphasize here
that when we have these situations where
there is a standard list of threats and
a standard list of controls if we don't
take the opportunity to extrapolate you
know both directions this is not going
to be very useful for your planning okay
if you want to make it a check the box
form just say this threat that control
we're going to move on if I don't know
if you have seen Joe McRae's talk on
sequel injection attacks from I saw a
video of him from a def confrontation he
did and he described of course the tick
mark 1 equal one attacks right and if
you've ever seen sequel injection you've
probably seen many rules written about
this and McRae's point was that if you
wrote a lot of rules detecting tick mark
1 equal 1 they work right they're
logically sound but all somebody has to
do to circumvent those rules is to hit
you with a 2 equal to attack
okay all right right so if you if you
don't get to the to the heart of the
threat right
if you don't extrapolate a little bit
then you may not have a realistic
interpretation of the threat a realistic
control implementation and I want you to
understand that that's going to be very
important it's gonna be specific to your
situation that's that imagining and
thinking you you're gonna have to do as
part of my research at work I consulted
these four documents quite a bit okay so
of course some NIST publications may be
hard for you to find now but Journal of
International Affairs cyber issue
introduced me to the work of Herbert Lin
and Benjamin Dean Benjamin Dean's one of
our contemporaries and what he did was
he took some of these quasi natural
experiments told the design techniques
and summarize them and he's alive I
believe he's working in Indiana and he
summarized the work of the book on the
right they're experimental and
quasi-experimental designs by William
shadows now shesh died 2016 but he spent
an overwhelming majority of his career
on experimental design now was primarily
working from the late 60s mostly through
the 70s and 80s a little bit in the 90s
and with a couple of contemporaries but
he wasn't studying cybersecurity Shanna
SH was studying education and josh's
fundamental problem was you can't teach
somebody something the first time twice
right you only get one first time so how
do you know that that teaching technique
worked and it turns out that a lot of
experimental design techniques that
shout investigate are really applicable
to Internet network because I think that
most of the time we have attackers that
are off premises there's an internet
between them and a target computer so
you'll never be able to really envelope
the situation we'll talk about some of
their work and these are some of the
situations are prepared based on our
time we might have to cut a couple of
them but what we're going to try to I'm
going to try to do for you is to show a
relationship between a given hazard a
given control and experimental design
for some of these techniques so that you
can begin imagining your all yourself
how it is you're going to take these
risk assessment techniques haven't
stopped being a piece of bureaucratic
waste of your time and start being an
active part of your everyday planning
okay I am a web programmer this I use
this photograph a lot because these to
be a block my photographer for a little
while now you might follow me on Twitter
I am a graduate student at UT
Chattanooga and a lot of this work we're
learning here today is part of my
master's thesis research and work I used
to work with these guys they were
smarter than me
and that's why I was working with them
okay if you're working in a place where
you the smartest guy in the room maybe
you need to get another room all right I
do make 100 mistakes a day as a web
programmer and they're probably three of
them in this picture right here I'm just
glad I was wearing pants this time okay
when I say a hundred mistakes a day I
mean 100 mistakes a day like I've had
bosses say who made these hundred eight
database errors on this one box and it
was me right you know if there were only
48 I knew I was falling behind today and
I really encourage you to go ahead and
make a lot of mistakes don't be too
ashamed about it you know if you're
making your mistakes and development
that's where they need to be made in the
first place I think I'm married to the
beautiful one intelligent mrs. O'Keefe
Odom she's seen here behind this taco
menu and I do have a little kitty cat my
cat
I enjoy some hacking stuff this is a
computer that recently submerged some
mineral oil I do like to run and
exercise quite a bit of courage you to
do that helps me with stress I like to
drive my car and I wasn't the army for a
while yeah and this is primarily where I
learned how to work and this is where I
learned how to control risk really I was
competitive shooter for a while if you
do shoot a cookie please be safe on the
range now when I was a young 19 year old
recruit our 17 year old recruit and I
guess about the time this photo was
taken us maybe 18 going on 19
at this time in our career soldiers were
just expected to work okay we're just
expected to to use be tough and get
through your job okay so I was jumping
out of planes quite a bit and I was
operating radio systems that look like
this and this was what we call rat radio
automatic teletype this is a encrypted
Wireless Worman networking over
shortwave that mostly preceded the
internet if you're a ham radio operator
some of this may look familiar to you
back then we had the past stress test to
lift the components like nowadays people
say why do you even have a 15 pound lift
requirement for your job for this job
you had to be able to lift the 100-pound
component three feet off the ground in
order to install it in Iraq so I think
that maybe they need to update today I
did learn the fundamentals of
information security while I was there
okay you get any information off a drive
when I'm done with it congratulations
you know maybe you need to do a master's
thesis an electrical engineer in this in
this line of work I learned a lot about
information security we were taught
everything from one-time pads to
generate your own electricity construct
your own antennas you had to run at work
whole system soup to nuts and I just
about every single time I hit the drop
zone somebody who went home in an
ambulance okay and that was just
expected people were just expected to
have to work for risk if you got hurt on
the job that was just too bad for you I
after was out of service for a while I
was out for over 10 years and then in
2001 as a large attack on New York City
or September 11th yeah so I went back
into service and volunteer for program
in which workers were allowed going to
management I call those yes and it's a
this particular program a pretty high
attrition rate but we were taught the
basics of planning and implementing
different missions and at this time when
I came back to the military risk
assessments were everywhere I literally
never saw a risk assessment when I was a
listed soldier back in the late eighties
early nine
but when I returned after September 11th
they were everywhere I was given this
briefing in a military environment I
would be expected to conduct a risk
assessment about this environment please
don't fall asleep by your chair gonna
trip and fall over course stuff like
that but I basically was able on a lot
of my combat assignments as an officer
to be very successful and to go into a
lot of extremely dangerous situations
now and in a chief victory now you might
look at me and recognize that I probably
don't look like Rambo all right okay and
the reason why I was successful was
because of planning rehearsals and this
is this has really become a big part of
my life to try to evangelize people
about risk assessments now when we look
at cybersecurity or information security
this tells us okay these are our steps
here and if we look at them you know
there are three of them in particular
853 applies quite a bit select assess
and monitor controls these steps of risk
management framework or premise is
pretty much universal but we can tie our
references to those now I'm going to
tell you that in environments where I've
seen risk assessment simplified
successfully most people have been in in
places where there was already a culture
for a language of leadership that was
there now like if you're in a corporate
environment and somebody tells you
what's our corporate mission statement I
hear just some of the most ridiculous
platitudes I could have imagined like we
want to be a better company or we you
know we want that we want to embrace
humanity but be profitable work you know
just the ridiculous mean like things
that you might see scrolling through
social media and in the military we did
not do this
we had very concrete mission statements
to who what when where why and our plans
were about how people did these things
and this language is very important to
being successful because it allowed
leaders to establish what Department was
doing
and then they're all subordinate ranks
we'll be able to extract their own
mission statements so that you could
have a sum total in other words if
you're in a low ranking unit the result
of your contribution should be a clear
distinct block that that contributes to
a higher mission we just don't see this
in the workplace today okay so if you
are working in a workplace right now
where they want you to just shut up and
do your job setup and your tasking is
just done through an email then you
might already be behind an 8-ball a
little bit okay you need to bring this
kind of this kind of concrete task
oriented thought to your workplace in
order to really have the risk assessment
stand up at scene another thing I like
to warn you about is like when I say
rehearsals for cybersecurity most of the
rehearsals are actually done through
your testing okay so that's really your
only opportunity if you don't set up
some type of wargaming yourself there
may not be any testing time and I will
tell you that as web developer over 95%
of testing I've seen done a workplace
has been done by the person who wrote
the program okay
95% easy the only times that I've really
seen situations where programs or I felt
properly tested
we're in places where I saw a federally
regulated workplace it's like you know
if you had had payment card information
you had HIPPA requirements that need to
be validated for instance maybe then you
might have good testing so you might
need to actually put that seed in your
employer's mind that okay you hire two
programmers to write your programs at
your company but we're gonna need you to
hire somebody else who's outside of us
to actually test this equipment test
separately if you're not having a
separate person do the testing we do
most of the testing there really what
you do is taking a convenience sample
right and I don't know how many times
we've had mathematics professors tell us
in statistics convenience samples are
basically just
- worthless okay so if we're going to
try to find testing results they're
going to have some sort of scientific
validity we have got to get the
developer out of the testing process and
get testers that get respect and their
companies now if we just look at the pay
scales I don't know if anybody here is a
professional tester works in QA but I'll
tell you is a web developer I really
perceive a pecking order in there and I
think that that pecking order translates
into pay in other words feel like guys
on QA for testing they're not getting
paid equitably now I attended a briefing
earlier today that said a bug in a
program could easily cost corporation a
million dollars and that their cheapest
solution is for them to ship products
that are stable work while well isn't
that worth paying the tester another 20%
no 25% I think it probably is we also do
some acceptance testing a simplified
unit testing if you do do testing a lot
of times what we're going to see them
and see people pen testing program in a
VM and again I really feel like this is
just another form of convenience testing
just because of the people that are
doing it in other words companies will
not oftentimes not spend on the testing
so now the testing is whatever you
decided and your cubicle you could pull
off on these machines that they gave you
and again you're almost setting yourself
up okay so what are quasi natural
experiments as I told you a moment ago
about Williams shadows and Benjamin Dean
we're gonna have a look at some of their
different design techniques now when I
saw Benjamin Dean's right up in that
journal article one of the first things
I said was AZ right you know we got to
go find out what sheds dead
so Dean summarizes work Tessa's book
that it read is about inna or some pages
think of different different qualities
of experimental testing and really a lot
of it is history and anecdotes of
different types of testing we boil down
test techniques into a few different GRU
we can see that there are really simple
farm user describing right first of all
I'd like for us to remember the kind of
scientific experiment most of us think
of right so like if you could imagine
you're in chemistry class in 11th grade
you're doing a tabletop experiment about
titration you measure something litmus
paper whatever a very simple tabletop
experiment we have a lot of control so
it's very easy for us to use a standard
scientific method all right we have we
can see all the components we can
measure everything but let's notice that
when we're doing network testing we have
that internet wedged in there and so
there'll be no way that we can control
or accept all of variables so we turn to
these things say ok one technique is
going to be one group post test only
okay you're going to make one
observation on groups of pre tests or
you say what we're going to we have a
group with a pretest and a post-test and
this is pretty close to our traditional
benchtop version we say ok we do a
pretest we do a post-test after our
treatment we see what's going to happen
post tests only for non equivalent
groups you know again it's you know
we'll have one test with a post-test
only well it looks well I'll be able to
explain this gets a little bit better
when we get on down the trail here
repeated treatment ok so we're going to
go ahead treat and treat and treat and
treat and treat now we suggest that when
I'm talking about treatment for for
Network testing or for for this type of
testing cyber security testing our
treatment is going to be whatever patch
we put in place whatever activity it is
that you were doing to actually defend
your system of your network that's your
treatment if you have you reading the
logs over and over again that's your
treatment if you get to run a program to
do a scan those laws that were passed
treatment difference in differences I
will talk about this one in a moment and
this is where we see two different
groups all right we establish a control
group and we establish a treating a
group and we do tests before and after
the treatment on one group
we have cohort control where we have
successive groups this is very useful
for people and we have an interrupted
time series okay so let's talk a little
bit how we're going to choose some of
these techniques let's imagine that
we're going to train a group of
employees I think a lot of times people
will tell you you just need to train
those users make sure this problem
doesn't ever happen again time and time
again we see this Bailes fails miserably
in fact I would suggest it probably has
one of most high with the highest
failure rate of a lot of treatment
techniques that we applied so instead a
lot of our security personnel are
instead say well I'm going to rely on
the Pats from a rely on a rule well I on
automate a program there's much higher
rate of success so what we're talking
about with cohort control is let's
imagine you work at a very big company
of course you know trying to teach
everybody the same times unwieldy so
what are you gonna do teach them in by
department teacher by section each one
of those groups of people is a cohort
now let's suppose we want to ask
ourselves is our training of these
cohorts going to be effective so we
train one group and we train the second
group now let's take the results of what
happened with the second group compared
to the first group you're tracking and
work our way through may as many groups
we need in order to train the company as
a scope this next one will say
difference in differences and I wanted
to talk about this one for a moment
because if we think back to our tabletop
experiment difference-in-differences
might sound like it doesn't make any
sense so let's say we're going to we're
going to take two groups and we're going
to split it in half so if you could
imagine let's say you have one
environment that mimics an active system
and we have another copy of that
environment so now we have two groups
that we're going to treat to the
treatment group we choose to go ahead
and apply our patch okay so when we
create these two environments we conduct
a pretest for both of them then we apply
our treatment and then we conduct a
post-test to both of them well it seems
to make sense over here on a treatment
group that's kind of what we would
expect right we do a pretest the
treatment and pose
test why are we testing the control
group twice it kind of doesn't make any
sense
right alright if we think about our
little tabletop experiment our control
group by definition is a group that has
nothing happened to it so if we didn't
do anything it ought to be just fine
right exactly
testing the test for testing other
conditions that maybe contribute to the
environment because let's keep in mind
now when we're actually doing our test
and we're going to let's say have a red
team attack attack this group that we're
treating now if we pretest on both sides
and we post tests on both sides and we
have an Internet involved in that
environment okay let's suppose that our
treatment group all of a sudden turns
out to be something that says oh that
treatment group there's a lot of latency
after the treatment and we didn't test
our control group you see I'm saying we
might we might accidentally reach for
qualities about the treatment which
might actually be confounded with the
environment or the test construction
itself when we talk about testing a lot
of times the rig's get our attention we
think about the vm's attack pattern the
cool toys we're going to play with and I
applaud the cool toys of course but
really it's about the tests it's about
our thinking right if we have poor tools
but good thinking we're going to have
something that's going to be more
reportable more actionable if you do do
a lot of tests in in VMs I'd encourage
you to look up this academic paper I
stumbled across it was written by some
guys in Kentucky Galloway and I can't
remember the solution initiative a
Stigall from Western Kentucky University
these guys presented I Triple E and the
brunt of their findings was they took
three very commonplace VM hypervisors
and they subjected model DDoS attacks
and unfortunately my favorite one
performed miserably okay
VirtualBox does crumbled but I think yes
that's all I was doing very well
Kirk you'll have that look at you test
all right so now I'd like to go ahead
and move to
apologies this was the attack that
changed my career as a web programmer I
had a client who all of a sudden had a
pollen production box and they found out
the box was pawned because all sudden
massive amount of directory just
disappeared look in the website I all
sudden was gone
and sysadmin logged in and huge block
files were gone so we just saw a
directory destruction
I went to have a look at some of the
logs and of course it's all a lot of
evidence sequence you actually attacks
for those of you who are not familiar
with injection attacks and we saw logic
attacks just like Union Polk cache
poisoning so a numerical overflow but I
want to point out that in real life
these attacks don't occur individually I
would see one line of code that cramps
all those concepts into it and so it
would be like 250 lines of code cramming
all those ideas into one you always
follow me ok so a boat of complex
attacks there a sequel map map defaults
my skiddy friends we can identify your
sequel map attack just by the shape of
the sequel code that is outputting the
logs and oftentimes they will actually
be a little trailer there and browser
identification we found a lot of
BitTorrent botnets and individuals
attacking us okay so basically what
would occur is when people would attack
we look them up and showed an and showed
an of course will tell us hey the site P
is Department of a bitch warrant botnet
and this would explain a lot of their
attacks so a lot of curl recon attacks
which seem to be seem to be similar to a
local apt recently released apt in which
ubiquity internet devices and mikrotik
test servers were being compromised in
South America and what these devices had
in common was that they had board
manufacturing Latvia so I believe what
was happening was one of the more
sophisticated attackers was compromising
those boxes hitting the site one time
just to see if it was there and if it
would respond and it would go ahead and
count it as a successful recon so we get
about 70 of those a day and then of
course Izzie the usual corner building
scanners like a kinetics scans and of
course direct intrusion evidence
well it shocked everybody when this
happened and so with being only a couple
people on staff at that client's place
we need to get smart fast so one of
course things of dips come down here and
start traveling a lot of b-sides
conventions and it's the many places
like go do as much reading as possible
because we had gets more ourselves that
we're not going to hire somebody who
already knew about these topics and what
limited what limited academic disclosure
I had to it was not good enough to
really match these these sophisticated
and Falk attacks of occurring these that
particular products so this is the the
attackers goal on a fraud box was they
want to basically establish a carding
site in order suppor prostitution
activities I had a couple of other
activities but basically they want to be
able to rip off people's credit cards so
most of the bait side topics were about
sex okay so no matter who you are if
these people had somebody who might be
remotely attractive to you and if you
heard motely attractive yet commercial
currency in their in their sites they
appeal to a wide range of sexual
orientations and countries and
combinations of people they also did a
lot of online banking and payments in
that they want to mimic a lot of those
sites we saw so I'm also wanting to go
to sites where people would bid on
expensive cars a maternity clothes well
it was kind of an odd combination but
really was anything people would spend a
lot of money on yeah at one point in
their lives so using these particular
sites
now when the using these particular
sites that would attract victims now I
assure you that the attacker did his own
risk assessment because built into his
site that he was using he would they
would deploy extensive black lists
inside those directories so I see dot
htaccess files would go on for two
thousand lines of Perl script naming
individual IPS that this criminal did
not want on the site and he would have
comments in there about who he didn't
want why he didn't want so if you work
for a big corporation like let's say
Google or
Microsoft or someplace that had
established security teams they would
just try to block you out in force and
then they would start listing
individuals after that including other
criminals right he didn't want his
competition seeing what's happening on
the site there was one person who had
apparently been a real jerk to my
attacker and he didn't want to do
business with him anymore and he was in
in blacklist also so they also had
segregation of duties and separation
stuff so as we talked about the topology
here in a minute you can see that the
attacker makes sure he keeps his
business to himself and he doesn't
really involve his customers very much
as the premium fraud features built into
these sites I mean when they go we went
to you went to this attackers site and
it was an online banking site it was an
exact copy of the real online banking
site in terms you know graphically
speaking oftentimes it would fake a page
with a single page application you Luis
Paz there really are angular okay that
was my introduction to spas was the
attacker would basically put a picture
of a real site place his own HTML over
it through JavaScript and then they
would fake page loading all right
because you got that big funky URL this
doesn't actually match at a top of the
address bar so what he would do is he
would fake the page loading that would
be expected by the user even though he
was running a single page application
looked very much like the actual ones
like these so here's if you can imagine
somebody's going to ask you to reset
your password I remember looking at some
of the source code for this and there
were slight there would be slight
deviations in there like the after the
person had given up all their
information they would be told that's
gonna be about 48 hours before your
changes take effect you know yeah it's
gonna be 48 hours of course some changes
take effect
okay well solicit figure out how these
guys fight so my friends I got some
photo album snapshots in there
they're basically four lanes of activity
and this ploy over here we have an
attacker what guy call renter and
victim and then of course for bait site
so our attacker would conduct sequel
injection attack he basically gain
access to the prod box we know that
because he bragged about it publicly
later and a unpack our calling card
which is literally a big sign that says
Here I am this is me is my hacker name
all my buddies who want to check me out
see see me here on this site you know in
fact the Trojan alright because they
want to be able to come back he started
on packing templated sites and he picked
a pretty good directory down pack all
this stuff and it took me a long long
time
they recruit renters right so criminals
that actually want to conduct business
with somebody who knows how to run a
carting site they would contact them you
recruit them and it established a
business relationship for them so what
the hacker would do is he take us you
take his template site he pick another
directory on the on the box he cloned
his template site there he'd give the
rent or information for just contacting
that one site to be a clone and some of
these at these the stylize or customized
to varying degrees I think of my
attacker had various service packages
that he was offering to his clients and
it looked like at least one time
somebody bought the cheap package and
they were going to customize it
themselves and in a really really poor
job about okay I guess if you're going
to purchase you know criminal technical
expertise you should probably pick the
gold package of course they wanted to
use a prostitution catalog site and bait
to you know so if victims would be
routed to the carding site okay so your
renter I believe was probably more in
line with lining up to prostitutes and
oftentimes we would see the prostitutes
on on websites like this and just be xxx
some females name not are you and then
there would be basically a a listing of
how much those that person services will
cost okay so you would imply that
alright if they go ahead and they buy
these things then this is how much it's
gonna cost you and so the most expensive
service on this list translated in
two dollars to about $30 a night okay so
we start to have some questions right
who is the victim here right I kind of
wonder if some of these people who are
involved right here aren't victims but
the goal is to get the person to the car
in sight and that's what they did now I
believe when the victim went searching
for for those services they were already
basically poison in their search with
cross-site scripting we could tell by
the reference sites they're already
carrying payloads from Yandex that are
you similar to Google so I think that
when they when they began their searches
they were already looking for these kind
of topics they were already going to be
routed to probably customized search
results that we're going to bring them
right over to these these car sighs okay
so now if he gets compromised or deleted
because every so often I find one right
what do you do
he just unpack another one all right
place it someplace else if you can
imagine this type of operation occurring
at scale right so not only is the
compromising this one particular box but
I believe because the periodicity
that these people were compromising many
one after another after another after
another all right so here it is this is
this is the trojan that caused me so
much trouble
there's the PHP cryptic Trojan and I
don't know if you can see the photograph
very well by Sheree they've all of the
red line in this picture is basically an
elaborate array and below that line is
the base64 probably multiple layers I
never have managed to successfully
decode it cryptic Trojan right
virustotal is exactly what this is and
what they had done was I have buried
this in a junk build directory and so
that's how we end up being victimized
it's Alisa move on to some attack
situations and some risk controls for
experimental design for it's a good time
I want to I will tell you though that
what
recommend in this case a daily log
reviews public-facing web applications
and I imagine that many people here work
in the enterprise level security jobs
and show hands please guys working
Enterprise probably absolutely hate the
concept that I just told you to read
those logs and considering the massive
quantity of logs of you guys face I you
have my sympathies in this particular
instance what we had was a a contractor
who had who had set things up and not
revealed all the information to the
business owner so logs were not readily
available it actually took months to
extract yield getting enough control
over the site itself in order to be able
to get a hold of these laws but looking
at these laws write daily log reviews
this is an example of our interrupted
time series that we talked about earlier
so every time that you're looking at log
that is another treatment that's another
opportunity for detachment another you
know one treatment group your one fraud
site with many observations before and
after that's that's your log reviewing
action I found this particular Trojan
online 100 78596 of a log that I
reviewed so it was buried down in there
pretty deep and as you can see this was
basically our first indication that
there was such trouble there and of
course they were getting referred over
for McGann Dec search so this part that
I've covered up in here this was a
specific directory that linked them back
to a targeted site and so from there I
was able to trace him back down to the
template his site alright so normally
you would conduct an initial risk
assessment you go ahead and begin to
implement your controls for code
injection and in this case what we're
going to use if we use log reviews which
is student haven't run the time series
and then we would again conduct another
risk assessment I want to point out to
you that okay when this happened to me
this is one of my best days on my job
when I found that trip I got cryptic
treasure
as a programmer I don't normally
encounter security problems this was
fantastic to me I thought everybody
would be happy about it but I'm going to
tell you that part of my philosophy is
that bad things happen to good people
who do the right thing every day okay I
definitely learned that a comic right
some people who think that oh if you if
you do right and you work right
everything's going to go right for you
and you should have a good life and we
see a lot of interruptions of those
sequences in our lives and this this
type of situation really caused me to
focus on our perceptions of actor and
victim responsibility you know if we
think back to some of the workers who
advertise in those catalogs are they
actors are they victims or both and
where do we stand in all this right this
is just part of the environmental hazard
of working inside a a very aggressive
environment which is that which is the
Internet
that's what I got for my trouble okay
was that work one day I go out to my car
to go to lunch and somebody couldn't
battery cable my car alright and this
was just one of many incidents that I
encountered in work place and part of
what was happening was when I discovered
his problem and I thought everybody be
glad about it it turned out that it
actually began to reveal business
problems with a disposition of and use
of equipment in a company and so then
people were angry right and so they want
to suppress report now I apply social
pressure to me to try to get me to leave
ok because when I hear things like
people say well folks are socially
pressure than InfoSec because of this or
we have a very nasty culture this is
this pretty much what I think okay I
think somebody pick up the stick in the
parking lot and manufactured this little
tool they Jimmy their way in my car and
they cut that battery cable I end up
leaving that job some months later ok
now my favorite issue a Harvard Business
Review how I work with toxic colleagues
and I will tell you that at the time I
was studying things like well what we do
about psychopathic or narcissistic
people in our workplace and there does
come a point in these these
really bad aggressive abusive
relationships where you might just have
to say okay I got a lead you might not
you might not be able to change those
people all right so I did I did end up
finding my brothers in DC 43 and one of
the things I learned if there any
students here one things I learned about
these kind of activities is that this is
almost a rite of passage almost to a
person a lot of the programmers and
hackers that I respected had a
significantly negative social experience
at some point in their career okay if it
hasn't happened to you yet
maybe you're just on the waiting list
okay I may not be as blatant as some of
the things that I encountered but it's a
lot of times it can be quite severe so
what I end up having to do is I just
channeled all this into my research at
Universe I still consider myself very
lucky individual okay I start working on
master's thesis on this topic and now
giving all the time I like go ahead and
jump into some of these other attack
situations so we don't just have to talk
about code injection okay we talked
about RFID cloning on mechanical
lock-picking
and as many of you know our great state
of Tennessee is some of the most
interesting laws about lock picking in
the United States okay it seems quite
quite interesting
I personally suspect don't but do not
know that you know hey somebody wanted
to write some industry protections to
these rules and now that they created
some of this quite aggressive about
locked up so as the Tennessee resident
of course I would not own any of these
locks these lock picks and I wouldn't
practice regularly okay but if you did
you might might learn a thing or two
about physical security are you all
familiar with this device that I'm
showing here on the picture this is a
proxmark 3r DV and for those of you who
may not be familiar with this is
basically a handheld cloning device that
is used for replicating RFID cards and
if you work in a corporate environment
you probably have just such a key card
to let you in almost every door every
day this this device is pretty much a
handheld computer all you got to do is
attach a battery and go ahead and start
replicative cards with I didn't have to
replicate cars is one place I showed up
okay it was a little cold rainy outside
so it's tapping on the door likey
hey and I was at a major federal
contractors office door with my key and
then ploy it was sighs oh you're here
there let me in let me let you in they
literally just open the door let me into
the facility didn't check my ID rank I
walk up to the receptionist desk I get
to the receptionist desk
yeah employee says me hey here you go
here's the book pushes the book at me
across the table sign yourself in opens
the book to the last page and he shows
there here's your card hands me this
card and as you can see it says visitor
no escort required so just gives me the
key to walk all around the building and
then says to me certain numbers on this
card are important and certain numbers
on this card are not important
well I blanked out the numbers that were
important in this picture okay so you
can guess how many digits were not
important and he explained to me that
there were were not a port to their
internal security procedures told me
what to write down in the law okay all
right so this is pretty much handed me
the whole thing so I put on my badge
okay and I started walking around nobody
had gotten there yet so I found these SS
IDs and passwords written on walls you
you often do and a lot of cooperative on
so we'll start logging in checking out
network and I drained my coffee cup so I
was walking around with a heavy coffee
cup and come across him another employee
that an employee who let me sign myself
in he disappeared left me alone at the
reception's desk was turned on computer
oh you know some of that was like let's
just say the entire thing was very
challenging of our professional athletes
all right so I had this empty coffee cup
I want around another employees oh the
coffee service is not here yet let me
get you a cup of coffee myself all right
so one scurries back to his desk it goes
gets me something out his private stash
okay so based on this incident right we
didn't even have to pick any locks I
would tell you I'll tell you you know if
if somebody was attempting to intrude
physically on
on your facility of course we might see
some parallels these Ola automated
threats right particularly footprinting
right and scalping and vulnerability
scanning and this is the course of
credential cracking account aggregation
so if you're cloning those cards you are
basically creating another account
you're going to want to do some foot
printing because once you get inside I
don't want to know what it is you can do
for you there okay and I'd say it will
count as scalping because you're
attempting to tell you something about
risk assessment over here and then let's
say we're gonna go ahead and implement
some of these controls there now this
control list I think we ought to go
ahead and select visitor control okay so
this gets us back to our employees
trained to interact with strangers in
the workplace or not right so we might
have cohort control right we might have
case control experimental designs I
would go ahead and conduct another risk
assessment - to evaluate the residual
risk and these would be their hazards
control of the designs that we just hope
you guys come out a little wiser based
on time I'd like to go ahead and skip
over land wiretap and go into Wi-Fi
replays and crime ejection now Wi-Fi is
used quite a bit a workplace and I would
suggest that most corporate Wi-Fi
networks are reasonably secure I don't
know if y'all have seen this issue of
2600 look at that there's an article in
there about one page but I'll go ahead
and build your own pineapple palm so go
ahead decided to try it they wanted to
go ahead and build one for 20 bucks you
had to use an adapter and a Raspberry Pi
so you can build yourself on out so I
put one together and that's what mine
looks like let's go ahead and I put it
in a binder thanks to suggestion from
Brent White I saw over here at a
different besides Nashville putting
things in common office supplies law to
carry Virani own varmint what this does
is it basically conducts monitoring so
that you can go ahead and do manual
if you use aircraft sweeter era want any
this is a hobbyist version of hac vice
premier plan so our all while automated
threats again would have to do with
County aggregation credential cracking
fingerprinting and foot printing and
bone scanning this script that I wrote
basically that's all it did was conduct
vulnerable vulnerability scans right so
I took that again we you have to have
enough in the initiative of imagination
to take the references that you receive
and extrapolate them alright so when
we're looking at these the advice or the
user dots for air bond or air crack it
doesn't really tell us how to build a
good offensive attack tool right they
probably have some liability concerns
there I'm sure so we need to extrapolate
so I was I was thinking of things like
okay I'm gonna use this I'm gonna want
to delay so I'm gonna build a delay into
my script
before my stuff starts when I start
scanning let's say I might not know that
I'm in the correct target area at a
given time so perhaps I need to do
multiple scans for a limited time in
other words what I'm suggesting is if
you start researching with this type of
thing okay you start reaching out
reaching out don't just accept what the
standard control the references tell a
so for Wi-Fi replay Wi-Fi replays an
injection we'd ask okay where is the
person most vulnerable and I would
suggest we see some different standards
and some companies and I know I have
seen particularly in private company
where you have executive privilege dates
okay like I've had president a company
showed me a nice pornographic joke on
his business email keeping on his
personal phone okay alright so what what
did I see there I saw a vulnerability
that's all a lot of vulnerability hey I
wasn't going to concerned about the joke
or a topic as a var ability so I was
just that if you have people inside
inside your organization that really the
vulnerability might not be in the
workplace it might be when they're
picking up these BYOD devices
moving outside of your boundary control
right is when you're establishing Wi-Fi
controls you're using that boundary
control risk control that NIST 853 tells
you about but when you get home it's not
there anymore so there's there there's
your place for doing the war dialing and
for doing the interception it's not
going to be inside your building as much
as it might be across the street in
their house okay so we would need to
conduct Wi-Fi training preparing
employees okay so you're probably
already preparing them a little bit I
would guess that most people will
require VPN in order to go ahead contact
your company but so I would suggest in
these case we're talking about designs
without control loops all right one
group and post-tests only in other words
when you test a group of employees you
probably want to test them afterwards
you're probably not going to not going
to bother with testing their performance
before because until they actually get
the tools and they received the basic
instruction it doesn't make sense to
conduct the pretest but just because
you're in that limited situation doesn't
mean that you can't conduct legitimate
tests okay let's go into phishing
campaign just briefly of course we're
not talking about this kind of fishing a
friend of mine from Las Vegas this was
the first fish he ever caught in his
entire life this was fishing of course
campaigns there are always dependent
upon the attractiveness of the bait and
this is one that I got the other day so
would you like a nice attractive job in
cyber security all you got to do is
agree to receive this router at your
house all right
receive this router and take it to
picked up shipping label off and put
this other shipping label on it send it
out and it's the same old dropship mail
fraud forwarding scheme that we're all
right but see how it's customized to
what we would want right that's the same
thing as happening of course to all of
our users they just want to tell you
what you want to hear while doing what
they want though and we tell these users
do not click on those attachments that
that might be loaded with come to you in
a phishing email and they do it anyway
because their nature right so we may
experience a momentary disappointment
right and really our best reliance is
good set of backups right how many times
we've seen ransomware get unloaded on
customer service reps are really
containment and backups were our key
protections I would tell you that my
most practical advice to the situation
in small companies is telling people
just stop typing stop typing stop typing
they'll click on anything just go ahead
and call your IT good call us and if
you're a management and a company I
record you please do not penalize
employees who report the fact that they
are a victim of some sort of main
transom where I know I've seen
situations where ok the the employees
computer is no longer usable today
therefore you're going home today and if
you're an hourly employee I just
penalize you some valuable one but
please think ahead now what we're going
to train you folks have about stuff like
this you might see a design and control
group at no pretest right post us only
for non equivalent fruits and with that
I would like to go ahead I'm probably
going to close your mobile but I did
want to show you at least one to these
slides here we've all seen passwords
underneath the keyboard someplace this
behind the screwdriver handles not
somebody's password it's not their
employee ID
it was the algorithm to compute an
employee ID from publicly available
information okay so if you had if you
gave me a cup of coffee and you have me
wandering around your business and I
stumbled upon this little post-it note
right here imagine how much more
damaging things could be right I also
want to advise you this this cwe is as a
programmer we rely on cwe's a lot Hey
insufficient psychological acceptability
if you make your risk control so tough
that your users can't understand it then
you just basically created another
vulnerability in your system
go ahead and catch up here alright guys
I did not get to cover absolutely
everything that I want to do today but I
will tell you this is me on my
helicopter day about the lead helicopter
no a very happy man right there we did
have a chance to talk about some of
these concepts here we're talking about
nest 8 home 53 controls we did talk
about some of our main references we did
have an opportunity to look at tax
apology oh but I told you enough about
some real-world situations that you can
understand what it is you're defending
against everyday what may be out there
waiting for you in a dangerous world and
we did have an opportunity to discuss
some of these other situations here I
guess I'll go ahead and open for
questions guys have any questions I see
there are no questions and pretty soon
to be time for us to go to closing
ceremonies thank you very much Bob to
talk to you