this is kind of forgetting some but
really that's kind of the focus of my
talk here is to talk about the people
and how we can leverage them in your
organization okay looks like we're good
there
I was gonna blame it on this laptop but
I'm glad to hear that it wasn't just
this time so so as you can see on the
screen no signal is not something you
want fortunately you know they did just
give me this my laptop died a couple of
days ago in Austin I got back to the
office for one day and they threw this
one at me so still figure hey
all right my hero agent all right okay
I'll get the mouse the hell out of the
way and we can get started here folks
okay
so again this is a brand new laptop for
me so trying to figure it out once again
this is like twice in a row now I've
done things here in Tennessee I spoke it
besides Chattanooga not long ago and I
did a totally new presentation that had
every opportunity for things to go wrong
so here I am repeating it in Nashville
right so anyways um we're gonna talk a
little bit about hacking the users and
what we can do with the users how we
make it most successful now everything I
talk about here you don't have to use
our platform whore are our software
nothing like that this isn't a vendor
pitch I promise I love to answer
questions talk about this sort of thing
anything you can do here if you're doing
your own awareness programs and stuff
you can leverage this sort of
information on your own - about me
a little bit about me I'm old I've been
around an IT insecurity since the BBS
days anyone else remember Wildcat BBS
and right okay Fido nets and right all
right there's my people right there the
thrill of getting a courier to courier
modem connection because the compression
was off the chart it was fantastic we'd
get sometimes you know up to like 16 K
BOTS it was Sam it was wonderful so
anyways I'm showing my age here I did I
worked with the Department of Defense I
was a contractor for about ten years at
the organization that does the network
backbone for all of the post camps and
stations across North America for the US
Army I was a security manager there it's
why I look like this at 28 years old
Security's hard but you know I've been
around a little bit been in the business
since about the mid 1990s seen a lot of
things what's interesting is over the
years some things don't change all right
we've seen phishing attacks and we've
seen social engineering attacks hit our
people since forever ago right think
about the old you know I love you virus
the Melissa stuff all that stuff back
then that was stuff going on back in the
1990s and people were falling for it
what has changed though is the impact
this is happening this is having on
organizations these days right it used
to feel like a big deal when
got a virus on our network but compared
to what's happening these days it was
more of an inconvenience right you get a
Zeus banking Trojan oh boy that sucks
you know compared to these ransomware
attacks it's nothing right so the issue
continues but the loss that we're
experiencing has really ramped up so
this is what I've been seeing over the
years I work for a company called no
before we've got 17,000 customers across
like all kinds of places right what's
important is I hear a lot of these
stories I talk to a lot of people and
hear what's going on what what happens
out there and we see a lot of the stuff
that happens out in the world when it
comes to fishing that's kind of where I
base some of my numbers and some of the
stuff that I've learned here on that's
why it matters okay so the agenda we're
going to talk a little bit about current
trends real goal politics of fishing
your users make an account dealing with
repeat offenders let's start with the
current trends and scams right oh great
I didn't even realize that okay fishing
leads to ransomware which is kind of a
big deal these days right I love this is
my favorite slide that I've ever done
because it's very true right before
ransomware we were just kind of cruising
along minding our own business we knew
what security was going on right it was
we knew what we were doing ransomware
hit and it's really just flipped us on
our lid and yes folks those are out
houses and that is a convertible okay
this is what's happened to our industry
this hit and really messed us all up
with the stuff that we were used to
doing all right how bad some of the
numbers behind it when it comes to
phishing phishing is like the number one
attack vector that people are getting in
91 percent of successful data breaches
start with the spear phishing attack CEO
fraud anyone ever heard of that right
that's where someone pretends to be a
leader in your organization sends an
email to somebody and says we need you
to wire money out right sounds really
simple yeah we're talking about nine
billion dollars in losses expected this
year on something that's stupid
people fall for this stuff left and
right w-2 scams same sort of thing hey I
need you to send all the w-2s all the
tax forms to me
and then the bad guys get that and file
all the taxes on behalf of all your
employees and the employees when they go
to file their taxes find out it's
already been done for them believe it or
not the bad guys always end up with a
refund that's amazing
but they've taken your money they've run
and now these people have to deal with
about 12 to 18 months of playing games
with the IRS and all that stuff to get
it straightened out it's an ugly thing
and it's all happening through phishing
now ransomware specifically we're
expecting by the end of next year
next year will be 11 and a half billion
dollars in damages due to ransomware
this is just not stopping it just keeps
growing and growing 2017 it increased by
300% over 2016 we're still seeing growth
like that and it is interesting in 2016
we saw about one hundred and fifty three
thousand cases of mobile ransomware now
that hasn't gone very far yet but I
expect that once they're able to get
their their grubby little fingers in
there and actually get it to work
reliably and on those that don't have to
sideload apks and stuff that that's
going to get a whole lot worse because
I'm pretty sure if you're anything like
me this little device right here checks
your work email connects to your work
may even have a VPN connection into your
office right these things are gonna be a
great target once they can get their
hands on it because you have a lot of
interesting stuff on here so these are
some of the numbers that are back there
now when it comes to social engineering
which is really the backbone behind
phishing you know I love this show
anyone else here watch mr. robot at all
right
I still think season 1 was the best but
you know ok but I love this I've never
found it hard to hack most people if you
listen to him watch him the
vulnerabilities are like a neon sign
screwed into their heads this is very
very true the thing is most of us fall
for the same things and the bad guys are
getting a whole lot better about
figuring out what that is
alright now what we found in our
platform is it's kind of discouraging
sometimes but about 55% of the people
will click on a phishing email within 60
minutes of it hitting their inbox that
means it's come in it's hit their inbox
that's competing with all the other
emails that are in their inbox
they've bothered to look at it and they
click the link now imagine if in your
organization
you could get 55% of the people to click
on important emails within the first
hour that they get it right we'd be like
99% efficient we could blow Amazon out
of the water Walmart would never see
anything like it okay how does this
happen
why are they so good at getting people
to click and this is from our platform
and so you know what we do on our
platform a lot of times is we take
reported phishing emails we defang them
and then we turn around and turn them
into templates for people to use this is
indicative of real types of emails that
are out there well to give you an idea
of some of the stuff that we see and the
click rates that we go go with it
they've made it so enticing for these
people to do this they make people want
to click give you an idea here on the
left hand side this is our queue for our
q1 is due out any day now is hoping a
bit yesterday but on the left side here
you'll see LinkedIn 53% click rate on
LinkedIn stuff now what's interesting is
for like q2 q3 it was around the 40% and
what's happened is though we started
hitting the end of the year so the end
of the year people start getting their
Christmas bonuses they start thinking
about hey it's a whole new year let's
make some changes maybe I'll look for
that new job maybe I'll do something
different so what do they do they start
answering LinkedIn stuff they start
playing around on LinkedIn a little bit
more they start clicking these things
the attackers know this sort of stuff
people are more vulnerable for LinkedIn
site it's rather interesting that free
pizza one has been on here for a while
I'm actually disturbed to find out that
I hear it actually dropped off of the
list for this one because I click on
that every damn time
but it usually runs about 8 or 9 percent
and you're basically sending somebody an
email that says hey this is Pizza Hut
click here for this coupon for your for
your pan pizza free pan pizza right it's
a fantastic way to get people to do it
but the attackers they leverage things
in social engineering they leverage our
human emotions against us and what's
interesting some of the most powerful
human emotions we have the things that
drive us to actions are things like
outrage and anger if you can outrage
somebody or you can make them a
they're gonna want to do something with
that they build that energy they have to
find a way to put it out there right so
you build a phishing email that's based
on that sort of thing what's really hot
this time let's see oh I don't know
politics that's been going on for a
while right now regardless of what side
of the fence you're on we have a sort of
controversial guy in the White House
right now that people get really riled
up either way about the bad guys
leverage that and they'll put things in
there that sound really outrageous they
get people riled up and then they'll
give them an action which is to click a
link and bam what do you know things
happen another example of some pretty
interesting and really common ones once
we see over and over again up here on
the top right have to do with delivery
attempts or orders who here has an
Amazon Prime account okay most of the
room right I get that like Amazon I
don't even remember what the hell I
ordered from them boxes show up I'm like
oh it's a surprise I ordered it two days
ago I don't even remember but this stuff
shows up all the time right if you're
like me and you order that much stuff
these things are especially effective
right you get something that says your
orders been delayed it's two ways this
affects people and it's kind of
interesting how this does it on both
sides right if you've ordered something
you want to know why the hell it was
delayed like oh no I can't live without
my you know whatever stupid thing it is
that happens to be in the box this time
just because I could order it for four
dollars and get it Prime shipped you
want to know why it was delayed right
but on the flip side if you didn't order
something that's the second class of
people you want to know why you're
telling if somebody's telling you that
your order was delayed it hits two
different groups of people different
ways and makes them want to click on it
like that
that's the enticing stuff that runs
behind some of these headlines that
they're putting out there of course
there's always the messing with your
money sort of thing everybody wants to
know about that and they're worried
about that when your money's getting
messed with so the bank ones are really
good all of those things kind of play
there but you can see where there's
they're attacking the people with these
things that get emotions going one way
or another and again they're successful
enough that this current state of things
right we've become this is the norm in
our organizations these days everything
is on fire
around us okay this is just our normal
our normal stance unfortunately but
hopefully we can do some things to get
out of that personally I think that
leveraging your users to help you with
that let's move on to the next one here
the real goal of security awareness
training I can't tell you how many times
I see people screw this up quite frankly
they do awareness training for checking
the box because whatever regulation
whatever something-or-another says that
I happened to do this right compliance
is not security is that shocking to
anyone in here okay just because you're
compliant with NIST or you're compliant
with PCI doesn't necessarily mean you're
secure oh wow that just ran right off
the side of the screen
okay everyone has a plan until they get
punched in the mouth I'll just spell
that out to you from the the great
orator Mike Tyson this is an interesting
thing for me because what we what you
want to do your goal for awareness
training is really to build reflexive
behaviors in your users when they do
something you don't want them to have to
stop and think about it spend a lot of
time on it you want it to come in you
want them to do whatever action it is
that you want them to do and then move
on with their day and continue doing
their job okay so that's really what
your goal needs to be it needs to be to
get people to identify these things have
a reflexive behavior and move on
unfortunately sometimes we fail at doing
that now when you're doing an awareness
program when you're trying to work with
your people when you want to turn them
into this human firewall thing there's a
few things we need to start with number
one when we set our goals we need to be
honest about some things we need to be
completely honest with ourselves about
the goals and what your organizational
culture will tolerate now I see a lot of
people come in and they want to do this
training and maybe even gung-ho for it
they see the value in and they're like
okay we're going to change all of this
stuff through the user training right
don't do that all at once if you try to
eat the whole elephant at once you're
gonna fail and that happens too often
and I'm gonna say something that may not
be horribly popular but I hope if we
look in the mirror we can understand
this a little bit more generally speak
us in InfoSec because I hate the word
cyber us and InfoSec us an IT those
sorts of folks we're probably not the
greatest with people all the time okay
we have to be honest with ourselves when
it comes to that right we're we're in
this place we're in this spot because
we're good with computers that do what
we tell them to do or if we screw up
they don't do it but at least that's our
fault humans are a whole different
ballgame for a lot of us right so this
is tricky for some people so when you
set your goals though you got to be
honest with yourself about some things
when you set your goals we need to get
away from setting qualitative goals and
move to quantitative what that means is
instead of saying we're gonna make this
better and that's our goal we need to
start putting some numbers behind it we
need to start measuring it we need to
start doing this because we need to
start doing a better job speaking with
our leadership too so when we go into
our leadership we're talking in the
numbers in the ROI sort of thing that
they sort of like to hear right so when
you set your goals set some goals sit
down take a little bit of time then the
next slide I'll talk about the magic
wand experiment but put some numbers
behind it for example I want to reduce
malware related tickets by 25% in 60
days you may pluck that number right out
of the air or wherever you're gonna
pluck it out of but that number is
something that you put on the board and
you may not meet it the first time if
you're not used to doing this and that's
okay but at least you have a goal to go
for you either exceed it you don't
exceed it whatever and then you can
adjust fire a little bit there but start
building quantitative sorts of goals the
organizational culture part is gonna
play a very important role when it comes
down to training your users if you're in
an organization that has recently been
breached or you're in an organization
that lets say a competitor has recently
been breached badly you're probably
going to be able to make more sweeping
large changes then an organization that
isn't really convinced that it's a
problem yet you need to look at that you
need to think about that how far can I
go how far can i push this how big of a
change can I make right now
and it takes a little bit of thinking to
do that but we need to be more aware of
that
I see people not think about that sort
of stuff when they come in just in
general with security programs that's
important all right I've been guilty of
it before come into a place and you're
like oh my god this place is terrible
you know this place is bad I need to fix
everything I need to do it now if you're
not in a position that that's going to
be supported by leadership because they
don't see the value in it you're gonna
fail at it so now the magic wand
experiment I like this because I'm a
Harry Potter geek I'm a nerd I admit it
just because it says magic wand but the
idea is if you could wave a magic wand
in your organization and change three
behaviors at once
immediately what would they be now don't
expect that you are gonna change those
behaviors immediately but at least that
helps sort out this stuff and typically
speaking what we see in this is it's
usually something around getting users
to quit doing stupid things and better
password hygiene because we're still
fighting that battle from 20 years ago
still right we still can't get passwords
right and then usually it'll be
something a little bit more related to
their organization right cover sheet for
the TPS report I don't know something
like that right we got to work something
else in there but generally speaking you
can pick three things like that and then
what you want to do is you want to focus
on those three things because you've
already identified that those are the
most important for you don't try to fix
everything because you will fail so just
spend a little bit of time on that we
recommend you take anywhere from you
know six 12 18 months maybe on some of
the big stuff if it really is that
important your organization to fix it
doesn't always have to take that long
and then what you do is occasionally you
revisit this and you go you know what
this has reached an acceptable level
because I have quantifiable goals that I
have met and now I can move on to
something else and then you go into
maintenance mode with those things so
magic one thought experiment think about
that in your organization what would you
change if you could change today use
that as your goals
now the next one dealing with the
politics of fishing your users right
that's always a challenge what's
important about this is messaging right
from the beginning
a lot of organizations when you start
talking about phishing your users along
with an awareness program which I think
is very very important there's that oh
you're gonna try to make me look bad
feeling
and that's not the goal of it let me
tell you something when you put together
these programs I'll talk a little bit
about how these play together a little
bit better in a few minutes here but
when you put these things together the
idea behind the phishing emails is to
give them a chance to practice what you
taught them in training okay you go into
training you learn something and it's
great okay who's gonna remember what was
in these slides a year from now nobody
I'm probably not gonna remember what is
in these slides a year from now nobody's
gonna remember that right especially if
all I do is show these to you but if I
were to sit down and have you practice
these things stick in your head and this
is what happens with the users this is
one of the big ideas behind doing the
fishing along with the training okay the
other thing it does gives them a healthy
sense of paranoia they get an email that
comes in and how many times have you
guys had somebody do something stupid
and you go to them and you're like what
happened and they go well it felt a
little weird but I clicked on it anyways
right that's the point where you have to
show restraint not throttle them but far
too often that happens they get that
kind of I call it the spidey sense the
little tingle in the back of their neck
that something was wrong with this but
they didn't really have another action
to do and so they went ahead and
collected well now what you're doing is
you're making them a little bit paranoid
because they know that you're sending
them the simulated phishing attacks and
they go I wonder if this is one of the
ones from the IT department I better
report it instead of clicking on the
link okay
gives them an out it's a little
psychology thing but happens very very
well and very easily the next thing is
and this kind of goes along with the top
one don't focus on the negatives so when
you do your messaging what you're saying
is we have a threat here there's a
significant issue we're seeing all these
things getting breached a lot of them
through email we're going to tackle this
through the users this is what we're
doing
we're training you guys to do a better
job and then you don't focus on the
negatives as tempting as it is to put up
the wall of shame so that Bob from
accounting there yeah okay far too often
we want to do that because man it would
feel good the shame Bob we don't shame
the users focus on the positives so what
that means is when your folks are doing
a good job
say thanks say good job a lot of times
what they'll do is they'll game if I
stuff like this so you'll say the the
department with the lowest click rate
for the quarter it's a pizza party you
know if you can't if your budget doesn't
allow for a couple of pizzas to try to
get people on board with this you've got
some other issues um but I mean even if
it's trophies even if it's a kudos to
everybody whatever works in your
organization's culture give them a kudos
make them feel good about what it is
they're doing go ahead yeah we'll get to
that we'll get to that yeah now I like
throwing him out of windows if you got
repeat offenders no we'll talk about
that a little bit you know the short and
sweet is you do it privately you don't
let them get away with it because this
is a threat in your organization so you
can't just let it go but remember when
you're starting your messaging your
messaging is always we're dealing with
the problem we're doing this not to
shame people but because there's a
legitimate threat these phishing things
if people are not paying attention and
they're not taking the effort to try to
spot these things and they're just like
screwed I'm not going to do it it really
ends up being no different than people
who are downloading pornography or you
know third party apps and stuff in your
organization that are doing risky
behaviors of other types and it needs to
be treated the same way and you
typically wouldn't shame Bob in
accounting for his pornography habit
right so you want to kind of treat it
the same way again gamified make it a
challenge make its make it fun people do
get nervous when you put this stuff out
there because they're afraid oh I'm
going to fail and then they're gonna
make me look bad
and it's gonna reflect on my you know
permanent record and you know all that
game a fight make it a challenge have a
little bit of fun with it it's important
that you collect stats and I'll talk
about that as part of the four steps
here but when you collect these stats do
something good with it let people know
you're doing a good job top-level buy-in
as soon as possible before you start a
program like this make sure again
through that messaging that your
leadership at the top understands the
threats and that may take subscribing
them to Forbes and Money Magazine and a
couple other ones right now which is
fantastic because all the time now
they're reading about these threats and
these breaches and all of these things
are happening in those magazines so it's
landing square in their their corners
right now
which has really helped us as a security
community to be able to get that message
across it's not just us running around
saying the world's on fire because
honestly we've been doing that for
twenty years maybe longer this time we
actually have a lot of back on that
we're seeing executives losing their
jobs we're seeing organizations really
being hit by this so we can get the
top-level buy-in but where this helps
you is when you do have those people
that push back on you and the executives
have your back and they're going no wait
a minute this is significant I've got
his back
that's a world of a difference in your
organization metrics and well-defined
goals again you got to measure these
things this is why I'm really stressing
having quantifiable goals because when
you're dealing with metrics and goals
and numbers you're no longer dealing
with Bob is a jerk I don't like him and
that's why we're gonna hang okay when
you can come in and say Bob is clicking
on 42% of the things that come in his
email just like everyone else then
everyone else is only doing at 10% or 2%
or whatever it's now not you picking on
Bob it's Bob messing up so it's
important to have those numbers in those
metrics and goals behind that it really
helps us paint this picture so moving on
here make an account
so I like to think about it this way we
really are arming our employees for
battle every single day they're getting
hammered with these emails the emails
are coming through and spam filters
that's for spam even the good email
gateways they'll do a decent job on some
of this stuff but even the best of breed
is still letting ten 15 percent of the
phishing or spear phishing emails right
through it's incredibly hard to stop a
spear phishing email from hitting a
person if any of you guys red team here
when you attack people when you attack
organizations attacking the perimeter is
great you can spend all day all week all
month doing it and sometimes you can't
get anywhere but you target those people
and you're in like nothing it's just it
happens right the filters all the
technology in the world these days is
not stopping these attacks from getting
through now endpoint protection is an
awesome thing you need it don't rely on
it if you're running stuff that's just
strictly signature-based I feel for you
go change that right now because
signature based stuff is not working at
all behavioral analytics all these cool
little buzzwords were flying around on
here on endpoint protection that's great
because you're going to need that if and
when it does get through all of these
different layers
slow it down reduce the number of
attacks that the people are seeing but
ultimately all things said and done
they're going to get through to the
users eventually somebody's going to
click on something you better have good
endpoint protection you better have good
backups in the case of like a ransomware
attack when it comes to fraud you're
kind of screwed quite frankly if your
people don't get it if your executives
if your leadership if your people in HR
or finance or any of those sorts of
groups that are handling money they're
handling information if they get fished
and they send the information out
you better hope your DLP catches it but
very often right now how many people
here are running a real DLP sort of
thing at your gateways ok I got like one
okay two hands two and a half hands okay
that's pretty difficult
we're not dissecting email we're not
dissecting that sort of stuff and
pulling it apart and looking for those
things very often so when it comes to
scams when it comes to that socials are
easy to spot you know credit card
numbers but what about a wire transfer a
request in the middle of all these other
requests how do you pick that one wire
transfer a request that was garbage out
of those things right you get an email
from your CEO it says hey I'm in
negotiations right now I got a deal on
something talking to one of my buddies
we're gonna buy this company we're
acquiring this company right now I need
you to send twenty five thousand dollars
to this account right now I'm in the
boardroom meeting with these folks right
now we're gonna take over this company
just get it done that's a pretty good
attack on people and in a lot of cases
25 grand out the door just like that
what's bad about that is then they'll
pick up the phone and say okay boss I
did what you said and that's usually
followed by what are you talking about
all right and that's where bad things
happen right that's a whole nother talk
I do a whole another talk on that sort
of stuff but when we're doing these we
need to think about a few things I love
this because it's so blatantly honest
three truths about human nature we're
lazy social and creatures of habit
design products for this reality design
your awareness program design your
security program around these as well
because if we try to fight against it
we're gonna fail so we have to
understand that we have to ease them
into things when we're asking somebody
to change their habits and what they do
and what they're comfortable in doing
and pull them out of that comfort zone
we're asking them to do a lot we have to
understand that when it comes to working
with people again we're not always that
great with people why not leverage in
and pull in maybe your marketing
department or your PR guru or something
like that
get them to give you tips and tricks you
don't have to do this alone okay so
think about that it's kind of an
eye-opening thing if you really consider
if you try to work against that human
nature we're going to fail you're
destined to pull another one
something that a lot of people don't
think about your awareness program and
the content in it are the visible face
of your department to the rest of your
company this is especially true in
larger organizations where you as the
security folks or IT folks don't
interact with a lot of the people that
are in your organization ever throughout
the year they just do their thing you do
your thing you haven't met them they
haven't met you everything's fine
where where your actual touch points
with these people usually it's through
your awareness program usually it's
through the training that you give them
every year and if it doesn't look like
you put any effort into it why are they
gonna put any effort into it why are
they gonna care so imagine this you're
building you're building your face to
them all right so let's say you're
somewhere where you just kind of throw
stuff up you bring them in every year
you throw them in a in a room and toss
up a bunch of powerpoints born to death
maybe after lunch like you guys you're
awake right okay
I imagine you do that to these folks and
then you kind of just move on all right
now Bob in accounting he does his thing
he clicks on the link and all of a
sudden well maybe not all of a sudden
maybe 10 minutes later his computer runs
really slow
and the fans are all running like crazy
right because he's clicked on that link
four or five times didn't do anything
the first time that was wrong with this
stupid thing I want to delete it right
so now Bob knows something's a little
weird because he can't do anything and
his fans are running a hundred miles an
hour and weird stuffs happening it's
Friday afternoon he's gonna go you know
what lock the computer screw it I'm
going home right as opposed to having a
bob that will call you up and go I did
something stupid guys and I know I did
something stupid please help me right
would you rather have Bob going home on
Friday while your network burns or would
you rather have him willing to call you
and say I did something stupid
we need to get ahead of this right
that's the things that when you're
getting out there in front of your
people and you're sending that message
that's gonna be the feeling that you're
trying to get through about your
security
apartment and your IT department are you
I'm not gonna say like warm and fuzzy
we're never gonna be people they want to
come up and give a hug to right that's
just not us but are we scary to that we
shouldn't be we can't be if you really
want them to help you out we can't be
scary when they call you you can't be
like what'd you do this time you idiot
all right we want to say it but we got
to understand that most of the time your
employees are educated in domains and
you weren't okay if you want a reality
check go to your accounting team and try
to do something in one of their
spreadsheets okay they got some amazing
crap going on we can't treat them like
idiots because they're not idiots
they're just educated in places we
aren't and we are in places they are
so things that are trivial to us are not
trivial to them and vice versa
we have to remember that we're dealing
with humans here everyone has a story
everyone has a background where they're
at so when we're talking to them we need
to take a little better approach at that
who remembers the Saturday Night Live
skits or the guys like move you know
just kind of coming in shoving people to
the side right that can't be us but we
have a reputation for that because again
we aren't always people persons that's
okay you need to be aware of it we need
to try to soften that a little bit so
there's four steps that we found who
work really really well when it comes to
awareness training and you can do this
again with or with or without our our
platform Oh No you know we make it a
little easier but other than that this
is four steps that we found work
incredibly well first get a baseline
understand how prone your people are to
be in fish okay this comes in importance
here as we move down a little bit but
make sure you understand just how prone
they are to fishing the second step is
you train them now there's some programs
out there that what they try to do is
they just start doing the fishing piece
and when people screw up then they try
to train it when they screw it up right
that's really not the best time to give
people the initial training how many
people here have kids okay
few more hands here I have
three of them they're all teenagers god
bless me but I can't tell you how many
times at least one of them has come home
at least once ever well every one of
them has come home at least once and
said man I had a test this week and the
teacher never even taught me what to
look for what to you know the material
right we've all heard that from our kids
if we have kids you don't want your
users feeling that way so don't fish
them if you haven't taught them how to
prepare themselves for it okay when if
you haven't taught them and you do hit
them with something you try to give them
point of failure training right then and
there they're probably pretty upset
already they're not gonna pay a whole
lot of attention to it right that's part
of the difference right there so you
train them teach them what to look for
we focus on like 22 red flags in email
it's actually not that complicated
you're not trying to teach these people
to be technical people because again
that's not their domain but you can't
teach them to look at things and go this
is weird did I get an email from HR at
two o'clock in the morning on a Saturday
and is that unusual that's a pretty big
red flag right there right maybe I
shouldn't click on this thing and put in
my social security number odd things
like that is there a sense of urgency in
the email that's never an immediate
discounters but if you start combining
that with a couple of other things all
of a sudden that little spidey sense
again is kind of going yeah you know
something's a little off on this and
they can react to it so we we teach
people to look for 22 red flags for that
you know if you hover the link does it
go where it says mmm that's a pretty big
red flag okay the other thing you know
take this time teach him about that
password hygiene piece each I'm about
passphrases as opposed to passwords that
is password one two three four and the
next month it's one two three five and
then you know what I mean we all have
users that have this kind of rotation
don't use the same thing on everywhere
that way when you are who gets breached
not everything else you own gets
breached I mean we should be learning
these things but this is where you're
gonna teach them all of those kind of
steps right and then you do the fishing
and quite frankly the fishing can get to
be a lot of fun in the beginning though
you may want to take it easy and that's
where this baseline test
comes in and frankly we can do it for
you you don't have to be a customer
anything we can set you up with the tool
to Fisher people and get you a baseline
there's no charge no nothing whatever we
can get you a baseline but what happens
is when you go to Fisher users if you're
in an organization that's already pretty
decent at spotting things say you're
down in the ten 15% fish prone
percentages you don't want to send them
the stuff with all the horrible
misspellings and all of that terrible
grammar stuff right don't send them the
Nigerian prince scam template if they're
already doing that because a you're
wasting their time be they feel like
you're wasting their time and they're
gonna feel like this whole thing is just
stupid but on the flip side if your
people have a 30 or 40% click rate which
is not unusual quite frankly you don't
want to send them the tough stuff where
they're like crap I'll never get this
this is impossible for me to spot right
you want to build their confidence a
little bit so send them the Nigerian
prince scam send them the things that
have those really blatant tells in them
so get a little bit more confidence and
then you continue to fish a muse you see
the results and those numbers are gonna
come down and as they come down make it
a little tougher but don't be afraid to
tell them to and you do it in such a way
that you're like you know what you guys
are doing such an awesome job here you
have improved so much you've dropped
your click rate down to like 10 15
percent we're gonna make a little bit
trickier now let's see who can hang on
here let's see who gets the pizza party
next month let's see who gets their name
on the wall let's see whatever it is
you're doing the game of I have a little
fun make it a little bit tougher but
tell them tell them we're gonna up the
ante here you guys have made us a night
II work harder
who doesn't love hearing that right what
user doesn't love hearing that so you up
the game on them and you just continue
to roll that through every once in a
while you may want to throw a little bit
of a training Adam throughout the year
that's specific to what's going on
first quarter things that are related to
tax scams everybody needs to be known
about that right so kind of pick a few
things as you go along but really if you
keep doing that what happens is they get
better at spotting them they get more
confident about taking the actions when
they spot them they're more comfortable
with it how many of us have employees
that are like terrified of their
computers right I worked in a machine
shop area 130,000 square foot machine
shop full of guys that had been doing
machine work since 1954 okay these guys
are used to large mills and turning
buttons and we deployed an entire system
with this it was an ERP system and
basically they're having to go to
computers and log in how many pieces
made it through the milling process who
met how many fail where we are here is
it going to make the order they're
having to put this stuff in there they
were terrified of computers you have to
build their confidence with that make
them feel good about what they're doing
and then you make it a little bit
tougher so those four steps will make a
huge difference five points to consider
when you're doing this I'm going to hop
through this build here you can't do it
alone
get your top-level organizational buy-in
and get your marketing department
involved have them help you with some of
these things right don't train on
everything because you're just gonna
overwhelm them with stuff pick those
things that are important hit him with
those people only care about things that
are relevant to that right how many
times have you heard people talk about
probably not to your face but hey if
they didn't want me to go to that
website they would lock it right we
can't block everything out there folks
we know that right they need to
understand that they have some
responsibility in it too and it needs to
be relevant to them as well right when
you're talking about relevancy to think
about this how many year think that
ransomware only hits people and
organizations right yoho-o know it hits
you at home two people have lost
pictures of their kids from infants
first birthdays everything else right
they've lost all of this stuff to
ransomware so what about when you're
talking to them about this training that
you're about to give them or what you're
about to do to them what if you tell
them that hey this is gonna keep you
safe at home have you ever thought about
all the stuff that's important you at
home all of your taxes all your cat
pictures from the hell it is they care
about right make it relevant to them
make it matter how many year have ever
had a cousin uncle mother-in-law
mother-in-law mother-in-law call you and
say something along the lines of
Microsoft called me and said my computer
has a virus and they're willing to just
log in and then fix it for me
and right we've all heard this and most
of your users have somebody that's heard
something like that it resonates with
them they think about it becomes
relevant to them because you're teaching
them how to be safe against these things
they can teach their family so make it
matter to them your mission is to come
along side the employees and help them
make wide secure wise security district
choices it's not to shove them down a
path or anything you're supposed to be
there supporting them and helping them
make those choices
they will learn to make those choices on
their own moving forward but you need to
come in maybe and help some of those
folks along and this is a way to manage
an ongoing problem this is not a
solution never treat awareness programs
never treat your spam filter never treat
your endpoint protector never treat your
backups as a solution I hate that word
there is no solution to this stuff it's
reducing risk at different layers okay
so there is no magic bullet for this
stuff it's got to be kind of a
comprehensive thing putting it together
oh the five best practice is to embrace
again explicit goals decide what
behaviors treat it like a marketing
campaign fish them frequently at least
once a month once a month we found that
if you do the fishing exercise is less
than once a month the return drops off
significantly if you can do it every two
weeks and just keep a running random one
going that's much more powerful and then
the last one again I can't reiterate
this enough don't be a jerk we've got to
quit alienating the people make them
feel comfortable coming to you when
there's a problem
now there's four stages of confidence
and I'm just gonna build this out this
isn't even my slide but I do love it
okay
but basically we start off with I don't
know that I don't know something we move
into I know that I don't know something
that's actually a good thing where
people are cautious they're like oh you
know what I don't know everything about
this instead of being completely
oblivious like all of my teenagers are
they're all still we're that way the
hell over here but then they'll move
about I know something but I have to
think about how to do it I have to spend
some time okay in the military and the
in the DoD it's like where you have to
read the manual on what the next step is
you've got to pull out the TTP to figure
out what to do next right
the
one is I know something so well I don't
have to think about it so using my DoD
experience I'm one of the things they
teach you in the DoD in the Army
especially is how to break down a rifle
and they teach it to you about 242 times
more often than you really need to know
just to be able to tear the thing down
and put it back together and the reason
they do this is when all hell's breaking
loose around you you can do it without
thinking about it it's just something
that your hands do it's a reflexive
behavior remember that's the goal of
what we're doing here is a reflexive
behavior these people as you get them up
in these stages and you will build these
stages over time eventually they get to
that point that email comes in they look
at it they go okay something's weird BAM
I'm recording it I'm moving on and I'm
doing my thing it doesn't take time out
of their business now when it comes to
getting them to do the right thing I
love the nudge theory thing and I love
this example of it
so the nudge theory is really something
that again I recommend you get people
like your marketing teams and some of
those folks involved when you're like
this
right the nudge theory comes into play
and this is a great example you're
standing there imagine you're standing
there with the soda bottle that you just
finished here right or that pan of rock
star which I - I love rock star they
just had one anything you can't sell
right according to this but on the left
you have a choice you're gonna put it in
one of these two spots on the left you
have the landfill it's kind of hard to
see it's a little blurry but that's
dirty trashy
garbage strewn everywhere unorganized
right
that's a nasty place to be on the right
hand side is the recycle and you almost
expect as you put the bottle in there to
have that like choir of angels singing
oh you know it's just so pretty we all
know that this is what recycling looks
like folks it's very pretty like that
right but as you're standing there with
that can and you're reaching out which
direction are you yeah you're probably
gonna go to the recycle one if you have
the choice right it's like in your
company break room putting healthy foods
at eye level and putting the garbage
down on the bottom right that's nudging
them towards making a better choice
without telling them they have to okay
there's nothing here that's gonna keep
you from throwing that can on the
landfill side but it's gonna make you
want to go that direction we see that a
lot in
like your password oils okay nobody
wants to have the read password and I
love this not great okay I don't know
that I've actually seen one that says
not great but you see the colors and you
know the difference between red yellow
and green right and you naturally want
to go up the scale towards green even if
it ends up you being angry because you
find out that your portal doesn't
support special characters and it grades
that completely on the length of your
password which is just stupid but that
didn't happen okay and I'm not still
upset about it but you get the idea it's
nudging you to do the right thing
without blatantly just throwing it in
your face
okay the gamification right playing the
game the metrics everything you do
reinforces your point and purpose in
this that's the other piece too and
we've talked a bit about this one
already so and I'll show you this graph
which is now what do you do once you've
taught them how to identify these things
you give them a way to report it if
you're in an organization you have a
phishing email right and it's fish
emails at whatever your organization is
and you have people who just want to
forward that to that that's great make
sure they remember who to report it to
when they get these sorts of things
that's one of the tricks to making it
reflexive we have a button again you
don't have to be a customer I'm not
selling you anything folks I promise
this is an awesome tool I just love this
tool goes an office 365 Outlook and
Gmail if they get something that they
think is a phishing email they click the
button it wraps it up with the headers
at all and sends it to someone in your
organization for them to do now this is
where the sensor part comes into play if
you get people that start reporting
emails let's say you get three or four
or five of these things roll into your
reporting inbox or however you want to
do it you can even set up a sim to do
something like this or if you get enough
of these things in a short amount of
time it triggers an alert you get
something like that you can pretty
confidently say we're we're being hit
with a phishing attack we're part of a
campaign they're targeting us we
actually get this all the time because
of who we are who doesn't want to own
the people that talk about phishing
through
right okay I'll give them credit they
want to try but we get this stuff and
they'll go hey you know what this email
is coming in if you see this this
subject line delete it so send it out to
all the users you can even go into the
email servers and just start wiping them
out on the larger organizations this is
great because now maybe 10 or 20 of your
people have gotten it reported it but
2,000 of them never got it mm I've never
thought they were never tempted by it
right so you can leverage people as a
censor through stuff like this the other
thing is if you're gonna use a tool like
this and there's several of them out
there and there's some that are free
make sure it's wrapping it up with those
headers so you don't have to go back to
the user how many here have done the
dance with the user where you're like no
no forward doesn't work no wait no you
got a drag and drop right yes get
something that's gonna send you all the
information you really need to spot
these sorts of things okay
the last year's Dvir who's so happy
because I've been talking about this for
a while now train your employees with
regard to phishing and provide them a
quick and easy way to report suspicious
emails like yes I'm vindicated I've been
talking about that someone else believes
it to remember to leverage your people
to also warn you so back to the agenda
here gosh I'm really gonna take these
builds up before I do this again dealing
with repeat offenders I believe we had
that question a little while ago how do
you do that well don't publicly shame
the users again it's so tempting
sometimes a sign remedial training now I
love this in our platform if they screw
up and click a link you can actually
automatically assign them remedial
training
nobody likes remedial training okay but
give them some remedial training it's
got to kind of hurt a little bit it's
got to be less than fun when they do
screw up I mean let's be honest about it
it may also teach them what it is that
they did wrong if you can assign them
remedial training that's related to what
they just did that's even better
focus on the positives hey you know what
you screwed up okay that's all right we
we know it learn from your mistake take
it seriously though don't let it go on
now if somebody
clicks on these things you can usually
tell the difference between somebody who
just doesn't care and somebody who's not
getting it
and there's another part of this too if
you want if you want to wait through the
whole bill to come I'm not trying to
call you out or anything but just trying
to help you out here
it's what's that it's see tell me how
that makes you feel okay but um when
something like this happens you may need
to involve HR so the first time you know
it may be like okay but you can usually
tell the difference between someone who
just doesn't care and someone who's not
getting it if they're not getting it you
may need to come up alongside them again
and guide them a little bit help them
understand if they just don't care and
they're like ask for this out then you
start you know the first time is it give
me maybe even the second time it's the
third time you bring the manager in and
you go hey come on Bob we need to talk
about this because remember this is a
putting your company at risk we need to
take it seriously so you step aside with
their manager and you say you know what
Bob your your activities here are gonna
cause a problem
and if we get breached because you
clicked on that how do you think that's
gonna look on your permanent record rate
as you're carrying the box out the door
because you're not trying if that
doesn't work bring in a charm bring in
HR and their manager and go but you
focus on the fact that this is causing
us issues because this is putting us as
an organization at risk don't focus on
the fact that it's Bob and you don't
like the fact that he wears that stupid
tie every Thursday okay focus on the
fact that 91 percent of successful data
breaches start with what you're doing
pal you know we see this stuff happening
in the news all the time this is because
of people doing actions that you're
doing Bob we need to fix that and if
you've gotten them involved from
involved from the beginning HR should
have no problem putting them on a pit
because your messaging has always been
about the numbers behind it it's always
been about the risk that's going on
it's not about Bob pisses me off when I
look at him so HR we've seen many
companies put
right on a bit because it is serious
enough that it could tank your company
right any other activity that they're
doing that's stupid like that they're
getting it in trouble for don't let them
slide on this if it's significant though
make sure you're involving their manager
and HR don't do this alone don't you
come up to Bob and go Bob I'm gonna get
you fired if you keep screwing up and
you don't take this seriously you have
to involve those other people if you're
in an organization that's big enough
when you're setting this stuff up get
legal involved to make sure they're in
line with what you're doing and why
you're doing it because they'll have
your back as well take it seriously so
does it work this is something that
blows people's minds I mean it and and
I'm not doing this to try to sell you
I'm telling you because a lot of us have
probably murmured the phrase at some
point in our careers especially its
older folks that you can't train use or
you can't fix users you can't patch
users can't fix stupid that's not true
and I'll tell you I think the problem
has been historically with us we don't
do a good job training the users and and
I don't mean to make that sound bad but
again that's not why we were typically
hire we were not hired to be people here
people
we're hired to deal with technology okay
so it's not necessarily one of our core
competencies so when we don't do it well
we put it back on the users and we got
to stop doing that this is six million
users in 11,000 organizations this is
not a small sample size folks this is
not oh this doesn't apply to my company
this is everything all right this was
not cherry-pick this was like all of the
users we had for at the time that had
been there for a year
27% initial click rate was the overall
average and we have some breakdowns of
this by industry and stuff like that
which is sometimes pretty shocking but
overall this six million people were
clicking on things 27% of the time so
that's like one in four of the phishing
emails and lands on someone's inbox
they're clicking on it
that's a problem that's a big problem
when I talk to people in the field I
talk to people that have much higher
percentages in this starting out too so
this isn't fluff three months later by
training them how to spot these things
and within 90 days or so you've probably
started one of your phishing campaign
something along those lines by that time
it's reduced it down to 13% these are
all the same people down to 13% click
rate that's like of the initial risk
okay if you stop at that point
it's gonna edge back up probably never
hit the 27% again but what happens is
it's gonna edge back up as people aren't
thinking about it life takes over you
know it's no longer they're no longer
paranoid about it you'll turn em again
next year right by continuing that
phishing exercise this same six million
people was down to 2% 2.1 7% at the end
of a year that is a huge reduction in
risk with what's going on
so don't convince yourself that you
can't do this with your people because
you can you see it all the time
it may not be comfortable for us to
initially do but that's why you don't
have to do it alone you get other people
involved with it but I'm here to tell
you you can train people to be able to
spot these things and to be able to be
actually a very important part of your
entire security program no longer the
users a problem these users can now be
part of the solution you get that
reporting stuff going on you get that
sort of stuff going on in your
organization people feel confident about
what they're doing they're picking up
the phone to you and they're going hey
you know what something is wrong with
this you're down on the tail end of this
thing and it's it's a good feeling I
worked at a place had about 250 users
about 200 and 200 something of them were
developers god help me again okay you
know production is there to make those
quick patches those sorts of folks right
what happens though is a lot of times
there are people that are like
developers and technical people we
I really suck at this sometimes because
we're too confident we think we know
everything not to pick on any developers
do we have any developers in the room I
need to see if you're bigger than me
okay I think I could take you but but
you know a lot of times the developers
are like I know what the hell I'm doing
and they're just they're real
comfortable stuff and they click things
and things go horribly wrong right but I
was in this organization had a lot of
developers I was kind of rolling out
this sort of stuff and I've always at
least later in my career I've realized
the power of being friendly to people
when it comes to stuff like this but we
were kind of a small shop 250 users kind
of under the radar although we dealt
with some pretty big things
matter of fact we did it we were a shop
we did unemployment sort of stuff I
think we did actually the payouts for
all of the state of Tennessee okay for
unemployment so if you're unemployed and
you're collecting that check that was us
yeah but we weren't really well known we
had somebody send in a w-2 fraud email
came in from the president and the
company looked just like his stuff went
to the HR director said I need you to
send me all the tax stuff I'm about to
get on a plane I'm traveling I'm gonna
look at it and then I'm gonna send it
off to the tax guy when we land okay
fantastic wonderful she hit me up and
said something just doesn't feel right
about this and the boss was one that
would be involved in these sorts of
things he was a very in the weeds sort
of person and sure enough his email
looked good but the reply to address was
something completely different we found
out that they actually got his email
signature and the information that he
was traveling out of his out of office
reply okay they had all that stuff it
looked beautiful but the lady that got
it said something feels weird and she
felt comfortable enough to come to me as
the security guy and go something's
weird about this can you take a look at
this for me and that made the difference
between us being in the paper and not it
happens in the real world I've seen it I
felt it as far as the resources I've
talked about human we got a ton of free
crap over here
no before Tom /resources also security
awareness company is out here if you
guys saw any of them as a vendor a great
group of people they have a
of cool resources for you too if you
want to help build out your awareness
program and things like that and finally
last but not least something I didn't
mention in the beginning how many here
have heard of a guy named kevin Mitnick
okay he's one of the partners in our
organization so he helped build out you
know a lot of our training and stuff
based on his social engineering skills I
have a couple of these kevin Mitnick
stainless steel lock quick business
cards that I'll trade what I have here
for one of your cards if you want or
whatever also the lockpick village folks
back there have one of these two that's
really kind of cool so check them out if
you don't get a chance to but this is my
contact info feel free to reach out to
me anytime
I'm always here to talk about this stuff
I love to talk about this stuff so feel
free thank you very much I'm open for
any questions and stuff that you have to
how are we doing on time two minutes we
got two minutes for questions anyone got
questions questions waiter we got one
over there well first of all you need to
let your legal department know that
that's wrong
I mean fact is the bad guys are gonna
use it right so do you want to set up a
program where first of all there's some
legal things about that that it's not
illegal to use those there's some
misnomers there's been actually some
campaign spread to say that you can't do
that however like in our case we use
real logos we use the logos that they
keep posted on their site we're not
trying to make any money off of using
their logo necessarily we're training
the people right so you may want to have
that discussion with them all right but
the fact is you know if you're using if
you're sending emails to these folks
especially if you're trying to get them
up on the on the lower click rates where
it's tough to spot them if every logo
you have is like a pizza smut okay
they're gonna spot that in a second
they're gonna know exactly what to look
for so that's not going to work in the
long run but you can reach out to me if
you need to I can get you older some
folks that can talk about that but there
was a lot of back and forth about
whether or not that was okay to do and
it is it's just fine so in the back
there
[Laughter]
and these humble folks a lot of it is a
confidence so she has she feels good
about doing it she's got some positive
reinforcement somewhere in there
somebody said good job to her probably
or she says that to herself we need to
make sure the positive reinforcement
happens one of the things that that fish
alert button if you if you do use our
platform when we send you the phishing
emails the simulated ones if they click
on it they report it it pops up and it
says congratulations good job you've
done a good thing here folks now
positive reinforcement is good likewise
if they're sending you this stuff in if
you reply to them go hey thanks a lot
for sending this to me that's gonna give
them that better feeling when they do
spot the phishing of the real ones
make them feel good about it build that
confidence yeah it's that's usually what
it is is whether or not they've felt
confident or somebody said good job to
them it doesn't take a whole lot so okay