see so with eridan let's just go quickly
around introduce everybody and I'm just
kidding
before we start who recognizes these
guys yes ma'am
Bonnie and Clyde right so what made
Bonnie and Clyde so successful in the
late 20s early 30s as bank robbers - two
things one was the interstate highway
system and two was really fast cars with
v8 engines and at the time if you were
able to rob a bank in Arkansas but cross
the border and to let's say Texas you're
home free the police couldn't couldn't
follow you and the FBI was what I think
ten five ten years old at that point so
Hoover came along and said hey maybe we
should make bank robbery a federal
offense
so we said maybe we got to think about
this stuff differently because this is
starting to really suck and these guys
are becoming heroes and we all kind of
know how it ended after they did that
not only could they follow him across
straight lines but they died pretty
tragically but the reason I put them up
there is the FBI at the time had to
think differently about something that
we we take for granted today of course
bank robberies should be a federal
offense duh but back then it wasn't so
obvious and all of us are in some way
shape or form working in cybersecurity
either academic cider studying it or in
business and I think we've based a lot
of what we do on what we did and just
because it's the way we did it doesn't
mean it's the way we should continue
doing it and I've been doing this for a
long time and I'm certainly learning a
lot every day when I try to find videos
that I think are emblematic of our
industry
I always try to show him and and venues
like this and I think I found one that
was pretty cool as on Reddit and I saw
this I have no idea where this is or
what this is but I think it really kind
of encompasses what our industry is if
you think of these guys with the white
shirts and I guess white helmets as the
defenders and the guys are running at
them as the attackers I think it kind of
shows what we do day in day out
it's only about a minute
[Applause]
and that just about sums it up right I
don't know who you have to piss off to
be the guy in the top of the pole but it
looks like it really sucks so a little
background on me I've been doing this
for about 20 years I started my career
with just the Defense Information
Systems agency down in Fort Huachuca
worked for Bell Labs a little bit in
Brazil but then I just started building
security startups companies like RIP
tech I was like employee five at arc
site built Imperva salera Networks took
McAfee through the Intel acquisition
I've written a couple books I wrote my
last book with the director the NSA I've
done a lot of work on the intelligence
side as well so I've been doing doing
this for a while with a lot of different
companies and learning a lot I've worked
in about 50 countries and as you can
tell they're all very high in
carbohydrates but I'm wearing this
pocket square and I read that it's
supposed to make you look thinner but I
caught a glimpse of myself in the glass
and I think mine's broken so if you guys
know of a good pocket square repair
place I'll definitely swing by what I've
got for you I think is a pretty cool
presentation I've spoken out a bunch of
b-sides over probably like the last six
or seven months this is actually my
first b-sides in Nashville so again I'm
very excited to be here it's about
killing this idea of assumptions
assumption based security that we assume
our products are working the way we want
we assume our Security's providing the
the capabilities we need and then also
addressing of iron metal drift the idea
that's something that was working
continues to work overtime and because
of day to day activity change in a tap a
span poured a patch a signature a rule
something that was working has stopped
you know I invested millions and
millions of dollars in a security
control that was logged into my sim but
then somebody an infrastructure
installed a proxy which is now blocking
syslog now I have no idea why I'm not
getting my information anymore and
attacks are going PI and I'm not getting
them so that's what I mean by
environmental drift I'm going to show
you several demonstrations today of kind
of how you can hack your own network in
order to validate and do security
instrumentation I'm not here to pitch
you a product I'm not here to talk about
the varied in way but I am here to talk
about security instrumentation kind of
as an idea and how you can approach it
we're not the only company who does a
but I want to talk to you a little bit
about how it can be done so boy that's
gonna be hard for everybody to see good
thing I'm not going line by line if you
we if we look at techno
ecology and kind of how it's evolved
over the years from cave paintings to
computer systems and radios and
telephones and everything like that we
live in a pretty innovative time who
would agree that we probably live in one
of the most innovative times in history
when it comes to technology I would I
would agree maybe not as fast as Wakanda
but I think we're we're pretty damn
innovative now I was told that of Greece
hadn't been sacked by Rome that by 1492
they would had a man expedition to Mars
but my dad told me that and he's from
Greece so consider the source on that
one but what I think is really
interesting is it's it's not a linear
progression right we have these quantum
leaps that we take occasionally in
security and one of them if we look at
Joseph jacquard he was the inventor of
the automatic loom essentially was the
world's first mechanical computer and it
was definitely the predecessor to
computer punch tape and computer punch
cards actually IBM took the design from
that and used it for their first
mechanized computer punch card design in
1899 but what was neat about this is
they develop this computing system that
could help make textiles specifically
blankets and they went for making about
ten a day in this Factory of workers to
making over a hundred a day because they
had these memory cards so input/output
it was know as a computer
well the employees got a little bit
scared they're like look they can just
buy a bunch of these machines and
eventually they're gonna replace us with
them so they one night they all gather
together they broke into this Factory
and they just smash this machine to
pieces I always think it's very ironic
that the world's first computer suffered
an insider threat right but then you see
things you know we had ARPANET in 69 and
then tcp/ip and you know web browsers
and Google and then the epitome of our
civilization is Netflix's skip intro but
in which that person was a genius that
came up with that if you're trying to
binge-watch anything but we make
assumptions all the time that this
technology is going to work it's going
to be safe and secure that's going to do
what we want if we put a key in the car
we expect it to turn on if we you know
turn our phone on we expect it to work
that I know one of my colleagues today
his phone wasn't working today on the
campus and it was made like very
difficult for us what's this look like
looks like an ant right
this actually isn't an ant it's a spider
- ant mimicking spider even nature makes
assumptions so this guy takes its front
two legs and holds him up in the air and
says hey look these are just in ten I
and he goes walking around an ant colony
and all the ants go hey what's up with
her aunt because they assume he's an ant
well he's not an ant but he likes to eat
ants so he looks like a nap so that's
the ant mimicking spider so it's not
just humans we see it in nature as well
assumptions are always made so the
problem is when you start making
assumptions in cybersecurity it starts
to really suck and things start to break
down you start spending millions and
millions of dollars on security I was
working with a major financial in the UK
they have over 350 security vendors not
products but disparate vendors within
their organization that's the extreme
side but I see companies all the time
with 50 60 70 different security vendors
and they're basing their a security on
these assumptions that everything is
working the way they want without
actually validating so here are some of
the issues that we see we assume
technology works as the vendors describe
there's a lot of good vendors out there
there's probably some bad vendors 1,300
security vendors got Series A funding
just last year 1,300 that's probably
about a thousand too many right some of
them are great in most cases they're
doing something new not something
different like so I'm on the board of
silence for example so silence does end
point in a new way I did arcsight which
was a sim arc site did it in a new way
you know Imperva it did wofe in a new
way but it's been a long time since we
had something it was actually different
a different category of security like
instrumentation that actually says hey
let's not just do something new let's
actually do something different let's
turn on its ear the other thing we see
is we assume products are deployed and
configured correctly
maybe the vendors the absolute best
product in the world but look at
products that are really great like Palo
Alto firewall I think it's a great
firewall highly customizable highly
configurable though you know ids/ips
like Sourcefire snort very configurable
silence very configurable it's very easy
to make a mistake especially if you
don't have a way to validate that what I
just did actually does what I want
and doesn't break something else in my
track it's very hard to do and it's not
just tech it's people in process as well
I want to make sure my people are well
trained and well practice so when
something bad does occur that they know
what to do in the processes they follow
actually work and I don't want to do it
by doing like a little war game once a
year where we sit around a white table a
whiteboard and kind of write out who
will call and what we'll do
that didn't work 20 years ago it
certainly doesn't work today and then
finally my favorite is about
environmental drift we assume because
we've got things working and it's really
just swimming along great that it's just
gonna continue to do that and it's never
the case a lot of you probably worked on
red team's and do pen tests and security
assessments and you know as well as I do
by the time the last line of that
reports printed out the network has
changed things have changed
vulnerabilities have changed and the
whole process starts again and I and
I've done this you know where you've
gone into organization view a pen test
you come back the next year you do it
again it's the exact same thing all you
need to do is change the date because
people haven't had a round of fixing it
so there's this massive gap between red
team and blue team offensive and
defensive right that's a problem so at
the core of this is the fact that we're
spending a ton of money putting a lot of
time and resources and security is not
being effective so my idea is this
there's this notion out there called
security instrumentation probably a lot
of you haven't heard of this but quick
raise it raise of hands who's heard the
term security instrumentation before
okay a couple year it's great a good
analogy for it it's probably not a good
analogy but an analogy for it if you
think about automated manufacturing
right I kind of like the Joseph jacquard
thing we talked about with textiles you
know we you know Henry Ford was great at
this idea so let's go ahead and build an
assembly line we'll go faster better
cheaper higher quality this that and the
other thing will instrument it will tune
it will improve it well and then fast
forward to like something like HP
openview has anybody in here ever used
HP openview is familiar with it a couple
yeah you know if you've got a router in
Nashville and a router in San Francisco
and the link is green it's up if it's
red it's down if it's yellow it's
flapping something in between
essentially in security we don't have
anything like that I mean I can tell you
Palo or silence or Imperva or our arc
site or all these products are up and
running I can't tell you if they're
doing what they're supposed to do could
just as easily tell you the hairdryer is
running I don't know if pal is blocking
that attack
if it isn't reporting it to the sim if
it is is the sim correlating it I have
no idea I have no way to do that so
that's what instrumentation tries to
address so I'm not going to necessarily
talk about how we do that or burden but
I want to talk about it as a concept so
consider this consider a very simple
model where you have a management
counselor we'll call it a director all
right this director is going to have
integration with your back-end defensive
sex things like your sims your lock
management your Palo Alto panorama is
your checkpoint firewall managers or
silence managers McAfee EPO wherever you
do security aggregation log management
etc okay and we'll get back to why
that's important later and then consider
these things called actors or sensors
that are applied throughout your
environment in strategic locations let's
let's look at how that works so here's a
very simple environment everybody here
probably has a much more complex one
even if it's your home lab but you've
got an internet connection you've got a
DMZ critical servers desktops etc etc
throughout these environments you also
have a ton of security controls right
whether it's Paulo or McAfee or sister
or whatever you happen to have there
sitting in this network so you take
these sensors and these are
self-contained sensors typically the way
instrumentation companies work is
they'll deploy these as virtual machines
and they can be hardware it can be like
a intone look I've even seen people do
it on a Raspberry Pi I wouldn't suggest
that for production it can live in a
cloud like Amazon or Microsoft but
there's just little self-contained
sensors they're not living on your
oracle database or patchy web server
your router your firewall anything like
that they're just by themselves in these
disparate Network zones big companies
sometimes have about a hundred of these
medium-sized companies still you know
maybe they have a few dozen of these you
usually don't see people running
thousands and thousands of different
actors this is where it starts to get
really interesting these actors act as
both attacker and target and this
changes the entire paradigm that I was
talking about this is why it's different
this is why it's not the same old stuff
we've been doing for 20 years the actors
only attack each other and in doing so
they're validating the efficacy of the
security controls for which they're
passing through hey attacker actor a
attacks actor B did get blocked or not
if it did get blocked
did at least create an event if a
created event had to go to the firewall
manager if that did did it go to the sim
it
got to the sindee to get correlated
which goes back to my talk before about
the API integration with your back-end
defensive stack very simple concept very
different actors deployed to attack each
other in order to validate your security
controls I'm not attacking your database
as your web servers your desktops
attacking myself which means I had zero
false positives which is great because
when you go back and say hey this
firewall didn't block it it's not some
kind of qualitative squishy our OSI
calculation it's real empirical data it
didn't get through and if it's a really
good instrumentation solution it will
further take the step to say hey by the
way if you didn't block it or you didn't
detect or you didn't correlate it this
is what you need to add then you go
ahead and add it you rerun the test to
make sure when you added it you didn't
stick a space where there should have
been a tab or a colon where there should
have been a semicolon and say okay now
it's actually working and now I want you
to test this once a day with a thousand
other tests every single day in
perpetuity that changes the game because
now we're validating security controls
we're not simply scanning for
vulnerabilities and seeing if we can
exploit a hole on something because
somebody hasn't patched it that's so
important red teaming security
assessments pen tests still absolutely
critical this augments it but it also
gives you a completely different angle
and because of that it's valuable not
just for red teaming but for blue
teaming and as you can probably
extrapolate from this it's equally
valuable for not just CISOs and CIOs but
also CEOs and even the board which is
always been a gap for security you know
we're in a situation where for decades
we've been saying hey we want a voice
security wants a voice with the
executive team we want a voice with the
board then oh then crap now it's
happening now they're saying okay that's
great you guys have a voice no you
better be able to measure security like
we measure other strategic business
units like sales and operations don't
come to me and tell me you need two
million dollars for DLP because we need
to protect our data and it's important
and everybody else is doing it come back
with empirical evidence tell me how much
it's going to cost and then I can say is
this a two million dollar problem or is
it not and if it's not you move on to
the next thing that's how we need to be
communicating at those levels and every
security team across the world starting
to do this and we're starting to see a
fundamental change generally speaking
and a lot of organizations the seaso
reports the CIO I'm seeing that flipping
now
in fact a major pharmaceutical just last
week that I work with now the CIO
reports to the CSO and a lot of reasons
that that that's happening is this
because of decentralization
consumerization of IT cloud etc CIOs
don't have the umbrella effect that they
used to business units are operating
more autonomously so they can be more
agile well what's the umbrella then then
the umbrella becomes a risk the umbrella
becomes security so now it's starting to
flip-flop in this particular
pharmaceutical the CIO promoted himself
to C so and hired a CIO under him all
right I'm sorry actually to see this in
a couple other organizations as well
very interesting change but let me pause
there just for a second because this
architecture is something new and I'm
going to actually show you this in
action it's one thing to talk about it's
another thing just to show it to you but
any questions at all on the architecture
of how instrumentation works okay cool I
like to break things up with jokes and
fun facts because you'll hear me drone
on about security and your brain needs a
break so sharks are actually older than
trees no relevance at all to what I'm
talking about I just thought I'd share
that sharks are actually 400 million
years old and trees are only 350 million
years old so I learned that on reddit so
anybody here going reddit that's a today
I learned on reddit I actually learned
it a few weeks ago but I thought was
pretty freaking awesome
they've also survived like for
instinctual events to it pretty cool so
anyway sharks are older than trees okay
now your brains had a break so what are
some of the usage scenarios for security
instrumentation well the first thing is
just I want to validate that my stuff's
working and I'm not gonna go through all
these I'll probably hit the top five I
want to be able to validate that my
firewall my IPS my endpoint my way all
these tools are actually doing what I'm
expecting them to do well duh of course
we want to be able to do that but we've
never had a platform to do it we've
always tried to kind to do with
assessments and audits and revealing
stuff but it's never empiric it's always
very qualitative second thing is I want
to be able to prescriptively tune that
that's still on point one but I want to
be able to say now I haven't just found
a hole but this is how I can fix the
hole which brings us to point to when I
make configuration changes I want to
actually be able to validate that that
change is doing what it's supposed to do
it it doesn't have a negative impact
someplace else
or when somebody else in my environment
makes a change reorders firewall rules
changes a tap or a span installs a proxy
that it doesn't break something that was
working we see all the time million
dollar infrastructures brought down by
five dollar configuration errors that's
the norm right number three I want to be
able to manage by exception I want
somebody to have to farm this stuff all
day long I don't want to have a team of
engineers focused on an instrumentation
tool I want to all happen in the
background and if anything ever moves
from that green state that known-good
to a not good state then I want to be
alerted so I can manage by exception I
don't need to be dedicated to this with
the cloud as well a big thing that we
see in clouds today is the fact that
clouds flat it's very hard in a data
center to stick your database on the
wrong sides of firewall it's a very easy
to do that in the cloud and a lot of the
breaches you see - they're just because
of that so if you want to measure paths
and segmentation and things like that
having those actors and sensors follow
that pathway to make sure it continues
to operate that way is actually a really
big deal it's a simple deal that's a
really big deal and then I want to
retire unnecessary stuff probably the
biggest value-adds we see from CFOs say
security people never take anything out
it just builds and builds and builds and
builds it's like a basement full of junk
yeah some Christmas decorations and some
Easter eggs from the 1980s and a Stretch
Armstrong that dried out it's ridiculous
we don't get rid of anything well with
this you can actually validate hey these
tools are working these tools aren't
these tools I can't even tuned to get to
what I need these are completely
redundant will get rid of all that
garbage then and then take that revenue
that you're gaining from not having to
pay support and maintenance and
everything else and use that to buy the
tools and hire the people that you need
that's a huge one in fact the seaso for
black stone did a video on our website
just about that you know again I'm not
talking about our company but it's like
you know Brian I love instrumentation
but all these other points are great the
big value out that I had is I went in
and I said hey we can rip out over five
million dollars for the product we don't
need and use that to buy five million of
dollars worth of product we really do
need
alright so pretty cool stuff also
because these actors are instrumented so
they only attack each other it's very
safe I work with a lot of power and
energy and oil and gas companies people
like the New York
exchange British Petroleum etc these
actors when they attack each other first
off they don't just speak tcp/ip they
can also speak Modbus and dnp3 which
makes them applicable to skate
environments with PLC's and other
industrial control ot environments right
because they're not attacking your
program the logical controllers or your
turbines that are all running on Windows
NT 4 oh and haven't been patched for 15
years because it's been ended life
they're actually operating in a way that
allows you to measure the efficacy of
the security controls protecting all of
those devices right which is really cool
so quick show of hands how much of your
security is managed by assumption I'll
give you a just a second to think about
that ok who thinks all of their security
is managed by assumption ok a few truth
tellers who thinks part ok none no nuns
and who just doesn't know ok let me show
you the statistics that we got from a
survey we recently ran two percent of
these people are horrible liars honestly
it's gonna be part I don't think we're
in a world today where I could expect
everything to be run based on
assumptions or at least year you have a
pretty good idea that what you're doing
is actually working maybe it's been
proven out through some other mechanism
but by and large people are managing
based on assumption that's what we see
at least in at least part if not all of
their environments ok let's go ahead and
show this to you because looking at this
is one thing but the actual attacks are
actually pretty cool is it going to
screw up the videos if we close the shut
the lights down is that ok why do we
track us it's just a little small and I
just maybe makes it easier for people to
see ok let's try it out how's that a
little bit better for you guys so what
we're going to do here is we're going to
execute a couple different attacks
between actors and just see how our
security controls respond pretty pretty
basic idea and what I want to do here is
I made a video of this because the demo
gods never never play dice I'm going to
run a sequence of various attacks using
Bar deluxe and bot tracks a bar deluxe
for those of you don't know it's a
memory resident dropper it's also
purpose and license to grab other bad
things that can install
so Bart elects is downloaded doesn't see
to beaconing it grabs vaad track bought
tracks the real bad stuff vowed tracked
us from CT beaconing starts moving
laterally looking for databases dumping
credentials turning off local firewalls
and at the end of this attack we're
going to actually exfiltrate data over
ICMP but you can use any Protocol SMTP
HTTP SSH etc you can compress it rip it
right at target whatever the cool thing
about this is we're actually not doing
this to your databases or your systems
it's going on in your production network
but just between these actors so it's
safe but according to all your security
controls because these are the absolute
honest-to-goodness real attacks this is
the real stuff so your palace your
source fires your impervious your arc
sites etc your Splunk s-- they should be
picking up on this and saying guys we
ought to block this and or alert on this
or correlate on this this is really bad
stuff happening and by the way most
instrumentation solutions will ship with
buckets and buckets of attacks but good
ones will also allow you to integrate
with threat intelligence feeds like
anomaly pull a nice ack information
powershell stuff write your own stuff
python ruby very extensible that she's
very very open so essentially i said
this is the attack sequence i'm going to
run and then i selected which actors i'm
going to run it between you'll see or
maybe see assume it's there there's a
little spinning circle up in the top
right that's the director talking to the
actors it's basically you telling the
actors what their role is your bar
tulips your bob track you're going to
exfiltrate data you're gonna do this
you're going to do that to take great
now we know what to do I've got my
little Lockheed Martin kill chain on the
top right as well everything from
reconnaissance to action on target so
these are the activities that are
emblematic of what a real attack would
look like because it is the real attack
bits and bytes going across your network
on your production controls done safely
my favorite part is this there's two
columns here they couldn't be simpler
first column is was this blocked yes or
no we know empirically no false
positives Iran Bartle X was bar LX block
yes or no period the second one is hey
by the way regardless of that did it
create an event so I ran this attack it
wasn't blocked but I at least did it get
detected and here we have it reporting
to cue radar and Splunk there's where
that API integration to your back-end
management stack kicks in right so went
to curator and went to Splunk good
it wasn't blocked bad but also bad is it
went to curator and Splunk but I didn't
show up as a notable event or a
correlated event which means no one's
going to see it some of our customers
get 50,000 events a second they're not
gonna see this nonsense so I goes
further down and say okay what about
this one so now I'm looking at the
Vaught track portion of the attack which
wasn't blocked but did create some
events you say oh cool it made two
curator and it made it to Splunk in the
case of curator and Splunk for VAR track
it actually correlated it it created a
notable event so now I'm saying okay now
I'm in a situation where not only did I
run the attack and it wasn't blocked but
at least my sim correlated it so a human
is has a much higher percentage chance
of actually looking at this thing so
that's a good thing now back to that
Bart elects one if you didn't correlate
it a good sip will tell you this is what
you need to add in to do that and I'll
show you that in another example in just
a moment but that's what we just did
there is we just took some attacks so
think of your boss calls you up hey hey
Brian I've heard about this thing wanna
cry
Apache struts bad rabbits whatever you
name it are we safe from this CISOs and
security folks get this call all the
time it's very hard to say empirically
yes we are know or not usually oh we
followed best standards we've got in
this date hundred fifty three for our
sim and I saw this and that but it's
hard to say empirically well if you can
say let me grab the peak app let me
execute the attack and say yes we are
here here and here but no we're not here
and the reason we're not here is because
I asked for IPS investment dollars in
this network and you said we couldn't
have it because we had to throw a
customer company barbecue and now you
can say ok so now if you'd like me to
block it I need somebody to invest and
maybe we we don't do the barbecue and
say ok now I can make a business
decision but again it allows security
people to talk in empiric ways instead
of just saying we stop bad things from
happening it's really cool anyways show
hands what solutions do you find most
difficult to get value from and this is
one of the ones that I think I already
know the answer but it's always neat to
see what people say so we've got
firewall endpoint IPS DLP and sim slash
lock management so who finds firewall
the hardest to get value from ok and
point
pS okay DLP and and sim
yeah simin DLP ro is the always the bad
one sim by far I think just because
people feel like hey I just spent a lot
of money on some I mean I've been in
deals you know back in the day I was at
Ark site for seven years we sold some
sim deals that were upwards of fifteen
twenty million dollars right and if
you're only getting 10% value out of
that that really really hurts right but
DOP is not far behind
anyway that runs DLP I'd say 99% of the
time you're just running it in detection
mode because you're afraid to block
remember when ISS first came out with
automatic remediation and it would
integrate with your checkpoint firewall
and everybody this is the greatest idea
ever so everybody turned it on when an
attack comes it will automatically make
a firewall rule change within 48 hours
we all shut it off because the CIO tried
to VPN and thought it was a DOS attack
you know we didn't turn it back on for
like 20 years and that's just how it
worked because you got burned right so
people don't want to turn it on but what
if you could validate it empirically and
say yes it's gonna block this type of
thing boom I've tested I validate it I
trusted it but I verified it and now
it's working now we can actually make
forward movement security people can
actually become more strategic now okay
I'm gonna tell it Jeff but I've been
told there's only some jokes I'm allowed
to tell so why were the Romans so good
at algebra because X always equals 10
huh get it
I had a better joke but I was told I
wasn't anyways so let's talk about snort
I think everyone has everybody here
which would snort pretty much or at
least you know what snort is and okay
very simple I'm gonna run an attack I
just want to see if snorts actually
going to detect it and send it to my sim
that's it very simple very easy so we
have a pretty pretty basic Network here
and I think I've got security onion
setup for this part of the demo
hopefully it moves here I made a video
to avoid any demo problems and then I
get demo problems there we go okay so
we're just going to run a single attack
we call it actions and bear it in but it
doesn't matter whatever instrumentation
tool you're running and there's a whole
bunch of attacks to choose from this one
we're running angler anger has been
around for a while it's nothing fancy
nothing cutting-edge it's not like one
of the 14 wanna cry variants or
something like that and each one has the
CVE the pcap all sorts of different cool
stuff about it which is cool so I'm just
going to pick two actors and imagine it
this way imagine that you've got an
actor and another actor in the middle of
it is snort can be that easy and snort
hopefully has some kind of integration
with your with your sim whatever your
sim might be well here we see that the
attack was not blocked but furthermore
the attack didn't create an event so it
wasn't detected okay so that's that's a
problem we want to fix that because we'd
like to detect Engler so we go into our
instrumentation platform and says oh
here's some prescriptive ideas you can
go to emerging threats you can go to
Paulo you can go all these different
sites to download stuff so we're
pivoting out of the instrumentation
solution we're going to emerging threats
which probably never you're familiar
with and says hey if you'd like to
detect Engler here's a signature you can
add in so I'm going to do this really
really cool hacker trick right here I'm
going to copy it and then I'm going to
use this other hacker trick called SSH
and just snort I'm going to paste it and
that's as fancy as it got so my
instrumentation solution said hey you
didn't catch this here's a signature to
use if you want to
go ahead and add it let's try it
again that's it
this is just snort restarting adding it
to adding the rules to memory nothing
really fancy there so now that I've
added it to snort
I want to validate that what I did
actually worked so I'm gonna click on
this button up here that says run again
what that's gonna do is it's gonna run
it again
and when we're ready to can hopefully we
get better results now we didn't change
anything from a preventative perspective
I didn't try to block the angler so we
see it's still not blocked but boom the
event came up and sure enough we see
that now it was detected by snort tied
into my security onion and reported to
Splunk as an actual event and that's
pretty cool and now we can take it to
the next level we can do it so there's
actually a notable event coming out of
Splunk so that's pretty cool stuff when
we run these tests and organizations
some of the statistics that we see I
think are pretty interesting 75% of all
attacks that are run between actors are
not prevented I don't care if you have
AV people in your security team or it's
just you this is just the way it is
because people haven't had a way to
validate that their tools are working
the way they want and that's a crappy
number right he wants to drive a car
that only works 25% of the time less
than 40% of the attacks that are blocked
actually have an event that shows up in
your sim so out of that 25% you only
know less than half of them actually
even happened right and this isn't the
extreme case this is the average case
that we see I don't care if you're a big
government organization if you're a
start-up this is this is what we see
okay
is everybody here familiar with sim
technology log management and you're
probably a lot of you would Splunk as
well
Splunk is a sim that I'm fond of as well
I think it's a great one also highly
configurable a lot of complexity there
so what we're going to do is we're going
to do something very similar to what we
just do with snort but I'm just going to
do it with spunk it's all about is
Splunk correlating my rule so this one
I'm gonna use VAR track if you recall
from our first example we use the odd
track as part of a large sequence I'm
just going to use this single bought
track attack though not Bartle acts and
no data exfil an exact same thing I'm
going to execute a vote raccattack
between a couple actors I'm gonna see if
anything makes it into Splunk okay so we
run this goes through this process
you've seen before it's not blocked but
we see it's created a couple events now
so let's drill down into these events
and let's see exactly what what our sim
told us so remember this was a bot Rack
Attack yeah we see all the raw data that
came across to us from Splunk and that's
pretty cool we can dive into that but if
we look at the metadata emerging threat
info we have some packed executable here
we have terse off of numeric executable
download or high likelihood of being
hostile nobody knows what that means
it says everything in the world but bot
track the person who wrote that log
doesn't know what that means so you're
you're kind of at a disadvantage as a
security person how do i how do I
actually write a similar that's
effective so now let's go ahead and
pivot to Splunk this is Splunk
Enterprise security so smokey yes so now
we're in Splunk we're going to create a
name a description but this is the real
cool part right here we're gonna paste
the information we got from the
instrumentation platform that says this
when you execute vah track in your
network this is what it looks like
based on your systems your
configurations and your tie in to Splunk
it won't look like that on your network
your network your network here you're in
there just the network it was tested
this is why when I was at Ark site we
could never share rules amongst
customers because attacks are always
different everyone's network this is why
you have to test it on your protection
network with a real attack and see how
your systems respond so anyways we ran
the attack with vote rec it wasn't
blocked Meriden the the sip solution
that we're using here says hey by the
way this is what you want to use we
added it in we ran it again and now we
said look it came out as a correlated
event or as Blount calls it a notable
event pretty cool stuff and I can tell
you that one little use case I just want
to write a rule in my sim and validate
that that rule that I just wrote worked
that's the one of the biggest use cases
in the world for some configuration I
wish I would have had this in my days at
Ark site then my pocs wouldn't have
taken three quarters to do they're
always a pain and I don't care you're
using elastic if you're using Splunk you
radar alienvault whatever
sims are really really hard to get right
and they're very expensive and they take
a lot of time and resource and at the
end of the day you have no idea if
they're even working
which isn't a great model the first stat
I had showed you was all about
prevention this stats about detection
response as we all know detection
response is much much more expensive
much much more manually focused right
but if we start looking at this from
okay we've figured out we're only
blocking 25% of our stuff we're going to
focus a little bit here of the attack
patterns that are not blocked less than
half of them had alerts in the sim so
not only was it even blocked it wasn't
stopped at all but less than half of
them even have an event they're not even
being detected right so again it's not
just tuning your preventative controls
it's tuning your incidence detection
controls now let's pivot from Network
good instrumentation solutions should
work across network and endpoint and
email and cloud and be able to validate
all those different controls so
endpoints a little bit different instead
of deploying sensors and strategic
locations this is how you do it and this
is really cool a good estimate ation
solution shouldn't require you to put a
bunch of code and agents and things like
that and all your desktops and servers
and again that's 20 year old thinking
you know let's think differently what we
say is go ahead and take a version of
what you're running a production either
a server a desktop you might have five
or six different iterations whatever I
don't care what your application is I
don't care that you're running some
custom tool that you're running exchange
that you're running active directory
that you're running Oracle or Apache
none of that's relevant all I care about
from this perspective is hey Brian I'm
running Windows 7 with silence I'm
writing Windows 10 with McAfee I'm
running Linux with that and running Mac
with that whatever and I want to go
ahead and stick that on an on production
system could be a VM whatever and throw
an actor on top and then I want to
execute a bunch of endpoint attacks can
I steal credentials can I shut off the
local firewall can i edit the host file
can i rename services can i exfil data i
want to test non destructive attacks
things that aren't horrible but are
certainly bad on the other side I also
want to be able to test destructive
attacks can I install a sandbox first in
our world we call a protected theater
but whatever it's a sandbox on top of
that then you sawed off the OS then you
install the security
control the endpoint and then you
install the actor the reason you do that
is now if you execute malware and then
Symantec doesn't block it you want to
burn down that image and bring back the
last known good image typical sandboxing
approach with the caveat is we're not
doing it for forensic analysis we're
using it simply to say we ran ten pieces
of malware your endpoint security
control only block nine of them let's
help you tune it so you can block all
ten that's it and the reason we do the
sandbox is we don't want them out or
getting out we're controlling all the
network input/output so it doesn't do
any beaconing see - bla bla bla right so
let's look at that oh one more not
offensive joke - give your brain a joke
let's see if I can tell this one so I
got this one off for reddit this morning
so there's these three sailors and
they're on a life raft or something and
they've got three cigarettes but they
don't have any matches
so one sailor gets a great idea and
throws a cigarette off the boat and the
guys well why'd you do that
how does that make any sense because I
just made our entire boat a cigarette
lighter right well that crush when I
read it three in the morning and read
it's okay so let's look is everybody
here familiar with PowerShell or shell
it's good all right so I'm not gonna go
too much background if you want to get
more on PowerShell you certainly can
research it but I'm going to run some
PowerShell attacks
I like PowerShell for a couple of things
I think one of the best ways to use
PowerShell against Windows is to steal
credentials so we're gonna go ahead and
do something pretty cool so a good
security imitation solution should allow
you to write your own attacks in
whatever shell including PowerShell you
can use Korn shell if you want to
whatever you want to do but let's say we
want to go ahead and write something
that we'll go ahead and escalate our
privileges we want to get system level
privileges so here it's well it's really
hard to see that on there I know but
there's an actual PowerShell attack
that's in there as you know it's it's
it's pretty simple it doesn't take a ton
of code to do to do the PowerShell
attacks but I'm gonna break it into two
pieces one I'm going to show PowerShell
running and then to say let me just
check what what user privileges I'm at
right now on this endpoint system then
I'm going to run my attack and see okay
what user privileges do I have now so
basically I'm gonna run Who am I
run a PowerShell
and then do the same exact thing and see
what the result is so the way you
execute endpoint attacks an
instrumentation solution should be very
very similar to the way you do it on
network email cloud etc so in this
example I'm pulling up on the PowerShell
attacks and we can see you might not be
able to see but it says Who am I on the
top and this is PowerShell on the bottom
ok so let's go ahead and run this we're
gonna run it just like you saw before
again nothing's really different when
you're doing it on on endpoint which
should be exactly the way it's done now
this is really cool
because when we run this PowerShell
attack this is the type of thing when
you're doing a pen test or any type of a
security assessment it really helps to
augment to you know when you're showing
people the results so we ran powershell
and the first one runs Who am I
and it says ok you're John Doe so it's
not really an attack it's just trying to
level set things right now our
privileges are John Doe ok well that's
what we expected it wasn't stopped in
create an event
there's nothing malicious about running
Who am I but the second portion of the
attack actually executed the PowerShell
script that we just put in there and
when we ran that and we look at it it
actually says workgroup slash system so
the power show was actually able to
escalate our privilege levels our
endpoint security product did not stop
it it actually did create some events
but it didn't stop the attack and we see
that a lot with endpoint a lot of
endpoint security controls will be like
hey you're getting hit by something
super bad just FYI not because it's a
bad tool event it comes out to
configuration you know when people buy
security products they buy it for two
main reasons one how good's the default
configuration and two how much do I like
the SC that sold it to me that's it
that's not a bad reason really
but default configurations aren't
necessarily going to be the best
configuration for you and we see that
with firewalls and other tools as well
this one's really really cool everybody
here knows some me me cats me me cats is
bad stuff often tied to getting you know
golden tickets and things like that when
you have to burn your servers down to
drill holes in the hard drive me me cats
can be used for a number of things one
of the things that's really good at is
still in credentials so let's look at an
example we're gonna run Mimi cats now
just like we did before with the
PowerShell attack we're gonna run it
against some endpoints but now I'm going
to run it again against a bunch of
endpoints and
but I've chosen here in my lab and I set
this up as I've got Microsoft Defender
I've got Symantec I've got malwarebytes
does anybody here run malwarebytes okay
this one's gonna sting a little bit and
I've got silence right and I say that in
jest because I actually I know a lot of
the guys at malwarebytes it's not a bad
it's not a bad endpoint this all has to
do with how these tools happen to be
configured in my lab and some of them
were purposely not configured optimally
or else it would be a pretty boring
presentation so I'm basically selecting
all the systems oh and I have a test
case to where I have everything turned
out so it's a wit it's all windows it's
all Windows seven and some Windows 10
but it's a test case so nothing's turned
on not even Microsoft Defender okay so
we'll kind of see how these different
things operate so I basically select ok
I want to run it against these five
systems remember these are non
production systems running all these
controls probably on a VM right and each
one has an actor I executed just like we
did before so endpoints run really fast
so let's look at this first one we ran
Mimi cats against Microsoft Defender
right off the bat Microsoft Defender
stops Mimi cats and we can see the raw
data and it logs it now did it log it to
our sim but that's okay because maybe in
our lab environment we didn't have that
set up it logged the local stuff to
windows right windows events so at least
they said hey I see Mimi cats it's bad
and I'm gonna tell you about it so
Microsoft Defender actually did a really
really great job as it comes to this now
we're running it with Microsoft oh and
here's the command line log by the way
so when these executed will tell you
what happened this one's already really
boring I said hey you tried to run
something and I said no that's what you
want to see you want to see something
really really boring
we don't want exciting things to pop up
in this command line log well now I'm
running Mimi cats against a Windows 7
machine running no security at all so as
expected
Mimi cats was not blocked and as
expected Mimi Kass did not create an
event but let's look at the command line
lug if you've run Mimi cats before you
recognize a little kiwi up on top so
Mimi cats is not iterating through all
everything its enumerated through all
the other credentials here and we're
looking at ntlm and sha-1 hashes and it
will continue to run and operate and go
through and tie the entirety of the
system until mimi cat says bye and exits
the machine
so all we've proven at this point is
it's better to run Microsoft Defender
than run nothing at all in this case
okay
so Mimi cats exited successfully okay
now we go to malwarebytes malwarebytes
was exactly a successful in this case as
running nothing at all
it didn't detect Mimi Katz and it didn't
report on it now we have silence silence
did not block it and we can see the
whole little Mimi Katz comes up and runs
but silence came up and said hey I just
want to let you know Mimi Katz is
running it's really bad and but silence
did log it to Splunk at least and it
told Splunk about it but Splunk actually
didn't correlated an event on it so you
probably wouldn't see it anyways that's
that whole instrumentation cycle now
malwarebytes and silence absolutely
positively can block Mimi cats they just
have to be configured to do so and
oftentimes out-of-the-box there or not
and then we look at the last case here
is semantics semantics interesting it
blocks it and they tell me it's because
it happened so quick it blocks it but it
doesn't log it so I asked Samantha oh
yeah we're just so fast we don't log it
that's right but whatever so
but semantics did lock it which I guess
if I have to pick between the two I'd
pick block but um it didn't log it and
again it's not to say one is better than
the other right at all at all this is
simply to say don't think of this as a
security assessment or pen test against
these systems think of this as a way to
evaluate where the gap is to help you
instrument in tune to get it where you
need to be right you're not gonna throw
out Splunk because it didn't create a
notable event you want to tune it and
get to the point where it can that's why
it bridges that whole Red Team Blue team
gap that's whole purple team idea right
we're all BFFs this one breaks my heart
again after years and years of being at
a sim company zero to 45% and 45s being
really nice actually
zero to 45% of correlation rules
actually ever fire when we're at a
customer site zero to 45
that's awful zero is happening sometimes
when you're spending all this money on
sim and again most of you raised your
hand for sim DLP was number two these
are hard devices to get right in terms
of validation you can do all the right
things have all the smartest people but
one little change was made in your
network that you had no can
roll over something was changed in a
firewall or a tap or whatever and it
makes these things stop working we've
been in situations where people have
rules written in their sim predicated on
IPS that they don't even have in their
environment anymore so then I'm going to
see the information and that happens a
lot remember that bank I mentioned with
350 different security vendors I
guarantee you're there Sims a nightmare
another fun fact this is a pallid room
so tacocat
and race car are actually palo drums
alright that's pretty cool
Atlanta is not even though my nephew
who's 25 years old and I call him mr.
baby thinks Atlanta is but it's not and
he's a moron
so last demo I'll show you and I like to
hold this one to the end because this is
you know we're all on security and
sometimes security doesn't have there's
a lot of voices we want with the
executive team it's because we're not
always speaking the language they want
and then sometimes you're invited to go
present and you get really excited and
you have a PowerPoint with a hundred
pages and all these technical bits and
bytes and then they never invite you
back because you scared them right so if
you have a way to speak their language
and a very simple very clean way that
talks about business risk without
getting into the details we find to be
very very effective and and you actually
become this hero so everything we've
done thus far that I've been showing you
has been all these ad hoc tests test
this test that the boss says are we
secure from that and I want to validate
but the real power of instrumentation
tool is the fact that where you get
things where you want it I want it to
all happen automatically and
continuously every day or twice a week
or whatever and do this validation
because it's very low load on your
network it's not even really detectable
each each attack is only a couple
packets but think of it this way I've
got a bunch of stuff that's green if
anything turns red if attack is allowed
if IPS isn't detecting if a sim isn't
correlating then let me know because now
something's changed from a known good
state to a bad state and then further in
addition to being able to do that we ask
people hey do you want three-dimensional
spitting Globes and laser beams and all
this stuff and they said no we want a
heat map that an executive non-technical
non-security person understands they
understand red is bad
they understand that green is good and
they understand other colors in between
is probably something in between and if
they look at something they want to say
hey Brian I see a bunch of
stuff here can you tell me about that
and then I want to be able to drill into
it and say yeah this is our critical
server Network it looks like we have
some issues here let's let's drill down
and see what's wrong and by the way
these colors for a good estimate ation
platform should be configurable but now
if I drill into one of these I see that
oh this is my critical server Network
but I got a whole bunch of clear text
protocols opened up I've got FTP telnet
I've got DNS TFTP pop and all these
other things I'm like okay that's a
problem and I also see anonymous FTP is
allowed I'm seeing that the actors can
go ahead and do PII data exfiltration
and they can also do exfiltration or
credit card data so now I can go to them
and say hey we got a problem where we
were leaking data and customer data and
credit card data I need a way to block
this so I get on the phone with Bob the
infrastructure guy say hey Bob why are
all these clear text protocols opened up
this is supposed to be all encrypted he
does all I was doing some testing on the
network I forgot to shut him off I know
that never happens in any of your
environments but it happens to other
people so you say please just turn on
port 22 sure everything else stops oh he
does done I'll set we're good to go
so we say run again which as you all
know runs the test again and when we run
that test again what we find out is port
22 is in fact open now but he forgot to
shut off port 69 TFTP so now we're in a
situation where we got to get back on
the phone with Bob Bob what happened
oh sorry fat fingered it forgot to put a
hash sign in front of that go ahead
we're good to go now so now we don't
trust Bob at all so now we're going to
create the the Bob continuous monitoring
rule so every day forever we're going to
go ahead and validate that the only
communication paths between the critical
server network and other networks is SSH
and should it ever happen to add port 20
21 or port 23 for telnet or whatever it
is let me know so I can get back on the
phone with Bob now multiply that times a
thousand or thousands of continuous
monitoring checks and now you're doing
real instrumentation and now you're
communicating to your bosses effectively
and now you're showing them reports
about what's working what's not and now
you're explained to them in terms they
understand why you need two million
dollars in budget to hire people and
invest in technology you're speaking
their language or speaking about
business risk and you're measuring it
just like they measure ops and sales
so extremely powerful capability this is
the last stat I wanted to share with you
this this is an interesting one this
company had 80 people in their security
team
they ran 765 attacks on their production
network about 500 came from our tool
came from Barden
they had anomaly as a threat
intelligence feed so they used some of
that they went to malware traffic
analysis and they dumped a whole bunch
of pea caps and they had some folks are
a pretty bright they wrote some stuff in
Python I think one or two things in Ruby
so a good combo of us in them kind of
anyway 765 attacks in total 67% of the
attacks were not blocked ok 80 people on
their security team 67 were blocked more
than half the attacks weren't logged to
Hue radar and it turned out they were
actually blocking syslog on a lot of
their systems that they didn't think
they were
it wasn't even getting a DQ radar which
was a problem because security only used
Q radar
Splunk was used by IT ops which was only
19 percent effective then we broken up
by product said oh and by the way I
think these are all good products I'm
not saying anything bad about web since
Paulo stores fire fire I but take a look
at fire right and by the way this was
when wanna cry was happening so
everybody was really concerned about
ransom or a hundred percent of the
attacks were allowed for fire I a
hundred percent of the ransomware was
allowed for fire I they spent fourteen
point four million dollars on their fire
I implemented four months before we got
there fourteen point four million
does anybody here work with fire I it's
a great product
you got configured correctly these guys
configured it with a very simple air
fire I needs to look a bi-directional
traffic the fire I see is unidirectional
traffic because you messed up your tap
or span port says I'm going to drop this
I have no idea what the session is in
this case it was completely useless it
could have just as easily been a
hairdryer eighty people in this room the
seaso and the CSO they had both kind of
had a palm to head moment they're like
how can I legitimize spending a single
penny on another product or another
person if the stuff that we've got isn't
even doing anything so he turned over he
goes well at least source fighters doing
a little bit soft forty-one of the
attacks and it blocked a bunch of stuff
and the one person in the room that was
responsible for source fire raised their
hand and said well that's not exactly
correct we've actually thought about
moving source fire
to preventative mode and we've actually
altered the logs so they report
prevention because we're in the process
of pushing things over but we haven't
actually done that yet so they were
creating fake logs right so this is not
the extreme again and it's not to go in
there and say you guys are stupid your
baby's ugly well it the baby is ugly but
oh you have bad products it is simply
saying to say guys you got complex
solutions we've got a lot of smart
people and they're doing a lot of great
things but they never had a way to
validate that that what they're doing is
actually working in a pen test and
assessment and audits not going to do
that furthermore there was no way to
look for environmental drift over time
so with that let me go ahead and open up
to questions as we have a few minutes
and see if you guys have any questions
for me yes sir yep yeah so the nice
thing about this is the attacks that you
run are the actual honest-to-goodness
attacks they're not some kind of virtual
thing so if you run like angler of odd
tracker Bartle X that's what it really
is so if you go ahead and implement what
the what the tool says to leverage you
should only be blocking those types of
attacks because it's predicating the
actual process and that's a well known
problem what you're going through every
every security person doesn't want to
block and they'd rather allow ten bad
things and stop one good thing that's
often the way people approach problems
this you don't have to worry about that
you're actually blocking the real stuff
with us great question though any other
questions yes sir
yeah there are some open source things
there's a attack from mitre
so check out some of the stuff miters
doing it's a little bit more myopic in
that it's focusing on just a I think
there's like 50 different attacks that
you're able to run for some pretty
specific things but I think it's a good
way to start kind of I don't know making
making people aware of what a tool like
this could do before you go into some
type of commercial solution like us or
some other some other instrumentation
solution this is a very very new field
so my company varied and we've only been
around since 2013 but we've only been
shipping products since 2016 so this
isn't something that's been out there
forever like endpoint or anything so
it's a concept that most people haven't
heard of before so take a look oh it
might or does I think you'll find some
cool stuff there anything yeah we
absolutely do and we've I didn't have
time to go into this but there's tagging
capabilities in this four CVEs the
attack framework we do stuff for gdpr
and other types of things as well this
date of 53 and the state hundred ninety
two so it can be tied to that and then a
lot of people take that on the backend
you stick some taxi to push things out
as well so it's it's what we call it is
our open so the way we do it and don't
really want to pitch us but we have an
open content platform which means we
want you to be able to take in any type
of attack and use any type of attack
framework that you'd like to use you
know it's very easy to use you don't
need to code or anything awesome alright
thank you everybody I appreciate it
[Applause]