all right cool all right so welcome to
social engineering for the blue team
green edition
my name is Timothy d-block this is a
green track so I have catered this talk
towards people just getting into the
field I'm gonna talk through some of my
experiences really this talk is getting
noticed at work to improve security
mindsets and get things done so if you
were looking for something I don't know
a lot more technical this is really just
social skills getting along with people
building relationship type of talk why
this talk because I think relationships
when we're talking about inner
organizations is really important it is
probably the most important thing within
the InfoSec community we do a really
great job of going to these conferences
building relationships having a good
time talking to each other I mean I go
to developer conferences and they're
always in all the talks whereas if you
come to a security conference a lot of
people are often out in the hall
laughing having fun getting to know new
people networking in general we do a lot
of that stuff really well but then we go
back to our own organizations and we
have a hard time getting security
implemented within other departments
those same techniques can be used to
build better relationships and
organizations get more things done
within security ultimately you know red
team a lot of the same techniques that
they're using to break into buildings we
can use within our own organizations on
the blue team side and again you know
why should the red team have all the fun
which you'll also find with a lot of
this stuff is that it will help with you
know life improvements connecting with
family friends job opportunity so if
you're really stuck in doing these
techniques can help you get better at
interviewing and making connections with
people and then of course also once you
get into an organization get more
responsibilities career advancement
things like that so my role I work at
premise health it's a on site well
company we have 600 clinics from 275
clients a lot of them Fortune 1000 44
states and two territories we have 4.2
million lives covered that's more than
most hospitals which means there's a lot
at stake and I my role is to sit with
the developers I don't sit with the
security team I said with the developers
so it is very important that they
actually like me because we have a lot
of stuff to protect or they're handling
some sort of information through a lot
of their systems a lot of different
processes of moving data all over the
place different things like that so
often times I have to come in and say no
or I have to give them guidance or I
have to you know pretty much make them
do things the proper way which means
more work for them and the conversations
go a lot better if they like me more
than if I'm just coming to them saying
you need to do this now so I see
relationships is very important and I
have managed to build some really strong
relationships with them to the point
that when I ask them for something and I
might just be asking a question they're
willing to drop what they're doing and
just go do it for me which is which is
amazing but before we get to how I'm
able to build those relationships people
we're gonna actually step take a step
back to my story and coming up through
IT and information security so as a wee
lad and as you can see there you price
all the little redheaded girl running
around spitting image right there but I
was a fun-loving kid had a lot a lot of
lot of fun got A's and B's in school
then I had to get glasses right around
the fourth or fifth grade I became aware
of my social status which was nerd so I
was picked on I was bullied didn't have
a lot a lot of friends and I became
enamored with trying to fit in to the
point that my grades suffered one of the
advantages I did have though was my dad
was in the Army so we moved around every
two to three years so I had pretty much
I got reset every time so no one knew
who I was so I had an opportunity to try
a different way of
acting with people and but I failed a
lot I constantly failed so and that was
really frustrating but after watching a
lot of MacGyver and then a brief stint
and Jenko jeans in high school yeah I
don't know if anyone who remembers Jenko
jeans yeah who wore who wants to admit
they wore Jayco jeans there you go all
right yeah I ended up joining the Navy
and else we doing the Navy because I
knew I didn't wanna go to college
because of the same people that bullied
and picked on me we're going to college
and if I was gonna be picked on and
bullied we're all gonna get picked on a
bullied in the Navy and plus girls and
girls like a man in uniform
right so it's an advantage I've always
had a problem with talking to women and
I at one point one like five years
without a girlfriend I was really
nervous around women couldn't talk with
them didn't know how to start a
conversation I had after my first duties
there towards the end of mine my first
duty station I had a really crappy six
month period so I had happened I did
manage to get a girlfriend she dumped me
my roommate left me left me with a
two-bedroom apartment apartment in San
Diego California to pay for for the last
four months and then I got captain's
mast right before I got out or right
before I was going onto my next duty
station
I was capped as fast as I came in late
like an hour which was actually pretty
standard for a lot of people who were
going to the next duty station he just
kind of rolled in a little later he left
a little bit later the reason why I got
captain's mast was one because
leadership didn't really like me
but two they they came in and a lot of
people are within the Navy so the
previous leadership had let things get a
little bit slack I spent you know I got
done what I needed to do at a very
minimal level and then had you know
spent a lot of time on the internet for
the rest of the day so I wasn't looked
at in the most positive light and and so
that was kind of just a really crappy
period and so but this was kind of kind
of out of this really kind of opened my
eyes so I need to do something I got to
figure something out and so I started
doing some really was focused on like
dating advice things like that but part
of that dating advice I found this
called feel the fear and do it anyway
about dr. Susan Jeffers what's great
about this book is that it really helped
me kind of accept the thicker realize
that I'm gonna be in uncomfortable
situations and then I can grow from that
and kind of just leaning into it and I
mentioned this here because social
interactions can be very intimidating
and so this is kind of what started my
path down down this down this journey of
trying to interact better with people
and connect with people better
of course my dating life doesn't prove
through through this book and and some
of the old dating stuff but another
strange thing happened which was my life
in general just improved like everything
was just a lot more positive it wasn't
perfect but it did improve which was
interesting to me so went to my next
duty station worked hard and expanded my
role I got to you know do some crypto
stuff I got I became a teacher I was at
a submarine learning facility I'd never
been on a sub and but they allowed me to
do some like teaching on Navy core
values because I wanted to teach became
a forklift operator and that is one of
the scariest things when you're moving
multi-million dollar equipment around
with a forklift and you're like just one
slip and there's some pretty steep
driveways but I was also a PT assistant
so I helped out with doing morning PT
things like that you know and then right
before this was I spent two years here
right before getting out I did six years
and I had people ask me I was I was
there for my last PT on Friday and I had
a lot of people ask me what are you
doing here
go away go stop making us do awful awful
exercises so like that was just a pretty
much I pretty much had flipped
everything for my first duty station to
my second duty station because I started
focusing and actually getting some good
advice so fast forward
I pulled cable after getting out systems
analyst system and network administrator
and then I got my first security role
put my two weeks in and right before or
after put my two weeks in with my CIO he
said something interesting to me he said
you get a lot of work done and everyone
seems to like you
now this was something that that I knew
I got along with people pretty well but
no one had explicitly called that out as
a strength and then realized I've been
trying I've been struggling with
interactions so this was the first time
that someone said hey you're like people
really like you and this kind of sparked
some inquiry by me like what am i doing
right like what exactly is getting
people to like me a lot more and and
also I started making that connection
between well maybe it's my relationships
having those that's allowing me to get a
lot more of this work done because I did
walk up to people and they were giving
me answers or you know dropping what
they're doing to help me and that kind
of started me death down this path of
discovery digging in a little bit more
we're at a couple books these are pretty
much salesman type books seven Habits of
Highly Effective People how to win
friends and influence people they talk a
lot about different things you know with
like favors and reciprocity and
relationship building and you know body
language nonverbal communication things
like that what made things really click
for me though was Chris eggy's books
social engineering as I was reading some
of those Red Team techniques I was
realizing holy crap that's what I'm
doing with these people within my own
organization
you know I'm asking how they are I'm
blending in I'm doing all these
different things that allowed me to
build those relationships and and here's
what I kind of learned these these are
these are what I can recommend as far as
building better relations with people
ask questions my mom always told me to
ask questions and even if they're stupid
yes you will sometimes you will get
laughed up I was laughed at a lot but I
always ask questions it's a great way to
learn but it's also people love talking
people love talking about themselves
people love talking about what they do
if you want to be seen as a
conversationalist ask questions and keep
asking questions this requires some
active listening and continuing the
conversation at this point now my whole
game internally is to keep asking
questions of people to keep them talking
because the more I have them talk and
the more the
the better connection I have with them
and their people are feeling about me
and this doesn't have to be necessarily
from a technical level you can get down
to the personal level how are you is
powerful it is you know often times I'll
say how are you doing and people just
open up with all sorts of stuff and I've
been you know blown away with what
people will open up to me with and often
times I mean if you see someone having a
crappy day all right how are you you
know
everything okay and sometimes people
just want to get it off their chest and
that again helps you build that
connection with that person a little bit
something I should mention here is that
we're doing this all for an authentic a
genuine standpoint I wouldn't recommend
doing this from manipulative standpoint
cuz this can get into manipulation and
if you're just taking taken from people
people will figure that out and that's a
good way to burn a relationship so
you're doing this from a very authentic
authentic and genuine standpoint when I
say how are you or are you okay I I
actually mean it you know is there
anything I can do to help you out and
people really appreciate that and this
is one of the strengths within the
InfoSec community is our curiosity with
technology and you know how things work
and how we can break them that same
thing applies to a person under sort of
how the how you can break down but the
the the understanding how they work how
they're doing who they are as a person
are all very important going the extra
mile if you work hard for someone else
they will work hard for you this is what
I did at that second duty station I was
all over the place I was picking up
responsibilities here and there and that
was really saying something to people
right before I got out I had a master
chief who was leaving told me hey man I
expect great things from you and that is
that is something that stuck with me and
is very powerful and shows that you know
they appreciated what I did and and
thought I'd go a little bit further so I
go the extra mile for people I often
tried to solve problems for them this is
also both from a security standpoint but
also not necessary from a security
standpoint I have access to our service
desk system and ticketing system and
oftentimes the developers will put in
tickets and if it sits there for a while
they'll come to me and then I'll go look
at it make
sure it gets routed to the right person
somes often within the service desk
sometimes things just fall through the
crack it took someone two months to get
a get a battery at one point and all it
took me was was looking at that and then
go and then going and talking to someone
about it and then finally got things
moving they really appreciate that type
of stuff and so then when I go back to
them with something from a security
standpoint they are more than willing to
help me because they know that I have
their back and that I'm willing to go
the extra mile for them will go the
extra mile for me
and this is called you know favors a
reciprocity where they want to call it
it's it's you know this isn't something
that you're counting this is just
something that you're doing naturally
and will come back to you when you when
you need and often sometimes it's not
even that so that the spiel about my
company is you know marketing wants to
get out and get some more brand
awareness for our company premise health
and I said well what can I do to help
marketing isn't necessarily somewhere
that I'm gonna you know benefit directly
but building that relationship with them
if they get some kind of phishing email
or they have some kind of security
question they will they will come to me
they know that they can come to me with
that kind of stuff because I'm trying to
help them out so nonverbal communication
probably one of the most important
things with connecting with people
interacting with them
of course present yourself well be
groomed have a haircut what and then
when we're talking about that also is
you know if you dress like them you
mirroring so people often are gravitated
towards people that you know we look
like or dress like or you know whatever
so I'm used to with an IT environment
wearing a button-up shirt some slacks or
khakis and then and working that way but
with the developers the gray all know
you know what developers like it's
t-shirts you know they dress down quite
a bit more so when I'm interacting with
the devs I will dress down a little
battle I still have my style still like
we're on a college shirt its its
button-up but you know lose the sleeves
are rolled up the shirts untucked when I
go down to iti kind of dress up a little
bit more
if I'm interacting with executives
that's definitely dressing up with that
too so you know dress is very important
to the actual nonverbal communication of
body language some of the things you can
do is face the person so you want to be
having a connection when you're talking
to someone like this it can be very
awkward you'll actually notice this too
is when someone's really engaged with
you they'll be facing you I contact sit
and stand you know straight up there are
instances where you're sitting down at
you you can be a little bit more relaxed
of course you know uncross your arms bum
up here like this it's just a very
defensive position
that's something I'm still working on is
having my hands down at the meeting in
the Navy we had our eddies pose and this
is just being more open to them show
them I'm open to whatever they're
talking about I could just be cold but
you know still it's it's something to be
conscious of when you're interacting
with people
of course smile and I'm talking to
full-teeth smiles
not the serial killer smile they've
actually done studies or as hard or not
you moved that were rated hotter where
were people who smiled weren't wearing
glasses and a lot of that is because
you're showing vulnerability with people
and that that draws people and you can
make a connection with them there and
then of course we all have these when
you're in our people stay off the phone
if you know I get buzzed from the wife
oftentimes I'll check it and then put it
away if it's not the wife it's like yeah
excuse me I got to check this just in
case there's some kind of emergency
usually if it's an emergency she'd be
calling but yeah if you get like text or
notifications we get noted notified it
constantly either keep it in your pocket
or look at it brief and then put it away
I can tell you people appreciate when
you look at it and then focus back on
that it's you know when you interact
with people and you just start typing on
your phone or if you're if you're just
trying to write something down I've had
people were like yeah hold on I want to
write this down while we're talking or I
want to get you know some type of
capture some kind of information we're
discussing so that's that's that's kind
of a quick and dirty a lot of this
there's there's a lot
more to this kind of stuff I just wanted
a couple things to be mindful of again
with the mirroring if you can test
engagement with people by shifting your
body language I've rolled my shoulders
once and I didn't even mean to and I saw
the other person I was talking to do the
exact same thing it is really weird when
that happens and and if you start paying
attention to that you'll start noticing
this kind of stuff it can take a little
bit of practice or I have like
specifically been like oh I wonder you
know I'm talking spurs we're having a
good conversation we're not engaged
there I'll just like shift and then
they'll shift or you know if I'm holding
a beer or something I'll switch hands
with the beer and they'll do the same
thing it's really crazy it's really cool
- moving on to electronic communication
don't your prefer like going up and
talking to people because email you know
I am things like that are can be taken
out of contact a very generic it's it's
it I I always try to walk up to people
some I still email and things like that
because I can't do that for actually
every engagement but when I can I do try
to get up and go talk to someone because
that's you know just you're just
building a better better better
connection with people versus something
that's over electronic that everyone
else is doing if you are gonna write an
email this is what I recommend is what's
called bottom line up front or Bluff put
your question comment at the top and
then you can explain in like one or two
sentences if they want more context
they'll ask you for it oftentimes I see
emails come in where it's you know two
paragraphs long and then the questions
at the bottom when you put the question
at the bottom that means they have to go
back up to the top and read it again so
you always want to move your question
from the bottom up to the top and you'll
see an increased response rate for
people because oftentimes I do it when I
get like two paragraphs of stuff it's
like I'm not answering that one right
now oh I'll save some time for it later
so this has been really effective and
powerful for me be direct or it in that
regard so those are kind of the quick
and dirty
tips that I can provide especially for
new people I really tried to think about
what I wanted to do within what some of
my experiences and what I really
struggled with I am doing a lot more
with this concept I have a github page
social engineering blue team is the page
and throwing a bunch of links up there I
gave this talk of b-sides nd that'll be
up there I'm supposed to speak at
converge and be sighs Detroit next month
I'm actually doing workshop for them I
didn't buy it for the b-sides nd I
practiced that and I had an hour and 40
minute talk so there was a lot of stuff
to dive into and yeah that's that's kind
of something to keep in mind too is that
this will take a lot of time try to pick
one thing to work on and then kind of
you know once you feel like you've
mastered that you can move on to the
next thing and I got a lot of the
resources there I love podcasts the
Jordan Harbinger show is one of my
favorites and talks about you know
social engineering social connections
different things like that success type
stuff of course got Chris had naggy
social engineering podcast again we can
learn a lot of stuff from the red team
you know what when like they're dressing
to break into an organization that's
just mirroring that's again me trying to
fit in with the devs is trying to dress
like them and then of course career
tools and manager tools really good
stuff from a business at a kid
standpoint but they're really focused on
having strong relationships within an
organization in fact recently they
talked about the three types of power
expertise power role power and
relationship power 50 to 75 percent of
your power is relationship power so they
have a strong focus on that kind of it's
actually where I got the electronic
email recommendation for bottom line up
front also really good for interviewing
and and other type of typist things so
that's pretty much it just reiterate
this this time a lot of this stuff can't
take time and practice
hopefully this content helps you
accelerate that a little bit of course I
got a lot of resources and there's tons
of resources out there and I'm
continuing to add to it this does
something feel like I can keep doing
blog posts on I do podcast things like
that which speaking of which
this is my contact information I run the
exponent for my security podcast or I
have a different security professional
in each week we talk about a different
topic we do it's not all sauce Co stuff
it's technical stuff and just a variety
of different things within Information
Security that I'm kind of exploring at
the time
Timothy D block at gmail.com is my email
reach out to me there are feedback
Timothy D block on Twitter and then
Timothy block comm like I said I'm doing
blog posts and stuff I will say with the
email I don't I check an email like once
or twice a day so if I don't get back to
you right away it's not me ignoring you
it's just I literally check it just once
or twice a day so that's pretty much the
talk any questions comments
everybody's blown away that's what I'm
sensing yeah there you go all right cool
well that's it thank you
[Applause]