good morning everyone how are you folks
enjoying the meeting
good good so this marks the 25th
anniversary of Nanak so 25 years ago a
collection of very bright young kind of
hungry engineers got into a room and
decided they were going to try to make
the internet work across the North
America and as a result here we are
their accomplishments been amazing I was
speaking to one of our board members and
he was in the or one of the early
meetings and he said that at that time
there are about you know 60 people in a
room and if someone had blown up that
room the internet would have died in
North America and the way it's grown
today there's no way you could just take
out the internet in North America there
are hundreds of thousands of engineers
and there are people with an industry
that makes the United States and across
the world an amazing place for
information sharing across the world
about 30 years ago I was in a conference
and there was a futurist who spoke and
he was talking about the challenges that
we'd be facing in the future and he said
the biggest challenge that we would face
is that the amount of information that
we had he said that in the 1600s a
well-educated man would have been able
to read everything that was written
within their lifetime he also wanted to
say that in one edition of the New York
Times would be impossible for someone to
consume it all in a singular day he said
the biggest challenge that would be
facing humanity is the management of
data and information and he said the
major careers that do not exist now will
be designed and focused in managing that
information and here we are with the
internet and everyone in this room
contributes in some way to that
information flow managing that data so
because of you people throughout North
America and the world have the privilege
of having access to information in ways
that we never could have imagined
before so I want to give a round of
applause to all but everything in the
room and to all those people who helped
make this happen so as non-executive
director one of my mandates is that
regarding to outreach where's my click
out there thank you was in regards to
outreach now my cousin organization has
grown over the years and in the
beginning because it was small it's
finding its way it was kind of insular
and so one of my goals is to start to
reach out within the community I think
that for a healthy thriving community it
has to be built upon diversity inclusion
and acceptance the more voices that we
get into this room the better for all of
us and as you look across the room we
have new people here but there's a lot
of people who've been around for a while
and it's my desire and outreach is to
create an environment where new people
want to comment and then I want to be a
part of this community and hope to
continue the growth of the internet
within this country I had the pleasure
of talking to Vince Cerf once and he was
telling me I asked him a question what
was the thing that just surprised him
the most about the internet what was the
thing when they put it all together that
they just never thought of and he said
we never considered the commercial
application it never occurred to us and
I believe that there are applications of
the Internet there things will happen a
technology that we in this room cannot
conceive of but our children and those
who come after us will conceive of those
things and will continue to advance the
internet so one of the core things in
our outreach is bringing people within
the community within the environment
where were those new ideas will come in
where when we decide that we've gonna go
on out to pasture there'll be a whole
group of young innovative people who
will continue the work that has made the
internet the success it is today
so what is
a college education the core of Nanak's
mission and outreach programs reflect
that mission they are designed and
taught by industry professionals and and
we are committed to the advancement of
the Internet in North America what is
our focus our outreach programs focus in
three distinct areas there is an
industry education for networking
professionals education career
development and for colleges and
graduate students and training within
underserved regions of North America now
most of us live here in large cities and
we have tremendous access within our
communities my home particularly I have
I think it's 300 down and 30 up but then
I have a house it's in a rural area
where I get ten down and I get 0.75
megabits up Valerie gets I think she
said about three down on a good day but
still that's access there are certain
parts of North America that have little
to no access at all how many of you had
the pleasure being in Matt's talk
regarding what's happening in the
indigenous regions did you guys enjoy
that talk okay well now Don's gonna be
kind of supporting some of those efforts
which I'll be talking about in a minute
our goal choose to operate our outreach
programs within the in the most
strategic way possible nanog has a 501 3
C 3 designation as a nonprofit and our
focus is on education now my personal
beliefs about nonprofits is they exist
in this realm between commercial
entities and government entities there
are things that nonprofits can do that
need to government's nor commercial
entities can do commercial entities are
designed to drive a profit they have a
fiduciary responsibility to their
shareholders to make a profit there are
certain things they're not within their
bandwidth to do certain things which are
not profitable enterprises
governments on the other hand are
sometimes too large to be able to focus
on certain small targeted goals and
that's where nonprofits come in
nonprofits are about doing good for
those communities that they serve and
our outreach programs are going to be
focused on that again I said we think we
focused on our core misses with your
education we're mindful of non augs
resources unlike some organizations in
our community we don't have this
automated flow of revenue that comes in
our revenue comes in from support from
our members and also from our
sponsorship programs we're gonna focus
on providing educational support to
Nog's industry organizations
universities and underserved regions
within North America our previous
efforts like Nanog on the road
operations we're gonna try to focus
those efforts try to use our resources
as best we can possible
we're looking to partner with entities
in North America so that we can leverage
those groups and to be able to offer
more with less in most cases these
organizations will provide the venues
marketing and audience and we will
provide the educational support so we've
had a couple of encounters this year so
far within our outreach and I'll talk
about a couple of those the first thing
we did is we offered support to the crib
nog crib nog is of course within North
America we do focus on North American
entities that are english-speaking
Mexico is part of North America but
because of the language barriers they
tend to reflect with latnok so in crib
not there were experts global
stakeholders across Caribbean United
States nor Canada
Kim perched in Bridgetown Barbados for a
regional meeting that was also Erin was
there as well
I spoke did the keynote and talked about
the role of nogs within our communities
also speaking was Sean Kennedy volunteer
and also board member who presented on
learning manners and best practices for
migrating global routing threats
Steve Feldman also a member and former
chair of the PC he spoke about the
insights into the global DNS attack that
it recently happened Eddie Winstead also
a
nanog member and a longtime volunteer he
spoke on so he inherited DNS server best
practices from day one day Harvey and I
Dave puts on our meetings so des does in
her team do an amazing job of delivering
these meetings when I first came on as
executive director and I really got to
peer into what all happened to make
these meetings take place I was amazed
at the time the staff is three people
that Betty Day and Valerie we're able to
put on these tremendous meetings with
just that small course the staff and the
assistants of Hamilton group so data is
amazing job and I'd like to thank Dave
for all her work and effort and Valerie
and the team that put this together
[Applause]
so then I went to write to see what we
can learn about the things that they do
we're trying to always make sure we're
delivering the best to our attendees so
this was an opportunity to see how our
neighbors across the pond manage their
events now ripe is a little different
than us it's kind of an amalgamation of
both nanog and aaron combined together
so we you know met with ripe training
team one of the things again education
is our core so ripe has a training
program that's been going on for quite a
while so I wanted to see how they do
things how they do things that are
different than what we do and well you
understand what I mean and what we can
do to collaborate with them in an effort
to bolster our training and educational
programs we're not in competition with
one another we're all about doing what's
the best for the internet as a whole so
I think that there's an opportunity to
deliver
create synergy between our two
organizations so upcoming outreach
meetings so this fall prior to going
into our meeting in Austin we're working
to solidify a date to have an outreach
meeting at Texas A&M we will use this
opportunity to build awareness around a
Nana as an organization for students the
wealth of tools resources and
programming that the programs that are
available in are trying at try annual
meeting excuse me we're looking to
provide students with that we're looking
to encourage them to participate in our
NCI program and we're looking to provide
information regarding our career
opportunities and industry challenges
and within our various organizations
within our community Cribb nog 18 so
we're also going to be going to crib nob
offer a bit of an educational support to
them as well to help bolster their
efforts in the Caribbean and the
indigenous connectivity subnet in Hilo
Hawaii so I know some of you people say
Oh Hilo Hawaii boondoggle why are we
participating why we are part of that on
the Big Island of Hawaii they're areas
and even some of the smaller higher what
they do not have access this is a
problem I mean there's a problem in
First Nations people up in Canada and
tribal areas within the United States
there are areas that not only do they
have not internet access they don't even
have power and we can't build those
networks we can't fix this problem for
them but what we can do as an
educational institution we can help
support their efforts help bring up
engineers who can out build out those
networks and change those communities
we're not in the business of building
networks we're in the business of
building the human network and that's
why you're all here to learn to grow and
to enhance your careers and we're trying
to give that opportunity to other people
as well
so they like program the Nanog program
is fuelled by people within this room
and people within this community we have
a deep passion about Nanog they impart
from their daily responsibilities step
in and volunteer their time to assure
that this program is informative
credible and on the leading edge
I'd like to everyone who's part of the
program committing in this room to
please just stand up for a moment
they're shy I think the core of nanog is
the program committee I believe that
with the right program we could hold it
in a tent in a field with people in
sleeping bags and they would come it's
core to what we do and I deeply
appreciate and respect the efforts that
the program hoody committee puts into
building this manag community keeping
people coming and and participating
within the organization on average our
audience is broken about a third of
people are new coming in a third who are
members and then another community which
you know who aren't members but who are
part and participate in that on all the
time and our program community keeps
them coming and coming and coming so
again thank you for your efforts so as I
mentioned again before that the program
is the heart of an event on it's made of
the industry professionals and is
selected by the board and within that
self that the program committee self
organize itself and then selects and
promotes its own members decides what
committees were going to be inside of
the organization and they determine what
this program is going to look like the
piece he reviews and so the selected
talks amended by the nanog community to
curate a program of the highest possible
quality and relevance
in an effort to better serve our
community the PC has created some new
subcommittees and effort took better
serve our community keynote speakers I
had asked the committee if they could
try to focus on being a little more
proactive as in terms of reacted to our
content and thus they've created a
committee on keynote speakers it's been
quite successful we've got several
candidates for the upcoming meeting in
Austin and there's other meetings
already where there's keynote speakers
who are interested in contributing to
our our program so the new subcommittees
they've created again keynote speakers
women in tech or outreach programs
lightning talks the tutorial attracts
and also a hackathon I believe that the
hackathon is a key element of the nanite
program it's been steadily growing and I
think it is Wiest it starts to grow and
we better defined it I think it's gonna
be a key component of bringing new
people into our organization and getting
excited about what we're doing and
helped to promote the organization in a
much more complete manner these
subcommittees allow the various types of
expertise to focus on knowledge on
specific areas importance within the
Nanog program so Nanog wants you we want
you to be a part of this we want you to
join become members we want you to
participate in the program so again it's
about building the future it's about
ensuring that nanog will be around
beyond ourselves I'd like you all to
face a challenge of getting involved in
a broader scale participate in ways such
as vote become a member I work for you
guys I am here to serve your needs and
to make this program this organization
the most the best program it can be but
I need your support and making that
happen
membership is not about what little
tchotchkes you get or what we can do for
you it's about turning around and what
you can
for the community so voting is critical
and to vote you need to be a member
membership fee is hundred dollars a year
for non students fifty dollars a year
for students it's minuscule I've got me
most of you if I have taken out dinner
for your family and spent more money
than that so it's a small thing but it's
a part of contributing and being part of
our program mentor as I mentioned before
that we have one third in this
particular conference there are 250 new
people that came to this conference in
addition when you count all the students
in there that another 50 that our
students so you're looking about 300
people roaming throughout here who've
never been to an AA meeting before and
for some of us who are more experienced
have been around it's a great
opportunity to mentor Susan is on our
board and spoken on the women Tech
meetings you talk about the significance
and importance of mentorship and how
it's great for any organization that
participates in such programs so here's
an opportunity for you to get back to
mentor someone else help guide their
career helped shape the people of
tomorrow so that they can make sure that
everything continues all your efforts
don't go in vain teach for about 15
years of my life I had the privilege of
teaching I learned more from my students
than they ever learned from me teaching
is a way of not just giving back it gets
back to you it takes your knowledge it
amplifies it when you're teaching and
someone asks you a question it makes
sometimes it turns what you know upside
down and makes you look at it in another
way teaching is about you it's about
expanding your knowledge and sharing
that knowledge of someone else there are
often things we do repetitively every
day we do it intuitively but we do not
understand the rationale behind what we
do you get in front of someone and you
teach they will demand that you give
them the rationale of how you got to
where you are and in that you understand
what you do in a more significant manner
present we need presenters we need
people who can share their ideas their
concepts submit your talks submit your
ideas it helps you again as I mentioned
for it and it's it's a form of teaching
it makes you take and organize your
thoughts in a cohesive manner and it
takes that information and it will
enhance you get involved present make
this community even better
evaluate serve on the program committee
it is that it is again as I said core to
organization core what we do and that
program committee is the lifeblood of
this organization and sponsor nanog is
an organization that exists upon the
support of members and also our sponsors
your efforts those investments allow us
to do other things on us to teach these
people in the room allow us to put on
these conferences without that
sponsorship dollars it doesn't happen
even for you of attending here the money
that you spend for registration does not
cover all the expenses that go to not
just putting on the conference but to
just feeding you sponsors support those
efforts so I'll leave you with a quote
from Robert Kennedy the future does not
belong to those who are content with
today apathetic toward comic problems
and their fellow man alike timid and
fearful in the face of bold projects and
new ideas rather it will belong to those
who can blend passion reason and courage
in a personal commitment to their ideas
thank you and hopefully we're all
working together for the Internet of
tomorrow so
[Applause]
so now I'd like to take what opportunity
and this is a community meeting
community forum if any of you have any
questions for myself for the board who
are their staff
we're helpfully happy to address any of
those questions mics are open if you
have any questions please step up
comments go too bad we need to hear them
no I think okay so thank you for your
time
[Applause]
you