[Applause]
yeah so short bit about me so I've been
doing tcp/ip and internet-based stuff
since 84 I started doing DNS in
large-scale in 1990 and the landscape
has changed pretty dramatically in terms
of how it's been abused over the years
both deliberately and inadvertently I'm
gonna go through a few basics first just
so that we have all of the terms we tend
to get very sloppy sometimes in where we
describe the various roles of your DNS
and I'm going to be doing some case
studies with this and I want to make
sure that we're all on the same page and
you're understanding the context of how
I'm using those so we describe that
you're getting exactly what's really
going on so first off Zone on or that
that's the person who actually owns the
brand name whatever you want to call it
they are the ones actually care if that
domain name functions correctly in this
parlance a dns operator is whoever is
running the visible authoritative name
servers on the Internet
whether it's any caster or uni casted
but not the hidden masters not anything
else but the the operator of the public
authoritative servers and this is the
one that I always used to confuse
registrar's of the people that you buy
domain names from and the registry is
the actual database that constructs
those TL DS so I can buy a.com domain
name from any number of registrar's but
Verisign runs the registry that actually
has the stuff that goes into com to do
those delegations there are also a bunch
of roles and we'll be talking about this
because these are all now attack
surfaces and unfortunately the bad
actors in many cases are more
knowledgeable and more sophisticated
than the sysadmin who may have inherited
the DNS infrastructure so it's usually
starts with the stub resolver and that's
most likely to be part of the operating
system of the device that is actually
making the DNS query and in most cases
it is literally a stupid stub and it
just goes to whatever was configured via
DHCP or in your resolve comm or in your
registry and goes and asks a fully
recursive resolver for the answers some
operating systems like Windows and Mac's
do actually also cache for five minutes
within the stub resolver but that's not
a requirement the recursive resolver is
the one that does all of the interesting
work it is the one that will go through
all of starting at the root and going
through all of the delegations to get to
the point where it gets to the name
server that has the answer for the
original question and it then sends it
back to whoever asked usually as I said
the stub resolver in this case almost
always fully recursive resolver czar
also caching so that they can give the
same answer again to other clients
without having to go through all that
work and give the answer faster and then
the other side of the picture are the
authoritative servers and these are the
ones that actually have the zone data
for that particular domain name that
you're interested in and answer only for
that this is in the slides it's mostly
there to show that basically the device
asks the question it goes to the caching
recursive resolver and then it will walk
through the entire tree the only thing
of interest here is that in the old days
everybody including the root server got
the full question if I wanted dub dub
dub example.com that recursive resolver
actually asked the root server for dub
dub dub example.com even though the only
thing that's going to get is a referral
to who has answers for comm cue name
minimization is a standard that is
starting to roll out fairly widely and
that's the one where you only put as
much name into that query as
you need to get that answer so the root
server will only see a question for calm
they won't see dubbed example calm and
the common security problems that we see
and that we were hoping to address one
of them is simply denial of service
guaranteeing that you were unable to get
an answer for that zone probably the
most notable example in in recent
history was the dine outage in 2015
where basically they melted connection
points such that you couldn't get to
their authoritative service and and
little useless things like Twitter
disappear off the face of the earth one
of the other ones which really drove DNS
SEC deployment back in 2008 cache
poisoning and we'll talk more about
exactly what it means when you poison
the recursive resolvers cache people set
up false authoritative server so if I
can get you to go to something that
isn't the server that's supposed to be
there it's not the DNS operators it's
one that I is the bad guy I'm running I
can put whatever zone data and I want I
can change where your web queries go I
can change where your email goes I can
set up man in the middle or honey pots I
can do all sorts of nasty little things
if I can convince you to go to this
server that it's not the real
authoritative and then finally if you
can get the credentials for the zone
owner or whoever maintains the zone data
and you can actually go into that zone I
don't even need a false authoritative
server I can just change the data within
the DNS zone itself and so primarily
these are what we are seeing in DNS
attacks I'm not going to be talking
about some of the other things like DNS
tunneling where DNS is used as and other
means where command and control this is
about hijacking the DNS data itself
results of those obviously you get no
answer at all so your business is off
the internet and and failing to take
anything or I can set up a fake site and
if I can set up a fake site and I can
get to your users too
that instead I can steal login
credentials I can give out false data I
can give embarrassing alternatives or I
can quietly make it look like it's
working normally and I can eavesdrop on
your email or your web traffic or other
things so some DNS SEC basics in the
simplest terms DNS SEC is just public
key or asymmetric encryption and the way
that works is you generate a pair of
keys one of which is public and and
given out widely and one of which you
keep very secure in private and those
pairs of keys allow you to either sign
or encrypt data private keys are always
kept very secure because if someone can
get your private key they can counter
finish you or they can decrypt things
that you wanted to keep secure in the
DNS use of this they do with digital
signatures nothing is encrypted with the
keys but there are signatures so you can
validate that nothing has changed
and since DNS publishes anyway and
public keys are supposed to be widely
available they've taken advantage of
that so the public keys are actually put
into the zone with other zone data along
with the signatures and you can take
those public keys and you can take those
signatures and you can walk that whole
chain through and you can then use those
to validate all of the signatures and if
you can do all of those you have
assurance that whatever DNS answer you
got has not been modified from what is
in the zone and if for some reason
validation does fail if the if you are
DNS ex signing your data but that answer
fails to validate the user will get no
answer so if somebody does something
malicious the user is protected from
going to that bad site because they
won't ever get da record or quad a
record so
first we'll talk about what DNS SEC
actually solves and what are the
problems that we're talking about in
security that it potentially could solve
so most people when they break down
security will describe that there are
certain key things that you need to be
able to do or not do confidentiality can
I prevent anyone who's not authorized
from getting this data integrity how do
I know that someone hasn't in some way
modified the data from the original
sender all the way to me is the
recipient and availability can I get to
that data when I want that data or can
someone prevent me from it from getting
it so DNS SEC solves the integrity
problem because when I put it into the
zone and I digitally create signatures
for it and publish the public key and do
all of the stuff that I need to do you
can go through and validate and you can
tell that what I put in the zone file
actually got all the way there
so cache poisoning because DNS
generically is udp-based I can send a
single packet as a DNS response and that
resolver if it's asked for the answer to
dub dub dub at example.com and a UDP
packet comes back that says be a record
for dub dub dub that example.com is
1.2.3.4 and I'm not doing DNS SEC I will
stick it in my cache and in 2008 Dan
Kaminsky did some research and talk to
me offline if you want the really gory
details but there's something called the
birthday attack which basically says
that counter-intuitively if I have 50
people in the room the chance of two
people having the same birthday is 80
percent or whatever it is but within a
fairly finite amount somewhere in the
low 500s I have a 99.9% chance that
there will be cool
and so what Dan discovered was if you
simply sent four or five hundred packets
with responses that were bad or
malicious at the same time that you
could generate a query for that answer
the odds were almost guaranteed that the
cash would take that instead of the
legitimate authoritative servers answer
and they would cash it and of course
they would also put a TTL that was
really really long so that that answer
stayed in that cache for a very long
time and so what happens is everybody
who then asks after that cache is
poisoned gets the malicious answer DNS
SEC because the caching server won't
cache it unless it validates if it fails
to validate it simply throws that answer
away so the most effective thing that we
have right now for cache poisoning is
DNS SEC because of that integrity check
we know that the answer is what was
supposed to be in the zone data or we
don't accept it at all it also means
that if I set up a false authoritative
server I don't have the private key so I
can't sign those records so none of them
will validate and so again if I managed
to somehow get you to come to a false
server but the correct zone is signed
you won't accept those answers either so
in both cases what this means is the
end-to-end integrity from the original
source of the zone file all the way to
the stub resolver and into the device or
app that asked we can know that it's the
same it hasn't been modified in transit
okay that's great but DNS SEC doesn't
solve every problem one of them it
doesn't encrypt all DNS even DNS X sign
still goes in the clear so anybody who
is in the network path and can observe
packets going by can see the query and
the response so if you don't want
someone to know that you are going to
AIDS org
like your insurance company that's a
problem because if somehow they can see
that data going by they know that a
particular IP address in a particular
home is asking about a particular
yes answer so confidentiality is
definitely one of the things that
doesn't do it doesn't fix availability
I can still disrupt things by breaking
signatures clogging links knocking you
off the net tossing your machine
whatever it also you get what's in the
zone but that doesn't it's not
autocorrect for DNS if I fat-finger
something and put the wrong name or the
wrong IP address into my zone file and I
sign it you will get something and it
will validate but that doesn't mean it
will work and finally you don't by
signing your zone control the parent so
for example comm you have to trust that
whoever's running comm is doing
something to be to be sane and secure
themselves but you doing DNS SEC doesn't
necessarily mean that your parent is
secure and if they're not signing you
can't use DNS SEC because it must be a
complete chain all the way from the root
all the way down there are ways of doing
things with additional trust anchors and
other things but they are not clean and
they still don't mean universal
availability of that DNS SEC validation
so I'm gonna talk now about the meet of
this now that we've sort of explained
the ground rules and a little bit about
what D in a second is not I've got some
examples of DNS hijacking broadly and in
the broader sense DNS SEC or hijacking
is you somehow managed to make sure that
the intended consumer of that DNS answer
gets the answer you want them to have
not the correct answer and there are a
number of places that because there are
so many tax surfaces that you can
subvert that data and I've picked some
recent ones there was an incident with a
Brazilian bank there was a website
two-face meant for the WikiLeaks site
there was an ether wallet Bitcoin
cryptocurrency issue and then most
recently what they're calling D an
espionage which is a
nation-state plumbing and and
exploration of other sovereign nations
so Brazilian bank was fairly
straightforward it was a Brazilian ISP
was giving out cheap CPE routers that
had unpatched bugs and as we all knows
you know consumer grade CPU routers or
the gift to keep on giving and so they
figured out a way of changing the
resolver from the stub resolver that was
in the router to their own code and in
most cases for most home set ups your
CPE is also your home router and it does
the DHCP so all of the devices in that
home will change their recursive
resolver to use that router as the
resolver and what they did was they
simply had this code work correctly for
everything except for a particular bank
that they wanted to target any queries
for that bank instead gave answers for a
fake site that they set up and since
they could control what site they went
to they basically had a little man in
the middle and they watched everybody's
login and password as it went through
and then they logged you in helpfully to
the bank so customers didn't notice
until those credentials were used and
they started emptying bank accounts so
the result of this was basically a
number of Brazilian banking customers
lost the money in their accounts so
remediations for this are pretty
straightforward the biggest thing in
this case would be actually running
decent secure and currently patched
routers because they wouldn't have been
able to put the code on DNS SEC would
only have been useful if the individual
devices in that home had themselves been
doing validation because they would have
then noticed that what the router gave
them didn't validate and at least at the
moment there are is code the stubby
project and a couple of other things for
trying to come up with validating stub
resolver small and
to fit on two devices but that's
certainly not common at the moment and
then regular searches for malicious
certs might have given them something
because if they went to the bank and it
was HTTP they might have noticed that
somebody got dub dub dub Brazilian bank
comm with a CA that they didn't use or
with a cert they didn't expect that one
unfortunately is much harder to catch
and will sort of bump into this with
several of these certificate
transparency logs and some of the
attempts at that or pinning are trying
to make the whole CMS less of a
festering security pile but it's kind of
fundamentally broken at the moment
WikiLeaks was actually much more simple
they basically somehow got the account
credentials for the zone owner and they
just went in and changed the IP address
on the a record so it looked like their
site had been hacked and they said we
have hacked the website and and blah
blah blah but that wasn't true the
website was out there just no one was
going to it because they were going to a
false one and in this case very simple
you know credentials keep them secure
and if they'd had DNS SEC and if they'd
actually checked to see that everything
was up in the parent and hadn't changed
it might have given them some more
warning but that's another and we'll get
to this with the last attack that we
were covering des records and NS records
and parents tend to have very long TT
ELLs so most of us don't check them very
often which means that if you can change
things in the parent life gets really
dicey and it's actually very hard to
catch my teeth or wallet a little bit
more interesting what they figured out
was they could actually do a BGP route
hijack of the actual IP address of the
website
and so the real website was still up DNS
was still working and most people were
getting to the correct website but
enough of them wound up getting along
the hijacked route and to the fake one
and they didn't do their certificate
stuff right but unfortunately we've also
trained users of the this certificate
doesn't match is that okay click and
they punch right through and so they did
they went to the fake site their
credentials were stripped their accounts
were emptied and cryptocurrency went
away so this is one where we're getting
sort of into the core of what Nana
preaches anyway BGP and routing security
obviously would have helped this and if
more people were implementing rpki and
doing drops and not just logging they
wouldn't have been able to take care of
this and that would have been the most
useful thing DNS SEC might have helped a
bit but once again if users are willing
to click through certs and other things
it it might have made it easier to
notice earlier if they had been actually
looking at that because validation would
have failed for some of the stuff but
they would have also had to have probing
that was sufficiently distributed across
enough IAS a--'s that they would have
had some of their probes actually in the
areas where the hijack route 1 that's
another one of those why doing things
with anycast is really cool for
robustness but really hard to debug if
something goes wrong and then again
watching your certs is certainly
something that everybody should be doing
unfortunately it's unclear how practical
in in real terms it would be at catching
this so now we get into probably the
most interesting of them this was a
campaign by the Iranian military they
have a cyber hacking team and basically
they come in every morning and go to
work seeing what they can do to find
credentials for people that they don't
like and in this case the two
biggest winners or losers were UAE and
Lebanon who they had concerns about and
so at some point in time they had
managed to get via a data dump they'd
gotten from a previous hack and then
stripping of data EPP credentials so EPP
is the protocol that when a registrar
makes a change that needs to go into the
registry so I register example.com and
they need to insert something into the
dot-com registry the protocol that they
use via API to do that is EPP and EPP
use asserts which are effectively just
like a password or a an SSL cert and so
they got the credentials for a couple of
registry operators including that node
in Sweden and PCH packet Clearing House
and now these are people they know DNS
SEC they are very technically
sophisticated but somehow some someone
had leaked some of the UPP credentials
so they were actually able to get into
the parent now fortunately the Iranians
were not terribly DNS sex savvy because
if they'd been really good what they
would have done was they would have made
sure that DNS SEC wouldn't possibly ever
be an issue by simply taking the DES
records out in calm for example calm
there's now you can't possibly cyan
example.com nor can you validate it
fortunately they did not what they did
do was they changed the NSS and
interestingly enough what they were
doing was they were trying to fly under
the radar so this was happening over
December in January when most of the
world was on holiday and that was
apparently a very deliberate choice and
they would change the NS for an hour at
a time and then change it back so they
also interestingly enough they did
understand enough to know that let's
encrypt which is usually what they use
for getting their fake certs when they
set up their man-in-the-middle websites
it actually checks for sea
records in the zone and it actually DNS
SEC validates those and if it doesn't
validate they won't give you a cert
comodo on the other hand is still of the
yep the credit card works and that's
their validation so they got certs from
Komodo for the PCH networks and so what
they would do was at that hour they
would change the NSS and they would now
point to their own which had IMAP and
web and other things pointing to
machines of theirs that they had set up
man in the middle and PCH because they
were doing DNS SEC and they hadn't
disabled DNS SEC it didn't validate and
what they discovered was that their IMAP
client when you can't reach the site or
when it fails to log in it simply says
no new mail it doesn't give you an error
I can't get to the other site so it was
during that the Christmas holidays
anyway traffic was lighter and it only
happened for an hour and so they were
going oh I'm just getting less mail than
usual okay
the problem was two of their employees
were at a hotel with a captive portal
that required using their DNS recursive
resolver it was not doing DNS SEC
validation fun number one fun number two
they were on iPhones which as soon as
they locked and got an IP address even
before they had validated with the open
portal were immediately trying to log in
and they were getting the non DNS SEC
validated incorrect IMAP so they were
connecting to the false site so these
guys got the two employees passwords and
once they had the passwords they already
could get into the registries and make
changes there which they were now they
could get it two emails so they went
into email
they also started hopping around to see
if they could SSH in finding what other
machines these two employees had access
to and then just copying every file they
found and every password file they found
and dumping them off for later use and
so they just did this four times over a
couple of weeks and among other things
they managed to get passwords for
customers of these registries which
included the dot UAE or gov dot UAE and
gov dot whatever Lebanon's two-letter
country code is and once they had those
they could make changes in the DNS zone
files for those and they would flip
those for an hour and they started
getting government employee credentials
and email and that was basically their
entire goal they wanted to be able to
walk around silently and unnoticed
through their enemy country's government
official sites email whatever to do
espionage and if they hadn't had some of
these things breaking because of DNS SEC
popping in and out it probably would
have gone a lot longer before it was
noticed so basically at that point two
sovereign nations were owned by one of
their enemies who had access to all of
their sensitive information now there's
a lot of stuff that were learned and
actually bill Woodcock did a
presentation on this a few weeks ago of
all the things that happen and all the
things they learned it's the IKEA DNS
symposium and I'm pretty sure there's a
link in the further reading check it out
because he did a very open and
forthright breakdown of root causes and
lessons learned one of them was part of
the problem with doing things was they
were checking NS records in the parent
and D s records but because they had
such long TTLs they were checking it
every 24 hours and these guys were
coming in for an hour at a time and
going away so they didn't catch that
they also realized that when they did
did graph of all the links in the chain
of all of the DNS delegations and who
owned them and who could do password
recoveries and get account for
credentials or who could change them and
how many people knew and all the rest of
it and they did essentially a risk
assessment they realized that they
actually needed to check NS and d s for
changes for everything from the route
all the way down to exactly the labels
that they cared about and on a much more
aggressive basis so they are now doing
that and they're walking the full tree
validating the full tree and doing it on
and I think eight I like a three or five
minute interval there's also something
that you could have in both the
registrar account that you as a consumer
have and that you can ask the registry
to do blocking which is exactly like
doing a credit lock on your credit cards
where you lock it and you have to
actually call somebody up and give some
password or some much more extensive
than you could log in to open it up so
that you can make changes in or have
access to your credit history and you
can do the same thing with your
registrar account and registry yes it
means that you might you know have to
have somebody woken up and get get out
of bed if there's some emergency and you
need to change the NS records but the
odds are pretty good that most of the
time you're gonna be doing that and it's
planned and you're gonna have a
checklist and you're gonna be giving
change management procedures out and
you're gonna be notifying your customers
and so it really shouldn't slow it down
but it really puts a dead stop to do
somebody malicious trying to do that
particularly if they're trying to pop it
every hour so that was there at the time
not everything they had had multi-factor
authentication enabled it was available
but it was not on everything they had
they also it hadn't really occurred to
them having their IMAP server something
that you could I map into directly from
the internet from the open not over a
VPN or an SSL tunnel was one of the
other reasons why it mattered that their
two employees were there because if they
had been over and encrypted tunnel even
going through a hostile network that
wouldn't have leaked their credential
and so they actually re architected all
of their service machines so that
nothing did anything more than one thing
it was all behind firewalls you had to
use VPN access you had to use VPN access
that had to factor all of those were
things they learned they also discovered
that it was very easy to change the
resolvers on the phone the stub resolver
z' and they turned on the MDM stuff
where you know basically your IT
department owns your phone I both hate
and love this it's very secure and it's
annoying beyond words because IT staff
but in this case that was another they
said they have too many people who are
in hotels all over the world because you
know they are global and they are going
into places like China and other places
where you know that the government is is
one of the actors that is trying to get
into your data dns sack would have
helped and it did except for the fact
that they were forced to use a resolver
they didn't work one of the things that
that Woody and I both think there should
be more of I've said multiple times now
the CA insert stuff sucks it's horrible
everyone should be telling every browser
vendor every time you talk to them Dane
isn't enough slower that you shouldn't
do it Dane is a much better cleaner and
more logical leap of trust for doing
certificates for web so what can you do
everything you should be doing
everywhere else every time the the term
InfoSec pops up so decent passwords
don't reuse passwords preferably use a
password manager you can even have group
vaults that you can give and revoke
access to employees as they come in and
out use multi-factor almost everything
these days supports it phishing training
if some of their staff had noticed
earlier that email was doing wonky
things that might have been another
chance for them to catch it during one
of the first couple of attempts as
opposed to after attempt number four
actually not attempt after success
number four other things that you start
looking at when you start getting
paranoid that Registrar account that you
have or the registry account in many
cases somebody registers to a domain
name and they're your web designer
because it's for a campaign and they use
their own email as the contact for it
and that becomes your password recovery
account and it might not be someone at
your company or it might be somebody who
left so make sure that every domain you
care about that the contact emails are
either role or a current company
employee so that nobody else can change
your password to get into your account
and go through all of that regularly go
through that directed graph of where all
my dependencies where all the places
they could change permissions or steal
credentials and come at me from behind
or the side monitor your your DNS and
not just yours the whole chain the
parent all of it and do it on a very
regular basis you know five minutes at a
time ten minutes at a time do it from
multiple different places you know use
one of the ripe Atlas thousand is
something that is across lots and lots
of a s's so you getting an idea of what
it looks like everywhere on the internet
not just from the path from your data
center and anything you care about you
should be monitoring those records and
in all cases monitoring is useful is if
you don't page somebody so actual have
alerts for things that you care about or
that are unexpected SSL certs and and
certificate transparencies at least
attempt it and there are you know there
debates about whether the more extensive
certs are actually worth the money that
they charge for them but you know if
it's millions of dollars of income to
you that might go away if your website
is out you know it's worth getting a
better than the credit card cleared
version of the cert and Dane and ackles
VPNs tunnels you know again it's all
just the standard stuff and then
validate on your
if you're gonna sign things you should
be validating so that you know the DNS
SEC is broken and sign everything and
registry lock everything and registrar
lock everything all right so I've left
we've got a little how much fun about 15
20 minutes so I sort of blew through
this but I'd love to have questions on
either other incidents or more details
on these look I'm sorry just a small
addition to a previous slide ok you know
it's like but maybe one more yeah talk
to you insurance company they these guys
know risk versus money better than
anybody that's their whole business yeah
it's a good suggestion thank you
Dameon mentor from Google one thing I
didn't hear you mention is HSTs headers
so just a quick comment or do you want
to describe you'll do better than I will
with that I sort of know but yeah so web
browsers have this option for hosts
strict Transport Security so basically a
website can respond to its customer
saying in all future transactions you
must use SSL and the certificate must
match you the user isn't allowed to
click through that so as an example if
like my ether wallet had done this their
users would not have been able to click
through these warnings and they would
have been better protected yeah and my
understand is it's basically much like
the SSH fingerprint the first time you
go in and then after that if you don't
present one of the acceptable ones you
actually get in here or you know I don't
think there's even I don't think there's
actually a certificate so when you buy a
fraudulent certificate from comodo you
do bypass this it's not it's not
certificate pinning it's just it
requires a valid cert so it's not
bulletproof yeah the whole search system
in general is fraught with peril but yes
I also had a question I vaguely recall
hearing that the one of the things as
you know I'm interested in DNS
amplification attacks yes all of these
attacks come from DNS X signed domains
because they have very large any records
right so this is why they're almost
always government domains because the
government is all happy about DNS SEC
has their I vaguely recall hearing talk
about trying to shrink these records so
they aren't quite as large yes so there
are a couple of attacks one of them is
current best practices to not allow any
war to rate limit it or to Akal it so
that only your knock can ask for any so
that's one of the pieces and there are
also other things with rate limits so
that you can't get quite as many the
other probably big win is algorithm
choice you see DSA has the same
cryptographic strength as RSA sha-1 for
a fraction of the size I will point out
of course also that I have seen people
doing spectacularly stupid things like
putting Fortier records in and then
having your app doing magic load
balancing as instead of
doing it in a more sane way and that's
gonna be huge and people have tax
records but yes anything you can do to
deliberately keep your spawn sizes and
also with v6 these days if you can keep
it below 1280 life is much better packet
fragmentation and dns are not friends
thank you other questions okay so like I
said um some were pulled down the slide
deck I've got some stuff with more
detail and definitely check those out Oh
Oh No yeah so those are worth reading
there couple of them like I can dock
there also actually themselves refer to
other things the government gave out
recommendations for using DNS second
doing other security stuff and doing
two-factor so there's plenty of good
advice out there but how long is BC p-38
been out so yeah if you can turn this
stuff on it where you are at least we're
getting ahead right if there are any
other questions thank you very much for
your time
you