hello everyone my name is Bert makovski
and I'm
work engineer working at the Amsterdam
internet exchange today's presentation
was done with max Jericho but
unfortunately he couldn't be with us
here today all right
the outline
jumping to the next sorry alright a
couple of facts about Amsterdam internet
exchange we are a non-profit neutral and
independent exchange based in Amsterdam
right around 14 datacenters with over
850 years ends with a traffic of above
66.6 terabits this year we 25 years old
so we had a small celebration working
with 56 people presenting our platform
it's a MPLS VPS Bates peering platform
with two Allah's peace between each pair
of access switches over to be routers we
have 10g energy access switch resilience
this button so internationally we are
having six separate ISPs with over 900
part is connected present in over 500
collocations in 350 cities so coming
back to the subject I would like to talk
about the am-6 management network and in
short our management network is internal
am-6 network which interconnects our
infrastructure including production
switches DW DMS photonic cross connect
devices etc it's being used for a
managing of our production platform
switches and also for collecting
customer statistics as well as as flow
data so it should be extremely reliable
since our monitoring system relies
solidly on it also when you are visiting
our websites you are going through the
management network so what kind of
issues that we see with our old
management network and a couple of plain
facts about it
so in Amsterdam we do have we did have
22 switches which were located in 40
datacenters plus one in our main office
on our small remote locations we had 10
switches in total and historically our
management network grew over the years
where we were adding set side by side
and
that's why we had a mix of different
playing their two devices from brocade
and still old foundry switches we used
also the ring topology in our setup and
a couple of disadvantages that we had
with it a couple of times we experienced
looping our management of network
because the devices did not support any
look prevention mechanism we had also
partially isolated parts of our network
due to a double captain fibers we have
some some MRP issues were some of the
parts didn't recover after flapping we
did have also bandwidth bottlenecks some
of the devices were end of light and end
of support and another important factor
is that as you could see at our previous
slide we had three MRP rings where every
fiber between the switches was a
separate that fiber that we were paying
for every month
[Music]
so as you can see here we were using 30
duct fibers for our production Network
and besides this 17 additional for our
management network so what we thought is
to reuse the existing production dark
fibers with DWDM boxes and in this way
we were able to build a fully redundant
spine lift topology for our new
management and work so as I said and
mentioned the fact scene about our
network in the past and the design
features the advantages that we had we
needed to upgrade we wanted to make our
environment more homogeneous to have the
same hardware and software and it was it
got hard during the time to manage
different devices on the network sorwe
aim was to make it more unified the new
devices would also bring more capacity
for our internal cloud and more
redundancy to avoid new people and
switches our relations we encountered
before so the question is where to go
which technology brand software and
hardware to use and
as you might know 10 years ago we didn't
have so many options but but as you can
see nowadays it's kind of a puzzle to
solve for choosing most suitable model
for our network we made some research
and a couple of proof of concepts of the
modern technologies and different
vendors as always m6 try to be at the
networking edge and we decided to go
with future-proof option and choose
Burton parameters which is with one of
the third-party software vendors what is
very metal iPod
concept it's basically in decoupling
software from hardware on the devices so
buying switch without operating system
and in studying later anything that you
can find on the market there are a
couple of software companies like
pluribus Komodos mix which type in
fusion and so on you can buy and install
the software from them and install it
like on a server or yeah you can also go
with open switch which is a free project
so introducing color choice after
looking into the technology and making
proof of concepts of course we went for
the very boost network solution with the
as 4048 only enabled switches so it gave
us some useful features like the CMP
look prevention that we were looking for
the rest api bx lam and their
proprietary fabric design so talking
about fabric concept let's look for the
classic switch plane approach so here we
can see a classic design of the switch
that we are all used to on the bottom we
have data plane and then control plane
and on the top segment single management
plane a pair switch with the new
solution the data and control plane for
the underlay of each switch stays the
same like classic design but the
management plane in common is in common
for every switch in the fabric all the
switches in the fabric federate together
in a peer-to-peer fashion for
distributed anciano
implementation practically saying
average switch is still independent but
you can log in and see configure any
switch from any switch you are connected
to you can add a nice yell and will be
populated to all the switches gives you
ease of use
[Music]
so a little bit background on how does
it work
each book establishes basically a TCP
management connection to every other
books every box has a microsd in
controller and the state database to
track the state of all other switches in
the fabric and this works well over
geographically distributed sites because
there is no central control
so if effectively it looks like one
programmable entity and the system
automatically builds the excellent mesh
the network operating system in addition
to running standard protocols in the
underlay establishes also we expand
overlay with V tabs terminated in
hardware on the switch the VX land
tunnels are auto created and establish a
full batch of tunnels try to represent
it how it looks from inside of the
device
earlier versions of bare-metal switches
there are indeed two different boards
one is switch with an ascii and another
on the top is Intel Atom on board some
of them even a VGA connector hood on the
switch in pluribus ocean there is i2
Linux installed which controls the box
itself and Broadcom ASCII an internal
API
there is also an Alexa container with
quagga installed on it for BGP OSPF so
this is how I tried to with visualize
how the ultimen l3 communication works
[Music]
one important feature that we were
looking for was the ability to connect
critical infrastructure as our mass
production web servers to two switches
simultaneously to avoid any downtime in
gate in case of maintenance or a failure
of one of the devices
this requires creation of a cluster
between switches where we want to
connect to MC lock unaware devices and
on the top you can also see spine
cluster to connect non v excellence
which and on the bottom leaf connecting
it to the server
so in the end we have built a spinal
leaf topology network for our management
use get geographically distributed
fabric we built over the standard SPF
underlay
it's loop free there is no controller no
speed brain scenario and slack for
critical services improve visibility and
our experience is a simple management of
our management network so far thank you
any questions
yeah question did you just use the
underlying
dwdm transport to establish a point but
you DWM TWD and transport is still
physically a ring what did you do
so we reused the colors on our DWDM
voxels yeah to come up with its finally
architecture yes okay like I guess
related to that so double cut basically
yes we do have a spine and leaf and it
goes to two separate collocations
all right thank you very much
[Applause]
you