hey good morning everybody welcome to
the nanog 76 hackathon so I'm Michael
I'm going to give a really really brief
introduction of what's going to be
happening today and then I'm gonna pass
it over to Syed and Deepak from our
sponsor Oracle who helped with this
hackathon together along with Hussein
from to sudo who helped provide all the
virtual lab infrastructure that you'll
be working on today so after after I'm
done talking and Saez done talking we're
going to encourage everybody to form
teams to then compete on this I know
that there's been a lot of great
activity in the slack channel where
people were coming up with some ideas to
work on Syed and Deepak are also going
to go over some exercises that you could
choose to complete instead so if if you
decide to go that route please form a
team of about five and it looks like
people have grouped off already
otherwise if anybody once the
introductions are done and the
presentation is given if people still
have had a problem forming a team please
either come up and talk to this table
here that has Hussain Jeff and Steve
from the hackathon committee so we'll be
able to help you out either form teams
or help out during the hack and then
also our friends from Oracle please
please wave Oracle table you could thank
them for sponsoring this as well as go
to them and ask for help on whatever it
is that you're working on I just want to
also give you a little overview of
what's going to happen during the day so
we're going to give this introduction
afterwards you're going to form teams
and start working we'll break for lunch
at around noon we'll break again during
the middle of the day and keep you like
well fed and well hydrated as you work
we're then going to have presentations
where everybody here gets to present
your work at at 6 o'clock you'll then
vote for who you think is the best team
then we'll break and have a little
reception outside so any questions
please come and talk to me or one of the
other friendly people who raised their
hands just a moment ago and then I'd
like to pass everything over to these
two who will go over what you're going
to be working on today are you guys can
hear me okay cool my name is Syed I'm a
network engineer in Oracle cloud
infrastructure and I'll be presenting
with Deepak and I also have like Mike
pointed out a bunch of other team
members he'll be helping me out
throughout the day running the hackathon
and answer any questions that you might
have so let's get started so let's say
if we have a network topology that
looked like this just a couple of
endpoints with few switches in between
and if there's a failure in the network
it's relatively easy to identify failure
in a simple network and once we have
identified the failure we can fix it and
everything is in healthy state and we
are good to go but the reality is we
have Network that look like this
so with the core distribution and access
layer and you might name those later
differently but there are there is done
NC on each layer or even if we are using
class fabric it's a really densely
connected topology of a spine of leaf
nodes so it's it's really complicated
network or if we look into the data
center it might look like this but we're
not here to solve structure cabling
problems we are here to talk about
network monitoring and that's the theme
of our hackathon today so you'll be
talking about active monitoring so just
give you a quick overview for agenda
today I'll go over the problem statement
then we'll talk about the hackathon
goals if you're like tasks that each
team needs to complete for the hackathon
I'll give you a brief overview about the
topology and then we will talk about
different tools and protocols that we
think might help you solve the problem
but feel free to use any tools and
protocols that you think it's more
reasonable to solve the problem this is
just to provide you a guideline because
we have varying set of skills and in the
group so just to get you started give
you some base to work on ok so just the
code the opposite of networking
is not working said someone smart I'm I
kinda agree to that so what's the
problem that we are trying to solve
today so in large-scale dance
complicated and accurate we need tools
that can identify and isolate failures
so we can fix them and we have more
robust Network that's highly available
and network active marketing give us
that great is a great tool to use
because its uses sensors and agents to
simulate customer traffic and it can
test for end-to-end reach ability it can
test for packet loss and can test for a
latency across the network but thing is
since if you have use active monitoring
it uses probes and if you have multiple
active paths in the network how you can
make sure that your probes are covering
all the active paths in the network and
I explained more on that in the next
slide
yeah so I'm on the right we have the
topology that we'll be using in the
hackathon today so you have six routers
and two hosts concerning all links have
equal cost between host and host B we
have four possible best paths that we
can use R 1 R 2 R 4 R 6 R 1 R 2 R 5 r 6
r1 r3 r5 r6 or r1 r3 r4 r6 so how we can
make sure that when we are sending a
probe it covers all those four possible
paths because if normally if I'm just
sending a probe from host h2s B it would
go to r1 and it can use either go to r2
or r3 and from r2 it can either go to r4
and r5 and I know I'm skip skipping some
of the ICMP hashing details but this is
just to keep it simple let's say we have
all equal cost paths and you're just
talking about a probe is going from host
a to host B so how can we come up with a
mechanism that we can more digital
deterministically tell that a probe will
take a path a or and then the second
side of probe will take path B and then
and that way we can cover all four
possible paths and identify any failures
as it happens on any of those four paths
so that's the goal we will be working
towards
and just the step wise what are the
hackathon goals first one is we expect
every team to extract topology
information using some kind of
automation you then once you have the
topology information you can build a
graph or network map using node links
and matrix once you have the graph you
can use that to compute all the best
possible paths between two end points in
our case it will be hosted in hose B or
Devlin and they have two boxes once you
have all the best paths calculated then
you can construct a pro packet and make
sure that you can probe all the four
possible best paths in the network then
once you have that you're probing all
the best paths just introduce a failure
in one of the pads and make sure you can
account that using your probes and there
is a bonus one if you can visualize the
collected data in matrix so that that
will be the bonus part okay just a quick
overview of topology again on the right
you can see the topology diagram you'll
be using today for the hackathon I have
included all the interface and IP
information so it's just a quick one
stop shop to look at all the details in
the network we have six vm x juniper vm
x instances are one through our six we
have two Ubuntu hosts Devon and f2
connected to R 1 and R 6 we are using is
is as the IGP but feel free to change it
if you want to we have configured BGP LS
on R 1 and R 6 and on devlin and f2 you
can run IX a BGP instance to pair with R
1 and R 6 and we'll talk more about bt
pls next so any questions so far before
I start talking about protocols into
yeah so in the end we'll have the links
for all the necessary documents and that
you'll need okay cool so bt pls
what is bt pls bt pls is basically
another NLRA of BGP defined in RFC seven
five - what it does it uses BGP TLV
fields to define objects so that's like
nodes links and IP prefixes and then it
uses a new type of vgp path attribute to
define attribute it's a non-transitive
optional attribute to define attributes
of all these objects sounds like note
attribute can define node name router ID
multiple topology identifiers link
attribute can define local IP remote IP
local and mode router ID and the
bandwidth available on that particular
link so what can we use it for so let's
say if I have a topology and I'm trying
to build a topology map for it and
choose for like offline path computation
or T purposes and my network has
multiple IP domain so I don't really
need to have a host in each IGP depend
to collect node information from that
domain I can just export my IGP into BGP
LS database and then just use BGP Alice
to communicate to the rest of the
network or any external entity to
distribute all the node and link
information in my network if you still
feel like what the heck I'm talking
about so hopefully this will give you a
bit more visual details to it so this is
basically a snippet from juniper router
I'm showing you three nodes and if I
look more into yeah the first one you
can see it has information about router
ID host name what protocol it's running
what area it's part of and all they have
good bits and if I look into VG pls for
the link you can see it has information
about local and remote IP on that link
what star local and mode router ID was
the T matrix for that link so once you
have that information you can pretty
much define the topology using it and
like I said you can run X a beach P with
R 1 or R 6 to get that bgp LS updates
under on the host so you can process it
so here's a quick snippet of XIV GP
Conte fell so the important bit is the
family address I'm using so it's bgp ALS
you can use a script to parse the JSON
the updates you are receiving from bt
pls as json you can be used any strip to
parse that information and this this is
just a message format you're gonna be
receiving from router to the host the
important part is again the NS LS
another I type if it's a type one that
means it's a node LS if its type two
means it's a link LS if it's a type 3
means it's ipv4 prefix if it's a type 4
means it's ipv6 prefix so again you have
option that you dump this update
messages to a file and then write a
script in your own preferred programming
language to parse the information you
need to build topology or we'll give you
an overview of JQ how you can use JQ to
parse JSON and extract information that
you want ok so now you have information
about nodes and links in a topology you
need to build a graph to be able to
compute all possible best paths in the
national network so there are multiple
graphing utilities you can use in python
you have network xor i graph in golang
you have Gore F I just feel network X is
like really easy to use really easy to
understand so on the right if you see a
network topology that has three routers
in it in Python you can just import a
networks library initialize a undirected
graph and you can add R 1 R 2 R 3 nodes
and then you can add edges as this is
basically the links between them so r1
r2 r1 r3 and r2 r3 and then that that
will give you a graph and you can see
that it has a graph with three nodes and
three edges so once you have the graph
you can run shortest path algorithm on
that to figure out all the best paths
between two endpoints okay so so far we
have topology information and we have
created a graph to extract all the best
possible paths in the network now our
challenge begins to how we can
all those best parts so like I said
initially that if you are sending probe
from host a to a host B it can take any
path so how we can deterministic elite L
it can take a path a or pad B so here
I'll just give you a quick overview of
GRE so what GRE is generic routing
encapsulation protocol what it does it
just in caps your IP packet in an other
outer IP header that has a new source it
can have a new source and destination
and once it can't you didn't capsulate
that outer header it gets routed based
on whatever the inner IP header is and
we are talking about here the state less
GRE we are not talking about
establishing a tunnel or anything of
that sort and in the next slide I will
give you more detail example of it so if
you're interested using this solution
I'll tell you more about it okay so
again on the right we have the topology
I'll be using for the lab so if you look
at it we have dev one r1 r2 so if I'm
trying to probe making sure that my
probe actually follow dev 1 to R 1 to R
2 I can there's an illustration of
header that I can use or GRE in-cab that
I can use to make sure that my packet
take actually that path so if you look
the innermost header it has source and
dust as that one IP and if you look at
the r1 actually or the outer IP header
it has sources still as Devon box but
the destination is said to the directly
connected interface on r2 and r1 so it
10.1.1.1 basically the IP right here and
if I look at the outermost header
it has source as still the Devon box and
the destination is set to directly
connected increase on r1 with Devon box
so what's going to happen when if I send
this packet through this network so the
first packet will get router based on
the outermost header so it will go from
dev one to r1 and if I have
GRE D cap filter configured on interface
in rest interface I will get rid of the
outermost header and I've included a
quick snippet for GRE D cap filter it's
already configured on all of the routers
if you want to go use that so what will
happen it will get rid of our remotest
header so now you have a packet with
source 20.00 - and destination as
10.1.1.1 since it's a diagnostician is
directly connected interface of r1 to r2
it will make sure it goes from r1 to r2
and then when it reaches to r2 the
second outermost header will get decap
so now there's a packet that has source
as 2000 - and destination as 20.00 r2 as
well so it gets out the back - to have
one box any questions so far hopefully
everybody is still awake ok so next we
will talk about skp that will walk you
over how we can construct the packets
and send it to the network and deepak
will take over from here so just click
down
so we need a tool to create the packets
and the option for you is to write your
own in any programming language of your
choice go see whatever but it will take
you enormous amount of time so something
we are suggesting but feel free to use
whatever you like is Cappy so so it's
Cappy is written in Python it's free
it's GPL version two very powerful
packet manipulation tool or a library
written in Python you can write your own
scripts Cappy importing the proper
libraries or you can just use it as a
shell you can open up multiple shells
one shell to send the packets the other
shell to sniff or receive the packets
and do the processing of the packets as
one as soon as you receive it so it can
send packets we have dissected Forge you
can write numerous network tools just
with Scapa and those tools discovery
scanning traced routing some of the
buckets for those kind of tools so let's
get into skep II so I'm having a simple
example which is just creating an IP
packet with ICMP so I've opened up two
shells and the center you see SCAP II
where and by the way you have to run
SCAP e as root or sudo you cannot run at
your user level so all your pods have
SCAP e you can open up two shells event
to start playing with it this is just
for ICMP echo request and reply the
bottom bottom screen of the screen you
see the shell which is sniffing you're
showing the interface you are showing
the filter you have to use a proper
filter to see tell what source or
destination IP you are expecting about
type of packet at size ICMP or TCP or
whatever and
how many packets if you want to justly
see few packets you can run it
indefinitely you can specify like the
number of packets or you can run in a
for loop you can do numerous things for
that once you receive a packet you can
do a summary of it and it will tell you
what what packet you received from there
and what time stamp is which is one
important thing when you are probing is
you want to see the round-trip time so
on the top great an IP packet show the
source destination ICMP that ICMP type
put a payload if you want to and then
construct the packet by putting a slash
between all the different constituents
and then use the send of escapee to send
that packet over the wire and the other
side you are sniffing it and you are
getting the packet on it escapee is
powerful enough if you have a GUI then
you can even see the diagram of like
what the packet looks like when you send
it and then you receive it so you can
see the different constituents of the
packet and here I am showing that this
is the source destination on the left
side what you constructed and what type
of request it was send what was the
payload and on the other side the
received packet from this particular so
if you want to run it in a for loop a
simple just use Python range 5 put 5
packets same payload send packets the
the receiving filter changed because now
we have 5 as a count and then we are
specifying a lambda function which is
doing a summary on each one of them so
you can write your own separate function
where you can specify what you want to
do with the packet right the received
packet you want to get the timestamp you
want to get what was what was the
payload of the packet what was the
source address what was the destination
address so going back to what side was
showing up in the IP GRE like sequence
of packets which you are creating you
can play with the payload and put in
stuff in there some sequence number some
time stamp something
and then when you receive the packet
back open it up and see what is in the
payload and then compare it with you
know with the time you receive it so
just giving you an idea of like how
scrappy can be used for any questions on
scrappy now let's move on to Jake Jake
you so said was pointing to like the
output from BGP LS which is a JSON we
need something to parse that JSON
because for proving or finding the
different parts you will have to process
this JSON and get the links and nodes
out of the output how do you do that you
can write your own Python program you
can write in Java whatever programming
language this is just a suggestion on
one of the tool which you can use but
feel free to use whatever you want to
use right so it's a JQ is a very
lightweight json processor and you know
like most of the vendors now allow you
to convert your CLI output into JSON and
also like XR v GP or any other tool by
the way we have X a BGP already
installed on the part so if you want to
use it for DG pls and the output which
we'll get from the parser you can take
that JSON and run it through JQ to find
out all your links and nodes so what is
VQ it's it's same as like in the same
family of tools as like said or graph
and if you look at for Gamal that is why
queue for XML there's XML starlett for
HTML that is pop which is in the same
category of tools single tool with no
dependencies which you can install
written in C and very very powerful and
some extra stuff on JQ it's it's it's in
the domain of the functional programming
languages so you have things like nap
filter select you can do flat nap
and other things it's doing complete so
you can take J cube and
you can run or you can write an
interpreter for someone has done it
actually interpreter for a programming
language called brain followed by a
curse word starts with F and that
programming language they have written
interpreter in JQ which is Turing
complete and what it means is anything
which is computationally feasible to
solve can be solved with JQ so that
particular language is just 8 set of
commands and instructions and it's
during complete and an interpreter for
that particular language is written in
JQ so what I'm trying to say it's very
very powerful it's a full feature set of
a programming language like Java C or
any other language which you normally
use which you can do it in JQ so for
going through JQ what we did is like
just a simple example this is the CLI
output on the left and and you have a
JSON output on the right you pipe it to
this position and you can get the JSON
from this Juniper router so there are
two blocks of a two interfaces the first
block I have shown an equivalent JSON
which will receive from the conversion
of this into JSON format and the first
and foremost important thing this is to
understand the schema can use whatever
you want to use use there are a number
of tools online you can cut and paste
the JSON output there and it can tell
you that the schema of the JSON or you
can go and read through this JSON and
try to figure out what are the different
attributes in the JSON what are the
different arrays in there how many
nestings of arrays in there and how can
go to a particular level and then filter
it out the NLRA types is something what
you might have to look for to find out
the links and nodes and go through your
JSON and Jake you can help into that so
we'll just concentrate on the first
block because I didn't want to put too
much on in terms of JSON formatted JSON
on the screen so the top one is a the
interface what the interface is what the
is eyes agency
level is what the state of it priority
IP address and other things so I I mean
if you guys are used to vs code you can
just use a plug-in like JSON to TS and
then quickly get the schema of your JSON
and you will see there is at the top
level there's a root object which
contains and which contains an array of
ice ice adjacency information then I
said Jason's information contains
attributes and I assess adjacency
another nested array into it and that
nested array is adjacency array has all
the details which you need about the you
know like if you want to figure out what
the interface it or the name of the
interface is and and if altima if you
want to create a CSV out of it so the
basic basic filter is a dot JQ as a
concept of filter if you say JQ single
code start and use it with your XML
sorry with your JSON you can you can get
a pretty print of your JSON that's a
pretty plain filter the first one after
that after the dot is two square
brackets the square brackets opening and
closing which is like a flat map of a
functional programming language so it
takes out the outer what you call the
one after the I sized agency indeed
formation that's an array the top array
it will take it out it's like a flat map
and gets you into the contents after
that so let's say if you were interested
in the xmlns attribute of it that's how
you will write the you have taken out
from the outer array then you've gone
into the first element of it and because
there is only one element inside that
outer array and then you go into the
attributes and then you want to get the
XML and s value of it there is an online
tool called JQ play dot org if you don't
want to do it on the command line as you
try out playing with JQ you will see the
output on this on the right and then you
can construct a test you would not do it
in a prod
an environment but you're all the JSON
on a website like Jake you played our
butt for this hack at least you can try
it out and construct and play with this
thing so if you want to go into the ISI
agents edges and see the 0 and the it
just sensory details you have to blocks
the first one you want to go in the
first interface and you want to get the
name of that particular interface so
this is the J cube query you can either
pipe it because it's you it works like
streams as well so you can get the JSON
file and then pipe it to JQ and JK would
print the name of the interface with
this particular query then if there are
multiple elements in an internal array
and you want to filter it out with a
particular criteria Here I am trying to
filter it out with a select select
interface name the data which the data
constituent is a 0.0 so it will go into
and and just get the a 0.0 element of
that array internal array then the goal
is to create a CSV so there are
different operators in JQ you can form a
JSON object out of the intermediate
output obtained from JQ so the last part
of this JQ query if you see after the
select the last of last pipe is creating
a custom json system name and interface
name which you see in the output you can
give any name of the property we want to
but that's what you are getting it which
will be used for creating a CSV so in
this what we added is square brackets
system name and interface name and then
we are passing it to at CSV which spits
out the CSV out this is just for one
element of the array and that particular
table so I mean it's too much to grasp
in this 10 minutes but
you have this PowerPoint you can look
through it and go through the example
and see it one additional thing is route
put in this JQ statement this route put
is to making sure that you proper like
JK will try to escape the double quotes
which is there in the output like vmx 19
1 1 that is in double quotes already the
data is already in double quotes so it
will try to escape it out you don't want
those extra double quotes so you can
just use route put on Jake you play
dot-org also you have a switch to turn
on the output or a compact output or
there are different options on line this
one little bit change in the the Select
query but now you are able to glean all
the interfaces from the table and that's
the CSV so think all links all nodes in
this format any questions on Jake you
you can write you a Python program to
parse the JSON any language of your
choice now for JSON there's nothing
better than GQ if you want to if you up
if you're thinking in terms of sad dark
to do things rather than writing full
flat Python program to parse or JSON key
thing understanding the schema that's
one if you understand the schema this
particular tool allows you to quickly
frame queries so now the bonus part if
you want to do visualization graph Anna
is already installed in flux Vivi's
already installed graph on is running on
the normal port for 3000 you can you can
format your output from what you get
from JQ into or what you want what you
want
the proach to look like said suggested
some are one or two or three or five you
can create those probes and and kind of
like do you create those probes and then
you run your program which is capi to
send to the different devices once you
get the packet back you open it up you
check what you got in that try to create
kind of like something which you can
insert at time series data into in flux
once it gets inserted into in flux you
can see it on Gravano so this one
example this is the format is called
Klein protocol format order in flux you
can create a text file like this you can
import into in flux this in this there I
am using two tags the probe number and
the time the RTT time and the sequence
number if you are using something like a
sequence number or the probe number it's
up to you to design whatever you want to
do and then the timestamp at which you
receive the packet back these are the
data points for in flux you can improve
influx into import this data into influx
with this once you are on a graph on ax
admin admin is the password and your
part go to port 3000 login and then you
have you have to configure for the first
time it will ask you to change the
password you leave it is the same as
admin and then you show the data source
as in flux try to connect it and flips
by default runs on port 80 0 it's sorry
yeah put 8 0 8 say 8 6 and then you can
check their connectivity and you should
get something the data source is working
properly so and then you have graph Anna
you have panels and you can create the
panels you can specify the query like
what probe what value you have to look
for you can create multiple panels so
play with it if you agree to the bonus
stage if you need help we are here we
can point to like write tutorials or
whatever there is already some links
there or we can help you to create the
dashboards so these are the packages
already installed on the part scappini
network ax X a VG p JQ n flux and this
is the credentials and the login details
questions for both of us
yea-ah
so special thanks to two pseudo I'll for
setting up laughs for us man see your
paper with all the details how he can
access the lab let's get started
these are all the links probably you'll
need to so like Scapa cheat sheet JQ
playground that Deepak mentioned you
cannot hear you okay cool
better okay so all the useful links so
Scapa cheat sheet that you can use to
construct packet JQ playground that
Deepak mansion some crap on a docks and
get repo for getting all the slides and
actually some of the documents so
there's a nice diagram of topology that
you can pull from if you just clone that
git repo on your laptop so you'll get
all the slides and other information
that we have put in that git repo I'll
leave this slide on so you can use all
the links on this slide and let's get
started I'll give it to Michael so does
anybody not have a team okay we have
just one just one person
okay so so anyway so anybody who doesn't
have a team please raise your hand
so everybody look around at the piece so
the people that have raised their hands
you could go and talk to other people to
see what they're working on and anybody
who does have a team and saw somebody
raising their hand if they want to be
kind enough to reach out maybe say like
hey you should come and join my team
because my team's going to do this
amazing thing so once your teams are
formed
yeah would would anybody like to so
anybody who is not working on the goals
that Syed and Deepak presented on if
anybody is doing their own project would
you like to come up here and pitch to
the three people who do not have do not
have teams
oh thanks so much hi I'm Ryan rod and
I'm a network architect with conversin
based out of Chicago and I'm gonna be
continuing hopefully a project that
started at the first and hackathon in
2016 which was to assemble commodity
console servers from raspberry PI's or
similar hardware the goal was to have it
be a self discovering SS aging back to
the central server so that you can SSH
directly into the device across
firewalls and other network boundaries I
have them be self discovering so you
have a single view of all consoles and
their downstream connected devices
ideally a WebSockets browser client so
you can point-and-click to gain access
to the server the downstream devices
through the browser and a bunch of other
use cases that would help you know
rather than having to talk somebody in a
remote office through connect you know
to this console port and web X here and
type these commands to get it you know
fix something or deploying your network
this is a device you maybe could ship
out with a 4G dongle attached to it and
it phones home as soon as powered up and
plugged into something else we used
within Deus era networks know their
locations so in nano 67 hackathon we had
developed a framework where it's self
registered with the main API you could
see the list of active devices and there
are downstream ports that were available
they opened SSH connection back to the
specified SSH server and the next steps
would be working on getting that console
port exposed via a command or a command
line or SSH access and then ideally the
WebSocket server and client if anybody
is interested in that this is a whole
all in Python 3 so anybody who's
comfortable with that and knows
WebSockets in particular I have no
knowledge of that
and could use a help with that aspect of
it so if Emily's interested I'm over
there I've got some hardware with me to
help facilitate development testing as
well thank you anybody else
okay so once you have your teams formed
please send a representative up to the
front table to get some instructions on
how to set up your virtual
infrastructure as well as let's know
what pod you are so that people aren't
everybody's not going to try to work on
the same virtual infrastructure and then
you'll can also write down all the
members of your team so we know who
who's working on what project okay
any other general questions all right
good luck today if you have any
questions you could visit this table up
in the front or the table way in the
back ends one of your friendly hackathon
mentors will help out all right like
okay so we followed the god today and
basically an overview of what we did was
be established bgp and the dev boxes
received and parceling state information
with EXA bgp we fed that into that work
x2 builder graft and as a weighted
weights and edges so we can calculate
the best path using network X and then
finally we crafted some packets with
escapee to test link for failure
scenarios so first basically we ran into
an issue with XM easy P at the beginning
we didn't think it was installed just
because the binary wasn't accessible so
lost a little bit of time doing an
apt-get install and then the boon to
version actually ended up having a bug
where it tried to send md5 for
everything so lost a little bit of time
on that but once we use the installed
version provided we were able to
establish BGP on the boxes and then
parse out you're able to parse output
via script received for each route
received we weren't able to get that
working we were playing around with it a
little bit but we weren't able to get
that JSON so what we did as a workaround
was once once we have BGP established of
course not only is the dev box receiving
the route but the juniper is also
sending the route so we logged on to the
juniper box and just did the show route
advertising protocol BGP piped it the
display JSON copy that into a file and
then pasted it into a Python interpreter
played around a little bit with that
and that we're
x4 network X we just did a couple
imports we added the correct weights
that were fed to us from from the BGP LS
information and then using Network X we
were able to calculate both best pass
using the provided single source
Dijkstra path method available in
network X and force KP I'm gonna pass it
off so for this KP initially it got a
bit tricky in at least sending out the
ICMP ping packets as well but eventually
we were successful enough to actually
send that and then we started forming
more packets the GRE and cap packets and
then sending them forward so based on
whatever information we received from
the network X we had those many paths in
there and those many packets for each of
those paths and we send them in a loop
and after that like so when we run the
sniff script where we are actually
sniffing for those packets so we get for
all the paths we get these so it
calculates the RTD and then as you see
the second loss field it's like one two
five three one is nothing but the router
path that it takes basically R 1 R 2 R 5
and so on
for all of those paths so we had that
and a transfer says fully for n number
of packets being generated and then we
did the failure scenario where we say
for instance our link goes down between
r2 and r4 and it was able to sniff and
probe correctly that information that
all the routes I mean all the paths that
included that link wall down and but it
was successfully able to probe the rest
of the links which was still up not
using that link so that's that was
pretty much with this KP and yeah so
this is what we had today so then for
future work we were looking to actually
take the data you saw in the last slide
and actually record it into in flux and
maybe visualize it with the graph on oh
and then we can actually set up some
alerts with a graph on I let's say I'll
link down or something like that so
that's what we have thanks so much for
listening
[Applause]
when we were continuing work on the
PyCon project I was describing earlier
from the Nanna hackathon of 2016 the
recap of the use cases we're looking to
solve or cases where you're deploying
new equipment in the field or having to
talk users through troubleshooting over
the phone they may not be equipped to do
the goal was to take some commodity
hardware and solve this faster and
cheaper than some off-the-shelf
proprietary platforms that you might
have a longer lead time to get and
configure and deploy in your environment
the overall mechanism that was already
in place prior to today is that the
devices can be deployed they call back
to the central API that the agent is
started with and they report their
addresses the port's that they're the
console ports they have available and
then they can also be given information
to tunnel back to an SSH server for
remote SSH access in the future I think
we're all familiar with the kind of
ubiquity of Raspberry Pi on the related
hardware the last few years it's cheap
its reliable it's easy to stock and
deploy and automate against with your
software of choice our next steps that
we outlined a few years ago that the
project's been pretty much dormant since
then was to apply some add some
WebSockets to get a browser-based
experience to access the console and
potentially have simultaneous use or
maybe exclusivity and then also have
more UI and API enhancements that you
can interact with the the data manually
or programmatically to automate against
it as well so today we were picking up
where we left off and the agent does
startup it registers it reports
everything and it gets some config
information back for the tunnel server
this is nothing particularly new in the
UI we made some enhancements for how the
data is presented and also started
adding the capability for the server to
take some configuration data of how the
console is connected to downstream
devices so in this case the main thing
demonstrated is the de port descriptions
which are configurable in the device
details page you're able to click on
those and edit them through the page as
opposed to have to as
to have to hard code it in the database
or any llamó files this came with some
changes to how the console port
information is aged and tracked in the
database as well so that this
information and other information can be
persisted as configuration Oliver also
made a lot of progress on researching
the WebSockets functionality and we got
a proof-of-concept embedded so that
multiple users can load the WebSockets
now you're able to see actions replicate
from one user to another however we
don't have it interacting with the
console back-end yet we do have a script
made by another teammate that is able to
open the serial console and that can be
embedded in the agent as part of our the
next steps on the project to hopefully
get some data flowing across it so we
gained a bunch of experience with
researching into WebSockets and then the
asynchronous workflows that come with
that I think none of us have really ever
touched anything like this before
interacting with the tty through the
Python serial module was a first for all
of us as well and then also we kind of
brushed off some of our experience with
bootstrap and jQuery to make some of
these UI changes and implement more a
few more api routes and then i describe
some of those UI tweaks and progress
made their takeaways are flask and
bootstrap do simplify non-developer aka
network engineer and and other people
hacking on this the progress is
accelerated however when you go to do
something like WebSockets and
asynchronous i/o and everything else
especially through a stack like we are
trying to aim for it is much more
humbling of an experience so trying to
implement the whole workflow through the
WebSockets front-end the API and and
kind of database middle layer and then
the real time interaction with the
consoles will take quite a bit more
planning but we have a few more building
blocks and proof concepts to work with
that's pretty much it thanks to
everybody on the team for your help
today
[Applause]
so hot hi everyone so we are the rookies
I'm to me now run off ribbon and sudden
shoot if I'm correct yeah so the next
line
yeah so this is the roadmap that we
decided to follow
we decided first to get of course the
topology of the of the network and then
to try to we try to build the network
graph and to use this graph to get the
only possible path to the two hosts and
then we try to construct construct probe
packets and they last the last step was
introducing and accounting failures but
wasn't able to do that so we just we
divided the team into two smaller groups
the first team or the first group was
supposed to do the three first part and
the second team was working on the three
last the three last parts that you can
see on the on the board so pro now we
will talk about this overview so this is
the overview block diagram of what we
were trying to do the ones in green is
once which were successfully able to do
it most of it and the light green Sun
were we ran out of time you were unable
to implement it so as you can see we use
X a BGP to collect the flows and you we
wrote a script to parse that information
and write it to a database for this
hackathon we just use yes we we didn't
have enough time to move to enter in
flux TB so we just stuck to CSV and we
had visualization on one side and we set
up an alert square email us email client
if it sees any changes it says sense was
an email and we have pro packets which
the team too has worked on they will
talk more about it and integrate into
the part selection for passing the data
we took the data which was being written
into our text file and we were passing
that information and writing into a CSV
file
collecting all the informations all the
information which we need it in two
separate files one for notes and one for
links so that we have clear
understanding of what's happening where
and then we used used Network X to
visualize this information and which
Lazar attributes related to that hello
for the second part we started trying to
or we were struggling to how to identify
the best possible path so we basically
get the notes and they're linked
information from the from Abitibi link
estate but at some point we assume that
we're going to have equal cost and we
discard to the possibility to to to
calculate the best path from the from
the house point of view so we basically
live for for for later on and please
Jane so we basically put the effort
because it took it took us some time to
build a profile send and automate the
the continuous probe sending that we
basically implemented as a cron job in
the in the dev device so we are
constantly monitoring their reach
ability for future roadmap Bob we want
to clean up the instead of using CSV use
in flex DB and cleaning up the email
client I have a very busy basic humidity
line and make it as close to real time
as possible both visualization as well
as alerts when it comes to alerting and
best part calculation what we want to
implement that and I didn't wanna fill
your links and writing remediation
scripts if if there was if there's a
failure to go back and fix it by a
config change or just by alerting thank
you
[Applause]
okay so we're a team pod 3 so what we
did was first get a better understanding
of xcb GP and what we did was once we
started that process Geoff one of our
team members started to work on Python
to parse that data then what once we
have that parsed data then we feed it
into network X to have a network graph
constantly updated as we get new
information and then scampi was a pain
we'll talk about it really quickly so we
split it onto two parts so in an
announced means that the path is valid
so what we did was we give Network X
this data set here where it tells you ok
router 1 has reach ability to router to
router 2 has reach ability to model and
so on and so forth so the announce is
good the network graph will map that if
a link goes down we send a withdrawal
and then our team member took that and
took it out of the network graph so I'm
not gonna linger on this it doesn't make
a lot of sense but this is what we tried
to visualize of what was going on this
was the data that was gathered from X of
EGP through Python parsing it to give us
this data that we fed into Network X and
then this is Scapa here so what we did
was very similar to one of the teams we
set it on these four paths right these
are the four best possible paths in
terms of hops the ending values there
show the route that it took all right
router one to two to four to six and
four five to six and so on and that's it
so oh yeah future roadmap will get
influx working with grow fauna thank you
so hi everyone we are team met buffs and
we are students in the University of
Colorado Boulder so honestly this
hackathon was a little overwhelming for
all of us because of the number of tools
and the number of objectives we had to
achieve but yeah I think we tried to
manage and try to do what best we could
do in the given amount of time so this
is the topology that we were given and
from that we tried to find out all the
best possible paths using Network X tool
and we could find out these number of
paths based on which we try to build a
network monitoring logic so this is a
code snapshot this may not be visible to
all of you but what we have done here is
we've used KP two of you know based on
the number of paths that we found using
Network X we use KP to create those
number of Pro packets for the number of
hops based out of each of the route that
we got and those Pro packets will be
sent from dev one - dev - and a response
will be received from dev - so the pro
packet that we created each of those pro
packets had the timestamp value for the
time the packet was sent at and when the
packet is received is received with the
timestamp of for the arrival time so we
took out the time difference to find out
latency in each of the parts in each of
the routes now this code snippet that
you see the first part of that is a
function that's calculating the time
difference and if the time difference is
more than one second or you know you can
take any number but we have just taken
one second as a latency value so if that
value on any route is more than one
second for a packet then we will trigger
an email will basically raise a ticket
with a tool called
freshdesk which is a ticketing tool used
by many organizations so that ticketing
tool will have a message that will
contain the route that had latency and
the monitoring team will take the
necessary action to fix that
because we didn't I mean as of now we
didn't plan on how to fix the issue so
this is a small video that yeah so we
try to just capture what we did so so
one part of the screen is the part
that's sniffing the packet back at dev 1
and the other part is actually running
the entire script which has propak 'its
so you can see the message there
highlighted part it says delay in this
route is higher than the threshold so we
are creating a new ticket based on the
latency or the threshold value so the
ticket looks something like this it will
have the content so the ticket is
automatically created with the contain
something like there is a high latency
on our one or two or four-hour six route
please take necessary action and this is
now coming to the X of e gb part we
didn't know much about XR bgp so we
tried to use the file that was given to
us the JSON file to parse some of the
information such as the neighbor ID our
neighbour address interface ID and
printed using pretty table in the UI so
for our project this is the future scope
we would want to scale this to a high
number of 4 devices as of now we did a
very small test
with just a few number of devices but in
future we would like to see whether this
works actually in a production network
with a large number of devices and also
we would like to add more features and
more metrics apart from the latency that
we try to capture and so with since we
just did monitoring at the moment we
would also like to incorporate some
traffic engineering where we can take
some action based on the fault or based
on the latency or some issue that we
find alright so the takeaway from that
entire day was we got to use KP this was
new for us
dislike XIV GP n BG pls and network X
but we did spend a lot of time using
scape e just like most of you so that
was a good learning for us and we would
like to use its KP and that too
in any other automation that we would do
in future and apart from that some not
so like some things that we learned were
like planning in a short amount of time
how can you plan a hack like this
we did some teamwork we assigned
different roles to each member in the
team so that we could make the most of
the short time and yeah some other
things like hacking and time management
these are team members thank you hello
are we good hi We're Team four or in
team zero all at the same time we had
fun trying to figure out how to do a
PowerPoint onto the screen and before
that we had fun doing the hackathon so
if we're gonna go into the first part of
it this is the exit BGP everyone my name
is Mark so we kind of did the same thing
I think a lot of people did we divided
and conquered so myself and David took
the exit BGP and Network X and
determining the best paths so myself or
David I don't think we had any
experience at the exit BGP before so we
spent a lot of time trying to figure out
how the data came back when it was
stored trying to figure out how we could
normalize it put into JSON so spend a
lot of time there finally we got the
data normalized
we have it now to the point where all
the structures in place where we can
populate the network x graphs what you
see up here is manually populated but
all the nodes are being populated with
code and the first block of addresses
are also being populated with code again
data that's being received by XM EGP I
would say next steps are to also same
thing we manually added the weights
in here they were all communicated as 10
so it'd be nice if we had some different
weights we noticed that they weren't
those values weren't being introduced
into X of BGP for some reason so we were
just able to manually see that the
weights were 10 I know that we can get
the way it's pretty easily by yeah next
steps are the framework is all there to
make all of this completely done with
code first is going in and you know hand
jamming it which I think most teams did
I'm at least for the the network X piece
and yeah I'm gonna hand it off work the
monitoring piece copy all right then we
did the Scapa piece which we divided
into two probes and the probe code in
the receive code the pro code was just
sending the timestamp and the payload
and the segment it was going over based
upon some manually entered data and then
that's actually this is the received
code so this cool
so this off that payload what would
happen would be in SCAP II they were to
throw that packet to that function
called calculate our TT and it would
print off into the file and it'd be good
this is the probe that we're doing but
most of it was just mainly entered
there's no sissy output we did it by
segments instead of hops just like
segment one would be R 2 R 3 R 4 R 6
test that segment there's your air TT
and then just send the probe packets as
it will so that was it thanks
yeah sometime
sorry it's kind of hard to drive and use
the microphone so we were able to get
the structure down get everything put
into the correct dictionaries and start
getting the data in as you can see the
all the nodes are being added in but the
edges of course
liyan I think what most people did was
putting these in manually and then
running it through the canned network
acts methods router info again all
dynamically brought in so I figured
another team code code I'd show some
code that we worked on too so one minute
and that's it thanks all right I think
we have enough votes in so we are going
to call it a tie between net buffs and
PyCon so a round of applause really to
everybody who hacked well and learned a
lot and hopefully made new friends today
let's do the raffle and so the stuff
that we're raffling off this time
so everybody pull out your cards we have
a total of eight things that we're
giving away four of the circuit
playground Express from Adafruit
and we also have Kanak it's raspberry pi
B pluses so you can build your own
console servers okay I will pull the
ticket and if you have it come on up
five nine one six zero seven seven are
you here us a present to win that's
right okay
are you right here okay good okay all
right
choose okay all right okay we're getting
an alternate now this one is for the
circuit playground Express this looks
cool okay I chose a number at random
five nine one six zero seven nine
there you go all right okay okay five
nine one six one zero six six one zero
six anyone's oh it's why you're there
good okay all right you get a rest right
[Music]
one of these okay okay oh this one here
okay that's why I lost count
okay
five nine one six zero nine zero six
zero nine zero anybody yeah okay there
you go you're gonna take your picture
you keep it it's yours yeah welcome okay
where's Barry Pike alright five nine one
six zero seven three looks right okay
here you go okay five nine one six zero
six one
[Applause]
there you go and she's gonna take your
paycheck okay all right all right goes
to you guys have gotten a lot faster at
checking your tickets by the way I
appreciate that if I have nine one six
zero nine two there you go
he's gonna take your picture oh okay all
right
and today's last prize goes to five nine
one six zero five eight hey remember you
can build a console server out of this
thank you okay thank you all right
thanks
I just posted a link to the survey for
the hackathon if you could please
complete that and give us your feedback
on a new experience today that'd be
appreciated I posted in a slack channel
it's also on the same page where the
surveys will be for the rest of the
Nanog conference so if you don't fill it
out now please fill it out this week
Thanks and so thanks again for everybody
who participated in here I hope
everybody had a good experience there is
there's a reception right outside so
please everybody go to it drink and eat
and be merry be sure to like talk to
other people that you haven't yet talked
to you today especially thank our
sponsors from Oracle and to pseudo for
the teams that won please come and see
me and aside from Oracle to figure out
how we're going to do the presentations
during the plenary session that's going
to be on Tuesday afternoon everybody
please save any work that you care about
that happened on these development
machines we're going to be destroying
all the virtual infrastructure later
tonight I don't think the the PyCon team
is going to be worried about this since
they didn't use the virtual
infrastructure but for team buffs we're
going to leave your stuff around so that
you can get a presentation together for
for Tuesday if there's any other
questions please come and talk to me or
anybody else from the sponsors or the
hackathon theme and again thank you very
much and see you outside
you