hello everyone
so I'm actually who in here heard me
talk about DNS Flag Day in San Francisco
all right
that Flag Day has already passed and
everyone's DNS survived more or less
yeah okay
all right if they're members of the
press here we're always here in this
room excited that the internet still
functions yeah all right so of course so
the whole deal with DNS Flag Day in 2019
and then also the new one that we're
going to do next year is that the DNS
protocol is goodness like 35 years old
now so we've made a lot of changes over
the years to the protocol with mixed
results on how people implement that and
what I mean by mixed results is very
often things like firewalls will not
implement exactly what the RFC state
they should implement so this is really
a lot of that push what what happens in
the DNS world when firewalls or
middleware boxes don't do exactly what
they should by protocol then DNS vendors
have to sort of work around that and
ensure that the user still gets the
answer that they need even though some
boxes in between aren't playing nice in
the protocol okay that's the very
high-level overview all right so when I
say in this talk we this is the we that
I'm referring to so when I say the DNS
community in this case these are the
folks that participation that
participated in this Flag Day so the one
in 2019 was about ensuring that everyone
that plays in the DNS protocol
implementation space implements properly
a DNS or extension mechanisms for DNS
okay that protocol is 20 years old so
yay for getting full compliance after 20
years in the Internet that's great
anyway this is pretty to me a
significant moment in internet history
if you will all of these parties came
together and agree
that we were gonna do something about
this problem again those workarounds
that implementers have to do create
problems for you in terms of you know
you know possibly more bugs in the code
more delays so we're trying to make the
DNS ecosystem better by doing this okay
I also want to say that I've been in the
operations community or I've done
operations for most of my professional
career so I understand the nervousness
you get with things like Flag Day and
the the Flag Day name is little I won't
sing misleading but it's a date by which
the implementers are no longer going to
work around brokenness it is not a date
in which your DNS is going to fall off
the earth and you're no longer going to
be visible on the internet okay but the
name actually got us exactly what we
wanted is that people started paying
attention to this and people that pay
people to do their DNS services or pay
firewall vendors ask their provider to
ensure that they were compliant with
these changes so so that worked out all
right yeah so what do we have now so
we've passed this other we passed the
2019 Flag Day and so you know as good
engineers do things went well so then we
have to do something else right
so we started looking at the DNS what is
what problems remain the main one that
we're trying to fix with this new flag
day in 2020 and I want to I want to
point out that's number one the Flag Day
date has not been set yet for 2020 one
of the complaints to us and the DNS
community was that we did not properly
announce in good fashion the 2019 for
that day so we're trying to get out
ahead of that issue this time around so
so anyway there are problems with
fragmentation in DNS particularly in the
ipv6 realm how many of you have had
equipment that does not honor i p v6
extension headers or
I've had or still have yes okay a couple
of hands okay so anyway this creates
problems in terms particularly for DNS
that if fragmentation isn't handled
properly oftentimes this will cause
problems for the clients now we work
really hard to work around that
so DNS works really hard to try to ask
other servers the same questions if they
don't get the answer that they you know
expect or don't get an answer but this
really again creates a lot of delay in
the DNS one thing I want to say very
clearly is this 2020 Flag Day does not
mean that DNS is not going to still take
place primarily over UDP it will still
mostly take place over UDP what we are
saying in 2020 which is the next slide
is number one that you have to do if
you're going to do DNS as any kind of
device or application you have to be
able to perform TCP it doesn't mean that
you will always it just means that you
have to be able to fall back to that if
needed if the answer is too large we're
not going to defragment at this point so
we're gonna switch back to TCP or switch
to TCP to to ensure we we can talk so
the other so I said that the 2020 Flag
date has not yet been set the other
thing that is not quite set yet is what
we're gonna actually set the e DNS
buffer size to so the extension
mechanisms for DNS allow for up to 4 0 9
6 bytes in the DNS message but again
there is a lot of equipment that can't
handle things and fragmentation starts
to happen right around that 1220 byte
size
so we're thinking somewhere around in
there is going to be what we set this to
be okay again pointing out firewalls
here my apologies to the firewall
vendors but we're happy to help you try
to decipher what the RFC's mean if
you're confused we'd love to help okay
let's see here okay so the other thing
we got a lot of feedback on is your
website and I want to state a lot of
this please for from the operator
perspective what do you have to
do today the answer is nothing in terms
of configuring things so yeah but please
still listen you're out your job is to
be aware of this and to go out to the
DNS flagged a net site and on there we
will keep you updated and posted with
things like the date and what we set
this buffer size to be also on that site
is a test tool that the test tool is in
progress so we'll be working on that in
the coming weeks you can do manual tests
by firing off these example Digg
commands here and again if you have
contacts at any of the people on that
list of folks that are cooperating in
this and you have problems with your
tests all of us respond to direct emails
sometimes even phone calls about how you
can be compliant or what you need to
tell your provider so that your domain
can be compliant ok so that's what I
just said please go to the DNS Flag Day
site you can also follow DNS flag day on
Twitter for you youngsters yeah and then
talk to us at different places and again
we're going to try to be more proactive
in announcing what we're doing and when
we're doing it these are some really
good references if you're sort of
confused about what I'm talking about
one thing that I'd really like to
highlight is Jeff Houston's link on here
and the slides will be available on the
on this site but Jeff really talks about
the problem with the fragmentation in
ipv6 you know v4 handles fragmentation
very differently than v6 and the
fragmentation of v6 does cause some very
significant problems in the DNS so I'd
like to point that one out the other
thing is fujiwara song from j PRS
reported recently you know until
recently we thought the the
fragmentation attacks on the dns we're
sort of lab only exercises but he's
maybe this isn't the case so we're
trying to get ahead of that as well and
so some of this is not only just for
functionality but for improved security
let's see
and I thought I had one more slide but I
guess I do not I do not okay oh this is
the older one it doesn't have I'm sorry
this this set doesn't have cat pictures
in it we did a new one that had cat
pictures and my apologies that one
didn't get updated anyway I sent oh it's
my fault okay so with that we have just
a few minutes if anyone has any
questions about this I'm happy to try to
address them
okay very good thank you
[Applause]
you