hi everyone thanks for sticking around
for the Wednesday lightning talks I'm
David wish Nick I am an academic fellow
at the University of Pennsylvania Law
School Center for technology innovation
and competition don't run out of the
room because I said Law School I'm
talking about rpki which is a technical
topic but it has some legal elements to
it so I'm presenting an update on some
work that I've been doing with
Christopher you who couldn't be here
today and we are funded by the National
Science Foundation you can see the award
number down at the bottom if you want to
go check out the details in the public
record so what I'm going to do today is
just describe a little bit about our
project where we've been coming from and
then give an update on where things
stand with potential legal barriers to
rpki adoption in North America so for
those who don't know I'll give a really
brief background on rpki it is a two
sided framework to secure routing tables
and what people do is if they hold IP
addresses they can create certificates
that identify authentic IP address
origins so it's origin validation not
route validation once you su a route
origin authorization or OA other people
who are running networks can then
validate routes based on those rows and
decide how to treat them in their
routing table so two sided framework
signing and validation now the last
twelve months have been quite eventful
for rpki
let's see so beginning in July MTT began
combining rpki information with irr data
to improve some of their filtering some
good things some bad things in August
2018 Amazon DNS was hijacked later in
2018 CloudFlare committed to rpki and
they began developing their own route
validator called octo rpki and let's see
in February 20 19 18 T began filtering
routes Google is doing similar things
and over a hundred networks have joined
I Sox manners
mutually agreed norms for routing
security so we're at perhaps something
of an inflection point in terms of
buy-in on rpki
in North America on the other hand if
you look at some of the figures from the
worldwide perspective you can see that
the North American region is not doing
as well especially as ripe and aap Nick
that's on both signing and validation so
on the signing side this graph is not
perfect it's but you can see the the
blue line represents Aaron in terms of
percentage of declared ipv4 space
covered by rows now that blue line is
well below ripe and below lakh Nick and
below a peanut but as you can see in the
past few months there's been a decided
uptick in terms of row issuance now the
problem that may in fact be a bigger
problem is that people who then issue
those rows might want people who are
doing validation to validate based on
those rows
unfortunately in 2018 a researcher named
Ben Cartwright Cox found that 80% of
people who are engaging in ROV
at the time that he looked into it were
omitting the Aaron tau that may have
changed since then but that is a that's
a disheartening number from 2018 so
what's what's the problem one hypothesis
that was kicked around a couple of years
ago at Nanog in fact was that there were
some legal barriers that were specific
to the North American region and what
Christopher you and I have been doing
over the past year and a half or so is
looking into that hypothesis trying to
kick the tires we interviewed a lot of
you we got a lot of feedback trying to
piece together what are the legal
barriers and how might they be addressed
so you know there were reports and
people was specifically focused on an
indemnification clause in Aaron's
contract called the relying party
agreement which is what people have to
agree to if they're going to engage in
validation using the Aaron trust Anchor
locator so that was the hypothesis what
did we do to kick to figure out whether
that was true or not we analyzed a lot
of legal materials contract
policies court cases we interviewed a
lot of stakeholders and we engaged with
people in the Aaron and Anna community
over over a number of meetings trying to
really understand things we made some
presentations and again I really want to
reiterate how helpful everybody was who
we reached out to for interviews within
this community we also released a report
in December 2018 you can read it at this
annoyingly complex link which will be
posted on the nanite website or you can
email me for a fresh copy and then we
presented at Aaron 43 and so one of the
things that our report had is a bunch of
recommendations for what the North
American routing community might want to
do to address some of the salient legal
issues and Aaron has been quite
receptive to the report and at Aaron 43
there was a discussion Christopher you
my colleague presented John Curran
presented on the topic and the upshot is
that Aaron is committed to conducting a
full review of their contractual
policies having to do with rpki
likely to conclude by the end of 2019
commenters at Aaron 43 in Barbados
encouraged swift action and indeed one
commenter said if you want to increase
my fees you're welcome to I don't know
if everybody agrees with that but just
reporting one one person's view on that
topic
it's about any rate the key takeaway
here is that there is a lot of interest
in this and there's dialogue going on
that Aaron is quite involved with and as
a member driven community
you all should you know feel free to
reach out to to Aaron and to you know be
a participant in this dialogue going
forward so that's the procedure of
what's going on what's the substance I'm
gonna go through this at a very high
level you can read all 35 pages of our
report if you want or like the three
executive summary pages maybe that's
more you know that might be a little
easier but at any rate the key
high-level issues the first one has to
do with acceptance of the relying party
agreement going into the past few months
there's been a difference between how
you access the towel for
the other four are IRS and for Aaron
that's because in or in the u.s. in
order to get a binding contract you need
to have some sort of manifestation of a
sent click a little box or you see in
your visual field something that says
there's a contract here you're hereby
aware and you're going through our web
page you'll be bound by this that is not
something that the other our IRS have
demanded but it's something that Aaron
has felt necessary based on the US legal
environment so one of the key things
that is perceived to be holding back
adoption is that that difference which
makes it hard to automate the download
of the Aaron tell also there are some in
dem there are some clauses in the our PA
that people have have suggested are
holding back their organizations from
participating in our PKI one of those
has to do with indemnification so you
know those are the key issues what what
did we recommend in our report we really
went through a couple of scenarios that
and we think Aaron should be considering
right now one of them is elimination of
the RP RP a altogether that would
obviously allow software developers to
automate the download of the air Intel
without any contract there would be no
contract anymore
now we think that's a reasonable path we
also think that there are other
reasonable paths one of which is to
consider dropping the indemnification
clause and replacing it or retaining
what's known as an as is disclaimer that
would allocate liability in a way that's
maybe less onerous on the user than the
indemnification clause there are lots of
puts and takes to this topic it's
complex and both paths are reasonable by
our lights but they and they you know
fall out in different ways in terms of
who's advantaged and who is able to do
what they want with with the air in town
now another idea we floated is the
creation of a new nonprofit that would
be in charge of distributing the the
rows and the materials you get through
the air Intel now that I don't know
whether that is gaining traction or not
it's maybe a little bit out there of a
solution but you could imagine
organization that doesn't have the other
functions that Aaron has taking a
different approach to how they view
liability that they're trying to protect
through contract lastly we suggested
that it would be useful to encourage
people to integrate acceptance of the
RPA into validator software rather than
having to send people on their own to
the Aaron website to get the to get the
towel now I'm happy to report that Rudin
800 dot 4.0 is doing that right now
and Aaron is open to anybody who wants
to build software that automates well
now other than puts it in the workflow
for getting getting a routing validator
software up and running to put it in
that and very very similarly what you
see in this workflow right here which
says if you agree to the agreement
please run the command now that's a lot
easier and a lot quicker than having to
go to the Aaron website and get things
going that way not everybody's satisfied
that by that it does it still is a
roadblock of a sort in the process but I
think that it's great that Aaron has
made that possible and that the
team-building route inator has put that
into practice so what are the other
issues another issue is in the RP a
there is a clause called the prohibited
conduct clause that prohibits the
distribution of machine readable
information about rpki
now you can imagine a lot of really
useful reasons why you might want to
distribute machine readable information
about rpki
analysis for research you might even
want to use it for real-time routing and
filtering like MTT is combining rpki
information with IRR information people
might have creative ways of using this
and wanting to do some machine readable
transfer of information in real time my
sense and and John can can correct me if
I'm wrong is that Aaron is open to uses
of this that are responsible and that
don't impose safety concerns and risks
on the use of rpki information so if
you're interested in doing that kind of
thing I think it would be sensible to
shoot an email Darren the one of the big
takeaway like the global take away from
Christopher and my work over the past
year and change is that dialogue and
reaching out to organizations that are
here to support the community would move
things forward and so if you have gripes
about legal things like that good to get
your team involved maybe check in with
the lawyers the organization reach out
to Aaron and try to build some dialogue
I think that we're seeing progress
because that dialogue is moving forward
right now so another recommendation we
made is if you are buying anything that
has any adjacency to routing think about
putting the use of rpki
in your procurement requirements that
would build a network effect to get
signing invalidation off the ground in
north america
lastly publicize information about best
practices reach out to manners learn how
to do this that is a way to get this
thing off the ground
legal issues might hold everybody up but
it's going to be tech deployment that
gets rpki going and to that end
deployment of best practices there are
our FCS on this useful to do it more
important to do it right and to do it
safely so especially for failover and
solicit advice from people and our IRS
also should be following best practices
in making disclosures about service
levels so engage Aaron should can be
considering the RP a changes right now
and the Aaron community should really
consider some of these recommendations
and should be engaging in dialogue as
this review that the erendor is
undertaking is going on and with that
I'd like to open it up for questions if
anybody has questions on this topic
happy to answer them and maybe engage in
some dialogue right here
hi my name is Ross can you explain what
the relying party agreement is and why
people would not want to agree to that
sure I'm sorry that I didn't give a
high-level description of the relying
party agreement up front so it is the
agreement that binds people who are
downloading the repository of Roiz and
certificates and things like that
through access to the towel I think John
may have some close enough for rock and
roll okay yeah so so the agreement that
you have to enter into in order to gain
access to the materials you get through
the air until now people might not want
to bind themselves to it because you
some people as organisations don't allow
them to agree to indemnification clauses
if you encounter an identification
clause then you as a person who's
considering signing that contract can't
do it under your organisation's rules
other people may not know what's in it
and may feel uncomfortable clicking
through it people may just not want to
on philosophical grounds agree to terms
and conditions on something like rpki
which is supposed to have very
widespread deployment so there all sorts
of reasons and you know an organisation
like Aaron has to balance which of those
they credit in which of those they don't
and people have to internally within
their own organisations figure out what
their policies are in terms of those
types of agreements and there's a big
thing in open source as well is that
helpful yeah thank you sure
hi I'm Scott do these same restrictions
apply and are these same problems
evident is it still relevant what you're
talking about so I think that that would
be covered by the registration services
agreement that Aaron has and that also
has very similar terms but everybody
who's running a network and who's a
member of Aaron has already signed on to
that contract so rubber doesn't meet the
road in the same way okay thank you
mm-hmm I I can speak to that
Rob see strim I'm on the air in advisory
council I'm speaking only for myself
here but I'm gonna limit my commentary
to the technical aspects of this this
there are two halves of our PKI and you
need to separate them in your mind the
registration services agreement is
coupled with your ability to issue Roiz
and whether you run your own you're self
hosted or whether you do the hosted
validator with Aaron is orthogonal to
the question of validating the other
people's Roiz and the discussion here
has been centered around the relying
party agreement which you need to get
the towel from Aaron which is it's like
the trust anchor that's in your web
browsers that says I believe Symantec
certs or I believe Komodo or whatever
it's it's what allows you to validate
other people's announcements so split
that into two halves thank you okay
thanks Rob and thank you David thank you
you