good morning everybody
so you just heard from John CEO of Aaron
my name is ELISA Moore and I sit on the
Aaron Advisory Council so I am NOT staff
I'm a member of the Aaron community and
I am elected to their Advisory Council
body which is a group of 15 folks from
different sections of the community and
were elected for a three-year term to
basically Shepherd
community developed community oriented
policy proposals through the policy
development process so we come from a
wide variety of different backgrounds
very representative of the community
some of us work for large ISPs media -
peas small ISPs I personally work for a
top-level domain operator there's
nonprofits representation for profit
representation university networks
government network so the whole gamut of
different kinds of network operators
representing network operators policy
and the wider Internet community policy
needs to the Aaron community so I'm here
as a representative of them of the
community talking about recent policy
developments in my day job some of the
other hats that I wear and so I
mentioned I work for a top-level domain
operator I work for the CA top-level
domain contrary to popular belief that
does not mean California it means Canada
we are the TLD for Canada so sorry
Californians you have to be Canadian or
have Canadian residency or be a member
of the royal family so if there are any
Royals in here you can also have a
dossier I come and talk to me so that is
my other hat and then I wear a couple of
others so I also sit on the Canada
chapter of the Internet Society in
Canada and
the Montreal internet exchange Board of
Directors so that is my hi hello this is
me and why I'm why I'm here is to talk
about recent policy developments
so as you hopefully know Aaron exhausted
their ipv4 free pool of addresses back
in 2015 so we're coming up on four years
since exhaustion and so the policy
proposal queue has has changed as a
result of that so there there are more
policies around the transfer market so
hopefully you know since you can't get
ipv4 from the free pool at Aaron anymore
there's a secondary transfer market and
third parties who broker or facilitate
these types of transactions to move v4
from a network where maybe it's not
being used to one where it can be used
and so there are a bunch of policies
around how that happens
Aaron oversees those transactions to
make sure that they follow policy and
yeah there's also a lot of database
cleanup efforts in the pipeline so Aaron
is a registry and the registry is not
very good if it's not very accurate and
so where the Aaron and and the wider
policy community is really focused on
getting those getting the registry to be
more accurate with better data and I'll
talk a bit about that later in addition
to of course ipv6 and getting that and
deployed out there on your networks
which John just talked about so please
go and do your case studies go talk to
the help desk and they'll help you with
that I know I should probably do one for
for our network yeah
so I'm not trying to get specific policy
feedback on the specific language of any
given policy I don't want to gather
support for any specific policy that's
not what I am here to do today however
if you are interested please chime in on
the public policy mailing list if you're
not already subscribed and you can go to
the Arin website I think it's under the
participates menu and get yourself
subscribed to that mailing list it's
pretty spicy lately so kind of some fun
conversations going on right now what
did you want to know is whether the
general concepts that we're working on
and in the policy world are desired by
the operator community whether they are
not and they unduly impact you in any
way we need to know who may be your
there's something happening in your
network or your particular community
that has just we've completely missed so
that's why we're doing this outreach
here today is to make as many people
aware of it as possible and get your
feedback on those things so yeah this is
a new way of soliciting that feedback so
quickly and I'm gonna talk a little bit
about the Arin advisory councils policy
response to some recent news a recent
case of address fraud related to the
ipv4 waiting list and then I want to go
through a few newly implemented policies
and how they might affect a network
operators as well as some that are in
the pipeline and could affect you that
you can still weigh in on and have your
voice cards and I'm going to quickly go
through the database cleanup efforts and
then hopefully open it up for a bit of
discussion
oh wait
all right so in the news recently you
may have heard that there was a case of
large-scale fraud related to obtaining
ipv4 resources from Aaron's waiting list
if you haven't heard about it again
there's lots of discussion on Aaron's
public policy mailing list there's a
Krebbs article and a circle idea article
but essentially a company meek fo
microphone never actually said that out
loud I don't know how it's pronounced
and created a series of shelf companies
to obtain resources from this waiting
list and provided Aaron with a whole
bunch of false documentation including
falsely notarized officer attestations
in order to obtain blocks of v4 from
this waiting list and so this was
discovered by Aaron through their due
diligence processes and it was basically
discovered that this this company had
amassed somewhere on the order of seven
hundred and thirty some one thousand I P
addresses and if you pay attention to
the transfer market at all depending on
who you ask an IP address and ipv4
address is worth anywhere between
fifteen and twenty-five dollars
depending on the size of block that
you're you're buying so that's that's
quite a large chunk of change that this
party was able to or attempted to
defraud the internet community of so
Aaron discovered this and house has
worked with law enforcement and
basically this this party
is now charged with 20 counts of wire
fraud so this is the first such case
first case in North America for sure so
kind of a watershed moment for the IP
address world and a little bit of spicy
news for everyone so back in January
after this was discovered the board of
trustees at Aaron's suspended so it was
discovered before January but in January
the Board of Trustees suspended the
waiting list and deferred to the
Advisory Council for a policy response
so how can we prevent this from
happening in the future we don't want
this to happen again how can we work on
policy to prevent it from happening so
the Advisory Council has made a
recommendation it's now out there on the
public policy mailing list for
discussion and our response was
basically if you're gonna put yourself
on the ipv4 waiting list which exists
for any dredges of v4 that come back to
Aaron and they do come back to Aaron
either because they've been revoked
usually for non-payment or any other
kind of contraventions of the the
registry services agreement or because a
party hasn't been following policy which
is rare as I understand it but they also
come back because people say I don't
want this v4 anymore they just give it
back to Aaron and Aaron says you know
you can sell the rights to use this
right and they go yes but I don't want
to deal with it so they give it back to
Aaron and resources do come back that
way so the policy response to that was
to create this waiting list to make sure
that they get distributed those
resources get distributed back out to
network operators so you can use them so
we still want this waiting list we still
want to be
able to distribute those resources but
we've put some stricter parameters
around how that would work so there
would be a limit of a slash 22 if you're
coming to the waiting list you can only
get a slash 22 is our recommendation an
organization may not be added to the
waiting list if it already holds in
aggregate more than a slash 20 and there
would be a 60 month
hold period so you would have to hold on
to anything obtained from the waiting
list for a period of five years you can
just turn around and sell it after a
year like the the party who was
defrauding or attempting to defraud
Aaron did so hopefully those parameters
would with limits and those kinds of
unlawful actions so in effect the
waiting lists be limited to pretty small
network operators and new entrants or
newcomers to the space so that is a
change if you're a larger organization
who is hoping to get themselves on the
waiting list that would no longer be
possible under this policy so this this
does change things for folks wanting to
get on the waiting list and it's under
discussion right now on PP ml you can
still weigh in I believe for a couple of
days so now I'm going to go through a
couple of recently implemented policies
that could have effect an effect or be
of interest to you for your network
operations so so far in 2019 we have
implemented a couple of policies so the
first one allows for inter-regional AAS
and transfers so this will be of
interest to anyone looking to obtain a
2-byte ASN or who works for a network
operator who does any kind of merger and
acquisition activity on an international
basis but basically there was a desire
to be able to transfer
MASN between our IRS with reciprocal
transfer policies so right now this is
ripe and a peanut has reciprocal
transfer policies with that and this is
largely due to a lack of two byte SNS in
the free pool those are exhausted and
that's of interest to operators who use
large BGP communities so yes there's
been an update that you can use for byte
ASNs but that was only implemented 2017
RFC 1892 and the the hardware and
software details have not been totally
worked out kinks haven't been totally
worked out so there's still an appetite
for to buy a SNS to make large BGP
communities work so to be able to
internationally transfer those those a
SNS was a policy proposal that someone
put in and it's it's now passed the next
one is removing real reallocation
requirements for residential market
assignments so this is a bit of a
cleaning up tidying up house type of
policy so there was a policy on the
books that was basically a vestige of
old cable network requirements that
required like a slash 24 for for every
neighborhood even if there were only ten
houses in that neighborhood to to
demonstrate use of your v4 to Airmen you
had to say hey I've I've put these ipv4
addresses into use in this network and
can I please have more Wilson's Erin no
longer has anymore and you don't have to
justify your need for v4 to Aaron to to
have to do a detailed reallocation to
justify it to Aaron is no longer a
requirement for residential customers so
if you're a cable network and you have
you do residential reallocations
you're going to want to look into this
it might break some of your tooling or
automation associated with those types
of reallocations so come and talk to me
if that is the case for you we also have
a few proposals under discussion
currently that you can still jump in on
the public policy mailing list that
could have an effect on your operations
so the first one is to allow
inter-regional transfers of ipv6
resources so this is a bit of a
controversial one on the mailing list
right now the problem statement for this
one is that there is operational need to
allow rir transfers of ipv6 resources
between our ARS with an equivalent
transfer policy Erin's rpki trust anchor
is measurably less widely deployed than
trust anchors from other our ARS as a
consequence our PKI Roiz published
through Arin offer less value operators
seeking to extract the most value from
their investment in ipv6 would benefit
from the ability to transfer v6
resources to our IRS with more widely
deployed rpki trust anchors so that's a
controversial problem statement in and
of itself so please chime in on the
public policy mailing list to let us
know whether you agree with this policy
proposal whether there is indeed a need
to transfer ipv6 resources and have your
voice heard and then we also have a
bundle of of proposals related to sort
of merger and acquisition activity on an
international basis and so these three
here are pretty closely interrelated so
if you operate an international network
you may want to take a look at
those those policy proposals especially
if you do M&A activity okay so next I
want to talk about all of the bad data
in the registry and there is a lot and
it's not a very good state of affairs
guys so 35% of points of contacts are
not validated sorry and this that this
data is from January but I'm assured
that it is still quite accurate it's
it's still quite up to date so 35% of
points of contact are not validated only
23% are and 42% are orphaned and I can
explain what what orphaned means in just
a second here but this is a result of a
variety of bad practices like just bad
scraping of customer customer order
forms that gets automated into into
points of contact a lot of this is based
on on faults and automation so we are
imploring folks who use those tools to -
please take a look at them update them
because it's resulting in some pretty
crappy numbers here and another cause of
bad data is like just entering nobody at
nobody com come on that we can't do that
it's result in really bad data nobody at
nobody intercom is not a person as well
as things that are like super bad the
covert ipv4 transfers or transfers of
resources that should not be happening
at all so we're really looking to clean
up the registry to improve this state of
affairs because good data is is super
important it contributes to Internet
operability if something goes wrong if
hits the fan and you
need to get in contact with an operator
at another company you want to know who
the correct point of contact there is if
stuff needs to be fixed on the Internet
so this helps identify and network
operators to each other get the right
people in contact to fix things when
they go awry the next reason is that
still bad data is a target for four
hijackers those folks are on the lookout
for old shitty data if if stuff hasn't
been updated in a long time that is a
flag that maybe this network is is right
for hijacking and of course Public
Safety law enforcement uses this data in
their in their investigations like it or
not law enforcement is a member of our
community there are members of the
internet community and they use this
data for investigation purposes and it
ought to be up-to-date to help them do
their job and finally it's a contractual
requirement of the registration services
agreement with Aaron is to keep that
data up to date so having bad data is
actually a contravention of the
registration services agreement and
finally it's just it's a core mandate of
the regional internet registries to
maintain an accurate database a registry
is not very good if it is is not
accurate it's it's a registry that the
data is supposed to be all in order
and so I touched on it a bit earlier but
some of the causes of bad data is the
automation the poor tooling the poor
scraping of customer customer forms that
are just eating it into into who is into
our DAP so that that we need as a
community to update our practices in
that regard another one is that simple
reassignments
are often sufficient there are a lot of
detailed reassignments going into into
the database with all kinds of data that
is inaccurate when a simple reassignment
which is just I believe the customer
customer name and address would be
sufficient so you're not just plugging
in and bad data for for the for the sole
purpose of just having it there often
you don't even need to have it there so
depending on the relationship with the
customer and depending on what you're
doing what they're doing with their
block it's often sufficient to just have
it as a simple reassignment rather than
a detailed record and then then orphaned
orphaned records
so there are orphaned organizations and
there are orphaned points of contact so
orphaned points of contact are not
associated with any number of resources
or valid organizations and orphaned
organizations are not associated with
any number resources so these these are
rampant and who is and Aaron is going
and threw a pretty big project of
cleaning up some of these these orphaned
records to get resources out of the
database that aren't associated or sort
of points of contact that aren't
associated with any kinds of resource
resources out of there and then of
course I touched on earlier the black
market
covert transfers just don't it's no no
please don't
and right now there are a few more
policy proposals related to improving
Whois accuracy and so one of them on the
docket is to disallow third-party
organization record creation so this
would prevent orgs from creating
third-party records so if a man is pure
content delivery network or whatever and
I have customers
I can't just create a record for them
with out their knowledge record creation
has to involve the knowledge and consent
of the organization the point of contact
that that record would be created for so
this one is pretty far along in the
policy process it's still up for
discussion you can look at some of the
history of the discussion on this one
but this would also hopefully contribute
to some more accurate registry data the
operational impact is that it could
affect some of your tooling so if you
have automation in place that is
automatically creating third-party
records from customer order forms and
this is not gonna work for you you're
gonna have to change some of that
tooling the next one is to clarify
reassignment requirements so this policy
proposal is is basically just to clarify
when a simple reassignment versus a
detailed reassignment is required so if
in your organization in your network you
are you have tooling in place that
automatically creates detailed
reassignments when they could just be
simple ones and that is something that
you're going to want to look into and
finally there's another policy proposal
on the docket under discussion that
would have
validation of an impious contact two
times per year that's this also under
discussion the proposer of this policy
didn't feel that the current validation
process was sufficient so they have
proposed an even more heavy-handed
validation process for abuse contacts
and now I'm just going to walk you
through sort of the new and improved
validation procedures for points of
contact that Aaron goes through so every
year Aaron sends an email two points of
contact to notify them like hey it's
your annual validation time please
update or confirm that we still have
valid data for your pox so this is for
admin tech knock and abuse contacts and
after Aaron sends that email out each
point of contact has up to 60 days to
either confirm or correct their data and
there's a variety of ways you can do
this you can click on the link you can
send an email that says correct or you
can log into your Aaron online accounts
and validate or update your data and
then if after careful analysis Aaron
deems a point of contact to be abandoned
they will be marked invalid in who is so
if your point of contact is marked
invalid you haven't validated your
contact and you've been marked invalid
then you lose the ability to do a few
things and Aaron online you lose the
ability to make changes to your
resources in Aaron online until you you
update at least the admin or tech point
of contact and
that the information is correct so the
only thing that you can do are make
payments or update those contacts until
until it is validated and here's just a
screenshot of what that validation
email looks like so highlighted I have
all of the places where you can like I
said respond correct in the subject line
and open the the URL in your browser or
go into era Nam and do everything in
there so I talked a bit about this or no
maybe I didn't talk about this one yet
so point of contact notification and
validation upon reassignment or
reallocation so this policy proposal is
currently recommended to the board for
adoption I believe they're meeting next
week and if they like the proposal it
will become policy and so this would
prevent circumstances where where when a
network operator makes a reallocation or
a detailed reassignment whomever is the
recipient of that reassignment or
reallocation is going to be notified and
they have to to validate their point of
contact before it will go into the Whois
database yeah
so I want to open it up for a little bit
of discussion and so just do a quick
recap and then if you have any input on
any of the concepts or questions about
any of the policy proposals or comments
this is the time for it I will take your
feedback back to the Arin Advisory
Council but yeah just as a recap if you
use automated tooling to create
reallocations or reassignment our new
point of contact validation procedures
might affect this this automation so
please look into it recent policy
changes are going to affect who is
eligible to get ipv4 resources from the
wait list new proposals may change
operators ability to move resources
between between our IRS and policy
cleanup efforts are designed to make
life easier for you so I will open it up
to discussion if anyone has anything to
say ask comment I would love to hear
from you nope
okay if if you come in find me in the
hallway if you have any questions about
this and if you would like to find out
how to participate in the Arin community
we have a meeting that's associated with
the fall Nana
in Austin so Nana's the first three days
of the week and the area meeting is the
last two days of the week and we also
have the public policy mailing list that
I mentioned and you can view all of the
current policy proposals online and see
the archives of the discussions about
them as well thank you
[Applause]
you