hysterical mmm afternoon friends I'm
happy to see so many people at the first
presentation I think you will have a
good presentation
I'll tell you a lot of stories from my
practice I'm a bit sick so I'll drink
sip from time to time from this bottle I
am working in 40 guard labs in Singapore
it's part of 40 net in Singapore there
is a CFC Center of Interpol it's a cyber
fusion center CFC which joint efforts in
withstanding cyber criminal worldwide
were in the same city we interact quite
closely we have an agreement between 40
Nets and Interpol and within that
agreement Interpol has the right to ask
for data in different samples and
different about malicious companies and
actors and we try to help Interpol such
requests highly confidential I cannot
discuss them here sometimes we do our
own investigations and we see that we
have a lot of evidence to identify
malicious actor we call the Interpol and
it helps us to generate a report and
pass it over to the national level
that's the second part of the
presentation but to begin with I will
tell you how we begin our negotiations
step one of any investigation
is operational saturation security of
course you cannot overestimate this
because first you shouldn't show
demonstrate your IP to the attacker and
then you wouldn't be able to get an
appropriate software because intruders
try to find out antivirus vendor IP
lists they classify addresses of
sandboxes and they have their own black
lists and they will never give their
malware to such IP so your IP should be
concealed hidden and there is also
prediction service when you will Google
something in the browser your browser
automatically goes to the first link of
the Google he will get the get request
and cache the answer if you try to
Google without hiding your IP you will
go to the site from your true IP and get
zero day from the prediction service
should be switched off disable and third
you should store all your URLs emails
and links in a secure manner if you
screen the points the headlines of the
protocol so that it wouldn't look like a
valid link so in Skype for example if
you make a link to cage days your Skype
will go
you can use it has a unique user agent
and if you share this with a malicious
actor he will understand that somebody
understood this in your in the main in
Skype so someone is interested in him
after operation security I launched the
great table auditor create a new table
with the name of the investigation and
enter the facts the starting point can
be different sometimes it's a sample
sometimes it's a report about an
incident the task initially is to
disclose the facts and enter them into
the table and we have a column verified
then each fact should be verified I'll
tell you why why you shouldn't believe
any one story one virus we analyzed the
Chinese company and there was a rubber
exploit in wind rare in 2018 the virus
total you will see that according to
virus total this hash is linked to the
main which is shown here H and it means
Honduras when we analyzed the sample we
watched it in static in dynamic we
didn't find the domain then in Exadata
we found the place and realized that
virus total just takes all bytes from
the sample and if
printed symbol printable symbols and you
have a lot of them then it's a stream if
it's there is a dot in the end and after
that there is something like that the
main he believes that this is a domain
name he doesn't check whether there is
such domain or not whether it is
registered the not he just sends you a
leak this so-called domain he thinks
that these dude
samples are linked so virustotal can
give you a wrong information story to
don't believe the reporters they joined
reports of home security and FBI they
merged two groups and it happens at the
end of December 2016
On January 1 there were a lot of
messages about malicious software found
in the company managed by Roush managers
elected power plants what happens in the
report it was recommended to install
indication of compromise IOC and the
security officer entered all iOS's into
the monitoring and on December 31 he
bought an alert that without that from
the network there was a malicious
traffic a malicious penetration attempt
what happened another officer came with
his notebook connected to the network
checked his mail in yahoo one of the IP
addresses in the indication of
compromise was a valid IP address of the
Yahoo Mail so you cannot believe
all reports and such incidents such
failures happen not only in the United
States here is a story from my personal
practice when I worked in Russia I got a
sample saying this is a malware please
detected I didn't find any malicious
software I said no I didn't find
malicious software they said no it's
malware this is a quote from the report
of Central Bank of Russia and the quote
was like that when we analyzed this
sample in the virtual machine there was
a connect to such IP addresses it means
that this is a malware I looked at the
IP addresses they are not in the
blacklist say Google them the first one
was VMware of update service and the
second one was Yandex matrix-y Yandex
matrix I don't know maybe they had
Yandex browser I told them that
according to our information they both
IP addresses were legal this is not
malware so take away you cannot believe
anyone at all but it's sort of a joke
after ensuring operation security and
filling the table you get you bought
some samples you didn't see any evidence
try to find new samples how looking for
similar samples you have to save users
and the find and create
a tool which would look at records and
try to find a similar once you can use
your systems of search for the similar
samples that is installed in your
company but they are different at
different companies and in virustotal
you can find several technologies
non-strict hashes links rules
everything is there you ristic records
your estate rule is almost your rule but
there is one difference between them who
knows which one rule create a lot of
falses with yuri stick record it cannot
do that even in the noiseless mode when
it just sends you notifications and
doesn't delete anything you can have G
dos as a result from here and get
hundreds of thousands of modifications
but you will understand what happens
modify your rule and started the game
but commercialization takes place prices
go up and retro hunts are more expensive
than they used to be but then they can
you can take information for the last
year and not three months a few life
hacks as I told you you can have falses
so you found the string in the excel
file and many people when they write
your rules they limit search confining
into executable files one be found
phishing HTML page we believe we got
there through the name of the user so we
found the phishing page in this way so
does not limit your search to do not
reduce it to executable files how can we
search in codes it's an art please do
not include absolute addresses and along
hopes for example in fin your report you
don't have any hashes there are some
researchers who publish reports without
any hashes and any domain you have to
guess what is happening what do you have
to do sometimes you have screenshots
then in screens using that screenshot
you can write rule and find samples this
is part of the code and I stressed
absolute addresses try to find this
sample you wouldn't buy a piece of code
and use wildcards instead of absolute
addresses absolute addresses can be
easily changed at random or
by intention to lead you astray so these
are the samples what kind of evidence
can we have initially it was a big
section I wanted to teach you long but I
realized that it will take me long it
would take me one hour and eight minutes
so I the stories or technical part
stories are more important because you
cannot fight them in the Google
technical cases can be found in the
Google so these are the cases that
attracted my attention in the last two
years you know so you know everything
cabin crew after that case everyone
knows that in age pets there is meta
information when you analyze a picture
the size is different and the time of
its downloading is difference and the
picture itself is important and which I
will show you the real investigation and
how it helps when when you analyze a
file PE in this case you can use any
unique strings you --tx rich Keys file
names very important to analyze perfect
time of downloading to Myra storage if
you believe that you can believe the
timestamps in the sample if it is not
edited sometimes there are reasons to
think that your way when was the first
download into virustotal it's very often
they
completion time and downloading time is
different by one or two minutes it means
that the intruder downloaded it itself
to see what happens it happens no matter
how foolish it is but and what is the
name of the intruder it may tell you
something about the language about the
purpose of the file ms-office history of
changes and you can find it you can
delete it
last year it was surprised I didn't know
that that inside in new formats of dog X
and Excel X the printing properties are
stored and we investigated attacks
against Samsung service center in Russia
and exploit was based on dog X this IP
address as you can see is inside the
organization few people can use these
addresses in the home network be
attentive because we attentively analyze
the samples and realize that they
intruded took legal documents of some
song and built his exploit there so he
could such documents from somewhere and
the documents belong really to the
organization not though they intruder
when you search the domain servers
X
so there was person next set and someone
asked me the colleagues asked me to find
him his famous he is well known for
organizing Satori but net on Mira with
miracle and he used the command center
but to see next solution dotnet I got
there look who is it was closed I looked
the history of who is there was email
and everything I tried to search by
email by username name surname of the
registrant found nothing and sometime
later I read other investigations they
say try to search by phone number and
you will get another site such as dress
not net and there the person used his
true address name and surname that was
his fault he fisted similar a similar
domain when I read I said well why
didn't I find anything I went to the
main tools and found that you cannot
search by phone number through a web
interface there is no such function you
have to use IP or transformer from the
main tools they make it possible for you
to look through every field so try to
search by all fields that automation
will help you issue number solution and
one more thing when you analyze who is
reverse history watch the expiration
time of the domain it may so happen that
the domain was registered it wasn't used
and the registration was removed in a
year and then it was registered once
again if you get the earliest - the
earliest who is you'll get the email the
real people but they may be different
people from those who registered look at
the expiration dates the text I believe
it's under estimated component of
malware there is a case with upon a
crime one a crime more about 20 or and
some nodes and the investigators not as
other people but I like them they
analyzed with Google Translator
what was translated from which language
to which language let's try to translate
and see what happens and if you
translate from Chinese you'll get almost
the same and if you translate to Chinese
there is something wrong so the initial
text was written in Chinese and then
translated to all other languages this
is another tool to disclose the origins
this is the method we are developing now
I live abroad and they use two languages
in my work if you have a jabber lock
where people write and correct the
errors you can analyze the frequency of
misprints if you know the Russian
keyboard e8e are the painful symbols if
you printed in Russian then switch to
English keyboard so you will have a lot
of miss prints in these 3:04 actually
there are four such key
what else and about Google Translator
one of the proofs of Russian involvement
in hacking in one reports there there
was an IP address from which everything
was translated into English and in less
than an hour it was in google translator
Google allows you to edit your settings
and look what was written but you can
delete it but not in Google Translate
everything that you try to translate his
stores I didn't find it in my history of
Google and I couldn't delete everything
that is done in Google Translate is
stored and it cannot be deleted and if
you want to find a an attacker so you
can use appropriate locks then false
flags hackers know everything I said at
least some of them all custom fields can
be falsified and you can see sometimes I
had a case of false
rich header everything can be faked
everything can be falsified please check
and recheck two stories of false flags
in our from our practice first last year
in one of the builds we found strange
Ukrainian phone number we googled it and
found the French in the forum where
people complained about a hacker who
collected the money from malware people
to treat sick children they said well
malware is all right but children oh
that was a bad thing to do everything
everybody was angry and his Kiwi was
published
we analyzed Monsoon company and they use
exploits of Microsoft Office on your
left you can see a screenshot you can
see that just food dot became the main
is use we analyzed it for a long time
and there was the face from screenshot
we googled the root destroyer and we
found Facebook profile where we had
pictures of an Indian student and he
calls himself root destroy looked at the
site where they fixed their deeds
ready faces and those Indian cyber
gangsters he faced against Pakistani
site because of India Pakistan frictions
tensions there was a just food okay web
server it was vulnerable and two groups
found the vulnerability and one of the
groups downloaded a pilot for exploits
the other defaced it it may happen and
if you do attribution
you can blame something for India but
actually it was not in yet was done by
Chinese dissidents so we reached the
real investigation area I want to
demonstrate it in full
I have never published it just look it
in dynamics how to search data about a
person how to prove our he cases and if
there are several people who are
suspected who is the hacker or the
greatest
natural abilities so posts terminals in
several countries in several trade
networks malware was found how did it
get there it is yet to be disclosed when
we bought the samples and look at the
similar samples we found a sample with
this path to debug files of course it
was compiled in Visual Studio and it
doesn't tell us anything there is no
username but there is a source and word
when we download the Susa
it's a Romanian for source so we got a
clue
a Romanian trace one more thread was the
buter when we try to use the mutex we
found the post at malware forum where a
person's discussed this mutex and if you
look at the code there is a message box
in for debugging we found the debug
sample where this message box was also
used a bit different slightly edited but
everything is around the same curves so
we try to look closer at this person
watch other posts and other forums that
person who posted other parts of the
same code including this screenshot
screenshot is interesting because we
could away download the page and look
here it is first of all I cannot
zoom it you can see a battery here it's
a notebook on top you can see the name
of the folder the perfect tool and I
remind you of the fact sorry yes it
works here the hook was used the perfect
hook was used there hotels is
interesting position resolution of the
file was five hundred two hundred fifty
sixty one thousand six hundred and
rating there are very few notebooks with
this resolution Mac Pro with one of
several servers and only one for Windows
if you look at the screenshot you can
see the network folder PSF PSF share
will be SF the first link in the Google
was forum parallels we understood this
is virtualization under Mac you have
Windows 7 installed with Visual Studio
and he compiles it and he gets some
mistakes also it's interesting to pay
attention to the time on this you see
the time of publication minute by minute
it's very close so the person has made a
screenshot through the post and of the
post rip in Italy but the hours the
clock shows different time
what you see you to seem possible zero
delay to UTSA minus seven which means he
is on the Pacific coast of the United
States he knows what we can get from one
screenshot we can get resolution
understand it it's a laptop that is
virtualized from my book the name of the
project and the time zone his profile
says that he lives in Las Vegas pay
attention to this user it's actually
moral you go to tales you're not really
I can tell everything
so we also found him on night Javadoc
yellow cards with Jemma machines tonight
that you can use if you have enough
information you can duplicate the card
and what the original never agreed that
was gathering the dumps of credit cards
gathering the pin code
keystrokes and sending to and sent it to
its owner and that's why it was called
phosphorus so we found the posts on this
forum and understood we are moving in
the right direction understanding we
have cards and in both cases and also we
found his was on the Russian according
forum with the same nickname and he was
writing in English why did we think his
Romanian because
a Russian forum he was writing in
English obviously Moldova citizen would
know Russian language quite well too
speaking in Russian then we found this
thing and this team profile with the
same we also found sheet reactor
rhetoric forces where he was discussing
some injects into processes we couldn't
understand whether what it has something
to do with the case but it is his
nickname tired of cheaters says that he
is tired final for cheating integers so
he is nine games in the profile but the
real breakthrough was when we went here
PC part speaker side that helps you
build your PC and he has a lot of
activity there he was choosing the new
configuration but his musi and he said
money is not an issue tell me the best
configuration I'd like to develop and to
play games
we compared the games to the ones that
you mentioned he has all those games and
it is profile and he also wrote that he
develop slaughter his MacBook as my draw
and he was not satisfied with the phones
he bought the top built top motherboard
then 18 by the time 4k monitor top
processor and the phones were not
beautiful he was complaining about
being not able to develop on the visual
studio in own windows because the forms
were still terrible and he was also
mentioned his TV compared this all and
understood that's our client
[Music]
breakthrough he said he is not satisfied
with not only the phones but also with a
noise from the fans and of course he got
the best cooler that will cool his
overclocked ji7
and of course the crew was too loud and
he was complaining about the noisy
cooler we have few his video he has
uploaded and we also saw that the
profile was called Alexandro aliens will
be Google's that name we understood it's
all devon football player name they have
four videos to private and to public we
watched this second public media
[Music]
there was smart phone video of the 4k TV
all three Albania Romanian football
nation where the guy got the yellow the
red card right in the end of the of the
game and it was you
[Music]
you have private sharing there was a
chance that he was just googled I just
shared it but there's a site called
YouTube native viewer and you can use it
to understand when the video was posted
and we decided and career posting video
hosting time with the video posting time
and understood you know that computer
has passed three hours and effectively
found out that the difference in time
between the upload to YouTube and the
post is like 3 min which so obviously
it's him just uploaded so remembering
our first first idea of using the
Romanian word confirms and his profile
also had a link to Google Falls but that
had no information but when I googled
his Google ID google gave me linked maps
that contains public
public comments that he was given in Los
Angeles around Hollywood Hills it's in
all five of his comments on Google Maps
I just bought my G Lexus SUV and I
highly recommend the dealership center
that sold it to me second one was review
of wood repair shops where he says he
was fixing his BMW sex next one is clear
clinic where he was blood test there was
five comments explaining a lot of his
lifestyle and I understood we have
enough information to make an arrest
just a matter of technicalities you know
he's in Los Angeles you know he's a
client of the cleaning he his steam
profile probably paid for it from his
real credit card understood it's time to
send a report to Interpol to tell you
about how it happens I will put the end
of the story to the end of the
presentation so it's dessert but
retaining Interpol first of all you need
to back up everything you have so
download the video from YouTube
screenshots France France can block it
and Singapore researchers will not be
able to get access to those posts
it's um it's probably actually so
everything is screen shot downloaded you
write a very detailed report my one was
27 pages long it had a lot of
screenshots with a connection to
Interpol nothing special they have
special mailbox with a special
encryption key and you use it to in
creeped after you send it after some
time if they say we want to meet you
when you find a meeting you come to the
meeting now my clicker is not working
yeah ok it's just like I don't see the
next slide slide here is the scheme from
the report for my for the Interpol
people my logical scheme made in Malta
to understand how after you are invited
you come to beautiful cyber fusion
center it's the security there is very
good spikes in the concrete that prevent
from you know what you're driving on in
in a car and exploding this soul then
there's an operative worker just second
line is cutting your hands your backpack
everything you come into some capsule
that measures your weight
I thought they want you to understand
the difference but later and so they
gave me coffee and I know ask me to the
toilet so it's interesting why how would
they account for that but anyways so the
person in Interpol who was reading this
report asks you a question and the most
popular question they asked
why is it important there isn't here is
that he has to write his own report and
to avoid this work he tries to delegate
a little bit of this work to you asking
why is it important
will there be new victims other invictus
and my jurisdiction and all the all the
questions to confirm that he really has
to do with some damage his jurisdiction
so it's interesting and we answered a
lot of questions what is the potential
damage monetary amount and then the
Interpol worker writes his own report
and I know he said to his superiors
where the Ministry of Interior does
instrument unfortunately local
investigators or Interpol do not have
any report so they don't track they can
ask the local authorities but usually
they know I think they can not even they
can even stay without reply but they
cannot push the investigation so you
wait and wait
you keep getting notifications from
virustotal
about the new samples compiled and
loaded they comply to your euro generals
so you understand the person is still
there
and sometimes you ask a question of
what's happening with my report and they
keep saying up yeah we have no reply
nothing we don't need to know anything
but sometimes it happens the other way
around
should you know what this lady
industries as a finals we had a press
release from the Ministry of Justice
from the United States about their
convictions to the group of 36 people
mostly Ukrainian some other people did
you know the stuff I Italian Egyptians
so they were doing doing carding they
were stealing the cards they had special
people linking the CVB's special people
making cards special people getting the
cash from ATMs somewhere rested some
name des don't Joey number one also
known in the nickname so part of the
group was not able to they were not able
to identify but let me introduce some
that were identified valerian
shoo-shoo flown from Moldova 28 years
old I just found it because I googled of
course no one has ever sent anything to
me or posted me about the investigation
proceeding so if you count on Fame and
fanfare probably that's the wrong way to
go and I'm not sure you will succeed in
getting anything from Interpol and of
course neither my company fortunate or
of me myself were mentioned
are they just a reference to the to the
occasion in cyber networks probably they
stay in cyber fusion centers this way so
it means that we security analysts from
vendors we just have troubled dark
destiny of going here they're living in
5-star hotels without framing so I told
you about the identifying of criminals
Interpol collaboration give you an
example of a real real convictions of
course are still going on so he's the
person is still not not proven to be
criminal if you read this small script
and the real damage is four hundred
thirty million dollars the intent was
around 2.2 billion dollars but this
needs to be proved during court
proceedings so I will be happy to answer
your questions and I'm empowered to give
you t-shirts as gifts so don't start to
ask questions before you have a mic so
that everyone listens and you talked
about heuristic old records and question
is when you use virustotal with cierto
SSDI and other things give us some more
cases on how you can use those heuristic
on modules IG gives you such files
probably again I don't think I'm a big
specialist
this is my hobby this is something I
learned and I had meat we have such
technologies rules and stuff are drawing
new things appearing we have API that
you can call it's being developed so you
have interesting options like you know
file names during uploads changes that
you track and monitor and it's part of
the answer to your question
unfortunately I'm not ready to give you
systematic details because there's a lot
of information on the internet on gerra
rules but that's not what I am expert in
and a lot of changes is coming so yeah
definitely there's a lot of father stuff
ga3 technology tree technology in your
investigations and if there's any use
yeah I will google it sorry I have no
idea I think my hope was that I will get
new ideas from you and obviously that's
one of them the question actually two
questions do you have any experience
working with the Russian authorities in
this direction and second are there any
databases for the Interpol that you use
so you said you use virustotal and
Google or other any databases that
belong to Interpol where you can search
thank you the answer thank you yeah I
don't have any experience working with
Russian authorities but there's nothing
impossible so if C does not belong to
any country and we have a practice I
think there's practice so CFC he was
changing after some interval so there's
no practice of CFC belonging and you
they work on a contract and then moved
in other countries they are from
different countries I never met any
Russians there and but even we have
experts from our companies and whispers
collab working constantly in helping us
consultants you got in Hell where they
have the sources to create and aware of
this level I have no idea about Interpol
databases probably they have some
internal infrastructure that they use
but they don't disclose it so they give
me tasks from the outside and I can
bring some results to them but I cannot
disclose anything even if I know but in
reality here I just don't think they
have they have them like sample
libraries and obviously some statistics
full and some data for the actors that
they follow but I never really
questioned thank you very much
interesting questions about life so if
there was a guy you know what Alexis was
driving BMW going to can you spoil his
beautiful life I think you did it just
to talk about this on page D or you
wanna did your company guarantee use
from this like what was the the
positiveness probably your company has
spent an Interpol has spent a lot of
money on this investigation oh yeah
you're right answer we are getting good
salary something company has budget they
spend it on me so that I do
investigations during mine
working time to mana fits first practice
practice understanding of the threats if
you were virus analyst you would you
have no he will have found a lot of new
signatures that's good
second is PR so Publishing's with
Interpol publications from Interpol the
coverage of all the audience and
investigations quality is very high so
that's positioning ourselves as experts
so any work with Interpol that you do is
very good positioning as experts even
this space thank you
question before this was submitted to
Interpol between this missionary
Interpol and invitation to you do an
interview how much time has passed
answer well roughly I gave it this week
Wednesday and next week Thursday I got
an invitation I had a letter asking me
about the time that is convenient for me
to come and we agreed on the time and
when was the person arrested
oh that took a lot of time so the report
will not mention specific dates but the
report was summer 2017 and the
conviction was published by the Ministry
of Justice and February 2018 so roughly
in a year they date the agents actually
had to buy the cards from the people on
the forum and we're trying to also
increase the scope of the investigation
so it's not my fame to find this
beautiful group I just contributed to
identifying one of the members of the
group and that's why they were
interested in working with them and so
the report was Papa's given in early
spring but in August the investigators
were trying to purchase something from
the forms so you can imagine they there
was a lot of time passing between
between those two ends in March or May
the person has deleted the video from
YouTube so he felt someone is interested
in him or something has happened and
with a simple authentication the last
sample of Education with my arrows was
us about that time frame so I'm not
working fast the dream of them you know
like opening doors with their legs and
arresting everyone getting fingerprints
and memory dumps from the hard drives
but in reality I understand they have to
start the proceedings the investigator
cannot start the proceedings himself he
needs sanj sanctions from the prosecutor
prosecutor means some information so
there's legal legal stuff happening that
that takes a lot of time it depends on
the country of course in many cases they
just don't you know they don't care well
the question the person whose life was
spoiled and sir I I can tell you it
after the presentation not publicly but
my ADEA is you need to put those people
to prison
next question you said he posted the
report to Interpol but does the victim
participate in the investigation
answer yes in this case the victims were
numerous so it was the United States
Italy some other countries and I don't
remember exactly how they were setting
up their post terminals maybe we have it
in conclusion part so the result was
malware sample right yes it was not a
complaint from a vendor that was the
start of the investigation happens that
you'd come to the investigation place to
some forensics but in this case we
participated in the investigation
without having anything to do with the
investigation itself we just had a
sample found the person wrote an article
and presented on a conference that's it
question you talked about the false he
talks about false flags the topic
disappeared vectors have I think
disappeared here they know how how the
attacks can be attributed so what to do
with those false flags when you know
they are there if you do everything you
know the ideal manner you do you will
not find anything in the country
so if you do everything right it's
really really tough to dig out something
there's a lot of investigations where I
could not find anything the person is
arrested by Locke and the source code of
the other middleware and detects yes
otherwise if are they false flags trade
works fine it works yeah people use
nicknames multiple times using mutex
username multiple times yeah it has
created a case for five hundred million
dollar damage but if everything is done
correctly yeah you can fool the
investigator you can fold the researcher
and no one will find your traces this is
true no magic bullet no magic tool to
actually fix it last question question
what is tools for domain analytics for
the main IP analytics to attribute them
to the malware answer it will have an
internal database with domain names we
use it you know the two I like most
domain tools there's the person called
craps it gets money from them i
advertised onion for free malta also has
a plugging this malta is a craft
building put a dome in there and they
reverse the Whois service and I'll take
a bill to a graph of saying this email
has a number of domains registered under
it and those domains have all the emails
and you have a huge graph of connections
it looks like police
with a lot of boys we have trees this is
all great so this is my weapon of choice
and my tool that I like and this is what
this is all the time we have and I need
to choose a person to give prices so the
person asked me about the new tool I
would like to reward him for this ok
would you like white wine and the second
question was about the profit very good
one also enabled me to open the war so
thank you very much guys vision that
support a public pool the presentation
will be published in the beginning of
the presentation you have my emails or
feel free to talk to me and don't worry
I will be happy to talk to each and
every one of you