right great how is your pH days going
looks like you're a bit tired and you
don't have enough of oxygen in this cell
room but I'll try to still stay within
our timeframe what people usually stop
from not with the title definitely
because it's on the slide
my name is are Thompson listen I'm Hyde
of information security Microsoft
Central and Eastern Europe and I'm here
today to talk to you about very useful
things especially for those of you who
are to this to that extent in charge of
security of Microsoft Windows Windows
Server I'm going to talk to you about
the latest generous generations of
Windows whatever we are going to refer
to previous generations I'm going to
mention it separately we are having very
strict time frame oh let me set my timer
by the way right so my plan is this
it looks like I'm stepping at something
from that never mind first off we're
going to discuss why the paradigms that
we used to live by for decades are
athletes not really my sound is
disappearing no it's here to listen to
us in online broadcasting you may have
problems so we're going to start by
discussing the changes in paradigm then
I'll give you a strategically then we're
going to drill down and describing stack
of security technology in 28:19
client-server all asses next we're going
to speak off of the safe cults with the
guards windows guards when this
protection family I'm not going to
discuss all of them because we don't
have enough time then the main of after
days is to discuss the internals of
Alice a local security authority
subsystem in particular we're going to
look at how you go into Windows what are
the identification protocols
what are the flaws what are the attack
vectors most popular among the hackers
and we are going to discuss the
technology that is there to eliminate
those vulnerabilities we are going to
try a live demo to demonstrate to you
how the how the how we can withstand
mimic a so including security support
provider and what was the help of
Windows protector family with the scars
and by going to look at the future and
outlook what are the challenges were
facing what is the route forward and I'm
going to introduce to you another
witness protector so let the fun begin
and most probably we are going to have
Q&A session in the Murray and we have
motivators for those who you who want to
ask questions to motivators the
questions that I find most interesting
are going to
aren't you a very nice price so that you
can post the old-school kind of price
before your peers in the next
presentation so what is this standard
paradigm the standard process of witness
protection first you get information on
an attack then in a reactive mode we
developed protection but then they
evildoers find another way to enter the
system and the attacker is always ahead
because they are not limited by Essex
they are not limited or constrained by
regulations by the way thing state
procurement is organized it and have
their schedules they can operate 24 by 7
I think it's pretty obvious it's just an
axiom so what's to do about it
first off you need to change your
paradigm the set of dogmas the set of
axioms that we live by day by day
several times a day and build our
security strategy using the new paradigm
rather than the obsolete one fantasy
fans out there would know that if you
change paradigm from time to time it's a
good way of us to attack and to defend
yourself this is how it looks earlier
and why this paradigm is now obsolete as
you can see standard schematic
representation of a model as we have
certain set of hardware we have platform
services that provide for this
integration we have apps or what not
things that we make use of everyday
browsers mail clients games for those of
you who are gamers here I I can't use
the pointer anyway problem is that in
this particular architecture when you
compromise the core you compromise the
whole system we have one and only fellow
points and exploits are popular with the
hackers there they evil to us that allow
the attacker to achieve full control
including concealing the presence in
order for me to illustrate
demonstrate this concept on a real
example you can see the Dubrovnik in
Croatia by the way it's one of the
places of shooting of Game of Thrones
they have one reliable if an evildoer
breaks the perimeter in only one point
it compromises the whole city the whole
old city while say caucus are my friends
it was designed in a different era from
a different paradigm there are various
Ashlyn's of protection we have we are
limited in terms of numbers of entry
points there is this on the left in
northwest of the picture and you protect
the score by all means
so how now back to windows how it works
and windows in Windows 10 we separate
all our developments in four categories
threat protection identification and sir
ization procedure management and
management of any credentials handling
any credentials
data production number three because
it's the direct way of monetizing your
attacks if you're an evildoer and a way
to manage this
this is ooh so the speaker security
manager
I'm not going to amplify on that I just
want to say that our main focus today is
some moderate protection in connection
with that I'd like to present to you
with this ten guards we have five device
guard guards from Guardian system guard
credentials course applications guard
and key guard what you have in the
bottom part of the slide is what's
coming next so let's discuss in greater
details what this guards around about
from left to right on this slide you see
the chronology of a standard attack
first and exploits or backdoor or rat is
delivered through two major delivery
channels a web browser and mail client
sir would defend ourselves here
through reducing the area of attack here
it's but device guards credentials gas
and Bushell secure mode via Sam so that
you understand the whole security stack
you need to understand what is virtual
secure mode and how it's different from
the traditional approaches if you
understand that and you understand
everything
then application control its control to
provide for integrity code integrity
through white listing is the development
of a block device guard it's called
application control application guard is
an interesting topic I'm going to refer
to it later
it's from by isolation of strapping of
potentially threatening processes one
few protects and critical services and
you clear the session after you close
the browser
exploit God in class system of IPs
windows it consists of four parts and
we're going to look at two of them in
greater details so that I don't have to
repeat myself it's control folder access
which allows you to minimize the
probability of full encryption of your
files by encrypting virus and by default
we are talking about user folders and
profiles anyhow it gets you a
notification or block data protection
exploit protection is something I'm
going to specifically I'm not going to
speak of antivirus but this is not the
objective of today's Windows Defender I
should play it's an IP P type of
solution win point puts player
production platform and win point
production response it's the umbrella
that unites all the Microsoft's security
technologies
and we're not going to look at this one
so we just have 40 minutes left so I'm
going to rush through the beginning part
of my presentation the introductory part
for you to understand it's part of a
stack that integrates with other
mechanisms and production components to
provide for you the most effective
interaction of the home combined smart
screen
you all remember what smart screen from
mental and Explorer times it used to
block the obviously malicious sites
using the reputation server of Microsoft
that is now in the the one that is going
to be on trauma mansion it's going to be
there as well
independent of the kind of place that
you prefer if you work on Windows 10 you
get the opportunity to use reputational
clouds filters even on other browsers
visit opera or pro whatnot in order for
it to work you need to switch on wind
protection in Windows and it's hijacks
HTTP HTTPS protocol requests and centers
do reputation service irrespective of
the applications that asks for
connection we can check its reputation
and have a red screen if it's not
reputable a very very very quick demo
hopefully it works
it all looks pretty
if you want to try and you take edge
open it with understand github.com / and
okay / Minich us and you get this read
saying it's a very dangerous utility and
you don't want to follow its that's how
red screen looks and you get a similar
red screen in Chrome or in Opera
irrespective of the browser
besides this reputation service can be
used to block a specific application
downloaded from the internet you
download the Mekons you you get blocked
unless you put it in in exceptions so
much for smart screen and network
protection intro we have a sandboxing
technology the problem of false unboxing
technologies out there that are
conventional for all the browsers the
ones that were initially use not the
ones that are currently is the
traditional challenge was that if you
use software sandbox you can bypass it
by hacking a software component if it's
a single security device the way the
industry develops you need a hybrids as
a solution so that your sandbox is built
on a hybrid of hardware plus software
including the functional offer hyper-v
the hypothesis it looks pretty simple
when web browser applications work like
edge will launch a small virtualized
container where you don't have any
extensions activated all of them other
des accelerated and interaction of them
where's the operation system are
strictly controlled in this particular
place and thus you can specify what can
be sent the system platform services
exception one you close each whether
everything disappears and Melbury cannot
persist therefore the buffer is
controlled the right function is
controlled
now let's rush through this demo and
that will be for the intro wait a minute
right there you go so let's say you
visit the resource that is obviously not
on the white list or obviously on the
black list
the policy is controlled by the main so
you see what if you don't use
containerization when you work with web
resources through web browser if you to
use it on the upper left hand corner you
can see application guards right on
orange background if you have a look at
how it works
you don't have access to file systems
objects and it works on hyper-v isolated
user and this credential has a minimum
privilege level tax reduction it's a
category that includes everything that
has to do with minimizing the area of
attack on a hosta of OS management why
wouldn't it work for ah there you go
it is an important point because you
have a lot of services what we thereby
define that by default the policy is not
too strict to provide for interaction
with the maximum amount of peripherals
to provide for maximum
amount of scenarios but it's not ideal
in terms of security let's look at the
standard example of palos that is
delivered into the target within
Microsoft Office we have a lot of
Microsoft Office documents the whole
setup the whole airing of them some of
them are with macro says these are the
ones that I used for evildoers some of
the macro says deliver the malware the
malware code into the system and I used
for complementation and some macro says
are not only executed in the system but
also download - first - you shouldn't
block them because your accountants use
micro size and your Excel spreadsheets
to generate your invoices and they would
say oh we can work this way but the last
two categories the lower ones they add
once it should be controlled and attack
surface reduction is in our garden let's
take a standard way of pilot delivery
delivering the cost of offence when you
deliver an office documents through an
email in mailing a client it's a panel
of preview and outlook when you do not
open it in a separate Microsoft are
separate
it's enough for you to just accidentally
click on and unless you have a patch for
especially for critical vulnerabilities
this heart is going to be compromised
with these things blocks on the type of
system calls that can be used etc
whether or not that code from macros can
be ejected in other processes already
launched in this saying because this is
what is used to get to escalate
privileges I cannot go in deeper details
but we're interested in the one fourth
from the bottom
it's access control to local security
station subsystem on the host where you
cannot use credential guards or
something like that you can use exploit
guards to prevent member cassa from
operating it's going to monitor any
access to memory and any download of
anything from memory that is
correspondent processes as far as
exploit god is concerned
like I said exploit guard is a host IPS
it's not something new
it's a hobbyist that if they want to
exploit a vulnerability into unpatched
application or one you want to deliver
payload into the target system you can
block it and advise the administer that
means so that self so you basically poke
backs in your word in the will of the
attacker it in crazy
the cost of attack and gives you advice
you enough time to respond to the attack
to give you an example how it works
this is malware was and it used DD
functionality
dynamic data embedding TD force it in I
think it was in summer of 2017 or 18 so
they use D de to execute power shell
script or another script and get there
by control of the search engines the
necessary documents and you needed to
push two or three times this is how it
worked
we have a conventional email that
arrives like your bank gives you the
invoice that you need to sign to keep
getting salary on your salary card you
open the document in a secure about you
click through okay it's because you are
sick and tired of this type of documents
right and then we have Aaron not
identified in this particular indicator
if you have a closer loop as is empty is
launched and then PowerShell is launched
partial script and then you see an
obfuscated commands here so in and then
you get the logs that and you get the
logs that inform you on the attempt of
exploit
this can be integrated was when the the
Windows Defender Microsoft and the ITP
and this information can be seen in a
centralized way of together with
information from other systems now the
main dish of my talk for Pseudomonas
local security Authority or LSA assassin
for you not to get confused because
oftentimes we get this confusion a
different document in different
documentation they used interchangeably
LSA is a local security authorities
subsystem and si is part of a local
security authority sub system L si si si
anyway before we actually go in from the
main dish let me remind you that la la
let's say SS is in search of
identification of user authorization
things like that or a change of password
storing verification data in memory etc
and we have two modes
just to carry out identification of the
user interactive and non interactive in
interactive we do not use SSL while in
the network access in network access we
we use this one yes I know I'm rushing
you just to look at credentials
credentials I think it's a very
difficult difficult term to define in
Russian
anyway it's names the Kerberos tickets
at certificates and passwords and the
pair of open and closed keys when used
when you carry out that since
efficacious reserved and derived
credentials I don't know how to
translate a direct reduction since
Russian but these are kind of secondary
credentials that you get from primary
credentials like user password is your
primary credential hash from a password
from the password one way hash function
is already a derived credential Alice a
the target of a let's say is to store
derived credentials not just the
passwords but the hash of the password
with some with some extent away
exceptions why we have issues and why
Magnum America is so popular there are
wholesale of those but the problem is
everybody loves single sign-on right you
don't want to introduce 16-point
password everybody wants to work
conveniently and it's no more it's
absolutely normal but you really need to
sacrifice it in security level and when
you do this sacrifice you have to store
your credential in some sort of way be
the derived credentials the hash the
password hashes or other kind of direct
credentials or sometimes even more
credentials there are some scenarios
like that as well the way it works I'm
going to refer to single sign-on later
let's talk about the most important
thing this is a very high level
representation but for us to understand
the future scenario it would be enough
ok I have 25 minutes left right we have
locals curious authorities subsist on it
has certain components the core
component is service that orchestrates
this whole process this is the most
important of the Guardians then we have
a full set
[Music]
well specifically for security support
provider's basically they support
certain a certification protocol and its
execution then its purpose yes it's
cameras cloud up the modern
identification products where you have
tokens of negative directories and
feeders all that smart cards these
things that are used in the process of
identification like the pair are open
closed key it's all as first by so net
lock on is easiest when you enter the
domain to have a secure communication
with the channel security account
manager started the local credentials
KDC as we see is the service that is in
Church of caprese tickets and all their
precious wisdom and defecation
DTaP is the saying that protects they're
basically a cryptic container inside
your ass that controls the data that are
very vulnerable and important for you
so how the interaction goes on you have
an application as service I win in it it
calls with Annette it's gas here through
a security support provider interface
through an RPC call or request and then
you have interaction as well let's say
with our certification providers and de
facto when you write your own customized
security support provider your own
identification provided you need to
write something right here and then use
either something that is already
existent the once that is already there
from the vendor that is already attained
asshole you write your own and then you
have to keep it in mind because this is
the most popular one of the most popular
of vectors of attack on Alice a because
it gives you access to the context of
execution of the core assessment
assessment you get the privileges to
just a deal out that is going to be a
custom provider classification and from
here maybe cancer does it let me Casa
does you have a dot X a mini they allow
it is registered all is perfect and many
Casas says hey provider address this
Alice a and give me the credential that
you find there and there you go so from
the point of view of operation system
design from the point of view of
security it's a Mexican mini cutter that
is executed was admin privileges and
debugging privileges
so the
is a very popular factor of attack and
it's not a problem from the point of
view of design I mean the way the
components behaves they behave normally
the operation system would give you no
sign of suspicious of things going on
the MC this is interaction first hash
bus ticket all that we going to skip
this one I already mentioned it means as
well anyway normally the admin would do
everything rightly but they will just
get the rights of a debugger I'll
consume all the allocated memory space
in whatever and yet another important
point yet another important point just
hold on a minute but it seems like that
my presentation has gone is there a
problem with the projector with the
monitor seems like I'll have to switch
the monitor I would like to see my
slides
anyway it's very important to understand
that it's not about deleting the LSA
data because otherwise you wouldn't be
able to complete single sign-on you just
need to minimize the log data the
credentials that you keep even after the
session is complete and also you have to
remember about the alienated extracted
data and the minimum set of credentials
can be later utilize that and different
device so it's not about storing the
credentials it would be stupid otherwise
as ISO would not be functioning without
it it's not the point
you just need to increase the number of
data that can be used in other devices
you can steal it you can hack it if you
can use some crypto data that you have
acquired through the course of bio and
identification you can steal it there's
nothing wrong about it
now a few words about the credentials
guard a few words about the credentials
guard the idea is simple what you need
to do is just to make sure that the
critical services that are most desired
during the attack are allocated into a
standalone container
that you can get access to not only at a
software level at a standalone security
domain the main point here is that when
you isolate this virtualized container
where you can keep and store the
isolated copy and version of a local
security authority subsystem process is
being controlled by both software and
hardware solutions like hypervisor
resolution for instance therefore in
order to breach it you should not only
get access to it at the core level at a
kernel level and compromise the security
but you'd also have to have a find
vulnerability and the hypervisor and
have to have a local access to this
system I've been trying it for one hour
to shutdown it for one hour but I failed
it although I had this physical access
to the virtual machine and had all the
admin credentials and I wanted to show a
couple of things
just hold on a second
what I want to do now is run my demo
there is nothing better than a demo tool
is there just a whiteboard maybe what
I'm trying to do now is just to take you
on a guided tour of my artworks
I'm an excellent artist as far as you
can see you can see that virtual secure
mall is one thing that we have to to
embrace architecture away there is a
problem in LSA and there is no other way
of resolving it but the one I'm gonna
mention traditionally there's a kernel
in TOS if you can see it here just hold
on can you sit now great so we have a
kernel that's the one here's the kernel
mode here's the user mode here's our
normal kernel exactly like I put it here
doesn't really matter whether it looks
fancier doesn't what we have to mention
is we have a an application with its
libraries for the program code
and here we have a set of phone data
data structures set of data structures
and they describe the access marker for
example what are the processes that have
access to it and it contains some
metadata what it can do what it cannot
do so imagine there is yet another
process running here in theory we have
to isolate this processes from one
another for example one exe extension
yet there is another one and they are
isolated assume that that's true but if
you isolate it from the kernel by one is
not possible I have to be able to get
access to all of them and the admin can
raise its credentials level to local
system and get access to all of the
processes as far as you can see that's
the paradigm I would like to describe
the problem here is it
Alice s is one of the issues for us
which is running in the user mode thus
if there is a hacker with the admin
credentials if it's trying to mimic to
such-and-such credentials because
otherwise it would not run properly
cannot pull off multiple cool scenarios
without so the problem here is that we'd
have to isolate with the is s dot TX
year
but we cannot do that because the
windows architecture would not support
it we can try it multiple times but
still be failing so how do we cope with
it how do we isolate the data what are
we going to do about it let's wipe it
all out and instead we'll give it
another try and we'd be adding something
into this equation like virtual secure
mode we have a regular user mode we have
a regular kernel mode and here's our
kernel here's the L say SS process this
is a normal operation mode what do we
would like to run a scenario when the
administrator the one who controls the
kernels security has access to this
process we need to put it into a
separate container to isolate it and
it's entitled isolated user mode thus we
have a very tiny like 10 kilobytes in
size LSA I saw local authority security
isolated which contains primary
credentials here it's in its own memory
space right here so in order to make
sure that kernel does not get access to
this part it is trying to mimic
[Music]
the actual performance but in actual
fact there is no access provided the
only possible way of having this access
is through the secure kernel which is
controlled by the hypervisor the whole
integrity is controlled by both hardware
and software
but hyper-v like for instance therefore
we address here here and here and
directly we cannot establish any link
right here but this gap in between now
I'm going to explain why it is really so
safe this real small gap small shared
buffer the Daruma makes change in your
foreign currency in a bank when you are
separated with a bulletproof glass from
the cashier with a very small small box
made of steel where you put your money
in and move to the cashier it resembles
something similar the actual kernel
would signal you when it's going to give
you this buffer to use where you can put
your so-called money and this shared
buffer buff is utilizing a separate V vs
L request protocol via cell requests and
right here we have standard s call do
you understand how it operates basically
because this container is called PS l
and inside this container you can
not only just isolate LSA you can
include multiple components there like
Colonel model mode integrity which
provides security for the entire stack
it sounds and looks cool but if you are
able to shut it down a simple switch
it's worth noting
so therefore would have to provide
kennel mode code integrity this
component must be isolated and cannot
belong here because otherwise the hacker
once it gets access there would control
everything all the settings if you get
the if you get the rights from the admin
to get the D back they would be able to
manage the configuration of the system
just like you are doing everything you
are doing traditionally does matter
it's an additional step and that's it
there's one more thing which is
important to understand and why it's
important to do how it can be hacked so
[Music]
ten minutes prior the end of the
presentation I'll just explain that we
have some kind of hardware we have some
fan where ufi bias etc etc whoever
hyper-v
then we have our interior sir that's our
Colonel in normal mode Alice a SS
process and standalone real atlas a SS
siloed and secure colonel everything is
managed by hyper-v how can it be hacked
well first of all you can interfere here
right into the procedure you by
initializing a system call intercepting
the data right before the data is sent
from Alice 8 to the colonel and gets
protected the second thing which can
manage configuration you can shut on and
off protection you can control the
ability of downloading some kind of a
mini driver device driver a mini driver
and the second thing is we move the
component which is responsible for its
therefore the integrity from here to
here but then if we completely rely only
on software tools the hackers would be
able to remotely breach them so we'd
have to add some kind of a hybrid
solution here would would be adding here
not only the tracking solution this
security tracking solution security
status once is bridged it's alerting the
admin and the system goes down and
nothing is capable nothing that the
hacker will be able to do any further so
we'll have to back it up with the
hyper-v enforced code integrity so both
hardware and software part
it's called hyper-v hypervisor which we
call you don't necessarily need to
install the entire hyper-v you just
needs small containers not fully fledged
virtual
machines there but I hope I've explained
this part about the two vectors of the
attack and I would like to show you yet
another one I'd like to explain that we
have a number a great number of
peripheral devices
Oh
EF good to say here's the hyper-v in the
trusted mode - one you can always zero
the user mode is three so we don't we'll
be scaling it up and in the virtual
trust levels zero and one and
conceptually they can be plenty of such
levels and the trust level can also be
different and now for example we have
some kind of devices peripherals which I
mentioned our mice networking equipment
GDI we have some allocated memory space
allocated for kernel purposes for the
normal mode and for the safe mode
some devices a great many of them by
default unless they have DMS protection
enabled which is a mandatory requirement
by certification unless it's in enabled
they have direct access to memory and if
we have the mimic cards with with a mini
driver imagine it's a device driver and
this device driver like I'm showing you
right here is trying to connect to a
networking device and this networking
device has got the direct access to the
memory also the memory part which is
allocated for the VSM virtual secure
amount the hacker may be sending
instructions
requesting this memory space to be
utilized its standard attack mode which
we can now withstand we cannot control
from here let me show it we cannot
control it from here because all these
are hardware devices that are plugged in
connected by administrator we can only
do it and should do it physically by
using IO mm you imagine that here we
create this input-output memory
management unit by all management unit
in other words in hyper-v we have the
agents to have the MMU controlled access
there is no direct access to it any
longer imagine that it's not mimicking
as a device driver would be able to
intercept this request right here and to
different memory pages would be
providing different access levels safety
wise and security wise
and you can only do it by using the
combined software and hardware approach
we need to use the hypervisor for that
sorry we are running out of time so
you'll have to wrap it up and this is it
by the way we we only have two minutes
before the end by the way we'd like to
check out whether it's really it really
works who would like to see it please
raise your hands then I've just bought
me some more time anyway it's a very
simple finger take a look here it only
works with this 64-bit versions of the
operating system it's a standard
solution for the state-of-the-art
security requirements but what if you
utilize a standard Windows 10 OS in this
case you can mark the LSA version as
protected and there will be no mimic in
access to it with the standard tools
there is a standard one through exe and
also through this driver if it operates
at the kernel level it has access to the
LSA and can unplug it here if you are
admin with all of the rights
if it's not backed up by the hardware
protection you can shut it down
Americans remove the flag and work with
the data it's real simple
but for this you can utilize an exploit
guard whether it's 80 for a 64-bit I
don't really know but it allows us to
control all of the requests and mocked
and flag them as potentially unsafe it
also regards the the dump files in
memory of which should be warned by log
file and all of the information in this
log file correspondent Lee I'm not going
to be showing any more slides I'll just
show you a standard solution 64-bit OS
admin rights that's what we have and I
hope it works right now it is fresh out
and I just prepared it this morning you
know I did have to remove all of the VMs
from the way of mimic cards and we run
it we run it and let's check it out the
recent built 19.3 that's their most
recent one bit dates this year 1903
March 1930 just raised the privilege
level to a standard let's check it out
whether it is going to work with click
guard
log on and we need our credentials here
it works it runs and now let's take a
look at this
we've already enabled the EDL and we've
enabled protected process light the
protected process mode if you try to
mimic it at the kernel level it's not
possible it would be not capable of
doing that but it's capable of doing yet
another thing remember I was showing you
it can just embed into the credentials
at the previous level for this they
would have to take this file this little
file that's the one that's the one this
is the custom authentication file which
we haven't the LSA and as the hacker has
the access to this system they can
register it like I'm doing now inject it
and see what's happening right now
Archie um you're out of time one last
thought and that's it come on let me
show me the clip guard hold on a sec
hold on a sec I'll be quick
[Music]
or come on anyway what's it doing right
now it's just intercepting the data
before they get encrypted and protected
that's the whole point
the idea is real simple damn it stop
anyway trust me there'll be a file with
the open credentials which is not
encrypted I know it belongs see windows
system32 folder that's the one that's
the one we found it with my mega
password like I promised you I'm showing
it to you but that's not credit card
enabled it will work like this unless we
control the grid guard configuration II
it's a very well known attack which
we've known since the end of the last
year so you cannot just unable it enable
it again and run it through hyper-v
called integrity for this we will be is
swiftly switch you know what I'm showing
you is going to be real quick real quick
I'm not going to run into console
solution I'm going to just use the
the simple mode come on honey
enable enable after reboot now it's
going to automatically run old all
through all of the dependencies it is
now running in the background we don't
have time for questions but thank you
very much for showing us