operating actually people have told me
that I'm going to be the last speaker in
this session so if I'm going to go for
too long please let me know and tell the
organizers of the events that i'm
alexandra bakker voice from Red Hat and
I'm in charge of the development of the
authentication and registration of the
users actually it sounds pretty rough in
Russian and it's kind of hard to
translate you should notice that
actually on the slide it's written
slightly differently than it was written
on our gender but that's just how tough
it is to translate from English into
Russian in proper terms as it were I
would like to start from a very
interesting anniversary seems like it's
this year that's been 40 years ever
since we started using those functions
get aw Nam get Yui UI I mean and so
forth at the system level
that's API version 780 UNIX it was 40
years ago in 79 and some of those
have so far been fixed the users
information would belong to different
files and approximately in 1993 the Sun
Microsystems had developed the Solaris
version which would add the name service
switch which is a mechanism of login and
it allowed to use different mechanisms
and different methods of data storage
for the users it needed to support needs
and other moments but later they started
to using it for other purposes in terms
of authentication such a mechanism which
would allow us to build in plugins
appeared in 1995 which was not far away
from 1993 it was the UNIX system
authentication in 1997 approximately
since then Linux Pam started getting
implemented so if we take a look at what
we have been using at the low system
level at the system library level has
been in existence without significant
changes but for 40 at least 25 years to
say the least so on the one hand it says
that the people who had developed those
interfaces were actually thinking
properly because they have stood the
test of time that's on the one hand on
the other hand I guess that nobody
nobody really wanted to break the
existence solutions that much and that
evolution that was not a revolution with
evolution rather it was a pretty slow
process and those changes had
occurred in the 1990s like Kerberos
dates back even to the nineteen eighties
and nice goes back to 1992 and then
Microsoft Microsoft took them all over
all those UNIX solutions and packaged
them in 1998 into an active directory
and it started getting used the
industrial-scale and it remained in such
a state ever since this is the finished
picture those graduates school graduates
would go on to such trucks dressed in
very interesting clothes and those are
the gradients from the 1990s that they
are on the parade ever since we have not
had much breakthrough so we deal with
technologies that date back to 20 years
something and these standard solutions
have grown there are different solutions
which allow to use different protocols
that I have mentioned to communicate and
this multitude of system says on the one
hand good and dear on the other hand
it's pretty bad so which helps us
resolve on result different tasks but on
the other hand vendor wise the vendor
that supports the base operating systems
seems to have a problem because he needs
to test all those interoperability
things in terms of interoperability of
the modules plus even more if you take a
look at the usage NSS and Pam Red Hat
Enterprise Linux 7 would look
approximately like the ones I am showing
you on this slide naturally there are
modules that people would install on
their own
but we believe that these are the
modules provided by SS SD the system
library module the standard pam modules
that belong to all of the linux's from
five and ten eleven which I will
elaborate and NSS and ten modules from
Samba and SS in spann modules from L tab
D project these modules seem to do quite
nicely but they have long-term common
problems that date back with their
sources to a couple of dozens years ago
because lots of modules have been
created having in mind the actual take
on them in the 1990s so to be more clear
those modules would be uploaded to the
calling application directly so if
that's the NSS module that would have to
connect to the LDAP server a remote one
basically it means that into your
address space there is a module
springing up with the LDAP library
uploader
which would have to have an access to an
account of a specific user which had
configure eight configured that module
etc in other words what we have here is
the heterogeneous approach so this is so
these users would get access to more
information rather than they need to so
then there was a need to isolate it and
put this into smaller modules so that
the modules would interact via the UNIX
domain
socket this is what the NSS palm l-dub D
works this is what some other ones work
that have been with us for the last 15
years and these modules were all
targeted at the local tasks they were
not about deployed they were not to be
deployed at some hundreds and thousands
of machines and as far as the user
limitations are concerned the user
rights are concerned all these user
rights would have to be deployed to all
of these hundreds of machines so
ultimately it would all get pretty
clumsy and the maintenance of such
modules was also getting pretty
difficult yet there is another problem
we all get older when I just started
doing that I was a very young kid I was
just 18 now I'm over 40 and there is yet
a new generation of the people who can
cope with this and this topic is not
that attractive for younger guys for the
younger developers because this topic
does not look that interesting and
attractive for them they have better
things to do more attractive things to
do it seems like that these projects
that I'm talking about are simply dying
out some people go and new people do not
come and some of them change their mind
and start doing something else so in
terms of Red Hat Enterprise Linux which
has 1012 years of support
you know we'd have to work with with the
projects that have to be buried with the
creators and be along gone forgotten so
therefore naturally people tend to say
no to some projects and ten years ago
started the SSD project which would try
to uniformly represent the access to the
user data
the authentication the authentication
for the different systems primarily for
Linux in many standard distributive the
main tasks for SSD is to take from the
modules that are loaded to the
application all the meaningful part of
the work so that the application would
not have anything as far as the leakage
is concerned so it's all on the back end
in the different context under a
different user so with this particular
framework with this particular tool with
more functions added to it we provide
the seamless integration of Linux to
different systems with the Active
Directory environment and with the
standard al-jabr CalPERS environments as
well in terms of the modules belonging
to Red Hat Enterprise Linux with get rid
of two modules found pix11 and NSSI LDAP
and pom LDAP they are rendered obsolete
and will be removed from the upcoming
versions of Red Hat Enterprise Linux
because those tasks are covered
completely and they are no longer
required so I will start with Pam care
be five-pump care b5 is responsible for
the authentication of the users by the
utilization of the Kerberos keys it
looks simple but there are subtleties
hidden capparis is not in charge of the
user authentication as such so at the
operating system level there should be
the transformation conducted by that
recognition principle so that we'd be
able to work with the user there must be
a chart the transformation chart not
normally it was static
imagine there are millions of users and
you would have to be able to have 50,000
users to connect to that machine you'll
have to arraign the return manually and
that's not the case that's not how it
should be done so on the one hand we
tried to find cameras in the library and
tried changing it
adding the login possibility and then we
added the login on the SSD side because
they are aware of this user they know
what this user is all about in terms of
this system and they know what would be
the user Kerberos or Active Directory
name etc etc but here is a special
feature when we speak about Pam care b5
there are actually two modules having
one same name and they tend to be
confused with one another there are
completely different but they're named
one of the red hat ones been rendered
obsolete hands been deleted the other
one B has a lot library from the Debian
project the other one does exist but it
has not been committed to for the over
the last two years the only initial Pam
care b5 function which is not supported
with is the token generation for Andrew
file system that is not very commonly
used by a loss of customers but for that
purpose there is a standalone module
which
allow us to generate such a session and
there there is a detailed instruction on
how to do that and this smart cards
access the traditional smart card access
to the system locally or remotely this
module is pretty nice and highly
developed it has a capability of
changing the names that we get in a
certificate to the user names it has
such a function but it's all tuned
locally and they all have to cascade it
down all of the machines anyway and we
did that with a number of customers of
Red Hat with different US governments
that all use such cards and they added
the login support with a smart card
capability and like three or four years
ago they did this capability and then
they expanded the ability of storing
this data in a centralized way so you
you just change this in the Active
Directory in a centralized way and then
as cascaded down automatically and in
the RSS 8 they added the rollback
capability when you just need to tune it
for the users that are the local users
only thus we have covered all the
functions by damn take ACS 11 and the D
actual developer had announced a few
years ago that if there's no one who
would like to take the mission from them
they would discontinue anyway for
various reasons they would discontinue
for not having enough enough time for
some
private issues some issues like that
they are very common reasons for people
stopping their work on their solutions
some time ago people found time and they
started generating the requests and
started going through all of the
requests that had had accumulated since
2016 people would find errors and such
errors could be exploited to use them to
gain access to the system and for three
years nothing had been done just for
that simple reason that it was not a
commercial project it was a free of
charge based one and if we move from
eleven to SSD all the functions are they
are in SSD anyway but to make good use
of that you should be capable of tuning
the whole system up and and since 1999
there's been a module in the Red Hat
distributive that is familiar to most of
you off config it's a utility which has
gathered all this logic of how to put
the palm and SS which all these files so
that they would be able to run with all
of these parameters that people would
like to get like the fingerprint
authentication the smart card
authentication plus some more so that
utility had become quite heavy to
maintain and support and each time when
the question was asked should we rewrite
the code really the Creator would say
well you know if I touch it here it
would crumble there so a couple of years
ago they said that's it . i'm not going
to touch it even if you pay me i don't
really want to
seniors so we decided to take a
different loan cut that you can figure
out some activities drive it podcast du
chateau de staat see the emotions have
seemed so pretty piece of it configured
so no file you've practiced King yet as
I advanced lip resource lost and riches
ad set a schedule don't conclude usually
potato dragoman no really post was also
a t-shirt what's a traverse to boy
rabbit is configured see a tourist and I
noticed Iranian in order to develop the
kind of configurations and it would be
easier to support they are
understandable both on the side of those
who use it and on the side of those who
answer the questions from those who use
it
another interesting trend is that
developers are sponsoring and policies
admins
is a different case settlements are
quite young and they come from spheres
that never dealt with UNIX was the
traditional unix approaches was they
conveyor about between you know call
utility they are used to other stuff in
the woman run it appeared that when you
would get a call to the call center
rather than trying and solve the problem
of a specific configuration you have to
actually go ahead and explain the
concept how UNIX system works what it
what was in it the whole generation
changed and the spectrum of people who
are involved in dealing with it has
changed and to say that you can just
launch this you till there was this
parameters and there you go everything
would work is not enough
I give an example here of a challenge
one it was actually not launched by a
human inside of setting script for F
print D a utility that inputs Damon on
fingerprints application so there was a
call one you it would call disabled
fingerprint option and it would write
over all the other sadness it would
delete the module of control of a
fingerprint and overrides the whole
configuration of the system and the
system was no longer capable to login
thankfully it was caught in federal
rather than in distributor but it was
one of the points when we realized the
situation has changed we really need to
rewrite the whole thing the whole thing
well so we have all select that has
three basic recommendations the one that
is used by SSD by default another
configuration that uses pom and this has
win bind to integrate with other systems
like exterior Vittori and the obsolete
nice-nice is obsolete for support in
certain spheres applications fears when
uses with Bernice are they are more
lightweight its high-performance cluster
systems where you have computations and
you have to send thousands of machines
and the tasks so for those who need to
execute them and the certain share like
200 milliseconds or 20 milliseconds it's
a big difference right how this users
are resolved for systems of this kind
so the target for all select was to tune
the identification system and
registering systems to make it usable if
you want to make your own configurations
yes you can write additional profiles
but they are not going to be kind of
module and combined able there is a
certain functional that you can permit
like automated creation of home
directories or the use of SSD in order
to drag public keys for machines and it
uses an automatical again through SSS HL
and these are the features inside the
separate profile if you create separate
another profile and you identify your
own features and you have to be
accountable for each of the profile and
ensuring test specific associations for
each of them in order to migrate from
the legacy systems a special module was
created in config so in the rel 8 you
would find it it translates the most
frequent calls into the Select calls so
all this is nice it's all new there is a
fun example of one case when the fact
that you need to support certain modules
for a certain period of time and you
cannot just go ahead and throw it out
actually played voiceless
there was this project that made use of
dns to store users credential not pass
codes not passwords but information on
users
somebody saw that it's
a good thing that you can put it in DNS
server it's a distributed and it's a
load resistance kind of thing so it has
your project no longer it is no longer
used but then Red Hat Enterprise Linux
and hazard support in Red Hat is inside
the document that's called application
compatibility guide that is Huestis
guarantee that we give in Redis respect
to the interfaces it's on level one
which means that within three major
versions we don't have right not to
change anything or throw anything away
and when we launched round eight we just
automatically added back on level one so
seven eight eight nine ten the major
versions only in the tenth version it
can be thrown out although there are no
longer any users of this module to throw
this code out of the distributive would
actually decrease the attack surface
because the attacker can actually make
your system might make your machine use
the system similarly was miss this that
created it was created back in 89 Ness
plus in 92 is still used although it's
insecure to store open hashes and not
encrypted
in the prodigal that doesn't have any
any kind of channel encryption is fast
but not secure at all it's very very
very inappropriate and unacceptable
there are certain tasks where such
clients are indeed used and in demand
and so together with customers of this
kind we decided to get rid of this
server in the next major version the
client will be still there but then
we'll have to part with the client as
well hopefully by this time some other
protocols would come by and live with
rice the performance but as far as the
cipher channels is concerned it's still
a big issue as far as LDAP is concerned
last fall there was a lot of noise
around several opal depth going out of
RAL and Red Hat Enterprise the next
eight just hum it so it's about several
things first off Red Hat doesn't have a
team to work on open LDAP and from my
personal experience working with
upstream of open LDAP is a challenging
task just to give you an example at San
Line patch that would just add the
already existence functioning to open
end up in the publicly accessible file
so that others would be able to use
these libraries while the function has
already existed would only be possible
in the next major release of open LD
LDAP
elaborate so two years have passed and
this is just about relocation of
existing code
it's that complicated or the other hand
there are companies that are prepared to
support open LDAP and they have much
greater experience in doing that and
they would be happy to enter this nation
to cover this gap open LDAP libraries
are being used because they are in sea
and they support all the Soltys of this
protocol they're going to still exist
only without server there's an
alternative alternative to this server
380 90s in particular the directory
server that's his that uses Red Hat
directory server so you can just have a
run on diem and you can then execute
it's over there with support on higher
level so you have it on the other hand
all these systems are nice but they are
supposed to be used together with
something we have the system to tackle
our tasks right not just out of the blue
so one of the layers in the system
modules in web server actually we had a
whole set of modules and they resolve
various tasks from for Kerberos
authentication we used to use the module
that he hung on the slide when we are
going to use a different module that
read from scratch when we systematically
started to going from low level and
going to the high level a server that
allows us to do a lot of nice things in
terms of security
as far as a certification for
certificates we used to support more
than the sass and now we'd get away from
it for the sake of consolidation on mod
SSL mode Auto kerb is almost dead nobody
is doing anything as far as rewriting
the whole set of applications it has
already been finalized that route two
years before this particular talk around
ten years ago rad had had its take on an
assess it's a crypto library on Mozilla
Netscape started to write it Netscape
actually if you if you happen to know
about from the browser pond they also
had a server parts they wanted to create
a vertical they had a nut scape
directory server that I made several
acquisitions mergers and became the guy
that also rat had on the other hand they
had browser yet on the other hand they
had a system for writing certification
that same kind of registry center
the only thing that Mozilla still has is
the browser support and crypto libraries
printer libraries are great because they
allow to work with smart cards were
special tokens it's better than open SSL
in this respect but upstream NSS the
Mozilla developers they think that this
library is basically part of Firefox
it's a and they don't view it as an
external library so they keep changing
say P eyes and cosmetics not just titles
so the name is unchanged but semantics
semantics has changed so we couldn't go
to an assess we started to go to SSL
with modest SSL it turned out to be much
more simple much simpler but for modern
assess there was a a locator model that
would allow us to go through the list of
certificates and make sure we don't use
the ones that were revoked by the
special listing and this river kata was
done I would would do this check up
automatically and that's all you don't
do it automatically you have to do it
kind of through external integration but
it's not not not too complicated and
there are examples of people doing it in
cameras they added added new functions
are we going to have more in the next
release they minor release as compared
to 7 we have KCM support added cameras
credential manager KCM and as we try to
rewrite most of code to use gssb a
low-level cameras a Cobra's function
certain elaborate especially
pasen ones were no longer necessary and
substituted by poison GSS api and Jesus
cast abiy I can see em is a mechanism of
storing Cobras tickets in MIT Cobras a
library they used to have three four
more depending on platform we're
referring to more often than not they
are stored in files and directories when
you need a lot of tickets for various
realms stored simultaneously or in
keyring the O'Malley memory but this a
part of the memory it's not subject to
the username space it doesn't work so if
you have a lot of containers and you
want to use Kerberos saying this
convenient keyring cannot be used
because any of the container would see
the contents of the global caring if
they say launched in the same user
gaseum is a server client protocol
through UNIX domain socket units among
UNIX the main circ socket is
you know it's something that can be
petitioned and use in certain criteria
containers such as the stores this in
its database and can make a lot of
interesting stuff like updating the
tickets or restoring them after reboot
if they are still usable in force as far
as global stuff is concerned that uses
excuse of all this functional rel8 added
something called modules it's a
mechanism for extension of repositories
that allows to manage several streams of
the same application or packages
independent of each other so you cannot
put them in parallel in one system but
you can get access to them in parallel
so if in your repository you would have
four or five types of not GS or Postgres
then on different machines you can put
various versions but you won't have to
break your hide around how to store it
and give permissions within one
repository
besides it gives you the opportunity to
make groups of packages on the level of
models but not the global repository
this is the way you can create profiles
for Postgres server from DM all the
service that would locally within this
that model resolve into the packages
specific of this model in case of IDM
were created to of flows like that in
one flow what is called IDM client and
it only contains clients library and it
is switched on by default so I should
you switch room and switch it to the
existing server from config kickstart it
would keep working and the nothing as a
server component it's a separate one and
if we change this server part then the
incompatible changes would be in a
separate module it would have a
different name and that way we ensure a
more stable structure and we or the
other hand gets a more stable mechanism
for planning updates and changes
the outlet we already had upstream
integration of this whole stuff into
releases in SSD we have support of
multi-factor authorization but we
couldn't use Oh big whether we think
gets two prompts like I need your
password and that I need your token or
just one prompt I need a password plus
token in one line there are different
products open VM to give you one example
it doesn't support multiple prompts you
only want to have one prompts and
everything in one line so token system
is not very good with it so now we
already had all the upstream wipe done
but to tune it's dependent on server and
so administrator can can actually
manually tune it in cumbrous we have
been supporting speak speak is a
cryptographic mechanism that allows to
resolve certain issues in Kerberos
protocol related to getting Kerberos
tickets in one request to server 1 :
server without disclosing the identity
and without disclosing additional tokens
I have a one factor manufactures fake I
would be there in the next version arrow
8 but one everything is already
integrated in upstream and multi-factor
spike is right now going through the
specification approval stage
and we are still writing RFC authority
now in case it's been ten years that we
started working on this multi-factor
spike because multi-factor spike is
something that would allow us to have a
supportive UTF which in turn would
strengthen this Cabras factor right and
we also work on two supports hardware
cryptographic systems in IDM and the
more complicated issues of integration
in the directory this is it and now I'll
be happy to take your questions thank
you thank you
good day thank you for your presentation
are you planning to do something about
planned like they are accessible to
anonymous user in the network are you
going to do anything out of the box to
prevent it from happening in role 7 well
i DM 318 90s by default wouldn't give
away date when addressed by anonymous
user apart from DSC when the user
addresses it to understand the
capabilities of this server why
specification DSC address has to stay
anonymous
but if you want to address anything like
this e equals example across test then
any address it would ask for
identification this is already done in
upstream free IPA we included
prohibition for anonymous address even
to DC and then it turns out that the
software stops operating so we rolled
back and we're now thinking of how to
rewrite the lady known applications
before actually having it but but yeah
we're working in this direction thank
you for this question
thank you for your presentation my
question is this probably there is an
article or something as to what are the
things that administer should check to
go from rl78
anything that's going to change this
onus pasteurization stuff well first off
we have several documents devoted to
this particular point release notes
surprising it is but miss them I looked
at release notes for l8 100 pages good
reading a solid book secondly we have
documents on going from RAL 7th to
around a 2 we have lived up that is
there to automate this whole process it
identified this configuration than the
route 7 and they each other I need to we
need to rewrite it and this way this is
how I rewrote it look at it and they
that this leap allows to go for certain
configurations from around 7 to 8 but
not for some of them in some cases you
have to necessarily go through
replication it goes up to rl8 it is
included in the replication topology the
data migrate and then the old server is
off another important point that you
need to check is OpenScape project opens
cap contains
description
of the secure settings that you want to
have when you deploy the system and this
or that infrastructure SCAP is supported
and needed when you deploy in the
Ministry of Defense in the US but these
same policies are open-source policies
so you don't want to have this you don't
want to have that you don't want to open
too much right to this config files or
you don't want to have write rights
other than these groups they are all in
distributive you can front them get a
report that would be generated
automatically and use it apart from the
report it actually generates the script
well I don't I'm not a big fan of a
blind execution of scripts you want to
read it but I think this would be the
best and fastest way to bring the system
to the desired security level but anyway
I'll leave up is the main mechanism to
run system from one level to another
from lower to the higher level thank you
for this presentation do you plan to
integrate it assists service and do you
think it's needed no we don't plan to do
that integration of information on
network topology for DHCP is something
that we have collected we have a project
or research upstream of free IP if you
visit the APA dot org you would find it
in the course of this research we found
out several things first off turns out
you need to understand that
HTTP integration touches upon other
subsystems that necessarily need to have
credentials identification and you would
need to rewrite certain projects to
support what IDM is based on like
Klara's I mean in three or four years
they've been added and now what's left
is to develop a mechanism how to present
the scheme to be used by this disappear
C server in storage in LDAP the scheme
that is there in the traditional recipe
Sarah to store in LDAP does not take
into consideration their peculiarities
it's just a reflection one more
reflection of how it's written in the
files which does not automatically mean
it's right and it would develop
correctly
so whenever touched upon this topic and
it turned out nobody wants it surprising
is it missing and I don't think it's
going to be too much of use to those who
use public clouds and providers such as
Amazon and the like they are not device
are the ones in charge of this
infrastructure DHCP configuration so
duplicating this information is not
going to make sure that it is going to
be stored
a way a face-to would have yet another
problem ts9 server scheme is not just
like Microsoft it would normally have
some settings that are specified to be
tuned to work with the Microsoft
solutions but when we're trying to do
some settings it would not open from the
box we don't have these attributes in
the nine solution and we found two
solutions first of all to add it there
manually and then there is another
transformation solution which would help
us rewrite the requests how are you
looking into the ts9 I talking about the
transformation of these requests are
going to be done in some different way
there are two answers to your question
the first one is I'm going to give you
an advice a piece of advice to start the
VMware customer cases and ask for their
support there so that they can actually
see that the users would like to have
such an option because some seems like
that there are no other way there is no
other way to do it and the second thing
we would experiment with that having
three or four options of this problem
this particular problem resolution 3 8
10 DEA's performance would have and even
reduce by four times when we have to do
quite a lot of things and introduced
lots and lots of changes now to actually
see this scheme so for this would have
to take we would have to create pressure
would have to push them would have to
push them and I guess VMware is just the
solution here thank you
[Music]
so one final question about that
dinosaur with the Hat the Hat has never
had a dinosaur there was a shadow man
and it's called Shadow Man not the
dinosaur the Shadow Man is still here
let me show it to you here but seriously
speaking on May the first Red Hat had
launched the update of its visual image
and this hat is currently our logo
you'd be surprised but the there have
been six or seven for the course of 25
years over the course of 25 years so the
Shadow Man was not the first it just
stayed there longer and we like it and
we love it and we are the shadow men on
this particular ride I have not taken
this hat with me because it's too hot
with it thank you very much for all your
questions to the person as suggested by
Vlad as suggested by Vlad in my opinion
I should select a person who I should
give this candy to the person who would
ask the most interesting question about
the updates and migration and thank you
very much again thanks