good afternoon everyone we are so glad
to have this opportunity to share our
research who is you and this research
when name is coaster no version too
it is about convert a ble command and
control channel to bypass air gaming
first self introduction my name is Mark
and my colleague wrong and we come from
China
Shifu 360 and she said she who 360 is
lady
like McAfee or SEMATECH our core
products antivirus security software for
computers and cell phones and our team
Pixar's team was founded in 2015 it is a
red team from 360 security technology
focusing awareness IOT security and we
created a 360 is cast can wear this
intrusion and Prevention say Sarah and
we have achieved a 100 success rate in
our wellies penetration test ok here is
the agenda we will first give you an
introduction about air-gapped Network
and the related art Ike Evans then we
will introduce some previous research
aircraft attack of the site we will
review the previous go sterno version 1
and after that we will introduce what is
the ghost an aversion to and how to
implement it
finally we will show you a simple demo
ok let me show you what is air gabbing
okay according to Wikipedia air gap is a
network security naira employment one or
more computers to ensure light a
security compute network is a physically
isolated heater from unsecure networks
such the public internet or unsecured
local area network soon the name arises
from the technique of creating a network
that is physically separated from other
networks and it aims to avoid the
intrusion and the data leakage through
network connections most of the time
air-gapped Network
I consider the most secure networks as
we all know hikers are exploiting
vulnerabilities is their operating
system application software or
communication protocols and attacking
via the Internet however those does not
apply to air gapped Network holidays how
do you remotely like a computer that
isn't even not connected to the network
yes area system were believed to be more
security in the past since the required
physical access to touch them but from
an attackers perspective nothing is
impossible they can break through the
air gapped Network where an infected USB
flash drive USB device oh I employees
laptop one of the most famous cases
involving the affection of air-gapped
system is the stucks night - tonight is
malicious computer warm first Ankara in
2010 sorry to help people development
here since at least 2005 stuck snide
targets scanner system and is believed
to be responsible for causing the
substantial damage to Iran's nuclear
program and the stocks night has three
modules a warm that excuse our routing
related to the main hello des of the
attack and a link file that atomically
excuse the worm and adjudicator
component responsible hiding all
malicious files and the processes and
preventing detection of the presence of
stocks night it is typically introduced
to the targeting environment
we are effected a USB flash drive there
by crossing any air gap the room then
propagates across the network as and the
scanning for siemens step7 software on
computer and controlling our PLC you
know since all four other criterion
stuck snide become dormant instead of
the computer if both conditions are
fulfilled
Stuxnet introduced the affected judicata
onto the PLC and the step7 software and
modifying the current the code and
gaming an expected command to the PRC
we're returning a look of normal
operating system ovalle was the feedback
to the users and according to an IC
document leaked in 2013
cottonmouths version 1 is a USB hundred
hardware implant which will provide a
wireless bridge into air-gapped target
network as well as the ability to load
the explora software onto the target it
comes with a penny in body the
transceiver and the spy agency can
extract and transmit data to a briefcase
the size and s a relay station and up to
8 miles away where our signals the
recent years the security researchers
have also began to focus our gaps
attacks so let's take a look at some of
the previous research in 2014
researchers at zebra security lives at
ben-gurion university in israel and the
health fund to spoon a personal computer
even with no net worth
the technology was using by FM radio
receiver in Claudia years some of the
mobile phones it is able to capture
keystrokes by interested in certain
radio emissions from the monitor or
display unit of the isolated computer
the researchers can take after the FM's
thinking it was nearby smart phone and
translated FM signals into the typed
text it is also the Israeli researchers
at cybersecurity lives from ben-gurion
University in 2015 have found new
techniques to hike UTRA secure aircraft
computers and refuel data only heat
emissions and a computer beauty in
thermal sensor and the last year the
zebra axe researchers and at by hat
Europe explain how to use filter the
data via RF signal by attacking Siemens
PLC the injector a letter logic code
into the siemens s7 - PLC thus the CUDA
using the memory copy operations to
generate a frequency modulated RF
signals and a slightly pillows a.m. band
with the modulation representing the
encoded code and the thing that will
then be picked up by a nearby aunt Anna
and that I coded using a low-cost SDR
and a PC so according to the previous
events and research we can see attacking
an air-gapped Network general takes the
two steps the first is we implant
Mario or hardware to the target assessor
and the second type is to establish
a communication channel to execute
commands and is filled with data okay
our previous research the kernel version
1 is a Wi-Fi card channel and it can
bypass air gap in the coastal version
one use the USB HID to release the
payload into the target system like your
Windows laptop then the pillow they used
the building where is natural kada of
the target you wants to establish a
command and control channel with another
computer controlled by an attacker
costano version 1 use a special SSID as
an identifier and establish the control
channel we are custom protocol based on
Wi-Fi beacon frame and the proper
request frame and the proper response
frame and this custom protocol does not
affect the victims normal network
connection so you will never see it
the conversion tool is a Bluetooth
convert Channel and this also can bypass
the air gapping and the ghost an
aversion to can be also used as a USB
HID to release the payload into the
target system like Mike OS or Windows
laptop the payload uses the built-in
Bluetooth adapter of the target device
to achieve the control channel with
another computer coaster no version to
establish the control channel we are
arms whereas the Bluetooth Low Energy
protocol that is a cousin protocol does
not affect the victim's normal Bluetooth
connection so the attacker can currently
pass the commands to the target system
and exfiltrate data and the victim will
not be able to
any abnormal the conversion to does not
require a normal network connections so
it can bypass firewalls and has no
interference with the target existing
connections and it is support across
platforms it can be used to attack any
device with Bluetooth adapter and we
tested her with acid attack on Windows
10 and it worked
waiting about 50 meters and a human
father we know Bluetooth is a technology
for where is the local area networking
with device devices use the usual
Bluetooth connection a commodity ones
must first establish a connection with
the master device like this through
scanning
Parry and the connection processing if
you take a look at the Bluetooth setup a
page you will find the car in the
crackit connection us is your computer
but go sternal version to does not
follow the euro bluetooth connections
the procedure that is we do not help you
go through the pairing connecting and
all that kind of stuff it only used the
Bluetooth Low Energy that what has a
data frame to communicate okay here is
the thing about the bluetooth low energy
state and there are four states and
three frame classes that are specify the
type of freedom can be transferred by a
device in each state and the second
state is discovery the discovery state
could exchange data with other adding
connections
and the otherwise otherwise magnetic
data it can be transferred here are some
taps of Bluetooth low-energy frame the
discovery frame and as a connection
frame and the data frame as we can see
advertising and the scanning pilla
belonging to the discovery frame so we
could trance transmitted data by the web
passing data or scan request and the
skin response the discovery state could
walk at passing with scanning mode or
actual scanning order we impress it with
scanning mode the link layer will only
receive about husband data and initial
never send out any packets and in active
scanning mode the link layer shall
listen for other work has in pillows and
depending on other what has in pillows
type it may request an advertiser to
send additional information after
interning the scanning state if the link
layer receives a scannable payload from
Edward advertiser
allowed by the scanner filter policy
initial respond with scan requests
payload and is then listen for the skin
response payload okay let's see how
kernel version 2 is implemented
according to the Bluetooth specification
version 4.2 the Bluetooth low-energy
link layer has only one packet format
used to focus on what has in general
package and data channel pockets
this is paralyzing channel data for
might the payload consists of
advertising address and other what has
been a data structure and what has been
the date advice is the at what hazards
that you want my advice
it has a sixth bias and advising channel
pillows serves only to Paris broadcast
data for applications and to know the
require a Foley connection or discovery
sleigh was Anacin connected resume we
will use that has metadata structure to
send it a custom data and this is the
other word has been a data structure we
could cause from the word husband
infrastructure to identify the target
the device a number of the word husband
it has structure having the falling
format and one biased data lines better
enclose the type field and the data
field and one one byte datatype and up
to twenty nine bias ad data okay not a
problem is how to send and receive
Bluetooth Low Energy frame through local
Bluetooth interface in userspace as we
know the Bluetooth shall has two most
the Bluetooth basic rate all the he has
data rate it is also called a PR or EDR
is a typically used for very huge orange
continuous various connections such as
streaming audio to hazards and is a
Bluetooth Low Energy and also called
prae is designed to use short bursts of
longer range radio connections make it
are you for Internet all the things
and they do not require the continuous
connection these apps they can often run
on just the wine corn style and the
steelhead were directly with long
battery life and luckily most of the
worldís module in PC has a double mode
awareness Bluetooth and the Wi-Fi combo
as it could work independently so you in
your Bluetooth highside connects with
your PC and you are listening the music
the beer he could still working as
another purpose for some connecting to
your band
at last we must find the read API to
send our payload okay let's take a look
at how to send and receive Bluetooth
frame in Windows we could use what
husband what has meant a tinnitus and
our custom payload we need one at what
husband in a structure to identify who
we are and followed with our custom the
payload so I didn't Fifield 0xff for is
the manufacturer specific what husband
in a structure company Andy field and
the data field could be any unique
number to distinguish our payload from
others ok here is Cody in Windows to
sender the custom payload and we could
create C Java console project on Windows
as we can see the manufacturer data is
used to identify our pillows the payload
the data section is used to send the
costume payload and once the publisher
stud heater the Pierrot module will send
the payload out automatically
and here is a code in Windows who
received the constant payload and we
couldn't subscribe our pillows by the
manufacturer data in the previous when
the manufacturer field a match to the
car in the payload the function at the
word husband Ricci would've will be
called that we can handle the cost from
data is that a function okay here's the
coaster no rushing to is BAE both client
and server could work as a scanner or
advertiser and use that what husband
scan request or scan response free to
exchange data directly without any
connections okay let's see simple demo
the PC on the life that is the victim
and we could see the PCs insight and the
Bluetooth are this connector so it is
not connected to the Internet the laptop
otherwise is the attacker
and we could send and receive data
through the costano version to this is
the system information of the victims
computer
okay that's my cousin aversion to
anybody have a question okay hello I
have a question have you tested maximum
possible speed of this Tom oh the the
speed yes yes 20 nights per second it's
slow yeah of course it's a covered
channel so that doesn't necessarily have
to be fast but yeah okay yeah thank you
but it is efficient it was cinder just a
commander there yeah but so this does
not make it useful for data exfiltration
right yeah if you send a fake file it's
it's almost impossible in the gate okay
okay
Thank You teacher yes thank you ah thank
you for your work what is it any
software need to be pre-installed on a
victim computer or it were cut off box
on Windows 10 sorry
is it any software need to be
pre-installed on a victim computer yes
you need to implant a software onto the
victims computer hardware and software
on it you can use a USB HID
[Music]
Lydia said that it's vulnerable on
windows and Mike is DD tested on Linux
different maybe its specifications about
Linux Tech Bluetooth some way it just
sees that Mike OS SDK and it does has at
her API but we didn't has today insisted
I of course Linux has data API what we
didn't test it yeah way we didn't touch
either way only tested on Windows 10 on
Linux did you test it yeah we tested on
the Windows 10 and we didn't I see there
are Mac OS and Linux Oh
since the report as the question is
doing it mr. Atif privileges on the
victims computer to install software
business oh it can be granting user
space user mode
sorry we need administrative privileges
to install the software that is needed
on victims computer or any user can run
it in the user mode without admin
privileges you need a malicious software
who implants yes but doing it
administrator privileges to run it on
the victims computer in Windows 10 or
any user on this computer controlled yes
the software should bypass
or syndication you know what you mean my
bypass the system is authentication so
the usual don't it
sorry the question is do I need
administrative rights on the computer of
the victim to install the software or it
can be runned by any user on this
machine
it's sorry I'll ask my friends first you
must have malicious software and you you
need you need a USB HID USB HID device
via USB taki it's just an Hallowell you
can use a hardware to flush that victims
computer the victim computer Master how
adapter Noah where is the Tetra it
should have Bluetooth Low Energy
all Wi-Fi
any questions okay
okay thank you