boys in Russia and if we're talking
about the NS attacks in 2019 but maybe
it's because like in the Wild West we
are going through your land full of
threats what a good girl good Cowboys
fall asleep and even can't Monroe mattis
so we have known for years about the
vulnerabilities surrounding DNS but
little has been done to fix them so DNS
attack has the kind of means to get a
bigger price and we have served our
great increasing attacks and million has
been lost an evaluation invaluable
information has been leaked but we want
this to change we want a good Cowboys to
wake and start fighting back so we are
going to show you who the gunmen are and
how they like the whiskey and how they
use their tools we want you to
understand the dimensions of this kind
of attack we want you to understand the
deep consequence they have and we want
to learn you to learn how to prevent
them and we want to show you how to
protect yourselves to protect your
secrets and the secrets of the ones you
love that have that don't have the means
to protect themselves but first let's
introduce ourselves
so I'm Valentina and my teammate is rude
we are both members of the little
Cantina celebrity we track a apts for
while in a daily basis and in this
presentation we are going to show you
the different types of DNS attacks that
we call the bullets then we are going to
review English public sources about DNS
attacks from 2007 until 2019 we are
going to see about the gunman which are
the IP T's and a little bit of
statistics about the state of this data
okay but the thrill every team does in
Argentina is to report and research
about three activities groups including
the mine where the tour's use and their
campaigns this is done to aid
researchers into knowing understanding
how a doctor behaves and how evolved
over time for doing this we we decided
to adopt the mitre attack framework
because that allowed us to better
understand and better communicate with
other teams and other communities about
their behaviors we have been done this
for almost three years now doing this we
don't only focus on current events but
also Impossibles this allows us to
observe how the ins protocol is being
abused for covering fictional
communication exfiltration and also
strategic compromise but first let's
introduce how DNS works just for the
sake that everyone is at the same page
we have here a little example requesting
a Spanish version of Wikipedia so first
when you wanna tell your browser to the
URL they will ask the recursive resolver
where the web page is if it's not in the
key share in the cache is going to go to
the root name server T as the IP for the
top leg of the Mende server and then we
follow until it got there to the
secondary level the - server to get the
whole IP for the e address it was more
or less like a telephone agenda where
you have the name and the IP address and
you just install between each other now
we are going to introduce the different
types of DNS attacks that we observed
that we call here the bullets which are
DNS tunneling hijacking and poisoning
first we're going to introduce a little
bit about DNS eternally so DNS tunneling
regarding a little bit of what we saw
before about the DNS how or DNS you see
that they will encode base64 data or it
could be in another coded method but
which is basically for for the example
and it will use them as a subdomain and
it will launch the request to the
recursive circle and then we'll go
through the fare wall until the Internet
until it treats the alternative DNS
server of the hacker domain which is the
C to come on in control but we were
afraid as it - mostly for in the next in
this presentation and so the Hat scare
will have all the information set in the
subdomain and they will live after that
will lunch response it could be in a DNS
record
which acumen for the victim machine
malware here we have a simplified
example of DNS hijacking in which the
hacker has a way to modify the DNS
settings and the user is going to try to
access or to one of those and modify
size and it's going to be directed to a
malicious website instead of the
legitimate one this is the case of DNS
spoofing it's a specific case but there
is also another way of DNS spoofing
which is DNS poisoning in this case a
user will attempt to ingress suicide and
the the DNS resolver doesn't help that
in the process so is going to ask the
Rudolf variety of DNS for the
information but when the root
authoritative DNS is preparing the the
request the attacker is going to inject
a rogue DNS entry into the servers
cachet so this way the answer is going
to be taken as a shitty mate and the
user is going to be redirected to a
malicious way but website instead of the
legitimate one so what we can see now is
the timeline for the attacks of DNS we
are going to cover until 2019 although
this timeline goes only to 2016 it will
further on we will see the whole
timeline and you can see the two types
of figures the certain ones are malware
pieces and the square ones are campaigns
so the first campaigns we chose was the
Julie Mayer case this case was in the
United States around 2004 schoolteacher
was given class to new students and some
what she was showing something on their
computer and it started popping up at
your content to them so she got
convicted for 40 years of prison and
given the absurdity of the case it got a
lot of international attention around
2007 this this sentence was overruled
and she only was forbidden for teaching
ever again but it's not that DNS attacks
were existed before it was the first
word that God like heat attention so
that's what we choose this one
at the section attack we are going to go
through it's called Operation goes like
operation Gauss click was an if SBI
operation that was how like the biggest
cyber criminal takedown in history at
the time it in mobile and malware called
DNS changer DNS changer I'm sure some of
you will remember a time where you went
to a streaming web page and you got a
pop-up telling you to download I don't
know an additional plug-in to be able to
see the video well that's how this
malware work and it will hijack the
computer DNS records to point to a rogue
servers so trying to remove it was
really hard and a lot of people the the
rug servers were online maintained by
the FBI for a lot of time because
millions of people were infected and
they were lost internet connection if
they remove them so it's estimated that
4 million computers were affected and 60
stoniest went down for this fraud and if
they estimated that they gain around 40
million dollars u.s. dollars through
clickjacking
contagion exercises but this last
distress case is a financially motivated
but we also have seen since 2010 attacks
that are made it should make a statement
the first example we have a statement
that are made just for fun for sampling
2014 we have the case of Craigslist
where they did there were DNS fight
shocked at the register level the users
were being redirected to a prank site
but we have also observed cases of DNS
attack made just for the glory for
example this is the case of the Romanian
top-level domain in which the most
popular sites such as Yahoo Google was
being redirected to a hackers control
domain in which it seems to be like a
defacement
but we have also observed since 2010
statements that are made for political
motivations and for example the Iranian
cyber army or the Syrian electronic army
this last one deserves a special mention
because they used DNS hijacking in most
of their attacks this is for example at
the case of Harvard University's site in
which this is the main image that is
there users were going to see but
talking about DNS attacks one of the
main big themes of DNS hijacking attacks
were sorry DNS spoofing is received
Brazil has also researchers have
observed a attacks in Brazil since at
least 2011 so the first case it was a
DNS poisoning attack at the ISP server
level so the older users of those ISPs
were being served with a pairing request
to download supposedly Google defense
plug-in which was in fact a bank
insertion the second wave were
compromising home routers to do the same
but the mimic English Java applet that
was also an insertion but we have a
observe a third wave that is interesting
because they attack a specific
vulnerability in the framework and they
at least six hardware providers a were
affected and that way they attempted to
they they achieve to compromise at least
four point five million routers which is
a lot so we have also served a attacks
that we're being using fishing social
engineering trickery to make the big
teams download also a also another thing
too to steal the credentials for the
breaking banking accounts so in this
last case since it was fishing it didn't
only focus on Brazil but also expanded
to US and China I'm speaking about China
we are going to talk about the first
case of DNS spoofing at the national
state level this is the great Canyon and
so I think that you all know what what
is the DNS and there sorry the Great
Firewall of China the Great Firewall
China is the means that China has to
prevent this is its citizens to access
into central sites so we see that in
2002 they start
in DNS hijacking to redirect users to
blocked IP addresses but this was kind
of easy to for the sink invention tools
to avoid so around 2015 they start using
redirecting users to legitimate websites
were while and these end up being a way
of carrying out denial of service
attacks through web pages that were
against China's addresses like for
example the great fire organization
which is an organization that helps
citizen from China to avoid the Great
Firewall there also
github was affected also some French NGO
regarding a freedom of speech and so
webpage in South Korea now we will to
the second part of the timeline which is
a much more targeted attack and the
first redactor we are going to speak of
is oil rig as you can see it's a very
active factor and you often use DNS
tunneling as a fuck back to fall back
channel for the cg communications what
is interesting about this thread group
they are suspected to be Iranian they
are considered to be expert because
they've done build their own tools from
scratch and they usually maintains a lot
of persistently to the systems that they
affect for a long time they are
motivated by some kind of advantage
being politically military or even
financially this this group loves to use
DNS for these communications to the
command and control or the c2 so they
usually uses for fishing attachments to
receive to incite the victims and they
can execute comments received from a
common and cultural through the command
line interface they they transfer the
information usually including the data
with pace it 26 or basic with 64 and
they use a lot of DNS record types as we
are going to see next
so the first tool we are going to
comment on about all rig is helmet
help means it's our user a record
breakers are 84 records
and it usually encodes the data you see
it makes this different base 33 sorry
so we also have is an agent with JSON is
mTOR variant the difference with between
this last one is that a SM door job they
use of the NS for covert communication
but they also used for a DNS record
which is used for resolving ipv6
information and they use a sequence
number into the the let's say the
subdomains
they are going to use for exfiltration
data so in this is interesting because
they can request information to be
retransmitted if they lose it and also
they can transmit data using the ipv6 as
a xs-xl decimal data
so these trick still is very much the
next is Alma communicator I'm a
communicator also used a deal-breaker
aid for its communication with the c2
it's pretty unique this is the only one
of the tool that doesn't have a fallback
channel so if it's not able to
communicate with DNS tunneling is not
going to work and it doesn't have a
config file the config file must be
brought by the deployer so another thing
about it is that the amount of data is
able to transmit is really limited so
it's pretty noisy and slow for
communication we have also served the
use of Punt
of the year which is a very first
reported on November 2017 discuss a
basic functionality of the factors such
as download and upload a information and
execute comments and they used a DNS txt
record but to receive advice and common
execution but if that txt record is
blocked for some reason is going to use
a DA report as a fallback channel and
finally we have create agent waiting Ted
it's pretty special to use just the only
one of the tools that encrypt
communications and it's used the app-6
records in order to establish the
communication it will establish
persistent using a schedule
tasks and the the encryption key will be
a story in a registry key created when
the malware is deployed it also have
father communication for HTTP and HTTPS
so now we are going to move to projects
our projects cherian was discovered by
Kaspersky around 2015 next this red
actually is suspected to be United
Stated regions this is not confirmed
obviously but their suspicion remains so
one thing about projection is that is a
really complex reactor and it used it is
DNS to in a long wanted mode so this
means that it tries to remain Stasi so
it will use it only to communicate
real-time status reports to the c2 and
also checks will trace some major data
for other amount of information or
bigger information it will use another
means but the interesting thing about is
it's one of the most complex characters
are there we wanted to show you with
this chart how big it how many tags they
use it's not color coded the colors are
only just for you to see the difference
between their tactics as you can see
they will use you too as a command and
control and for infiltration it also is
able to infiltrate
air-gap networks which it's a sign of
how complex it is but we hope also dark
hydrous IPT which was first disclosed it
on July 2018 by Polanco researchers the
this specific group it uses my work that
is called Rock ravine and open source
tools - so this actor is expected to be
on Iranian an introductory and hub is
also a consider to be an expert and
their motivations or military and
political advantage so in the first
campaign that that researchers of sir
they have been using an come on excel
web query file to chop up our shea
butter which is Rock ravine that has DNS
tunneling capabilities what is
interesting about this reactor is that
they have a hard copy list of DNS type
records which are the ones that you
theater and they are going to attempt to
communicate to the command and control
with all of those records and the first
one that answers quickly is the one that
is going to be used as a channel for
communication through the trash on to
the government culture but we have also
observed of course in these kind of
attacks in point-of-sales and crypto
wallets and so the first case I'm going
to toggle here happen almost a year ago
in February 2018 when what black wallet
and reported to its users that they were
DNS I shocked so the attacker is called
control to the youngins panel of the
registrar and they changed the IP
address and all users were being
directed to hackers cultural domain that
was trying to get organized and they
also injected called to automatically
exfiltrate all money on the accounts
that called Martin Bedell immense which
was the point that they share they
exchanged and they that way they
achieved to stole four hundred thousand
dollars u.s. dollars this way they also
they transferred the money to another a
big big sorry a crypto exchange crypto
exchange platform which my speech works
and that way they change the world from
wrong with one crypto mining a greeter
going to another one and they hit the
tracks but we have also served this kind
of a taxi point-of-sale systems so the
first one the first cases that we
observed some point of these systems is
partner post this is the first case that
they used in s planning for a situation
of great car information
but about it thing why do they do that
so the great card ID the serial number
the expiry date
everything is little chunks of data so
these types of data perfectly fits in
DNS
records so that's why they use this kind
of information so they are still using
this now they are a little bit more
stealthy in their way to infect victims
so they usually try to check if the big
thing is four feet resistance they are
running their service that they want to
to infect and also they mimic a city
maid service so just love me so now we
are going to talk about fin 7 fin 7 is
financial money motivated Fred actor
that uses DNS messenger as a tool for
its tax so fin 7 is suspected to be
Middle Eastern I mean it's a sorry
Eastern European origin something in our
charts so the main motivation for the
attacks is the financial game but what
we wanted to show you about this is this
tool is the first tool that we see that
implements a method to avoid being
detected being detected as DNS online
communication I mean if you see most of
the tool we see in coded data and send
it through the safe DNS record this
means that you are going to see in your
logs a lot of requests to the same to
mine and would see the same record it's
pretty stunning saying that this is a
DNS tunneling communication but this
tool what we do will change the DNS
record according to it wishes will be
USD a record e txt record and it will
also use almost random way to generate
the demise to which it will send
information using the computer the
information system to do it another
thing to notice about this tool if you
want to check it out a little bit more
it's based on a public tool available
and it only have that's called the NSTIC
txt pwnage so if you want to take a
little bit more you can see something
about the tool over there
depression they use is heavily
associated with in both confiscation of
course we wanted not to let a Android
outside this we hope also Serbian s5
shocking attacks for Android to insert
my worry to Android phones we have
served this researcher house observed
this campaign through made 2015 and last
reportedly active on April twenty
nineteen so it's probably active now so
they use the anezka shocking to job man
we're into the users phones they were
prompted to download a fake Chrome or
Facebook application which was you in
fact dropping roaming Monte's which is
also known as extolled or mock how you
may know those names too but they this
case is really really interesting not
only because of the great span of time
that they have been active but also that
they expanded geographically they just
started with South Korea then they
expanded to Asia then to the to Eastern
European countries then the rest of
Europe and lastly in April 2019 was
report has active in Middle East so if
we give him a couple of time maybe they
will reach her some dinner sometime
started using crypto my name young
software to yeah it's interesting
because they they didn't just a funny
geography believe it also technically
because they are now supporting iOS is
iOS systems and also home computers
because they also expanded in these
business they are not just dropping
magnet churches but now they are you
soon also crypto crypto mining a my work
so now we are going to speak a bit about
ocean letters which is suspected to be
Vietnamese apt it has a really complex
attack workflow and they're one of their
preferred tools will be da Dennis factor
that is factor is usually used as a
first taste factor that will drop later
a second stack back turn this back there
uses
DNS channeling as a means for
communication we have seen it
the NSA and the NS null records and it
will encrypt the data you see in base 32
and other thing that is worth to mention
is that the last report issued by a set
about this backdoor establish that these
tooling had now has a fallback channel
in HTTP POST communication if they is
not able to communicate through DNS and
lastly we are going to see the last
alerts about regarding DNS attacks it
was first detected DNS espionage was
first detected in November 2018 by Cisco
DNS espionage is suspected to be Iranian
Iranian Iranian threat actor and the
reason behind this attack is affected to
be credential harvesting they deploy you
two tools one with the same name DNS
espionage and another one that was
fabricated later of the disclosure
what's called Karkaroff
the difference between the second tool
the first one is that the second to
introduce new anti sandbox methods do
you remain to difficulty analysis work
and it also use DNS records as similar
communication what is interesting about
is that in the same campaign of DNS
espionage
researchers found out that the IP that
they were using in that campaign were
also being used in DNS redirection
attacks so in February 2019 I think was
a lie right sorry general sorry if I
reported about some DNS redirection
attacks also using DNS a records abusing
DNS providers admin panel DNS NS records
using compromised registrar or country
code top-level domains resolutions so
what is interesting about is that in the
report a fire water assess is that they
are probably not only one traductor
because of the of the growth of the big
that they have been attacking yeah the
other thing to mention is that they used
let's encrypt certificates to mimics the
victims domain so they to abolish
suspicions from the user so the thing
that we the issue will notice was just a
little bit of delay within that
communication so this take us to see
Churchill after a final report saying
that they might have another Frederick
terrible Cisco published in April this
year and article about C Churchill which
is believed to be a nation state actor
that's also hijacking or manipulating
DNS records so about this productor my
winner we wanted to show you it's a
little bit of the workflow they do they
will compromise as a service provider
for the addressed registry or the
registrar and it will use the
compromised accounts to manipulate the
records and get into the registrar
information and harvest credentials for
a second wave of attacks it centers
mostly they main targets were ministry
Foreign Ministries intelligence agencies
and some internet service providers so
now we are going to move a little bit
over the gansan data which is the part
of the statistic about this attack after
we bombed you all with all this
information so it is going to talk about
DNS hijacking common techniques I'll be
observing these attacks for example we
have several of the brute-forcing
attacks using dictionaries to attempt to
login into the the home routers a
configuration to change the DNS
resolutions we have also served a
trusted relationships a attacks because
they for example in the case of the
Brazil is very shocked the users are not
a they are not in fact the victims I
mean they are the victims that they are
not in fact infected with this but the
ISPs and that way they are going to be
redirected to a malicious sites and we
have also served ballot accounts as I
initial access because they usually try
to get it
for a DNS owners so they can change
their resolutions into the DNS servers
so about the DNS Italian common
techniques we have found that 78% of the
malware is deployed through spearfishing
attachments 50% of them establish
persistent using a scheduled tasks and
42% of them uses PowerShell does I mean
of executing commands that the city will
send them to a DNS tunneling and finally
30% of them will use fallback channels
it could be that they use DNS and some
main channel and have an HTTP HTTPS or
another channel as a fallback it could
be that they have DNS as they fall back
channel for other communications and
regarding the records but we can see
here they have a clear preference for da
record although they will use others not
to and for the effect CT for encoding
they will treat the IP addresses that
the situation them using as a binary or
ASCII data but now we want to give you
some kind of recommendations we are just
starting with the general ones such as
for example activating multi-factor
authentication of the mains and
importance to avoid attackers a
modifying those or use UNIX password
password managers and we also have so
recommendations for DNS hijacking yeah
for example we recommend you to use the
security NS because they are a lot of
implementations to make DNS secure such
as DNS SEC or you can encrypt your going
your DNS communication with the NS
script
yeah you should all be validating your
DNS a and name server records yeah well
we also have some recommendations for
DNS tunneling that could be like blog
txt and old records or you can block
them the size of the packet that
receives but well I think when you get
all ready they what we wanted to say
that you should all be monitoring your
DNS traffic so this is kind of the end
so we want to thank you all and we want
to thank the organization to you for
giving us this space we hope you like it
and we really want we wanted to show you
how these were the impact they have
everyone we hope you understand and now
you you are able to start fighting back
and we want you to all to start
monitoring your DNS records thank you
anyone has any question yeah hello first
of all thanks for coming to Russia and
thanks for this interesting overview of
DNS attacks my particular question is
what may be may be some particular trick
is you can you can propose to ask how to
monitor generous traffic's maybe
triggers or something like this I think
you know in our slide we just stated one
for you to if you want it which is using
elastic and cabana plus row IDs I'm sure
there are other ones you can use any
blog monitoring system yeah there are
multiple things that you can observe
about the DNS communication for example
there are a lot that they are attempting
to contact the same domain over and over
and over again so they are maybe suspect
or suspicious so you should check that
information and any kind of not usual
traffic from DNS usually DNS traffic is
not a it's not a monitor at all so
starting doing it doing that is just a
lot more than it's being done now thank
you
hello I have a question if we want to
resolve the man-like base64 that hacker
demanded calm what would be the answer
from the server the answer it depends on
the implementation of each each each
thread but for example there are ones
that the ipv6 or IP before information
is useless binary or accessible data to
drop an additional file or stuff but it
depends a lot on the implementation of
each one of the attacks thank you thank
you very much representation in your
presentation you tell us about some more
tax in blast years and there was some
suspects on what date you was figure out
the suspects of some of attacks
especially the last year I think you're
referring about the attribution of the
introductory right just of information
on the public reports okay yeah we
mostly use public report I mean the
presentation you will have all day
biography we used available to consult
if you want we also use some Deloitte
internal sources without not available
to consult but we try to avoid stating
that some trajectory is from that place
or some way we use the word suspected
because attribution is pretty
controversial thing so we are kind of a
stadium while the the current actual
Karen is saying right now right
any other question I would like to ask
your opinion on why is it taking so long
for such taking says then s SEC and then
I script to take over the place so they
they have been for quite a while now but
the percentage of integration to mobile
systems the net system is very small
white by it so I think you asked why it
takes so long for people to start
implementing solutions maybe that yeah
we don't have an answer for that
actually we can no speak for the people
that's not implementing the solutions if
there are solutions but we don't know
why why they are not you have the point
of our presentation is kind of urged
people to start doing it and we can say
that monetary and manually DNS logs is
pretty heavy work pretty demanding and
tiring work so that's why we believe it
has been not having like in mind Li
until now but we have now more means to
monitor logs with more how you say in a
more comfortable way any other questions
okay
and we have seen the history of the DNS
attacks but I want to know if in the
last year's let's say two years they
have increased or decreased and what
they have in common for example okay
if you see our timeline let me show you
just quickly you can see that timeline
for previous 2016 sorry so the
determinant for decisive previous this
2016 is pretty wide and you have a lot
of space they are plenty of attacks too
but if you see after 2016 it's a clear
increase and we don't mention it but in
2018 there's an us-cert alert about
global DNS hijacking so it's kind of
being ensuring that is pretty little to
say normal but is kind of frequent now
yeah now it's going to it's being used
in more strategic attacks more than
wide-open attacks no more questions
thank you very much well for listen to
us at an estate for hours until the end
and thank you very much pH day for
having us to here today thank you
[Applause]