name six fast track yes I would clean
under Nikolai yet which is intermittent
Ibiza passes Bantam credit emo declawed
buton budget position at the movies I
speak to us Bishop Aston his apostasy
privilege Iran overdosed au poivre
infrastructure a windows icbo service
Castle subsume uu at the timidly honest
was not but a most what profit roses all
monopoly is was profit company analysis
usual miss Chen we do the the
vulnerability analysis security analysis
not many do you raise ahead but sooner
leaders a pen tester so gets the domain
admin rights and why it happens because
in the typical Windows infrastructure
can identify the following groups of
admins so support of the users and so
that workstations that can appear it was
remote and physically close to the
computer then and then admin group
Windows servers people who maintain the
system so applications and each of the
points so where they input their
information so they can compromise the
entire domain because the systems are
interconnected and so we just put
together the main two techniques of
compromising the credentials so input
capture credentials dumping input prompt
network sniffing etc and the server they
get passwords from the from from RAM so
which makes the pentesters life easier
but in life it getting more and more
difficult so even look at the common
flaws privileged access that we have in
any organization so it's a first it's a
non non unique password for enable built
in local administrator account because
the workstations usually
so then they have standard passwords and
how to change the password using the
same account for productivity tasks
email internet etc and for admin tasks
especially when this account is admin at
more than one computer so if there are
many many more than one host Windows
host working stations or a server and
then saving saving passwords so then
sometimes they admin so could be not bad
or special soft where for for storing
sitting passwords and sitting for add
credentials and manager and then using
accounts with admin rights at dirty
workstations
so when eventually so the technical
support guys that goes to the users
working stations install software and
then can enter its own information on
the user's computer and then then if
there is malware it will immediately
catch it and that the artifacts or the
password in the form of hashes so then
smart cards so they are not the 2fa
replacement because we need to be be
aware of anti hash rotation not every
you can again just abandon out
notification in every structure the den
credentials card that appears in twenty
and ended at the interpreting system
number ten and higher so they they could
be bypassed with malicious security
support provider's so there are links
you can always read more about that and
then not to invent something that has
been invented and undo the security
secure privileged access and microsoft
placed a special document describing
basic principles and there is quick wins
so the list of the events that is very
cheap for the organization
but they are low-hanging fruits and
server efficient is to increase the
level of security very quickly so basic
has so then separate working station
isolated monitoring working station and
then dividing accounts into into
standard and privileged and then another
and there so then just just in time just
in time password local admin password
sort of privileged so then it's given on
on Dementor after certain administrate
at miss so miss nature should not know
this password does have to have this
passwords all the time and it's now with
the help of labs utility and in the
document we have it that when administer
and when you work under working stations
it's not allowed to use the main the
main the main entry that has privileges
so this is the domain of entry of the
administrator as I can easily cancel the
station because not correct I saw it in
the right one is a necessity to get to
query for they put the passport of local
entry the working station so that we
generate with the help of labs and so
retrieve this local account password set
by ellipse from and that what is what is
laps so those who don't know laps is is
a client to utility or Microsoft so they
have PowerShell module and GPO templates
but the main idea that this is something
that provides opportunity of rotating
the path mordant and keep it in Active
Directory special attribute that stores
the the clear text labs password and the
time when the password should change so
it works various
in a stable manner no problems okay
we're introduced laughs now we have
under working stations on the servers so
have the local unique network or local
musician but how to use it and
throughout the challenges so then a
technical support guy comes up to the
computer here was the password the local
administrator what he wants to do so
their clients application can launch on
powerful spring and and and then and
then he does its own his own entries
thus it can be compromised them but
lapse keeps bad passwords open though it
is a special attribute but it still if
you have the rights to read these
attributes so that you can easily have
put in a request and get all the
passwords from all working stations and
workstations and so what to do there is
no network you'll come to the host and
so there is no network and they cannot
get the password so no mechanism until
factor two to FA not supported and and
that's why since this application
standards application is windows so it
cannot be do the limitations of the a
life a life span of the session and also
justice you cannot you cannot set the
path
and so sometimes necessary just go into
this workstations and and an RDP session
and there so he goes for lunch but the
application is open and we start to
collect passwords again and then and
then so then so the user can set to long
password expiration time and and then it
will not be changed
so it's problem for monitoring because
if you do the audit of access to this I
attribute that IP address will not be
fixed and so it just says that this is
this user went to the main computer and
then another very important point many
don't know just that if there is a
special entry that allows to enter the
machine into the domain that it has the
rights to all attributes and it is why
so then then labs and permission to join
compute the main do not forget to modify
computer on the rights so these are the
problems and so this is the question and
our wannabes first what we want when it
comfortable when is it pretty
comfortable comfortable usage usage and
that we wanted to give the
administrators a comfortable way should
be something about web web portal so to
guarantee that we could get access from
UNIX from Windows should be mobile app
preferably to get local admin passwords
the southern 2fd to have a capture yeah
etc then registration of IP addresses
integration or say museum system might
be login high availability about remote
support secure passwords backup in case
of 80 and availability etcetera that's
what these are all wannabes and so this
is what we got so we call code
the web laps this web portal plus mobile
app in Java
hmm Java app so there should be a good
for Windows and UNIX the works under
windows in service a demon mode he one
is compromised the the system will work
on UNIX and the third EMBs can use so
built-in SQLite or external mi skill
married and and high availability is is
provided and they saw dangerous and then
the circle always a request passwords so
that's what the screen looks like a
rebel apps web GUI mobile app it repeats
the interface of Microsoft applications
away so we had just the coca you can
just add computers to select that item
in the mobile application of I have the
same functionality concerning
authentication so there are two modes so
then at your discretion you can
implement this or that so the left one
is - - fa so when they ask for carefully
passwords and one time code at one time
password and so then war has its OTP
providers or well there is no embedded
service then then you can use and in
built in 8000 TP per provider and if I
make a decision that so we can use both
the software from dirties workstations
and that mean and the one one passport
one-time password so that's it and they
will be so then the then the passport
will not be a key
we'll be stored on the user's computer
and so then so we just we developed this
mobile and we added support from push
authentification
so you just put the button and then
immediately comes support or not support
registers not registered then then user
sessions user session protection so
there are mechanism server but so log of
idle users log off on the remote
connection detection window size color
depth chart changes yes color colour
change
NASA if it changes that means someone
connected to the users through DP and
then we do automatic logoff and then the
session is connected is bound to the
source IP to the source IP and then if
they are so loose so the the password so
then they they they reflect all events
of security as all events and and then
there is an imbalance event and then you
can import so all these events in this
form then about access control
configuration if if the company is for
the volar russia like in our case so
then the hcg administrator should see
all the passwords computers from home
from his own computers and this so that
is why so we do the mapping of a you and
if you are part of the group then you
will get the passwords only from your
own region and then another thing that
we faced so there was a task as add
another administrator and then a
technical support unit
so the first have access to all computer
said there are some users so that that
gives supported applications as
seungho's
they could be 50 holes 400 holes and
that and actually and we not want to add
them to the grow that were Corral to
request the passwords well computers and
as we need to do the attribute that is
reflects either the the entry or the
attribute yeah and and there's another
to guarantee that you identify the
accidents so when we scan the Porsche or
something else or then strange activity
then certain certain instruments allow
us to enter the workstations in
automatic mode and collect forensic
information so that the system could
enter so then you do the IP key for the
API access so the API is connected to a
pack IP address and the system
automatically can request password soon
and then another mechanism of protection
is when too many requests so then the
session identification expired and it's
not it's not logged on and the bad guy
got an access so then there are some
system the system as to the number of
how many times the password is requested
and there's a limit and then other
features is so one of the ways one of
the ways so if we saw the expiration
time of the password is one to one
minute so that we requested the password
and
and then within the administration and I
wanted to be changed then we can
forcefully put the expiration time of
the password at the plus one minute for
example and then there is a difficulty
that in if a replicated not immediately
then twenty to forty minutes has already
passed before their application comes
toll the control controllers so that not
to force the admin to do this
optimization and their application so we
just do the push push this all these
changes to each domain controller time
out to a spoke about that so we can
limit the at the maximum time a lifetime
so this always said we don't want it to
change in three years later and
automatically at each request of the
password the system will immediately
dated and after the request of the
passwords will change change the
passwords in sixty minutes in this case
and so that mean for more comfort for
that min so we have the quick launch
buttons and so then a command command
line and then with the help of our
special special templates I can put the
name of the computer a guillotine and
the password and it works only and he i
IE only so then the user to launch it
just with one button can also go down
into the session but able to RDP client
that does not support the transfer or
password to through the command line
and so then there is a there is a
special there is a special a special
combination of words that will put the
password into the exchange buffer and
candy and the user could get it later
there and so then let's Mobile is the
same interface not a difference being it
supports the so as s ID and so the
fingerprint works as well and so the
main features
that doctor guaranteed immobile
operations so have only one at pointa
and it supports the the masking of the
endpoint if you want to so they would
elapse dot domain.com so that the miss
Corinth could not see it in our zone and
so we can always place it in an existing
balancer and add some some traction
there and then only our users will know
about that and so as you when you
install sodium of application so first
initialization J is a G key generated
during device enrollment process also to
sensitive information is additional
encrypted during transmission over TLS
and then we imported and then they then
the bad guy will not see anything son
and the server that had a server side so
device profile checkers at server-side
platform
OS version device ID etc is done and
then then push notification I spoke
about and ideas for future releases so
one just windows thick client windows
thing client but the clip that will be
in tray now or in the context menu will
be added to guarantee quick launch from
standard so that you could go away from
this standard application that's what
will guarantee a quick RDP launch I can
get to get a passport with OTP I put the
credentials manager open RDP cooling
credentials manager easy
and then we can do the mechanism that
would add the users right the user
rights of he wants us to not to keep his
account in these privileged groups for
example so you can if he went through
the two-factor authentication so then he
gets groups and in an hour's time
removed the little group after defined
time out so then so that's it if you
have any suggestions amendments
proposals of be happy to implement a
thank you
[Music]
because whether introduced elapsed so
the first thing we did is we we took
stock of all the accounts that were
added to the local group of
administrators so they need to be
cleaned out rather edit enter account
yeah but we are a getting away from this
from the subject that's monitoring of
abnormal activity of the work stations
and naturally if I see the abnormal
activity
yeah so to do the detect of a remote
connection but the first thing that
comes at a occurs to me that pin test
being tested near from some virtual
machine and then full-hd and then a
redesign of the screen occurs and the
screen size changes no no it's not an
event we launched the the user has the
browser the browser JavaScript watches
regularly the width of the screen and
height of the screen and the depth of
the screen and so once so like you know
successful because we remember the first
one which with which the user came in
entered so when the end and so on when
he is not pure Asian there's a changes
so some just remote connected to his
workstations but all these values change
so we think if they change then we think
that that there is a connection to the
user so it's not the windows event it's
not OS it's the fact on the web at the
level of application
[Music]
in the event so they detect some
suspicious activity you know - you take
the majority the majority of logs from
the workstations for forensic for more
in-depth forensic so then you as you
that the security logs collected and you
collect all other no no it's not very no
no it's a different subject for
discussion for a new presentation but
the AG is that there is a we're um we're
work mail warm cancer so we adapted it
to our needs so we had it at the cortex
to hive added it to cortex in hive and
see him registered and anomaly and and
the anomaly is his processed and
registered the event in hive hive
launches cortex and with the help of
special cortex plugin so it gets the
admins password goes to the machine I
want your scans cancer and then gets the
list of security logs additional
information for insulin formation which
goes into one place and this is done in
order to so we do one account which is
admin for all stations and what we're
trying to avoid that actually yeah
that's true but so but there are no
instruments finished products that would
our higher P systems so the incident
response platform but when we ask either
supported labs so they say they don't
give you the direct answer right and so
they serve developed systems yeah
and so then opens it's not open source
so there was a reference to the website
that there was a link you can ask a
question you can write to us that was a
link to the website and directly at the
website it has it and the plus extended
documentation how you can do how you can
cancel how you can use it yes we thank
you
[Music]