Minister Koizumi hell yeah engineer pub
is a person occipital as a company pawn
of the classy hotel visit along with
popular I would like to speak about the
popular topic of services development
cycle of secure software and in
particular I would like to discuss the
design stage and modeling the threats
many people underestimate at this stage
because they believe it's a superfluous
you can just take a checklist and give
it to the developers security that's how
you implement your security in fact it's
not exactly like that so modeling these
threats simulation of threats is a link
between the requirements that we
determined in our first phase where
we'll be to turn the risks for the
application data and the confidentiality
it is done uttanasana Kotaku shield
lepida lasagna and so so director of
attack so modeling of threats it
connects the stage of requirements with
implementation so threat modeling and so
all of you yes
so we started to model threat starting
from this primitive step as using using
free free program
like trance rat modeling tool that can
could be downloaded from Microsoft site
for frames and everything that you do is
you determine the diagram the
architectural application then you
determine how data come in and how they
and then you get this eventually others
huge lots of threads you get and all
threats so they require filtration they
require prioritization to be prioritized
so intended then the clear module
prioritization is very important because
threats lots and that's why we need to
prioritize and and most threats are not
applicable so then excessive database
weak access to database some are not
relevant at all and this way can be
disregarded and so when we deployed it
and we started out with this and we came
to the conclusion that that this process
is very time-consuming because we need
to see each threat classifieds threat
then then study each threat and in
accordance with this model verification
should be done and then eventually to
either accept this threat or reject the
threat the most important problem of
this approach is that so then the study
the study of those threats takes a lot
of time
a lot of time and there's why using this
model of security advises security
champion whether security specialist who
is an expert and sdlc and security
champion software the guy who is has
been seconded so by the team so it is
responsible for the project for specific
project and as and on the basis of this
interaction so they the deployment of
still see is is built to what extent
this interaction will be efficient to
the same extent the modeling of threats
will be efficient so one comes with the
other and much depends on what questions
will set to security champion some what
recommendations will need to give the
security champion and what what is the
framework and then there's the proper
questions put to the security champion
and depends on the on the clarity of
modeling and precision of modeling and
the regional process looks like this so
all the threats that you get we get we
request afire them based on our risks
based on on a factor of attack based on
our profiles of attackers that could be
dodging us exogenous attackers and based
on the data involved and the level of
confidentiality clearance availability
and then we always how this identified
threats who assign to the project team
and
they and then they do the investigation
as a rather destroyed is applicable to
this specific hurtful for them is it
irrelevant for them and if they take it
as a threat than they do the
implementation so the weaknesses of the
model are around this is a
non-transparent process for the security
adviser because we don't know whether
they the team did it right the
mitigation right or wrong and whether
they did the investigation correctly and
there is no feedback with the security
commander then another thing that the
security command is not they're not
working very hard so we did it once this
cycle several cycles and every time we
realized we had a modeling threat
modeling takes too much fun and we
started to think how can you improve it
and we decided that why don't we map
most all threats to beginning and in our
security practices concerning
configuration and input one and put one
set against the other infrastructure
solutions and and and then and put it
into a special model so that we define
they already finished ready model that
we can we give the team to developer and
all they need is to implement the
originated security practices finished
and don't do any investigation and no
need to do that and not to spend time
for the investigation of threats and not
to look how to mitigate this specific
threat on a specific platform and the
specific solution etcetera
so we followed on this process of
storing mapping how security practices
and threats of mapping in reference
model return it into reference model and
regard this process and so when we give
the team our model so safe model where
all the mitigations are observed and all
the threats are identified and mitigated
and all we have to do is is to do the
verification of their architecture and
their code and and to implement this so
this is a this is a model example where
we implemented many security patters gmz
if you have a confidential data and you
need to protect it and you need to
identify data storage and put it in a
different close the network so then we
started to think about the accuracy of
our threat modeling and actually we
always dealt with general threats not
technology specific threats so we have a
threat for example the tempering
information to score for specific data
flows and we understand that there's
this data flow can so they can be
different protocols that they could be
different variety variety of data move
around so the problem had to do the
elevation of privilege evasion of
privilege so could be
exploited differently in different
different service of different servers
on different platforms and jinx for
example and it could be a module which
you forgot to turn off and the attacker
attacked then and do the remote code
execution and in a posh it could be a
different module so that I could there
could actually address the same issue
and had the same problem etc for these
threats technology specific for a
specific application or platform
database and so on so at the next stage
we try to identify such threats with
every technology of our model so and
gradually we accumulated these data a
determined we found so-called a library
of threats where we keep all the
information about all the threats
it may be both general and nature
threats those that use this specific
technology and again as GPS and
processes and something well and then we
saw that when we
kept accumulating threads we saw an
interesting things very often they may
repeat themselves they may reappear it
will take a DB as an information
disclosure from the file system it does
not make sense to waste in every model
for HTTP we can actually group them into
an abstract level and determine some
kind of a model offer inheriting to
simplify the manage to simplify the
management of all threads and we
continued refactoring our model and we
got approximately this model when at the
top level we have general threads then
SQL a dirty piece and then we can
continue specific implementations of
Mongo was Chris and MySQL SQL Server and
so finally - we need to take a high
level thread cells then add the threads
that are specific of no SQL specific
data storage threads and then MongoDB
specifics for instance MongoDB injection
where you allow scripting for your DB so
we made it for the processes for
injector then there will be a similar
situation that we determine a common
threads for front-end server and the
thread specific for engines
and then we noticed one more thing
composition of threats if for instance
your process is at some docker container
or within a server within some
environment it's clear that the threat
for those such processes are amok
accumulative threads within which the
process lies in this case those friends
related to the network server and threat
linked to a specific process if for
instance you have problems somewhere
with a port server order then it makes
sense for the process to describe
complete model comprehensive model and
the last stage that we added to the
library is how specific threads should
be verified if we take this simplest
[Music]
CSRF threat we can verify through
security code review on C there is no
token and the sunnah synchronization i
will look until the configuration of
application and they'll find that CSRF
protection is not included and it's
rather a question of convenience of the
revocation of specific threats it's
clear that there are many ways to do it
but now we were to on convenience to
identify and which is more convenient
for instance it's good to set a rule for
static analysis and it will find all
spots for instance if you have a hundred
it's clear that the manual security
testing is a is difficult to do
considering the time it may take for
penetration testing and the last thing I
wanted to mention is that we certainly
can build the ideal model of threats
cover all risks mitigate virtually
everything but most important don't
forget about our model if we make a
threat model and then left it in the new
release so we may add some functionality
some button that will be accessible to
unauthorized users that can drop all the
tables and although threat model will go
down the drain so the compulsory process
is building a model of threats for the
new functionality that you introduce you
have to upgrade it and continue the
process within the building the threat
model so the library that we have built
can be supported both security experts
they may put all the security practices
in and simple developers who can give
recommendation on technologies Java C
don't net and you may also store their
infrastructural threats and in such a
way we shall get as a general library
which may be reused by other projects if
for instance you use any DP you can just
go to this library and look up what tray
or the threads and at the design stage
account for them and ensure security at
the design stage and he will not need to
do additional verification and so on so
in such a way you can save much time I'm
done thank you thank you yeah hello
thank you for the wonderful presentation
I would like to ask you in more to
describe more in more detail the library
processes do you mean the actualization
from the point of view of new features
no I mean the relevance of the threads
and the 18 new threads and revision yes
this library has to be supported all the
time and there are many tools to support
it and risk and threat modeler and they
provide interface and which if you
create a Moodle there and you get some
new thread you will add it and
automatically it will be sent to all the
project teams
they will know that it needs to be
mitigated and all models will upgrade
correct me if I'm wrong the threat is
like a vulnerability it so a threat is
potential vulnerability which we can get
over so if we get a vulnerability and
attack it's dangerous so this way we
avoid all those vulnerabilities so more
questions thank you Michael thank you
very much and good evening ladies and
gentlemen it was our last presentation
for today's fast track and we are done
for today as here tomorrow