so demon-like see Jax of Superman the
medium enters the water world in the
modern infrastructure yes quite a lot
changes is changing our approach is
changing expert approach to the search
of other villages is changing how to get
prepared for new challenges at least you
need to ask this question so I'm passing
the floor to Dimitri our speaker good
afternoon dear colleagues of the Metro
Binet aberration MIT security experts at
crop I'm happy to welcome you at this
event I'll tell you about the role of
machine learning in looking for
attackers and the world is changing
everything is changing the cities the
country's new technologies appears cars
replaced the steam is a Tesla car is
basically server in wheels that allows
controlling the car also fully
automatically of course you need serious
computing resources to do that large
companies include more and more of a
server infrastructure one of our
customers has more than 10 thousand
servers consuming about 8 megawatts of
energy this affects business processes
what happens with the information
security the edge of the networks
becomes blood users work with different
devices mobile devices web interfaces
cloud resources as as model is getting
more and more popular so you have to go
beyond the standard multi-layer
protection
approaches but also utilize how the user
interacts with all information or source
of the company or what application with
any data to use in order to process this
size of information is clear that the
number of servers may go beyond a
thousand and large companies fault
tolerant solution with the backup site a
toe leads in a situation of where
millions of events have to be analyzed
using proactive security system as
opposed to a standard security system
that was following a pre-configured
profiles and patterns and require
regular updating of attribute-based
new systems are based on machine
learning this allows any system to fully
adapt that any changes in the item to
structure in the human resources and
processes of course developing as such
models requires new competences these
the companies of data analysts
scientists people who know which a task
which algorithm can be used to so task a
data engineer who knows who no
requirements to the physical
infrastructure may be it would be enough
five devices or ten devices in the
cluster maybe your needs Edition and in
every database to have prompt access
surfaces to the user profile comparing a
physical activities improving the
response times and of course a lot of
other things if you consider this in
practical terms and then the ones they
offer data scientist looks like this
first they get information that some
logs need to be analyzed to identify
some anomalous activity motifs or some
other tasks for instance so we get a
task of analyzing
logs from the firewall to see what uses
what makes us different from
administrators and to use an algorithm
other the use of activity is related to
the work of administrator so this our
hypothesis and it needs to be confirmed
you know to confirm this hypothesis we
need to develop a lot of models and part
of them shed has not effective for a
specific infrastructure well as others
expanded added to you know to minimize
the number of false positives and to
maximize the potential outcome for the
organization of course after that you
need to customize the algorithm improve
the performance so that you they could
be used alive in enterprise solutions
right on live data so how does it look
as part of the data scientist workday
for instance they're getting a number of
columns at the input and the check point
the next stage of their work is to
determine whether this information is
enough to build a model as I said our
task is to build a model that allows us
to differentiate a regular user from
administrator because you don't have a
user name the most important entity that
allows matching an IP address or a set
of IP addresses if the user works from
different workstations with the
different activities then this
information is added to by indicating
the date and time for instance because
you don't know the workday of an
employee we clarify this information and
enrich the model so they should also
know that the workday of an employee is
from 9:00 to 5:00 and the rest will be a
potential deviation from the working
schedule of the next step would be to
convert all information into some 2d and
3d models the standard representation of
a machining learning not only is a
multi-dimensional space that includes
hundreds of elements in our case for
firewall backlog analysis 77 attributes
turned out to be enough oh but enough to
visualize this information connect way
so it could be worked with we need to
use a special algorithm to reduce this
dimensionality as you can see over a
several points here related to the work
of an illustrator indeed it's possible
to separate the irregular user activity
from anomalous activity represented by
red and green points then you use
different algorithms that allow us to
reduce the dimensionality showed in 2d
mode to filter out a necessary component
in the previous slide we saw that there
was some service surface identified in
blue you know to get rid of the surface
we just ignore the first two components
which the report for us and just leave
75 instead of 77 components and then we
convert these 77 components into 2d
representation here we use quite
sophisticated mathematics because we
need to identify the most effective
criteria and threshold thresholds for
our analysis and this analysis can
includes not only administrators and
user but it can be applied to any task
that you have in terms of a data analyst
it looks like this
they analyze analyze the model using
purely formal attributes looking for
dependencies for instance here we see a
normal motion representation of users or
distribution of you but it can't be
shown as a classic ellipse in this case
the data analysts use a mostly solution
that allows to assess better which
algorithm or a set of algorithms must be
used to identify outliers
based on the results of the data
analysts work we arrived at the
possibility to create a specific model
that the models a sophisticated the
behavior of profiles it identifies a
number of blue points representing
normal user security so everything
beyond that is potentially abnormal
activities that require IT security
relate investigation so therefore we're
talk about a model of machine learning
the before the performance my so the
criteria can be formulated firstly by
being able to analyze large volumes of
data this slide showed you from a
processing of a million events this
information can't be processed to using
standard methods
so therefore a distributed system is a
huge error or Hortonworks
stack which allows implement different
behavior model models based on hadoop
and all these models are adapted to all
changes infrastructure we don't need to
reset the correlation rule every time
saying that five false names
failure attempts and is bad the next day
could be 10 the model takes a cancer
that automatically I statistics for the
past week and for the past month in
cases larger history is required to be
analyzed for instance to identify
abnormal activity related to the close
closing causes or a year and then we
arrive at patterns of abnormal
activities not only in the next work
architecture but also the level of
application systems that are of interest
to the customer of course there are some
drawbacks of course for instance the
system requires the data be quite clean
that requires additional analysis on the
part of the data scientists to get some
additional logs involved and of course
it's also it also depends on the
competency of data scientists which by
the way according to the information
from Yandex
so within me I mean the de quoi demands
for such specialists has grown three
times has grown a threefold and in
conclusion I'd say that machine learning
is already used in quite a lot of
information security solutions it's
about getting protected from all sorts
of attacks attacks sand boxes analyzing
the code in some special conditions
including the changes in registry file
activity network activity this includes
a different system for instance hackers
also use machine learning as part of
fuzzing additional system that allow
analyzing and identifying
vulnerabilities and the classic approach
requires considerable time resources
machine learning and AI systems allow
reducing fuzzing computational
requirements to explore levels and of
course it's about processing a large
volumes of data which we need to
proactively respond to threats such as
in cyber security cyber intelligence we
need to analyze a lot of data when it's
analyze data from closed and open
sources we need to analyze how hacker
groups work what Nick nicknames were
used in underground for us how these
nicknames are related to one another how
connection graphs designed so as to
understand which specific information
security abilities threats exist for
this particular customer all this
requires analyzing huge volumes of data
so therefore for cyber intelligence
machine learning and AI are fully
applicable well that's all I want to say
just a small advertisement as part of
our positive half days we are drawing
tickets to RSA conference in Singapore
you will take part you need to
fill out a small questionnaire today at
4:00 p.m. the winner will be announced
in the main stage so get registered for
joined using this QR code and we'll be
waiting for you there
Thank You Dmitry questions to the
audience may be questions from the
audience maybe you have some doubts
regarding this technology so my question
is turns out that the quality model in
any way depends on the quality of data
that you fed to it am i right yes
exactly this indeed is a big problem and
because the source date can be
incomplete inaccurate they can contain
errors for instance when were analyzing
firewall dogs we identified that they
use simple you user could connect from
the RDP domain and start session it was
a clear breaking of information security
but this data were part of the initial
selection so the model of machine
learning showed us that there were
certain anomalies then it was done out
to the data scientists identified was if
it was a false positive or bad low
quality data that needed cleansing thank
you questions yesterday in the biometric
biometry session they give an example I
think it was a picture of some dog and
the were 70.7% of some structure edits
and as result machine learning would
issue a picture of a given so how to
identify such things because theythey
using specific example something may be
present that has got there by accident
how to understand that it's not a given
you're absolutely right perfect comment
yes indeed recently a lot of hacker
attack on physical infrastructure have
been made allowing them to cheat the
system a Tesla for instance I put
special labels on the lane there were
standard plastic squares but the machine
learning learning system perceived them
as a change in the street marking and
the Machine drove to the opposing lane
these are kind of had a hacker attack
the cookies you can put on a t-shirt
with a special QR code and personal with
this code will be will no longer be
perceived by information systems a human
there's an AI system forests built on
the premise that different machine
learning systems are compared so they
compete with each other and so the best
one is selected the better a model is
trained the better it is considered yes
so the drawbacks of the initial
selection is mostly related with the
size of data in it the more data we'll
have initially the better the quality
well I'm sorry but the question can't be
translated because the speaker is not
using the microphone
in our case for instance when analyzing
the file log what did we do to avoid
such situations firstly we had two
models model one was retrained it was
analyzing interactions of each user with
information system it was doing in a
retread mode and then this training mode
was no longer used in live operation but
the results of this analysis were used
for the operation of the second model if
we had information that the information
was recognized incorrectly by the first
model then the second model was trained
additionally so they had this feedback
loop my name is hello Demetri maybe I
missed out you shared a general concept
but can you share a specific experience
of specific implementation of this
mechanism in life would you use as log
connect how did you store them how did
you distribute your confusing I'll tell
a bit about that because unfortunately
were limited in time what did we do as
part of this research firstly we need to
collect the information from the special
connected Swiss for that different same
systems in our case we were using
connector aux ITSM then we needed to
normalize it initially Alysha
nominalization was done in two stages
firstly you as part of C format that was
we get ultimately from cm system and the
second normalization was based on our
platform the platform it was based on
the Hadoop ecosystem and it includes
such component in fi that did this
additional normalization the filtering
out unnecessary data the next phase was
to transmit this information after
different models where data analysts
would see which models work better
we used Gaussian distribution or this is
a model that
the performance very well we also create
more complex models for Bach sphere we
we needed to create a recommendation
system to recommend to recommend the
credit for what some was the maximum and
so on - what client and so on this is
implemented with different decision
trees and additional machine learning
algorithms that we also use an our
proactive protection systems another
questions question if I may
you gave us a good example that I would
like to it become more to be more
concrete more new applications can be
embedded into what your analyzed it
becomes senseless two years ago there
was a spike in the Europe technology in
the interest for this technology and it
changed the so fast that the analysts
couldn't keep up so now what's the
what's your prediction yes indeed that
was one of the problem so why did we
begin to create our own model or just
behavioral analytics Eby solutions are
good the eb e is good it is trained it
is it suits the needs fits the needs of
the majority of clients and it is
assumed that after two or three months
you begin to use it to decision-making
in our case it's much faster if we
decide that an employee is user or a
business trader we can we can make this
decision based on the logs within week
and that's a very good example that's a
very good result
[Music]
that's right it's one thing when we
consider machine learning as a system
that it complicates the landscape of
threats but it's a completely different
situation when we just use thresholds
the security administrator does not need
to think about unnecessary detail so we
have to know how to keep all the sub
supplementary I did was and accounts and
perhaps of the administrators have
certain perfect so that we can take and
decide decide whether or not an employee
is as privileged access so we can
determine the subscription but the more
we try to keep this information
up-to-date the more correlation rows we
have to write manually
machine learning allows us to create a
general rules the rules that fit the
majority of employees in which just set
the threshold that we need to analyze
that the figure of every single user or
do we need to analyze the groups of
users all we can raise this threshold
and we just need to let's say separate
the users of our company from the users
of other organizations Thank You Dmitry
we have a lot of hmm presenters you
could take you you can go back to you
see thank you very much
what the last question from the audience
is a nice segue to the next presentation
the the boundaries of what's possible
for behavioral analysis of information
flows he's going to tell us about mr.
from CTO of web control I'm going to
what the previous speaker has said
regarding the collection of a raw data
we didn't discuss this a lot so here's
what we're going to analyze but but what
do we analyze it is assumed that there's
a large geographically distributed
infrastructure and this infrastructure
contains a lot of information resources
a lot of activities and so on probably
part of this infrastructure is somewhere
in the cloud part of it may be
virtualized and how do we collect from
it primary data or rotater
the technology that I'm going to discuss
my presentation is exactly the
technology that's going to do that so
that does this I am going to mostly
focus on network infrastructure how do
you collect primary data from fresh
clothes
widespread standards NetFlow IP fix and
current versions of the standards allow
you to determine the set of metrics that
you select there is active network
equipment that generates network
telemetry so all the information flows
so that go through our information
structure goes through network equipment
and you network equipment can generate
this telemetry who went where we
download water of what data through what
ports and so on and what are we going to
do with this data well first of all we
need to collect this telemetry and one
place in some place of important place
of our infrastructure there is no it
wouldn't disappoint the expert of
network infrastructure you can place a
special probe in this place that can
that can generate this geometry from raw
network the next task is to ensure
real-time access or fast access to this
vastness data provide search capability
since one and on top of it use it for
what the previous speaker talked about
machine learning maybe other
technologies
so what can we accomplish doing this we
can say that if we can say that the
primary teacher does not depend on our
infrastructure everything changes and
new equipment appears becomes and all
the Whitman goes and this network
includes its own life if we had if you
had the experts of geometry and into the
standard configuration we would cut
ourselves we save ourselves the
dependence on little poetry since
network telemetry is quite lightweight
we can collect all the telemetry and in
one place and analyze it as a whole we
will never end up in a situation when
the direction between two nodes of the
network it was in one place the other
will be enlightened in other place of
course we can parallelize this we can
distribute these computations but
primary data can be collected in one
place then we can need different trends
we can plan the infrastructure and so on
if we have statistics over a long period
of time we can see where the bandwidth
is not enough where our resources are
overloaded overstressed and the most
important thing that we are all talking
about today is the analysis of these
information flows the use of different
algorithms
different algorithms and the incident
response I was responding to incidents
that have been I'm not going to spend
much time on the modern trends of course
one of these trances being is increased
traffic to the mountains equipment is
grown SNMP monitoring are becoming less
and less chaotic over time if we try to
grab all network traffic you won't have
you won't have any capacity to process
it even with machine lorian's you won't
be able to crunch it so I believe that
the system for the analysis of network
telemetry are promising technologies
that will allow us to to be successful
in the future also it should be said
that inter network marketers share of
devices that are able to generate this
and photometry is growing also received
growth in the amount of this equipment
that can customize what kind of
telemetry you want customized what
character limitary you get so as the
previous colleague has said
an important foundation of a parallel
sister often what is profiling it means
that you choose a certain object and
then you will define a set of metrics
for these objects and then you collect
these metrics if we have a set of these
profiles so we can compare them to each
other over time and we can compare these
profiles with known anomalies with known
spreads and with known dangerous is
behavioral patterns so the next question
you want to ask of course is what are we
going to profile we have a large zoo and
how do we choose the right thing from
the zoo what we want to profile the
different behavioral analysis systems
allow you to profile different things
starting from network nodes all the way
to network hubs all the way to more
complicated things so four parameters
some network equipment can generate for
example n bar to application tags or you
can you can create these profiles of for
applications with secure applications
what are the metrics so starting from
the standard ones such as the amount of
data transfer ports several drivers
the use of different information
services and thesaurus research is Dina
DHCP AARP and so on there is no point
for some URL it's not it doesn't make
sense to measure the amount of data sent
over URL if it's just so if it's just
some service that doesn't interest us at
all so we ended up needing a compromise
it is impossible to profile everything
because that's gonna require just you
know the bottom resources metric so you
can store all the metrics so that s too
much data you are able to process it and
another important point is how much time
do we spend to its keep these profiles
but what if our reporting is once a year
do we need to keep these profiles for
the entire year
on one hand well that would be the
obvious solution however some system
allow you to create a time table for the
different for example the last freaking
day of every year is an anomaly
anomalous activity in some application
and that's no no
so of course you can you can do
different things so you can strike the
right balance between the amount of data
and the fullness of data and equality Oh
what tasks what problems can your so
love using this approach oh that's quite
obvious you can you can create maps of
networking you can create trends you can
detect all sorts of different anomalies
nevertheless unfortunately there's no
button doing everything right here now
and well of course you will need to have
expertise on data analysts or data
scientists and so on so forth so you'll
still need some humans in the loop and
nevertheless in what applied areas you
do these behavioral analysis
technologists work well I have come to
believe that through the use of the
model if you create the right model you
can recover all the applied areas of
course for every area terrific
infrastructure you need to to create a
custom solution some networks have more
did you determined that flows such as
SCADA corporate networks always
determined how much deterministic
in death centers and corporate networks
at a purposes of this analysis may be
different if in corporate even corporate
networks we want to find malware a a
network provider may not be interested
in looking for viruses it's not very
critical for the provider and the
behavioral analysis algorithms will be
different as a conclusion of my
presentation I'd like to focus on what
you need to take into account if you
want to introduce behavioral analysis
you need to focus on the quantitative
parameters such as the load that the
system will with will be able to handle
the threat model that's the second thing
what we were afraid of what we want to
look for 1 2 and what type of
infrastructure we have then we choose
what we're going to profile which use
the set of amid a set of metrics and we
choose for how long we store the data so
we based on based on that we'll make our
choice thank you Pavel Thank You puggle
nobody wants to ask a question well this
topic is so quite and trendy everybody
keeps talking about behavioral analysis
some or try some even try to deploy it
or people try to create analytics so
where this is going to work how to use
these templates and what to do with it
well I made an overview of systems I
have been involved in behavioral
analysis of network flows since 2010 and
everything I've shared so far is just a
snapshot of for what there is out there
in the market so what I have discussed
is doable is doable using the existent
with existence solutions in the market
thank you very much for the presentation
my question is this okay what if clients
are mostly most interested in what do
they want to analyze most from Network
you know telemetry what clients what
plans
well enterprise corporate corporate it
starts with anomaly detection is looking
for is Jumel we're looking for champions
in other words in terms of traffic in
terms of visiting certain URLs looking
for attackers or hackers within the
corporate network okay all right thank
you Paul
I'll come back to you later the next
speaker is about battalions expert of
Microsoft he will talk about the
non-trivial topic that although we
introduce a lot of different systems but
for some odd reasons we all the time we
run up against problems hi everybody my
name is bum Lord in the Tech Center Oh
Microsoft Microsoft Excel future works
in architecture and division most of my
time I spend talking to the client
through this - the biggest most
established Russian customer so
and I press the button and they get the
results okay
and I listen to them and them is the
story I fear perhaps not from every
inference but every other what and by
the way let's do a warm-up PDMS in this
room raise your hand 1 2 3 well to a few
because my message my message is going
to pay for them ok but I believe in you
you will take this message I carry this
message forward here's the story ok a
top manager attends a conference Sultan
and the gospel Sultan paints a beautiful
picture of the future and then the CEO
comes back in reached and has great
ideas that are going to be good for the
company
in terms in terms of transformation
these persons is the sole enthuse term
goes to his colleagues share ideas and
everybody says well that's so great we
all everybody needs everybody's happy
and they have even found the budget but
there is one really small formal step to
get approval from this weird guy we are
department that does security and then
there is this boring guy from the
security department my desk right here
it says no you can't use oh why why does
he say so well because you can
understand him from the point of view of
humans
ok ok you have decided to transform
business without ok I'm going to show
you how to transform this transfer and
just get this but the business decision
maker doesn't like being told so he says
but who are you
they use my money I earned this money I
create all sorts of ID to earn money to
pay paycheck for you by the way and you
were telling me this
ok I'm going to it and you end up
an award the business is not this but
this story is pretty a pretty frequent I
I keep hearing stories like this all the
time but if we okay reset human emotion
society if we think about why security
professionals are so conservative we
will see if we analyze that these people
these people are trying to retain their
point of control because without it
nothing will work out what's better for
a bank not to have a mobile bank or to
have a mobile vendor that will be pried
open with a nail and hackers will be
practicing on it the answer is clear is
there any Universal answer to this is a
button to me everything is not yet on
porous so in Microsoft we were unhappy
to think about we have a hundred and
eighty thousand employees throughout the
world they crazy
geeks as they take these security
systems systems around the world and we
have we do have things to to protect IP
money and so on the work of security was
not fail but worse than hell
[Music]
you I don't know or the universal word
Universal answer to that could be but
I'm going to share with you what we have
done and what I'm saying when I'm
talking about how we see information
security I always point people to what
we have done because I can only share
what we have done our personally so when
we transplant our information security
into this Center combating cyber threats
we focused three on three things first
organizational aspects to determine it
abroad and if you want the mission of
this security service and people and the
third support is techno enable and
technologists and in my presentation I
am NOT going to say anything about
technologists well how's it possible and
here's a guy from Microsoft and not
saying anything about technology that's
right well my my boss has told me not to
just joke you would agree with me that
technology is the best way to solve a
conflict between business and security
so the security guys say you can do it
and the business say we need this we
need that this approach doesn't worry it
doesn't work it's not all the solved
using money so focus on people
people are going to make you secure yes
technologies technologies are important
technologies are important there are a
very many technologies we have
technologies that people have what
technologies you're going to use depends
on what you feel comfortable is living
with it doesn't matter whether you're
going to use some electric instrument
them tool or some I don't know any other
instrument the only thing that matters
is the end result organizational aspect
the first and the most important task is
to ask them what they are here for and
then ask and then ask the business
inventor
ask them what they think security the
security department he is for you won't
believe how different these answers are
how how far away so they are from each
other if the security guys tell you that
we are to answer the questions of the
Federal Security Service well that's a
position but remember you need another
structure that will be in charge of
protecting against the separators
because somebody has to do it after all
no the answer in FSB khalsa but in terms
of business it has to be a constant with
a security center the security
operations center what is important for
the business money IP reputation to
market share the trust of the client
center and back you are going some
business intelligence friends were being
attacked with we are under attack and
the attackers are trying to get at
something we wouldn't even imagine Hey
business guys do you know what that
means perhaps something changed in the
market that's the information that can
the associate provide to the business
business outside of the house so I
believe yes indeed we need to conduct
union and conduct exercises
twice maybe three times a year just like
fire evacuation exercises so let's say
for example we are in a serious
situation we have we have I don't know a
serious incident what we do and if this
incident indeed happens happens we have
to decide who is going to be the point
of contact who is going to coordinate
this collaboration between the business
departments and the security guys if
there is some minor or suspicion that
there's an enormous activity no there is
no there's no need to raise alarm but
but if there's something serious then of
course the business the department need
to know
about this as soon as possible culture
culture is of course an important aspect
because without this as they say
corporate culture you know is is a cult
corporate culture has all sorts of
regulations for breakfast
please use people wisely don't ask them
to do some routine stupid things that
could be automated do not dump
everything you can everything you can on
the people just to keep their heads
clear unfortunately human beings are not
machine learning models that that a
better off that feel better the more
data you feed into it so it's the other
way around with human beings so if you
ask humans to create some stupid reports
just because they have always been done
yes they will be done but but that
doesn't put you in a better position so
teamwork teamwork is an important thing
teamwork not only within soc between the
different analyzed within it but also
with all sorts of Reddington pen testers
and perhaps you can think of creating a
purple team you've probably heard about
this term raise your hand if you've
heard this yeah there are some some
people that know what a purple team is
this is to conduct research just
remember in your infrastructure research
and third is
training very often in investigations
you're left with some gaps gaps of
unclarity or uncertainty these gaps of
uncertainty are the most interesting
things that's where you need to look for
that's what is where you need to
concentrate all your analytical
resources after the incident has been
resolved but they unless go there and
review these gaps will visit them and
try to make sure that that this
uncertainty is resolved matrix as a rule
everybody saying is great in so so when
how we're going to measure this the
performance of s shock operation and
business likes measuring things we have
a set of simple metrics attempt to
furnish time to mediate a number of
remediated incidents by the way
separately manually and automatically
and the number of escalations between
levels so the combination of the last
two things will allow us to identify if
some level of our stock overloaded if it
is like all the load is taken by a level
one analyst and the rest is not used
enough oh maybe the other way around
there escalating incidents all the time
at a level two level three analysts are
overloaded whereas a level one people
are just shifting their load than others
to understand the reason maybe some
competencies are lacking maybe you
should modify the organization's and the
overall stock model looks quite
traditional
the tier one supports results in most
incidents where they define what
specifically happens if we escalation or
escalated highest level to t3 mostly is
mostly busy during correcting work
preparing for attacks that have not yet
happened
but the information from all three tiers
can and must get into the automation
tools so we need to shift as many items
as possible to the category of well
known attacks that will not require
massive employment of human resources
but rather be handled through automation
tools motive s if you look higher than
so we can say that on the one hand we
need an internal incident management
team because people who have been in the
major disaster situation will appreciate
that the situation is quite nervous IT
people start coming to security
specialists and start you know thrashing
about asking work so when exactly you're
going to fix everything it was specific
when when and when you should have
dedicated people for them to turn to
because other ones have to have clear
heads and work so there should be some
point of contact prearranged so that
people could go to and these people
should understand how to do business how
to interact maybe with the press if it's
needed and so on so forth
and a threat intelligence the thing that
so you can't have enough you shouldn't
just restrict yourself to just
yourselves get in touch with external
vendors get as much information as you
can
it's very important so therefore if you
get two ways of conducting investigation
hut-1 and a cold one hot one is like
something has happened has happened in
that infrastructure the cold one is that
we've learned from the internet and deep
we're both from anywhere else that this
thing is becoming relevant let's try and
model this attack simulate this attack
on our infrastructure do a POC
investigation maybe develop some
automation tools that will help us get
protected from this kind of attack unit
before we actually encounter it so what
are the action items for me to you or
say to you I mean representatives or
business units so firstly transform your
security team beforehand the earlier you
do it the easier is going to be for you
looking forward and the less painful oh
well this business transformation
approaches we first transform the
security team and then transform your
business focus on people people rather
than technologists will make your life
safe and secure there are no technology
in the market that would have a make it
safe for me buttons and everything will
define more than that we have a lot of
movies that attempts to make such a
system can lead to the emergence of
Skynet with terminators but don't rely
on this people first and thirdly involve
security team early so it's not to allow
a situation where everybody has already
done everything and there was only
little steps
to make forward thank you Thank You van
it's quite important that this year we
have the slogan breaking the constants
and actually the vector is shifting if
the past I was saying here's a machine
let's learn people to use it so they
could move from manual day but
automation then we implemented lots of
technologies were saying that one
technology is better than another one
replacing people and now we're coming
back to people again back I think this
is quite an important aspect that
security is really about people well
you're welcome to a booth and we'll give
you some paper posters firstly with this
slogan and secondly with our vision of
how we believe you should go bus service
security in the right way thank you
thank you any questions no questions
thank you very much as they say there
was a good joke the cost the price of
observing the observer is much higher
than that of observing the process and
now we're going to talk to Dimitri Conti
Belgium cunt about GM at staff called
regarding the analysis of employee
observation this is a hot topic every
year it evokes an explosive interest in
both parties do we have DLP implement
your sitting as desk at work it says do
they have DLP running and if yes then
what is it doing and the security system
well we've introduced DLP and what
should we observe to see the things that
are a real interest well colleagues good
afternoon
let me introduce myself once again my
name is Dmitry candy bhavish am head of
staff cook and today we're going to talk
about employee control controlling the
users who are in the network I'll try to
briefly explained the subject area and
then I'll do a FAQ on DLP and other
technologies and I'll say a few words
pitfalls and at the end I'll touch upon
the question which is very important for
users it's about legal aspects okay the
first thing I wanted to mention that we
have both internal internal threats and
part of some avenges are focusing more
on external threats from such abstract
hackers others focus on insiders we take
this statistic and spend some time on it
will see that in actual life of a number
of external attacks is growing on the
one hand because darknet is growing a
lot of students joined a darknet and
there are quite a lot of attacks that
don't really have any malevolent intent
just for fun well that has the market of
espionage industrial espionage is
growing very fast so we always face the
risk related to our employees so we
argued with our colleagues and peers and
our opinion is that with every year
hacking a system is becoming more and
more difficult and basically
novices like students would have hard
time breaking a Cisco firewall so
therefore it is becoming easier to rely
on social engineering extortion and
things like that because you know here
people are people and in our opinion of
the shift is now going towards humans as
the weak link in the security
environment I would now mention the
risks that are linked to people inside
firstly a very promising token is the
company that doesn't belong to the
company and users may not always agree
with the company
it can be an eaglet negligence so it can
be just made a malevolent intent and the
second thing is that people may you know
skip working at the workstations if you
don't control them I would know the
internal fraud because it's so unique
and people have very good you know
imagination but this is one of the big
things a large company regardless of the
line of business internal fraud is there
you can't ignore its and there's a risk
group that me you need to keep track of
just understand how they behave and I
mean if you observe people behavior you
can identify these risk groups they go
for fraud this is one of the vectors
threat vectors not really the latest
data I decided that it's quite enough so
here we have a list of leakage channels
periphery devices printers and the
network was about a fence that the bane
of security system is mobile devices
with cameras that I brought sober
employees inside the perimeter perimeter
nobody knows how to do it other than
using the old way of just taking away
the phone as you enter the organization
there are some tools that say we can
protect at least understand who made
pictures and which user had some
documents but they all they operate
under certain conditions and the there
are no products like that in the Russian
market and they're quite expensive
so the trend is to steal using a mobile
device and if the user also actually
keeping an eye on users through cameras
and pictures laughter the best way and
it's difficult to fight this kind of
fraud regarding approach there are two
approaches that we encounter in
companies either everything is learning
company so businesses know we're not
going to block anything let people do
what they do use any information
channels it improves customer relations
because customers are comfortable using
whatsapp for instance the other approach
is the other extremity where you ban
everything creates a whitelist of
applications of internet sites and
people are only allowed to use the
channel of communications that are
available so when you press people that
has it's exactly the situation where
they attempted to take the camera the
other way is the other extreme area
extremis extremity extremity is where
people know just to do all sorts of odd
things and you need to do a lot of work
tracking them all sorts of logs if
everybody is going to use all sorts of
messages you won't be able to intercept
them you can only use key loggers or
something like that
Akeelah if use a similar project mass
for a thousand machines you won't even
be able to help to muster the resources
to keep it under control I think there
should be a trade-off away
to be used some of the functional
functional blocks others should be
regulated and you always have to be
aware of a thing called a hole in the
fence Francia can't block telegram you
you block but you can't control you tell
your colleagues that we don't use web
mail from the workstation and use the
cloud because it's not allowed and then
you release like a rumor saying this
channel is still opening with the
recognition say it isn't and then you
can just open logs on dawkins being sent
to web to web mail and easily take
incidents out there or if and yeah if
you say people you can't use telegram
and launch it you viewer you may not
restrict them from access but you can
keep an eye on them as soon as somebody
opens up telegram ourselves doing them
just the fact of using telegram would be
enough to make them eligible for the
risk group so that he should apply logs
and monitor their activities just a few
words about it a couple of words about
looking how we presented ourselves as
monitoring system that's why our
colleague from DLP don't like this
content blocking doesn't work from my
experience even though there are people
who would never be with me why don't
they want everyone else about false
positives if you have a lot of false
positives
it must be divided by the time about the
number of people processing of this
these incidents in real time to allow
reject the content considering how many
people have the security services and in
IT departments two or three people at
max so even if you have even a 500 users
then your business process was off for a
day so business will just ban you doing
that
so content-based blockings don't really
work
they only work for a small segments of
the networks and if you have some
valuable information you can only
restrict you to certain perimeter and
set up looking there
so channels blow channel blocking it
works better because as I explained the
whole in defense principles for looking
I think labels work best when you tag
the information let's see how valuable
for them for you and us set up
restrictions for this information to be
accessed by users so a person for
instance can run a certain document only
in verb in words and not any other tools
so the blocking works at the tag or
label level if we take IT people
security people until security people
the effect of blocking is a good thing
you've locked and no problem but if we
talk about a security service even a
sending a letter with an important
anymore with an important attachment is
just the break of regulation of the
company won't be able to prove that it
was really a something that person
something serious so security people
need to have a pool a full body of
evidence this by the way is about
looking and content analysis is quite a
compute intensive thing those people who
don't do P and then they perfectly know
how user desktops start working slowly
if lots of such programs run and them so
this approach a content-based blocking
is going out of practice for all these
restrictions so much about channels and
information leaks
the second approach is about timekeeping
work timekeeping people start thinking
about that especially business because
if we take look at the exhibition for
the past three years when you ask people
are you interested in time work
timekeeping they used to say no now
eight out of ten say yes so the business
is trying is starting to look for points
of growth so what's this slide about so
we're sitting around the table those
guys from IT IT security and we had a
discussion about IT budgets how to get
them how to persuade the management to
me as a lawyer and a speaker I have one
kind of model so my brain works in y
direction technical guys for them
numbers and finance things that they
don't quite understand so as a
discussion we arrived at second sentence
that any process can be translated to
the language of expenses and benefits
and business intelligence when you say
it's the problem of performance and they
say yeah I know I have half of the
people who are lazy bones but they don't
notice the scale I am showing some
statistic that shows the scale of
problems it was an anonymous poet haba
haba people ask how much time do you use
in your worst fate in a workstation I
usually ask other workaholics in the
room there are six people like this
other people in the room who allow a
couple of hours a day for personal
development for reading reading some
professional editions the whole room
usually raises their hands and listen
visitors and other people who come to
work and spend half their time at the
desk or maybe just drinking tea and
smoking nobody says yes but anonymous
polls say that there are 60 people like
this one we try to explain this to
business they start thinking about this
but because people doing business
really are not really good at
calculating we offer them in an
opportunity of translating this data
into money if we don't take this extreme
which is saying that half people in this
room it doesn't work in the workplace we
can just calculate how business would
much more business would lose if people
spend two hours a day not working so we
take this picture and the most important
thing here is that so
it's about multiplying two things
these are losses related to business not
being able to control large departments
when they see that those numbers they
started standing at a scale problem so
we don't use this light to speak about
lost profits actually you could make
this formula make this algorithm much
more sophisticated but the reason I'm
invoking this is that any risk can be
translated in to specific numbers same
thing and selling any IT product you can
say how much it will cost your company
if servers are down
it cannot be translated into money terms
so it's so about my claim that any idea
project should we translate into the
language of money now about
functionality firstly a couple words
there are gateway based systems battery
stolen gateways unfortunately that time
is up almost up because you will only be
able to control the email with the
clouds and second system is patient
endpoints endpoints a good thing
collects lots of data not only about the
movement information but also about
programming started audio
messaging it covers the entire
functionality so what's up it is can we
encounter here if you are purchasing a
solution that based on the thick client
and most product unfortunately have this
huge technology
Taylan companies experienced
difficulties in just as severing they're
cutting it away so if you buy a solution
based on modern technology SAS not in
terms of the server being stolen
premises but a customer being fair
connected to the to the network so you
get the opportunity of collecting this
information that without logging every
device
the second thing another thing is that
these systems don't consume enough
resources everybody of you haven't got a
situation that you've drawn up your
budget and paper in licenses and other
things and as a result your spending is
much higher because you haven't
completely and consider the
infrastructure the database hardware and
also the service of those are going to
do that the big problem with the OB
system is that they're costly and they
need hard hard well the vector of import
substitution has been taken us by
because we understood that the future is
with open source so we have about to
have post press we now subsidies click
house and it is it has become possible
to bypass all the difficulties by
selecting fully open source products
another big boon about this technology
is that we have an open stack and when
the server side is open you can take any
data to either download or upload data
for instance use domain v ID
or for timekeeping furnaces you can
synchronize it with the Outlook calendar
so there are two challenges here the
infrastructure being expensive which
discourages people to use the LPS and
complexity of its a setting up talking
about NPO the best things is you start
being able to see what people are doing
with the information documents you you
can make a shadow copy of everything and
you can set up alerts on the content of
the files also it's a pure DLP saying
it's within the competence of IT and IT
security but an experience shows
internal fraud for to fight internal
flow the classic DLP is not enough so
any business owner know isn't a business
owner is going to spend their money on a
DLP if it doesn't address the biggest
problems the functionality mentioned
here messaging control microphones
camera so these tools have become
absolutely indispensable tools used in
DOP so this these logs are used for
security people outside pure IT security
so for instance you can't a large
company is a big company and say do you
use microphone control they said no so
you've collected this log it it's being
stored is good
it's can usually be defined by common
config files so what can do with this
long log file firstly a you become
capable to run incident investigations
to understand the dynamic who was
involved it's very good things
a second thing if you have a large log
file no just allow you to visualize it
so you can take a look at dependencies
between different employees you can take
a look you can track the distribution of
documents you can see outliers so it
works very well
specific DLP that keeps an eye on a
certain document as then a person you
know resigns from the company I start
downloading information if there's no
document there you won't be able to
confirm this but if you set up your
anomaly for the email or for the ESP
device and the cloud you can identify
like for instance the person has never
used the cloud and then they start to
upload a huge amount of data this
approach works very very well
alongside specific rules of document
management these widgets offer your
great opportunity to process large
volatile data and identify risk groups
if an incident has already happened it's
clear identified investigated but you
also need to work proactively and these
things are just like big data
visualization is a big helper to our
security officers and of course it's
very difficult to do it all manually
considering especially that you don't
have enough people of course automatic
alerts need to be there oh that's can be
the set up in DLP buy masks that's one
thing also you can set them up to target
any event of interest to you for
instance you are interested in sending
some documents from the digital archive
using web mail so you said you described
this event you set it up in the filter
and every time it happens again you'll
be getting an alert also anomalies may
not make me depend on just some
activities that you don't allow also we
collect information about the work time
control it's a very useful thing even
Faye's when people are taking a free
pallet for several months they get great
consulting and audit of the to identify
the worst people in their organization
so basically this smoke a little bit of
consulting can strongly affect your work
and punish the perpetrators and at least
a you can bring a beautiful report to
your management after this pilot with
specific losses assessed so the last
area is about endpoint machines you can
remotely manage them you can download
enough information you can set up port
blocking blocking the capability to
connect additional devices this is the
base set of tasks that goes way beyond
DLP it actually allows a working over
the program for several departments HR
for instance security ports and systems
that will be for IT so this approach let
me know proceed to what concerns are
calling the most the legal component of
having such a system implemented
unfortunately in this country we have
not too many judicial practices to
exchange no consist a gray zone on the
one hand we have laws that directly not
allow us to control personal information
it's in the criminal code it was
unconstitutional but I would like to
also point out that the government has
started moving in this direction
propose a law that's going to be a read
soon that better explains so what
special means are if you look at the
footnote it better explains what it may
be this can be a technical devices can
be a piece of software that yes that has
the properties of being able to collect
information correctly so yeah if it gets
passed then that complicates things but
the most important documents regulating
the relationship between the employee
and the employer is the labor law so we
are in very tight conditions so the
criminal code only concerns personal
information so you have to be able to
you have to be able to transition or
transfer personal into public into kind
of service so you can be able to monitor
information in terms of compliance
compliance with anti-corruption law
antitrust laws as soon as you give a
person a paper that says that okay we
have commercial secrets we'll be able to
monitor for this so we have to monitor
the technical communication
and channels and the person should
expressly agree as that he doesn't mind
being monitored and this document should
also say that the person agrees that he
or she will be a reliable for you know
transferring information and channels
along the channels that not a service
then that person will be a subject to
reliability but okay this is just a
document as well let the persons know
that there won't be any unchecked
surveillance it's just going to be a
document waiting the person know that
the information must be protected and
the employer reserves the right to
monitor the compliance with these
non-disclosure agreements so if you want
to use it to increase efficiency and to
prevent the motivation you can do this
as an icon in d'etre if so the person
the person should be confident that this
surveillance this surveillance is within
reasonable limits it's
is not not excessive and you can display
all sorts of notifications and the
trades and so on and the person has to
be confident that the logs should never
be should never be given to court or
anything or any other for any other
organizations or law enforcement
unfortunately many companies do this in
a covert fashion so in other words they
don't even know wet as they don't they
don't announce to the employees that
they are under surveillance and yes you
can do so but if there is a breach of
security or something a stolen you will
not be able to go to court and present
your evidence that you have collected
while in doing surveillance on the print
on the person or on your employees I
have talked about this colleagues if you
if you surveil your employees of course
you have to keep this a secret
and if you do do so if you do choose to
surveil your employees openly then you
have to of course protect yourself by
having them signed so-called documents
so everybody everybody I mean every
employee of your company should be
completely aware that he or she is being
monitored so there should be a consensus
between the employee and the employer
any questions I see there are lots of
questions quick questions okay are there
any ways to monitor file shares no we
don't have any crawlers because we don't
know how to accomplish to implement a
technologically okay a person's sticks a
flash disk into a USB port and what else
[Music]
it's it's not clear how to how to handle
those cases we take data from husb
devices and you can even connect to a
specific computer if you are doing an
incident response or if you do it
investigation we don't use crawlers for
cloud services such as a Google cloud
gdpr
is a serious hurdle here so perhaps by
by the fall we will be able to deploy
something but not now
pain isn't a person does with Network
folders you will be able to see this but
we only create shadow copy of a document
if the person has tampered with these
documents we're we don't consider this
in any serious way now the CTO of Wacom
two hours ago in the out of room they
were there was a question about GOP
phobia so so what a feature said can be
offered to VIPs to companies top
managers that just don't don't want to
let anyone in on their data thank you
very much for the question yes that's a
very relevant question it has a
technical dimension and other dimensions
many VIPs are Mac OS Mac OS is a closed
system it's a proprietary system it is
impossible to embed loggers such as to
any loggers voice recorders and it's
very hard to technically control VIPs in
fact the main is a and by the way they
pose the main threat of the main risk
because they have access to money and
direct access to money if there are no
technical problems so then the next
question is who is the customer if the
customer is the owner or if the offer is
a shareholder they will of course will
be monitoring VIPs in the first place
but if the customer took the top
managers themselves they will be
controlling anyone but themselves that
is that
a problem for the security department
yes but the problem is briefly is real
it is relevant a ok move all discuss
these questions by at the end of our
sessions if you have more questions
please come to our booth and I'll be
happy to take your questions ok
we will go back to the principle of
breaking the constant very few people
know that in order to maintain in order
to create a city for hackers here with
noise with parallel networks so that it
is impossible to find a target all of
that requires a lot of computational
resources and fast systems I'd like to
invite here and record in skill of a
wooden system he will talk about data
storage systems at the present the
company and I'd like to say that this
standoff was now organized by violence
and everything works very well
good afternoon please don't go away it's
gonna be more presentation this is not
the most boring one of them okay we have
happy to provide our debt storage system
for this event I'm here for the first
time and really impressed I'm impressed
by the scale by the number of
participants and vendors and partners
and indeed we we provided our solar
system it's the most high-performance
it's the fastest perhaps you're you're
not from the right audience but anyway
when I talk to customers I had realized
that the business people security guys
they play important role so security is
one of their consumers and one of the
customers and one of the main
clubs that make sure that everything
works oil company company violent has
been on the market has been active in
the market since 2000 since 2005 it has
created the fastest that storage system
originally it was an in-memory storage
system without any hard drives and since
then with this company violin has been
actually developed in this concept and
just a year ago this company became
really ramping up its activities it
became more and more popular so
everywhere you need high performance
that's the system of choice well a
certain time ago hybrid system disk
systems were quite popular they were
cheap but they were slow now but the
required performance requirements for
input/output has really increased and it
is important it is important to kind of
keep up with these requirements and
that's where our new system the violin
system comes in this company is a
company that has developed all of its
solutions in house it is mostly software
however the hardware platform has been
developed by violin flash module also
designed or manufactured by Toshiba
using the
violin designs $400,000,000 open
investors been invested well the company
has developed kind of with different
speeds in different years and Igor has
said that infrastructure here he is
infrastructure that we have here is
based on violin and all the companies
organisations and businesses why they
think about data they're only concerned
about two things I'm not even talking
about responsibility we're talking about
speed we're talking about archiving
tasks then we only that we're only
interested in the price and the amount
of data between the capacity you know if
you look like a you know net up they
come to and asks of who our clients are
we have a lot of clients because of
course you don't use violin to create
your own infrastructure you only use it
for analytics for high load high
performance databases so you only use it
for a certain segment of your
infrastructure we have Russian customers
we have foreign companies in the UK in
the United States and Turkey let me tell
you about one case how the company got
to be how it came to be and
at first the engineers that were at the
beginning of the company as they created
the fastest storage system and then they
decided to find who may need such a
system then they came to Walmart that
needed to calculate to the inventory
remainders that was in 2006 6000 sk use
6000 stores and 15 million sk use so
that's a huge huge amount of data and
entries Walmart in fact them did all the
RNG itself it had its own R&D department
they could solver this problem in eight
hours and then a violin came and told
them you don't need to change anything
you don't need to rate write the code
just change the storage system and they
were able to solve the problem in three
hours instead of eight hours
now of course the load is much larger
and when logisticians makers send
these angled trucks and of course you
can get these benefits in terms of
savings of course I took time to get
this system up to the performance level
that it can deliver now so that the
savings are significant in the range of
several million dollars and many
customers are many customers like a
violin and polymer / steel containers to
you as a violin so violin in fact is
major player and high performance data
storage systems so what do analysts say
the violin has cooperated for a long
time with I just see it is a it is a
famous analytics provider they analyzed
consulting servers anything and that's
that's a quote as you can see on the
slide you can see the quote of the vice
president of ideas here Eric Bergner and
ITC in fact predicts that is gonna be a
sharp increase in the performing
performance requirements for storage
systems so flash storage systems are not
enough there needs to be a next
generation extreme performance extreme
performance or systems with a latency of
less than 100 microseconds
that can handle 2.5 million operations
per second so that's it we have a booth
here lever stand encourage you to visit
us I'd like to thank the organizers for
installing our equipment here and
testing whether it's how it can perform
given the load well I hope that
everything went without a hitch but I
mean of course we will request to get
the technical parameters and then we
will perhaps will perhaps feature on our
website how great of a jump we we did
that's VHD Thank You Andrey Andrey is
will stick around if you have any
questions you can come to his state all
right well we're gonna change gears
we'll talk about internetwork screens
which love goes deeper for Jeanette
systems engineer will tell us about a
simple simple web application firewall
colleagues hi my name is Gustav
Kirchhoff I'm a systems engineer at
fortunate today I'd like to tell you
about
the unique characteristics of a modern
web application firewall why they are
trending up or why are they so popular
so let's start with the basic problems
that are encountered
according to Verizon genetics and
positive technologies
virtually every third or even every
second application has vulnerabilities
that can be exploited by attackers even
if even if it's exploited the user may
not know it it can be used this exploit
can be used to infect a website or an
application for example last year a
group of attackers in effect to the
website in the United States it was a
bank website there
of the transactions were made by the
clients of the band and the hackers just
collected a small cut from all of those
transactions they decided not to take a
one thousandth of a percentage point but
they decided to take one hundredth but
then they were caught so finding those
exploits of finding those
vulnerabilities may take months and
patching them is not so straightforward
it's it cannot be automated it cannot be
solved fast and firewall applications
are constantly developing and they're
engaging the functions that they didn't
have before
this slide shows that of several basic
criteria that a modern oil Web
Application Firewall must have okay the
first one is machine Lorien it's not
it's not something that yes I think of
its own it exists everywhere this
popular in healthcare security and
research and so on but if you look at
the specific use case of a Web
Application Firewall you can create this
graph let's say for example I have
samples that are clean if there is a
threshold so we can threshold these
samples if they are below a certain
threshold and they are clean if they are
above a certain threshold then they are
potentially anomalous that's a telltale
sign to the administrator to the
administrator that this may be a threat
and at the second threshold the traffic
should be blocked so we can use all
sorts of parameters we can block
specific types of traffic post requests
get requests and so on and so forth we
can use very many different renders then
we create a model that takes all values
alone all of these parameters as we fit
into the model and then we test it what
does it mean instructive algorithm
it means that this algorithm makes sure
that the model performs as designed as
intended and then we deployed to
production we see let's say for example
we have users that make legitimate
requests this traffic goes through and
then the user uses some special symbol
in physical request it isn't normally
but it doesn't mean that is some
malicious Gordon and if a user makes a
database request and it it is packaged
as a get request of course this will be
blocked as an anomalous hardware
acceleration that's the second most
important thing that a web application
for home needs very many customers
complain that software that the software
cannot handle the load all the
processing is done on CPU every security
function is implemented on CPU in order
to offload the CPU different chips used
such as a six Asics are
kind of restricted instructions that
chips that perform rather fast but
they're cheap asacs Asics are faster
than fuel program monkey doing array and
we use with it ships in conjunction with
chips we use encryption ssl RSA 3G RSA
256 IES hundred and twenty eight and the
trick here is not to use the processing
capacity the compute capacity of your
CPU but on dedicated chips such as a six
that's how we offload as a CPUs now
let's look at this Kemetic of a modern
web application firewall we can use some
additional chips so we can use USB ports
or some other ports management ports and
our chips that the network interfaces
are the link to the network traffic will
be processed on the chips and then these
chips transfer information already
processed to the CPU so the CPU is not
overloaded and then API protection
that's a very relevant relevant question
these days because api's are extremely
popular these days many organizations
many services work based on an API there
are very many data exchange formats the
most popular of them are XML HTML and
JSON all the parameters of these data
transfer protocols
be screened by wvf but not all web
application firewalls can handle all the
formats of course we should check with
the parameters are within tolerance with
the DES values that are contained in
these JSON XML and other containers we
can use mathematical models another
interesting function is the support of
correlation and multi protocols such as
HTTP HTTP web socket and FTP I've seen
projects where two protocols can be used
so they used to both WebSockets and HTTP
is not all web application firewalls can
support WebSockets if we don't support
the WebSockets and we have a we have a
gap in our security so good Web
Application Firewall must be able to
handle all these different protocols
such as HTTP HTTP web socket and FTP
didn't be able to aggregate events into
a common incident and create row WAF
rules directly from the event blogger
integration with third-party solutions
modern wife waves should be able to to
transfer files into sandbox solutions to
be able to integrate with NGH w
so if you get some emails for example
they should be rounded to the sandbox
check their and a clean message should
be forwarded to the recipient and if it
was an affected email then it should be
a quarantined
WAF is a collection of different
protection functions including IP
reputation DDoS attack protection
protocol correctness checks the modern
trends is kind of becoming more more
fashionable to use these WAFS and I
represent other company that offers
these WAF WAF site development around
the world and in our country colleagues
if sir any questions I'll be happy to
take them
well there are no more questions thank
you well I'm sure there'll be questions
when the customers all starts rolling it
out okay thank you
we're rolling session we have final
presentation it segues from well to
application security statistical code
analysis practice and theory a
represents over security the other stuff
Alexandrov will tell you how it all
happens in a real life and where the
pitfalls may be when it comes to
implementing these tools colleagues hi
thanks everyone who stayed until the
ends your few and far between but still
[Music]
this presentation was planned for a
longer time but I'll try to squeeze
within the time allowed in 2014 we've
been developing developing our own tool
since 2015 for the first two or three
years we've been actively building the
software this secure development
methodology with our customers when
talking about static analysis it's about
security but looking for vulnerabilities
without running another code it's quite
difficult problem which means that you
need to find objections for instance you
need to build a model simple text
analysis doesn't allow you to achieve
high quality and looking for
vulnerabilities and so assess tools wrap
sophisticated algorithm to support in
envelopes and embed these SAS tools into
development tools so a small example of
what makes assessed goods or what it can
find here we see a standard SQL
injection vulnerability to functions so
the practical user enters one function
and then is transferred to another
function through a standard string
concatenation so a simple open source
analyzer won't find this so it looks
like this sample it's a simple but you
understand that really sophisticated
injections arbitrary different modules
involving 10 to 15 two functions a good
static analyzer I should cope with that
so what follows from this I measure this
in a few minutes so when implementing a
number of questions arise from
implementation experience from our
communication with customers we've put
together a list of most frequent
questions and most frequently
encountered in errors the first question
that they often ask us is that we
already have free static analysis tools
soniku but others that look for errors
well would you need something else
especially if it costs a lot of course
there are lots of differences between
different differences between free tools
you know and paid tools here we have
some examples of Patos pay tolls have a
focus of security so they implement
specific algorithms to look for
vulnerabilities large rule basis for of
the search of vulnerabilities they
supports many programming languages they
and they offer support of course there
are free tools all tools mentioned it's
lighter actually quite good for their
purposes so we don't try to diminish the
values the virtues especially sonic qube
it's a great tool a lot of people use
and that gets embedded into development
tools quite well but there's not enough
there about security and the
vulnerability only the slight one would
be you would be able to find what this
tool there are others more focused on
security manito fighter another one for
job they're more specialized but maybe
whose qualities should support
development integration integration with
service backtrack is ID everything that
developers use the normal process here
we have a brief example of how you can
as schematically set up this process
from the acknowledged point of view so
there are developers using their
environments developers usually commit
code to the development repository a
server gets other code out of the
repository using different triggers it
could be some regular launches or by
triggers so they start testing and here
we launch a static analysis the outcomes
of static analysis can be viewed by
developers in their own environments and
in the analyzer interface UI the
analyzer usually provides information
not only for the development but also to
a higher level analyst for security
officers for managers and finally quite
often is sat down to the security
officer to initiate a vulnerability back
tracker so that developers can fix these
another question that seems good okay in
incest pay - how to select it simple
things you first I need to run a
comparison this first thing you do there
are not too many tools out there in the
market there may be two or three three
or four better-known you can pilot every
one of the compare them against the
functional requirements which features
you need to be happy using it also you
have to understand that you'll be
embedding tools these tools into your
process which are specific integration
the schematics you use are these tools
integratable your devices also you need
to take your code for scanning I think
perhaps the most critical system and
compare the analyzes for false positives
for instance it's also important that
you need to run a specific in your case
you have a specific development process
specific integration system and specific
code now licensing can be quite curious
because some avenges limits the license
but number of users but now code lines
and this may not fit here fit your case
another question
at which point in time to run the
scanning so the classic answer is quite
simple you should run scanning as
frequent as possible the earlier we find
the vulnerability and the chip is going
to be to fix it static analysis say
improves development competence the code
becomes more secure as a whole and of
course imitation to see ICD simplifies
the assessed uses process so usually you
have to use it both in the development
process and also you need to run
pre-release checks and this is exactly
what we're going to talk about we have
quite a lot of cases but I'll talk about
a specific case where all the problems
are there I'm going to talk about having
we fix them and I'll explain how we fix
them firstly there were a lot of
developers and many development tools
many programming languages a lot of
codes lots of different systems and
everything worked differently in each
development team and we needed to
implement deploy sassed into this
company questions that's right we
understood that paid tools they need to
be used we roughly the same way to run
them so the question is how was the
complexity and let's just connect it
just like any other verification and
checks will be running it from time to
time we shouldn't be having problems it
turns out that there are problems
because the search for sophisticated
vulnerability takes a lot of time a lot
of resources and how you are not able to
run it just like you're not simple
checks it takes a lot of work and then
the question comes up of how to set up
her the usual dev shakeups a process so
usually when we start talking to the
developers there's an expectation that
would work fast so you can run it
forever commit may be to understand who
and when introduced the vulnerability
but it goes against the reality and
explains why it can take quite a lot of
time to run you don't normally have
resources to run it after every commit
it's very it's a difficult attribute the
authorship to a specific user because
there are different features different
functions that are shared between
different modules a change of
vulnerability will introduce changes in
other places and also there are false
positives in and it's not quite clear
how to set up quality gates how the
results of static analysis will affect
the builds of the release and so on and
so forth if you want aesthetic so the
sense is like this for instance a we
have quite a large piece of code for two
million lines it takes six or seven
hours to analyze
they said you can see that the 20,000
line code can be analysed in 40 minutes
and other projects twice as large in
seven minutes
so the reason
is that the time of scanning by
statistic a static analyzer depends not
only on the code and language it depends
on a lot of other attributes of a
specific problem the complexity of
structures the modularity and so on so
forth so it's important to understand
how much time the scanning of your
particular code will take and how much
resources will be consumed when they
sterilize if you understand how
frequently went around scanning how much
time is going to take you understand how
much resources you need and it's
important to define the triggers by
which the scanning will be lost so that
on the one hand the use of this tool
should be comfortable for developers and
they should get results and work and
also they shouldn't consume too much
resource and too much time to mean
yourself too much time
the resources are will have to be
factored in because it's an analyzer it
has a new process in the system and
finally sometimes you can use
incremental analysis and process and
that allows analyzing only the cheat
code have to be cut Karen will do this
because in all analyzers at least
missing vulnerabilities you can't run a
fully fledged analysis because what will
disappear at the interface between they
feel different components so a lot of
critical vulnerabilities may be lost
there so basically the case that I
mentioned there was an interesting
situation how we found the compromise
between the time required for doing the
scan on large amount of codes and the
desire of the result so briefly talking
to the developers who understood that
the adequate number of scanning runs
would be if for a specific development
feature branch the scanning would be
started from when passing from status in
development to interview so it turned
out that such transfers were only done a
few times a day and it fitted the
process and the amount of resource
available with this approach so the
finishes the work on the task then
transfers it to review automatically the
scanner gets the most requests and get
love they see comments to their code
from static analysis in the environment
where they ran the merge request so that
one had we see the scanning runs in the
process in the run process then the
other hand developers don't need does
need to go to the sass to test to so
this is a real integration developers
could also run a scanning manually and
the results that they were adding to my
requests were filtered by severity by
the vulnerability being old and you saw
that the number of such complaints
should be adequate to be fixed in time
sometimes you fail to find such a
compromise such as right off so the
classic approach is direct scanning
every night so that next morning
developers could see what the
vulnerability says they added in the
previous day the next point okay we're
gonna search how to run the scanning how
to integrate we've understood that we
need to find a trade-off and still we
run a scanning and see a lot of
positives there may be tens of thousands
of them and you have feeling there are
too many false positives so the question
is what to do with them so in practical
terms practical advice first you have
filters any static analyzers allows your
filtering out filtering the code by
directory by files by packet package
a library in some some analyzers have
inbuilt Library exclusion tools and also
you can process the results based on
severity and there's another parameter
in addition to severity for instance
there's confidence it makes sense to
start with those vulnerabilities a
weather analyzer in which they own
analyzer is the most confident that
another false passports fear you should
exercise caution employing filtering
because it may lead to losing
vulnerability the results the good
analyzes allow marking the results are
also good analyzers have a tracking
function even in large projects you can
do this certificate once and then you'll
be verifying only new vulnerabilities
even after the filtering there are still
a lot of vulnerabilities left that you
need to process the most important
recommendations to all our colleagues
give is to start with not long new
vulnerabilities to happen so to set the
process up in such a way that if you are
only looking at the new vulnerabilities
that have appeared in the past day a
week that the number of them should be
not too large to be fixed at the time
also you can fix vulnerabilities in the
first scanning in the previous scannings
gradually by using the filters princess
histogram for specific a project so we
had five vulnerabilities appearing every
day and they were fixed in time all the
vulnerabilities that were found in the
first run of the scanner were fixed over
over a five month period by five
developers and the last point if all
these questions around since everything
seems to be clear for you we run the
scanning work with results and still a
lot of people talking about building the
secure software development process so
what
well there are some prerequisites which
are quite obvious and I'll talk about
technical features of static analysis
that many people are not exposed to even
develop as because runs a lot consumers
not the resources but you need it
because it can find sophisticated
vulnerabilities and based on this and
not everybody else how to use it how to
work and this turns from a technical
aspect into a national aspect how
historically a development security have
been separated vulnerability is not a
features not a bug so in classical
approach it's not the responsibility of
the developers the responsible
responsibilities of security people it's
not quite so clear to all developers
that they need to do that coming back to
the case many teams many systems and
then you get the new objects static
analysis from abilities to handle which
they hadn't need to address in the past
some what kind of problems we got them
and how we solve them firstly about the
implementation time when we were
discussing the problem with customers
business unit we wanted to introduce us
at the same time and it went bang with
our teams and remove all vulnerable T as
fast as poss as soon as possible based
on previous experience for I understand
that it normally ends in bad results
because well firstly releases start
getting blocked and there are many
releases you're not keeping up fixing
them developers don't know why it is
needed this functionality is running
there are bugs that seem to be more
important so they remove our ability to
take two months the release gets stopped
and there are real cases where business
just stops the implementation of
ourselves because of this behavior so
therefore it's important to implement
science especially in large company in a
gradual way it makes sense to stuff with
two or three critical system web
applications mobile applications so the
self-assess
adds to the security of this system and
then start expiring this code it's also
important to start without blocking the
release
to the trial round of the process to
train all the participants on assess to
let them understand that it's not
something to fear there is really an
important thing now and gradually in
half a year here you could start using
it in the real release process you have
to start with removing new newly found
real nura bilities and then gradually
remove the old ones also for the large
companies it's important to regulate the
process to prepare the rules and
policies and get them approved by
participants in our case the
implementation has taken almost a year
it's now almost finished I talked about
regulations and ampere what can be
included in the secure development
process there should be certain steps
are made from identifying the well
detecting a vulnerability to fixing it
so our responsibilities should be
attributed who's responsible for who
owns the results how communication is
built between different departments
especially between development and
security who verifies the vulnerability
who confirms that this vulnerability are
not alone rebuilding how do you escalate
when security and developers can't
arrive at the same conclusion there
should be a slate not even to fix the
vulnerability because some
vulnerabilities take maybe six months
because you'll have to write their
kotecha but there should be responses
away so security found if owner ability
send them to development and development
should reply should respond within a
specified time if it is a vulnerability
and how much it'll cost to fix it and
also what's important to mention in the
regulation is how new systems would be
added to the process you need to be to
know who's responsible for the addition
which information needs to be added to
keep for the software development
process safe and secure also
understand that secure development
regulations should also be much where
other regulations private policies
practices activities you have to
understand what other policies and
regulations exist the company which
apply to development and how they
interoperate sometimes you need to apply
secure software development say in the
situation where you don't have a
development environment regulated in
total the approval process can take a
long time so specifically in this case
that I'm describing the implementation
has taken a year and the regulations are
not yet fully approved a lot of
participant in the process everyone has
their own point of view how it should
work and ideally well actually the real
life you have to take a cus certain
things and discard others but in real
life you have to understand who approves
which document in their final form also
what we encounter quite often and
specifically in this case it applied as
well no resources so so quite often the
responsibilities are for identifying the
vulnerability is not part of a developer
job description so the one hand you need
to allocate budget for new resources
then you should regulate the ownership
and finally vulnerabilities should be
fixed in the same way as bugs are in
each release in the process of
negotiation approval and interaction
with developers so that everybody should
understand why SAS and what's it needed
for it's important to make sure that all
people should understand and
why and how important is there are
certain things a vulnerability affixed
at the development time is many orders
of magnitude cheaper than a
vulnerability found in production it's
important to find real vulnerabilities
in your code to show how they exploited
to show what a real outcomes or impact
is can make quite often developers are
interested in getting in getting new
information improved for their professed
level and assessed does allow improving
the skills in application security we
get these stages in implementing assess
choosing the to process definition
technical solutions definition
implementation and trial run all these
steps run iteratively on the same time
but with the gradual expansion of the
scope team by team system by system so
what are the outcomes for our specific
analyzer and for our specific customers
and we have about 100 successful
implementations almost all users
continue using the tool and now the
trend is as such that customer society
with many oldest and this was most of
those customers start to migrate to
secure development process to
integration to implement into
implementing assess in the development
process the numbers are here we now have
more than 30 customers gradually
migrating to integration and more than
and about 10 have already built the
process and implemented it so the main
conclusions that we can make something
you need it indeed is a useful tool to
find sophisticated vulnerabilities must
be used it's important to use every
phase the development adapting the
process to your specific code and your
development process you need to work
with scanning settings with the results
were verifying them editing them you
need to start with fixing newly found
vulnerabilities and then gradually
remove the older ones that were found in
the first scan scanning you and need to
create a process based on cest because
especially in large company they use
will attenuates and customers will go
away give up on using this tool because
they haven't been able to implement the
process and finally as a process it
needs to be implemented gradually
gradually expanding the scope thank you
thank you your Aslam so we've finished
our session finally it was a it was long
it covered a lot of technologies any
questions we can discuss or we can
adjust to talk it's a microphone and if
there's nothing we can actually go
outside because somebody shout three two
one and everybody shouted and I got
because they interested what was
happening so if there are no questions
to speakers let them go continue their
work because the work day is not over so
they can continue thank you for your
attention thank you for being with us I
have a good day and come back again
thank you