yes in disguise Oprah I will talk about
the Android applications vulnerabilities
what I mean when the realtors are quite
easy but the specialists there often
they they ignore their analysis and
that's putting flags so then they just
browse them and they don't go into
detail that is why I wrote I will just
it's kind of workshop lecture and so you
later can take this presentation and do
the same steps that were going to do so
we can just follow the same steps that I
will I will follow then let's do it
I'm from alarm company I and I analyze
vulnerability of applications and mobile
Wi-Fi and I do everything channel where
you can always publish my materials and
I talk there about the applications
security vulnerabilities applications
because I'm security specialist I can
always visit visit my site and see so
we'll talk about two vulnerabilities
which is application debuggable and
Android backup vulnerability hmm
and so those who are familiar with this
they may think that there is not nothing
special there but I think that certainly
you still can learn something from it
so first we'll talk about debuggable
application debuggable and because the
main the main challenge so there are
fairly simple to understand owner
ability but not not not the easiest to
exploit and analyze yes it's a high risk
they just flag it and this is it and
this is what I talk about when it to
analyze what can be done with the help
of debuggable approach and if there is a
danger then we need to talk about that
but but here we'll talk how to do now to
look at it how to change it improve it
and how to properly unit and so then the
specialists they just say that this
vulnerability there is a flag red flag
so then the analysis is not done
properly of the application and that is
why we need just to follow up on that
and so this slide is for those who want
to work on it with Android applications
and and so there are instruments so
there are lots of it because for example
Android studio can can do a lot but this
presentation tells you about the
instrumentation set and a very popular
good good good list of the proper
instruments then so we'll check it on
execute Bank developed by a secure bank
developed by one of the specialists and
so he developed this a wonderful
application to secure insecure Bank -
that has the banking interface password
parole server and so transactions are
stored there and so then there are other
things in this app insecure bank and
that could be easily applied in and so
if even you know you can you can even
just try to play with it because it's
it's a good learning device so I can
just learn a lot and so you can just do
a lot and learn a lot using this
application so then there are some other
there is another application which
describes many applications so let's
talk about the so debugging of this
application
[Music]
so what is debuggable application
debuggable I think that everyone knows
so we can somehow they do the process
command by command and Android provides
a debugger that allows to do the
following and you can see that on the
slide
gerrae Kotlin and CC plus code set
breakpoints that examine variables and
evaluate expressionism why is it
dangerous because I will explain why
it's it's really dangerous because
because if you do the debug on your
application on your cell phone because
you can have just a similar rights to
this application so then and so a
specialist who will get your cell phone
can can I can't manipulate the
environment settings of the application
gain access to the information stored in
the application and and get lots of
information from this application on
Android not not not all models and some
some models opposition differently and
so they say it's not possible and so a
fixed it we can go around the blockings
etc and it is much more difficult to the
same application that does not have
debug mode enabled since you must have
root access in some Android devices
getting root access is difficult and so
we need to describe this support yeah
and then the user who solve his cell
phone so can can actually if it's in the
hands of a professional so I can make
sure that no information can be
extracted from this cell phone so how we
do it then that's in this application
first let's talk about how to determine
that there's an application is
debuggable so arrow the commands for
consult
I wrote this commands for consult and
file manifest all information is there
for proper tuning of the application so
then we can unpack application apk epoch
then with the help of grep will find
debuggable
which which is in the tag application
and and then so it means that it can be
tunable if it has this point then let's
see what what can be what can be done in
this application and we have different
solutions but the they were not of
interest to me and I developed my own
application can use different resources
layouts and I developed this example how
can get the password from the root time
so after you have to bring a brief
analysis of the application you can
understand that that it can feel in the
credential fields automatically if they
have already been developed
and then and then they they get the
legging and and password and send them
to the server and so then the
application when you authorized it once
authenticated and then you get during
your session you can't continue to work
so this is the session cannot be dragged
out so it should be encrypted but it can
be decrypted and sent to the server and
this is the same so then share
preference files they being scripted
password is there and a certain runtime
it's okay without root because not
everyone will take it out information
about the but the press work and then we
can transfer the help of tuning we can
do it so then you can see the function
code analysis how to how to properly so
break break this break the password so
after examining the activity which is
responsible for the login page we can
find so this field data function and if
you can see that at some point the
corrupted password is put into a
variable and can stored in it and this
means that we can monitor the state of
the variable and Yakuts value when
debugging and you can easily and that
might take a lot of time
and so how did logging how to how to
connect or debugging so this is very
important so not too how to connect it
as you can see how it's done so there
are different ways of debugging so then
GDP that is is the best means and then
GDP and then then other paths Android
studio can be tuned up attitudinal as
well this use j DP 0 and and so here you
will find the first line is that the
process that is is performed and we know
that it's it is debuggable a so then
common command draw it so that 4 to 7 7
J DWP and with the help of j DP protocol
and Java debugging protocol and with the
help of this protocol they to connect
this process can start sending commands
and to debug then so then then the
before the port JDP protocol process and
connect with the help of GDP JDP attach
local host host and you can see this
picture so it means that you
successfully connected then
so there are lots of lots of commands so
what can be done in GDP I will tell you
only so that what we can do with the
help of GDP so can work with the
debugger and now debugger has a number
of commands and some commands a very
convenient so come Android since if your
bank - okay so getting on on the results
in the run times you can find your own
your own part that is responsible for
your own function field data and so this
list is command is and then the output
is quite quite considerable that we
found the class that responsible for the
method of field data field data then we
see method class has identified that we
need to tune top debug and we find that
there is method method is there and then
we can do the breakpoint breakpoint for
this method and then then order 23 stop
in class method so this is the command
so when you when you when you get this
in runtime so we can always restore it
and slowly debug it and look where the
fluid the password is is decrypted and
and try to drag it out so we press this
button so it just goes down to
breakpoint age IT so thread may mean and
then you can always put the Java and
commands list you can see where you are
and then available mechanisms available
debugging commands first itself
continue continue continue yes after the
break point then step execute the
current line stop at the method entry
and so then step by step command by
command then it goes into the functions
this process then it goes inside the
function and start to look for the
password so next allow us to do the
function in one step
executes the current line so then you
can just reference data extraction that
next can just do not stop at the method
entry and then another for looking
possible for the password is local local
so give print the values of all
variables local pair to the current
method and so on you can see them and
even change them so then there is a
function of set but it can change the
value of our variables as well a yuta
detectors are feeding etc but it's quite
difficult but but for debugging is this
one is quite easy and this is the
results so the locals command that shows
all variables and at the certain point
in time so I did several next and I show
that there is a there is a password open
password that I got in this application
that could be debugged then this is this
is the indicator that it's applicable in
this application so then debugging is
applicable to this application so then
Joe tack that leaves five minutes and it
can just drag it out of the help of
debugging at this and no need just to do
that because it's easy to kill this
application
and he says this is what we talk when we
do the debugging and then for this
passion is what security specialists
when they just to take more effort to
debug applications and for developers
you need is the body because when you
when you develop the code you need to
use the different different different
methods of development so they're not
for debugging for releases you need to
do this debugging and can be able just
to provide both those variants and to
confirm the availability of this
opportunity demonstrated now backup by
capping let's talk about the cups and
the so those who don't know what Android
is it might be very interesting for him
so what is back up where the how
dangerous it can be and how prevalent it
is so what goes into the backup and what
they will do with the backup so then
data gets into the backup
of application if an application it
allows reserved backup then backup
function can actually with the help of
this you can just get this this
information as we'll talk about the
leakage of data it's not that you can
can get the backup of your application
you need to have physical access is
difficult but what Android version six
zero you can hire so NATO L to do how to
backup my data listen you you think so
it's included but if it's on this
automatic backup if you go from Android
on draw it and you don't want to lose
data your phone you don't turn it on and
you need to understand what is doing so
it gets the information from the from
the application 24 hours if it's allowed
top by Wi-Fi and now no more than 25
megabytes so what kind of summation goes
there but in my experience when I
analyzed this application the developers
put there very often so developers put
their different
so so Android has four types of chip
reference databases internal storage
external storage so four types so then
shared preferences file see we have so
what is stored there was not stored so
what is internal stores internal
external storage
what's external internal storage so that
the keys will of keys as well passwords
peon etc so very very comfortable to
store their their shared preferences is
not encrypted and shred preference goes
into the cup every time you backup your
application it goes into the into the
cloud but the cloud is connected to your
Google account and a Google account
through the social engineering so then
you can always restore it from your
smartphone if you get a new smartphone
and download all your data there a
southern files saved to your app
international storage so they get there
as well so they are to be backed up
backed up as well but not all files and
files and directories also get files
dear which is an application and then
there are directory files inside so they
don't know
so the same the same was true of
databases they're not encrypted they
encrypt a lot especially that they did
the work with the social media people
contacts could be can distort their
banks who liked it so that develop their
own propriety for mation for the
department's HR stuff so they they love
to store their nests so that's the HR
files or passwords etc the an external
storage storage so is your SD card SD
cards as the is very well since SD card
so every application so you can they can
always see your SD card so then
everywhere everything from A to Z but
not the SD card is backed up but only
one file date
Android Android data application than
files so then not not all SD card
information will be backed up because an
SD card you can put in to the SD card
anything about then then ok then the
leakage channel exists so with the help
of a adb so one utility that is very
good for working with android so you
need just to learn it because it's great
as a very good utility
so so then you need to know the password
to this device otherwise you cannot do
the backup and the second method is a
leakage on auto automatic backups user
data from apps that targeted around on
android 6.0 api level 23 or later and
that's all they did a basis and it's
stored in G Drive could be interesting
to unpack people in fact that works and
then various vendors away so they do
their own things for backup and I was
implement their own backup mechanisms
and it's the same story in the
application backups data so this data
may become vulnerable vulnerable so when
a specialist do the backup and so it's
kind of some sort of database pressure
is just sending data to the cloud and so
and they certainly related to many risks
and I will order them for each
instrument for health template in the
way of social engineering yes so that's
Google Google page Google account
Android is there so so long all open and
so this is the after determine that an
application is allowed backups so we can
see that what works what doesn't
so they try to unpack application apk
and then you look and in attack
application rights activities
applications looking for android
debuggable true if it's true could be
backed up if not could not picked up as
about you need to to go deeper
exploitation so that you know to check
it you need to work with the application
and fill it with data then using the
Android debug bridge and then we connect
us through ADB and get backup file and
backup file is an archive tera our key
archive it has 24 bytes and its
signature so
just have a be all on Java Android
backup extractor it can unpack and
repack and you get backup it will have
this same spatial reference TP Zen
resources that is nothing interesting
very often there are files external
files and the only thing I wanted to
tell you have you seen it because in
fact you well don't think that is just
background some files some data 0
mechanism of signifies unit which the
developers should listen to and these
are exceptions you can accept some
storages of files or you can show tell
point to the descriptor file and tag it
and actually point out was going to be
backed up and there are files that cache
files and no backup files you can
actually deactivate the backup function
if you are sure that your next iPhone is
I an iPhone just which a tougher if you
are not going to have more androids it
works so and as I told you we planted
this topic in Russian
Ronit and show how you can simply learn
it and the purpose of this lecture is to
explain that I have many friends who do
on occasion security and are afraid to
go to Android or though etcetera it's a
nice thing when you understand
everything is competitive
and you can see you can just look at the
vulnerabilities and the settings that's
good
that's why I appeal to you study it's
simple and gives you new knowledge and
skills I thank you I'm ready to take
your questions
thank you have a short questions are
there any ways to fit Google account and
they will spit out all the backups I was
looking at you cannot just drag back up
from the ground you can get and show all
the applications probably the wrong I
don't know
was there any research it's my next
research probably thank you for the
question
so that's it thank you I'll see you