simply via NASA on tumblr you are a lot
of companies where our pizza pies Nicole
Marie provision invested GT nutricai
company so we check we check the product
we will teach we train we train the
developers and I'll talk about how to
start testing security myself in my free
time I work with bounty and in the
evenings I I launch clusters library
Qyburn niches kubernetes kubernetes
clusters I do it in the evenings so who
works everyday with kubernetes who have
who has heard kubernetes so could their
natures
so it may seem very difficult instrument
complex instrument but it's a very
difficult system it's complex system
that's right and so when you come across
it for the first time
divorce admin developer tester doesn't
mean who you are so the first little
victory is to make the system work so
it's a complex system and it works out
so then some some settings by default
and security settings by default this is
bad if they leave them at default level
few words about the architecture so the
most important is the master mode master
node then the DVD storage there
and there so then cubelets is an agent
of the node that that manages the the
launch of pods and that takes care of
their safety then there are cute proxy
so that handles the traffic and then
there are some pods with containers so
let's imagine that we have this web
application and it comes in the users
come so they they buy they do something
they visit sites so then the application
works fine and then so what what what
happens if not very nice guys will come
with bad intentions what will happen
then so let's imagine that this cluster
this web application and certain the web
application showdown and some socks the
people like so let's think that this is
vulnerable right for example so this
command injection so you send directly
this command to operate the OS and
that's what happens let's see what
happens
for you to understand so the attackers
so they send a command for the return
shell and and then at their own server
they open up the port and wait for the
connection and then they were through
web application and they get the
connection of all neural connections so
the attacker is inside the container and
now he knows where he is what he does so
what
so then what he can do so see the files
and see the files were just rights and
all about vulnerabilities so then the
zips and in to be shown and then the
attacker has a different task since he
understands that he is inside the
cluster he needs to follow through on
his attack Kim CTL that he'll make that
that allow us to communicate with the IP
server and the attacker downloads from
the server and checks there's a file
gives you the rights so the rights are
given granted the rights then by default
kubernetes
I also provide secrets of this service
account into the pod and you can easily
find them that's exactly what happens
and then the effect I found that there
is this he found this and this you can
see on the screen there's a certificate
and key for the connection to the
cluster and informing the command for
the keep city and the certificate opens
up this token the token looks like
Judith 64 then stores it saves it a
certificate and token so were to go grab
burn em burn HS and defined IP and the
port where you need to go then the rest
is easy so I keep CTL is one of the main
instruments they form a command IP
server identified certificate key
identified and get one simple honorable
and then you get into a space where all
these nice socks cards front them
everything so then you can see all the
parts everywhere called the Netscape
system everything and the socks and the
sock shop so where the attacker found
himself
and then attempt number two so then
first a service account so there's
rights exactly then you see naturally
that you can go further so that the
attacker comes and says we have some
some bias miss something good maybe I
should go and see those bars where
device were made and then he goes into
the pot with all orders purchases
sensitive information data data the data
file and then and then he he doesn't
stop already
gets to the other spot I can find
accounts emails accounts cards if they
go forbidden there so even if they're in
krimpets United incident incident anyway
and
[Music]
what happened so this bad guy came yes
so then I found this vulnerabilities
went to pod also found secrets chapters
download CTL downloaded and went to the
master and then found more interesting
part so where the sensitive information
is is is available about the socks from
and he got the access to the shop and
all the information what's next
what else could have been done hmm could
be done okay we're still there and the
frontality now more interesting things
are going to happen so they use the
yellow file for different operations and
I am filed which which shows that it's
upon and then the images used in jigs
and then what's next so it takes the
directory and mounts it onto a host
what's going to happen why he's doing
that so I'm very accurate slow reliable
hacker checks every step and he launches
the command to perform yellow file
create support attack pod Creed
and then we need to wait until port is
created the containers go away then he
has exact rights and he gets into the
attack pod and he can see the file
system of the node where the container
was launched in the pod more interesting
so there are the secrets of the server
already available to bleed disabled ECG
so using all the data I can actually
grab the server
okay let's play the thought went to the
IP server master note to use the
dashboard dashboard this is dangerous
it starts with images and a close down
your dashboard everyone says but there's
no company's sound like web the
terminals dashboard and they keep it
there both inside the network so here
the attacker through the web application
gets into God and then he cannot go
further these settings do not restrict
him you can go to dashboard to see the
scriptures or pods that is safer for
even launched their own pods through the
dashboard but for this Ian sqrl that's
it and the knowledge of headers the same
with CD CD in old versions by default it
was decrypted and the access was open so
now it's better now but still it was
connector this EGCG defined all the
secrets description of parts variables
internal and hand points anything and to
see how cluster was built and found
tutorials
he will talk about cloud providers this
is a Google Asia
digitalocean Amazon naturally so they
provide their clusters but but for some
reasons so you can go to from portal
metadata and use metadata and drag and
steal the data and have to take away the
data can read all the security secrets
find this easy CD secrets and to get to
the inner sanctum of all the clusters
what have they found
you said kubernetes is a new product and
so then in 2016 appeared this is the
statistics of identified vulnerabilities
so then December 2018 when the
Commonwealth to upgrade the clusters so
they found a mistake in the end oh the
logic of the processing of IP queries
that allows the attacker authorized
unauthorized to get access and to
increase their privileged preference and
privileges address of Cuba server
there's a gothic connection
query and then to be rejected others to
send queries the same connection and
they would go to backstory straight to
the nose and that allowed to to grab the
whole cluster
at the beginning of this year February
this year more difficult there's a keep
city HCP copy command by default if you
not to copy a container file it does it
they take the tar from container this
file and then archives it but what can
be done if you replace dark appeals
network does not check if the difference
that that tower and instead of tar you
can just put in a symlink script shell
to head and scripture and then you do
things and then they come together to
that means and then debug doesn't work
help me
download the bug look and see what's
happening coaster operator out there
Loudoun see how they exploit this
vulnerability to to entice you as the
cluster iterator today to the of the
network and it's worth workstations and
the workstations there were more secrets
that you could get access to that could
include minor death and so then to make
a command to send some information from
his and then that's that's that's how he
could do
what I'm driving at so it's our
mentality or not so because this
temporary things are very constant as
you know I will just I will do it later
using settings by default default
settings so this is very bad because it
might hit you in the back and so if you
forget about security and if you use
only default settings successfully if
they attack they're exploited here at
the beginning of the I became interested
kanji eraser searches they found some
things passport cards and they found
everything and I became interested so
other public clusters yes there are so
why on the face why should you open the
access to cluster for the whole world
and I watch clusters and went to sleep
and the others just are working on them
so the rest of the debug moments there
are some initial stages to get to earn
about technology more and then then this
cluster is vulnerable open because it's
being developed and this is bad and then
it could be taken full advantage of
because because they they put everything
in there
so this is an open door to the
infrastructure the rest when it's
Shradha when they show them some API
limit limits and and and and port at
thousand 250 so that works on a secured
connection ssl true and if you do HTTP
IP 2250 then you will see 404 that's the
query result so I hope the number of
results would be great now but it's
increasing
so then 660 500 added in the last two
months so I like showing guys that edct
atcg
so 2,000 homes support 2379 not all of
them just go in and see the majority
open a closed secure but nevertheless if
you filter short by the same standard
organization region then you can you can
narrow down answer again you'll see what
kind of car companies operate the city
they are exposed to the home
and then I thought maybe we shot that
automate something and I automated it a
little bit I like to automate cubone
cubone
just the right from cube let me know
what is what is the kind of utility is
it four stages looking for clusters of
shoulders
storing addresses or develop analysis
white cube off works only with the 10/22
10250 port and and besides for 10250
there are other interesting words where
the attacker may find sensitive
information for 10 5 2 5 5 so this read
only 43 you can build anything but you
can read spare clusters a container laws
mattresses and all this information is
very good for the attacker to prove the
vulnerability of the cluster so we need
at least one working and then keyboard
execute command inside the container and
then he hit parses so if you take URL
and send it to this port to 10 12 to 15
and you'll see the pods that are
launched up and running right now you
see containers that are working at this
time and if you said that so then you'll
see the whole list of pots then we check
and by thunder the containers the
containers and then we went then the
command to launch so this as a
description like in running pods
so this long long line is is the name of
the pods cube system and container cube
control manager so cue ball does not
move for a specific name space does not
look for specific Bolton container it
just takes the first one because by
default it rotates the results if you
update the page so it generates new set
of information how can you do it with QQ
you seen URL so the cube system and then
cube controller manager or a know what
name and then cube controller manager is
the company so the ID command has post
post dated nothing extraordinary if
everything is successful you will see
this this list you will see this list
I'll show you how it works
[Music]
I want to warn you that when you execute
any commands on someone else's resources
so you could be punished one day if you
have no no no no permit for that so when
you want you to always remember to find
zero filtration and shuttle afford for
organization operation
Ida faced IP trodden goes in and finds
three nine nine nodes that detection can
reward me I did ID command and you can
she asked you out let's calculate 392
host almost so ages too much I don't
know this is seem too many or little but
if we practice responsible approach talk
so the attacker needs only one if he
can't deform God get to the note he may
actually check this system and that's
what's that's scary
so again this marine battle so someone
has come he doesn't hit a web
application he has discovered that the
cluster is in in the internet or 10250
and and then again the same he would do
he would fulfill the commands inside the
container and the same thing now may
happen so you get to the dashboard ECG
it's not very difficult for is a
attacker but then I automated that's
good I played the Rosetta I liked it so
wide for one reason so along with q-ball
zero other larger useful utilities that
help to estimate the security and the
setting so DNS cluster q-ball is needed
as another line in your security
pipeline you just know you may get
public cluster in the if they are
protruding and sticking out and close
does it's on right now we're all people
we all make mistake on this line may you
know a failure one day if you find such
a cluster and call your security guys
just do it under so why does it happen
why does it work where is the magic
magic is simple
so in the source so there are two
functions get run
that's why cubot works and get exactly
so one of them is going to become a
legacy but it doesn't because anyway
there's only one of them get exact works
differently at least you will require so
cat cat and Heather so you just do what
you see on the slides you do the same
thing if it is successful you will get I
should it be 302 as a negative residence
and you take this key and then add it to
the ID command so let me tell you about
some stories from real life Cisco so
let's talk about Cisco earlier this year
I encountered a wonderful TCG cluster
that was giving me many interesting
things when I tried to find out who it
was when an attacker gets it gets and he
still in Amazon how can you find out who
is that it's some kind of cloud of
provider it's a cluster in my view one
of the simplest way to find the engines
is to find it jinks and then description
of the hosts hosts and understand who is
that
in differently if it is not a cloud
provider and the network is in data set
just take a local BSN and this IP
address was in the same system with the
main Cisco site what happened such
beautiful things default cluster and
tokens from Cuba DM and you can use it
to connect your node and then there were
hash passwords doesn't matter that it
was hash dollar six five one two but
these passwords were known so there was
no need to use magic and still after I
wrote about this IP address
I asked within 24 hours after talking to
Cisco I realized that they know about
this vulnerability on the 5th of January
as I sent it to them probably because it
was some critical system their internal
system they fixed it this IP address and
seven others and at the port 10 2005
there was something else description of
the pause with all their variables
they were secrets you don't you just
opened this idiot joystick you'll find
secret internal points and parameters so
it was a huge sis complication they were
many endpoints internal and external
[Music]
they said nothing works but actually
there were some external hosts working
and after our reporter they have closed
them down but still and there were other
interesting things but unfortunately I
didn't work closely with them you know
this is centralized a secret storage
keeps of all the secrets in one box very
cool and protected there were secrets if
you take those secrets get into the pod
and get to the note you get the pretend
to be an application and get all those
secrets that are available for this role
so you can always state the cluster and
actually see what kind of hardware you
have a disk lustre what's interesting
and you know how it happens I imagine
those miners who mined in the evening
looking for resources they have this
automation they go to these Port Salut
prospects look for fat nice servers and
clusters and just attack them even
industrial IT Giants I may be wrong yeah
no rocket science it's that thing called
the digital network architecture Center
unauthorized access vulnerability there
was much information because the
password was weak and it was not secure
you can go and read about it who else
right empty AT&T unique University of
Arizona and this Chinese I thank God I
didn't go there but others got it very
funny I told about it
those clusters once you try they give
you this type of in the infrastructure
it seems to be oh and there was nothing
else to try but turned out wrong
remember is a cloud provider who gets
his post to metadata and when you have
an IP address and you want you don't
know who and what is that
and for automation is convenient to use
Asia pleasure they give you this and
pointer you are insert their IP address
that you get and see that it's that you
look at it and then digital oceans good
guys they recently launched their own
cue brunette custards so when you have
this master notice somewhere else you
don't have much access but in the courts
you could deliver wonderful secrets you
take the private certificate and you
bastard and my favorite Google they are
amazing metadata flavor without this
together you will not get anything but
if you do it you can get the same thing
for cubelet and again then you get nodes
and codes and secrets and whatever you
want you launch
and another summary so once he found the
cluster he he look at the cluster in
kubernetes so when he wished and typical
vulnerabilities and tried to exploit and
then it goes as usual first you launch
the container and the nodes and then the
intelligence inside the system bug
bounty you must have heard about a
wonderful case with Shopify for twenty
thousand five thousand dollars what
happened there was a web application did
Shopify screenshot and it looks like
give me a screenshot and smart people
inserted this line generating the end
got a default token and then we took
those talking we insert in the header
and go make an enquiry and they get a
response with a certificate a private
key and then it is simple we take the
cube CTO certificate and the token and
according to Shopify for most of the
shops you would go and see was there
why 25k bounty is not a payment it's
simple
[Music]
according to Shopify this cluster was 44
development but feels they were real
production cluster real users real cars
the real payment that's why 25k why is
it dangerous you all heard what house
Tesla burned their sport after that we
got the phrase don't be Tesla close your
dashboard so attackers were smart what
was interesting about the dish some
secrets that allowed to launch in the
cluster miners with minimal resources
not to get burnt miners communication
they used they used command servers and
thanking servers they used it totally
they hid the real IP addresses so any
ideas EPS most probably has addresses
and it works well for mining
unfortunately we don't know how much
they mined but certainly a lot because
Tesla had big resources Aviva is a
British insurance company a large one
good player in the market and you see
the dashboard was hacked and they came
in and asked for a pod you see the way
as far as I know it's manera and then
you could see how much of they mind
another find unfortunately I cannot tell
you who is that just like in bug bounty
there are kilometers of report they will
just fix within one day and keep quiet
it's a large College in a large country
a lot of big continent it's a Jew the
men age eg why I was walking across a
lot of the parts I certainly didn't
watch a minor so they were reps with
scientific articles some mathematic
calculations some clients were getting
access to those ropes scale shortened
says it was around fifty thousand I
calculated some 1.5 k for clusters not
pastors but hosts taking those filters
country regions whatever filter and look
for your company or any company you know
this cluster when you try can be an open
door into your infrastructure how do we
protect
there are a number of guides and
trainings and I cannot tell you
everything so what so what is the main
of a skin in the images of skin check
the packages for vulnerabilities don't
let search images more even if you have
have more than one customers if you have
a large organization and you deploy 104
is a day and you have totally a thousand
I really know companies with that one
thousand two thousand clusters there is
an internal attacker why don't shoot
your side images because you reduce the
risk of insider a minor or evershell a
backdoor where the number of people who
have they seek the right to science you
mitigate that risk images and image
possible to avoid situations of
deployment of all packages because that
thing will ask you for a new one and the
second one will respond to similar
situations
throw out docker hub if you use it don't
you better have
registry and keep all the images and
scan them and sign and be happy
utilities that can be of use the first
three allowed you to scan the packages
for known vulnerabilities and the floors
allows you to size so minimum privileges
use SPS cruelty in names face is a good
thing we landed mean from development I
don't know your structure if you know
that you have a big application from a
small service just as we provide the
minimum quarters it would not save you
and at least you know when a minor
launchers there and start just picking
your resources at least you will see
their bug is not easy you need to study
it's not simple are bad is worth
studying when you have it look at this
utility I guess made by one of the main
contributors good thing
try pond security policy avoid
privileged containers in the second demo
it works because they launched of
privileged containers was permitted use
see comp of honor and see Linux the
launch under different users as the most
system if if you can avoid writing
something there don't try it for
security policy
we'll be there to assist the works
approximate relaxing previous utility
and you feed them your configured more
or less reasonable policies than the
network perimeter issues restrict
restrict but policies IP addresses use
well we use tags whatever policies can
work with them ingress control with web
application firewalls remember the
injection format it's all the silver
over the vasila a simple one will
protect you from summer cats restrict is
an incoming traffic elements for bits
and system related data if you use well
providers is not easy because you needed
it but then if you restrict you will be
safer than air but we use a mission
controller in charge of security they
have over twenty but still privileges do
not launch they activate container known
routes and dinners rotate certificates
is a nice keys that can save you or
mitigate the risk even they give the
attacker five certificates and keys this
key restricts a time it will just reduce
the time available for the attacker else
will help you you heard about my
security ah yes patriarchy is a major
market for applied and cue bench
launched on the almost on the masternode
and you can get much information they
will tell you how to do it's convenient
and automates very well what else I like
CSD IDs so you will have a panel with a
chart when you see that someone sends
exacto pod and you will be able to
respond adequately but it does not have
preventive measures so it will not save
you at least you will know about it
and a cool if you like check quick so
this is from the report about ways to
hack you or not to hack here so
pipelines you check the emergency your
sign if you can sign it with
functionality restrict library's traffic
dependences and monitor suppose there
are villages and find known
vulnerabilities and it will help you in
case of emergency so when you
to debrief and understand how an
incident handler when you need to do the
forensic into the runtime to check you
bench the same money aqua security the
does pin tests it's interesting it works
fast and allows you to understand which
ports are open which as a vulnerability
and just like people try to perform the
command inside the an arbitrary and we
use so I was shocked but in fact when in
December 2018 we found a logical mistake
illogical error we went to the cloud
good and it's it's easy or they have
already upgraded that a new release but
think about they upgrade
what do we need to remember when you
work with metadata consuming is a
promise to remove it but still you can
provide your metadata one way you need
to recreate the cluster people in your
resources launching your cluster with
this takunda
users is their own directories and cue
bench and cube hunter work intends to
make an encrypted filesystem for their
secrets should be good but we shall see
I have more useful utilities for you
these are the more or less attacking
utilities except for the last one with
the audit try there are so many and you
have different infrastructures and goals
and businesses some of them will fit and
the instruction to the captain upgrade
if you Burnett is develop said I would I
would take as a main version and then
upgrade there permanently try to catch
up with Google and think about security
at all stages from idea to deploy
deploying and automate cheers and
if you have many things many clusters
it's unreal two handles and me do it so
add a couple of lines in to safe
security pipelines starting remember
that your resources and the keys and
certificates cost money every mining
story hits your resources they cost
money and sometimes it may very strongly
impact your infrastructure and our team
was laughing when we was getting ready
for the presentations we went to the
places where miners are already present
so we found those ID kilometers of idea
when you go to Manila and insert and see
how much they have mined and we saw that
the two small clusters are mined some
some $600 if you multiply by a thousand
three you know they did it that's quite
lucrative this is a wonderful slide
where you see nothing that's the way it
should be there is an organization that
called called native computing
foundation that takes top utilities and
the announcers and distributes and they
broke down into categories there is a
link for you
it's an interactive map where you can
select I'm a developer I want this
utilities I'm a security guy I want
those utilities and you can go to the
public clusters utility and I'm done I
thank you
[Music]
unfortunately there is no time for
questions and after the presentation you
can approach the speaker personally