search operators and we're not supposed
to use essentially you can find this I
have a blog post blog blog post based on
its alan stanwyk ghost I do but other
than that let's have started we had some
good times last night was here for dual
core anyone stay for dual core a couple
people okay responsible afterwards right
very responsible so Dorking what is it
and how do we use so back in the day
there is a protocol called the web
exclusion protocol where it started out
saying that google had scrapers and
that's how google search engine work 6n
scraper BOTS out and they gather the
information of the website and put it
into their shirt database so the way you
could the way you're supposed to tell
that's where they weren't supposed to go
if i tell them to disallow them to go
there what's the problem with this is
that when you put it on your web site
your website goes my website calm /
robot dot PHP that's always going to be
there that's always that site that's the
robots.txt location so if you put that
in their attackers all of a sudden know
where you don't want them to go on top
of that they also have Google BOTS
happen to index things they're not
supposed to index to begin with so this
is part of the OWASP guide and this is
one of the very first things they use
and as you can see there there's a
couple of different search engines you
can use you can go through all of them
show it in most you're probably familiar
with that one by two you know all that
good stuff so here's a couple of the
more common operators that are useful
quotations search for the exact phrase
sites restrict to the site file types
you can restrict a certain file types so
for instance you work for cisco gear and
they know that the VPN Gringer typically
in the PCF file you can type file type
PCF and then all of a sudden you can
find all the publicly available cisco
dumps all in your own URL in url that
restricts with you just in the URL type
operators and or things like that and
then after you do the search you can
also do URL modifiers so once you get
the search you can copy and paste these
in and so the first one the QDR limits
by time frame and if you put in you know
s per second Denver minute H for our
stuff like that will restrict it to just
the past down and then the tvm restricts
it to just blogs apps images stuff like
that literal no auto correct that means
you will never get an auto correct
and then the disabled the personal
search the personalized search lets you
know what kind of a bubble urine so if
you ever want to try to get out of it
and see what Google might show you
naturally just paste that in at the
order to your search so there's a couple
of use cases and there was recently the
yahoo hack was recently supposedly done
by a Russian and one of the ways he did
it was identifying web servers with
Google so what can you get you can get
foothold you can get generic admin login
pages you can find all kinds of stuff
like that you may be able to get
credentials from that the credentials
might be reused somewhere else you can
do vulnerability search you can go for
pet certain files certain server types
certain specific versions of server
types things like that you can get
verbose error messages so if there's a
log message that you know that has you
know just way too much information in it
you can search for that and find out
what people are writing using it you can
do it for a recon enumeration and then
again you know you can find devices on
it in a similar way to show damn too so
this was a recent airbus support they
were an emergency 911 system and not
thing on twitter if you don't follow and
follow me is a very smart guy but he
basically said you know hey look look at
this worm support site where all of a
sudden when i change my user agent so I
tell google that and I'm no longer me
I'm a bot all of a sudden I can get
their login portal so the first part
footholds and pivots you can find file
uploads you can do with your url
mutations for it too so let's say these
two images here I had were a file upload
service that are based on similar tale
um you know underlying frameworks and
all that so I took you know X you too
and that was the in the the URL and I
thought well maybe they're doing a
version number so I tried xq three
actually one things like that to try and
see if you know they were older and
newer versions of the same thing so
vulnerabilities again servers files logs
software login admin portal you can find
crazy amounts of stuff with this
passwords database backup files uploaded
files site scrapes credentials files
again you can find crazy amounts of
stuff with
and one of the best things to do with it
is automate it as much as possible and
there's two cool tools for there's a
bunch of them out there but snitch is a
cool one and then what I really like
there's a new one by a guy named vector
and it's a it's called a like dork net
and I like it because it allows you not
way to use proxies it uses silentium the
bypass Google patches and then on top of
that it allows you to import custom list
most of them have like pre-built lists
they say oh enter this into it and you
know you'll start searching you don't
tell us to look for the vulnerable files
one will do that this one lets you
import your route so alright so here we
are and now i'm going to show you guys
how to change user agents there's two
ways you can do it you can download a
plugin for chrome called using a nand
changer and you can literally go through
and tell it it's useful developer tool
if you can see oh well what is my
website look like on all these different
devices and then if you go down you can
start telling it the year bot now if you
want to do it the manual way because you
don't want to rely on a tool you can
bring up the developer tools in chrome
here go to network and then network
conditions and then this is usually
checked select the user agent
automatically if you uncheck it all of a
sudden you can change it again now keep
in mind with that when you do it you
have to reload the page every time so
every time you do it will only work once
then you have to reload the page and
then go go away but other than that so
here the robots.txt for wall street
journal com and as you can see here is
all the disallowed parts they don't want
to go into there's you know some of the
stuff to sitemap stuff we're allowed to
go to and we're going to try going to
one of them that we're not supposed to
go to so all the
as you can see this is a part of their
site that you weren't supposed to be
able to get to but yet we're still
getting there without much of a problem
just because we knew where to look and
again you can do this admins will leave
admin pages like login screens all kind
of crazy stuff of it it's so easy to
find it sometimes it's almost setting
all right so let's start doing some
because this presentation is going to be
half just kind of blowing through giving
you the basic information and the rest
actually showing you how to use it so
this dork right here it takes the quotes
and it puts a PhD Mahler prove eight
mailer and then it's like the extension
and put your PT attention so all of a
sudden you can find publicly available
versions of the phpmailer that you might
be able to use and abuse they might have
default credentials you know stuff like
that and again for generic footholds you
know first place so you can start
getting into you can try uploading files
to their site that well maybe shouldn't
be there so all of a sudden we start
going through this and we start going to
Gingka or no okay so we got PHP airs it
sells so we got a Hawaiian 60s let's see
what happens over here in this one oh
hey there's actually two oh yeah so now
I just found a file upload page I can
just upload file to their site yeah but
that sounds cool right guys okay and
again this another one that searches for
a file upload
we're just reversing their directories
let's see where we can go now we can
just I mean you can just do so much
recon with this it's it's ridiculous so
this X you to this is one of the example
that brought up earlier and it brings us
to this which is the same thing we just
found with that generic file upload one
but then we notice down here it mentions
that extra upload v2 and this is what I
was talking about when I said you know
I'll try looking at different version
numbers and new Meridian because if you
look at the URL there it says X you two
extra upload to so maybe there's a first
version make it Xu one maybe there's an
extra three you know try doing that you
can not only you know take these door
from these are all publicly available
you can go to exploit DB for the Google
door from database and these are all
just publicly available so you can
create your own out of one's others have
already created for you and then again
there's you know just some of the other
one actually 1x you three things like
that and then you can also just trying
going back directories so maybe that
dork was just too exclusive maybe it
excluded some search results all of a
sudden we go we go back just you know
one little directory there and we're
finding you know slightly more getting
some in different languages you know
there's only three on that first one so
alright so now finding vulnerabilities
this one is a PHP author of
authentication bypass dork so the second
you type it into Google I'm not a robot
believe me see how good of a robot I not
am geez Google there you go
no I am a robot after all so there's an
admin panel for the very personal type
that comes up the peach babe in town
just like that and again it searches for
one that has a specific known
vulnerability so you can go and look at
recent see bees that are dropping go and
look it you know vulnerabilities from
last year five years ago and if you know
what specific one you're looking for you
can just and find all the publicly
available ones and if you're using it on
an actual engagement like with what
certain client you can use a site
operator and then you can say it do it
so that it only a text their site so
you're not searching the whole internet
anymore you're just doing their
particular website so this one again
talking about looking for very specific
versions by using the in-text modifier
there you can look for the version
number seven point three two and that
again has a specifically known
vulnerability vulnerable files so this
one here will look for publicly
available fire files later shared on
onedrive so if you happen to know that
so what the client you're using uses
Microsoft products they use onedrive for
you know uploading their files you can
start searching and going through people
and see who shared something by
exhibition it maybe there's a Patroclus
that I key left somewhere you know maybe
some sea level somewhere that has
administrative access to the network
left their password file on their
onedrive and now all of a sudden you're
just looking for it so this one
for ssl king okay so there we are
there's their authority-- just like that
that was hard right now this one is
going to look for recently there was a
lot of MongoDB instances that were being
right white because they had default
credentials you know they were left open
on the internet stuff like that this
will specifically look for those types
of servers and there's still more than
10 pages of search results of them still
publicly available even after how many
of them got home still there this one
this one's a really cool one if you pay
attention when you're using you know any
kind of website that you you know you
frequent often you can just say okay
well take the way the URL looks and then
this one will look for wordpress backup
file that often contain the passwords
the users credentials in them and here's
a bunch of wordpress sites where we can
probably find our credentials like that
now this one is a really cool this looks
for specific versions of openssl that
are vulnerable to attack and this attack
again known for a long time now and
there's MIT showing up really okay well
you know so one more try out move on to
passwords so and this is really one of
the when you're doing the custom tools
the scrapers the automated part of it
this is one of the cool ones because you
can start using it and search password
dumps and you can start thinking okay
well maybe I should just scrape these
collects them collate them and say well
okay what are people's most common
passwords that are you so i can increase
my hash cat so that way i have better
rainbow tables stuff like that that way
you can find you know the most common
passwords and again this is looking for
anything that has gmail com and password
in it so this is probably people
uploading documents with their own
password leave the whole company's in
there that was crap and what this one is
a much cool looking at home so this is
going to search github for publicly
available passwords so it has anything
at the extension CSP and then it has
user ID user name user example blah blah
blah and there is a scatter password
list so if you want to know the the
default passwords to any of these
vendors devices there you go you just
found it less than a second and this one
again like I was saying before if you
know certain file types you can do you
can search for the dumps of the
credential so here we are but see what
these guys password is see so you're the
good one what do you guys think you're
going to use a good password or like a
default or something no user password a
little user password that's sound like a
good one right what do you expecting you
just down to the Google you know let's
see let's try find another one here and
again just use a password but what do
you expect really to be honest oh right
let's go big yeah that's pretty much it
on you guys have any questions comments
concerns about the presentation here
video is pretty it's pretty
straightforward again you can literally
just go to exploit exploit DB com use
these publicly available ones find them
and use them against anyone companies
you know use them for scraping for you
know data gathering you know whatever
you want so get to Dorking you dorks
what are you waiting for red yeah
the capacitance yeah yeah and that's
actually um I was having a problem
installing one of the tools one of the
modules because i had a demo that i was
going to do with one of the newer tools
that came out but one way you can get
around it is that tool users selenium
and it uses web gecko so it kind of
makes its way around and you can also
you know if you input a proxy list stuff
like that you know you can get start
getting by it through that yep that's
unfortunately just going on the history
of the product itself and not really I
mean what can you do to stop it the
protocol still exists I mean it's the
only way that Google spiders work I mean
they would have to change that what
their entire operation probably i mean
that's just it's just not going to
happen it's unfortunate but i mean you
know you're going to do anyone else all
right well thanks for coming guys i hope
you have a good rest of the day here
today