for recording do I sound okay hear me in
the back oh alright so this is
cryptography 0 2 128 in 15 minutes
because it's a 15 minute time slot so
our goal is to cram as much cryptography
into 15 minutes as possible I am NOT a
mathy person so I don't explain
cryptography in terms of math which if
your math a person may be a bad thing
but I think for most of you that's going
to be a good thing I work blue team so
I'm thinking practically about what does
this mean to me not o theoretically an
attacker could maybe I want to know
cannon attack or do it or can't they win
can they win campaign so it's going to
be very practical and it's a subject
like cryptography and we're cramming
into 15 minutes so this is going to be
very fast-paced so I am vegt I saima
Bloomsburg University Alumni I graduated
with degrees in digital forensics and
anthropology i'm a huge nerd I'm play of
the games and I run of the Linux I have
never shown up to a LAN party running
anything except one I'm proud of that
I'm currently working for the blue team
for one of our sponsors g3 technologies
okay so who deals with crypto well if
you do digital forensics to deal with
crypto if you do I are you deal with
crypto if you do Red Team you do with
crypto if you do blue team you with
crypto if you connect to the internet on
your smartphone yoohoo crypto so this is
relevant everybody although Baylor talk
seems pretty cool so I wouldn't have
blamed you had gone to this topics we're
going to cover symmetric cryptography
stuff like a s where you have one key on
both sides both em crypt and decrypt
asymmetric cryptography where one key
encrypt and then the other Wendy Crips
and then the other person also has a key
pair one of which encrypts the other
windy crypts Pasha's um who hears
forensic background okay so you should
all be familiar with hashes
pseudo-random number generators these
are actually really important as we're
about to see this one of the four things
you need to do cryptography ours actual
random numbers that practically can't be
attacked cryptographic protocols you get
really do much
with just one algorithm with one
primitive you have to fit them together
to do something meaningful and then
slide general attacks so when you're
designing a cryptographic protocol
you're thinking well what can the
attacker know and generally you're not
thinking well the attacker can know how
many milliseconds it takes me to do my
calculations that's a side channel it's
not it's not attacking the crypto
directly it's chatting it into it so for
things that are necessary for strong
cryptography you want to be successful
you have strong algorithms probably know
if this is the easiest to get right
because I can just give you a list of
use these algorithms don't use these
algorithms or if you want to break it
down you can use these algorithms in
these circumstances but not these
circumstances so this is the easiest
part you're going to configure SSH
you're going to configure a cell for a
website that that's the easy part next
one a source of random numbers when
you're making a key to actually be able
to do some kind of encryption or
decryption it has to be random so the
attacker can guess it and then we're
constantly making nonces and
initialization vectors that also
generally have to have some entropy to
them this is often mess up but it's
pretty easily solvable you just need to
make sure that you do it and you don't
forget about it next correct
implementation making an implementation
of an algorithm that doesn't have side
channels is really hard ensuring that
your implementation of something does
what you think it does is hard and
lastly robust protocols arguably we've
never done this if you look at the
history of a complex protocol like pls
and SSL which would you use the yo
connect to google the HTTPS yes Forster
means is actually going through an
encrypted tunnel that's a complex
protocol with like four different major
steps and you know four different kinds
of cryptography going into it ah it's
had issue after issue after issue after
issue why is this big ugly and complex
making a correct protocol is really
really hard so we're going to start with
symmetric cryptography going to talk
about block ciphers and stream ciphers
is the requirements for a symmetric
cipher if the attacker seats out what
they are not allowed to know what the
input is this is the whole you know
point of doing this is that if I have a
secret message that I need to tell dr.
montante I encrypt it dr. montante also
knows the secret key I encrypt it with
the key hand it to him I can also hand
it to Rio and Rio can't find out what
the message was and then dr. montaje can
find out with met Strich because he also
has the key okay the other thing is that
he can't recover the key because if you
can recover the key then you can then
decrypt it as well results requirement
it's not always relevant but there are
situations where an attacker can
actually hand a good guy data to be
encrypted and exceed the output so in a
situation like that it's important that
the attacker not be able to find the key
from doing that even if they can do it a
bunch of times ciphers start start start
easy route 13 the transposition cipher
rotates through the alphabet 13 forward
that sounds pretty secure right you know
fixed key and 26 should be even more
secure write something about I only know
one company that is ignorant enough to
actually use rot13 to try to protect
something I'll let you guess what
company that is so I bring this up for
dreams 1 it's a classic example of a
simple cipher that caesar wrap your head
around the other one is it's a
transposition cipher which is going to
come back up later we talked about black
fibers the actual real parent cipher of
all modern cryptography is the one time
pad so in a one-time pad you have a key
that is the same length as your message
you take your low entropy message that's
human readable and your random we have
to be true random key and use or them
together and then you get gobbledygook
out that looks random then if you take
that same one-time pad again you soared
across again you get your input out
we're going to talk about in a little
bit more detail limitations here the key
size is equal to the message size if I
have a one gig file I want to transfer
to you I either they need to through
some out secure outside channel give you
a gig one-time pad or I had to have
already given you a really big one time
pad that you're now using a chunk of it
so you're moving huge keys around which
is
impractical and how it works is the
cipher texts the Playtex resort /
one-time pad so stock codes or who here
knows Zork if i give you a bite two
bites you could throw them together who
here has never heard absorb before okay
so a couple of our forensic students
that's that's great I was very
disappointed when my friends with math
classes didn't cover this but did cover
like all kinds of other things that
weren't important so you take two bits
of the time if the bits are different it
so the output is a one if there's the
same the output is a 0 so 0 0 0 0 1 1 is
a 0 0 1 is a 110 is a one ok it
preserves the difference the cool thing
about this is that it's reversible so
plug the encrypt and decrypt look at the
column we've got 110 so we're going to
secret key again 01 so the output is 1
we've reversed it and this works across
the entire thing so once I've had really
really simple except when it's not so
when you reuse a one-time pad zorry to
puppy if you it's one time because you
can only use it once if you use that
same key again you're going to break the
security of both of them there is is
because you can encrypt to you can zorb
together to remove the key and you'll
end up with a mash of the two messages
if you have more than two things that's
been encrypted with the same one-time
pad you can do even more fun stuff this
also allows you to guess plain text if
you guess correctly you'll decrypt the
plaintext for all of them and other
stuff like that so example this first
message suncast bitmap Zord against the
one-time pad get gobbledygook out
different message zorgons one-time pad
get gobbly gook out zuhr the two
encrypted messages together completely
removes the encryption but it's a jumble
of the two messages but the encryption
Scott and thank you to crypto Smith for
doing a really great visual
representation of what this actually
looks so
for a couple we have a two issues with
one-time pads right one of them is that
we have this whole reuse issue where we
have to generate a 100-percent unique
pad for every message we want to encrypt
and the other one is that we have to
move around these huge keys of the same
size of the message stream ciphers are a
way to solve that so the first thing we
do is we don't exchange a one-time pad
we have a pseudo-random number generator
that will generate a pad basement seed
then we exchange seeds we both generate
the same pad and then we can do one-time
pad with it and logically this is how
stream ciphers work even though
internally the the pseudo-random number
generator in the combination step are
mixed together this is still logically
how you can think about there's
important because you can still do the
whole boring together thing brings the
other thing they take a not we're going
to talk about that more but right now
usually know that I can keep using the
same seed the same key and just change
my number used once and as long as I
never repeat that number and key
together I will always be secure because
the nonce changes the output but then it
can be attack or narrowing so block
ciphers stream cipher is taking a bit
another bit and encrypts them here's the
next bit you know also think it was
encrypting a stream at a time watched
over six of junk and grips takes the
next chunk grips takes the next jump
Crips there's time Chris generally
old-school block ciphers were 64-bit
blocks newer good ones are 128 bit
blocks are not going to go over why that
matters but it does so the most common
construction for how a block cipher
actually works is that it be a
substitution to say four plus those
transposition cipher so a substitution
cipher is something really easy like if
i say rio no really I mean been in this
email and I send dr. montante an email
and every time he sees Rio he goes meta
that actually that means been that's a
substitution cipher and it turns out
that if you combine a substitution
cipher in a transposition cipher like
rot13 but not rotating through an
alphabet protonating through all
possible bite values and that where that
substance or the rotation of the
transposition depends on the key you can
actually have a publicly known
substitution cipher and it was
constructed correctly you can substitute
rotate mix the stuff around substitute
mix the stuff around substitute mixed
stuff around and if you do that for
enough rounds it becomes infeasible to
figure out what the input was or what
the key was based on the output and
that's how des works and that's how a es
works so stream ciphers everything onto
his one-time pad you can never reuse a
key stream ciphers at least good ones
take a second value it's either an
initialization vector which means that
it's unique and random or not the number
used once a nonce doesn't need to be
random you may started in a random place
but it can just be a counter just has to
be unique and never be reused with the
same key so for example of how this is
failed in practice rc4 inside of web
anybody have the raytheon singla jigs
breathing on challenge codes I know
we've come to have them there's our c4
on there for you to try to break our c4
so our c4 has its own issues but when
they implemented in weapon was during a
time when the government had
restrictions on strong cryptography you
weren't allowed to have strong
cryptography so they restricted both the
key size but also the initialization
vector 24 bits means there's two to the
24 possibilities for that initialization
vector it means eventually you encrypt
enough packets moving over your Wi-Fi
channel eventually it's going to repeat
and when it repeats you'll have the same
team the same not used and you can then
decrypt that's content even if you
replace our c4 with something stronger
something like a counter mode or ChaCha
20 as long as the initialization vector
was that short you would always have
these repeating nonsense yeah okay
if we had already exchanged a one-time
pad and I wanted to give you another one
that was the same size and the first one
was trust insecure so we knew we were
allowed to use it I could then send you
a second one using the first one and
then we could use the second one for
something else but we're still stuck
with the same exact situation in terms
of who has what keys right we still have
we started with one usable key and we
ended with one usable key of whatever
size so we absolutely can but there's
not really a point does it make sense
we're going to get to the key change
when we get out of symmetric Gupta okay
so stream ciphers that are good didn't
you should use not our c4 chacha 20 AES
and counter mode we're going to get to
how a s which is a block cipher is also
a stream cipher and they SGC n which is
a counter mode that has authentication
built into it instead of doing your own
doing a message authentication code to
check whether or not a was changed so
block ciphers one block at a time is his
head script block that's on crip the
block pass it on different block modes
do different things for example ECB mode
just grabs a chunk encrypts it passes it
on the problem with that is that the
same input data will perform the same
output data every single time we're
going to see what that actually looks
like in a minute good news about block
ciphers they resist the Kokiri use thing
so even if you don't have an answer to
say we're initialization vector you want
one for a reason you're going to see but
even if you don't have one you can do
the whole soaring stuff together to get
stuff out you can't do it resist that
I'm the technical term for the
substitute rotate thing is perm uation
substitution so the perm you ate is the
change it and the substitute is map one
symbol input two different symbol output
okay this leads to an avalanche effect
which is also important for hashes where
if you change one bit of the input every
bit of the output changes different blog
modes we're going to
way okay for example counter mode take
some of the input puts it back into the
important and has a counter on it so it
turns aes or some other block cipher
into a stream cipher and that once did
you do that it behaves like a stream
cipher then it has the soaring against
this health issues and things like that
good blocks loads use an initialization
nectar or not block ciphers to love and
use a s in CBC mode the the of a s ones
that are turned into streams types are
also good but there are pluses okay
nobody's going to laugh don't worry so
this is ECB versus CBC for that image
anybody want to want to take a guess
what the issue is with ECB mode you can
still see it so though the white blocks
up in the corner get encrypted to a
particular value that is glitter Lee
being interpreted still as pixels and
everywhere that it's the same white
pixel value it's the same kind of ugly
looking black pixel value outside and
then every other place that's the same
exact pixel value turns into the same
exact bit value that is then being still
interpreted so you still see the shape
what may be an even better example is
this tux linux penguin this is very very
there's a version of a very famous one
because the using tux the linux mascot
is an example of ECB mode is kind of a
tradition app but i don't know if you
can see it we even still see the
individual like chunk of two pixels or
whatever it is it's one block worth of
data so all right questions on symmetric
crypto Gregory first
so to a security professional ECB is a
joke the problem is that missed when
they made the standard didn't actually
test their block modes so they came up
with like six or eight different block
modes and you only really want to use
one of them most of them are fine ECB is
really not yet so the reason why I use
images in that example is because the
human eye can see the issues with ECB
mode the same issue exists no matter
what your data is if it's any kind of
predictable structured data the
structure will be preserved at a bit as
a resolution of whatever your block
sizes so the issue exists regardless of
what you're doing but pictures / bitmaps
particularly are really nice because you
can see the issue there's a performance
I don't actually know if there's a big
performance difference I think strange
diapers maybe slightly softer you know
there seems to be a smiled preference
for using stream ciphers these days as
partially because we'd prefer
authenticated encryption so chacha 20
actually has a message authentication
code that it uses asgn uses the gallio's
counter mode message authentication code
all the ones that they made it where
it's the authentication the basically
it's a sign hash of the stuff so you
know that it wasn't tampered with for
the ones that is built in with that high
performance the ones we've done out of
stream ciphers and it's part of why they
prefer them ultimately in terms of
security you can have a completely
secure block flavor or a completely
secure stream cipher and my
understanding is the biggest impact on
performance barring weird things where
you're getting your data is what the
algorithm you use is so I'd it's your
question any other questions before we
move on
okay that was symmetric this is a
symmetric we have two keys per person or
four people talking right so
requirements given a public key the
attacker must not be able to find the
private key so I have a public key I
give it to dr. montante he is a public
hehe gives it to me he's allowed to give
it to all of you as well it's public but
if Rio evil Rio wants to try to find one
of our private keys he shouldn't be able
to from knowing our public key next
given a cyber attacks an attacker must
not be able to recover the plaintext say
basic encryption if it's encrypted you
can't decrypt it next given the a
ciphertext and a public key for the
private key that did the encryption you
also can't find the plain text or the
private key right because you're going
to have more information and you have to
worry more about data leakage and again
given the ability of data encrypted by
the private key of the attacker must not
to be able to recover the private key
there are many situations where an
attacker it's not all the time but live
protocols where an attacker can give you
a good guy data to have it encrypted and
I can see the output so if that happens
it's important that they not be able to
use that to recover the private key okay
so it's back to crypto AKA public key
cryptography because it requires a
public key and a private key it's often
called public key cryptography every
person generates a key pair the public
key encrypt and the private key decrypt
but if you encrypt with the private key
you encrypt or you decrypt with the
public key so we can use this as a
secure messaging protocol right dr.
montante and I know know each other's
public keys I have a message I encrypt
it I hand it to dr. montante I also hand
it to Rio Rio doesn't know dr. montante
is private key so he can't decrypt it
dr. montante does so I know the only
person who can possibly decrypt the
message is the intended recipient now on
the flip side how does dr. montante know
it was me that sent him the message well
if I take a hash of the message and then
I encrypt it with my private key then my
public key will be able to decrypt that
but it's not a secret just
well by doing that I proven I've signed
it in such a way that nobody else could
possibly have tampered with the message
so then dr. montante gets it calculates
pash he decrypts using my public key the
sign passion bola hash was the same he
knows it was for me for a handshake for
what for Wi-Fi so I believe like TLS
uses a three-way handshake and it's
doing this the one that I know of this
for is Wi-Fi 4shared keys no a little
different but yes there is a back and
forth that goes on and we're going to
talk about that next so really mentioned
well how do we get keys back and forth
like you know with a one-time pad or
with something else well the answer is I
can encrypt a key with dr. Mann tante's
public key and then I know only he has
that key and then we now have exchanged
a key and practically if we were
actually going to do something like
encrypted email that's how we would do
it the body of the email would be
encrypted with something like AES and I
would give him that AES key using public
key encryption the reason is because
public key encryption really only works
on messages smaller than the key size
the other so the simple option is to
just use encryption like I just
described a better thing to do is do
little fancy mathematics where I know
dr. montante is public key and he knows
my public key and we can exchange back
and forth a couple of non stal use and
we can actually come to an agreement on
a key and Rio can watch everything going
back on the fourth on the network and he
can know both of our public keys and he
still can't figure out what key we
agreed on and this is based on the same
mathematics as so RSA like the
encryption or in the terms of a look
curve based on Sam mathas elliptical
curve other stuff the this exchange is
called diffie-hellman key exchange or 2p
Hellman key agreements and that's how
practically how two people can exchange
a key every time you go to a website
there's this whole verification of the
websites certificate which I'm about to
talk about and then you've picked a
bikini and then you do diffie-hellman
some variation of difficult man to
exchange a key and then in within your
TLS connection and all your data is
encrypted with that symmetric key so
certificate is okay so dr. montante
wants to know what messages for me and
he knows it's from a particular key how
does he know that to my key well
certificates are a public statement of
this is who I am so it's got data about
you practically they have like your
business your address fully qualified
domain name and email bunch of stuff
looks which is very silly and then the
public key and then it's signed so again
we have hash and then encrypted with a
private key of some trusted third party
or some equivalent signature algorithm
so that then I don't know who this
person is but I see that they're signed
their certificate is signed by that
person I don't know who they are but I
see their certificate signed by that
person you can chain this back up until
you find somebody that I trust if I
don't find anybody I trust I don't trust
that certificate this is how this is
called public key infrastructure it is a
royal pain to manage record and this is
how when you go to a website you know
that google com is actually google com
is that you connect your browser grabs a
certificate it looks to that certificate
is signed by and follows the chain up
and then it checks whether or not it
trust the top of that list same thing if
you like your oh you're on Windows
you're going to install something it
says you know from oracle corporation
well the reason it knows it's from
oracle is because of that binary you're
installing was signed with Oracle's with
a private key associated with Oracle
certificate you can then verify okay so
algorithms to know and use carefully you
may have noticed there are a couple more
requirements in terms of what
need to do to be secured that's because
these are more fragile than symmetric
algorithms so it's actually easier to
screw up asymmetric stuff used carefully
RSA is still okay have to be careful
with what it's being used for but you
can still use it okay and productively
diffie-hellman there's a version called
ephemeral diffie-hellman that's what the
e stands for prefer that one you means
you keeping a key thank you for like two
minutes something like that instead of
using the same to you forever so we have
the Edwards curve digital signature
algorithm so there's a different one
that's not based on Edwards curves it's
ecdsa elliptical curb digital signature
algorithm that one's curves are junk you
can't write a constant time
implementation which we're going to talk
about why that matters later Edwards
curve one doesn't have that issue it's
constant time they also made it so you
don't need a nonce to do the signature
because it's using a hash to generate
the knots value so that's cool and then
elliptical curve diffie-hellman is the
lipstick which is dip Yellen but based
on an elliptical curves so RSA is
basically multiplied as an encryption
function elliptical curves are
multiplied across a weird graph as an
encryption function so that's that's the
difference a lot of people like
elliptical curves because they're
stronger for the same key size and
they're still fasting feud stuff but you
can do diffie-hellman using that
mathematics as a basis and you still
want the ephemeral version so questions
about asymmetric cryptography yeah you
never have to make loo your browser to
use for that for you and the reason for
that is because bra websites don't
verify users users only need to verify
the website so it doesn't really matter
what your browser does it can generate a
new one every day or new whatever
connection or whatever it wants my guess
is for performance reasons they probably
don't go that far but I don't actually
know but it's because you're only
verifying the website that your browser
can do more or less whatever it wants
for performance reasons there's a lot of
cashing that goes on but if it doesn't
have the one then yet it will have to go
out and pull the next one or get it from
the website itself you can actually have
your website set up to not only provide
its own certificate but also the limits
find it and potentially the entire chain
so it has to get it from somewhere and
that's really matter where it gets it
because it's cryptographically
guaranteed whether it's correct sites
your question other questions I was
expecting lots of questions on a
symmetric Wow hashes know them love them
use them all the time so a hash is an
algorithm that takes a variable sized
input and produces a fixed size output I
can mean I can do a blank cash you can
do a hash of nothing and it will produce
the hash you can do a hash of a few bits
you can do a hash of a few bikes you can
do a hash a few gigs you can do a hash
of a terabyte you do a hash of a
petabyte if the hash output is always
going to be the same fixed number of
bits out doesn't matter how much data
you shoved through it the other thing is
a 1-bit change in the input will produce
a dramatic change in the output looks
like same avalanche thing that we talked
about with block ciphers very very
important hashes has to be one way had
given an output the attacker must not be
able to find an input anybody go to the
hash reversal talk yesterday okay one
person he did a really good job of
explaining hash functions and all that
stuff so go on iron geek calm and go
watch that talk because it was awesome
given an input and output must not do
the attack must not be able to find a
second input with the same output thanks
certificate right Rio has evil Rio has
my public key and my certificate my
certain areas my public key my
information about me a hash of that and
in the ashes sign if he can so he knows
the input and the output of the hash
from
if he can find a different public key
one that he generates it'll hash to the
same thing he can forge a certificate
that looks real that verifies you do the
signature verification it verifies as
being mine but actually it's it this is
why getting away from sha-1 is so
important because if you're going to a
website shell one collisions means
somebody can manually as well as VPN
connections and everything else to use
okay so this is called collision
resistance that you can't find us
another input that'll have the same
output so hashes know and love Shah
three like two skeins sha256 and shop at
12 these are all good the figure shows
have been around for a while they're
still solid shot three like two and sky
and are all from the Shah three
competition the keck keck is the
algorithm that one and became sha-3 but
the other two finalists were also really
strong and there are a lot of people
that prefer Blake to over show three
hashes to burn and salt the earth md5
and sha-1 shall what is expensive to
find a collision but governments can do
it companies can probably do it as well
md5 is trivial you can generate a
collision on your laptop of seconds
which means that for forensics you can't
trust md5 for example that shows
software reference library is a list of
hashes of known good stuff that you can
ignore in a forensic investigation
pretty sure its distributors md5 they
may have improved that now I could have
a malicious file that I find a collision
for something that's in the NS RL and
then voila it's being emitted from your
forensic investigation because you
trusted empty pot if you absolutely have
to use md5 to compare to somebody else's
md5 hash that's fine just make sure that
you have some hash it's a
cryptographically secure one we're also
going to talk about password hashing I
know we had a password hash reversal
talk yesterday I've incorporated into my
job so if you're going to store a
password you do want to hash the
password
so how this works is I oven I'm a
website in my database I have a hash for
a certain user so many blogs on claiming
to be that user they hand me a string
that's their password I hash it and
compare the hash the hash is the same
the string inputs were the same the
person knows the bathroom so what type
of hash do we want to use well we don't
want to use the same hash as we use for
something else you need something
specifically designed for passwords or
for he de River a shin that key
derivation is really syntax to want
something insulted and iterated so
assault is a value that can be known by
the attacker when they steal the hash
but you don't want them to know before
that and it's stored with the hash in
plaintext is just there and it's a
second input to the hashing algorithm
that'll change the output think of this
is kind of like the nonce when we're
doing encryption eiv something can be
known the goal of assault is to prevent
pre-computation attacks that the
attacker only finds out the salt value
once they've actually stolen the hash so
they can couldn't have done any work to
speed things up before they steal the
hatch okay so traditionally this would
be a rainbow table it's an optimized
space optimization on a lookup table
where the attacker just has a list of
fancy list again talk yesterday explain
this much better than I ever could of
what input maps what output and so they
see the output they just look it up in
the dictionary just a dictionary lookup
to crack your password that's a
pre-computation attack to do something
like that against hash that has a salt
it's now exponentially larger because
you have to then calculate every input x
every salt value go talk yesterday the
bloom reversal technique also defeated
will reversals a whole lot faster than
rainbow tables but it's also
exponentially larger if it's salted and
iterated hatches are slow so when you're
practically because hash functions can't
be reversed you have to guess inputs to
see if the output is correct as an
attacker that's what you have to do so
the slower the hash function is the
longer it takes an attacker you can get
a hash function you increase the work
factor until it's taking like 15
milliseconds
that is going to take the attacker for
ever so next which what algorithms you
want to use argon 2's scripts and bcrypt
in that order so what are the issues
here is that the attackers generally
have better nicer more specialized
hardware than the good guys do great one
is GPUs right if you're going to do
Bitcoin mining is basically this type of
operation hash you know password
cracking you can use a GPU that means
the attacker is really cracking a lot
faster than you're using it so something
that will crush your website the
attacker can play strip you want to even
that imbalance between attacker and
defender and you do that by choosing a
hash function a password hashing
algorithm that is also hard for
attackers for example decrypt doesn't
run very fast on GPUs so even though you
can paralyze it on the GPU it's still
running so slow that you would be better
off with cpu as opposed to something
like sha-256 cribs or pbk day of two
that runs like 100 times faster on a GPU
than it does on a cpu all right argon to
an S crypt gain this equalizing force by
being memory hard there's a time memory
trade-off the more memory attacker
throws at it the faster it runs if your
memory constraint is going to run really
slow this means that even if an attacker
builds like a super customize a sick or
fpga board that that board all it does
is calculate that hash they're still
going to have to stick a big Ram notch
upon it and RAM is expensive so this is
going to drive up the price is going to
keep things equal between a tachometer
if you have to be standardized you have
to use something in this standard use
pbk df2 but turn on the pepper feature
TB heyday of two as i mentioned
accelerates on GPU and everything else
it doesn't have this equalizing factor
which is why you should exceed this
standard and use something else but if
you have to be standardized USP pKa of
you and then use the pepper feature the
pepper feature is actually an encryption
key that encrypts the passwords as well
so that and then you store it someplace
else other than when your passwords are
so then you've increased the attackers
work this isn't foolproof because of the
attacker is completely in your system
they can steal that as well
doing something that snow protects you
no matter what the attack does things
not to do don't store the passwords in
plain text hopefully this crowd that
makes intuitive sense to don't don't
encrypt them being having having to be
reversible is bad particular because
you're gonna have to have the key around
someplace to then be able to check
candidate passwords you're comparing so
that's not what we want we want the
one-way function of the hash that's not
reversible and then don't swim in a
straight md5 or straight anything else
it needs to be salted iterated otherwise
rainbow tables and the really crazy
stuff that the noblest guys we're
talking about yesterday will work and
you can crack like really crazy
passwords in like 15 minutes all right
questions about hashing and password
storage in the back
yeah you can think of them as being the
same thing it's the exact same idea in
there by having something that's going
to be different for every person were
you know adding uniqueness so another
issue if you don't have a salt if both i
and rio have the same password we're
going to have the same salt it'll save
so many time ago these two people use
the same password if you have the salt
is different and it prevents
pre-computation thank you for next isn't
isn't that what's used in decrypt we'll
have to double check that but I believe
that the the magic the special sauce
that makes decrypt work is that it has
low fishes really expensive key set up
step and that's the part that's really
slow on GPU so we can double check that
on how fast you want to crack it
practically it still runs fairly fast on
a GPU with a decent amount of memory the
thing is it's a time memory trade-off
the more RAM you give the algorithm the
faster you can get it to run the less
Ram you have the slower it runs so it's
not like EU you need a certain amount
its leads to trade off the more you give
it the faster you can crack it that make
sense what one terabyte of memory is
going to be oodles and oodles and oodles
of money like Ram RAM gets exponentially
expensive the more you have so if you're
going to try to crack a bunch of these
things it's going to be very very
expensive no no I can't even imagine
that the other cool thing about like
argon 2 and s script is that they are
also intended to be parallelized so you
actually force the attacker to use a
certain number of threads to efficiently
calculate your stuff so if you're on
like a 16 thread Xeon you optimize it
for that number and then that's going to
eat up that many channels in the
attacker tacker system we get in the
back no we
have shall run chawan be gone now if not
sooner if not a few years ago so the
research paper that Google took and ran
with I forget here they were doing the
research side by side with it's been
known for years that you will be able to
find collisions in sha-1 it's just that
nobody had proven it and to put the nail
in shaa ones coffin Google actually came
out that got the supercomputer they did
it and they calculated a sha-1 collision
2020s too late today is too late we
needed to have this stuff gone years ago
it's actually very likely that china has
been intercepting VPN traffic by forging
certificates which either means they
broke our essay or they broke sha wan so
this is an issue and it needed to have
installed a long time ago so you stored
in the database with the password so
window when a person creates a user
account you randomly generate them
assault preferably through a good source
of randomness which I might be the next
thing we talked about and then you just
get stored in the database if you look
in the X shadow file on Linux you're
actually going to see a little number
that tells you hey this is what version
of hashing algorithm we have you're
going to see a salt value a separator
and then the hash right that's exactly
how you'd sort in a database for users
logging in or anything else you just
generate the salt and you store it with
their password that makes sense right so
the whole point is that you want to
prevent pre-computation username is
publicly known long before that so there
are systems that have done that but it's
not a good idea it's much better to
choose it'd be random in particular
device vendors also did that for like
Wi-Fi and other things like that for
theirs where it was the vendor name that
was the salt and that was really bad
which is why on a lot of like routers
and stuff you like to see vendor name
dash something something something godly
cook because they're still using it as
the salt but now they've changed it so
their name is different Kirkuk
I have no idea so it's been known for
quite a few years the sha-1 was having
problems and that's why they put up shop
3 when they started the shell three
competition because they thought that
shot two would be broken as well but as
far as I know nobody's found any any
like cracks in sha2 that are going to
make it look like it's going to be
broken in a few years sha1 we knew it
was going to be broken shot to it's not
looking like it's going to be broken
quickly so there's I don't have data to
guess probably not in the next few years
right
so collision resistance is not a
requirement of a password hashing
function you don't care whether or not
there are collisions you care about that
for certificates and file verification
so you can have a super crazy you know
sháá 2048 that's based on Shah three
and it's super powerful it's still not a
good way to store a password because
it's not salted and it's not iterated
and it will accelerate really fast on a
GPU that make sense so you actually want
to use a goal whole different set of
requirements and everything's you're
looking for when you're storing a
password compared to comparing two files
to prove through the same
you can still you can still run
paralyzes very very well on a GPU now
you're not using anywhere near enough
memory you want to use a few Meg's /
require at least a couple Meg's / / hash
when you're doing that calculation so
that's what you can do with that script
in argon too so accept any other
questions before I move on okay and I
was right to the random number
generators our nags so the requirements
for a cryptographically secure
pseudo-random generator every
programming language out there has some
kind of ran function or a random object
that will give you a random numbers they
are not cryptographically secure in fact
if your do have any red team people yeah
that's depressing so do we have any
other blue team people in you okay there
we go so if you're saying generating a
user token or a session cookie or a
password reset code or anything else
like that using an off-the-shelf ran
function from PHP JavaScript Java sea's
people us whatever by seeing one maybe
two of those outputs an attacker can
recover the internal state of student
random number generator and figure out
every number it will ever generate shoes
I can figure out the next one that's
going to be generated okay I've seen
demonstrations where people actually
reset their own password find that and
then reset somebody else's password they
don't have the email for but then they
know what the code is going to be so you
don't want to use a regular
pseudo-random number generator you want
to use a cryptographically secure one so
the requirements given the output the
attacker must not be able to predict
this see this seed value is just like a
key okay it has to be a secret the
attacker knows that they can generate
the entire string and then two then
given the output the attacker must not
be able to figure out the next thing so
the reason I just told you as well is
not the previous things so if we do
something like generate a nonce value
that's going to be publicly known and
then we generate a key that's going to
be publicly known or that it has to be a
secret it's really really importantly
attack or not be able to figure out what
the next thing to be generated will be
or vice versa so these are actually
really easy to build
if you have a secure hash function you
just need a seed and a counter and then
that counter is a number used once never
going to be repeated which means you're
going have unique values output from the
hash which really easy most things that
do hash-based pseudo-random number
generators are shoving way more data
into them because they're also using as
an entropy collector given a secure
stream cipher you can make a PNG out of
it by just having an encrypted zeros I
mentioned before that logically they are
a pseudo-random number generator if it's
secure as a stream cipher it's equally
secures a pseudo-random number generator
and vice versa practically most
cryptographically secure random number
generators are made out of stream
ciphers either chacha 20 or a s and
counter mode which brings us to give it
a secure block cipher you can run it in
a block mode that turns it into a stream
cipher and voila you have a stream
cipher encrypt Algiers you've got random
numbers so if these are easy to build
how do they fail so I mentioned before
number one reason people don't use them
all right there in their PHP app and
there's like you know land same thing
with see same thing with everything else
you don't use it that problem the other
one is you need entropy in that seat ok
so we're cheating here we're not
actually generating I'm going to output
you know a 256-bit key and I'm then I'm
going to generate ten more of them or
100 more of them where I'm going to be
generating random naw nonces for
hundreds of connections on my system
over the next couple of days uh I don't
have you know a couple gigs of random
data to pull those out of we're cheating
all we have is a short little seed which
means that to take that seed and expand
it to something big you need to make
sure that there's actually some entropy
in the sea what is entities entropy
technically its randomness from the
statistical or mathematical sense
practically and should be a stuff an
attacker cannot possibly know if there's
no way the attacker can ever find it out
that's an acceptable source of ramen so
how linux does this is hard drive head
timing jitter there's just the physical
system of a hard drive or it's got the
platter and the head moving back over to
read data that's not predictable there's
always going to be a little bit
difference between each head and then as
it wears down
things like that the other one is mouse
and keyboard events we're not actually
good at generating randomness but if
you're recording every little twitch of
our mouse and the tiny timing
differences between keystrokes but it's
good enough Tigers not gonna be able to
recover that embedded systems and
virtual systems also have often have
issues with its if you have a headless
server no user input with an SSD there
goes all your entropy okay same thing
with embedded systems raspberry PI's
other things like that on virtual
machines it's not touching any actual
hardware and it probably doesn't have
user interaction for talking the
enterprise probably served with no user
interaction so again a situation where
maybe there could be failure to and of
course there the pseudo-random number
generators that never had entropy in the
first place I have yet to see somebody
do a new reverse engineering of windows
script gender annum but the last one was
of Windows 2000 and they didn't have an
entropy source they had a hood
everything in the kitchen sink in terms
of the internal state of the machine
machine named the process block a bunch
of other things and then the time to act
as an OPS that would never output the
same thing twice actually no actual or
very little actual entropy going into
the output trees an attacker gets on
your system they can find the stuff out
okay another way they can fail as it can
have a backdoor name so our government
specifically NSA was so happy as to
create us a backdoor pseudo-random
number generator and that to NIST this
is the standardized it people started
putting it in library thank goodness
they didn't put it as the default random
number generator too many of them
juniper systems who produces netscreen
routers thankfully they're not they're
not a sponsor so i can i can pick on
them they've changed a whole bunch of
stuff and how they deal with random
numbers to turn this back toward
pseudo-random number generator into a
functioning backdoor for their VPN
connection and it's like a list of like
six different things they had to change
to get it working but the end of the day
they generate a nonce before the key for
that connection you tack or seize the
noms with a bigger not big enough you
can do optimizations on it and the
attacker takes that and generate the
next thing this is based on the
elliptical curve
cryptography which should seem a bit odd
right because elliptical curves are used
for asymmetric cryptography where you
have secret values that are transforming
other values and that's exactly how this
works where there's a secret value that
will transform outputs to the next
output and if you know that secret then
you can see any output from the
pseudo-random number generator and you
can predict the next one so I see the
non predicts the next thing that's going
to be the key so that's how this works
thankfully well there so it is but bad
news foreign intelligence probably
somebody man just break into two number
systems change the elliptical curve they
were using that changes the secret key
juniper and whoever whatever
three-letter agency problems the NSA
told them to put it in no longer had
access to the back door somebody else
did Juniper's a pretty big name when it
comes to government contractors business
etc juniper went oh crap somebody else
is using our back door we need to tell
people so they switched it back and
somebody was like whoa what's going on
here and then they figured out oh no
juniper had put the back dooring years
ago so they finally removed it questions
about HP randomness random numbers back
door repair and geez why you should care
yeah so so are I say an elliptical
curves are all based on mathematics
involving primes and multiplications and
stuff like that no I have no idea so
that's the thing i know Prime's are
important but i have yet to find an
actual cryptographer who can explain to
me why they matter why it has to be
prime or anything else like that
so in if it wasn't a prime it would be
easier to factor okay do you know if
that holds true for the problems in
elliptic curve cryptography sorry my
guess is that it does because that's
also a like you can do it one way but
starting put it back thing so all right
thank you any other questions I've been
doing on harm I'm pretty much out of
time that's always exciting protocols
verticals are bad the more complicated
in protocol hanging action see this is
fine we're complicated protocol the more
vulnerable it is I was going to go
through examples of every single step of
TLS and SSL can be vulnerable but I'm
going to skip that okay let me have
side-channel attacks when you're doing
stuff you can leak data about the key
this falls into one of two categories
either the attacker can guess something
directly for example guessing a password
based on how long it takes to do the
string comparison or whether what
they're looking at like power the cash
in the CPU or something else like that
you can actually figure out what some of
the bits of the key are so side channels
are an issue why you don't want to use
myths elliptical curves for a lot of
stuff is because this ellipse are curves
you can't have a constant time
implementation so how long the signature
function takes actually leaks
information about the key it's really
really hard almost impossible to write
an implementation that's not true for
okay recap we had to skip almost all of
cryptographic protocols I apologize but
you now know all of the primitives that
go into a protocol like that the reason
we need corrective limitations is
largely because of side-channel attacks
even if you have a logically correct
implementation it can still have issues
kriffing and leaked data let me talked
about cryptographic primitives this is a
symmetric like a s asymmetric like RSA
and a lipstick incurved if you Hellman
hashes and pseudo-random number
generators quick before I pass this over
to the next person do we have any
questions concerns roaring screams
aspirations or snide remarks
very great so it's elliptical curve
digital signature algorithm is the thing
that's particularly vulnerable to that
and the reason is to implement the
mathematics for that curve you have to
have like a bunch of different stuff
depending on what it does so there's a
whole bunch of conditional branch logic
and depending on what stuff it is you're
signing it will go to a different branch
in the code and that's that's required
for creating a proximal invitation of
that that's why so it's maybe you can do
it but it's really really hard