working now got it okay hi how y'all are
sorry about that I'll mute next time I
got a cough my name is steve larson
sorry for my voice I've coming off of
the flu I'm not contagious anymore so
don't worry about that and I'm going to
tell you how not to make an expensive
paper weight out of your SSD or how to
make one I don't know first of all I've
got a disclaimer neither am i that's my
disclaimer so and you'll see why later
okay we'll talk a little bit about data
erasing fundamentals for those of you
that don't know much about it and then
we'll talk a little bit about the issues
that we have with racing SSDs so we know
that deletion of data doesn't mean it's
going to be destroyed right if you pick
up a book this is what I i tell my intro
peep my intro students and we imagine
that this is a book when I'm erasing a
file out of the book what am i doing
find me racing a chapter and it was a
hard drive yeah in other words all i'm
doing is i'm taking the entry out of the
table of contents well actually i'm not
even doing that i'm just making it so
it's not it doesn't appear to the OS
right so taking it out so the OS can't
see it if i'm going to format the drive
i'm just getting rid of all of the list
of the files that are on the drag but
all the data is still there no matter
what right and the text is still there
on the book of stuff i guess so we know
that this stuff doesn't work so
generally what we do is we wipe a hard
drive and who can tell me what wiping a
hard drive means i can pick on somebody
from slippery rock university that i
know knows it yes sir I'm sorry
that you overwrite every single bit on
the disk right with some kind of random
0 or 1 or something yeah and that way we
can't get the data back yes sir I don't
care what your record I'm not coming
through on video well it's because it's
pointing way up here Oh in Miami HDMI
know i'm i'm a vga okay when it comes to
SSDs we have a different technology so
we gotta use different methods and
sometimes we don't know what's inside
the black box so you all know about hard
drives these are spinning platters that
we all use and all up to you you know
the OS has direct access to writing to
the hard drive we can say go to this
address on the disk and write this text
there's no real state for the page you
know all we have is reading right we
really don't have a delete on there when
it comes to SSDs the OS does not have
direct access to the pages and then we
have a we're leveling issue that we'll
talk about later on and each cell has a
state to it okay so manned memory which
is what insight what's inside SSDs has
three operations we have the read
operations the right operations and the
erase operation when we write to the
block form SSDs that it can only be
written once if you're going to override
then of course you have to completely
erase it and then be rewritten and a
blocker a page has a state it's either
programmed or is he raised they're
organized into blocks you start off with
all bits set to one so everything on the
on the SSD is set to one at sea or a
state when you write a block you set the
necessary that's 20 and then you get
your zeros and ones and so now we have
our data and now we're in a program
state and we can read that block
repeatedly we can read it all the time
anything we want to do unfortunately
reading it to
many times will cause problems with the
nearby block why is that who here knows
about static electricity yeah do you
like being shocked by static electricity
no why not it doesn't hurt a little bit
here but you know it's temporary right
one of the zeros don't like it why is
that they might change the state right
you get electrical shock here and it
might hurt here a little bit or
something like that you kind of a
nervous system so that's the closest we
can come to why we're shooting electrons
at these guys to change their state and
the nearby cells that are getting shot
might start to affect might start to be
affected so you know we're SSD is a
little bit more complicated than hard
disk drives one way you need to update
even just one little bit in an SSD we
have to first erase the entire block so
we copy everything into ram FST ram many
we erase the entire block and then we
rewrite the whole thing there's a 50-50
chance that you only have to put in a
zero but if even one little bit and the
entire block goes from 0 to 1 then we
got to read the entire block into ram
update it erase the block and rewrite
the block okay on these program erase
icon can only happen a certain number
times before they wear out it's kind of
like if you get that little static
electricity shock pretty soon the little
nerve ending in your skin that's
receiving that shock is going to wear
out right it's going to get numb and
you're not going to feel the shock game
or so it's kind of useless and also some
songs today to get updated more
frequently than ours there are certain
files that we use on a daily basis that
get updated all the time every time you
press ctrl s to save something then you
know the file gets updated and then
there's some data that we don't update
hardly at all I when was last time you
change the JPEG I don't remember last
time I change one right every cell in
the SSD
every cell in the SSD has a certain
number of program erase cycles that it
can go through before it's worn out and
when it does we reach we have our mean
time between failure level that's marked
on to it and it says left you know
before we fail we want to write this
someplace else oh so then it will put it
someplace else on the SSD because of
this manufacturers have we're leveling
and they also do over-provisioning so
we're the leveling is we want to make
sure that the SSD doesn't get worn out
in any particular cell so in other words
if we can write something to sell a
100,000 times cell a2 has nothing then
sell a one's going to wear out quicker
than cell a2 so we don't want that to
happen so we put this we're leveling and
and what that does is it means you know
data is going all over the place excuse
me I gotta numb up my throat here well
that that I can't talk ah lovelady right
okay so so any time a cell gets
rewritten too many times read the mean
time between failure and we write the
contents of that cell someplace else and
we mark that cell as or its block as
don't use now does this cause a drive to
get smaller over time you think so right
does it because anybody notice their SSD
the available state I know the available
space gets march mama does anybody
notice that their disk it gets smaller
is anything report that it gets smaller
not really i don't think the firmware
lets it happen right if the firmware
doesn't tell us by the way you know
you've now got 17 blocks mark bad and
you now have one megabyte less on your
hard drive right we also have a thing
called over-provisioning in SSDs and
i'll show you a different graphic on it
later on but basically because this
we're leveling and cells can wear out
they add between seven and twenty
sent more space in your SSD then if then
is advertised because if we mark it bad
we don't want you to think you're
running out of space so I've got a 64
gigabyte SSD here as you can tell it's
not as new as we would like it's a
little bit older model but that means it
could have you know up to what one-fifth
right what's one-fifth 12 12 extra gigs
on here that we don't know about so when
we write a file for example our balance
sheet I'm an accountant I've got a
balance sheet how many times a day any
accountants here know how many times
baby you updated a balance sheet guess
it depends on your company right you're
doing walmart you get a hundred thousand
sales of age you might be updating that
balance sheet 100,000 times okay when
you write it to too many times we're
going to do some wear leveling and we're
going to take it off of one cell and put
it in a different cell and we're going
to update a couple more times and this
is going to happen and then we cut we go
back to the first cell that we are in
and then we realize oh that sells been
updated too many times now we're going
to mark that as bad because we don't
want that cell to go bad and we're going
to put the balance sheet now is going to
be up here I don't have a mouse anymore
we're going to put that balance sheet up
here in the top which is where our
over-provisioning is so we didn't put it
anywhere else now we're in the
over-provisioning state where we're
going to add that balance sheet okay so
the biggest thing that impacts how much
space you have available on your SSD is
how dynamic your data is so if you're
changing files all the time then maybe
you don't want to use an SSD yes it's
fast and yes they are reliable now but
you could wear out real quick so I hear
of a lot of companies using SSDs in
their servers and I I say you know that
a smart idea because it's you know
really fast to read and write data but
you're going to be wearing out your SSDs
real quick depending on how dynamic your
data is
and they haven't understood that part
yet however not all is lost right the
SSD controller gets shirt make sure that
all pages get programmed any race about
the same number of times so we have our
we're leveling and stuff like that and
of course there's a larger pool of spare
over provision space now that space is
only accessible by the SSD itself by the
firmware so we have our spinning disk we
know everything where things go and
stuff like that and we basically got
access to just about all of it except
for the you know sometimes the notebook
manufacturer the hardware manufacturer
will say I want to put this aside here
so in case I have to recover something
I've got a recovery partition and stuff
like that we basically can get to every
single part on a spinning this when we
go to an SSD we have some visible
invisible areas that BOS that the
operating system can't see and it's
really interesting because you know I've
got 64 gigs here but I've got maybe up
to 12 gigs that I cannot see with my
operating system and that's the
over-provisioning part in case these
cells over here go bad I I need
someplace else to remap them okay now
SSDs are gaining in popularity of course
and the best way to get popular when
you're a hard drive manufacturer or an
SSD manufacturer is make the SSD look
like a hard distract so if you look at
an SSD with I don't know a hex editor
running on Windows it's going to look
basically like a hard drive you're not
going to see much difference right and
they do this by following you know these
88 commands and stuff like that they
actually have to have what's called see
if i can get this up here this flash
translation layer so the flash
translation layer tells the operating
system okay you've got these 88 commands
which has been going on for you know
like a decade and treat it just like
that so we're going to take the 88
command and we're going to write things
to our SSD just like you were writing
them to the hard describe so when we
write something too hard this track yes
sir
it's yes it's SSD firmware which which
which raises another question right
every single manufacturer has their own
class translation i right yeah its
firmware in thank you great so when we
tell it right to something on a hard
disk drive we say go to this page and
write stuff when we have our flash
translation layer we say go to this page
and write stuff but if thats been
written too many times then we're going
to go to someplace else we're going to
put it there however we're still telling
the operating system we know where it's
at and here's where it's at so
unfortunately what happens is that can
leave from stale data all over the SSD
we also have some other issues what if
we want to wipe the SSD military
specifications how many times we
overwrite for mil-spec up to 35 right
depending on the confidentiality level
of the data right one project I was on I
did a stint with scic and one project I
was on we had to not only do all these
overwrites but then we had to sandblast
the disk and then we had to melt them
down so I don't know why we're good just
couldn't melt them down to begin with
but you know it's the military right
okay unfortunately we can't access all
the pages with an operating system on
here because we have over provision data
that will still contain data over
prevent in the over provision space also
anybody remember anybody dealt with
fries lock yeah you like it of course
not it's inconvenient but you know what
we trade convenience for security right
so we have this thing called freeze lock
and it's basically so we don't
mistakenly wipe our SSD or our hard
drive itself okay some other issues SSP
is a fairly new that's why they got this
flash translation layer in so people
will accept it because hard drive
manufacturer I'm sorry computer
manufacturers don't have to come up with
their a new way to access the SSP
because we can just use the ATA commands
that
we been using for over a decade ata
security race that's in the in the
firmware and stuff like that it doesn't
work very well with FF DS and way a guy
down at UC San Diego and his team tried
11 SSDs that say they supported the HEA
security race command and only eight of
them supported it and three of those had
a bug the implementation where it wasn't
reliable so out of 11 we really only had
five that they said you could actually
rely on for security racing okay you can
do a cryptographic key razor it works on
hard drives or SSD or whatever and you
just delete the key you encrypt the
entire disk and then you delete the key
Bruce Schneier says that's great if
you're implementing it perfectly and
it's got to work perfectly every single
time and the other thing is yeah we
could do that but what happens in three
or four years when somebody breaks that
cryptographic key and then they can get
in at your data and you know for us we
really don't care I who have data from
three or four years ago that they still
use one that wasn't hypothetical
question you know this is a real quick
yeah one two three or four yeah not very
many others though right and if you
don't do the cryptography wrong or
correctly you know you can have some
problems now how would that be would
that be easy to break just stand it
upside down right okay so when we're
doing erasure on SSDs we got to deal
with this FTL and the fries lock and
stuff like that we've got to have the
OEMs got to cooperate they have to
actually perfectly implement their
security race or their version of
security race on the H a command the
security racer has to be verifiable can
we verify improve that it actually
happened and how are you going to verify
that if your operating system how many
of you use a
a hex editor or something like that to
view data on a hard drive without having
an operating system yeah how would you
do that how are you going to verify that
there is no data left on here we just
have to trust the OEM the people making
these SSDs and implementing that
firmware and once they've been once
they've said they've done it you know
they have to report it well how do you
report it if you don't know if it
actually happened so here again we have
to rely on their implementation of a
flash translation layer what doesn't
work here's some things that myself and
some other researchers have tried
logically racing formatting this cheery
race we know that doesn't work Chris
perfect eraser we delete the key which
kind of sanitizes the data but you still
got data on the hard drive and maybe in
the future somebody you know will find
that SSD and they'll be able to decrypt
it because you know we're humans and
everything we make is imperfect by
nature so perhaps one of these days
somebody will be able to break the
encryption and then we have traditional
overriding but when we do that we're
going to overwrite stuff however some of
the stuff that we're overriding the SSD
is going to say maybe that should be
over here and then we have stuff stale
data left over on the parts of the SSD
that we don't have access to because the
operating system now what might work if
you want to use reuse the SSD there are
some people out there that have
solutions Blanco ease as part of
managing stuff like that but when you
use them how do you verify it actually
happen like Blanco they'll give you a
report yes we sanitize this SSD well
heck that's good enough for me I can
throw that away now right they said that
their solution works Who am I not to
trust them after all I paid 129 bucks
for that for that software right so they
wouldn't lie to me would they well maybe
to grandma grandma would believe him
right but you know we're a little bit
smarter than that
here again we got manufacturers
utilities Ars Technica also did a study
and they had 12 drives only for erase
their data reliably and one of those
claimed that they were doing it but all
they did was you know just the basically
formatting so we got three from him okay
you could overwrite multiple times and
use the security race and use a firmware
initialization that should be about that
hasn't worked reliably in the classes
way found out and also the freeze lock
you need to overcome freeze lock and all
you got to do for freeze lock is you got
to go to sleep for a little bit and then
wake it back up the non-volatile systems
laboratory said that they bypassed the
FTL and got to the nan but they had to
develop new flash translation laterz
they developed new extensions to it and
stuff like that so they could directly
access the SSD so they could make sure
that they sanitized it now here's
another one of these I'm not a smart man
guy I took this little SSD here somebody
gave this to me and they said hey can
you check this to see that everything is
completely erased off of it and I
checked it of course and guess what
there was data all over the place
unfortunately I was checking it with a
hospital program that was running on top
of an operating system and guess what
the operating system can't see the over
provision part of the SSD so how was I
supposed to verify that this was totally
able to come here and be thrown away I
couldn't I couldn't find a way and then
my wife said well don't you have
forensic tools at your disposal so I
said hey I do I wonder if this will work
so I did a bit copy from a hard disk
drive to this SSD using a tableau
forensic duplicator guess what happened
bit copy bit stream copy
the FTL did get in the way right just
going to tell me do this do this do this
to this right so did it work not quite I
couldn't access it with the operating
system anymore so i tried parted magic
and here's what came up and parted magic
so i have 64 gigs and when i open it up
in parted magic you know I got this our
ID or our I data right so what is this
so one two three what is that 8.7 gigs
no 8 point yeah eight point seven
gigabytes is what its reporting well if
I did the bitstream copy of this
shouldn't there be nothing on there
that's bike that's how much space is on
this hard drive I'm looking at the
bottom one it's bri data one so i got
88.7 gigs that parted magic is saying is
available here but wait a minute i did a
bit stream copy from 64 gig to 64 gigs
so i should have 64 gigs of space
available to me write minus a little bit
you know I could I could figure a couple
of Meg's for over-provisioning because
we had to use it and they got the sales
got written too many time so then I
thought okay we got that much space
there and then I selected it because in
parted magic you select which disk you
want to run this on and I did a wipe and
when I did that it reported a different
number and I was thinking what huh what
well I'm doing this in hearted magic
that I was also doing it on a linux
distribution so here again I've got an
operating system going up against this
SSD and the flash translation layer not
telling me you know everything that's
going on so of course this is unreliable
I set it to wipe anyway and lo and
behold I did it on three thirty in the
afternoon and I realized well you know
on this isn't making very good progress
here so I came back the next day
it was Oh golly 19 hours I think or
something like that when it finally
finished and when it finally finished it
said hey success we're done so then of
course I connected up to my window
system and Jessie buddy hey you know
what I need to format this drive so I
connected it up to my window system and
I said okay I'll format this drive ntfs
no problem 64 gigs or maybe eight gigs
or maybe four gigs whatever the size is
it shouldn't go shouldn't take too long
and I even did the little you know I
uncheck the box so it's going to do a
quick format and it failed on the quick
format but it took about three hours to
fail so then I thought well what if I do
a full format so I check the box to make
sure it doesn't do a quick format and 37
hours later it failed yeah so it was
like oh ok good thing at spring break
and I don't have to go teach raising so
now i have an expensive paperweight
because not only can my OS not see it
parted magic couldn't do anything with
it I tried that OS can't see it so this
is how you get rid of it now is the data
gone according to researchers and
according to what I would think I would
think I still have data on here I'm not
trusting anything way in and those guys
they wrote data to an SSD and they put
fingerprints on it so they knew exactly
what data they personally wrote and so
they could find it again and they did
overriding 20 about 20 times up to 20
time it's been reliable and they said
you know the built-in sanitized commands
are effective when implemented correctly
but they're usually not and so they
ended up making three of their own flash
translation extensions to sanitize files
and disk SSD now when you really got to
get rid of the data what do you do well
you could do physical destruction right
take this off and take the hard take the
motherboard out and all that kind of
stuff but you can still get data off of
the chips we had a chip off thing
yesterday right so or was that today
I was this morning right you can still
get that was yesterday right you can
still get data off the chimp I've got a
colleague at George Mason University he
and I are working on chip off
information from point-of-sale devices
so you know the little telephone size
things are in the in the restaurant you
swipe your card if they don't get a
response when they put in the phone
number they don't get a response in five
minutes they spit out a receipt anyway
and then may batch process all of the
leftover transactions that night and if
somebody comes and swipes that before
the batch processing gets done then they
could have a whole bunch of information
on their hands well we couldn't get any
of the information out of the chip that
when they were connected to this device
so he has a team now that's doing a chip
off retrieval of the data and he said
it's not very fun but it's still
possible if you do want to disintegrate
or pulverizer melt it down or whatever
be sure you check the laws in your local
area for electronic dispose of waste or
electronic waste disposal because there
are some parts of the country where you
can't throw that out in the garbage just
something fun I went on a business trip
to China and we were looking at
electronic waste disposal stuff and they
brought us to their factory and so are
there any heavy metals in motherboards
and chips and stuff like that yeah like
what mercury anything else lead yeah
there's some gold and silver and copper
and tin and you know stuff like that
well they brought us into this factory
and they had workers on a table and they
had little chisels and pointy hammers
and stuff and they're going breaking
these things off they had some people
that were melting some solder off of it
and stuff like that and I said what are
they doing oh well they're dismantling
at men we're going to melt the metal
down and you know separate them out and
stuff like that and I said what about
the mercury oh we're not worried about
the mercury thank you I'm not getting
any closer to that I'm worried about the
mercury evidently when you have more
than a billion people in your country
you know you lose a couple of mercury
poisoning you really don't care right
okay so basically for ssds here's some
more information if you want to read
more and this is a very shortness of
places some if you want to delete
securely delete data on the SF vs right
now i would say pulverize or melt or
something but whatever you do you got to
you got to get rid of those chips yes
sir pardon me um Blanco says that
they've got a really good solution ela
VLAN CCO however we are relying on their
own reporting so self reporting I mean I
have not seen them given to NIST you
know this has some stuff right there but
I haven't seen them tested by Miss yet
oh yeah the UC San Diego guys maybe
FTL's those haven't been made publicly
available yet yes sir yes anything with
an SSD as part of it now you don't need
to pulverize the spinning disk part of
it yeah yes is the chip yes sir to
destroy for ssds 0 for any hard drives
oh really wow I have I haven't worked
for the government for that part of the
government for a while right double
check to see what it is and right of
SSDs em yeah and this put out a new one
in 2014 new data disposal thing so and
there's actually says you know depending
on the confidentiality of in levels
here's what you need to do and stuff
like that yes ma'am
sure exactly yet you can't trust the
manufacture when he says oh yeah this
this cot sanitized we're good to go
because they're doing their own
reporting there's no third-party
objective checks and balances on this I
guess you know there's nothing nobody
verifying that and you know I wish
Consumer Reports would come out and say
oh yeah this one works but do we trust
Consumer Reports anymore some people say
yes some people say no I mean they're
paying the vendors pay for them to do
the report so well if there's no other
questions and I know I'm the only one
waiting between you guys and getting
presents so our prizes or whatever it's
called is that and here is that next
door that's next door okay we have to
wait on them so sorry i would give this
as a prize paperweight to somebody that
wants it but since there might still be
some data on it i'm not going to do that
[Applause]