uh hello my name is pascal
and i will be talking about our work uh
foggy site a scheme for facial search
privacy
uh so this work is joint work with uh
yvonne eftimov and yoshikono
and it was done at the university of
washington
so this work is
about face recognition technology and
proposing
to use adversarial examples to defend
against space recognition technology
and you know to understand why this is
an important problem overall
we have to understand a little bit of
background about face recognition
uh so for those who don't know
face recognition is the use of computer
vision and machine learning algorithms
to automatically detect who is in a
particular image
these days space recognition technology
mostly uses deep learning
and because of modern compute power and
sort of the rise of larger and bigger
deep models
face recognition has gotten very very
strong it's been very
uh performant in the last couple years
to the point that it poses
a threat to individual privacy right um
if
people can identify you from just photos
they take of you on the street
any stranger could look you up and you
can see why this can be a problem for
your personal privacy it can enable
you know stalking behavior it can be
used it can be abused
by law enforcement in criminal cases or
by the government
to crack them in descent so there's a
lot of reasons why
we want to be careful about face
recognition technology
and why we might want to find ways to
protect our own privacy
um against this right there are a lot of
news reports recently about
the subject about why it's important to
protect one's personal privacy
um against technology like base
recognition technology so hopefully
that statement is not so controversial
so basically the way that this
technology works and very brief
is you have some query photo of a person
you're trying to identify
you run them through a face recognition
model which then produces
an embedding in n-dimensional space
and this embedding has the property that
photos of the same person tend to
cluster
far away from photos of other people so
photos of the same person cluster into
distinct clusters in in-dimensional
space
this embedding space is produced by a
deep neural network
and then a k-nearest neighbor's
classifier is usually run on top of this
photo
to determine given the query photo which
is the stark blue photo
and the look up set photos which is all
these other photos in the embedding
space
who is most likely to be depicted in
this photo
so you can see that a casino classifier
in this case is very accurate
um so we propose to use adversarial
examples which are
small perturbations and images that sort
of fool deep learning models
um to attack face recognition systems
um in order to get there we need to
understand the goals of our
scheme of using adversarial examples the
first of which is privacy so obviously
we want to fool a face recognition
system
we want to make sure that that system
cannot identify us
in our query photos um
two the goal is to not actually degrade
the quality of the photos that we are
changing so if we modify a photo of you
that you put on social media or that you
have online of yourself
you want to make sure you're still happy
with that photo and that photo is still
useful to you as a human being
and finally we want to make sure that
it's not immediately obvious to an
automated detection system
that this photo is some adversarially
modified photo
right it's it's picked up by a face
recognition company
and put in their database without them
knowing
um so there's a lot of actually related
work
on this subject about using adversarial
examples to
attack face recognition systems uh
sharif at all talk about
um using physical adversarial examples
um
to protect one's privacy um using and
those
adversarial examples are sort of in the
form of glasses uh
shannon all morrison paper proposed the
system called fox
which uh uses pixel level changes to
sort of attack the training set
using data poisoning so there are a lot
of similar
papers on this work and hopefully as we
keep going through this the
presentation we highlight what makes our
paper unique
and of course there are other papers
that we don't mention on the slide for
the full list of related work i
encourage you to see our paper
so to talk about these kinds of privacy
protecting schemes
we need a way to determine okay how good
numerically can we quantify the
performance of a privacy predicting
scheme how good is it
at actually protecting our privacy so we
introduce three different metrics to
sort of quantify this
uh the first is the recall rate so if we
have some query photo which we embed and
we
use the deep learning network and we get
a hundred photo closest photos to
my query photo the recall rate asks
how many of those photos are of the
query photo
so if you take a photo of me and you run
it on your face recognition model and
you get the top hundred matches
the recall rate asks what percentage of
those top hundred matches
are me so if i appear in 70
of those photos the recall rate is 0.7
the discovery rate is a stricter metric
than the recall rate
and it asks how often do i appear
at least once in the top k uh
look uh lookup set so if you take a
query photo of me and you're running
against your
database search and on average with
different query photos of me
i appear in the top case set 50 or
60 or 90 of the time at least once even
once in
the top k nearest neighbors that's the
discovery rate so it's a stricter metric
strictly stricter
strictly larger than the recoil rate
and finally we have identity uniformity
which is
how many different identity which
measures sort of the entropy of the
recall set
so intuitively we want
uh a lot of different people
to be in the nearest neighbor set of our
query photo right if we have one query
photo of me
you want to make sure it's hard to
identify me in the lookup set so you
want lots of other people
um in in this in the lookup set
and the enemy uniformity is defined such
that it's zero
when there's perfect entropy so there's
uh there's
every person in the lookup set is a
different human being
and it's one when uh i'm the only person
in my own lookup set for a given query
photo
so for all of these metrics it's
important to realize that they're all
between zero and one
and the lower is better so all of these
the goal of this privacy protecting
scheme
is to get these as close to zero as as
possible
okay so our work
focuses on two different paradigms of
defending
uh one's privacy in this sort of
embedding space
uh the first is what we call the
individual approach
so let's say you're a person and you
want to protect your privacy
and you know that this face recognition
company
has access to you know these five photos
of you which appear normally in the
center
uh what do you do well if you can modify
those photos of yourself
the best thing to do the most obvious
thing to do is sort of scatter
your photos as far away from the
original location as possible
because when you have a new photo this
new query photo
it's gonna appear close to your where
your old photos used to be
and since you've moved your old photos
hopefully
photos of different people will be the
nearest neighbors as opposed to the
original focus right that's the most
intuitive thing to do
and that's that's actually the proposal
of many previous works is to
talk about this line of thinking um
the issue with this approach is that
you don't have access to all the photos
that a company might have scraped of you
right so
if you're thinking about this problem in
um it's likely in fact highly likely
that a face recognition company has
already scraped several photos from your
social media and has them erasing their
database
and you have no way to modify those
photos so even if you modify all future
photos that you put out
in in on social media there are already
some immovable points
that you just can't change and that's
going to make this problem harder
right so we do a quick study on this we
talk more about this in the paper
but we find that if you can modify every
photo of yourself in the database
then you're golden then it's very easy
to drive all metrics very close to zero
problem solved you know without with no
problem but the issue is that
if you have even you know a small number
of photos
lingering behind that you can't modify
for example from the past
clean photos that a company has already
scraped of you then
this problem becomes much much harder
and these individual approaches
become less and less successful the more
photos they have so we need to think
about this problem in a slightly
different way with a slightly different
tack
and that's the main thrust of our work
today
so the goal is to do this on a more
community level to think about how
we can protect each other using a large
number of decoys as opposed to just sort
of
only focusing on our individual privacy
and moving our own photos
how we can sort of flood facial face
recognition systems
with lots of decoys in the internet
so we have some look up set again an
embedding space
and we have some particular query photo
um
and the goal here is well normally
without any intervention
right the top five nearest neighbors i
didn't identify us perfectly
so we want to make sure that the top
five nearest neighbors are not these
five photos
ideally they would be decoy photos
ideally
we could find some way to perturb other
photos
of other people or or celebrities or
whatever
to be closer to the average query photo
than the rest of our our look up set
photos
right so this is the key idea of the
foggy site
uh scheme is to use lots of decoys
to predict where nuclear photos will be
such that the nearest neighbors of new
query photos are going to be
people who are not us who can't be used
to link back to us who can't be used on
nfis
so there are a couple of different ways
to sort of take decoy photos and move
them into our space
from a mathematical perspective we talk
about four different approaches in the
paper which i'm not going to go into a
ton of detail here
but they're listed here and we do
compare against different methods of
doing this
although you know further investigation
into this could constitute interesting
for
future work so
given some decoy we can see the decoy
photos with different levels of
modification here
it turns out that we do fairly well
at driving metrics low as long as we can
have a lot of decoys
so we compare against uh the
perturbation amounts of the
the magnitude of the adversarial example
on the
on the x-axis and the mean recall
which is one of our metrics on the
y-axis and we show that as long as we
perturb the image is enough which is
still
not visible to humans with a certain
perturbation we can drive this recall
rate very low
which is great which is a success
we do the same with other ways of
targeting the lookup set
the mean as opposed to an arbitrary
vector
and this seems like a success which is
great um
but one thing which is even more
important question
which is how many decoys do we actually
need so
for some fixed epsilon uh how many more
decoys do we need
than your average look up set to
to cloak you to protect you and it turns
out that
depending on the epsilon depending on
the model um
you may need anywhere from you know two
to five
times as many decoys relative to look up
photos
to protect yourself which means
let's say for example a company has
scraped maybe five
photos of you you would need upwards of
10 to 25 photos
to sort of decoy away from you
to protect your privacy which sounds
like a fair bit
um and it is because this is a hard
problem
and that's why we're sort of talking
about this at the community level rather
than the individual level
i'm going to blow through one more
result or two more results because i
want to
get through the slides um here are the
other metrics as
a as a with the same x-axis as last time
the proportion of decoys relative to
clean look-up photos
and it's important to note that in this
slide and in the previous slide
this assumes a white box model so this
assumes that
in some scenario we know which face
recognition model the company we're
trying to protect against is using
this is not an entirely unreasonable
assumption because
you know these face recognition models
are usually public in github
and even if they're proprietary by the
company the architecture that's used is
usually from an academic paper
which again is public in an archive
but we also do talk about the white box
setting
there are some techniques to modify
images
even without knowing what model you're
attacking
and we use those techniques but we find
that in the black box setting where you
don't have access to the
proprietary model that a company is
using this problem becomes much harder
so it's still possible to protect your
own privacy
but instead of needing two to five times
as many decoys
you might need a as as many as seven
times as many decoys as clean look up
photos
and you need to make your perturbation
magnitude much much higher so you need
to
visibly alter the image a lot more
and this just speaks to the difficulty
of this problem this shows that
if a company already has photos of you
that are clean especially a lot of
photos
and if that company takes great pains to
keep its model private
then protecting your own individual
privacy computationally
especially if your computational
resources are limited
is a very very hard problem um and our
results show that while it's possible
it's difficult it's difficult and we
don't want to overstate
the difficulty or understate the
difficulty of protecting your own
privacy
um so that's sort of an overview of the
foggy site system it uses adversarial
examples to protect against
face recognition technology and the
novelty really
is in the way it frames the problem so
previous approaches
really focus on this problem as
protecting your own individual privacy
but we find in our work that this speak
is a very difficult thing
because if if a company already has
clean photos of you in their database
then it's almost impossible to defend
against
any face recognition system uh on your
own
but we show that with the appropriate
sort of community level approach
it is possible actually to defend
against your own privacy
as long as you use the right targeting
strategies and especially
in the white box setting where for
whatever litigation or publicly
data access reason the company's model
is is available
um so that's sort of a quick overview of
the fog state system i would encourage
you to ask questions now and see
original paper
and also reach out for further questions
um after the talk
um you can email us and connect us on
twitter
all right thanks for talking and i'll
see you in the q a session