thumbs up
okay excellent all right i guess we'll
just uh
get started so welcome everybody to hot
hotpets2021
uh brought to you from a pixelated
rochester hopefully you've all had a
chance to explore pixelated rochester
i now know a thousand times more about
rochester than i ever did even though i
spent my youth watching
rochester's fox station including their
news
because that just happened to be what
was broadcast to my house
if you wanted to watch the simpsons so
um
we have a really nice program set up for
you this year
there's going to be two sessions three
talks per session
the talks are each 15 minutes and then
we've got a 30 minute block at the end
of each session
carved out for a discussion as i just
mentioned for those of you that
didn't hear me the discussion is more of
a
proper discussion than a q a we
encourage
you to bring your own ideas we encourage
the speakers to
pose questions we encourage lively
debate joking around etc it's not
formal like the conference question and
answer period so
if you have anything even remotely
intelligent to say
on the subjects that were talked about
it doesn't have to be directly related
to what the speakers said please please
please let's uh
let's all engage and keep this lively uh
so in our first session we've got these
three speakers that you can see in front
of you mona wang
muhammad malek
after that we will have a coffee break
unfortunately we can't provide the
coffee that's usually my favorite part
of conferences but
uh will give you a chance to go brew
some of your own and then we have a very
exciting
keynote lined up uh merritt hansen a
regular at pets is going to be talking
about
data pets and data protection
authorities what is the a's yeah perfect
is the enemy the good talking about the
interplay between
regulation and regulators and the sorts
of technologies that we all spend our
days obsessing about
then we'll have another short break
followed by the third session or the
second session the last session of the
day which has got three more talks
same basic idea as the first session
and then in the regular hot pets uh
tradition we are going to have a vote
for the best
talk so we'll be using this mentee
website
we'll we'll provide this information
again when it's actually time but
you enter this code you give your vote
and whichever talk gets the most
votes will win a prize
and so we'll we'll discuss that with the
presenter after
because of the virtual nature of this we
have to send the prize to the um
to the presenter so there will be a bit
of a delay but
um be prepared to vote for your favorite
by whatever criteria you deem fit
and then we will all convene you may
have noticed
the very bottom of gather town there is
an ice cream bar
again much like the coffee this year
you're forced to bring your own ice
cream
hopefully you've all got some stashed
away in your freezer
and uh we'll hang around and eat ice
cream and continue to talk
pets or whatever we feel like talking
about
so with that i will hand the floor
over to our first speaker mona
uh okay hi i will start presenting
one sec
um all right great uh thank you for that
introduction
ryan uh that was great uh hi everybody
i'm mona i'm a graduate student at
princeton university and thank you to
hot pets for having me i'm excited to be
here
i'm sorry for the mess in the background
i'm moving right now
but i'm excited to be presenting here
instead of packing
so today i'm going to be talking about
leveraging connection migration for
network privacy
also known as comps my very cool and
very legitimate acronym
uh so let's talk about pets i love
privacy
enhancing technologies i love animals my
parents were unfortunately
allergic so i never had pets growing up
it was because of that that in my youth
i was severely addicted
to a gaming website called neopets that
lets you care for virtual pets and play
games with them
unfortunately my legal adult guardian
depicted here by this
disembodied eyeball emoji thought my
addiction to neopets
and the internet in general was morally
objectionable
which like maybe and also bad for my
developmental health
which is probably very true um and so as
many of you
probably already know there are lots of
ways unfortunately your regular internet
usage
is not at all private um it will reel
what you're doing to anyone on the
network listening
for instance a parent that runs your
home router so unfortunately
it was quite easy to put parental
controls on the router and foil my
gaming experience and also my use
um so whenever i got blocked i would be
very sad
because i could not feed my fairy cow
so i did what any desperate
eight-year-olds would do in the early
2000s which was to ask my friend
jeeves about it luckily jeeves actually
had great advice
he told me to use vpn i used tor
and armed with this new information and
this new technology
i was able to feed my cow and freely
surf the web and it was glorious
for this period of time however
my legal adult guardian only got smarter
they realized that even if my connection
wasn't
encrypted it turns out the sizes and the
timing schedule of packets
is enough to fully identify the website
i was visiting
so they memorized the general packet
timing and sizes
that the network would experience when i
opened neopets and they would block the
connection whenever it occurred
so it turns out that today this is
actually a whole subfield of
cs network privacy research called
website fingerprinting
so state-of-the-art fingerprinting
classifiers you know nowadays
are using complex neural networks to
discriminate between hundreds of
websites
um you know like convolutional networks
and they even what
work well in the context where you
experience
unknown or not before seen traffic or
websites
uh and you know even non-neural network
classifiers work pretty well there's
okay fingerprinting which uses manually
engineered features with
random decision force that works quite
well
and so you know like in the face of
machine learning driven network
surveillance attacks i was completely
defeated
uh by my legal adult guardian and
there's nothing i could do so for now
we're going to
elegantly segue into talking about
modern encryption and network protocols
this is their site banner as of now i i
think uh i think
this you know this is a really smart
move global smartphone
penetration is almost 80 and everyone
has a phone
so in practice what does this mean for
me
well this just means that i'm i'm going
to be browsing neopets on my mobile
phone
these days my phone and your phones
probably also are real estate moguls
they have not one
often but two network addresses on the
internet one through your wi-fi one
through your mobile provider
and the tcp based internet moving
between network addresses is very
annoying
right when you walk outside your wi-fi
range your phone such as data
tcp connections uh have to get dropped
and restarted on the new
network because they're so tied to the
network address
these kind of network changes also
happen when you're not moving if your
mobile map just decides
to change or rebind your phone's ip
address
so luckily many modern udp based
encryption protocols are network
agnostic so
uh you know in other words unlike tcp
which tightly couples connections
to individual network addresses from any
udp-based encryption protocols
the connections are not defined by the
address but by some other data so just
the negotiated key pair or a proxy for
it
the biggest one is quick which was just
made into an rfc
i i think like maybe a couple months ago
i don't i don't know
and is really rapidly gaining support
it's going to be the sole transport for
http 3.
it supports connection migration uh
there's also
protocols like wireguard and mosh that
both support ip roaming you know as long
as
the received packet is valid you know
the server or the end will accept it
and so to be a little pedantic this is
what such a migration
might look like you know in particular
for quick uh you know at some point
our device will change the network uh
and
they'll detect the change number maybe
rebind you know the socket onto the new
uh on a to a new port and then send data
from the new network address
and so long as the server is confident
that it comes from the same endpoint
it'll accept data
even in the middle of a session so one
gotcha in
is not in quick the protocol requires a
two-way reachability to be established
first so there's this probe
uh before accepting more data on a new
network path
uh in practice path validations can also
be cached we're gonna talk more about
the sort of practicalities of quick
connection migration if you're
interested in the discussion
um but we've sort of established what
connection migration is i hope at this
point so
now let's talk about what comps is what
is what is cups
and so the primitive here and the
intuition cool intuition is that we can
split a session in the middle
of a network connection this breaks a
lot of assumptions that network control
devices currently rely
very heavily on devices like parental
control so let's go back to our
adversary who's
using a machine learning to determine
when i'm visiting neopets
and using this insight you know for the
same individual connection
i'm making to the near pets home page i
can send packets from different
addresses
supposing you put support something like
quick this would work
um and uh some intuition as to why
this might foil uh even advanced
fingerprinting defenses or attacks
until recently a lot of defenses against
web fingerprinting
often involve obfuscating the size and
timing information by you know
injecting dummy packets or standardizing
packet sizes
uh the comps kind of depends and other
recent web fingerprinting defense
is involved lowering the amount of
actual information the adversary can
learn
so now the adversary has more problems
to solve right beyond just
what is the network fingerprint and you
know what are the possible ways they
could slice it how are they going to
sample
from the network fingerprint and then
they also have less information to
determine
what the network fingerprint is in the
first place so
there's also a sort of combinatorial
explosion of the slices
but what if i'm not multi-homed right a
cool thing with about comps
is that i can utilize different
encrypted protocols over the same
network
as long as the packets are delivered to
the intended destination and also routed
back
accordingly so here i'm showing two
different vpns but we can imagine one of
these is
you know maybe just a regular encrypted
quick transport
or another encrypted proxy you know it's
up to you it's your imagination on the
wire format you know
even if the adversary can see all the
traffic uh
it can sort of make the correlation of
the same flow more difficult
we also have the extra problem to solve
you know what are the ways the client
could splice the connection here
i think intuitively this is maybe less
strong than the previous one
but we can also combine the two right if
this doesn't convince you
not only are we using different paths
but also different protocols and so on
the wire
uh it might look something like
this we have different protocols being
sent down different paths
you could also limit one protocol to a
single path it's up to you
and so one valid you know complaint or
gripe
might be you know neopets doesn't
default to https yet
uh you know what makes you think they'll
support quick anytime soon
that's okay yeah that's true like we
mentioned before we have other encrypted
udp protocols like wireguard that also
support ip roaming so we can do all of
the tricks that we mentioned
the past five six slides but instead of
connecting directly to neopets we can
just
connect to a regular unaltered instance
of regard
and so here's a quick summary of all of
the things we've learned so far
so with comps we have this primitive
this powerful
primitive involving mid-sessions
splitting
we can split across different network
paths uh different
sort of encrypted protocols you know as
long as the packets get delivered
uh to the end point uh as long as the
end point
is you know a connection migration
endpoint and there's minimal overhead we
can also talk about that in the
discussion a bit
as well we don't really get into that
here um
that's pretty cool and so i'm going to
break up the
talk a little bit because it's very
early where i am i don't know about you
all
and with a little demo it's nothing
special it's just gonna show the
connection migration
uh so we're going to be
taking a look at sort of this model and
so what we'll see
is we'll have pcp dump sort of listening
on the two interfaces of the client and
then
we'll run a very simple you know path
scheduling packet scheduling
um on the client as well to split
between the pads and so it
should just be able to
remove this here
um all right and here so we'll have
here i'll uh stick it up here
on the
well let's do let's do uvp only because
sometimes
oh what's going on all right and then
you see
here on the f0 interface
let's open a website on the client
you can sort of see
huh i think i think something's gone
wrong never do live demos friends
oh this is capturing the vnc traffic i'm
sorry
there we go so refresh here we can see
all the wireguard traffic or vpn traffic
going through
uh zero uh nothing's going on uh we can
just run a really simple vibrate
script here uh and this will basically
just you know alternate
interfaces you know five times a second
and then we run here we can see the
traffic
just sort of bouncing between the two
interfaces um
successfully visit neopets.com it's got
mobile and so have we
evidently alright so that's it that's
that's the demo
um all right
let's go back
here
uh okay i think i'm running a little low
on time so i'm going to
um sort of skip over the side
slide again we can talk about it uh
later as well
so uh another thing i want to point out
that i think is very important is that
comps also has other use cases right
so we've been focusing primarily on the
web fingerprinting threat model
defeating the sort of biblical angel
that is managing my router
but let's consider a more common one sni
censorship you know is on the rise
because https is on the rise and
yeah i mentioned you know when you
connect to
an https website the server name is
completely in the clear
and this makes a really great target for
sensors surveillers etc
to use as a clear tech signal to either
block the connection
or throttle it or take some other action
like throttling it and
so you might ask
uh why don't we do the thing that our
good friend jeeves told us to do
uh and just like use a vpn right that
worked last time
uh and so to that i would say you know
vpns maybe are too slow i'm i'm gaming
here so i clearly need that low ping
to defeat my enemies and successfully um
play neopets and so comps uh enables a
sort of compromise right throw the
handshake packet over the vpn path then
migrate the
enter of the connection back on to the
sort of regular fast network path
and so if you know your adversary isn't
is just doing sort of keyword censorship
uh nothing complicated then this would
work and i can continue
my gaming career on neopets there are
also probably other reasons
other than gaming to desire a faster
internet connection but i'll leave that
at your imagination
so in conclusion some items oh yeah
so yeah connections are less and less
dependent on network addresses that's
very
cool so we're proposing comps to perform
this sort of mid-session splitting as a
general defense
against uh web network controls in
general
some items you might find for discussion
that could benefit from all of your
expertise and your thoughts
versus talking about systematic security
evaluation there's a sort of
explosion of hyper parameters for a very
flexible system like this
how do we design the best one best
instantiation of pumps given certain
resource constraints
can we quantify the limits of what an
adversary can learn from certain slices
of the traffic
we don't have a great answer for this
other than sort of generating data sets
with different
cons instantiations and throwing dozens
of hours of ml at it and then
you know if the cnn doesn't work then
we're like yeah this is probably secure
um but this doesn't seem very systematic
to me and also i strongly dislike
running ml evaluation so please help me
um uh oh yeah and the second one is
other use cases so we focused on
fingerprinting because there's this
established academic narrative
you know and it's very interesting but
i've seen you know tricks other than the
one we talked about here that involve
connection migration
to do censorship circumvention so we
invite the communication
or the community to continue to think
about
other set models and how network
agnostic protocols are
sort of breaking the primitives that
network control is reliant on
that's all i got for today
can i unsure
yes so thank you very much mona
interesting talk i'm sure that will
generate lots of discussion
even if uh the discussion ends up
centering around fond memories of
playing video games
so our second speaker is muhammad
uh take it away
thank you very much i hope you see my
screen
hi everyone very happy to be here i'm
presenting our recent work with
anastasia and denny's
on honest but curious nets basically
we show that sensitive attributes of
private data
can be encoded into the classifier's
output
let's start with a motivational example
we know that infinite information can be
extracted from users
faces like crazy attributes of
emotion how attractive we are and
even what else what is the body mass
index
just from face image these are all
attributes that you can find public data
sets for them
out there and we know that
every face has a face print all mobile
devices are using to
identify people but we are not
always want to be identified everywhere
so we care about the sensitive
attributes that
about about our private data
are collated
as another motivational example just a
few weeks ago
an insurance company tweeted something
which quickly went viral and
lead to a blog post by that company
apologizing that this is not what
people are understanding about what we
are doing
but the point is that when an insurance
company says that
we can extract non-verbal cues
from your face images to understand
whether you are lying or not lying about
a claim
people are showing sensitivity
and the point is that what are these
non-verbal cues
that you are extracting from my video to
for example process my claim
so this shows that
when we processing people's private data
we are not supposed to collect as
much as i we can we sometimes just
supposed to collect
what we agreed already with the user
to correlate from let's consider this
scenario
that i have a private data for example
is my face image
here is alan turing by the way and
the task is to predict the age
for example and there is a machine
learning service providing a model which
is an
age classifier and it's supposed to
classify
the image and produce an output
which estimates the probability
let's consider binary classification
whether it is more than 18 or
less than 18. so
we know that and in the literature you
can find lots of uh
prior words that show that if
we let people to have access to this
model f here and internal representation
extracted by this model
basically they can infer anything
like for example if there is a sensitive
attribute like gender
that we don't want to be revealed and we
just want
age to be classified here
um so
a machine learning service can extract
this if we let them to process
our data current state is that
we can use h or encrypted computation
to hide all the internal computation and
just release the output so in this
setting
we can run for example the model on the
browser or mobile or use
encrypted computation and just
reveal and just release with the machine
learning service provider
this single value 93 for example
that is the probability of being more
than 18 for example
now the question is can a machine
learning service
just from this 93 0.93
can they also infer the gender of the
data owner
or any other sensitive attribute that's
the
question that we are answering in this
word
that even this single innocent looking
number can be manipulated
to reveal more than what is supposed to
reveal
so in a general setting we consider
that there is a machine learning service
providing
a classifier f here
and they process our data
and we just let them observe the output
of this model
in two settings one where we just
release the raw output of the model or
even
we can do uh processing
and for example by a soft mites option
just reveal the probability like output
a soft score as we call it
and so we have such a
mark of chain that there is a data
like face images and
the service is only supposed to infer y
which is the target
but from the output the y-hat that is
the output of this model
maybe they also trying to infer another
sensitive attribute
s-hat here so this is the general
setting that we consider
and we show that machine learning models
can be trained to be
honest but curious meaning that
they can be honest in predicting
the target attribute but at the same
time
they can also be curious in revealing
a sensitive attribute through this
single output
our main results which i will talk about
them
in a few minutes are that this is
because of the over parameterized
property of ml model
basically high capacity of ml models
allow us to have such an attack
and we show that it is not easy to
distinguish between a standard and hpc
models and also we show that
if these models are used in a teacher
student or knowledge distillation
setting
then there is this risk that
a honest but carious teacher can
transfer curiosity to students
so to show some results let me just
introduce a brief notation
and when i show delta y i'm talking
about the accuracy for the target
attribute
delta s is the accuracy for the
sensitive attribute
and a delta y delta shbc
means that a model which is delta y
accurate for the target and also delta s
accurate
for the sensitive attribute
let's see this basic example consider
this synthetic data set
just a binary and two binary attributes
and data is perfectly
split into four regions and we know that
for example for predicting y
here we can perfectly use a logistic
regression model
but a logistic regression model does not
have capacity to
be also curious model this is the
relation that
we have for a logistic regression
between honesty and curiosity
for example if we use this line
we can just be perfectly honest we can
just predict perfectly
y and we have random guess
accuracy for attribute s
but if we choose this decision boundary
for logistic regression
then we can have moderate honesty and
curiosity like 70 percent
accuracy 75 percent and
if we choose this one we will be
perfectly curious but
no honesty at all and
this shows that a simple logistic
regression cannot be at the same time
both
honest and curious but
if we just double the capacity
like designing a models like this and we
reveal the output
by this formula we can easily see that
we can achieve perfect honesty and
perfect curiosity
i mean this model output has just
four possible outputs which give us
information about both attributes
so the conclusion here is that just by
doubling the capacity of
a simple logistic regression model we
can build another model
that is both honest and both
precarious in a perfect way for that
synthetic data
in the paper we have more theoretical
results on
convex optimization but i cannot explain
it here
but how about more complicated data list
both takes images we have experiment on
two big data sets of face images
for more complicated we showed that
a regularized technique based on entropy
can be used
to train a model for being both honest
and curious
basically if you look at this formula
the first one is the simple
cross-entropy
loss function for the target test but we
can add
another term to the typical binary cross
entropy loss function
to put
the sensitive attribute into the output
as we see for example when the sensitive
attribute is zero
so we can minimize the entropy and when
the sensitive attribute
is one we can maximize the entropy of
output
but this minimization and maximization
of entropy can be done
by some regularizer in a way that we
can again be accurate for the add
prediction of y and then by a threshold
function
we can easily
infer the attribute is
the sensitive attribute but just by
looking at the y hat which is the
output for the target attribute
a result on a utk
data set for example for two attribute
gender
and race we see that for gender
the standard model can get a very good
accuracy
it's the target test but a standard
model cannot be accurate for the race
the top plots but in the bottom plots
we see that hpc model just by trading
a bit accuracy for the public target
task
can achieve a very high accuracy
also for the race which is the sensitive
test
we also in the paper show a more
generalized attack for
attributes beyond binary attributes i
can talk about this in discussion part
for example if we consider agent rays
three classes each of them
we see that we can train a model
that achieve the same honesty or
accuracy for the target task similar to
the
standard model but can achieve
a much higher accuracy in predicting the
sensitive attributes
we also considered a compression
operation to hide this kind of
suspiciousness in this model because
if you look at the average entropy
of um honest but curious model you see
that they
tend to have higher entropy outputs
so this may make them
to be revealed by the users
but a compression technique can help
to also keep the output entropy of these
models
as similar as a standard model
and the final result that i'm showing
now is a result on
a violin vulnerability vulnerability to
knowledge distillation and we showed
that
if a teacher for example if this is a
typical setting these days that
people who have access to large data
sets train a model as
teacher and then make them public and
people that have data
but don't have label for them use this
to do knowledge distillation and we have
shown that this knowledge distillation
is susceptible to this kind of
attack by teach the provider of the
teacher
model and
i think yeah that's the
basically take away of this talk that
machine learning service providers can
train their model
to encode a sensitive entry to be
attribute
into the innocent looking output
for a target attribute there are some
open
questions that we can discuss later
about how to distinguish between these
two or how to encode
more than one attribute and also the
implication of these
on other area of machine learning such
as federated
learning thank you very much
[Music]
okay thank you very much muhammad
another interesting talk
so we have one more speaker who's
escaping me for some reason um which one
was next
sorry i should have killed him as next
um so we have one more speaker in this
section
subham and then we'll jump into the um
30-ish minutes for q a looks like we'll
be slightly less than 30 minutes but
uh yes take it away so
yeah okay let's see
okay so can i even see the screen i
think they can
go to thank hello everyone i am shivam
jain
and i am a graduate student at imperial
college london
and today we will be talking about the
ongoing crypto wars
which are based around the messaging
platforms
that we use at least i use on day-to-day
basis like whatsapp signal
and so on so let's start with the
story of when it began so this started
in 2013
when signal or then of messaging
supported service tech secure released
an app along with their protocol which
provided
two people to chat with each other
in a encrypted end to an encrypted
fashion such that
the intermediary servers cannot know
anything about what they are doing
or what they are talking about in 2014
this protocol was adopted by whatsapp
then came secret chats and telegram
in 2016 messenger by facebook released
secret conversations based on this
protocol and today we have more than 2
billion users who use this
end-to-end encrypted services on a
day-to-day basis
and instagram and messenger might
use and adopt end-to-end encryption all
over their
messaging platforms by 2022
so what how does the end-to-end
encryption works
and the promise of end-to-end encryption
is that when i'm talking to someone when
i'm chatting with someone
it's only me and the other person or the
group of people should know
what i am talking about and not the
intermediate servers
so how it works is basically let's say
i'm sending a message there's a
shared secret key on my device
which encrypts a message an encrypted
message is then sent to a server
server then sends this message to the
recipient which then decrypted
the shared key and then we both can
share the messages
now not just text we can also send
images with this or any other media
and the question comes then this can
also be used
to share possibly illegal content
and several organizations and
researchers have raised the concern that
encrypted messaging platforms can be
used to share
any illegal content such as child porn
or
ex terrorist content or something else
and illegal as defined by the
enforcement authorities
but the server won't know what is going
by
and now people came together again to
find a solution
that okay how do we stop this what do we
do and like in 90s the first solution
that they came up with
is key escrow systems or one of the
first
and what it is is basically you have a
set of
devices and the keys are stored on a
cloud or in a database
in some secured way
and third parties or law enforcement for
example law enforcement agencies
can ask for these keys under exceptional
access
or under certain circumstances which are
predefined
and so these key escrow systems
are raises significant privacy concerns
within the privacy
pets community including by researchers
that were there i think
yesterday and maybe now in the session
as well
and the main concern that is being
raised against this
systems is that firstly it is
impractical to build
such a key escrow system for
large scale data like you're handling
keys for 2 billion users
but at the same time you need this to be
secure and you need this to be abuse
resistant
and this concern comes from is grounded
in the
examples that we have seen over the
years for example companies like apple
have tried building such as
such a escrow system but even those have
been found to be vulnerable
and the community doesn't have enough
confidence that this is possible
so since last few years people have been
wondering that okay what are the other
possible solutions
and they come up with an alternative
which is client-side scanning
and the way this works is you have now i
i want to send a
miss image to someone i
upload it on my app for example whatsapp
now the whatsapp will create a digital
fingerprint which is
in this fingerprinting algorithm will be
part of the app itself
and this fingerprint will then be sent
to check for a match
against a database of fingerprints of
known illegal images
and if a match is found i wouldn't be
allowed to send a
send this message and some further
action will be taken depending on the
implementation
and if the no match is found then i can
encrypt the data and the message is sent
as routine
so again like when this came out about
in last couple of years
and several privacy concerns have been
raised against this as well
and firstly the biggest concern is that
this
increases attack surfaces what does it
mean is that now you have
uh digital fingerprinting algorithm and
match that is happening which can
possibly be exploited by
hackers or attackers or other
adversaries
then the second most important question
here is who controls the database what
is the process
what is there in the database how do you
avoid this being
abused further you start with illegal
content
such as csam or child porn
you go with terrorism what stops them
from
using it for other purposes
so there is a possibility of mission
creep
so based on this the other concern that
has come up
is basically can an adversary evade
detection for example if i were to send
this dog message
dog photo and if a match was found
can an adversary who just has access to
this app
in a black box setup try to change this
image by a little bit and
create a new hash such that it will
evade detection
this is the question we ask in our
research is that
is client-side scanning is a robust
solution
is it possible to evade detection easily
or not
and to do this we first understand how
exactly the
proposed client-side scanning will work
and the current proposals rely on
perceptual hashing algorithms
so these are the standard algorithms
that have been
there in the usage since couple of
decades where they are mainly used for
efficient image retrieval the way it
works is basically you say
give an image it creates an index or a
fingerprint which is much smaller in
size
and so it protects privacy in some way
and that's why the claim is
that the client side scanning does not
just solve this problem but
it does it in a privacy preserving way
and the perceptual hashing algorithms
are designed such a way that similar
images
would have similar fingerprints so that
it is harder to modify an image and
e-way detection
while the different images would have
completely different fingerprints
facebook's pdq is one of the commonly
used
open and also open sourced perceptual
hashing algorithm
and it is important to note this because
purchase flashing algorithms which are
used in practice lot of them
are closed source and no details are
available to the public
so and the next part is now you have the
fingerprint that you created using
perceptual hashing
how do you match the fingerprints so for
each
fingerprint we in the database we match
the
send fingerprint with it and we measure
a distance between the two
and this distance is measured using
something like a hamming distance which
is basically you take the two
fingerprints and you see how many pixels
are different if number of different
pixels is less than a sum predefined
threshold
then you say yes it's a match if there
is no such
match possible or in the database you
say there is no match form
now if it was a safe image or a non
illegal image
and a match was found that is false
positive it shouldn't be there
it shouldn't be flagged and ideally it
should be
saved as no match found which is a true
negative and similarly we have an
if an illegal image was found a match
that is true positive
and if a legal image was could evade
the match then it would be a false
negative
the threshold is basically chosen such
that it balances
the trade-off between the false
positives and false negatives
it is chosen in such a way that both of
them are within a certain limit
and what we know is obvious like
as threshold will increase more images
would be flagged
the false positives would increase true
positives will also increase
and the false negatives would decrease
and again going back to facebook's pdq
it recommends a threshold of somewhere
from 20 to 90
why we are mentioning this because we'll
come back to this later
so what we show is basically now
can adversary bypass the detection by
css and now what we know from
the our knowledge of the proposed client
side scanning
is that our adversary has
access to black box and now it wants to
change the
image in such a way that the resulting
hash is away
at a distance of at least t or from the
original hash the adversary will choose
the threshold
will choose the image that it wants to
perturb and
run the black box attack or if it and
see if it is possible
and what we show is basically that more
than 99.9
of images can be modified successfully
using standard blackbox adversarial
ml techniques for five popular hashing
algorithms and a wide range of detection
thresholds
for this we used image in a dataset and
we adopted a standard
approach for the adversary attack based
on evolutionary strategies
so the images look like something like
this so here on the left
you can see the top examples you have
the original image
on the right you have the modified image
for pdq algorithm when threshold was 30.
at the bottom you can see for four
different thresholds for the pdq that we
tried 30 70
85 and 90 and
almost all the images seem really
very similar but at the same time now
we know that we can successfully perturb
the images images look similar
but does it really evade detection
because now it's not about one image
it's about the whole database so the
question we asked next is
is pushing hash beyond the threshold t
enough to evade detection
and to answer this we calculate the
false negative rate
which is probability that a modified
illegal image would evade detection
and we create a data for this we use
image the data set again and a database
size
of 100 000 and we find that for
threshold of 30
97 of the modified illegal images evaded
detection
and this number goes down to 67 as we
increase the threshold
so yes if we increase the threshold the
attack becomes a bit harder to carry out
but is increasing threshold and
effective defense
and to measure this we use false
positive rate which is probability that
a safe image is detected falsely
or detected wrongly and
what we see is that when we use a
smaller threshold
about one out of thousand images
are or safe images are false rejected
but as soon as we go to like threshold
of 90 which is where we
saw earlier our attack might become a
bit a bit difficult
here every third image is being flagged
wrongly what does it mean in practice
is that if there were 4.5
safe images that were shared daily
4.5 billion then almost 1.6 or 1.5
billion images would be flagged
daily
so to conclude this i think there are
three main points that we discussed
today firstly
we talked about client side scanning
which is proposed as a privacy
preserving solution to detect illegal
content
secondly we showed that css is not a
robust solution
and almost always an image can be
modified to avoid detection in even in a
black box setup that is the proposed
way of how it will be implemented and
lastly we showed that defenses to
improve robustness of such systems
don't work we have the paper is
available
on archive you can look at it this work
was done in collaboration
with my colleagues anna maria and eva
exam at imperial college london
you can follow us on our twitter thank
you for that and
this currently under review thank you
okay thank you very much for another
interesting talk
um so we now have plenty of time for qa
i will
share my screen again just to put the
um the talks that we just saw back up so
you could remember everybody's names and
so on to help uh facilitate the
discussion and
please if you have questions ask in the
chat or be like ian and hop right up to
the mic and just start talking