hello my name is daniel smolin and today
i'll be presenting our work
titled managing potentially intrusive
practices in the browser
a user-centered perspective today
web browsing is a really tricky
situation because on different websites
there's many different data practices
and not everybody feels the same way
about them some people see practices as
good
they can make browsing safer more
relevant potentially even more useful
and some practices can be seen as bad
some people see them as intrusive or too
complex
and they can be difficult to understand
in this work we use the term potentially
intrusive practices
to generically refer to common
third-party tracking methods
this includes fingerprinting as well as
other types of scripts that run in the
browser to collect data
monitor activity redirect users
attention or operate in the background
to gather something of value
but note in our study we refer to these
practices neutrally
using terminology such as web
technologies and i'll discuss more about
why we did that a little later
fundamentally whether or not an
intrusive practice is a problem for you
depends on many factors it can depend on
your preferences
or the type of website you're browsing
or what you're doing there
as well as how security and privacy
conscious you are your confidence in the
ability to control data practices
and even what you actually have control
over as well as potentially many more
factors
but where harms occur is when your
expectations don't match with your
browsing experience
so being able to manage what you're okay
or not okay with
is really crucial
so that's why the aim of the study is to
understand what users want
what they actually get and to find ways
to fill the gap between the two
therefore we focused on a few key
research questions
first what are the signals that users
rely on to determine that they're being
subjected to intrusive practices
or being protected from them second what
affordances do users associate with
enabling or disabling these practices
third are there practices that users
would want to control such as opting in
or opting out of them and subject to
what kind of contextual attributes
and finally what practices do users
prefer to be notified about
how often and in what sorts of contexts
for example
are there differences between popular or
less popular websites
or different website categories
employed a methodology which can be
summarized as follows
first we created a taxonomy of
potentially intrusive practices
using both technical definitions for
internal use
in order to remain technically
consistent and also with non-technical
definitions that we used in our survey
instruments
that would be suitable for laypersons
without them having to understand
all the details these also included
descriptions of risks and benefits
all with neutral language these
descriptions also underwent further
analysis
by focus groups and were also tested in
pilot studies
we used these definitions to create a
qualitative survey
where we collected information about
where users had encountered them
what they'd done about them and how they
recognized the different practices
and these results underwent grounded
analysis which then informed the
creation of a large-scale quantitative
survey
where we collected people's preferences
to opt out of these different practices
among different contexts this
large-scale corpus of preferences
was then used to evaluate alternative
settings which could hopefully offer
better results in terms of more accurate
settings
with less user burden associated with
them than what are currently offered
across different websites
and different browsers
the taxonomy of potentially intrusive
practices included the following
practices seen here
ranging from identity sign and services
such as sign in with google and so on
all the way down to targeted advertising
behavioral profiling
reporting and analytics fingerprinting
nag screens
session replay and crypto mining
and for each of these practices we ask
questions about them in different
contexts
different website categories such as
news entertainment
shopping travel finance adult health and
social media
and for each of these website categories
we showed examples of
popular websites as well as unpopular
websites
across each of these different
categories
however there was some important
methodological considerations when we
went about doing this study
as mentioned earlier it was crucially
important that we mitigated bias as much
as possible
by using neutral language we didn't want
to impart our own bias as researchers
we also found that amongst ourselves we
often felt quite negatively towards
these practices
and it was really important that we
didn't prime our participants
accordingly
however there were instances where we
did want to prime
the participants on purpose for example
we wanted to make sure that they
understood what the different websites
were
among the different categories therefore
we provided them with screenshots as
well as other information about the
websites
such as where they were based when they
were created and so on
and we also wanted to prime them about
the different categories of practices to
make sure that it was clear
based on the definitions that we'd
created for them earlier
finally we employed randomization
wherever possible
in order to mitigate learning effects
such as among the ordering of different
website categories
and showing popular versus unpopular
websites in particular order
so what did we find well here's a brief
summary of the results from our grounded
analysis which we organized into the key
themes you can see here
but the ones that i'll focus on for this
presentation are demonstrating
understanding
and misinterpreted signals
when it comes to demonstrating
understanding what we found was that a
majority of our participants
74 were able to demonstrate a clear
understanding of the potential risks and
benefits of the practices that we showed
them
based on their descriptions however we
also found
that our participants mentioned benefits
of practices
without us having prompted them even
though we later provided them with both
examples of risks
and benefits so for instance when it
came to nag screens
our participants mentioned that nag
screens could draw their attention
to important items of interest even if
they did find the nag screens annoying
when it came to fingerprinting
participants mentioned that
it could be used to potentially secure
their accounts which they saw as
important
especially on financial websites for
example
we also saw evidence of misinterpreted
signals such as in the following quote
well with the ad blocker script blocker
program i know i successfully opted out
because i don't receive any ads at all
and with the script blocker i'm pretty
sure the website isn't receiving any
information from me based off my limited
knowledge of the program
same goes for private browsing i guess
so is this participant suggesting
that no ads on the website means that
there aren't any intrusive practices to
worry about
we saw evidence of a similar pattern
such as this one
in many of our participants responses
we also saw evidence that most people
want to deny intrusive practices most of
the time
which is clearly seen in this table
summarizing those results
also you can note that fingerprinting
has a slightly lower level of preference
to deny overall
which is likely explained by the focus
on benefits that we saw
as mentioned earlier
but what if the settings work
differently what would that be like
in this study we also wanted to explore
based on the corpus of preferences
whether we might be able to improve upon
the settings that are offered in a
patchwork
between websites and browsers
however when evaluating these
alternative settings it was really
important to focus on the two key
measurements
of whether these alternative settings
were better the first measurement
is accuracy meaning in what percentage
of scenarios do the settings enable
users
to align the practices that they're
subjected to with their preferences
after all not all models of alternative
settings would enable users to get the
granular settings that they were looking
for
also we evaluated user burden meaning
how many individual settings need to be
changed for the user to get the settings
that they actually wanted
and we'll note that the maximum
measurement of user burden
was determined by the number of websites
we surveyed since we surveyed 16
websites across 8 different categories
16 would be the maximum value of user
burden
and what we found in terms of accuracy
it looks like this
when we start with the first no toggle
allow model
we're referring to essentially what's
offered by chrome
where all of the different practices are
allowed and there aren't any settings
available
to deny them next when we look at no
toggle deny
this is what is most similar to strict
mode in most browsers
where all the settings are denied with
no further settings offered
you can see here that the accuracy
substantially increases
between the no toggle allow and the no
toggle deny
and this is easily explained by the
proportion of participants that we saw
preferring to opt out in general but
when we look at the other two models
category toggles and website toggles
this allowed us to answer two different
sets of questions
with category toggles we're answering
the question of what if browsers offered
comprehensive settings
that were based on website categories
and you can see
that this results in a substantially
higher accuracy
then when we look at individual website
toggles
that's answering the question of what if
every website offered comprehensive
settings
allowing participants to allow or deny
each of these data practices
across every individual website which is
not currently offered
of course this would allow 100 accuracy
since in every scenario there's a choice
available
for the user to change the setting to
what they want
but measuring only the accuracy gives
only half of the picture
and so you the burden is also important
to evaluate these alternative settings
because these different models offer
wildly different amounts of burden
you can see that the no toggle allow
default is actually what we're currently
considering to be the default and
therefore
has no user burden associated with it
and it only takes one setting change to
move
from this setting to no toggle deny
but when we also take a look at the
different default settings
among category toggles and website
toggles we noticed a pattern
where the allow by default settings were
substantially more burdensome
and then of course on the flip side that
did not deny by default settings
were substantially less burdensome so
when we consider the trade-off between
the amount of user burden associated
with configuring these different models
and then reconcile that with the level
of accuracy that we get
we can see that there's some
improvements to be made the no toggle
deny settings overall
give a good improvement in accuracy but
still only about 75
overall so this is a reasonable
trade-off especially considering that
there's a very low level of user burden
but we certainly can do much better than
that after all the category toggles
with deny by default offered roughly 92
percent
average accuracy and yet also have a
very low level of user burden associated
with them
so we recognize that this might
potentially be an optimal trade-off
so the key takeaways from this
particular part of our study were as
follows
deny by default settings are much closer
to what people want
and we could clearly see this earlier
when people express their preferences to
opt out
but we also see here that deny by
default is
less burdensome people need to make less
decisions and need to change less
settings
when we have deny by default settings
we also see however that individual
website settings
are simply too burdensome if we offered
settings across every single website
which is not currently offered
it's still better than the situation
where people don't have any choice at
all
but we're simply offering them far too
many choices particularly
if we're doing allow by default settings
therefore standard settings which are
based on website categories
would likely be much easier to configure
but would still retain
very high accuracy
but there's still a problem and that
problem is website breakage and
misaligned incentives
you see as i mentioned earlier websites
only offer a patchwork of different
options
and so if we were to ensure that
websites each offered comprehensive
options
for controlling all the different
practices we described in our study
it would create a large amount of
additional burden
but a single place to configure these
preferences would be far more ideal
rather than forcing people to
reconfigure these preferences on
individual websites as they browse the
web
so let's make the settings standard if
they're configured the same way
and applied everywhere it would
certainly be a big improvement for users
but would it unfortunately it's just not
that simple
standards such as do not track and other
similar voluntary standards have failed
as they're often not respected by
different individual websites
and the reason why this happens is
because websites have different
incentives than browsers
or different incentives from users
websites could potentially break
when people try to enact their
preferences but then blame the user
just because they're trying to take back
control what we need then
is standards that websites will comply
with in order to prevent
the situation where people get punished
just for simply enacting their
preferences
so to summarize people have different
levels of appreciation
for the risks and benefits of different
practices even if they don't understand
all the different technical details and
what we found
was that there's relationships between
people's op debt preferences
the types of practices and the types of
websites
which suggests that one size fits all
settings really can't satisfy everyone
we also found that most people want to
opt out and they assume that settings
must exist whether it's in their browser
or on websites
but they have a hard time finding them
typically because they don't actually
exist
and this results in a lot of frustration
people also want to be notified about
the practices that exist on different
sites
but they're misled by what they see when
they're browsing particularly when it
comes to things like ads
and what results is a misalignment
between the control that people expect
over potentially intrusive practices
and what they're actually getting when
they're browsing
we believe then that standard settings
have the potential to help
they could be both more accurate than
one size fits all preferences
and also be less burdensome than
offering settings individually across
every different website
for every different practice
so to find out more about this research
we invite you to check out
privacyassistant.org
for the personalized privacy assistant
project as well as our paper
and we'd like to thank dr steve
englehart and professor alessandra
acquisti
for their helpful suggestions with this
work we also want to acknowledge that
this work was supported in part
by grants from the following
organizations mozilla
darpa the air force research laboratory
and the national science foundation
if you'd like to contact us to find out
more about this work
please feel free to get in touch with us
using the contact information seen here
the corresponding authors for this paper
are marked with an asterisk
and are shaded in gray thanks very much
for your attention