hello everyone thank you for being here
today i'm siddish a second year phd
student at the university of washington
and today i'll be presenting details and
measurements
of a new privacy enhancing bns protocol
called odo
or oblivious dns over https this was a
part of my internship work at cloudflare
over the last summer
and it would not have been possible
without all the incredible collaborators
i'm very excited to be representing all
of them in today's talk
as a quick introduction and most of you
might already know
dns is the domain name system and is
really the foundation of a human usable
internet
it responds to client queries for host
names with the corresponding ip
addresses and records
and traditionally the dns protocol is
not encrypted and it uses udp
which continues to be a majority of the
traffic that is received
by the public resolver that cloudflare
operates
the usage of non-encrypted dns leaks
user information to network
operators and passive network
adversaries like this detective eyeball
who is observing the network
and also allows active attackers like
the red monster here
to modify the request from the client or
the response from the resolver
to overcome some of these problems there
have been recent efforts to secure dns
using dns over tls dot or dns over https
or doh
both of which have been gaining
popularity and have been integrated into
various web browsers and operating
systems
these protocols protect the client
traffic from being observed by onlookers
or being intercepted and changed by an
on path attacker
but a problem still remains the resolver
operator can continue
to associate the client requests to
their ip addresses and build a profile
around their browsing pattern
over the past few years we have seen
active measurement research trying to
understand and measure the impacts of
encrypted protocols like doe
or dod and many large scale measurements
have shown that the performance of
encrypted protocols they vary by the
choice of the resolver
it does not significantly impact page
load times and it improves user security
there have also been various attempts to
improve page load times by prefetching
but why don't did improve the security
of dns queries
for the clients it also received a lot
of criticism about the small number of
publicly available resolver services
essentially centralizing the internet
and giving these organizations a lot of
control
additionally these resolver operators
can associate all the client queries
with the client ip addresses and using
the ip to geo locate their client
to maintain privacy guarantees some
operators like cloudflare actively purge
data exceeding 24 hours
and give their users privacy
policy-based guarantees
but bringing together organizations to
agree on a common set of privacy
practices
to maintain user privacy requires
explicit negotiation and effort
mozilla for example actively defined the
criteria around data retention and
aggregation
with frequent audits before a dose
service can be configured as a preset
default
in the firefox browser but while some
users might be comfortable with a policy
driven approach
these are difficult to enforce and are
really time consuming making users want
a system
that can technologically guarantee their
privacy in this talk i'll kind of focus
on the privacy critiques and the ability
of the resolvers to be able to create a
profile of their clients
this is exactly where oblivious dns over
https or odo kicks in
odo was originally proposed as a draft
at the ietf
to improve client ip privacy at a high
level there are three main components in
novel
the first are the clients who prepare a
query for which they would like a
response
the goal of the clients in odo is to be
able to successfully send encrypted
messages
receive valid responses to decrypt and
in the process
be able to identify if there are
malicious actors and take corrective
action
the second is a proxy instance whose
main role
is to relay the encrypted queries and
the responses
to and from the targets while removing
the ip addresses of the clients
the third is a target instance which
receives the encrypted query from the
client
decrypts it and obtains a dns response
for the query
the target's role is to then prepare an
encrypted response
and send it back to the proxy with no
ability to identify the client by their
ip addresses
let's dive into the design of the yoyo
protocol at a high level
the design of odo is similar to that of
doh and it kind of builds on it
in indo the the resolver can see the
client ip addresses
and the query while providing secure
encrypted communication channels
by injecting an intermediate proxy node
which terminates the client query and
performs the query on the client's
behalf
the resolver now no longer sees the ip
address of the client
but the intermediate proxy sees both the
client ip and the client query
information
and the usage of go on both the client
proxy and the proxy resolver segments
of the connection prevent network
adversaries from modifying or passively
analyzing the information
but building on the proxy door design we
would like to ensure that the
intermediate proxy
not have query information and the
result will not have the client id
addresses
with the main goal of odo to prevent
recursive resolvers and isps
running such resolvers from being able
to link clients to their queries
the security model here builds on the
premise that the proxy and the targets
do not follow
that's a critical part of the design so
clients need to choose proxies and
targets such that they are not operated
by the same entity
or known to be colluding and finally we
have the protocol where the client
encrypts
the dns query using a hybrid public key
encryption scheme
and using a valid public key of the
target resolver
and sends the query with an encapsulated
symmetric key from an authenticated
encryption scheme
to the proxy instance there are various
ways in which the clients can
learn about the services and validate
them to dns sec validation or look for
conflicting keys for the same resolvers
but in our design we assume extended
olivia adversaries
which have the ability to create drop
and modify any messages
and also give them the ability to
compromise tls sessions in our analysis
of the security of the protocol
practically colluding adversaries on
various network links who
who can decrypt the connection to read
the message contents can create
associations
between the encrypted query and the
encrypted response
and compromise the resolver's secret key
and and the compromise uh
of the secret key could actually help
such attacks
uh in in aldo the proxy instance can see
the ip address of the client but not the
contents of the dns query
and forwards this message to the
oblivious target which decrypts the
query and decapsulates the symmetric key
and obtains a response from the resolver
the response is
encrypted by the oblivious target using
the symmetric key provided and it is
sent back to the proxy who only sends
the message to the client
where it can be decrypted in this
process the target
only sees the dns contents and not the
actual client's ip addresses
and we often say that the target and
resolver are independent entities but
this need not really be the case
ideally in practice for performance
reasons the oblivious target and the
recursive resolver could be co-located
to avoid additional network messages
between the oblivious target and the
resolver
but it is still possible to maintain
these as individual services without
co-location
but that would incur some performance
penalty due to additional network
requests
we formally analyze the protocol and
prove dilemma that
an adversary is unable to associate a
connection between the client and the
proxy
with the corresponding query unless both
the proxy
and the targets are compromised this
brought to light a replay attack in the
original proposal
which has been fixed as a part of this
work
now with the understanding of the
protocol in place there were three main
research questions that interested us
what is the impact of odo on the dns
response times
how does odo compare itself to other
privacy enhancing protocol variants that
are out there today
and how does using odo affect page load
times and user experiences
this helped us understand the cost of
privacy for the user while maintaining
the security guarantees that are
provided by encrypted dns protocols
for the measurements in this work we
implemented and deployed the oblivious
targets and proxies using google cloud
and a serverless platform like
cloudflare workers
we physically separated the oblivious
target instances from the resolvers and
randomized the query from the target to
three public resolvers cloudflare dns
google dns and quad9
which we use in our measurements we use
nine google cloud data center locations
seven across the united states one in
montreal canada and
one in sao paulo in brazil with 10
client instances running at
each one of these vantage points
performing an experiment sending dns
requests at a rate of 15 requests per
minute
which is the average number of dns
requests sent by client devices with
very high internet usage
the average bandwidth of all the clients
running on a single core
intel xeon processor is roughly 480
megabits per second
the clients perform dns response time
measurements by choosing
pairs of available proxy and targets and
this brings us to the first result
by choosing a low latency proxy target
pair for the measurements
shown by the orange line we find that
the average
query response time improves by 22.8
percent
compared to only choosing the low
latency proxy which is shown by the
green line
this this kind of hints towards the fact
that having an intermediate proxy
on the same network path to the target
will improve response time performance
and this path however can be quite
different from the path that a udp-based
dns packet might actually travel on
this then brings the the connection the
the question of connection reuse
and connection reuse is an optimization
that can enable clients to improve their
performance by at least 48
at the median avoiding unnecessary tcp
and tls handshakes for every request
but however the reuse of connections
could leak some
client identity information but it still
does not leak any information about the
query
or their responses and in our
experimental setup
we evaluate for the worst case
performance and we incur an additional
network latency
between the target instance and the
resolver in the architecture that we saw
before
as we can see here the target instances
which are located in google cloud
and performing queries to three public
open resolvers have a faster response
time for google dns
because of potential co-location within
the same data center compared to the
other services
and integrating the oblivious target
into the recursive resolver can reduce
the network latency
to that of a cache hit for that for the
answer and a cache miss
incurring the additional network cost to
speak to the uh
name servers we find that co-locating
these services results in better
performance and we've engineered that
into the public resolver that is
operated by cloudflare
as a public service for everyone
to understand the performance of odo we
compare this to other protocols
offering similar privacy and security
guarantees
and use dough as the baseline protocol
which is shown here on the blue line on
the left side
and go over tor which is a variant of
dough which provides both security and
privacy guarantees in addition to some
anonymity guarantees
and this is the orange line to the right
side of the figure that you see here
when compared to odo in green we notice
that odo with no service co-location
achieves this interesting position
roughly between do and do what are
and the results get more interesting and
better as we start to co-locate the
target
and the resolver together which is shown
as the purple line on this figure
and we notice that the response time for
odor compared to that of do as the
baseline
increases at the median by 50 percent
with the service collocation and 100
when the target and the resolver are
actually not co-located
dns protocols with message encryption
like dns script
tend to have much larger compute
overheads and use
non-encrypted channels these protocols
have
higher response time and lie between the
doe and odo
and over tor as shown by this dotted
arrow in this figure and the performance
uh
in response times is is a middle ground
between baseline doe
and privacy enhancing variants such as
do over tor or on an
or anonymous dns script all while
achieving similar privacy guarantees
i'll keep it short for this talk but
here's a slide for reference which you
could revisit for
seeing the comparisons of various
network architectural variants
and where odo fits in along with the
protocol security and the privacy
guarantees that is offered
there's also a link to the production
service which is the case of co-located
odo that cloudflare operates today
this brings us to a crucial measurement
that we're really interested in
the page load time impact to do this we
establish a measurement node in a lab
network
connected to a commercial isp the node
runs a local stub resolver which is
configured to use
do or odo for various runs in each run
the web browser browses to the same set
of pages
after purging any local cache entries
and performs the page load time
measurements
and we retrieve the hard files
and identify the various page events the
measurements presented
here use the public order services
operated by cloudflare
and considers the complete page load
event and dns response times
we find that the median page load time
increases by 6.7 percent when using
dough
compared to do 53 and 9.8
when using co-located odo services
in summary odo is a practical privacy
enhancing protocol
for dns with minimal total page load
time impacts
and the performance impacts of the
protocol are purely network topology
effects
for better usage in production systems
having an ecosystem of on-path proxies
service co-location and connection reuse
along with the support for the protocol
by clients could be valuable for dns
privacy
our code libraries and implementations
are open source
and are made available along with
operational production services
thank you so much