hi today i'm going to talk about privgan
a novel privacy president protecting gan
architecture
dataset sharing is hard essential
sharing data publicly or between
institutions leads to
innovations such as development of new
machine learning models
drug development etc however such data
can often
contain private information about
individuals which can be misused by
malicious actors
therefore there is a huge need to
develop the privacy preserving
techniques to share data between
institutions or publicly
one potential solution is the use of
synthetic data
recent progress in generative machine
learning has led to models that can
generate realistic synthetic data
after training on a real data set
an example is shown here the leftmost
image
is a real image and the two left images
are generated by cans
as you can see the fake images are quite
like the real images
the idea with synthetic data is that the
synthetic datasets can be used to train
models for downstream machine learning
tasks such as regression classification
etc and the naive assumption
that people had when this practice
became common was
that since samples are synthetic each
sample does not leak information about
real people
however this is an incorrect assumption
and i'll explain how
to do that i'll first need to describe
what a membership inference attack is
a membership inference attack is a
privacy attack
where an adversary with access to
many samples wants to just
simply know whether a sample was used to
train a machine learning model or not
the adversary has some access to the
trained model query access
and uses this query the query output for
each sample
to predict whether or not the sample was
used
to train the machine learning model so
why would such an attack work
for tasks like this to work the query
values for
samples used to train the model should
be very different from samples that were
not used to train the model
and as most of you who have
worked with with machine learning would
know that this happens
a lot overfitting a model happens a lot
in machine learning particularly as
model complexity increases and hence
the trainings that sample the query
output for single training set samples
are
quite often quite different from the
samples that were not used in training
making such attacks very powerful
okay um so let's take a quick diversion
diversion to
first uh to define what again is
gan stands for generative adversarial
networks
generally adversarial networks are broad
family of
generative machine learning models and
they usually comprise of
two machine learning modules a generator
and a discriminator
the goal of the generator is attempt to
generate realistic data
while the discriminator attempts to
identify
fake samples from real samples so the
process of
training these two modules reduces to a
two-player game between the
discriminator and the generator
and eventually the generator succeeds in
generating samples that are
indistinguishable from the real
or in other words it learns the
data set that the sample the real
samples are drawn from
so how can such a model overfit to the
training set
to demonstrate that let's look at this
experiment
here we plot a histogram of the
discriminator scores
a quick reminder this screener is just a
binary classifier
for real versus fake so its output is a
number between 0 and 1.
so we plot the histogram of the
discriminator scores for samples that
were
used to train the model shown in red and
samples that were not used to train the
model
shown in blue and as you can see there
is quite a large discrepancy between the
distributions
to the red and the blue distributions
and this is even larger in
passionateness than
compared to mnist uh since fashion
numbness is a more complicated data set
um and as one might imagine since there
are such
there's such a large discrepancy between
these two distributions an
adversary that relies on this difference
would quite would be quite powerful
so what are the existing solutions to
this problem the most common class of
existing solution
is are differentially private gans
as most of you might know differential
privacy is a way to bound the privacy of
algorithms
not models and leads to strong formal
guarantees
it involves the addition of noise to
gradients during discriminator training
as in dbgan
or adding noise to labels
for discriminatory training as in patty
the problem however is that this leads
to very poor synthetic image quality
um as demonstrated in this example here
so the leftmost uh
set of images are real images uh whereas
the everything right of it
are synthetic images and as you can see
as you
decrease the amount of privacy epsilon
here
you eventually get to a point where the
samples are
quite realistic however only for the
rightmost
column where images are horribly
corrupted
is the privacy parameter epsilon
even in a realistic range to provide a
private usable privacy bound everything
left of it is the provides a privacy
bound that
is so loose that it's almost as good as
not providing a bound at all
um this brings us to our solution
protgan private is much like a regular
again
it contains uh of generated and
discriminatory modules but
instead of one generator and one
discriminator
it can module it contains multiple
generators and discriminators
the way it works is the data set is
initially randomly split into two or
more
non-overlapping parts each part of the
data set gets a generator and a
discriminator
the goal of this the generator is now to
fool
not just its corresponding discriminator
but an
additional module called the privacy
discriminator
the privacy discriminator looks at
synthetic data generated from different
generators and tries to tell them apart
and the generator's goal is to therefore
generate synthetic data
that is that somehow has the
characteristics of the overall data set
and not just the portion it's being
exposed to
so this takes the form of a multiplayer
game
and it can be shown that the effect of
adding the privacy discriminator
is um mathematically equivalent
to providing a regularization
of sorts and it bounds the
um the distribution learn
the synthetic distributions learned by
each generator
so the overall
outcome of this process is that proofgan
prevents generators and discriminators
from overfitting to any data split
so how private is bribcan so coming back
to our previous example
of now on
the same data sets that we showed that
the non-private can horribly overfits
um to the training set uh we can show
that trivian
uh again has multiple discriminators so
we
choose one of the one one of the
discriminations on random
and we perform the same experiment and
we show that um
the distribution the difference between
the distributions of same
distributions blue and red is much
smaller
so um discriminatory scores for
samples that were in the training set
versus samples that were not in the
training set
are very small in case of proof gain so
an attack that relies
on the use of such scores would be very
ineffective
so can we show this quantity uh to
demonstrate this quantitatively
we performed experiments against several
state-of-the-art attacks in our paper
uh the one that i'm going to show here
is
um quite similar to the qualitative
experiment shown previously
so the way it works is uh you have data
set
you pass the data set the address has a
data set
passes each of the samples in the data
set through the discriminator
obtains a score for each sample and then
sorts the samples in descending order
the attack also assumes that the
adversary knows how many samples were
used in
the training of the model say n
and takes the top end predictions
um so how successful is this attack
so in the case of a regular gan shown in
red you can see that as you increase the
number of epochs
uh the white box attack accuracy can go
up quite a bit um however prick can
consistently
uh provide um you know
privacy membership privacy protection at
least against this stack
here and we show that
uh we in in the paper we show
that this is true for other
state-of-the-art
heart attacks as well
so how does the hyper parameter choices
improve can affect membership privacy
um tricant has two hyper parameters and
the number of generator and
discriminator pairs
and lambda which is how much we weigh
the differential the privacy
discriminator module
in the in the loss function
so we show here that as you increase
lambda
the white box accuracy decreases on all
data sets
and similarly as you increase the number
of generators you
see the same effect however it is
important to point out that unlike
epsilon and delta and differential
private differentially private
approaches
n and lambda and privigan are data set
dependent quantities and they don't have
an
intrinsic meaning in terms of privacy
so what n and lambda will work best for
your data set is dependent on your data
set
and has to be experimentally determined
so um as mentioned before
uh one of the motivations behind privgan
was uh
providing a decent level of performance
downstream utility
um while providing membership privacy
benefits
so to see whether we're able to do that
we perform this experiment where you
take
um various gans for again
the non-private can and dp can generate
synthetic images
same number as the training set um
in these various data sets train a
cnn based classifier model on the
synthetic data
and then test on the real test set so
uh you can see in the very er on the red
bar
is if you train them the cnn model on
real data
um and test on real data this is
obviously the best case scenario
uh the gray bar is if you use a
non-private can
and then the three blue bars are private
for increasing levels of privacy
uh we test point one one and um
ten uh values for lambda
the green bar is dp again at an epsilon
of 100 which is a ridiculously high
epsilon but anything below that
leads to unusable images pretty much
and you can see consistently that
provgan leads to very
little drop in utility um compared to
um compared to the non-private gan and
the utility is much higher than db can
even for
a very high value of epsilon and d began
um so so far we've shown privacy and
utility separately
and shown that privigen
provides both privacy and utility
benefits but what if we compare
them simultaneously so we
do that here where we take various
values of
epsilon in the case of dpn and various
the lambda in case of privgan and
generate synthetic data and perform um
you know the utility experiment record
the classification accuracy and the
privacy experiment and report the
white box accuracy and you can see that
in across two data sets we can see that
for
most values of membership privacy
quantified by the white box accuracy
privigan provides
much higher utility
measured by classification accuracy in
the previous experiment
and so we can
show that in most regimes uh privcan is
a better alternative to dpgan
and we performed a similar experiment on
patty again
there are several practical deployment
considerations while using privian
the first is scan architecture selection
we recommend performing architecture
selection on the non-private can of your
choice
and then use the same discriminator and
generator architectures
for critcan um the privacy discriminator
which is the additional modules found in
privacan but not in other gans
is simply a minor modification to the
regular discriminator modules and
requires a modification in the final
layer as described in
paper
another consideration might be
membership privacy certification
for both the model and the synthetic
data sets um
we recommend using either
state-of-the-art protects
as query specific empirical certificates
or using
formal query specific private membership
types privacy certification mechanisms
as described in our follow-up work below
um finally private has two additional
hyper parameters
which affect both privacy as well as
utility
we recommend users to identify their
desired utility and query specific
privacy levels
and perform a grid search to identify
appropriate values
of n the number of generators and lambda
that provide the desired utility and
privacy levels and this too can use the
framework cited below in summary
provegan is a novel membership privacy
protecting
can architecture provegan can
effectively protect gans against
state-of-the-art membership inference
attacks
shown in our paper while maintaining
high quality of generated samples
propaganda compares favorably in terms
of privacy versus utility against
other privacy preserving canard
approaches such as the began and
pakistan
and here is the link to our repo
thank you