hi everyone my name is jen tian meow
a phd candidate from swimmer university
of technology
today i'd like to present our paper
titled the audio auditor
user level membership inference internet
of things voice service
we'd like to thank the precious
suggestions from these papers
reviewers chairs and the shepherd
which greatly improved this paper's
quality
now allow me to elaborate this research
step by step
for your information this is today's
roadmap
in this research we focus on the core
component of oil t
voice service automatic speech
recognition system
in short asr system briefly
we design an audio auditor to perform
user level membership inference tasks
the auditor can verify whether a
specific user
has unwillingly contributed audio used
to train
an asr model especially when the
transcription is the only output
the story begins that voice servers are
emerged increasingly especially in iot
devices
like google assistant amazon alexa and
etc
however with lots of news reporting the
unauthorized use
of users audio recordings
people start to worry about it from
privacy
and security concerns like what bbc
reported that
hmrc forced to delete 5 million voice
files
and gta pr and law have
have been enforced to regulate personal
data
processing till here we concern
is there any tools to check the regular
data preprocessing
especially the information hidden from
the model itself
for instance when a user intends to
cancel the account of a voice service
expect erasing the records stored in the
database
is the model behind to still remember
this user or not
is it in line with the right to be
forgotten
regulation in gdpr law
firstly we unfold asr assistance
behind the voice servers
there are two state-of-art pipelines
used to build the asr system
including the typical hybrid is
assistance
and hnas assistance a hybrid asr
system is composed of a pre-processing
step
an acoustic model training step and a
decoding step with the help of a
language model
to output the transcription of an input
audio
it is the acoustic model that learns
the audio information from its training
data set
an ancient nissl system mainly refers to
an attention-based encoder decoder
models
unlike the hyper-asr system the model
predicts
sub-sub-word sequences which are
converted
directly as word sequences
as we understand our target model now we
explore
some possible solutions membership in
first attack
in short mia was firstly introduced by
chancry ato
it can infer whether a record was once
used to
train a target model at or not under the
black box success
the reason is that there's always an
overfitting issue within
an ml model the model will behave
better in predicting a record in no
before
than a record in never seen the mia aims
to learn this kind of
different behaviors to distinguish the
record level membership
specifically shockery at all use shadow
models to learn the
target model's prediction behavior with
a few assumptions like
knowing the training sense distribution
the target model structure
and the output contains the label and
its confidential scores then
leonato and hey settle utilize
generative
adversarial networks to generate
more accurate shuttle models while
selling metal
relax the first two assumptions
further soon and shematical
performance user level mia against the
tax
generative models instead of knowing the
confidential score they rely on
several top ranked predictions to infer
their membership
however in our case we need an
auditor to help users to determine their
user level membership of
an asr model while only
one final transcription without
confidential score
is the output additionally because the
characteristic
of the voice we can't expect users
to replay all of their past recordings
when they want to audit
an asm system therefore
we defined our user level membership as
these
acquiring with a user's data if this
user has any data
within target models training set
even if the query data are not members
of the training set
this user is the user level member of
this training set
so far you can sense that how
challenging is this task
on asr systems in the real world
since asr systems in real world provide
only
one transcription without any confidence
score
the link of the information is our first
challenge
secondly the user level inference
requires
a higher level of robustness than the
record level inference
especially for audio recordings
the third challenge brings from the asr
model
itself its complexity in the
learning architectures results in
computationally resourced
and time consuming
before we move on to the math knowledge
we clearly defined the problems
wanted to be solved here behind the iot
voice service
is an asr model like this trained by a
set of audio recordings
where a user query this model with
an audio under the black box success in
real world
the only output is the final predicted
transcription
our audio auditor aims to help users to
determine
whether an iot voice service still
obtains their audio recordings
as training set or not instead of disc
uh discussing a specific model's trans
uh membership
our auditor aims to distinguish this
user's
membership that means a user can still
find out
if he has audio recordings in
that training set even acquiring with
the audio that the model never seen
before
because users can be expected to replay
all of their past recordings in the real
world
with black box success for our
audio auditor the user level membership
inference
is more meaningful and practical than
the record level
membership inference here is our
methodology
there are two processes the training
process
is to build our audio auditor while the
auditing process is to use this auditor
and gain our user level membership
result during the training process
shuttle model are chained with different
data sets to mimic the
target model's behavior then we
collected
those shadow models different behaviors
on their
own training and testing samples in user
level
our auditor learn this kind of behavior
and hope
the target model shared a similar
behavior on that
which help us determine its training
sets user level membership
specifically with the feature extraction
and some statistical analysis in user
level
our auditor's training set is prepared
herein the record processed from the
acquiring results of the
shuttle model's training set is labeled
as
member otherwise the processed record
is labeled as num member
according to previous study when shadow
models architecture are the same
there are no big difference in the
performances between using one shuttle
model
and using multiple shuttle models
thus we only train one shadow model
for each model architecture to
differentiate the
auditor trained with different settings
of the shadow model
we use the combined auditor inferring
the settings
of using multiple shutter models
as for the auditing process firstly
a user requires the target model with
their audio
with the same feature process
pre-processed
the record will be feeding to the
auditor
while the output is either member or
non-member
to achieve user levels determination
the feature extraction in the training
process
is the most important part we firstly
extract two kinds of features
the audio specific feature like speed
and frame lengths and modes
behavior specific features like
similarity score
missing characters and extra characters
here in glove model is used to measure
the similarity score
between the transcriptions and the true
text
here is an example about the missing
characters in brown and
the extra characters in green with some
feature
process in user level like statistical
analysis
we discussed the effect of different
features
here we find that the missing characters
and extra characters can enhance the
ability of our auditor
while the performance is not improved
when considering the
additional mfcc information
therefore we use the feature set
5 in feature extraction to build
our auditor to be noticed since our
auditor is the first
work investigating the user level
membership
in asr system the comparable baselines
is considered as 50 percent
in accuracy briefly
we evaluate our audio auditor from four
perspectives
including effectiveness efficiency
data transferability and robustness
to test the auditor's effectiveness we
evaluate
whether users are feasible to use this
auditor
with acceptable performance especially
in real world
for efficiency we evaluate under what
condition
the audition can perform the best for
data transferability
we evaluate effect on the auditor's
performance when it was trained
with different data distributions and
for robustness
we evaluate the effect on the auditor's
performance when it was trained
with different architectures or in the
noisy environment
part of the results are shown in today's
presentation
this huge figure showed that our auditor
still effectively discriminates the user
level membership
with only a limited number of audios
used
per user figure 3
on a smaller number of users in the
auditor's training set
we observe a rapid increase in
performance
with an increasing number of users
assume
a user is one user level member of an
asr model from figure 4 we know that
the auditor can perform a much higher
accuracy
using the recordings that the asr model
seen before
than using that on-scene recordings
specifically it has a peak accuracy of
around 94 percent in conclude
it's better for users to choose the
audios once heard by the model
the auditor audits target asr models
trend with different data distributions
we observe that
for accuracy and recall the target model
with the same distribution
as the auditor performs the best in
general
the data transferability is well
observed
with reasonably high matrix for all data
distributions
in this table the target model is lstm
based asr model
however the auditor with the lstm based
asr shadow model is not the best instead
the auditor with giu-based asr shallow
model
shows the best result in fact we can
observe
from the table although they have
different architectures
the overfitting level are the most
similar one we can conclude that the
best is the shadow model
shares a similar overfitting level as
the tracking model
and when the offering level is unknown
the combined auditor can achieve
accuracy higher
than the average with small set
to test our model in the real world we
keep our auditory model locally
and conduct a proof of concept child to
audit
iphone series speech text service
according to series statements i can be
considered as a member
user of my iphone series asr model
since i choose opt-in option to improve
theory and dictation as stated by iphone
series
privacy policy users data can be
retained
for up to two years thus another 52
non-member users were selected randomly
from liberal speech datasets whose
samples were collected
before 2014. to get the average
performance of our auditor in the real
world
we store 100 auditors under the same
setting with the training set conducted
a hundred times
the average overall accuracy is around
ninety percent while orc
a usc score is around 73 percent
further we'd like to discuss the threats
to our auditor's finality
first of all is voice prince and
normalization
the speaker's voice can be disguised by
using robust
voice conversation while ensuring the
correctness of
speech content recognition it might
affect our auditor's performance
second is differentially private
recognition systems differential privacy
is one of the most
popular methods to prevent a male model
from leaking
any training data information in asr
it might influence the transcriptions
confidential score
considering our auditor is not relying
on this information
its performance remains unknown third
one is uh workarounds and
countermeasures like
dropout generally change the
target model's output probability
however the change to probabilities of
the asl model's output are not as
sensitive as
change to its translated task
to conclude we propose the use of user
level membership inference for auditing
our auditor is effective has promising
data transferability
and is robust to various architectures
and pipelines thanks for your time
the related codes and turkeys are
published in this github
feel free to explore it and any
questions
are welcome to discuss