hi today i will present our work on
cname-based tracking
and our paper called the c name of the
game large-scale analysis of dns based
tracking invasion
our work was in collaboration with
ganesh from kosic
lukash an independent researcher and
router and tom
from distrinet
traditional third-party tracking works
in the following way
when a user visits a website that uses a
certain tracker
in this case tracker.com the browser
sends a request to both the website and
the server of the tracker
the tracker then responds with a cookie
containing a unique
identifier for the user this cookie is
stored in the browser
under the domain of the tracker
when the user visits a different website
embedding the same tracker
the identifying cookie will be sent
along with a request to the tracker
this way the tracker knows that it was
the same user that visited both websites
and is able to build a behavior or
profile of the user
so this raises privacy concerns for
users on the web
for this reason there are a number of
tools
that users can employ to protect their
privacy on the web
on the one hand users can install
extensions
browser extensions such as adblock plus
privacy badger and ghost3
which block requests to third-party
trackers trackers all together
on the other hand some browsers have
built-in tracking protection
for instance safari has its own
mechanism
called intelligent tracking prevention
which basically deletes cookies on
websites that haven't
been accessed in a while preventing
cross-site tracking
firefox has tracking protection enabled
by default
and while chrome does not provide
tracking protection by default yet
it is planning on phasing out third
party cookies all together in the future
so on the one hand we have publishers
who use the services of advertisers and
trackers
to monetize the content versus the users
who try to protect themselves from
online tracking by using tracker
blocking tools
as a reaction to the use of those tools
trackers
try to come up with new ways to
circumvent them
our paper studies one of the most novel
techniques
used by trackers called cname based
tracking
which works in the following way
instead of issuing a request to the
third party tracker
the website visited by the user issues a
request to a subdomain of the website
the subdomain is used by the tracker in
this case track.example.com
the tracker responds with an analytics
script and sets a first
party cookie it looks as if the request
is simply fetching a resource from its
subdomain
however on the dns level the first party
subdomain of the website
is linked to a third party domain
belonging to the actual tracker
the request disguises itself as being a
first
party subdomain of the website therefore
circumventing blockless based tracking
protections
it is important to note that as the
tracker is included in a first party
context to the visited website
the tracker will not be able to track
the user across different websites
cna based tracking is a type of first
party tracking
however this limitation can be bypassed
by using cookie syncing as we will see
further in the presentation
so how do we detect cname based tracking
first of all we need cname records and
not just
any kind of scene records but cname
records
from a first party to a third party
domain
in our example we would look for a cname
record from track.example.com
towards x dot x.tracker.com
for our analysis we use the public data
set of http archive which contains
millions of frequently visited websites
from the chrome user experience report
and using this data set we looked for
first party
requests to a subdomain of the same site
again from our example we look for
requests from example.com to
tracker.example.com
and by combining these two steps we are
able to set up a list
of c name tracker candidates
however not all
services that use cname records
are per se trackers for instance
cdns also use cna records to connect
with their customers
so in third step we perform a manual
analysis
on each of the tracking candidates we
analyzed
their website and we looked for
references to tracking
or analytics or features mentioned on
their website that require tracking or
analytics
so we obtained 13 manually verified
trackers
and for each of these trackers we
constructed a tracker specific
fingerprint which allows us to
distinguish
actual tracking requests to the scene
trackers
from other traffic in the last part of
our analysis
we ran an additional crawl with a
different user agent namely safari
and we found one tracker that was only
tracking
safari users they also branded
themselves
as specifically circumventing safari's
intelligent tracking prevention
this table shows our results for the 13
different trackers we as we detected
the number of publisher websites using
them
and we also estimated the actual number
of websites using them and this number
is a
a lot higher we achieved this by using
reverse dns
we also noted the price that the service
the price of the service if it was
available
on their website and finally we had a
look at
whether the view block origin tool on
firefox and on chrome was able to block
requests to those cname trackers and
whether the tracker was included in the
next cnsc name block list
this is a list which we also used to
extend our list of synonym trackers
considering our study
interesting results are that a number of
synonym-based trackers
are blocked by the u-block origin
extension on firefox but not on chrome
this is due to the fact that firefox has
implemented a dns level defense
against cnn based tracking which is
technically not possible
because of the limitations of the dns
api in chrome
further i'll we detected
a number of of cname based trackers
which were previously not unknown to
tracker
tracker blocking lists
we examined the popularity of publisher
websites to use cname name-based
tracking
according to the tranquil rank or their
popularity rank of their website
and we find that the z-name-based
tracking websites
are heavily biased towards very popular
websites almost
10 of the websites that use cnn based
tracking in our data set
were in the top 10 000
most popular websites according to the
tranco rank
we also had a look at the categories of
publisher websites that you see
name-based tracking
as a baseline we compare with the
distribution of categories of the tranco
top ten thousand most popular websites
during the same time at the same time
of analysis and we see clearly that
40 of the websites belong to the
category of business websites
to sum up we found more than 10
000 publisher websites using cnn based
tracking most of which are businesses
10 of them are are very popular websites
and we found 13 synonym-based trackers
in varying sizes
and some of them were previously unknown
to tracker blocking tools
i will now talk about the historical
evolution of cname based tracking
in order to do this we again used the
public data set of http archive
and we use the recursive approach where
starting from the most
recent month of our analysis we
determine the
amount of cname based tracking in the
previous month based on the cna based
tracking in the current month
so we obtained an analysis of 17 months
and here we show the results
we can see that throughout the whole
period
seen name based tracking and its use
has been increasing steadily
same site cnn based tracking refers
to the use of a cname record that
is same side to the visited website and
cross side refers to the use of a domain
that is different from the visited
website however in most cases these
domains were related and belonging to
the same company
we compared synonym-based tracking to
third-party tracking
and we see that while the use of
cname-based tracking
keeps on increasing
the use of popular trackers
is steady and while
the smaller the use of smaller trackers
keeps decreasing throughout our
measurement period in order to assess
the effects
on third-party tracking of cname based
tracking
we had a look at the specific evolution
of third-party tracking
so we considered websites that had
become recently
customers of cname-based tracking more
specifically we look at websites
that were not actively using cname-based
tracking for six months
then we then started using it and used
it for at least six more consecutive
months
and we found that on these websites the
number of third parties was unchanged
which suggests that cname-based tracking
and third-party tracking are used by
websites on a complementary basis in
order to achieve
additional information about the users
finally i will discuss the implications
of cname-based tracking
we found some serious privacy and
security issues arising from the way
that the cname scheme is set up first of
all
we found cookies leaking to the cnn base
tracker
those are cookies that were scoped to
the domain of the website
and we had a look at more almost 9 000
websites using cnn base tracking and we
found
that cookies were leaking on on 95
of the websites in the table below we
can see the most common origin of the
cookie that was linking to the cnn base
tracker
for instance google analytics sets a
first party tracking cookie
on the dominant website and in
a large amount of cases this google
analytics cookie was leaking to the cnn
base tracker
so these leaks are not all intentional
but we also had a look at cookies that
were leaking
via request urls which could indicate
the practice of cookie syncing which is
also meant to bypass tracking
protections
we found that the number of the cookies
were set
by the third party domain of the tracker
which clearly indicates
the practice of cookie sinking
we also had a look at whether any
sensitive information was leaking to the
cna based tracker
for this we performed a manual analysis
on 50 websites
and on 17 after the 50 websites
we found some sensitive information
leaking
the full name a location an email
address
and in 10 cases an authentication cookie
was leaking to the cnn base tracker
and last one also has some serious
security
implications finally
we also found a couple of issues
security issues arising from the way
that the cname
based tracking scheme is set up
because of the tracker being included in
a first party context
to the visited website we found
a couple of security vulnerabilities
namely two major vulnerabilities that
were affecting
all of the publisher websites using this
tracker
to sum up our study on cname-based
tracking
our methodology allowed us to detect
cname-based trackers that were
previously
unknown to tracker blocking tools we
performed a large-scale evaluation
of cname-based tracking and we found
that the popularity of senior-based
tracking has increased by
21 in the last two years
and finally we found some serious
privacy and security issues
that arise from the cname based tracking
scheme
namely we found two major web security
flaws present on web pages
and some sensitive information leaking
to the trackers
thank you for your attention
you