hello everyone
i welcome you all to our today's
presentation titled as
too close for comfort morasses of
anti-censorship
in the era obsidians my name is devashes
yosai
and this work was in joint collaboration
with my colleagues
my mahindra and sampato chakravarti at
triple iet delhi india
internet censorship has always been a
point of concern for free speech
activists
this is because it is the control of
what information
can be accessed published or viewed in
the
internet typically by nation states or
governments
as can be seen in this figure almost all
countries
engage in some form of filtering or
surveillance
across the globe thus
various popular circumvention systems
have been proposed
popular ones being thor and vpn however
these proxy based solutions face cat and
mouse game
as soon as the ip address of the proxy
becomes common knowledge
it is simply blocked thus various newer
anti-censorship solutions have been
proposed
that aim to end the censorship arms race
for example required
but these newer solutions assume
that a popular web content is hosted
outside the census purview for their
successful work
if we talk about popular web content for
example
alexa websites series comes into the
picture
in last two decades there has been a
rampant growth
of syrians over the internet and thus
alexa websites are replicated across
multiple geographic location called as
frontends
as can be seen in this figure clients in
the different parts of the globe
rather than communicating with the
parent website ends up in communicating
with the frontends
likely located near them within their
own countries
thus popular web content example alexa
websites
are likely proximas to clients
geolocation
if this is the case then various
anti-censorship approaches that rely
on them with the assumption that the
popular content is hosted
outside the census regime may get
impacted
due to seed in polyphenols the first one
is required routing
in require routing various entities are
involved that is
od over destination set of unblocked
websites that a sensor is not willing to
block
cover destination that is those websites
that a sensor
is willing to block and a friendly isp
that hosts a dr outside the sensors
regime
it is a special router
that is going to be different from the
normal router
in its working it is further assumed
that the client is going to send a
specially crafted web request
that would be intercepted by the router
when it would be going towards the ot
the dr would understand
that though it is destined to od the
intent is to communicate with cd and
thus
dr with the help of dr proxy fetches the
content from cd
and send backs and sends it back to the
client
spoofing the source ip as of the od a
pretense is made to the sensor
that the client is communicating with od
but in practice
it was communicating with cd
if the od is hosted within the sensors
regime
the specially crafted web request would
not cross the sensor's boundary
and would not be intercepted by the dr
and eventually
decoy routing is going to be hampered
the other approaches that could be
hampered are cache browser and cdn
reaper
in these approaches it is assumed that
the blog websites
if hosted on a cdn can be accessed via
frontends located outside the census
boundary
for example if a client is hosted within
the census
boundary is located within the census
boundary
and attempts to access a blocked website
hosted on a cdn
it would likely be mapped to a front end
that is located
near itself within the boundary say with
the ip address ip1
it is obvious and evident that the
sensor can trivially block the ip
address because it is in its own
regime however it is assumed that it is
not trivial for the adversity to
enumerate all the different ip addresses
associated with different frontends
across the globe and would block them
further if the client in the census
regime
would communicate with its peer outside
and obtain this iep address out of band
say by an email the client
in the census regime can directly
communicate with the iep address
and can obtain the content
but if the website is hosted
on the anycasted cdn the assumption that
different front ends have different iep
addresses would go
and all the front ends are going to have
the same ip address
in such a scenario client would have no
option
to send its traffic outside the census
regime as
was the case with the previous dns based
cdm thus if
a large fraction of the websites are
hosted on any carcillions
client cannot access foreign front
trends and the approaches
cache browser and cdn reaper would also
be impacted
further the other approach that could be
impacted is domain fronting
domain fronting is require routing at
the application layer
it assumes that different domain names
can be sent a different layer of
communication with the cdn front-end
and that front-end is going to
understand that though
the client is sending different domain
name it's in
its intent is to actually fetch the
forbidden dot example
for example in this figure
client would send allow dot example as a
part of dns query or tls client
hello sni field and
to a sensor it would appear that client
is communicating with allow dot example
as these two fields are in plain text
once the secure channel is established
client is going to send
its real intent a forbidden dot example
in an encrypted
packet the domain fronting supported
cdn fronted would understand and would
reply with the
forbidden dot examples contained but
if the ctn front end is located within
the sensor again
the sensor can coerce as agent provider
to abandon its use
it is already alleged that roscommon and
zor the nodal agency in russia for
controlling the information within the
country has
coerced some giant companies that were
supporting domain fronting
and as a consequence of coercion the
domain fronting has been abandoned
further the approaches like covert cast
could also be impacted
in this approach it is assumed that the
content of the blocked website is
transported
via real-time encrypted video streaming
services like youtube
but if the youtube front-ends are
located within the sensor
sensor can coerce the youtube to stop
its
use this has already been acknowledged
by the authors in the paper of cover
text
if there are enough newer
anti-censorship solutions
that actually depends on the popular
websites
we asked this question
whether the websites are hosted within
or outside the census regime
and for that we we assumed alexa
top websites as the popular ones
we resolved the websites and identified
their ip addresses
and eventually predicted whether they
are inside or outside
and to geo locate these websites broadly
there are two approaches
passive ones that rely on database
up but they are known to errors and the
other ones are active methods
that we used and the popular one is
multi-literation
in this the position of the target host
whose geolocation is not known is
estimated
using distance measurements from the
sufficient number of fixed reference
points
for example in this diagram l1 l2 and l3
are landmark nodes or the reference node
is geolocation is already known to us
we are interested in geologic
geolocating the target ib tau
the process is very simple at a very
high level
l1 will try to estimate the one-way
delay
to tau using ping and then it would
multiply
the o w d with a speed of light
constraints a two third
c and would obtain a radius
and would construct a circle on the
world map
where it would assume that the target
would be located anywhere within it
the same process would be followed by
other landmark nodes and the
intersection point of all the circles
should ideally the position
where the target is located but in
practice
we cannot always get the precise owd
and very likely we'll get a higher value
of owd because of congestion in various
network factors
and as a consequence we'll end up in
having a larger
radius and a bigger circle and rather
than having an intersection point
we end up with an intersection region
and the centroid of this region
is assumed to be the target top
however in 2017 previous authors
demonstrated that even cbg can result in
large errors
up to 4000 to 5000 kilometers in extreme
cases
they concluded the closer the landmark
nodes better the accuracy
thus we adapted cbg for our use case
and called it as rcbg
the goal of the rcbg is to identify
whether a given ip address is located
inside or outside the niche
we selected landmark nodes within the
said country
because we assume that the target
ip addresses of alexa websites are going
to be likely within the nation because
of syrian proliferation
and those landmarks could be closer to
them if this is not the case and they
are located outside we handle that case
as well
that i am going to discuss in the
subsequent slides
notably rather than predicting the exact
lag long coordinates of the ip address
we used multiliteration just to predict
whether the if is located
in or out of the set country
we relied on four heuristics
the first two predicts the target to be
inside and the latter two predicts the
target to be outside
for example in this figure different
landmark nodes are represented at
circles
and the target ip is represented as
cross the circles are going to intersect
and the intersection region is going to
be formed within the country
the target type is located with however
if the intersection region is somewhat
within and somewhat outside
but major part of the intersection is
within
and the centroid also lies within it is
obvious that we are going to predict
that the target is located
within the country because it has a
higher likelihood
as most of the region is within the
country
but if the target iep is located outside
the country
so somewhere here we'll end up with
having larger values of
radius and bigger circles and as a
consequence that the
intersection region is going to be
formed is going to subsume the entire
country
and thus we predict the target ib to be
out
but again if the intersection region is
somewhere
within and somewhere outside but most of
the region is outside and the centroid
is also outside
we predict the target ib to be out just
to summarize
for the first two conditions rcbg
predicts target as insight
and for the latter two conditions it
predicts the target to be
outside we used
ripe atlas probes as the landmark nodes
using them we predicted the top five
thousand country
specific websites to be in or out and we
did this for five different countries
india around saudi arabia brazil and usa
as we believe they represent diverse set
of
in in terms of internet penetration and
censorship levels
before directly applying rcbg to
estimate the positions of
country-specific
alexa websites we calculated its
accuracy
as can be seen uh in this table
most of the nodes that were located
inside
were predicted as in and the ones that
were
located outside were predicted as out
and this was applicable for all the
different countries
we selected rye probes with known
location as targets as a ground truth
and other ripe lobes as are landmark
nodes
and we obtained this set of accuracy
after obtaining the the decent accuracy
we used rcpg and predicted the locality
of elixir top 5000 websites
and we observed a large fraction
of the alexa top websites to be located
inside the country and thus
we likely conclude
that these
traffic localization because of syrian
proliferation
can inadvertently impact various
anti-censorship
approaches we even went a step ahead
and we further classified whether these
websites
are located on cdn or is on non-syrian
infrastructure that is simply a single
hosted server
and if it is a cdn it is dns based or it
is any cost based
as can be seen most of the websites that
are located inside
are either anycasted or non ctm and the
ones
that are hosted outside are
and are also dns based are very less
less than
uh seven percent and thus
we say that cache browser and cdn reaper
might not be used
as they assume that the website should
be hosted on
dns based areas and likely outside
how we identify the type of cdns and we
classified the websites
we urge the listeners to
read our paper and find this in detail
there
eventually we also took a closer look at
the notion of nation state hegemony
that is previous authors reported a
large fraction of
internet paths to alexa top 1000
websites
originating from underserved countries
either transit
or end in powerful countries like u.s
however our results paint a different
picture
most of the alexa top of 1000 websites
are hosted within the countries and even
the trace road paths
to them also remain localized within the
countries
we believe that we obtain a different
picture
because previous authors used
max mind for ipgeo location that is
known for its inconsistencies
whereas we used multi-literation
and attempted to reduce the geolocation
errors to our best
thus we recommend that the clients must
be made
aware of those popular websites
that are hosted outside for
circumvention
and importantly this set should be
monitored
periodically as popular websites are
being migrated to cdns
day by day and we believe in future
will have a even lesser set of
alexa popular websites that are going to
be hosted within the census regime
finally i would like to conclude by
saying
a large fraction of popular websites are
hosted
within the country and thus cannot be
directly used for the fire routing
and importantly other schemes like
domain fronting and
covert card covert cast could also be
hampered
as sensors can simply coerce the seeding
providers
to abandon its use eventually we end up
with a new dilemma
traditional solutions are relatively
easy to block
based on the ip addresses whereas newer
solutions
might not work due to the proliferation
of
cdns with this i would like to end my
presentation
and thank you