[Music]
Tom Arnold 2017
you
okay so we're going to talk about
but emerging within binaries and the
button that we're going to design our
graphs so we will see how we can write
pattern that graph and match them within
binaries just a quick words about
ourselves so I am voluntary I'm Malou
analyst at Airbus and I'm Jenna thank
you
I'm also a malware on a list but that
storm shield so through our presentation
we will talk about malware sample which
is a backspace actually that's more like
a malware family it was first seen in
2015 and it's the what so what we found
in what is what we find in the back
space is a small decryption function
that will decrypt encrypted
configuration variables such as C and
C's for our registry entries so what we
see is that the decryption function is
quite simple so it's more routine here
we can see it on the left so you have
simply a loop with a call which has an
argument 11 then followed with a serve
that has as argument 25 in the backspace
family we find many variants of this
decryption sample so with this kind of
family what we want to do is first to do
detection so they detect the malware
then to classify the variants based on
the decryption algorithm that is used
and then to be able to decrypt the
configuration variables since we know
which algorithm is being used one thing
you can use to do that is to use the app
RI it works on bytes so it will write a
regular expressions and byte and so it
will look like the following expression
you will save in order to detect the jaw
with the then the served you will say ok
I need the byte 80 then I need any bite
you can take anybody any debate 11 which
is the argument here of the drawer 11
then I need the bad is about 80 then any
bytes then the by 25 which is the
argument of sub but this way of writing
a
a matching a signature is not really
easy to read so what we wanted to do
with grab was to add signatures that are
based on the instructions that are
within the binary and how they are
linked to each other so the kind of
signature that we want to do is to say
for this sample we want to say okay if
now find me absorb that has as argument
211 and it is directly followed with a
sub that has had argument 225 I'll
present a quick overview of the web
project so since we're working on graphs
we used the dart language to represent
graphs that is a simple text file that
we will see a lot of examples later but
it's quite simple to write the graphs in
this language and grab these at the same
time it's under own tool that you can
use on the command line then it has
Python bindings to leverage the
algorithms from grab from Python and we
also developed an Ida plugin so
everything is open source and available
online so grab as two main components
the first one is a dessert sampler that
will take binaries and give you a dot
file that is a graph representing the
binary so it's it's coded with Python
and it's based on capstone and the other
part of graph is a graph matching your
libraries that can pass dot files and
then can do the graphs matching this
part is more coded in C and C++
so a typical workflow for our analysis
with grab will be to write pattern so
that's what we have here pattern dot dot
so you will write a pattern for
backspace then you want to analyze
activate that agree so you give it to
the desertion row that will give you a
button
backspace that dot which is a desert
animal part as a graph and then we will
give the pattern and these are symbols
graph to the graph matching library that
will give you matches and extracts the
instructions that you were interested in
so
backspace is a binary okay so it's a
sequence of bytes those bytes can be
interpreted in assembly language so
a sequence of instructions so we can see
the legs on the subroutine for the
encrypt the decryption then we can
create a graph theory so the flow of the
execution of the instruction and in the
standalone rule we use recursive
function to create this graph and we are
best for the disassembler in on capstone
but for the Ida plug-in we use the idle
engine for the graph so we can create
the graph at the right we have
comfortable sorry my French web we have
the graph of backspace ok at the right
and we want to match the pattern at the
left which is the decryption routine to
do so we use the usual we can use the
usual algorithm so at the left we have
the pattern and at the right we have the
test graph and the goal is just to
search the first call so okay we found
the first call then we got to look to
the children there is an ad so we got to
look to the right we have the absorb so
we got to try the other child so we have
the push so we got a search for another
call so okay we match a coal the same
things we have a head so we could we go
to look to the push at the right the
right children and no so we tried the
other one yeah we match the ad so again
there is a cone yeah there is a compound
okay so next and so on so we found a
push okay and so on okay it's pretty
simple but you need to check every child
of the node and it's pretty flow on big
graphs so since the usual solution is
pretty slow and grab and de Grasse we
want it to have a fast resolution so we
want it to a different algorithm
so one thing we can say about control
progress is that they are not any graphs
so the first property they have is that
usually when you're when you will do
decimal them you'll see that a node in
the control flow graph are that most 2
children it happens when you have for
instance quick sorry a conditional jump
you have a 1 check that will be reached
when the condition is fulfilled and one
child that will be reached when the
condition is not fulfilled so that's the
first property we have in control for
graph another property that the children
are not symmetrical usually you will
find that one of the child is directly
the following instruction at the next
address and the other child is a remote
instruction somewhere else in the
program so we cannot invert them so we
will force that in your graph you cannot
invert the order of children so what you
need to see now is that once we say that
children are order in the graphs the
object we are manipulating and not
really graphs anymore and that will help
us have a very fast matching the other
thing we can say about patterns so I
talked about control flow graphs in
general but patterns are specific as
which so earlier it's easier to match
them from their first node so we will
fault that every pattern has the first
node so the first node it's a root node
that that from this node every other
node of the graph can be reached so on
the example on the right that is our
button for backspace you have the first
node on the top which is a root node
because from from its you can reach
every other node okay so with this
restriction we will have phase matching
I'll explain why
so this slide will show you how we can
represent a pattern or on a different
form so the pattern we have now are what
we see on the left so we have a curl and
added compare the new push on the push
and the children are order we have child
number one and child number two and
child number one here so there is with
this kind of thing since we have a root
node which is so cool there is a unique
way to number this graph with a
depth-first search so that is the
following I take the root node so
difficult I
this one one then they take the first
child of the call I get here to the ad
I'm number it to then I take the first
child and number is three then I go back
to the call I will do to the child
number two number H four and go to the
chine number one number is five so I can
describe it in a text way as this so
it's equivalent to the pattern and that
means okay I'm looking for a button for
a graph which has as a first Noda cool
then it has a first child if you take it
you get to an ad then I take again the
first child if you take it to get to a
compare then you go back to the first to
the node number 1 which was the call so
you go back here and say okay now you
take a little child number 2 and you get
to a push then take the 5 mm the child
number 1 and get to another push so this
representation as a text where this text
representation is equivalent to the
pattern representation as a graph so
once you have this we were the question
we need to ask is can we perform the
traversal of the pattern within the test
graph so we saw that the pattern on the
left is equivalent to the text
representation I add some color because
it's nicer with karora yes it is okay so
now it's easier I need to find the first
thing I need to do is to find root note
that would be a call so I have a
candidate and the right here which is
this one then I get to the you know I
get to the add part so I need to see
here if is there a node a child number
one that we didn't add so I take the
child number one here I get to observe
so it doesn't match I have to go back so
I have to find another root node that
could be a cool so there is one here now
I ask is there a child number one that
is another yes I will number this one
too so I get there is there a child
number one that is a compare yes it
works then okay take me back to the
child number two the node number one so
back to the call so I get there I ask is
there a child number two that is a push
it works I say is there a child number
one that is a push it also works so this
gives us a matching for the pattern from
the pattern to the test web so that is
the algorithm that we will
so the difference with the previous
algorithm is that now that children are
ordered use we saw that we know that
we're looking for child number 1 or
child number 2 so you don't have the
exponential factor anymore you will only
have the premium last time for matching
so it's much faster okay so I will stop
with algorithms now I will go back to
the pattern so I talked about how we can
match them but now we'll say what our
patterns how do they look like so on the
left you have a pattern for backspace
which was a decryption with him and so
we said that pattern they are dot files
with specific fields because we will use
like conditions we use conditions and up
close on our on arguments of
instructions on the addresses
instruction so on so on the right here
you have a an example of a pattern for a
for backspace that matches exactly the
two instructions door and sub so what it
says here so it's a dot file it says
likewise that's a dot keyword then we
have the name of the pattern so it
decrypts with the Google and the sub
then it has we say it has node it has
two nodes the first node is a with the
condition and the node is okay I want to
match an instruction that has Sora as
its sub code and has as argument number
211 I have another node that is B and
the condition is I want to match an
opcode that is 7 and that has as
argument number 225 and then the part
here specifies the edges so there is a
net from node a to not be so it means I
have a child from the base that is not
be okay a few more things about node
options and Egyptians in our pattern
language so I said that the pattern
graphs are supposed to have a root node
that is a node from which you can reach
every other node so in order to specify
this node you have to you can say
adsorption root is true that means this
node is a root you have the count field
that says specifies the condition so we
so we can have a condition and of course
for instance we have the gate idea fly
you get a diamond - it will tell go up
okay when you find the match for this
note I'm interested in this in this
match so I want you to print it or I
want you to keep it aside so I can
access it later okay so that's four node
options for trade options for edge of
edges option sorry we thought that child
are numbered either one or two so we
have an option to specify on an edge if
it's a child number one or child number
two so the example below is the same
pattern as previously but with every
option explicit in so we have still the
condition we have okay this node is the
route so that the first node of the
pattern we were interested in this node
and I want you to March the node with a
so that the name of the node for the not
be I'm interested also in the nodes who
you have to market be and the child
number of the edge was one because they
are following each other that's
sequential instructions okay so back on
conditions conditions and we will be
able to make conditions on instructions
and there will be conditions on the full
string of the instructions like move yay
a a X something for instance we will
have a condition and the address
condition on the opcode on the argument
of the number of arguments and the text
of the arguments so these are string
field we will also have conditions and
the number of incoming and the number of
a growing edges sorry
so that means the number of others and
the number of children of a node
I have an example here that says I'm
looking for a function that is
frequently called so that there is a
call to this node so the call is the not
a and the instruction decode is B and
then there is a nature between a and B
so the number of the at the edge is 2
because it's a it's not a following
instruction it is a remote instruction
and the condition we have an not be that
it has multiple incoming nodes that will
help us find functions that are
frequently called in the code okay so
until now I explained how we can match
one node to one instruction but what we
will want to do next is to match one
node to multiple instructions like when
you want to match basic blocks sometimes
you don't care how many instructions are
written the basic block you want to
metric say okay this node needs much a
whole basic block so we can specify a
minimum number of matches for all node
on the maximum number of matches
internally works on sequential
instructions using basic blocks so these
are instructions that have one father on
one child so it looks like that you have
a basic block that we see here in Ida so
there is the art wind coming node 2
outgoing node and only three
instructions here to match this kind of
things in grabs you just have to say
okay I want you to match any
instructions that what it means come is
true and then you I need you to match
one or more instructions or repeat this
plus if I want to match three push
instruction I will write something like
that like the I want instruction with
the opcode push and I want them to be
repeated three times so by default the
graph will take the most matching
instructions when you specify a
repetition which you have an option to
change that you can say lazy
is true so the first point was greedy
repeat like you take the most of them
with lady repeat we will stop when the
next mission is to see is fulfilled I'll
give an example here so back to back
page sample we had a decryption loop so
we're interested especially in the door
and the sub instructions but we can say
okay I want a look that looks a bit like
that so I will want to match one two
five any instructions we have three here
but maybe there is less maybe there is
more then we have the growth and we have
the sub then we have again and one two
five instructions then we have a
conditional jump that loops back to the
beginning of the loop so the pattern
will look like that we I will have here
that's a dot representation on graphs
one two five an instruction then the
exhaust the sub 1 to 5 any instruction
then the conditional jump will go up it
will where's the pattern will look like
that we say ok I'm looking for any
instruction with it that max 5 times and
I want you to stop once the next
condition is fulfilled so it will match
for this node age will match move add
move then here it will stop because the
next condition and B should fill because
we have a go on then B will match the C
will match sub D will match again mini
instruction so we compare move and it
will stop on the last one because the
last one it says that it was instruction
to begin with J and you have two
children so that the case with the
conditional jump here okay so back to
our backstage samples so I'm going to do
a demo we have a 100 backspace sample i
want to disassemble them and then i want
to detect the decryption algorithm that
I saw that is the one we reverse NIDA
then I want to find variants of this
decryption algorithm and finally I will
need to detect all these decryption
algorithms so demo time okay so I have
my samples here so 100 samples of
backspace and I have a pattern so that's
the one between the side so we have a
lazy repeat we have
we found eggs or here then the sub I
want to match it against the the sample
we know so I I asked wrapped to match it
against sample this one so that the one
we worked on so first it will
disassemble the the binary then it
learns the pattern so there is one
pattern that was round the test graph
which is the sample has a thousand node
and it found one matching yeah so the
matching is described here so we have
the restriction that match with see the
glow and the step that we were looking
for okay
so that was for one sample I want to do
it in a way some print of backspace to
see what happens okay so it will take a
white because it should need to this as
decimal 99 samples it takes around 20
seconds so much we will see the lot of
matching and a lot of text and then I
will show you another option to have
less less less verbose output and more
quite one with one one one sample per
line so that's what I say we have lot of
text so now I asked it to do it quietly
so it will be much quicker because we
don't have to listen to the files again
and show you that if I show the folders
now we have the dot files which are the
decimal diversions of the binaries okay
so now I just launch it again but with
the quiet section so here I see all the
pattern that all the memories that
matched or pattern but I don't see the
one that didn't match so we find a lot
of samples that choose the same
decryption algorithm exactly the same
let me be you there are more so I will I
will ascribe to show me all the binary
so okay we see that some samples match
and some others didn't match so what I
wanted to do next was to find variance
to find variance I went back to Ida
which is here okay so here we have the
Google algorithm I will see how it is
called so what we see that it's very
simple you have a first date o'clock
then the loop then another basic block
we will see how it is called
so there is a function here that has a
lot of calls to the decryption every
algorithm it's always two pushes because
there's other arguments then a call to
the decryption function so I wanted to
write a pattern to see and to detect
this so what I did let this pattern so I
ask that we find something with two
pushes then the call then again two
pushes another call four times in the
old point to a function that is that has
a first basic block then a look then an
N basic block then a return instruction
and what I say here that I'm only
interested in getting the loop so I say
get ID
I said get ID only on the loop node so
I'll show you how high droops like with
that and I have a code version because
it's always better with Quran okay so we
have here two precious than the core
then to put it another call the all
point to the same function and we
interested in the loop here which is
where the decryption algorithm happened
okay so now I need to match it against
my samples okay so I find here the first
decryption algorithm that we already
know we exhort 11 and 25 and again the
same here we have another one there is a
sub then exorbitant other constant then
another sub then there is again the same
one then while we will find that there
are many more I won't see them show you
them all but what we did next was write
a pattern for this these decryption
violence so we have a very small pattern
so the first one is when we new so 11:25
this one is the one we just saw the with
B and 12 and there were like five other
ones that I won't detail so what we do
now is we want to match them against the
back space centers
so what we see here that a lot more
samples matched and we know which
algorithm was used so here on the
pattern that met with the gossip here it
was observed or sub here there is
another one another one etcetera so one
more thing which wanted to know is that
we had still had some unmatch binary so
oops
so I want to know why they don't match
okay
one C two thing we did that you read in
this order but it works okay which we
asked for a taxonomist X names we see
that it's you P so it's a some some
person seemed to be packed with you pigs
so what I do is I wanted to have a quick
signature for this GPX files so I will
look for basic block loops that mean
basic blocks that loops to themselves so
I have a pattern for that that I will
use now
on this pattern so I find two basic
block loop I didn't really look into
what they are doing but I want to treat
them as signatures so I wrote a jpg
signature which is which contains these
two loops
EPX loop one big slip to so what I did
next was to match them okay so there are
there seems to be more sample data box
which depicts and I always match the two
loops so I know how to detect volumes of
back space in order to detect fights
packed with GPS so I want to detect them
both so I will combine the two the two
signatures and I will merge them okay
it's better so we still have a few
unmatched binaries but most of them we
see that there are either a violent of
backspace and we know which algorithm is
used or they are packed with GPS okay
back to the side so what we saw that is
that we found seven volumes of GPX so
there was a there was the first one with
a draw 11 and step 25,000 otherone but
we saw then five other patterns we also
found out that some my name is are
packed with GPX and we were to a small
quick signature for this file we match
them so what we did is on all 100
backspace samples took around 20 seconds
to the decimal Rams then to do the
matching of nine patterns it took a
little more than two seconds and in the
end we see that there are like 17 files
that are packed with GPX they hunt the
half of the samples that have the first
pattern that we looked at and the other
patterns are used sometimes and in the
end there was this 11 memories that we
did not identify correctly so ok
to simplify the creation of
scripts we create Python bindings of the
C++ library with weight and now with
item we can do the sum we can note
patterns and test graphs you can not
grab a pattern graph in death graph we
can match patterns and pass all the
results so here we have some example of
Python script so at the beginning we
have the input of a library then we have
the we load the pattern that file we
extract the graph from the binaries with
this and file then we load the test
graph and after we match the the graph
the pattern in the test graph so here is
an example of the pattern we want to
match three bushes so we use the match
graph and now we can get all matching
patterns then you can select the bushes
patterns and now we can with the species
patterns we can get all majid
instructions then we can say ok I want
to get the IDP so it give all
instruction with the get IDP and then we
take the first instructions so now we
have the instruction so we can request
some information like the addresses all
the old instruction strings the opcode
the arguments and so on so ok we can
match the description loop and we saw
that we have a lot of pushes and call to
the decryption strings so we want to
match the two pushes and the call to the
decryption routine ok so we have we want
to check match the first bushes which is
the length then the encrypted string
then the code to the entry point of the
function to decrypt both strings so we
have the decryption entry point we can
match the address of the all the
decryption loop so we have the address
of the match
oh damn it ok so to get the entry point
we know that the function is very slow
very tiny so we can say and we know also
that the decryption on three point is
before the decryption loop ok so you can
say we want to search a node between the
decryption address and between the
decryption address minus 30 and we want
to match a node with at least five or
more incoming
so let us demo so this creates is see we
have the import then we get the the
binaries we create the graph then we
have those patterns to match the the
entry point then to match the profiles
before the call of the decryption
function and we implement the all
variants of the decryption algorithm so
here you have step though sub add and so
on so
we have my lord okay so we got to
execute the script with a sample so now
you can decrypt those strings so we have
the sample we match the Decrypter third
okay then we found the address of this
routine here we match the entry point
with the more than five or more than
five incoming between the address of the
decryption -30
then the address of the decryption so we
found the decryption function it's the
entry point so now we got to look for
the the partials
okay with the entry point of the
function and then we match 35 calls to
this decryption function and so after
this we take the string the encrypted
string then we decrypt it with the the
algorithm and now you can see we have
some registers and some text files and
so on so now we can do this on all
samples so here we have first samples
with strings registries then we can find
some eglee on other samples and so on so
there we have all the strings of the
configuration and so on of backspace
[Music]
so okay we have a tool but you can be
nice to have a plug-in clue in either to
match those those buttons so we have an
Ida plug-in we convert the Ida graph to
for grab then we can match patterns with
P grab which is the Python binding and
then we can with the UI bros those
matches and put some color on it and
then we apply some filters technique so
match a single pattern for example for
FC for a set key we have two small loops
for the initialization and if we create
just one pattern for those two loop we
have a lot of false positives so we
create some filter techniques it's quite
simple in abuse so for example the set
key of our a/c phone we have two loops
for the first group is the first pattern
and the second loop is the second
pattern so if we don't have those groups
in the function it's not all function so
you can see at the right we have the two
patterns all okay it's accepted but if
the you we have just one pattern it's
rejected we have also the right
techniques so also quite simple we have
two loops but if we are more than the
mod and two loops in the in the function
so if we match for example three time
the pattern one the function is rejected
too because we just want the first part
at the first loop one time in the second
loop one time two then we have the
threshold so sometimes with the pattern
can have some errors so at the right we
have four patents for one function so we
match all pattern so ok it's good but
the middle the pattern number five four
three are not here so the function is
also for example the function of
decryption but we missed some some
patterns so we created threshold so here
we have a threshold of point seventy
five that means that at least we want
three out of four patterns so in the
middle its accepted too but at the left
we just have two out of four so we
really we reject this function the last
one is the overlapping so in for example
again the FC for set key we have the two
loops we create one pattern for the
first and another for the Siam and if we
match the same with those two pattern
that means we match the same loop and we
don't want this but in the example at
the left we have to match of the two
matches of the first pattern and one of
the second there is an overlapping
between the first and the second so if
we remove the pattern number one for the
overlapping we have valid matches at the
right so we can say okay it's our
function this technique is not yet
implemented in either graph so the
creation of a rule for the plug-in is
quite simple - so for the SC 430 we
create the the first loop so loop one
will give the the pass through the dot
sign to the pattern then we give a name
a decryption a description of this
pattern then we say okay a minimum
pattern is one so that means I want to
match one time this pattern or more then
we fix the next pattern so we say I want
at a next one time this pattern so we
must match just one time the
the first group we do the same things
for the second loop then we create a the
function pattern so we gave the two
loops because we we must match those to
the two loops in the function set key of
FC form then we put the threshold that
here is one so it means we must get the
to the to attempt to regulate the
function then a name a description and
data so they know okay so you load the
plug-in you get so the fingerprint is to
find the patterns so okay we launched
here we can see we have matched some
patterns so we can click on it and then
we have the decryption routine okay but
sometimes we don't know really where out
the matched so we put some color in it
so here beam's
okay and then we have the color on the
two instruction for the decryption loop
and we have some color on the entry
points so here we have okay is the
pushes for the strings and if we are
knowing renamed okay then we launch
again the scan here we have the name of
the function also with the number of
instruction and so on
so okay
SC for the match are not efficient
because the boots are very small in very
generic so we have we still have many
false positives but we have few false
negative which is cool
so the the cooling is appropriate okay
and we can try maybe to create other
signatures for other cryptographic
algorithm placards and so on and maybe
we can put the filtering techniques in
pig wrap because it's only in Ida grab
so the perspective some limitation of
our tools all the arguments instruction
opcode and so on are in our strings so
sometimes we have to do some dirty hack
to get for example here the conditional
jump so we want to match an instruction
strings that begin with J okay and we
want the node to have two children
because in the graph the instruction
with children our codes and conditional
jumps so we are lucky codes begin with C
so okay then we have other problem
because in the standalone tool we use
the capstone engine in in either we use
the Ida engine so sometimes with for
example the variables we have in either
25h for the integrity small value 25 and
in capstone we have oxt 5 so again dirty
hack to catch both cases so aku we catch
25 or the Oh X 25
so the solution is semantics the IDB and
that is to say okay I want to check if
my argument one is a register or I want
to check if the opcode is the
conditional jumps and so on the same
thing for the fog one if we want to
catch an intent integers with the value
25 but maybe in grab me too okay okay
there is another limitation of the how
wide pattern that is that we can we
explain how we can do note repetition
but there is one limitation that that is
the following we can either when with
not repetition we can either say I want
the least number of matched instructions
or I want the maximum number of matched
instruction there is no in-between so
the problem is this one we have a button
that says I want to match one two for
any instruction then I want to match
exhort and I want to match your color
then I say ok this is our forming
instruction so it's one two five
anything then the called a nickel and so
there is a lazy whippet here we can
either put true or false if we put true
it will mean that we want to take the
least number of instructions if you put
false we want to take the maximum number
of instructions so we will see how to
match this pattern under on a binary
graph that would have a push then a push
then ago then another glower then call
so with the follow with the the current
to set if we put lazy repeat to through
the matching for the any node will stop
once it switches eggs or so for n it
will take push push then it will stop
then the gore node will match the absorb
then the call node will try to matrix or
it doesn't work so there is no match so
it doesn't work with lazy whip it at
crew if we put lady repeat that false so
any the any node will try to match the
maximum number of instruction so the
problem is it is greedy
so the any node which match push push
door and go because it matches for
instruction and then we get to the door
that finds a cool so it doesn't matter
it doesn't work either so there is no
way for all two now to match this binary
thing with this pattern but it is
counterintuitive because as with regular
expressions we'd like to say okay I
don't care if any takes one two three or
four instructions I would like to test
them all so of course the solution may
be also for grab v2 would be to try
every number of repetitions so one two
three four of course it will be slower
so we will need to watch watch out for
an impact on performance okay we have a
lot of more IG that we would like to
implement in the patterns one thing that
it's limited also with the current
version is that for basic blocks we only
have instructions on the into the
condition and basic blocks for now will
apply to every node and which we would
like to say is I won't find your basic
blocks that has at least one X or
instruction or find me a basic block
that has at least tubes or instructions
on one compare instruction that we
cannot do for now so maybe we will also
work on that later so we said that
children are numbered so you have to
specify when you do edges if you're
talking about line number one or trend
number two sometimes we will want to say
okay I don't care
so is it maybe the for instance for
conditional jump you could say this
could be the child for when the
condition is fulfilled or for when the
condition is not fulfilled I don't care
so we would like to add an option that
would be child number is a question mark
and so the algorithm should try the both
options then as the nettan explained we
would like Twitter buttons in bag web
which would be labeled for us to say
okay I have five buttons I want to match
if we find three of them that's enough
or we would like to say okay I have two
patterns p1 and p2 find me of a binary
that has one match of p1 that is
directly followed by a matter of p2 that
is there is one instruction of p1 that
has as a child an instruction of p2 that
we would like to do some pattern linking
like that the last point is that for now
we constructed the graphs
manually with writing
a text file it works it's okay when you
have a when you reduce to it it's quite
fast but it would still be zero to be
able to select node in Ida and then
click export and will generate a nice
dot file with all the nodes and all the
edges that you want it will be much
faster to create patterns okay so this
will end or all talk the conclusion is
that graph is at the same time a
thunderdrum tool it has peyton manning's
we have an IDE a plug-in our goal was to
create a tool that can make a graph
buttons that are easy to write and easy
to understand we believe it is useful
for detection and automatic analysis we
show that on backspace and it works the
tool is a fully open source and you can
find it online at this address as
perspectives for the future maybe for
the v2 we would like to add some button
features we talked about processing stem
antics information from instructions we
talked about condition and basic blocks
we would like to be able to create
patterns directly within either and then
we would like to have many more examples
that work on crypto algorithms we were
going to try with AES and on Packers on
incumbent Packers so this will end also
thank you for listening and we will try
to answer questions
[Applause]
thank you for the talk very good talk I
will ring if you had thought about using
since you can have capstone in Adana I
think I haven't tried it but could you
just use capstone everywhere I did not
buy that so ready to use captain NIDA
yeah we thought about it but we have not
decided yet another thing to put into
the design
[Applause]