[Music]
recon Arkell 2017
hello everybody so like you said this is
a this type talk is entitled a
transforming open source to open access
and closed applications specifically
we're going to be talking today about
how when auditing open source components
of applications like Adobe Reader you
can find bugs easier instead of looking
at the binary and transfer those bugs
into the closed source application which
then you can actually leverage to write
exploits we're going to go over several
code matching techniques that exist and
we'll also go through a series of case
studies that will show the underlying
vulnerability in in the open source
components how to pinpoint it in the DLL
that's a shift with reader along with
how Adobe actually patched the
vulnerability itself so first though
quick introductions if you don't know
who I am my name is Brian gorn's
malicious input on Twitter so I'm never
really on Twitter I'm a beast senior
senior manager for vulnerability
research inside of Trend Micro's
tipping-point organization my primary
purpose in my life basically now is to
run the zero day initiative program
which represents the world's largest
vendor agnostic bug bounty program now
what does that mean that means we work
with researchers around the world we
purchase zero day vulnerabilities from
researchers a lot here in the EU and in
this region we produce detection
guidance for the tipping point IPs and
then we ship them to the vendors to get
them fixed we do a lot of vulnerability
purchasing and research inside of
Microsoft and Adobe products and in fact
we're actually one of the top suppliers
for both of those vendors for
vulnerabilities for multiple years now
I'm also responsible for organizing and
adjudicating the ever-popular pound two
own hacking competition which is
actually happening --hi in March at
Cannes a quest so if you have some zero
days and some exploits that you would
like to sell in a public forum
definitely come on out and check it out
I'll let my colleagues here introduce
themselves so my name is Abdul I'm a
security researcher working for the
zierden estate program which is part of
Trend Micro now I've been working for
the CBI for the past four years
I do a lot of viability research which
cause analysis and stuff like that based
off Montreal Canada
alright I'm Jaisal Spellman go by
wondering which I've been with CDI since
2012 but I've been with tipping point
for 11 and a half years now I focus a
lot on static analysis and reverse
engineering and just really root cause
analysis in general all right so lucky
for me I and when when we were going
through this presentation I drew the
straw to talk about the attack surface
that we're going to be going over which
means I get the lucky honour of
presenting XSLT to this audience which
is very exciting for me because you
likely already know all about XSLT but
there is a point to this section so that
you can actually start so we can put you
in the right place in the sabola Tron
code to find vulnerabilities so first as
we all know it's very very very common
now for applications to integrate open
source projects into their closed source
applications it's a way for the vendors
to quickly add features to the product
without having to go through all of that
really costly engineering effort but one
of the one of the real problems that
we're starting to see inside of the zero
day initiative program is the vendors
don't actually understand the security
side effects that exists by integrating
these products there's a lot of
misunderstood assumptions about how the
code works and as a result this can
interject security weaknesses into the
applications that they're shipping to
their end users there's also a lot of
poorly implemented components out there
or code that's no longer being
maintained and as a result now the
vendor has to take on that burden of
keeping that open source project active
and implementing security features into
that project long after the project has
died there's also some sometimes missing
security mitigations vetting that that
don't get rolled in you know some of the
new mitigations that are being released
in say edge and things like that
you know the those types of ideas aren't
actually implemented in some of this
older code that's being integrated into
the products so what we're going to do
is we're going to look at Adobe Reader
as we all know Adobe Reader is a widely
used document reader it's got a ton of
features for document authors to
generate really complex
documents and in vdi we spent a lot of
time looking at a dhobi reader we've
done several presentations over the last
two years related to vulnerabilities in
this product including things related to
JavaScript API s well for overflows use
after freeze all sorts of stuff that
we've talked about but we're going to
look at specifically today is the code
that Adobe really didn't implement the
stuff that they're actually bringing in
from the open source community and the
vulnerabilities that exist in that so
we're going to highlight some of the
security side effects that we just
talked about in the previous slide but
if we look at Adobe Reader it has
several open source projects that
actually integrates one being a modified
version of Lib Tiff's for test parsing
and also a modified version of Sublett
Ron which is used for extensible
stylesheet language transformation
handling and unfortunately for Adobe
this tablet arm project is now abandoned
there's no more community out there
actually implementing new features
there's no security fixes going on in
that in that project in the open source
space and so it's kind of left up to
Adobe now to actually integrate and fix
all the bugs that are coming in into
their into their Security Act group in
this in this old code now if you don't
believe it's that sab Letran is actually
being used in reader well you can
actually leave the licensing information
and the product they show the fact that
they are integrating that product and it
actually exists in ax SLE DLL and we
pulled the version information from the
code as you can see it on the screen
here it's actually using version 1.0
point to of sab Letran and so just kind
of just proof that it is actually
integrated into that DLL now XSLT has
been around since the late 90s
was part of w3c s extensible stylesheet
language and specifications and it's
used a lot by application developers to
transform data into other formats xml
data into other formats and back when I
was developing code in in my everyday
life I used XSLT a lot and XML a lot to
define this and bring it into a system
and transform it to different formats
like HTML plain text where you can also
transform it into XSL formatting objects
for later use but what's important about
XSLT are the logic elements that exist
that do processing
and these logic elements are used to
describe the transformations that are
going to be applied to the XML that is
transforming so we have things like for
each which will select every XML node
inside of a node set and perform
processing on it there's eczema ssl
attribute which will create an attribute
on it on a node an output node so
there's copy that will copy node and put
it to the output and there's a value of
which will actually select the value of
the XML node and print it out into the
output now to also understand X at the
XSLT format you also need to understand
how XPath works because XPath is used to
query the XML document to select nodes
and perform calculations on the data
that's coming in as it's going to be
transformed you know we have I put a
XSLT or an XPath on the screen here /
music / artists square bracket 1 this is
going to select the first artists
element that is a child of a music
element in an XML document and start and
then allow it to be have processing
performed on it now XPath functions
actually adds flexibility to the XPath
itself you can you can use node set to
actually get a set of nodes related to
XML string to actually do evaluations on
on a different string arguments boolean
and number to do the same thing for
boolean to numbers so there's a lot of
functionality that exists an XPath and a
lot of code that exists in these
projects that can be audited and looked
at for vulnerabilities so XSLT transform
really simple looks like this on the
screen is probably hard to read in the
back but this XML on your left is a the
XML that contains a catalog with
multiple CDs which a bunch of metadata
related to the CD itself and then there
in the middle here there's actually an
XSLT document that's going to transform
that XML into the HTML that you see on
the screen and you can look at that if
you look at the XML it's kind of hard to
see but there is a for each logic
element in here that's going to select
every every CD that is a child of
catalog and then perform processing on
it using the value
of XSLT logic element so as a result you
can start doing processing and
transforming data that is XML formatted
into HTML and produce this really
amazing CD collection HTML page which
everybody loves so if we look at exactly
how you would actually call the
underlying XSLT engine in Adobe Reader
you have many ways in Adobe Reader to
actually do that one is xsa and the more
common way that we're seeing is actually
people using javascript api to trigger
that underlying engine so what we see
here is in the first variable is
actually the XML document that we're
going to transform the next variable is
the XSL document the transform itself
this will trigger the underlying code
that we can use to trigger
vulnerabilities in the XSLT engine what
you have to do is you have to parse the
the XML document variable bring it into
a Dom and then select the root node and
then apply the XSL transform on that
root node and as and underneath the
covers you're going to be exercising the
establish on source code that has been
compiled into a XLE dll now there's this
is just the beginning of how you start
up triggering some vulnerabilities in
this code to understand what type of
bugs and where to look in the code we're
going to show you a couple places where
you can at least start looking for bugs
in this case what you're seeing is the
definition of all the different logic
elements that exist in sabola Tron
that's being used by Adobe Reader and
this enumeration here talks about the
different lot there defines the
different logic elements and you can see
that copy of is in there value of is in
there attribute is in there for each all
of the different XSLT logic elements are
defined here now where is the processing
for all of these different logic
elements located well there's a class in
establish Ron called XSL elements and
inside the execute method there's
actually a giant switch case switch to
case that actually goes through and
performance processing on the different
logic elements
so if you're going to go start looking
for vulnerabilities as it relates to the
processing of XSL logic elements you
want to start looking in the execute
method and we'll actually talk about in
a dual section about some
vulnerabilities that existed in this
code now XPath functions are also
implemented in stab electrons and these
reside in expr dot CPP and again it's
another switch statement that exists in
this code an expression called func
method and we've lifted listed some here
on the slides but there has been
vulnerable ''tis in XPath processing as
well and too you can actually if you're
going to go audit and look for
vulnerabilities in this open source code
you want to look here for XPath style
vulnerabilities and then what you can
transform those into the same
vulnerabilities inside of Adobe Reader
now we've also seen inside of this code
some issues related to heap and list
implementations and so it's another
place for you to start looking if we
look back at the vulnerabilities that
have occurred inside of Adobe readers
XSLT engine we can see back in 2002
Adobe actually fixed two vulnerabilities
in this engine and we'll talk about
those bugs here in a second they've got
an interesting back story that actually
affects the latest patch that Abdullah
talked about these were discussed at
length on the conference circuit but the
community really hasn't paid attention
to this codebase much since those
discussions then in the zero day
initiative program in 2015 we started to
see new submissions from multiple
researchers in this codebase coming into
our program and it got us interested in
how exactly they were going about
finding the vulnerabilities in a w
reader and it all comes back to two
source code analysis of sabola Tron and
fuzzing techniques that they're using to
finding these bugs and so we'll kind of
go over some of those here in a second
now if we're to kind of give you an idea
of where some of the bugs are located we
kind of generally generated this table
here the name column just has the
different source code locations for for
toad inside of Sabbat Ron along with
descriptions of what that code actually
does and then the corresponding CBE's
that were discovered in those in those
source codes of source code locations
and you can see there's a couple here
from 2012 and the rest of them are from
2016 in fact all of these bugs were
actually at the leaf patched in January
of this year but assigned CVEs of 2016
for whatever reason so what we're going
to do now is I'm going to hand it over
to Jaisal where he's going to talk about
how you can pinpoint the vulnerability
in a closed source application using
some techniques after you've audited the
code of sabitch on to find bugs so the
first thing I want to mention is that
we're not doing a straight Bend if
against a built binary in part because
initially wasn't entirely sure how easy
would be to build it but also because
there a number of preprocessor defines
and you can't initially we didn't know
whether or not what all those values
were in addition to that adobe has
implemented a decent number of changes
on top of what's public they did open
source their modifications a few years
ago but they have not done to any time
the recent past and the Sabbath on
source that is available is incredibly
old so start off using something that is
a very very well known technique and
that's just looking for strings so here
we have this struct has a pointer to a
string followed by two two enum values
an x functor and x type but in the
binary that's just going to look like
raw of integers and since this is a
32-bit application that we're looking at
it's only going to be a D word each and
so if we look for last in position we
see a structure and we can kind of glean
that this is the exact same structure we
were just looking at the function
information table on its own this
structure is not all that useful
specifically because it does map from
the a facility function names to their
IDs but then their IDs are not the
easiest to find and if you were to do a
search for say last which is hex 1a
you'll get a bunch of references they're
a bunch of hits and not
really go anywhere thankfully one of the
entries in there is one that's called
system property and that one has value
it has an ID of hex 3b and takes a
string and this one is specifically
useful because if you look at the code
it is responsible for returning version
information of the accessibility engine
itself looking at the code we see that
within this call func function we have a
switch statement which I kind of hid
away but in this particular case for
system property we have a few strings
that are guaranteed to be referenced and
this is just quite fantastic for
whatever reason today we'd never
modified this and this code base is so
old that ginger allcom is now I think a
Polish website for some other completely
different purpose not software related
at all but by looking for these strings
and then looking for where one
particular function in particular uses
them we're able to see exactly where
call func may be and ends up being this
function which is probably impossible to
read perfectly find them but it
references vendor vendor you're a ginger
Alliance and ginger allcom and if we
were to keep going up we would
eventually see that e x FF system
property value being reference I would
have shown that but it ends up being
kind of worthless and that math is
performed on it and it doesn't it
doesn't end up being x3 be like it is in
these structure itself kind of expanding
on that and one that is incredibly
useful I've used it in reader a lot and
in flash is looking for just data
structures so in the previous example we
had a pointer to a string followed by
two integers and those integers were
just enum values but you can expand on
that and look for any array or any
content structure where you have and a
bunch of static data this also works for
if a function has static data and is
going to place it in a data section
because then you can look for those
values and more often than not you're
able to find them sometimes the compiler
will create multiple copies of a table
but you can still find the references
and then to kind of
code matching techniques if on top of
that so in this particular case
EXO canoes and enum and token at sign
token D : token L / N and L bracket
we're all I looked for basically just
converting those into little endian V
words and then looking for the raw hex
string and ended up finding exactly that
strings that's B X B five and seven and
now we know exactly where the neighbor
table is using this was able to then
find where some of the utf-8 functions
that we'll be talking about
we're located kind of in the same vein
you can just do looking for straight hex
values for one of the functions that was
vulnerable Abdul just looked for DC 0 0
or X CD 0 0 1 & 2 and was able to find
the find and isolate the function but
being able to look for data structures
themselves can be incredibly useful one
of the things I had mentioned about not
being able to build and do a been
difficult that is that you have
preprocessor defines and this is
probably also not very readable but you
have huge chunks of code in cell Letran
that are going to vary based on the
value of these preprocessor values and
in this particular case you have
basically an entire function that will
look very very different based on that
there aren't that many places where you
can kind of discern what that looks like
outside of looking at a particular
function and looking for the absence of
or presence of certain code blocks but
thankfully there are a few places such
as this XSL off name structure that has
a string that is only present when this
c t underscore change which is one of
the more prevalent preprocessor defines
is actually defined so by looking for
forward compatible we're able to see
that this that in the production builds
of Adobe Reader they did in fact use C T
underscore change and on that note I'm
going to hand it over to dual taking
over books themselves
right so I'm going to be covering a
bunch of bugs here basically the
previous ones that have been found in
the excess Lae XSLT parser in Adobe
Reader I'm going to go over a bunch of
bugs of different types
I'll also be covering to all bugs the
first two bugs that were found by
Nicolas Gregoire also known as by caused
by a guy I won as a heat based buffer
overflow and the other one is a type
confusion the reason for us like going
through these bugs is that it gives it
gives us like an idea of how Adobe
patches these bugs
basically they patch these bugs twice
once in 2012 and the and once in 2016 so
basically there was like a four years
gap between these two patches so it's
kind of interesting so outside of the
key based off row flow so Excel elements
in a sublet on are priced inside a class
called XSL element inside it has a
method called execute that contains a
big switch case and parses the elements
based on the type so the way this works
is that it checks whether each element
has has a name attribute and then what
it does is it grabs can make the value
and then calculates the length of it
allocates like a buffer based on that
length and then tries to convert it from
utf-8 utf-16 and this is done inside a
function called is valid and C name
basically as you guys can see I don't
think you guys can see in the back but
it does the string condition inside
utf-8 sterling and then allocates a
buffer passes it to a TF 8 3 a 16 for
the conversion so we went back to the
Letran source code just to do some
analysis and we figured out that the
core of this bug was because of the way
the strength the length of the string
was being calculated basically inside
utf-8 sterling and the way this works is
that it loops through
through their name through the string
like bite by bite and sex for the length
of it of each bite of each character
basically and it keeps incrementing by
one but in special in special cases when
you have like Unicode string or
something like that it doesn't calculate
it actually calculate it calculates it
but it doesn't add the length to the
count
it keeps incrementing the count by one
so that basically leads to a
miscalculated miscalculated length that
length is later used in allocation and
then it's passed to utf-8 utf-16 where
there's actual hit baseball also happens
all right so the way we pointed this out
in adobe basically in the dll the
compiled dll is by looking for DC zero
zero and if you do that directly in
lndian Sai utf-8 to ATF sixteen so the D
compiled code here basically roughly
matches the sub block from source code
so adobe didn't really touch that code
they didn't modify anything and from
utf-8 utf-16 ik just can can grab the
extras and then you can hand up and is
valid and cname the first function
called inside here and C name basically
the utf-8 stare length and this is the
same case it hasn't been touched so it's
roughly the same code in sublet ROM
which is kind of interesting
alright so as of the patch the way they
pass it back in 22 2012 was kind of
interesting so we grabbed a bunch of
their elves from previous versions and
Adobe is generous enough to put all
these and the previous one it is on the
FTP server and we were kind of expecting
to see some changes inside the length
calculation function but in fact what
they did is they they modified the
conversion function and they added an
extra argument to it which is the source
length and then obviously they just use
it to keep track of what's being
keep track of us being written which
didn't actually make sense so until 2016
when we want to be receive the like a
bug from the same researcher Nicholas a
guy ahead Nicholas Gregoire he submitted
the bug that we trigger the same the
same exact class so we submit this book
to Adobe and then got passed in January
20 2017 like a couple weeks ago we dip
the bug and this time they actually did
it right so they modified the the utf-8
single car length no excuse me
they actually modify the TF still length
function that does the calculation and
in this specific case you guys can see
that it calls utf-8 single car length
just to calculate the actual character
length and then they added to the
counting such as incrementing the count
by one so basically they got it right
like four years later alright so the
next book that I'm going to be
discussing is the second bug that was
discovered by Nicholas back in 2012 and
basically this is a type confusion bug
he specifically calls describe it as a
sexy top confusion just kind of cool
alright so the root cause of this bug is
in an expert function called lang so the
way that the way line works basically
just first of all it checks the number
of arguments being passed to it it
checks whether it's sex the type of the
argument in case that Lang is being
executed against the note set what it
does is it tries to convert nodes to two
elements and that's being done inside a
macro called to e so to be specifically
interesting as it uses another another
macro called cast and gases is an
interesting case as basically a bit
called dynamic cast but it does it in
the debug mode if it in production it
just does it this like the classic C
style and that's basically what causes
the whole type confusion issue
so pointing this out in Adobe is pretty
much a straightforward goal we have to
do this like run a search on lang
and then we're going to end up with
three hits and it's pretty much trivial
to to find the right one so what the
right one is going to land you inside a
function with a huge switch case this is
this is not a problem pretty much easy
so that's it's the same case that
happened with the previous one basically
nicolas submitted a park in 2016 that
triggered this walk again and again we
went back with the old dll's and we
started this thing just to see what
happened back in 2012 and basically what
they did is they just make sure that a
certain type of node is being casted
right but you can you can figure
retrigger the bug again by giving it
like other types of nodes and that's
exactly what Nicholas did basically he
gave it a command mode I guess and in
some other of the type of text node and
he was he was able to trigger it this is
the diff of the January 2017 patch and
basically they did it right this time
and they called a function called RIT
dynamic tasks to do that casting in a
the right way alright so I'm going to be
talking about some modern bugs basically
this one is an outer boundary that's one
of my favorite it's really easy to spot
in source code at words found by one of
our researchers called Whaley and he's
based off Singapore all right so this
one is in the way
expat functions are being handled inside
a sublet Ron basically the way it works
when like the expat functions in sublet
on they check for the arguments 1st
argument types and then it references
these these arguments and all the checks
are being done inside macros so for
example check args count basically
checks if the number of arguments is
right if not then it's going to be
allowed physically so if you check the
pattern inside a function called call
func the implements or
expert functions you can again notice
that what happens is they do take check
args and the reference of these arcs
only in one case which is a substring
afternoon substring before the reference
darks and then they check for the args
and that's exactly happened here and
this caused that upon grid right so it's
not that easy to spot this one basically
this is just the function that contains
the whole switch case that implements
all these XPath functions but you can
use one of the techniques that we did I
described before which is basically just
look for rank and then you're gonna
you're going to be able to just land
inside call funk and from there you can
calculate calculated axe the case number
and then you can learn from we can land
in substring before and after by the way
both are handled inside the same switch
case so it's all good
so as for the patch I think you guys
like probably figure it out they just
moved the dogs check before referencing
the actual arc so it's kind of
straightforward alright so then next
month I'm going to be talking about this
a little bit more complicated than the
other one it's an out of bond right and
it has been found by really - so this
one basically affects like how lists are
being implemented inside sublet Ron so
subwoofer implements the list object and
they're just basic structure of ordered
lists according to what they they say
anyways so two things we have to we have
to notice or we have to study about this
list object which is the constructor and
that pend method so in the constructor a
variable called original block size is
being set to 2 to the power log block
size and there's no check against that
value whatsoever in append specifically
that value is used in a loop and that
value is used in an allocation of a
buffer and
and a value a value is being appended to
that to that specific block and then I
think about it is that if someone
controls that that size that length then
they configured some kind of entity
rapid eventually allocating a very small
buffer and then writing out of onto that
buffer to that object so this is
specifically what happened inside create
context basically all the the expat
expat expressions are handled inside
that create context function so first it
defines a valise variable called called
reached and it's set to the predator
count predicates count so basically
predicates are things that the user can
control inside XPath expressions so in
this case the predicate is controlled by
the user and later there's a call to
reach that append 0 so basically if if I
use it defines a certain number of fats
counting he will be able to figure I can
to the wrap which is then be passed that
the values gonna be passed on allocation
and then will be able to go out of bound
alright so pinpointing this one is I do
B is not really straightforward first we
have to find create context and from
there we will be able to find create LT
context level that function calls a
function twice I called I call that this
constructor and if you de compile it
you're going to see exactly that it
matches the sub block form code and
nothing nothing has been changed there
too so the next one so that we can check
which is this depend basically adobe
just copy-paste the same thing they
didn't use they didn't modify any of the
code and as you guys can see that does
the same thing grabs that original block
size use it in an allocation and then
writes that to that block
all right as for the patch I don't pass
it in a really interesting way
personally I was I was expecting them to
do some some checks on the other
valuable initially but what they did is
they did they implemented some checks
inside that end function so they make
sure that the value is in a certain
range if not then it's going to be set
to the negative value and then the
allocation is going to fail so basically
the check is a check and decide the
length is greater than four zero to zero
or is the negative value if that check
succeeds then fine if it fails then it's
going to be set to minus one and Dan's
allocation just fail so the last part
I'm going to be covering is a double
free and this one was found by Whaley
too interestingly Nicholas found this
book too he submitted it to us but we
had to reject it because there was a
duplicate submission so insights of
later on they implement something called
the guarded pointers and basically these
these are pointers that they allocate
themselves automatically on exit or when
something out of bound out-of-band
happens like an error is triggered
anything like that so what's interesting
about the implementation is the
assignment operator which which can
which returns a uh dull pointer so there
is there's no there's you can they
cannot actually track these or there's
no cut like there's no counter for these
or reference counting as we call it so
in certain cases if if you have
reference to that to that tota a GP
inside a function there is no way that
the function can get into the lifetime
of this of these pointers so basically
if an error is triggered then the first
point is going to be freed and then the
reference grab is freedom then you're
going to end up in a bad situation
so this specifically happened inside a
XF filter case okay this is really bad
so in the end there's right here there
is a filtered see GP pointer which is
assigned to you see
for the set to you see and basically
you're gonna you can end up with a row
pointed inside so let's see when you're
dealing with XPath functions you can
force it force it force it to trigger an
error by calling a fake function and
that's going to force these GP pointers
to deallocate or to free themselves so
you can end up with with new C being
freed and then filtered C to be free too
so you can end up in a double free
situation here so I don't be implemented
this in a really interesting way
basically as you guys can see it just
retrieves the reference and then stores
it another local variable later in code
it just grabs one reference and then
deletes it and then grabs the next the
other variable and then deleted too and
that's how and what was triggered by
Adobe so as for the patch they they
patch it in a really interesting way too
which is basically they remove the code
responsible for deleting then the second
reference but you still have a reference
in the stack valuable so if someone
actually was able to to force that
reference to deallocate again then
you're going to be in a difficult
situation so I'm going to give it to
turn to Brian now so he's gonna he can
conclude all this wrap it up alright so
what why is all this interesting the
thing is instead of having to actually
audit the binary you can go directly to
the source and look for vulnerabilities
and find vulnerabilities in a lot easier
way
so stablish ron has been around for a
long time and one of the things that we
actually learned by looking at it I
think we look back to Adobe Reader 9
yeah yeah so Bill did some analysis
where he looked at the dll that was
containing the XSLT engine looked back
every single release of Adobe Reader
since said there we read or nine came
out and they really only implemented
security fixes in every one of those
updates and in white paper that will
release in the coming months we'll go
over basically every single security fix
that they've implemented inside of this
engine over the years and it really
provides like an interesting way you can
use some of the techniques that Jaisal
talked about related to pinpointing the
vulnerability in Adobe Reader and look
for that vulnerability in the code and
for programs like like the 0-2
initiative we're buying vulnerabilities
I mean that's a perfectly valid way to
go look for bugs and find bugs and if
you look at our contest we're actually
would pay somebody like fifty thousand
dollars for for an exploit against a
deadly reader by and they can easily
just go audit some open source code find
the bugs and Adobe Reader and write an
exploit and bring it to the contest so
it's an interesting technique that you
can use Adobe Reader is a very very
popular software inside of enterprises
in fact I was meeting with some
government officials this morning and I
was looking at their laptops all of them
had there'll be reader on it so it makes
a very very interesting target to go
audit and look at looking you know many
of these projects you know no longer
have communities available to them to
develop security fixes or any
improvements at all and it's really then
on the on the vendor to go find and fix
the incoming security vulnerabilities
and because they didn't implement the
code to begin with they may not have a
good understanding and as we've seen
here with the bugs that a dualist talked
about is that many times they don't
actually fix them correctly and so the
two bugs that were actually discovered
in 2012 had been around still around for
many many years until most recent they
were passionless recently with the new
incoming submissions into our program so
just kind of leave it at that you know
it's an interesting code base to look at
you can kind of trend transform those
those open source bugs into close source
application weaknesses
and we hope you enjoyed the presentation
or you're here to answer any questions
if you have any
[Applause]
[Music]
yes so I have a question regarding not
automatically matching source to by me
by compiling source so you said the
defines become an issue because you
don't know which defines are used by
Adobe
have you tried similarity techniques to
find which defines are used or not like
automatically trying to determine these
so we have but at least when I'm doing
things I like to go more I like to be
very static to know for sure and so
finding things like the that array of
strings where you know for sure that it
has that particular define I usually try
and go for that just so I know I can
build a list rather than having to do
bend if similarities that's a personal
preference though
you
perfect thank you very much thank you
[Applause]