I'm Malcolm I'm a board board member and
I'm going to be emceeing this first
section of talks so it's with my uh with
great pleasure that I introduce Jacob
with delete your data
thank you and good morning everybody
everybody hear me okay
awesome uh as was stated my name is
Jacob I'm a recent law graduate out of
Las Vegas Nevada I am anxiously waiting
the bar results which come out in four
hours so if I look nervous later that's
why
um I mostly work in data privacy open
source uh non-profit formation and a
little bit of alternative dispute
resolution so if you see me afterwards
and want to talk about any of that I
love to talk about all of those I'm also
the backup plan our executive director
was supposed to be here but she just
started a brand new job so congrats to
her she's been at least a few years to
the Portland uh b-sides so she's very
sad she couldn't make it uh this time
so what I'm going to talk about today or
I guess I should go back and talk about
delete your data generally delete your
data is a non-profit that is based in
Las Vegas Nevada but we operate
throughout the country we do data
deletion services for
individuals looking to delete their data
from different companies websites and
that sort of thing
so I'm going to kind of use delete your
data to frame
the laws surrounding data deletion in
the United States and abroad so how
we're going to do that is we're going to
first talk about just how the data
deletion process works and it's not
going to make much sense because it seem
oversimplified so then we're going to go
into the laws that support what we're
doing
uh and then with that legal framework
we'll be able to revisit how
deleteyourdata.com deletes your data and
then we'll talk a little bit about why
it matters and things moving forward and
how we can support data privacy and data
deletion uh in the future
so how it works is a user reaches out on
our website uh and then we have a
scraping service which will scrape their
information
or if they just give us specific account
we can delete those specific accounts
and then we just request the deletions
so like I said if that seems a little
bit oversimplified it definitely is that
last part uh is where you need the legal
framework to
to get a little bit more context
so there's there's multiple laws that
enforce a right uh of deletion for
personally identifiable information upon
a user's request
in order to really understand this we
got to know what that personal
identifiable information actually is
so what is it it's any information that
can be used to distinguish or trace an
individual identity some common examples
are names social security number uh the
date and place of birth uh mother's
maiden name and then also biometric
records so uh anything that would
identify that person as
for me it'd be Jacob Jacob Smith uh
so it also includes any information
that's linked to that information that
could also be used to identify that
person so that's really what the data
deletion laws focus on is that personal
identifiable information
um
so the gdpr which we'll talk about in a
little bit gives some good examples of
what is and what isn't personal
identifiable information at delete your
data we get
a good amount of requests for that top
stuff so if somebody writes a journal
article about let's say a politician
running for court in Nevada uh you can't
really request that that be deleted
that's information somebody else wrote
about you but if that person were to
upload a bunch of information on their
social media that can be requested to be
deleted
so what are the big laws that help us
control our data
first we have the gdpr which all of
these have their limitations
um and then there's also the California
consumer Privacy Act uh the CCPA it
operates mostly in California but
there's also a bunch of other state laws
that do things similar in different
states and then lastly we have just
enforcement of a company's privacy
policies
so the general data protection
regulation the GPR
um it's the big player in the EU the
European Union
um and it among other things provides a
right to be forgotten
um so that right to be forgotten is a
right to be deleted
um
so although it only applies to EUC uh
citizens a lot of companies will include
in their privacy policies a general
right to the lesion uh that encompasses
both EU citizens and abroad so uh even
if you're not an EU citizen sometimes if
a company is compliant with the gdpr you
can still request your data to be
deleted
uh CCPA is kind of the like first U.S
counterpart to the gdpr
um it's the California consumer Privacy
Act it's really limited uh to who it
applies to so it only applies to
for-profit businesses
that collects uh or uh sell the
information of California residents and
they have to have one of those three so
they have to have either gross annual
revenue of over 25 million
they have to either buy a receiver sell
the personal information of a certain
number of California citizens or they
have to derive at least or over 50
percent of their profit from the selling
of data
so yeah the CCPA states that people have
a right to request that a business
delete the personal identifiable
information about the consumer uh which
the business has collected from the
consumer so again that comes from those
requests so the user has to request that
they get their data deleted uh and then
if that company falls under the CCPA
they are required to delete that data
so some other big state laws uh you have
Virginia which is almost identical to
the CCPA except it has different levels
of control for organizations and then
you have Colorado Colorado is an
interesting case because it's the first
one to apply to non-profits as well as
for-profit businesses
so a lot of the people I work with are
nonprofits so they're very concerned
about Colorado Colorado and Virginia I
think both don't start uh
becoming enforceable until 2023 so it's
going to be interesting to see how that
impacts the uh the legal framework
surrounding data deletion
so that gets us to privacy policies so a
lot of companies will have the CCPA or
some other Provisions tied into their
privacy policies
um privacy policies are tied often to
terms of service
and these privacy policies in terms of
service are basically a promise or an
agreement between the company and the
consumer that's visiting the website or
engaging with the product
um and the FTC Act is what allows us to
uh or allows them to enforce these
Provisions within a privacy policy so
the FTC act prohibits unfair or
deceptive Acts or practices in or
affecting Commerce
most of the litigation there surrounding
data privacy has come from the uh
deceptive acts so that's if the privacy
policy promises something
and the company's not doing that the FTC
can come in and say you're not you're
being deceptive you're lying on your
privacy policy uh we're going to seek
enforcement against you
um
so the big question here that companies
think of is you know why not just not
include a privacy policy or just make
the privacy policy so confusing that
it's rendered useless uh so a lot of the
state laws like the ccba the Virginia
the VC DPA I think is the uh
acronym for it
they have requirements within them that
the company have a privacy policy that
it be easy to read and that it be easy
to find on on the website
um
so
a big thing with the readability privacy
policy uh is like not using a bunch of
legalese it drives a lot of the older
attorneys crazy but there is a big shift
to write things in plain language
especially things that are like put out
to a consumer like a privacy policy or
terms of service in plain language so
this is the flesh reading ease test
basically
what it does is it using two metrics the
number of words
per sentence and the number of
syllables per word it gives every uh you
know paragraph or body of text a score
and these scores relate to different
grade levels so you can see uh the
higher the score the more readable it is
so a fifth grade reading level uh is
between 100 and 90. and what they want
from these privacy policies in terms of
services is uh
like a seventh maybe eighth grade Max
but as readable as possible
um
so looking at this and looking at some
terms of service we can see really how
they stack up uh Facebook's score on
that would be a 10th to 12th grade level
uh
and it only goes up from there with
Reddit and YouTube being uh
significantly higher so these aren't
very readable documents these terms of
service and these privacy policies
so that's why a lot of these laws like
the CCPA the VC DPA the CPA which I
think is a Colorado Privacy Act
um
these these new Clauses in them that
will enforce the readability and
simplicity of these terms of service and
privacy policies are so important
and then as far as the ease of finding
the hyperlink on the website
um there's a great case uh involving
Uber and their hyperlinks
um they had
what is it it's I think it's gray text
on a white background uh for their link
for their privacy policy or terms of
service and so it's basically unfindable
on a website so uh the Court ruled that
they needed to have it in blue it needs
to be distinguishable and it needs to be
at the front of the website it needs to
be easy to find
um and this one did involve specifically
the enforcement of an arbitration
provision
um but it's likely to see it expand to
uh greater context and just being like
enforceable generally
so this is a great website the terms of
service don't didn't read
um so it uh
it's a play on the acronym tldr
and what they'll do is they will
go into these really confusing terms of
service or privacy policies and they'll
simplify them and just provide a much
simpler version of it so it's a great
resource if you have terms of service or
privacy policies that you need to look
to like the Reddit one which is
particularly confusing they'll provide a
more simplified version of that
this is some more grading of
different websites and how well they did
on their reading ease of use and
everything so Facebook obviously not
doing great Amazon also a grade e some
good ones however as far as protecting
your data privacy our start page and
DuckDuckGo
here's another website with a
confusingly similar name which is
tosback.org this one's done by our
friends over at the eff which is a great
organization I highly recommend reading
their blogs
um
so this one will give you live updates
of changes to the privacy policy in
terms of service as they happen great
resource great organization
um but let's get back
to how this now that we have this legal
framework how it applies to how we
delete people's data so once again the
user reaches out
we scrape or we find the particular
sources that they listed and then we
request deletions but now we have a
little bit more context for that last
one we request the lesions either
through the state laws or what we often
look to First are these privacy policies
so if a user were to come to us
um it's the example I have here yeah
true people search so if a user came to
us and said I have information on true
people search
um I want you to delete it uh what we
would do
is we would first look at the privacy
policy
um none of this text really helps us but
it is the start of their privacy policy
but as we go down to what data they
collect
um and what they do with that data that
they collect
we eventually get to this one here and
this is where it's really important for
us at least
um
that link right there allows for a
deletion request and so if a consumer or
a client comes to us we will go
to the company's privacy policy find if
they have a link like that which is
usually good news
and we'll follow it uh
and so here simply have to put your
email in verify that you're not a robot
um
and then agree uh to their terms and
then they sent us an email in this case
with another link that we had to click
on
clicking on that link led us to another
page where we could fill out a request
to actually get the data deleted I don't
think this one
this one has company here
um a lot of them will ask if you're
deleting data on somebody else's behalf
and so if that is an option we let them
know that we are deleting
John Smith's information on his behalf
as uh delete your data.com but not all
websites and privacy policies have those
um
and so if we would have run into any
trouble here we would have looked for
this link here
uh
and importantly
this address here uh and then we would
send demand letters and that sort of
thing to the company uh to try and
enforce the deletion of that user's data
so this outlines a couple of the other
laws that are
built within the CCPA and some of these
other state laws
the ability to opt out of data
collection a lot of different state laws
require that they allow users to opt out
of the collection of their data
non-discrimination is a really cool one
that's in the CCPA you can't treat users
differently just because they decided
not to get their information collected
um
and then a lot of people and or
companies and organizations will have a
specific section outlining uh if you're
a California resident your rights as
more and more of these states uh adopt
data protection laws we'll hopefully see
that uh Bridge throughout the United
States and become the norm not the
exception
so to protect people's data what can be
done besides uh just deleting the data
um
so there's a big uh
spicy case going on right now FTC suing
kochaba which is a Data Tracking company
that sells data location to other
organizations
and the FTC is suing them this one's
kind of fun because instead of relying
upon the deceptive part of the FTC act
that I mentioned earlier this one
actually talks about the unfair act and
it says that it's unfair to track
people's data because that data may lead
to clinics places of Warship and other
sensitive locations so hopefully that
expands to where the FTC starts
enforcing the unfair acts and practices
as well unfortunately the only relief
they were seeking in this case was kind
of like blacklisting those locations so
you can't see if somebody actually goes
to those locations so it's not as robust
as it could be which is why the FTC
could do more with better laws in place
a federal data Protection Law would
allow them to act a little bit more
uh diligently
so here's some resources just real quick
monitor.firefox.com do not pay.com and
then of course delete your data.com
and I want to thank everybody for their
time uh I am happy to answer any
questions uh in person you'll see me
around I'll be here all day
or you can visit us at delete your data
you can follow us on Twitter at delete
your data you can follow me at IP Las
Vegas or you can follow my Sideshow
Instagram at Yeehaw circus or you can
just email me if you want
so thank you all this has been wonderful
I really appreciate it
all right
I I have a question is this mic on oh
perfect okay if you want to ask a
question please come up hey there I was
wondering what your thoughts are on
Discord
on yeah because disc on Discord when you
try to delete your account all your
messages on Discord servers still hang
around
oh that's interesting yeah um
I mean I don't I don't have any personal
thoughts on it I think we're so far
behind as far as data deletion laws go
that any steps in the right direction
are great but I think something similar
happens with uh
Facebook groups I think it was or
something like that that'll be an
interesting one to get to so if you
would like your information deleted off
of Discord we would be happy to you know
visit the website and we can see what we
can do hi I'm just curious if there's
ways that you can maybe proxy through uh
European union and then get gdpr
enforced or if there's any tricks like
that I've heard of ways that you can
maybe get your IP coming out of
California and then do an opt out
um wondering if any of those Avenues
have been explored
we haven't explored them yet the good
thing is a lot of
I write a lot of privacy policies and
stuff and that's kind of my side of
things usually uh this is like a
non-profit that I help as well uh and
a lot of more organizations are caring
about data deletion generally and so
those requirements and Provisions that
are in the gdpr and the CCPA are being
applied across the board to all users so
I think encouraging companies to do that
is really our best bet
um but I haven't looked into like
patching people through
um
yeah thank you uh so my question is like
with the California and Virginia one is
there like a list somewhere of states
that have published a law or a policy
type of thing that we could go to as a
reference point yeah we have a couple
um blog posts on deleteyourdata.com uh
but I found a good
table
um like maybe a month ago but I forgot
who posted it so I will track that down
uh and find it and possibly repost it on
our website uh hi so I was wondering
with respect to the uh simplistic
language so that people can actually you
know understand what a privacy policy
means
when you're mapping from
legal language which I'm assuming has a
very specific intent behind a lot of
words you could have
a very precise meaning and in
simplifying that language you might get
your syllable countdown or whatever
metric you're using there uh but you
might be hiding some of the actual like
Precision of what
the the agreement actually means uh is
there a way to kind of
I guess account for that without being
uh falling under the category of being
deceptive because it's like oh well you
know you said one thing that has a
common English like understanding of
what it means but it it actually means
something a lot more uh confining
yeah it's a so there's a definite
migration uh to to just like
common meanings of contract terms so the
first when you're doing contract
interpretation one of the first things
you want to do is look at the plane
meaning uh and if the planning's there
and it's unambiguous then you're done
like uh in most cases
um
so
the idea that more complex language is
more precise is a bit of a fallacy so
you you do want to just use like
plain unambiguous language hey thanks
for the talk um I was just wondering if
there's like one addition or change to
U.S regulations with regard to people's
personal data and pii and things like
that like do you have one in your back
pocket that you'd like recommend hey
here's a policy change we could make
that would protect people's privacy and
help the customers you have at delete
yourdata.com
is like a government level or a company
yeah yeah like a a lot yeah I mean as a
government level if we had a federal uh
data Protection Law that wasn't
didn't have a bunch of hidden stuff in
it
um it would allow the FTC to Greater
like enforce data privacy a lot better
um yeah they're kind of handcuffed by
the the unfair and deceptive Acts
got it thanks yeah no problem
awesome thank you everyone
[Applause]