[Music]
[Applause]
hi guys uh we're gonna get started here
my name is will kinderman uh thank you
for showing up to this talk about uh
some Mac OS persistence mechanisms I'm
really excited to be here I hope you
guys are having a great day and excited
to hear this talk
um as mentioned in the keep them out
this morning
um this talk is going to be discussing
things like using technology in ways
that were unintended uh you find like in
Mac OS there are a lot of
mechanisms that you can use to do cool
things and so let's talk about four of
them and then at the end we'll close
with uh how you can protect yourself
against this
so first a little bit about me I work at
Oracle Cloud infrastructure I'm on their
red team the photo you see on the right
there is of my wife and our two dogs uh
Lucy Liu and Cedros I'm a huge fan of
retro gaming I have a ton of consoles I
love to restore consoles and I love
modding them like there's so much crazy
cool technology that people are coming
out with these days for like consoles
you know like the Nintendo like it's
it's pretty amazing my first ever
exploit was in 1997.
I was able to steal my parents uh AOL
password from aol's like the save
password thing so I could use AOL on my
computer uh anytime I wanted to a 13
year old me thought that was like the
most awesome thing in the world and it
probably led me down the path that I'm
on today
and finally I did the lock picking
challenges for the CTF this year so if
you haven't had a chance to go check
them out uh go do I think the last time
that I looked the second the last
hardest and the hardest one both had
just one solve on them and so you know
if you get some time on those try to try
to solve them let me know I did that's
my first time ever Keen locks for
pinning locks for a challenge like this
uh in this presentation there will be
some QR codes
um and I have like three for Apple
documentation and then one to take you
to uh some third-party tools that'll
help you protect yourself and so if you
see that QR code it's going to be
talking about like whatever Apple
documentation on the mechanism that
we're using Apple
does not write good documentation uh
but often you can get enough out of it
to do what you want to do
so before we get into talking about the
persistence mechanisms I'd like to talk
about TCC and what TCC means for you so
TCC stands for transparency consent and
control you can find it in every modern
version of an opera operating system
today so like it's on iOS it's on iPad
OS it's on Mac OS and I'm sure it's
probably like an Apple TV OS as well you
know they're all very similar but
they're their own builds and what TCC
does is limits an application's access
to sensitive information right and
sensitive information defined by Apple
in this case are things like the user's
documents the users downloads
and uh
uh the desktop folder as well as like
the trash is also considered to be a
trusted source and so if you don't have
TCC permissions for your application
when you try to access those the user
will get a prompt saying hey you're
trying to access documents do you really
want to do that and it'll say like
whatever application is trying to to
access that and so like it's one of the
the major tells that we run into when
we're trying to like land on a machine
and and do things on a machine when the
user doesn't know that we're there
um and so like I said you know these
most of these are in the user's home
directory and they're like the directors
that really contain the information that
is more most interesting to us
um
as a user you can manually see what
programs have permissions in these
directories by opening up system
preferences then security and privacy
and then privacy and then there's like a
full disk access panel and a files and
folders panel and files and folders will
like be the certain like single
directories that your application is
able to access and then hold this access
or full disk access we'll let your
application access the entire disk no
matter what uh you'll more often see
that like in terminal you know a user
will like get tired of getting prompted
every time they go to a new directory so
they just give like terminal full disk
access and so then you have cart block
on the machine to read anything that you
really want to that you have permissions
to read
um you can reset the TCC permissions so
if you're testing this
um you know just keep in mind that you
can reset them at any time you want just
pop up the terminal and then run the TCC
util and it just reset all and then the
bundle ID for whatever you're doing so
like for terminal it's
com.apple.terminal
and some applications you can just do it
by like the application name so you
might be able to do like terminal.app
and that'll let you clear out those
permissions and so you get reprompted
and it's just a really easy way of doing
testing uh it's also important uh to
keep in mind TCC when you are gaining
for persistence and you're first landing
on a machine because you don't want to
accidentally like CD desktop and then
like all of a sudden your user is like
getting a prompt when they're working on
a PowerPoint presentation for you know
uh totally not uh malware payload uh you
know wants access to your desktop
directory that's kind of embarrassing
um
so just you know be careful that you
know don't browsing directories unless
you know what your contacts that you're
in
um the first technique that I like to
talk about is launch agents and this is
kind of like the bread and butter
um you know this is uh in a Linux world
you would think like a systemd like this
is just like a systemd in its script uh
there are these
P lists which are like property files
and they're really just XML documents
um there's two types of of launch agents
there's the actual launch agent which
are our scope for the user and there are
launch daemons that are scoped for the
system
um so
you know you you you're not going to be
able to do anything with launch
statements you're going to need pseudo
access so when you first line a machine
you're going to only have access to uh
the the launch damage or the launch
agents for the user and you can find
those in the user's home directory and
library and then
um launch agents sometimes the directory
exists sometimes it doesn't exist TCC
doesn't care if you make it so you know
if you land on something just you know
make sure and you can do you can add
that
um so that's you know really cool to
know there's a lot of files actually
that are really interesting that are
under the user's home directory that
Apple doesn't protect
um you can interact with launch agents
uh using the launch CTL command and this
is just like uh you know systemd uh you
know start stop that kind of stuff so
it's you know very very similar to that
on the Linux World
um
and so the ones that we're really
concerned about are the launch agents
here and they are used to run per
background processes uh and they're
super simple to configure uh and the
picture here you can see one for uh a
program called steer Mouse right just
like a tool that you install lets you
control your mouse a little bit more and
you know you're basically writing the
same thing like you'll see the next page
that you'll see that the boilerplate
that we're going to be using is almost
exactly the same as what they have here
um and again they're very uh simple
they're XML sometimes they are binary
encoded XML and you need to use a
utility to decode them and we'll go over
that a little later when we we talk
about another persistence mechanism
uh so here's the cookie cutter code from
Apple like this is literally stolen from
the documents uh and you can find the
docs there in in that QR code uh and so
you can see like there's really three
sections that you might be concerned
about the first section is the name of
the PLS that you're using so like each P
list or launch agent is going to have
its own unique label and so just make
sure you're not stomping on something
else because they will get overwritten
and then if like somebody tries to
unload an agent on their own and you
have the same name like you can confuse
things
um next is the path of the execute we
like to run and so uh and in this
example they do like hello world uh and
so the hello would be the application
that you're actually running and then
the world would be the argument and you
can add as many arguments there as you'd
like
um so just make sure that when you do
put uh your art your program there if
it's not like in the user's path already
give it the full path because it won't
execute otherwise one of our favorite
things to do is land our binary under
um
the the user's home directory and and
just like the um the library directory
and just call it from there and so just
make sure you know you have the user's
full path uh don't use tilde
um
and then you can also like
just let you know put this in place and
then just wait for the user to restart
for this uh to run or you can uh force
it by using launch CTL and just like
launch CTL load and then the path of
your
um
your P list
so there's some also like some
interesting features like you know what
we just saw was just very basic it just
the user logs in and then it starts
executing uh everything under launch
agents and eventually it comes to yours
and it loads but you can also do other
things like
um you can make it look like cron a bit
like it's not totally like chronic
because they use like a calendar uh
Start calendar
um interval and that is really like the
the date the calendar date so and our
example here with like every seventh day
or every seventh of the month it will
run at 1 45 pm
um and so it's not exactly the Quran but
you can do like load uh run at like
every X seconds and just choose you know
you want to run it every 15 hours just
put 15 hours in seconds and it'll
continue to persist there another
interesting uh feature that I that I
found was you can actually listen for
sockets and so you can say uh you know I
want like I know this user is using a
jupyter notebook and I only really care
about uh running something when they
actually have Jupiter up right it's like
I can start pulling down or using you
know a persistent message there or
whatever you want to do but so like you
listen for 8080 or you watch 8080 and
when 8080 comes up you you know can
launch your application based off of
that
finally and it's not the last launch
agent feature but the last one I think
is really useful and that is you can
actually monitor a directory for changes
and so uh you know I was thinking like
if you uh you could like monitor a
repository that the user is working on
for code and then whenever they start
editing it you know that they're active
on their computer so you know you can
use this to send yourself uh like curl a
web hook for you so you get notified
that the user's back online
um
you know or that you know they're
working in a directory that you're
interested in you know maybe it has it
has the cool stuff that you're looking
for and so then you can also like base
attacks uh on that
um you know just knowing when they're
active which can be a little hard if you
you know everybody working from home you
don't have to see the user in the office
or whatever
um so unfortunately with like this ease
of use uh comes like easy
discoverability uh you know any EDR
worth its weight and salt will be
monitoring launch agents right and so
you know uh your detection Response Team
should get like an alert that hey
somebody's putting you know pretty shady
launch agents up here maybe we should go
check out what this user is doing uh you
know this doesn't look like a normal uh
launch agent also there are software
um that has been written to actually
monitor launch agents and let you know
as the user when a launch agent is uh
being initiated like when it's the first
time it runs it you can choose to you
know allow that or temporarily block it
or whatever until you can figure out you
know what's going on with that
um and then finally I think like the
biggest downside to launch agent
persistence is
you're not going to get the TCC
privileges that you want right like
you're going to want to be able to read
the documents directory you're going to
be able to read all those other
directories where all the interesting
stuff is at and since you know you're
you're Landing your own malware uh you
know it's not gonna have those
permissions by default so you're gonna
have to do some tooling around uh how
you land your your payload uh you know
an easy way is just like make an
installer they're pretty easy to do uh
you know just make that installer have
the user say like oh you know just click
this over to your full disk permissions
and
you know users have been trained just to
do that so I think you'll you'll have a
high success chance there
and next
uh persistent mechanism that I thought
was really cool and I recently got to
use this
um is
uh abusing terminal
so
um
terminal is great because
you know you have
the you have the terminals TCC
permissions right so if a user's already
given the terminal full disk access
you have full disaccess by running under
the same TCC context as terminal is this
should also work with iterm with some
minor modifications item keeps their
settings in different places but they
have the same functionality
and so if we look at iterm our terminals
preferences in the UI you can see that
there are like two different uh
two different ways that like you're
allowed to change what happens when a
terminal opens and the first picture
over here you can see that we can change
the shell of the user uh you know so
like if you didn't want to use zsh it
would be an easy way for the user
themselves to change that to like bin
bash I think that's the the kind of what
Apple was going for rather than having
to use chain shell but um
so you see the shell method and then on
the other slide you see that under the
preference there
um you can run a command whenever your
profile loads up and so there's you know
a bunch of built-in profiles and each
one of them has their own Uh custom run
command that you can use
um and so you can you know find out what
the default one is and then change that
run command
uh and and to write these you don't need
TCC permissions because it's also under
library and preferences and apple
doesn't care about that
so uh
this is the first binary P list that
we're going to be talking about and to
use this binary plist you need to use a
PL utility is what Apple calls it and
you can convert that binary into XML and
then make your modifications and then
convert it back into binary and then put
it in place and so the next time the
user loads up their their terminal it
will inherit all those permissions that
you've changed and you'll you'll you
know start start cooking
um
this isn't the only way to actually
convert or change these settings but it
is the easiest way because there's so
much nesting in this P list that it's
easier just to convert it to XML make
your edits and then convert it back I
was hoping like a one-liner with
defaults uh but it just just doesn't
work out really well
and so you can see here on the right
there's
um
just an excerpt of the PLS file after
it's been converted to XML and I
highlighted five different sections that
are interesting to us and the first
section
we can see that the default profile of
the user and now we need to know that so
we know which profile to modify because
you'll have all the profiles that the
user has saved in in terminal but we
only care about the default one mostly
second we have the path for the shell
and you can see in this example uh I had
it highlighted to you know opt Homebrew
bin fish to use the fish cell
um third we have the command which will
run which will run at the default
profile launch and so in our case like
basic I think is our our default profile
and this is the command that runs at
launch of a new basic shell
fourth uh we have processes that
terminal should not warn the user uh
that are open when the user tries to
close the terminal so if you are running
if you open up a shell
and you're you know it's using zsh
because that's the default for OS X and
you type in Bash if you try to close
that window you're going to get a prompt
that bash is still running would you
like to close the window you can tell it
you can tell terminal to ignore those if
you put your application there the
default ones that Apple has in places
tmux and screen and so you can just kind
of follow the examples that they have
there and you can see those in the
screenshot here
finally
we have the option to disable warnings
when closing the prompt and this will
disable the warnings no matter what
application is running and so like it's
kind of like an easy way to cheat to get
to the end but you know every time that
you take one of those shortcuts you're
like leaving a tell and you know and
what we're trying to do is not let the
user know that we're there
so terminal is really awesome because
processes launched from terminal
inherent the TCC permissions of terminal
so if the user already has you know if
we'll just access and you launch a you
know your your payload from terminal uh
as a launch script it's going to have
full disk access as well which is pretty
powerful
um and likewise if you're if it only has
access to documents you'll at least have
access to documents
um if it doesn't have access then the
TCC prompt that pops up will be from
terminal so you know it's kind of
like Wolfson sheep clothing a little bit
uh you can kind of hide what you're
doing the user might not realize that
something's going on
um if they're actively moving around the
file system I know that a lot of people
are using like oh my CSH now and you
know there's autocomplete functionality
in that that will prompt you uh to show
that like your documents directory even
if you're not trying to use your
documents directory and so like
as you know these functionalities clash
with TCC like users are just kind of
like clicking okay you know it's fine
whatever I just want to continue so keep
that in mind when you're when you're
doing uh any persistence
um
so there's some best practice that I
found uh when I was initially starting
out with this I was like yeah we just
like run a command and it'll be like
hunky dory everything was going to work
um but as you can see here like when you
run a command on that first screenshot
up there
um it says what command is run right so
we don't want to like be like hey run
this and then and and the user notices
every time they start their new shell
like it's you know malware dot you know
jxa you know and you know it's gonna
it's gonna give you a way
um and then uh
I would also recommend not replacing the
shell for the user because it's so like
user forward there like don't use the
the first method uh to replace the shell
unless you're going to like compile your
own version of bash that has your back
door in it and then replace it that way
um which would be a you know a good way
of doing it uh you know you can write
the opt Homebrew bin people don't
install bash a lot uh from that so
you're using like some old version that
you know Max still ships with or you
know even zsh you can write there all
you want
um
next if you're using a script to to be
your run command ensure that you're
running your command backgrounding it
clearing the screen and then returning
to a login shell if you don't do that
the user is totally going to know that
like something's up there's still going
to be a tell even if you do
um
the I didn't get a chance to work it out
but like there's a banner at the very
top it says the last time you logged in
and there's got to be a way to like
easily you know print that to the screen
before it does the login shell I just I
wasn't able to figure out a way for this
um you know just be really observant
with how your victim works you know if
you can do a lot of profiling on them
and just understand how they're working
you know it's going to increase your
success uh and not getting caught
um finally I would recommend
um not to change the worn Shell close
action which is the one that will close
no matter what it's a zero which would
just you know you close it and it just
closes the shell because that's going to
be a tell for you uh just whitelist like
whatever process that you're you're
coming back to
other than that you know enjoy your
access to the user's uh projected files
okay so uh next is folder actions uh
folder actions are really interesting
um
you know like launch agents you know
Apple's automator allows you to create
folder actions and so like just like we
saw we can uh do monitor directories you
can do kind of the same thing with
automator and folder actions and there's
like multiple ways you can do it but uh
the GUI I think is the best way or the
easiest way at least
um now these will do things for the user
like run scripts that you decide on the
user's behalf so I think apple is
thinking with this that
um
you know a user has a watch action for
like a document or a photos directory
and every time you drag your photos in
there it'll remove the exit data or
resize the photos in there and that's
kind of the idea behind it because you
can use everything that you can use with
applescript with that as well as you
know run your own shells
um
so to do this uh you know just launch
automator select a folder action
you can also do this with jxa or apple
script but you know the way that I found
the easiest again was just to use
automator on your computer
um you know select the folder action
select which folder that you want to use
specify what you want to do when that an
action happens on that folder
and
um
and then just have automator run a
scripts you know it could be uh you know
a binary it could be a bash script it
could be a Zs you know so whatever you
you really want applescript or jxa are
also really good because you can find
out other information
and so you just create that that action
and uh to save it right and so on your
computer you'll have that folder action
now so you like uh you know for an
example if I was watching the downloads
directory and I get into the downloads
directory I make a change and then
whatever action is going to happen on my
behalf
and then once you've done that you just
copy your folder action dispatcher PLS
from library preferences to your
victim's computer
ensure that all the paths and scripts
exist on your victim's computer
then
thank you
um and then
uh
oh wow I'm sorry we had so then you just
make sure that your victims uh
everything's like the same as your
victim including your user name that's
really important and then just copy over
your folder action script and then just
run folder action setup.app and kill it
immediately and that will register your
your action on the user's behalf and the
user is not going to be wiser
um
moving along kind of quickly here
so there is a tell for this uh if you
are running a very long script you are
going to run into
um an icon popping up in the menu bar
and so you just want to make sure you
back around your script or your
application that you're running and then
also like you have to make sure that
your username is the same username as
your victim because if it's not it's not
going to work you can't unpackage this
uh PLS binary list for whatever reason
PLS utilt will just not unpackage uh the
nesting of it
um the next one I want to talk about is
login and logout hooks I'm going to go
this really quickly they're super simple
um they they run on login and log out
you can register them with defaults
right
and com apple login window log out hook
and login hook and just register your
script they require pseudo access so
just be sure that you are you know have
your password because you're not going
to do it without it
um they're deprecated but like Chrono
Mac like they still they still work and
they probably will work forever
um to protect yourself go check out
Objective C software that's Patrick
Wardell uh knock knock and block block
two awesome applications that will help
you protect yourself and then kind of
just understanding what's going on with
your Mac behind the scenes because
there's definitely a lot there
um and then finally be vigilant like
apple and and pretty much every other
vendor analysis training you to click OK
click OK you know let's get through the
security prompts uh you know try to
understand what's going on with those
prompts because you know there is
somebody that understands that and is
going to try to do everything they can
to make you click uh and then finally uh
you know thank you guys
um
I'd like to thank uh you know my team at
oci for and my wife for uh being really
supportive This research and I want to
give a shout out to Cody Thomas and Saba
fitzel for the great work on folder
actions like I was able to really
understand them and and build up on that
so
thank you
[Applause]
yeah yeah we got five minutes I think
for questions uh four minutes so if
there's anybody have a question you back
there
[Music]
okay so I guess like if you did that uh
so he's saying that you can hush the The
Prompt for the user uh the last login
prompt and so you can hush that and
maybe get the user to stop seeing that
before you do your your persistence
over there
the various things that have rights is
there any demand to export the clouds
uh it is all stored in a sqlite database
I think that is protected
um so you can do it with sudo but you
cannot do it uh you know if you don't
have privileges as a user and I think
that it's kind of like
it's it's obfuscated a bit like I've
read some things from probably Cedric
Owens that talks about it
um and so I would check out Cedric Owens
and he can probably uh has a blog post
about it
uh you there on the front in the green
shirt
when you enable uh openssh for remote
login
no so if you are SSH so um remote login
features for sharing under the system
preferences you can enable remote login
and that'll enable SSH for you SSH has
TCC full write permission already you
can actually see that in the full
um this access section of the
permissions and privacy
uh there was another one behind that
gentleman
yeah so I haven't so the question was
have we seen these uh successfully in a
fishing campaign
um we at my job we don't actually do
fishing we we work with our victims so
they know that we're there
um but
um again Cedric Owens who does a lot of
Mac OS research uh has done fishing
campaign campaigns and when he does it
he writes an application uh unsigned and
then just you know tells users to click
OK because they're kind of of use to
that I think that is all the time I have
questions if you guys want to talk to me
about it anymore I'll be in the hallway
thank you guys
[Applause]