welcome to the crypto for crypto session
um our first talk is on the paper uh
craft composable Randomness beacons and
output independent abort MPC from Time
by Karsten Baum Bernardo David Rafael
dowsley Ravi Kishore yes prabhu's
Nielsen and Sabine Ochsner and Ravi
Kishore is giving the talk
can you hear me yeah uh myself I'm going
to talk about craft
um composable Randomness beacons and
output independent about MPC from time
this is a joint work with my co-authors
custom Bernardo Raphael esper and Sabine
agenda is as follows
I'll introduce you to the refillable
delay functions and time log puzzles
and
I'll talk about artist model of abstract
composable time on which uh we built
this protocols and then I talked about
probable sequential computations in UC
setting based on this I'll show you a
couple of constructions for ucvdfs and
publicly verifiable time lock puzzles
and uh building on this uh building on
these constructions I'll show you a
couple of applications one is uh MPC
with output independent about
and um efficient unbiasable Randomness
Beacon and I conclude with uh feature
works
okay so what is a PDF uh PDF is a
function
and its output is generated only after
performing a certain number of
computational steps
and that means there is a delay is
involved and moreover uh this PDF along
with the output it produces a proof and
this proof can be to disprove guarantees
that to get the output a certain number
of competition ships have been performed
and moreover with this proof we can
essentially check whether this
computation
this output we got after performing
these many competitions is independent
of the number of steps
primitive which allows uh encrypting a
message to the Future
so to construct these uh Primitives we
need a computational task that must be
executed in sequential steps taking at
least some time
so in RSW 96
First Construction of TLP and which is
uh based on iterated squaring
uh your trading square is not elements
from groups of unknown order
let's see what it is exactly
um let's say you start with n which is a
product of two primes as in RSA key
generation now you pick an element
random element G from GN star
if suppose if you want to compute the G
to the power of 2 to the power of T then
you need to perform T sequential
computations uh starting from z z g
Square g g to the power of 2 power 2 G
to the power of 2 power 3 and so on G to
the power of two power t
um
and uh so notice that suppose you know
the order of the group which is pi of n
then you can perform uh you can compute
G to the power of two power T much
faster than T sequential computations
because uh G Port 2 power T is nothing
but G to the power of 2 power T mod Pi
of n
okay so under this assumption uh what
how how do you construct time log puzzle
so time Block Puzzle is nothing but B
and then M times G to the power of 2
power t
uh once uh once you compute G to the
power of 2 power D then you can find the
inverse uh and you multiply due to the
power of 2 probability inverse with M
times e to the power of 2 power T and
then you get back the message m
so that's the first construction uh what
are our contributions uh
um
uh you see a treatment of verifiability
of the functions we give the definition
and then matching construction and same
goes with uh pvtl publicly verifiable
time lock puzzles as well and then a
couple of uh a few of a few applications
uh based on this Primitives that's uh
one is UC MPC with output independent
about and you see MPC with punishable
output independent about
and uh efficient Randomness Beacon
protocol
okay so related Works uh a few Works
exist on uh modeling cloud
functionalities in the first two Works
uh model the wall clocks where
functional where parties and
functionalities can ask for the current
current time so whereas in the last work
uh which is uh we follow as well where
functionalities can ask only if a Time
unit has passed
and moreover the Standalone time lock
puzzles and vdfs have been constructed
uh of course which are not uh UC
composable
and non-reliable time log puzzles too
um
building on this time lock puzzles
protocols exist for partial fairness for
2pc
over like again no Comfort no composable
guarantees for any of this except Tardis
work Tardis first introduced uctlps and
and presented an application to PC with
application for two PC with output
independent abort
okay so uh what is start this model in
the studies model there is no Global
clock but in its in place of global
clock we have a global ticker where
functionalities can ask the a global
ticker whether a new tick has happened
since the elastic that means whether a
Time unit has passed or not
and then in response Global Response
with yes and new tick has happened or no
still in the same time unit
and whereas the parties just observe the
events from the functionalities
uh if suppose they have to if suppose
they are get activated by the
functionality then before doing that you
just acknowledges the global ticker that
it got activated by the functionality
but in response uh parties don't get any
information about how many tics has
passed whether that has passed or not
that's the
Tardis model for artist model of
composable time
um so now in this setting uh I'll show
you how we model the probable sequential
computations
this functionality of PSE which is pse's
probable sequential computations this
captures the notion of generic
Standalone trapdoor vdfs so FPC fpsc
allows both comp Computing and verifying
sequential proofs okay fpsc has
four uh
blobs at one state table salt solve and
verify and then parties can ask so
present the from initial State st0 and
then solve it for take computational
steps it can ask for uh solve and then
when party or adversely asks for solved
that will be added to the list of
puzzles being solved and then in the say
I minus one I minus one to take parties
are parties are adversary asks for
advanced take this it will be Advanced
only in the next take
um see there is an Epsilon parameter
which which we allow for adversary to
get this let's say yeah adversely may be
a little powerful than the a honest part
is so that is why if I is Epsilon time T
that means uh by Epsilon times T
adversity will get the yes after
Computing these T mini steps what would
be the final state that gets is that is
stt and then get the proof whereas uh
parties must wait until the uh tier the
sequential step happens then only a
party gets a final State STD and then
proof pi
uh however there is a Blog for the
trapdosol suppose they are
um somebody who's having trapped over
from the
um
uh somebody who's having the trapdoor uh
trap door from uh trapdoor can starting
from the st0 in t steps directly gets
the final State and then proof pi
so also this uh there is a verify
interface as well in the verify
interface when party asks for verified
gives the proof this is the initial
state after T steps this is the state
sdt and then this is the proof if you
want to verify that then suppose it
verification takes G of T time units
then after G of T time units
this functionality outputs a bit B where
uh with ACS this is valid proof or if B
is one yes this is valid proof otherwise
no this is invalid okay let's see our
vdf construction based on this
um so now you start with a random state
st0 from State space and then you set
your input as st0 and then now you you
query the fpsc to solve this from
starting State SD naught then fpsc after
T steps it outputs uh spp and then Pi
okay so once this is ready you set your
output as a hash of final State and then
proof
uh proof which you got from fpsc and
then you set the proof of a vdf as uh S3
Pi STP and then the original proof you
got from
um you know fpsc so how do you verify
this now once we have the output and
then proof you want to verify whether
this is uh computed after certain number
of steps then you pass your proof as St
80 and then pi now compute uh a hash
that is output Prime which is a hash of
T HTT and Pi now you see you already
have the original output and then check
what would be the hash you got both are
matching or not if matching then s
that's the correct
correct output otherwise if you say that
okay so that's the video of construction
and then now uh let's see how to
construct pvtlp
um here again some random state from
State space now
because it's the owner who is creating
the time log puzzle you simply send tap
those all St 0 to fpsc and then you
immediately get the final State and then
prove now you compute the hash of all
this
and then that is call it H1 and then you
compute a tag which is uh xor of this
previous hash and this message now hash
everything you get the the let's say
call it H2 which acts as a
commitment for these values now you
output your TLP as
t 0 and tag one tag two
so now suppose somebody wants to solve
this time log puzzle so then like you
have an outcome like puzzle St 0 to add
one tag two now if you want to solve
this what do you do you simply compute
uh stt sequentially from st0 and then
get the proof because your PSC outputs
proof as well now and then you compute
hash of as usual here you compute hash
of all these values and then now extract
the message M which is uh uh tag one xor
with H1 now you compute H2 because you
already have now proof and then tag one
and then message as well
and then see if it is matching with the
tag two if it matches then output
message otherwise it's an invalid time
log puzzle
so how do you verify suppose somebody's
gives you the message and then proof
contained in this message content in
this PL TLP if you want to verify then
how do you do that you pass your TLP st0
tag one tag to do and then because now
you know the final State and then prove
you can directly get the
um you can you can you can directly find
out the
final state sdt from proof pi and then
you follow the steps from two to five of
the solve procedure
yeah so what are the applications now
you you know you have uh you know how to
construct uh pvt LPS
so one application is output independent
about MPC
um what is output independent about MPC
the adversary if adversary decide to
abort it must decide before learning the
output of the MPC protocol how do we do
how do we do that
um so you do MPC protocol as usual uh
till the last round but before sending
the last message what you do what you do
is you put that message last message in
the TLP now
like every part in our sense these
outputs to the other parties now you
expect uh
um uh you expect to this if you're a
honest party you expect to receive uh
the other part is TLP before uh your TLP
is solved if you don't receive then you
know that uh about is detected
so that's the one application of uh
uh TLP and um
let's move on to uh efficient Randomness
beacons uh here also uh
um protocol works as follows
um all parties starts with some random
number which they put in a time lock
puzzle and then broadcast it now uh say
I part is Randomness is RI and then you
broadcast it and after broadcast delay
all the parties
reveal their Randomness and then
trapdoor if suppose
what you can do is because the TLP you
compute uh you'll be able to compute uh
you will be able to solve the time lock
puzzle
so once you solve the time log puzzle so
look at look for the valid ones and then
now we exalt all the values that is uh
that is the output so
um so yeah I mean that's the main idea
suppose some party fails to uh open the
TLP but uh
you know that TLP can be solved after
certain time units you just simply solve
and then now eggs are all the valid uh
messages from the time log puzzles
and then you Excel you get the you exert
all of this and you take it as output
suppose some parties won't comply in
sending the in opening their time log
puzzles then we can impose Financial
penalties
um
yeah so open questions
we can try for we can look for UC
compilers for fairness and efficient
output independent about for generic
functionalities also we can try to
construct
a home office uctlps and PDFs
also we can look for uh applications in
crypto space
yeah thank you
we have time for questions
I was wondering if you can comment a
little bit more on the implications for
rational MPC yeah so now
um
for example like look at this protocol
after uh sending the TLP you can expect
immediately all the parties to open time
lock puzzles like by providing the
trapdoor you suppose some parties are
not providing then you can impose uh
Financial penalities so
um
um if computation is taking too much
time then you can adjust parameters
accordingly
um so if it is a rational adversary then
there is no incentive to cheat so
adversary behaves as honestly and then
immediately tries to open the uh time
lock puzzle by providing the trapdoor
thanks any other questions
right well let's thank the speaker
um
so next up Daniel is paper 24.
all right
um
so the next talk is on the paper
efficient and universally composable
single secret leader election from
parents by Dario catalani catalana Daria
Fiore and Emilia Emmanuel giunta and
emmanuelli will give the talk
thank you
does it work yeah sounds better so
welcome everyone I'm American and today
I will present uh this paper is a joint
work with Professor letter catarano and
professori uh from Catania I'm India
from Madrid so
um today I will be talking about uh
leader election protocols and to give
some motivation uh the reason we studied
interaction protocol is because they are
a way to achieve consensus in blockchain
so for instance uh when we elect a
leader in blockchain in motion
application the leader is the one who is
supposed to post for instance Block in a
chain and let everybody agree on the
content of the chain at this moment
now since the leader is a very important
role in keeping the protocol alive it is
important that when we elect a leader we
keep it secret in such a way that it is
impeasable for anniversary to maybe
perform a DDOS attack on the leader and
block the protocol execution
so for this reason uh secretly Direction
protocol actually deployed in practice
but they have a drawback the fact that
in many applications they are just
probabilistic secret leader election
protocols
so this means that the protocol is
divided in three phases at first there
is a protocol to elect the leader uh in
practice you can think of this as
choosing around put a random inputs and
then user basically evaluates a vrf on
these random inputs then there is a
potential a phase in which many
potential leaders are elected for
instance those who have evaluated the
function their own vrf and got for
instance a very low uh outputs but they
don't know yet they are the leader and
finally revealing their own secret
information uh parties understand who is
the leader for instance the one who got
the lowest vrf value and they've also
collected only one leader of course
because they can only be at most one
smallest value on expectation uh so this
is nice and it's very efficient because
it's not interactive but it creates some
issues for instance statistical Imports
because if somebody doesn't receive the
output of some leader some potential
leader maybe you can think the winner is
someone else uh and also create wasted
effort uh because if uh all those
potential leaders have to create the
next block maybe they need to lose some
proof of work and they need to waste
computation to do that
so for this reason in 2020 uh
proposed a new primitive called single
secret leader election but there can
only be at most one leader uh for each
election indeed
um so this was proven to be harder to
attack uh by azulian capital in 2021 uh
and the only disadvantage so far is that
there is a inefficiency gap with the
probabilistic redirection now in this
case uh more interaction is usually
required
um so just to be more formal and precise
uh so in the case of single secret
leader election we tackle basically
three properties and we're defined in
the first paper
and this property are essentially
uniqueness uh saying that for each
election there can be at most One winner
and notice that we cannot have precisely
One winner because adversary can win and
say uh and decide not to claim victory
so we can have at most one leader but
maybe none for some elections uh we want
to have fairness meaning that all users
have the same probability of winning one
election
and finally we want to have
unpredictability meaning that uh before
the leader decide to reveal uh she won
the election uh there should be no way
to guess uh who the leader is better
than guessing at random
unfortunately uh the only issue with the
definition proposed by bonuses
security May Fail if we compose the
protocol concurrently with itself and
actually in the paper we provide some
situation in which this does happen so
this is a concrete threat and for this
reason uh we propose a UC secure
definition so for those who are not
familiar with the UC model we
essentially provide an ideal
functionality which describes which
specifies how elections should be
carried out uh for instance handling
registrations for election for instance
party can access the functionality to do
an election and the functionality can
privately tell one of those users that
he won the election and when this user
wants to claim victory this can
communicate with the functionality and
say I want to claim victory and the
functionality convince everyone that
this is indeed the winner
and what we have to do is simply show
that real protocol behaves in
distinguishably from the ideal protocol
up to simulating missing messages
uh so prior to this work and also after
uh this work was published on ePrint uh
essentially we had only the game based
uh early game based uh secured
Construction in the first paper and
there were three of them uh one based on
in East initially obfuscation another
one on threshold photographic encryption
which are mostly theoretical interest
although they have some nice feature and
the most practical one was the one was a
shuffling based solution based on ddh
which has as a main drawback the fact
that uh essentially each user is
associated with hypertext and we need to
permute this list so we have we have a
high on chain costs we need to keep this
list on chain for each election
uh next many other improvements there on
chain to the shuffle based construction
essentially were published uh with a
paper last year in podzi which improves
this achieving UC security and adaptive
security uh and there are other
construction which for instance uh
improved on uh presence managed to
distribute the shuffle uh and and
finally there is another construction
that is based I don't think it works
okay I reconstruction that it's based on
NPC which is another advantage of having
like very small on chain uh complexity
so for verification we don't need to put
many things on chain but it's very high
on communication uh on of chain
communication so our construction so the
the main feature that it achieves is
that we use only uh well started and
basic assumptions and we achieved nice
uh poly logarithmic on chain efficiency
so this will be the main contribution of
our work
so now I can just uh present a little
like what are the technique we used
uh so the main building block we used to
provide our construction is a keyword
search functional encryption uh and a
slightly enhanced version of it so
keyword search functional encliction
essentially uh is an encryption scheme
in which there are functional secret
keys that are associated to messages in
this case sky is labeled with message Y
and when we decrypt with secret key we
can learn if a cipher text is encrypting
why or not and that's the only thing we
learn we don't learn anything else about
the message
so in the paper actually we do need a
slightly enhanced version of this uh
which we call Modular keyword search
functional encryption and instead of
checking if x is equal to Y uh we can
actually check if x is equal to Y module
one
so of course the message X and Y needs
to lie in some uh given a set of
integers like in a given range uh but
that's a lot more technical details I
won't go into
so at the high level uh in order three
percent thought protocol and I just need
to specify two things I need to specify
how a user can register into the system
and our elections are carried out uh so
at first I will just focus on election
and then I will mention more like I will
say more about registration but for now
we just need to know that a registration
we assume there is a subject subgroup of
users who maybe have a secret sharing of
the master secret key of the functional
encryption scheme and a registration
time gives new user a secret key labeled
with the identity that they have uh so
that's okay so they have a secret
keyboard the modular keyword search
functional encryption scheme uh and next
every time you want to perform an
election uh We Begin by We Begin by
simply by publicly uh selecting a random
committee or police mode and it's
another committee as the duty of
computing a commitment to a Cyber attack
social and Cypher text uh so this
challenge ciphertext will be the one
deciding the winner
so first this committee uh select this
uh create this commitment to running a
random challenge Cipher text then all
the parties together threshold of and
his commitments and get the challenge
Cipher text and finally only the user
who is able to decrypt this message here
uh is the one who can who won the
election and it proves it uh throughout
the knowledge proof
not this year that by the way the
modular keyword search is important
because uh this message here I'm
identifying the winner uh is essentially
taking us the sum of several uh M1 MK
several shares all lying in this range
So eventually this m will be lying
between zero and if there are Kappa user
Kappa times n uh so we need to do
modular reduction here to check that the
identity is equal to the message model
one
uh so just to give also a bit intuition
like why this scheme is secure uh we
immediately have the scheme satisfy
uniqueness because for each M uh
reducing it module and there if the
entities are from 0 to n minus one that
can only be one secret key that keeps
this message uh it is uh Fair uh
satisfies fairness because if there is
at least one user honest user in this
committee one of these Mi is uniformly
random uh in zero and minus one and in
particular this m is uniform module one
and finally it is uh it is unpredictable
because uh because um other parties only
learned that they didn't want the
election but again no information on who
the winner really was
okay so just a little bit more detail on
this uh so again uh the election phase
Begin by selecting a random committee
and it is done through a random Beacon
which essentially gives random values
and identifies a small subset and the
small subset against us to produce the
commitment to Virtual and ciphertext and
then encrypting like the sum of all this
share that they're randomly sampling all
of these like laying in the range from 0
to a minus one
um okay and so how do they do this I
need to go a little bit more on the
detail of how the encryption scheme
works and this is by the way a modified
version of uh uh encryption skin biotech
query from 2018.
um so we don't need to know much about
the details but just that the encryption
comes from this expression those are
like public key elements and the issue
is that uh the randomness used to
encrypt uh so everything is linear in
the randomness used to encrypt besides
for this term uh so if everything were
linear the nice thing is that we could
have each user in the community selected
on Randomness then we multiply things
together and this would be a valid
Cipher text but because of this
quadratic term we cannot do this
directly so we might need more rounds
and this is problematic uh so the way we
avoid using more rounds of communication
is uh through random oracles
so the idea is that uh we use the random
Oracle to sample two uh uniform
municipated group elements and we
interpret those these two group elements
as an encryption of a random message uh
under algamal or whether like a random
commitments commitments that is the
orange element in here and then we use
linearity of El Gamal uh to uh build the
remaining parts of the cycle text which
now only depends linearly on the secrets
that is the message and the randomness
as used for the encryption
so now uh we just can compute everything
in one rounds by having uh first
teranomorical compute this part this
orange part and then you said in the
committee uh producing their own share
and finally multiplying things together
uh so to conclude the election uh we
just need uh to essentiate a textual
decryption I didn't mention maybe that's
uh we assume that this is a random
commitments under secret TZ so assume
there is like uh G1 and zg1 uh publicly
available to every user and also that
they use it as a share of Z so user can
can threshold The Click then this is
just the standard Algoma threshold
decryption there is nothing new and
finally uh to clean Victory uh the
winner simply provides the generalist
proof that he knows a secret key
decrypting the challenge Cipher text and
this can be done easily with a sigma
protocol like very efficiently Maxima
protocol so finally I just need to
explain how the registration Works uh an
area is essentially the same so we
assume that at setup time uh there is a
committee design probably larger comedy
of user who has a secret sharing of uh
the master public key for the encryption
scheme and uh for the secret Z that was
the secret key for the Algoma commitment
scheme
um okay so this can be simply by having
issues are sampling on the wi and zygi
and then implicitly defining w and z as
the sum of all these shares
um so given this uh the the secret key
in our scale must essentially this shape
and we again have the same problem uh we
have this random Sr that it's uh fresh
for its secret key in this case okay we
just have it but here we have a
quadratic independency with the
randomness and the master public and
master secret key so in theory we would
need more round of interaction to
computer sharing of R times Tableau but
again we can use the same trick of the
random Oracle by sampling by generating
these two uh these elements randomly for
all the user in the committee and
finally having each member of the
committee uh return give to the user
like wi times all these things uh and
then multiply all this element together
in order to get uh the correct secret
key
uh okay so to conclude
um we have okay so we did uh compare our
work essentially with the shuffle based
Solution by uh bonus
uh and in particular we observed that uh
okay so for each of our uh Rich columns
here uh we assume that we perform an
election and between every two elections
uh there are uh 10 20 and 50
registrations just to provide uh I mean
just have a way to compare both the
restriction and elections at the same
time and we observed that in our case uh
the setup cost is a little bit is of
course more than the shuffle-based
solution uh because we need to
instantiate the verifiable secret
sharing at first which is with high in
communication uh but then uh the fact
that our registration is very efficient
uh the committee simply need to send a
constant number of group elements to the
new user uh the cost of the scheme is
eventually better than the shuffle based
solution where you need to shuffle the
whole list uh every time there is a new
user
um and this is a problem by the way that
affects all the shuffle based
construction that came afterwards so the
efficiency in those cases are comparable
with the first construction
and even for on chain costs our scheme
is even better than uh the square root
of and Shuffle where your list Shuffle
subset so yeah you have even less
anonymity in that case uh but uh still
like very high on chain complexity uh
for the previous constructions
what I present today is a practical and
you see security scheme uh that achieve
uh poly logarithmic uh on chain
complexity and only relies on standard
paying assumptions so there are still
problems and ways to improve this
protocol and for instance one of those
questions is can we reduce the setup
costs like do we need to use the
verifiable signaturing or uh can we use
different techniques uh and finally if
it's possible to achieve adaptive
Security in our setting uh for instance
the reason why we don't achieve adaptive
security is that we rely on committees
and uh if
and if those committees are fully
corrupted actively then the adversary
completely breaks the system so we can
only uh prove security against study
Corruptions so that's it thanks for your
attention
and
related questions
thank you for the talk we have uh we
have a few minutes for questions
so I didn't get how to make sure that
the N is correct in the encrypted
messages
uh okay I I I missed I mean I didn't
mention like how we ensure that all
these cyber attacks are correctly
generated uh but in fact the small n is
the number of registered user at the
moment and this is a public information
and uh in fact uh all user or you say in
the committee uh that produces these
partial ciphertext that are later
aggregated uh need to attach the
knowledge proof of that and uh and it's
part of these statements that the Cyber
tests are correctly generated so it has
to be the number of registered user at
the moment
uh thanks for the question
I actually have a quick question
for the zero knowledge proof uh do you
use Sigma protocol or like customized
protocol based on pairings okay uh so
essentially use the fact you mean the
general Edge proof for the uh for
proving like that I can decrypt The
Cypher the challenge Cipher text
okay uh so we essentially use the fact
that our encryption scheme and
especially in the decryption procedure
is essentially linear uh so we can we
can essentially a lot of like known
techniques like uh like this grammar
version of Sigma protocol for uh linear
statements uh so essentially it's not
basically has no proof uh but for a
slightly modified statement uh and also
like uh since the Cyber text has only a
constant amount of group elements that
provides to us like five group elements
in total if I'm not wrong thanks for the
question
I I'm gonna ask my question so so
um so this is a beautiful construction
and you really kind of looks like
um s s x DH is doing a lot of heavy
lifting there so I was wondering
um what are your thoughts on achieving
the same asymptotics but from other
assumptions
uh so I think that without pairing it's
uh probably hard because uh I mean we
need parents to have functional
encryption there and without it I don't
I'm not aware if there are like keyword
search function encryption for weak
assumptions I I believe it could be
possible from lactices but I don't know
if efficiency wise would be better or
not but that's definitely an interesting
question thanks thanks
all right other questions right so let's
uh thank the speaker
so um
So Daniel
um the next paper is paper 37. yeah
all right
so
um
so our next paper is uh
simple fast efficient and tightly secure
non-maleable non-interactive timed
commitments by Peter and Tibor Jagger
and Peter will give the talk
okay thank you for introduction can you
hear me yes okay so hi everyone I'm
Peter and I'm going to talk about simple
past efficient and titles secure
non-miable non-interactive time
commitments which is growing work with
Tibor Jager and let me start with
motivation example uh imagine that you
have uh set off and bidders who wants to
participate in Seal bit auction
and the first thing they do they commit
with standard commitments came to their
bids and they publicly made these
commitments to available everyone and at
some point of time they reveal their
bits but now assume that one of the
bidders claims or I lost my Randomness
I'm not able to open the commitment and
and he claims that his bid is the
highest which is interesting for the
seller because he wants to sell the item
for the higher highest price and now the
question is can we resolve this issue
uh and one way how to resolve this is
use so-called time commitment and time
commitment has additional feature which
we call Force the commitment and this
feature allows to open the commitment at
a specified point of time automatically
without the intervention of another
users
um so what we require from such a times
commitment are following properties uh
the first one is called public
verifiability of the commitments we want
to be sure that the commitments are
correctly generated and also we want to
be especially sure that they can be
really forced the committed
uh then non-interactivity for practical
reasons uh we want to be that they are
non-mariable we don't want to allow uh
users to create their commitments based
on the time commitments of another users
uh then some kind of homomorphic
properties can be interesting because uh
usually this Force the commitment
requires to execute some sequential
computation which can be expensive and
now imagine that several users reject to
open their commitments
in the case that we are interested only
on some evaluation on the messages which
are hidden in these commitments we can
homomorphically combine the time
commitments and then Force the commit
only resulting time commitment and then
we also also introduce this new property
which we call public verifiability of
the first day commitment and this allows
to Outsource the computation of the
first day commitment to untrusted server
and he can prove us that he execute the
first equipment correctly
okay this has found several interesting
applications like achieving unbiased
e-voting or fairness in multi-party
computation protocols like Fair coin
flipping and several others
uh let's start to be a little bit more
formal non-interactive time commitments
were introduced by cuts at all and it is
a couple of algorithms so we have a
pigeon algorithm which they just input
the security parameter and time
parameter and output the CRS then we
have committing algorithm which comments
to the message and produce the
commitments and also committing and the
committing proof then come verify
algorithm that checks that the
commitment is correctly generated uh the
commitment verify algorithm just think
about it as a standard opening algorithm
for the commitment and then we have this
special force the commitment algorithm
which allows to open the commitment
without any secret information and the
requirement is that the runtime of the
algorithm is roughly thin as I mentioned
we introduced this new property called
public verifiability of course the
commitment
and in that case the first the
commitment additionally outputs uh also
additional algorithm first document to
verify we check that the first day
commitment was executed correctly uh and
then that again it I'll also introduce
this homomorphic properties uh where
there is a evaluation algorithm which
works in the following way it takes us
into the CRS circuit and set of time
commitments output and under time
commitment and then we can run for the
commitment algorithm and open evaluation
of the circuit on the messages which
were hidden in the time commitments
uh there are actually several security
property which are which are required
from uh such a time commitment but in
this talk we are going to focus only on
one which is called indcca security and
this property is actually very similar
to indcc security or public key
encryption uh and it works in the
following way adversary a consists of
two machines a0a1 and then the
Challenger run speed and algorithm to
obtain CRS it sends CRS to the a0 a0 can
ask the commitment queries but we are
going to answer the commitment queries
only for commitments which are correctly
generated and the requirement is that we
answer them using Force the commitment
algorithm
um
so at this point I want to mention that
if we want to achieve tight security
proof in the proof there must be another
way how to answer this the commitment
queries because the runtime of this
algorithm is rough City and it might be
expensive then a0 provides a challenge
messages
Challenger randomly sample a bit commit
to the message MB compute the commitment
provides a challenge commitment to the
adversary A1
uh A1 again can ask this the commitment
queries again we are going to answer
only correctly uh generated uh
commitments and it must be also
different from The Challenge commitment
uh and then adversary A1 output B Prime
and the requirement is that the runtime
of the adversary A1 is less than t uh
because otherwise A1 can run this Force
the commitment already and he would be
able to uh see what is in the inside of
the commitment
and then the output of the experiment is
defined as the true uh truth value of
the expression Biz equal B Prime and
Advantage is defined as a probability
that uh X Prime and outputs one minus
one half
okay so I told you uh that this security
notion is very similar to invcca
security notion of the public key
encryption and also we need this public
verifiability of the commitments uh so
therefore uh the idea is to start the
publicly verifiable public key
encryption scheme and the candidate of
course now yeah in Paradigm where you
can uh
encrypt the message twice using two
independent Keys using CPA Secure Public
encryption scheme and then prove using
one-time simulation some music that the
uh that both encryption contain the same
message okay
and uh we want to have however efficient
construction that is also efficient
music so the base would be some Sigma
protocol and we know that the sigma
protocol exists for algebraic languages
and therefore the challenge is to find
the replacement to substitute this
public encryption scheme
okay so the candidate for such a
substitution uh is actually homomorphic
time or puzzle of malabota at all which
consists of four algorithms setup genes
solve and evaluation algorithm and this
evaluation algorithm works as expected
and now notice if I just rename the
algorithms as speed didn't come and
force the commitment then I have a time
commitment but uh
this time commitment has very weak or
weaker Security in Ocean and it's very
similar to CPA security and option okay
so this is the candidate
and malabota at our show how to build
this primitive from the strong
sequential squaring assumption
um which is the following assumption
adversary again consists of the two
machines a0 A1
and uh Challenger runs then what
algorithm produced to large Price p and
Q and is the product of the primes and
GSM generator we provide ntng to the
adversary a0
and then Challenger randomly sample X
from the group of J of n which is the
subgroup of that star of elements which
Jacobi symbol one y zero is computed as
x to the two to the T mod N and y1 is
the element of J of N and I Define it as
two algorithm two experiments so in one
experiment we provide X and Y 0 a second
experiment X and Y one a one output B
bit B Prime and the runtime should be
less than P of the algorithm A1 and the
advantage is defined as a probability
that adversary a outputs 1 in experience
zero minus probability that adversary a
outputs one in experiment one
okay so in their paper actually they
show uh
linearly homomorphic and also
multiplicatively homework Construction
in this logo I'm going to talk about
only leader article morphe construction
of timeline puzzle
um so in Pigeon the Iran decision mod
algorithm then they uh they compute this
Euler functions by of the N which is T
minus one times Q minus one and then
they compute the Special Value t as a 2
to the T modify of ND divided by two and
this is the order of the group of J of N
and H as G to the T mod n and CRS is
then NP G and H
and now the commitment commitment is
something very similar to paella like
encryption where we randomly sample R
from some interval and compute c0 with G
to the r naught n and C1 is very similar
to Pi a h to the r times n times one
plus n to the power of M mod n Square
and now notice we can force the commit
it without any secret information we
compute the value y as c0 to the power
of 2 to the P naught n and this can be
computed by repeated squaring and it
takes three steps of the repeated
squaring therefore we say it has runtime
roughly D and the message can be
recomputed as C1 times inverse of Y to
the power of n mod N squared minus 1
divided by n
now notice we have also by like
homomorphism it is sufficient to
multiply separately c0 parts of the
commitment and C1 parts of the
commitments and additionally okay we can
also Define standard opening algorithm
uh if you give me message on Randomness
I reconcute the commitment from the
scratch and just check if it match the
client commitment
and this was shown to be kind of CPA
secure based on strong sequential
squaring decision of composite
residuality and decision of the film and
assumption
um so our first attempt how to obtain
this CCA security is just use the
combine two independent homomorphic time
of puzzles which were produced using two
independent Keys okay
and on this slide I also wrote two
independent modules and one and two but
in reality if we want to let's use
standard Sigma protocol then N1 is equal
to N2 and from now on I assume that this
holds okay and now look let's look what
will happen in the security proof so I
told you that in the experiment uh there
is this requirement we have to answer
this the commitment queries using for
the commitment algorithm and in order to
obtain time security prove there must be
another way so let's say we use kt1 and
this is indistinguishable based on the
soundness of the music uh then we can
start to simulate the proof okay here we
rely on the Zero knowledge property of
the music and now we can try to replace
the message in the second homomorphic
table also with the random message
but now what happens this kp1 has this
special form two to the team of order of
the group and in order to compute this
key we need to know the order of the
group and essentially we need to know
the factorization of 10 but at the same
time we need to reduce the security of
home morphic time on puzzle and
especially we need to reduce to the
strong sequential squaring assumption
and this assumption does not hold if we
know the factorization of n
so we are a little bit stuck with this
approach
and there is a simple observation that
from this homomorphic time of puzzle we
can just get simply homomorphic uh we
are homomorphic public encryption scheme
if we sample the Key T uniformly at
random from some interval and then I
just simply rename the algorithms and I
have standard public encryption scheme
very CPA secure based on decision or
composite residuality and decision
assumption
okay so what uh what is our second
attempt is to
combine homomorphic timelock puzzle uh
with uh with this encryption scheme
and they were produced using independent
Keys okay but now what happens in the
proof that at some point of the time I
again have to use this key T which is
this special form
and for which I need to know the
factorization of N and I will have to
reduce to the DCR assumption and now the
problem is that this air assumption does
not hold even on the factorization of n
so we can fix this issue simply by what
we call Triple night or young and triple
now or yank is you can encrypt the
message twice using two independent keys
and the third time you commit uh using
this homomorphic timeline puzzle because
you still want to have this feature of
force the commitment
and why this works
um so in the security proof you can
always uh answer the commitment queries
either using pk1 and change the message
sorry
change the message in the homework time
of person and second public key
encryption scheme will be the random
message
uh or you can answer them using key K2
and then change the message in first
public encryption scheme with a random
message and you never have to rely on
this special key which for which you
needed to know the factorization of and
yeah so the security proves simply works
and this is essentially our construction
that we can do little bit better uh we
can use the technique of the biagini at
all and instead of having three
independent keys and three independent
commitments we can generate just one
generator G and produce H1 H2 H3 with
respect to this generator G and then we
can comment with using shared Randomness
so we compute G to the r and then we
compute this three pile like commitments
using the same Randomness r okay so
instead of six elements we will have
four elements
um
and therefore we need one-time
simulation sound music for the language
which shows that c0c1 c2c3 is correctly
generated commitment and contains only
one message in a Randomness and in our
paper we show how to build a sigma
protocol for this music and we show how
to obtain uh either uh music in random
record model or in standard model using
this Collision intractable hash function
okay
so to just uh point out to the important
things uh okay in PGN we randomly
sampled these two keys K1 K2 from some
interval and then we have this special
keep uh which is completed as 2 to the T
mod order of the group and if we have an
easy in standard node model then we have
also the setup of the music
series of the music
and uh then we commit as was explained
on the previous slide with the shared
Randomness and we prove that the
commitment is correctly generated and
the randomness R is actually just
standard opening of the commitment okay
and in our paper we also show how to
implement all other algorithms uh
efficiently
so to conclude in our paper you will
find four constructions two
constructions are linearly homomorphic
two constructions are multiplicatively
homomorphic
and always one is in random Oracle model
and one is in standard model and
compared to the previous Works uh we
either actually uh efficient committing
time type security proof some novel
properties
um smaller size of the commitments uh or
that the constructions are standard
model because often they are in a random
Oracle model
um okay if you are interested in the
paper you can just find it on the ePrint
or you can contact me via my email uh
thank you for your attention if you have
any question you are welcome to ask
we have time for questions
questions
um so I have a question about the
applications of uh uh of this type of
commitments yes so uh as I told you like
very often you want to use it for
achieving this uh fairness uh in the
multi-party computation protocols like
Fair coin flipping so you uh
like for example in this uh coin
flipping protocol like it can happen
that at some point the
participants see their uh
messages which they are sending in the
protocol uh or when they are opening the
commitments and one would reject to open
then the protocol fails yes but because
they commit for example with this time
protocol uh they can still open also the
commitments of the other users and the
product already continue how is it
different from
I mean verifiable
I mean verify of the UI function you are
really not committing to the value yes
it's just the output of the I mean this
verified UI function is good for
achieving this unbi uh unbiased Beacon
yes but for example it wouldn't be good
for achieving uh unbiased evoking
right yes it will be done enough yeah I
guess my bigger question is the
relationship between between this result
and the one we just heard it in in our
you know the craft okay yeah
yeah so
yeah the construction is UC secure yes
also they have to also rely on the uh
a random Oracle model and I mean
if it is UC secure I think it means it's
automatically not malleable but they
don't have for example these homomorphic
properties
yes
okay uh thank you thank you for your
talk I want to ask uh what assumptions
uh do the first three Works rely on
uh okay cut uh
uh okay uh it's a sec this circulation
squaring assumption uh is in all of them
I think
and uh
the second one is real yeah is relying
on uh generic musics uh
so therefore like they are relying on
snacks actually snacks yes
uh and they are the first two are or all
of them are in the random Morocco model
I think
yes
so they are also revised
okay thanks
welcome
so the next paper is paper 83. your plan
all right
um so our next paper is a certifying
giant non-primes by Charlotte Hoffman
Bible hubachik Chetan Kamas and
Christopher and Charlotte will give the
talk
okay thanks for the introduction
so I hope you're not too disappointed
that this is not going to be a talk
about crypto for crypto but we're going
to see an application of crypto in
computational number Theory
namely we're going to look at prime
numbers
so prime numbers have always been of
Interest not only in number Theory but
also just in the General Public
so for example there are those
large-scale projects that are dedicated
to searching giant prime numbers
they are called gims and Prime grid
um and when I say giant I really mean
giant so the largest prime number that
has been found by Prime grid consists of
more than 9 million decimal digits
yeah
to find those numbers the projects
perform expensive primality tests for
numbers of special form for example
profit numbers or mercen numbers
and to prevent cheating and computation
errors until recently they have done
this via double checking so do two
different parties check the same number
no matter if the result was prime or not
Prime
but of course we as cryptographers we
can ask ourselves if we can replace this
expensive double checking with
cryptographic proofs
um and in our work we show that this is
possible for some specific cases
um namely we're going to look at Cross
numbers
so Prof numbers are numbers of this form
K times 2 to the N Plus 1.
where K is odd and it is strictly less
than 2 to the n
and for numbers of this form there
exists the where non-family test called
Prof steering
so
this says that for any X which is a
quadratic non-residue modulo n we have
the NS Prime if and only if the
following holds
we take X we raise it to the power of K
times 2 to the N minus 1 and then we
check if the result is -1 modular n if
the result of minus one we know that the
number is prime if the result is not
minus one we know that the number is
composite
but notice that even if we now know that
the number is composite we do not get a
divisor of the number so we don't have a
we don't have a proof that this was
actually the correct result
um but if we look at the permeability
test we see that this is this uh
big a big exponentiation so
um
and in cryptography we have a tour to
certify the result of some big
exponentiations
and those are called proofs of
exponentiation
so there we have approved render
verifier
and approver claims that the result of
some big exponentiation is equal to Y
and some group G
and to prove this the proofer can send
the Poe
so proof of exponentiation
those Poes are usually only interesting
in Hidden order groups
because if you know the group order
then the verifier does not need any help
from the proofer it can just reduce the
exponent module of the group order and
then raise X to that power and it's
usually efficient and it can just check
if the result is true or not
but if the group order is hidden then we
don't know of a significantly faster way
to compute the result than to perform T
sequential exponentiations so that's
what the proofer does but
then it sends a proof of exponentiation
for which the cost of computing and
verifying it is much less than T so the
verifier does not need to work as hard
okay so this looks promising now can we
use this for our primality test so can
we use Poes for primality certificates
or non-parently certificates
uh yeah again here you see the primality
test it's this big exponentiation
and in fact games and Prime grid have
already discovered this connection and
they have deployed PHX Poe to certify
primality tests
but there's a problem here so as I just
said future xpoe was constructed for
hidden order groups
and now we're working in the group z
modulo n
so if it's a prime number then we know
the group order it's just n minus 1.
um so notice that this does not speed up
this computation because
the group order is still larger than the
exponent so we cannot reduce the
exponent anymore however PHX protocol is
unfortunately enough sound in those
groups
and in fact there even isn't a tick so
for any Prof prime number
um the prover can come up with a fault
proof convincing the verifier that the
number is composite even though it's not
um notice that there are other Poes in
the literature there are also
statistically sound Poes that work in
any group
however they are more complex and
because we are working with such huge
prime numbers here we can really cannot
afford to use a Poe that's much more
complex than phxpoe
um right so in our world we take care of
this problem so our contribution is we
construct a statistically sound
certificate of non-premability for proof
numbers
that reduces the complexity of double
checking from n multiplications to all
of Lambda Times log n where Lambda is a
statistical security parameter
and it increases the complexity of the
currently deployed protocol which is not
the cryptographically sound only by a
multi-duplicative factor of two
okay again not so this is a certificate
of non-premality however in practice
more most of the numbers are not Prime
and so with this certificate
we cover almost all of the cases
um okay now how do we achieve that
uh the rest of the rest of the chart
we're first going to look at phxpe uh
then I will show you the attack and
cross number groups and then finally
we'll see our protocol
but first I want to remind you of the
definition of interactive protocols so
again we have approver and the verifier
and they both get us input some
statement X and then the approver also
gets a witness or just more computing
power than the verifier
then they send messages back and forth
until in the end the verify outputs
accept or reject
and we say that this protocol is sound
if whenever the statement is false then
the verifier rejects with higher
probability no matter what the malicious
proofer does
and we say that it's complete if
whenever the statement is correct and P
is honest then the verify accepts with
high probability
in this talk all of the protocols will
be trivially complete so we're just
going to discuss soundness
okay so let's take a look at pictures
Poe
here the statement to be proven is that
x to the 2 to the T equals y and some
group
to prove this the first message of the
proverb is this element G1 which we also
call midpoint because it's the result of
the exponentiation X to the 2 to the T
over 2.
notice that by sending this element that
implicitly splits up the first claim
into two smaller claims
so one of them is that this G1 is
actually the correct result of this
exponentiation with 2 to the T over 2.
and the other claim is that if you take
the midpoint and raise this one two two
to the T over two you should get back Y
which is the result of the initial chain
okay good so now we've made some
progress we've reduced the exponent from
2 to the T to 2 to the T over 2 but we
now have two statements instead of one
and so to take care of this the verifier
now
since a random coin R and The Proven
verifier for those two statements back
together into one
like this so we obtain this equation
down here by taking the first statement
raising it to the power R and then
multiplying this with the second
statement
okay and then now we feel the rate
progress so if we use the exponent from
2 to the T to 2 to the T over 2 and now
the proverb again just needs to prove
one statement so we can request
um the proverb again since the midpoint
and we do this for log T many rounds
until in the end the verifier just needs
to check the result of this one squaring
and then it can output accept or reject
notice that all the messages the
verifier sends are just public random
clients so this protocol can also be
made non-interactive using feature
now what you can see is that if you if
the approver here starts off with the
wrong statement in the beginning then no
matter what it sends in the first
message at least one of the new
statements will also be incorrect
however for soundness to hold we need
that also after the folding step
we still have a wrong statement here
um so that in the end the verify notices
that there's something fishy
um so pitchek proves that this holds in
certain groups but unfortunately it does
not hold in proof number groups
and now we're going to see the attack
so let's assume that we have a prime
number of prime n so the correct result
of the terminology test is minus one
however we have a malicious prover that
claims that the result is actually minus
Alpha for some other element Alpha
now there are different messages that
the prover can send in the first round
uh it's not really important to us how
it looks like but we as we just said
um we still have that one of the new
statements there's still incorrect and
this bad element Alpha is still in there
somehow
um then the verified sense of random
coin and then we fold the two statements
back together into one so we take them
we raise the first one to the power R
and then we multiply it with the second
statement
but this might be a problem right now we
have this bad element here and we raise
it to some random number
so we might actually be unlucky and have
that Alpha raised to that random to a
random number equals one modulo n
and then this means that the bed element
vanishes from the claim we have a
correct claim and the proofer can be
honest in the rest of the execution and
the verifier will never notice that
there was something wrong in the
beginning
um now what's the probability of this
event happening well that depends on the
order of alpha so if we say that Alpha
is an element of order D then the
probability that Alpha raised to a
random number equals one module n is
just one over d
and so we have the probability that
verify accepts that and is composite
even though it's Prime is at least one
over d
uh I forget to say that this attack was
first shown in the context of ddfs by
beneathans and fish
um okay good so this is a problem but in
our setting we can take care of it so
let's see for our work we first make
some observations so here I'm reminding
you again of pro steering and now we're
in the setting where we have approval
that claims the number is composite and
the result is minus Alpha
so the first observation we make is that
in this case the verifier only needs to
exclude that the correct result is minus
one
so we don't care if the proverb cheats a
little bit and claims that the result is
minus Alpha even though it's 7 or it's
13 or whatever because in all of those
cases we would have that the number is
composite and that's all the information
that we want
we just need to remember out that it is
actually Prime
then we have seen that the success
probability of the attack depends on the
order of IFR
but if we assume that we have a
malicious proverb then n is Prime and
then we know the group order it's just n
minus one and we know that the order of
alpha because it's an element of the
group divides Disorder so then we know
that Alpha divides K times 2 to the n
and we can use this information to check
if the order fiber is too small
okay so here we're in a lucky situation
which is very different from the usual
settings when you use vdf
um we're assuming that if we have images
proverb then we have a prime number and
so by assuming you have a prime number
this gives us much more structure that
we can use to construct the sound
protocol
and this is how the protocol looks like
so again this is a non-premulatory
certificate
uh this is posterior again
and now we have approved by their claims
uh it has a number that is composite so
the result of the primality test is
minus mu for some mu that is not equal
to one
and now what the verifier does is it
performs checks on the order of mu and
then depending on the outcome
um the protocol looks differently
so let's first assume that the verify
has raised this element here to the
power K and has already gotten one
so that means the order of new divides K
so it's odd and it is smaller
this isn't for the very very lucky case
because then again it doesn't doesn't
need any help from the prover to check
if the result is true so I don't want to
go into detail what the verifier does
but it performs some number of theoretic
tricks and then it can just output
except or result reject simply without
ever seeing a message from the approver
the second case is that the order is
large enough so the verifier has taken
the element mu raised it to the power K
and then 2 to the Lambda Times log n
where Lambda has some statistical
security parameter and the result is not
one
again recall that if we have a malicious
prover the order of mu divides K times 2
to the m and now we've raised it to K
times the sufficiently large power of
two we didn't get one and so this means
the order of mu is very very large so
the success probability of the attack
that we have seen is negligible and so
in this case the problem can just send
phxpv without anything else and then the
verify can sound the output except or
reject
and the last case is that the orders
even but it's not big enough so we're
performing this check raise mu to the
power K times 2 to the Lambda log n we
got the result one
so in this case we're going to use a
trick that's similar to the one we used
in a paper from last year at crypto
so we let the provery step a little bit
earlier the Hoover should not perform
the entire exponentiation but it should
stop at 2 to the N minus 1 minus Lambda
Times log n
and output the result way and also a
proof that Y is the correct thing and
then the verifier performs the final
exponentiation itself so it takes this
way raises it to the power two times
Lambda Times log n and then checks if
the result is really minus mu as the
prover Clint
again I don't want to go into detail of
why this is sound but the idea is that
by performing this final exponentiation
itself the verifier somehow weeds out
potentially bad elements that the prover
used to cheat with and so also this case
is statistically sound and with the
verify outputs except reject
and that's the protocol now we've
covered all of the cases
so to sum up we construct a
non-permanent certificate for profit
numbers with the following efficiency
properties so compared to PHX Poe in
person number groups it's only slightly
more
a complex but our protocol is
statistically sound and hxp we didn't
give us any cryptographic soundness
and compared to double checking we've
reduced the complexity of verifying from
n multiplications to all of them at
times login so in practice that means
we've reduced the work from weeks to
hours
one interesting open problem is to also
construct a cryptographically sounded
certificate of primality as I said
before most numbers are composite so our
certificate already covers a lot of the
cases but of course it would be nice to
cover all of them
and another open question is to
construct similar certificates of
non-permability for other types of whole
numbers such as mercen numbers which are
of the form 2 to the N minus 1.
and that's it now we're happy to take
questions
thanks we have plenty of time for
so my question was why are Prof primes
interesting why is there you know what
why was there so much interest in this
uh and why is it interesting that
they're non-primes right so fraught
prims are interesting for the community
because we have such a nice primality
test which is deterministic right
um so yeah that's why
um they're testing a lot of protein
numbers and then
um
yeah of course you want to make sure
that you don't miss a prime number so
when you work with such giant numbers so
you want to approve for both cases you
want to be sure when you found
paranormal you want to be sure that it's
Prime but also when someone claims no no
this number is composite and then we
also want to be sure it's actually
confidence that and you have not missed
a big Prime member
um yeah
well let's let's thank Charlotte and uh
let's
see
look thank you
I'm going to introduce you
um
all right so uh the last paper in the
session is transparent batchable time
lock puzzles and applications to
Byzantine consensus
by shravan srinivasan Julian lost Julia
malavolta cardig Nayak Bob is papamantu
and Shri
um and
um shravan will give the talk uh hi uh
thank you for the introduction I'm going
to repeat it uh this is a giant work
with Julian lost Julia
so our work our work is on building
transparent batchable time lock puzzles
that has applications in our Byzantine
conferences
uh thanks to the speakers before me they
pretty much gave all the setup and
examples which I was I'm going to go
over in this talk but yeah here is it
one more time so um time block Was A
cryptographic Primitive that lets Alice
encrypt a message into the future say uh
Alice wants to send a message M to Bob
Alice puts this in a Time Block Puzzle
and gives it to Bob
Bob will be unable to open this time
lock puzzle Before Time t uh two Key
properties which we want from the time
log puzzles are first uh it should be
easy for Alice to generate a time lock
puzzle and um even if Bob implies
parallel strategies Bob should not be
able to open up open the time lock
puzzle anytime before d
um panel business have found
applications and uh timed commitments
auctions blockchains and many more
applications continue to emerge
um unfortunately uh existing time lock
puzzles have a key drawback first it
does not scale with multiple users say
uh in a setting like auction where you
have to open up multiple time lock
puzzles to figure out who the winner is
then
um with traditional time lock puzzles
you are stuck with opening one puzzle at
a time
um however uh matchable timeline puzzles
are just New Primitives introduced by
maloval.ly agarajan uh in in this uh in
this setting uh in in this in these
constructions uh you can combine many
individual time lock puzzles into a
single bashed puzzle and you can open up
the batch puzzle for the price of one
yeah um as mentioned by the other
speakers before um they also support a
homomorphic properties where you can in
fact perform computations inside uh the
bashed puzzle so um yeah the batch plan
block was the focus of this work uh and
there are two known um time lock puzzle
constructions one is based on the RSA
setting and the other one is based on
our class groups uh RSA based setting uh
RSA based construction does not does
require a trusted setup on the other
hand class groups based construction
does not required uh however uh both of
these constructions suffer are two
drawbacks first one is these
constructions required on a priority
Bond on the batch size meaning someone
even before they generate a puzzle they
should uh they should know the total
number of puzzles that could be bashed
in this setting and uh and which is a
which is a drawback because you can't do
unbounded batching another drawback is
um
the uh the puzzle slices in these
settings are
um are linear in the number of number of
uh uh people in the in the batch set in
the batch size so um you're stuck with
large puzzle sizes uh in these
constructions so um we ask in this book
can we build a batchable uh uh time lock
puzzle that has transparent setup can
support Unbound and batching and uh and
uh and has puzzle size independent asked
uh the batch size
yeah so why do we care about a time lock
puzzle with these properties so the
first crucial
um
uh and these app these time lockers have
applications in the context of
decentralized setting uh especially in
uh payment consensus and mme prevention
and so on so um yeah uh considered in a
permissionless setting um these
properties are off the bat useful so
first we don't know uh number of nodes
that are there in the system and uh and
it's also impractical to rely on a
trusted setup uh moreover you are stuck
with large puzzle sizes in the previous
constructions and that increases the
communication overhead as well so uh our
contributions are as follows so we
introduce a new time lock puzzle which
has which is matchable has transparent
setup and has uh can do unbounded
matching and has compact password size
however we use indistinguishability
obfuscation so uh this makes it a
feasibility result and we see that there
are no fundamental barriers in achieving
a construction like this and we leave
the task of coming up with a efficient
construction to future work so
these time lock puzzles are useful in
conferences and especially uh they solve
to long-standing open problems first one
is in the context of permissionless
setting so uh in this setting uh uh this
in the setting it's called as mobile
sluggish model where it's a weaker
notion of a synchrony where the messages
can get delayed uh uh and in this
setting we can we show that uh we can
achieve the first permissionless
protocol and we also uh build the first
round uh expected uh oauth one around
Byzantine broadcast under strongly
adaptive and uh current majority setting
so um this is going to be the outline
for the rest of my talk I'm going to
introduce the preliminaries that are
required to realize our construction I'm
going to tell you how we build our time
log puzzle and then I'm going to explain
how we can use uh this time lock puzzle
uh
and and permissionless setting so um
first jumping into the preliminaries
being the first building block which we
need is homomorphic time lock puzzles so
homomorphic time lock puzzles are these
mice Primitives say you have uh time
Mark poses for message M1 and you have a
time lock puzzle for message M2 these
puzzles let you come add these up
together and come up with a new time
lock puzzle which is for the message M1
plus M2 and some a solver has to spend
time only opening this bashed puzzle to
get the values uh um the summation of
these values out of it for the price of
one they don't have to open M1 and M2
separately
um the second key building block which
we want the uh we use is key homomorphic
to the random functions say a function f
is uh key homomorphic pseudo random then
this has this nice property with if you
take the prf of message M under key K1
and if you add it with the prf of
message M under key K2 this is same as
the prf of message M under K1 plus K2
yeah so uh jumping into how our
construction works so uh in a
traditional time log puzzle you'll be
sending around a group element as a time
lock puzzle but in our setting uh since
we use IO we send around obfuscated
programs so let's say in the setting
player I watched player player I sends
out an obfuscated program bi so um what
to tell you more about how this program
works first this program takes in uh and
the size of the batch as an input it has
two key elements inside the circuit so
first one is uh this is the message Mi
that the player I wants to put it in the
Pam lock puzzle that's that's hardwired
inside the circuit and also the uh the
prf key which which we use that's also
hardwired uh enter this circuit so um
when someone runs this program with bot
size n uh it spits out
uh important uh two outputs the first
one is it's going to spit out a time
lock puzzle off the key Ki and it's
going to give another uh Vector which is
a structured Vector of ciphertext so
what it's essentially going to do is
it's going to uh take the prf uh under
the key Ki for position one so we put
plugin value one and get the prf value
out of it and you we do this for all the
positions in the vector however at
position I uh we also mask it with the
value or the message that has to be
encoded here so that's going to be RMI
so uh with this uh this is how somebody
generates a puzzle in our setting so uh
once you have these puzzles so the
question comes about how do you do how
do you open up these puzzles in a
matched manner so um uh um uh so to do
back solving so first the solver gets
the program p12 in this example there
are three uh batch three batch sizes
three the the solver gets these programs
first the solver runs the program P1
gets the two values out of it uh K1 and
that's a TLP of the key K1 and the
master ciphertext Vector it does this
for the player number two Justice for
play number three and so on so you can
see that uh the M1 is appropriately set
in uh in position one M2 is in position
two M3 in position three and so on so
once uh the solder has computed these
values so using the homomorphic
properties of the time lock puzzle we
can just sum them up sum up dot or
timelock puzzles to get a new time log
puzzle which is summation of the keys
which that were used in the individual
time lock puzzles and uh we call this KK
start and the proof and the solar also
um sums up these uh individual vectors
that was generated uh position y element
wise so you end up with summation of
multiple prf values plus message M1 and
position one summation of prf values on
under position two with message M2 and
so on with SH M3 yeah I'll so from now
on I'm going to focus only on the stuff
which is on the rightmost corner so I'm
going to copy these values to the next
slide so in this slide so first we
exploit the homomorphic properties of
the prf so uh essentially uh when
earlier this was the summation of PR of
values but the the mice property about
homomorphism lets us take the summation
inside the prf so it's going to be a
summation of keys rather than summation
of prf values so uh we can do this for
um all the positions in the vector and
you Mr you end up with a vector that
looks something like uh this on left so
now we go about opening the time lock
puzzle by spending time T you open the
time Block Puzzle and you come up with
the key case start once you have this
key K star uh
once you have this key case start so the
solver runs the prf under PK start and
position I position two position one
position two and purchase position three
and so on and then can come up with
another Vector uh as I show uh and if I
show it here so once you compute this
this Vector we can simply subtract it
from the previous vector and get the
message M1 M2 and M3 so uh that's how
you recover the message uh messages from
the uh from the timeline puzzle so um
jumping into how we use our time lock
puzzles so um a brief uh context so in
the permissionless setting we do not
know the number of nodes that are there
in the system and we do there is no
authentication mechanism between nodes
and nodes have to communicate with each
other over uh unauthenticated channels
so um Nakamoto contents this was this
breakthrough result where you they
should shown that you could do this you
can achieve permissionless consensus and
they use
proof of work and the key idea here is
the longest chain always spins that's
the the governing principle behind how
Nakamoto consensus Works
um prior books have shown that Nakamoto
consensus is secure only in the
synchronous model of communication
um so uh just the overview of how it all
buys together so in the synchronous
model of communication uh you assume
that all honest messages have an upper
Bond Delta so this is the time it takes
for any honest message to get a
delivered to another honest person uh
and uh and and and and and synchronous
model you assume that every player knows
the Delta and even the protocol designer
knows the Delta
um but if you assumes if you make such
assumptions you know that you you know
that you can achieve permissionless
consensus which was considered to be a
difficult problem in the past
um however um the topic of synchronous
model is it's exceedingly optimistic so
we deployment to consensus on the
internet but expecting uh you have
synchronous communication is something
it's excitingly optimistic
um
other models of communication are
partially synchronous and asynchronous
model of communication so in this we
don't assume that there's an own Delta
uh for the honest messages and uh of
course
um when you make stuff when you assume
that you can't do that then uh there are
impossibility results to say that you
cannot achieve permissionless consensus
by Ellen true and Raphael pass uh but
partialist synchronous and uh
asynchronous model uh capture the
realities of the internet much closely
than the synchronous Network so can we
have the best of both worlds for the
long lingering question and uh um go at
all and later by Andrew ham and I'll
propose this new model called um a
sluggish model of communication where
the honest parties are of two kinds
first one is the prompt one those nodes
follow the protocol to the dot and also
have synchronous communication
you also have another kind of harness
node called sluggish node these sluggish
nodes follow the protocol but for
gardeners they are suffering Network
Jitters and bunch of other network
problems but they are unable to uh
satisfy synchrony so uh the question
which we ask in this work are can we
achieve permissionless consensus in the
presence of mobile sluggage faults so uh
one way to think about these models are
are uh through the uh through the power
of the adversary and the synchronous
model the adversary can read the
messages but cannot stop them but can at
most delay them by Delta and partially
synchronous or asynchrony uh the address
so you can read the messages can delay
them for a really really long time and
the model sluggage model you kind of
have a mix of these two things
um yeah uh to get to give an overview of
what we do in this book so uh we modify
Nakamoto consensus to achieve uh uh
using time lockers as we modify it to
achieve our consensus in the mobile
sluggish model so um the key idea here
is we timelock encrypt any message
someone sends in this network so since
the
um messages are time locked with uh the
duration to be uh the synchrony value
the Delta here so um the adversity is
now forced to open the time lock to see
what's inside the inside uh what's
inside the uh the message so um uh that
inherently forces the adversary either
to deliver the message or take time to
open it and see what's happening here
um however
um a key drawback in Nakamoto style
Protocols are there's only one person
who is transmitting a message at any
given time so you need to have some sort
of a decoy mechanism where even the
non-block vendors are creating enough
message cover for someone who is the
block winner so that the adversary
doesn't know who is sending the block or
who is sending ID card so in this case
the adversary is now first to randomly
pick its victims without knowing
um without knowing the contents long
story short we modify an automotive
conferences in such a way that the
adversary doesn't know what's inside a
message and it has to arbitrarily pick
some uh messages to stop and uh and we
use time lock puzzles that helps uh to
get around
um the challenges first by adversary so
um to tell you more about decoy so
decoys are essentially a dummy time lock
puzzle messages it's going to give tower
for the honest uh person who has just
mined a block uh however and as I said
in the permissionless setting we don't
know who is there in the system so this
is prone to civil attacks so uh we just
like Nakamoto contractors we use a proof
of work to get around this problem so um
so let's say that when you have a
payload in Nakamoto consensus you just
compute the hash of it and if it falls
in some windows 0 to D1 then you say
that you have mined a block that's how
it goes about so we just use the two for
one trick which uh was used in the past
in food chains career at all and so on
so what we do is if the hash faults in
another bucket D1 to D2 which is much
easier than mining a block but at the
same time it's not too easy enough for
the adversary can flood the network uh
we say that if someone Falls in this
bucket then it's going to they have
mined a decar in this uh exam so in this
in the setting so uh to give you a high
level overview of what uh and a
simplified version of our protocol uh
our protocol proceeds in two phases the
first phase is where you mine blocks or
a decoy if you're lucky you stumble upon
it and of course you first pick the
longest chain uh then your time lock and
trip whatever you find and you keep the
messages those messages with you uh
right now then when you enter the solve
phase you multicast the puzzles uh
multicast the puzzle you have it could
either be a decoy or a block or if if I
was unlucky I wouldn't have anything but
we said the parameters and such a way
that with good probability if you are
able to mine at least one of the other
uh then you multicast these uh these
time lock puzzles and um Everybody
relieves these puzzles they batch open
uh using our time log primitive which I
introduced uh in the previous section
and you extend the chain and you keep on
doing this so um here is an example a
contrived example of how this happens so
uh in this example um these four miners
are trying to add a third block to the
to the blockchain so what they do here
is um
first um they enter the Mind phase they
start a timer
um Everybody tries to mine a decoy or
block in this example uh except the
third Miner everyone else is in lock uh
mines are D Coin but the third minor
mines uh uh mines are a block so once
they have uh their respective messages
uh they go about time lock encrypting it
um
uh whatever they have and they wait for
the Mind phase to end so now they get
into the solve phase so at the at the
beginning of the solve phase first thing
you do is you send out all the messages
you are you have so uh in this case a is
sending its messages to everybody in
this in this thing minor number two is
sending it to others in this case minor
three is doing it and minor four is
doing it so uh at the end of the day
everybody should have had uh received
those messages and if the uh adversary
would have stopped some message you
wouldn't have received it but
unfortunately adversary cannot see what
is inside the uh inside these uh time
lock puzzles without spending time on it
so once you have these individual
puzzles you spend time
you uh you bash them using our matching
property so you can come up with a
single puzzle and you can uh and you can
uh spend time opening just the one
puzzle you have and figure out who the
winner of the puzzle is so with this you
can find out who the winner is and you
can keep on doing this for other blocks
in this uh for other blogs in this
manner so uh and and somebody we
presented a new time lock puzzle which
has cool properties then we developed
the first permission let's show or show
the first permissionless protocol on the
mobile sluggish model and uh in the
paper we also show an attack on
locomotor consensus in the mobile
sluggish model and uh another word which
I didn't get to talk about was we show
how to do uh we build a generic compiler
that can convert any weekly adaptive
broadcast protocol into a strongly
Adaptive One so here's strong says that
uh the adversary can look at the message
can delete any message from the network
even when it was sent by a node that was
harnessed so it's much higher culture
power of adversary we build a compiler
that can convert any weekly adaptive
protocol into strongly adapter one and
we should give the um the first expected
non-constant uh Byzantine broadcast on
the strongly adaptive and majority
Corruptions but the highlight of these
uh broadcast works are you don't even
have to use the TLP from our paper you
can use any batchable time lock puzzles
to uh to do it uh and so you can fun
fact realize it in practice uh yeah
that's it I'll stop and take questions
and I apologize for the animations I'm
not sure why it was just zooming out and
off yeah
thanks questions
foreign
so can you can you say a little bit more
about this generic compiler so um this
isn't and uh um uh um we use a random
Oracle model so essentially it takes any
message one sent in a weekly adapter one
we put it in a Time log and uh we send
it send them around the challenges and
when how do you prove that this is in
fact correct and uh we show in the paper
how to do it nicely uh uh yeah um this
is a long-standing open problem where
you want to figure out however a oau of
one or own complexity is that that's in
the sluggish model right no no that's
not an isolated model so there are two
independent results yeah okay yeah
other questions
all right I guess uh let's thank the
speaker and that's the end of the
session
thank you