today I'm happy to open the last session
for today so it will be a session on
isogenes we will have sweet talks the
first one is about some
fisherman problem
so the talk is entitled scan up scaling
the sea fish
it's a work by Luca de fero Taco Boris
fosa beta kutas
is here
yes
thanks a lot Serge for the introduction
thank you everyone for attending the
isog session
I'm gonna talk about our recent work
scallop scaling the sea fish
this is a talk about cryptographic group
action can you actually hear me all
right yeah
um this is a talk about cryptographic
group actions what is a group action
it's it's a function on a set
um where where G is a group which acts
on the set and certain axioms are
satisfied namely that the identity
element of the group acts trivially and
that if you act with a product on the
group it it is the same as if yet
consecutively with the factors of this
product
now it's quite easy to see how to get a
diffie-hellman style key exchange from a
group action if if it's a commutative
group that acts you just fix a set
element in the beginning and then you
have Alice in Bob both take the secret
group element they just act on this uh
fixed starting element and then exchange
the resulting set elements act again as
long as your group is commutative they
should arrive at the same set element in
the end and
um well
this can be used as your shared secrets
now the
the problem that resembles the discrete
logarithm problem in this context is
called usually the vectorization problem
so if you're given two set elements you
want to find the group element that act
that Maps one to the other
and the parallelization problem is the
one that resembles the computational the
human problem
um this is quite a powerful framework
um so if these problems are hard even
for a quantum computer then this gives
rise to a post Quantum secure key
exchange
um
probably the most prominent one is the
seaside key exchange which is also like
a non-interactive key exchange very
powerful tool to build other post
Quantum constructions and this talk is
going to introduce yet another
um post Quantum group action that gives
you even more properties
but
what could you actually ask for more in
the than the seaside I mean it's it's a
very cool group action you can you can
build a lot with it
um well if we start just see site is not
an effective group action what does that
mean you cannot actually evaluate it on
all the group elements of your acting
group uh the truth is Seaside
you you can only evaluate it on certain
uh
fixed elements of your acting group and
um
this is for many constructions not a
problem namely uh you just restrict
yourself to a a list of elements I'll
want to end that span your acting group
and for which you can efficiently
evaluate the group action and then
in practice you just evaluate on product
of the of these elements just by
consecutively evaluating the group
action this this is called the
restricted effective group action which
is as many of you will know quite
powerful but there's some constructions
where you would like to evaluate your
group action
on all the elements and where you want
to have a unique representation of every
group element for example and
for example this is very useful to build
uh for hme style efficient signatures
um but Seaside doesn't give you that so
is there a way to transform a restricted
effective group action into a effective
group action
yes there is a general strategy you can
pre-compute the group structure of the
acting group
um so that means you pre-compute for
example the cardinality of a group and
you pre-compute something that's called
the lattice of relations so if you have
your generators from the previous slide
these L1 to LM that span the entire
group you look for vectors in the
exponents such that L1 to the LI to the
e i the products of those act trivially
so um the exponents give you like a
vector well each each one of these
relations gives you a vector if you
consider all of them that's the lattice
and this lattice is called the lattice
of relations
if your compute the reduced basis of
such a lattice that uh
allows you to solve CVP instances
efficiently then this can help you to
evaluate the group action everywhere
namely assume you have for example L1 to
a very large power e in in fact the the
groups we're interested in are usually
cyclic or nearly cyclic so you can
assume that if you can solve this
problem you can kind of evaluate the
group action everywhere now if you just
want to straightforward with your
restricted group actually evaluate this
is not going to work because for a large
exponent if you have to do it
consecutively it's just going to take
too long
but what you can do is you just solve
the approximate CVP problem in your
lattice of relations uh so you look for
a lattice
Vector
that is close to e followed by zeros in
this case so that that gives you a
decomposition or a product l i to the e
i that acts in the same way on on your
set
such that the exponents are small and
well now you can just use your
restricted group action to evaluate it
the caveat of course with this idea is
that depending on the group G you may
not be able to actually pre-compute its
group structure
and in fact for the groups that we have
in Seaside for example the the groups
are notoriously known to be very hard to
compute
however this this strategy was uh used
by Berlin's Klein young and
outerman in 2019 to build efficient
isogeny based signatures there they just
took the seaside 512 action that is the
smallest Seaside parameter set group
action
pre-computed the lattice of relations
with an index calculus approach and then
uh
basically that the strategy from the
previous slide
now the the group action of of Seaside
is a class group action so this these
class groups are uh well hard to compute
and to compute the structure of this
group they did a world record class
group computation so this was the the
biggest class group ever computed to
just get the smallest parameter set of
Seaside uh in into this effective group
action framework
uh unfortunately it doesn't scale very
well so Computing the structure of
larger Seaside parameter sets is firmly
Out Of Reach with the currently known
algorithms and computational resources
um so this was the motivation for our
work can we build a different group
action from misogynist in our case that
solves this scaling issue can we somehow
build effective group actions for larger
parameter sets
uh uh and that's yeah that scale at
least to some extent
um so to answer this questions let look
a little bit at what the seaside group
action actually is
so
for group actions on exogenes you have a
imaginary quadratic order you can think
of it as like some as that square root
of minus P for Prime p
and then you consider as your Set uh
that you act on certain elliptic curves
um these elliptic curves have
endomorphism rings that is uh the
isogenes that you have from a curve to
itself and they have a certain structure
there are orders in a quaternity in
algebra but each of them also has many
embeddings of of different quadratic
borders into them so it turns out that
um those elliptic curves that have an
embedding of some fixed imaginary
quadratic Border in them
um you can act upon by invertible ideals
of this imaginary quadratic order
principal principle ideals act trivially
so this gives rise to a well-defined
group action of the class group the
class group is just the set of all
invertible ideals of your imaginary
photographic order divided out by the
principal ideals
um
on the set and now Seaside is the
special case where you take the
imaginary quadratic border Z squared of
minus p and you consider a curse that
are defined over FP the finite field
over FP
um
and square root of minus p is under this
embedding this embedding is called the
orientation is mapped to the frobenius
endomorphism which is well defined of
over curves defined over the base
now this raises the question if we
cannot compute the class group for for
this order the class this the structure
of this class group for larger parameter
sets can we maybe do it for different
imaginary quadratic borders
um but if we do so can we then still
evaluate the group action like we know
it exists but can we compute with it how
do you represent stuff um this is one
question we answer in our paper for one
family of of group actions but
why would we want to do that why why do
we want to use a different quadratic
order
the reason is that for certain quadratic
borders you can compute the a class
group of it uh more easily if you have a
imaginary quadratic border of the form
that plus a conductor that's called the
conductor F times uh what imaginative
quadratic order of which you know their
class group or the class number like the
cardinality of your class group then you
can
compute the class number just from the
factorization of
so that's that's a simple formula you
don't have to do some huge computation
for that
so our strategy was
um we just take a a class group that has
a trivial
um with X trivially so class number one
and then we generate certain candidates
or generators of a larger class group
uh larger imaginary quadratic order
sorry
um and compute the the conductor and if
it's Prime well then we know it's
factorization we can easily compute the
class
plus strap well not the class structure
but the class number sorry
um and
we just sieve over these candidates
until we find one class group that has
reasonably smooth class numbers so the
cardinality is divisible by many
small factors
now this is where our approach is also
not super scalable right you still need
to sieve through many candidates until
you find a reasonably smooth number if
you just model this as a like a
the class number as being like a random
number of a certain size
um but if you have found one that is
reasonably smooth then we can compute
the lattice of relations just by solving
this instances of the discrete logarithm
problem in your class group uh because
well if it's reasonably smooth you can
solve this pretty log problems
then the rest is as similar as was done
previously in C fish namely you just
compute A reduced basis this is also
fine in our case because the dimensions
we deal with
this is not going to be the bottleneck
of the computation
and finally we need to instantiate the
group action with the starting curve you
need to find something to start acting
on this is not as straightforward as it
is in Seaside where you just take some
curve defined over FP
um but instead you uh yeah we give a
solution for this in our page and this
is also efficient
now to actually compute the online phase
I said earlier we generate the imaginary
quadratic order to have a smooth
generator this smooth generator under
the embedding into the endomorphism ring
corresponds to an endomorphism of smooth
degree and these are nomorphisms you can
you can represent you can write down a
the representation of it in in terms of
its kernel
and this endomorphism plays the same
role that the forbino's anamorphism
plays in Seaside namely it stabilizes
the kernel of the isogenes used to
compute the group action
now on the right side you see the
isogeny graph involved so all the curves
on the outside are the ones that
essentially you walk on in our group
action and they are all connected to one
group with a trivial group action in the
middle and lines
represent a large degree exogeny of
degree f
now
you can evaluate this group action
similar to Seaside by Computing certain
isogenes that's Maps between elliptic
curves for this talk
um the drawback here is that you have to
transport your orientation so this
endomorphism along the curves so there's
some additional computation you have to
do compared to Seaside where you have
this as an implicit feature
um already available and that's also why
our support action is a bit slower
uh so let's just look at the like a
brief comparison of sea fish and scallop
our two isogeny based effective group
action
one has a fixed imaginary quadratic
border the Z squared of minus p
whereas in scallop we can instantiate
all sorts of imaginary quadratic orders
of this form that plus some Prime Times
a like in our case is it's the gaussian
integers the o0
um whereas while in C fish you have to
do this very expensive class group
action which only allows you to compute
the class group for the smallest
parameter sets and afterwards it's
infeasible
um in in scallop you get the class
number so the cardinality of the group
for free
um but you then have to do some sieving
until there's class numbers smooth
enough to compute the slabs of relations
asymptotically both of these steps are
unfortunately actually have the same
complexity but in practice the constant
is much slower so even moderate
resources we managed to instantiate
larger security levels with a scallop
um the evaluation in sea fish is with
these this implicit orientation by the
frobinus endomorphism and is quite
efficient unfortunately our group action
is less efficient because you have to
compute this explicit orientation along
the evaluation
um we implemented our group action in C
plus and it's available under this link
um more precisely we gave a concrete
instantiation for scallop that matches
the security levels of Seaside 512 and
seaside 1024 just a reminder Seaside 20
1024 would be absolutely infeasible with
the sea fish type of computation
the public keys of our group action
[Music]
um
are roughly 1600 bits for the smaller
parameter sets and 2300 bits for the
larger one that's still quite compact
it's larger than the seaside ones um but
that's not the not the main problem
what's a bit more annoying is that the
evaluation of the group action for the
small parameter sets takes 35 seconds
and for the larger ones 12 and a half
minutes for our parameter sets and to
for example build signatures from this
you would need dozens of these group
action and allegations
so in summary this implementation shows
more the feasibility of our group action
than well that's the practice that is
practicality
so in summary we provide a framework to
evaluate new group actions um
unoriented elliptic curves by isogenes
we give very concrete instantiation for
class group actions using this uh
imaginary quadratic orders of prime
large Prime conductor into in a
imaginary quadratic field of small
discriminant this is what's what we call
scallop and this instantiates
um effective group actions for larger
security levels that were previously Out
Of Reach
and allows you to build schemes that
where you have to uniquely represent
elements and efficiently act by
arbitrary group elements
which gets us through the questions so
the obvious ones is how can we make this
group action more practical is it faster
and scallop still has a scaling issue
um we can do larger security levels but
they clock out eventually maybe there's
a way to resolve that thank you for your
attention you will find a lot more
details in the paper and I'm happy to
take questions
uh thanks for the interesting talk um I
wonder the uh the smoothness of the
class group order does it have any
implications for the hardness of the
like the discrete log problem or
whatever the analog is I think you call
it vectorization problem
um for the class group action we don't
think so no
um
of course it immediately influences how
hard it is to compute the lattice of
relations right the more smooth it is
you more easy it is to compute the
um
the the lattice um but yeah no we don't
think that it has security implications
on the actual class production
thanks
and here's a question
thank you for a nice talk
um I seem to recall that Seaside has
this Gap structure where you can like
you have uh the underlying uh assumption
Gap CDH
in pre-quantum cryptography which you
which is hard notoriously hard to find
in post Quantum cryptography do you know
if uh scallop also has this I think
Seaside was the only one previously
known to have this Gap structure
um what do you mean by the cap structure
so uh with access to a decisional Oracle
uh the computational problem should
still be hard
yes I think so yeah I mean it's it's
pretty much the same thing
um
one
I think it's it's a very similar problem
so if you abstract away a lot of the
structure they you get the same like
General problem
um
that makes sense yeah thank you
I think say what's another question in
your back yes
oh just a question that you you were
mentioning that that you uh that you
take the uh the maximal order to have a
cluster number one to to um to to sieve
right so why why is it that you could
also use another small one or one one
that is known we just um we started
working with gaussian integers and they
they on one curve uh you have like a
real class group action there
[Music]
um
I'm not sure you gain anything by taking
a larger one that's maybe interesting I
don't know I don't think so there's only
finally many right with class number one
so at some point uh you want to uh to
have a bit more uh no but this is just
your like uh if you look at the isogeny
graph that I had here so the one that
has action of class number one is the
one middle curve and then basically the
curves that are actually where you
compute the group action are the ones on
the outside Circle so ones that are
connected by a large degree exogeny
um and if
the degree is large enough you can
basically reach many many curves and it
depends on the con conductor which
curves you actually reach to compute
your class group action on
um so I don't think it really matters
which curve you have in the middle
um
like think think of sidh you have like a
starting curve in the beginning with a
lot of structure but then you you walk
away into all sorts of directions until
you reach curves far away
just that in our case it's not a smooth
degree asserting but a large Prime
um
yeah I don't know whether this answers
to your question yeah and I was just to
find to find
um the this uh
um the disorder from the maximum from
the maximum order that it was starting
from a maximum order of class number one
yes so I was wondering was the technical
but anyways to exist
um so okay if you have one that's
sufficient okay okay fine
okay if there is no other question let's
thank the speaker again
so next we have a round optimal
oblivious transfer and MPC from a
computational Seaside
she
[Music]
is
Patrick Patrick
is here sorry for uh Miss Francis
uh hi my name is pratik today I'm going
to talk about round optimal oblivious
transfer and MPC from computational
Seaside so this is a joint work with Sai
Krishna badrinarayanan Daniel masmine
pratha Mukherjee Shikhar patanovis and
srinivas and raghuraman so this work was
done when all of us were at Visa
research and now we are in different
places only srini is left in Visa so
yeah so uh let me first introduce what
is MPC and OT and then I'll go into the
constructions
so I will talk about uh secure two body
computation so there's two parties who
have their private inputs X and Y so
they want to compute a function f on
their private inputs to do that they run
a protocol over here and it satisfied
that the protocol output should be same
as function output well security says
that the protocol should not leak
anything about X and Y beyond the output
now a more specific uh two-party
protocol is
OT so this OT primitive there's a sender
who has input messages m0 M1 and there's
a receiver she has a choice bit B and
now the OT protocol uh outputs MB to the
receiver so security says that the
sender should not know B and the
receiver should not know what is M1
minus B so this is a very simple
primitive in the two-party setting and
this is a very interesting primitive
because we know that around optimal OT
gives you around optimal MPC so just if
you just build this OT primitive you can
go all the way up to NPC which is a more
generalized version of 2 PC so that's
why we are going to focus on this round
optimal OT in this talk
and in the stock our focus is OT product
protocols in setup model and plane model
which are around optimal so in the setup
model round optimality means two rounds
and in the plane model is four rounds so
that's why um I'm saying round optimal
and then simulation security as in you
need indistinguishability-based security
and also you will be able to extract
akara party's input so that's what
simulation security means and finally we
will try to construct it from weak
isogeny based assumptions we will mainly
construct it from computational suicide
and by applying the results of benmuda
atol and
gargeton we will get MPC in setup model
and clean modern uh satisfying the same
properties which our Roti protocol will
satisfy
so now uh let me talk about our
contributions and compare with state of
the art
so in this work in this talk I'm going
to focus on the seaside based protocols
I'm not going to talk about the sidh
based protocols so in the seaside based
protocols there's three Works which
construct two round
OT protocols in the setup model mainly
CRS and CRS plus random molecule model
and they satisfy UC security but they
rely on this diffusional Seaside
assumption so it's like a ddh variant of
Seaside then there's a recent work in
eurocrypt 21 by lie at all so they
construct a foreground protocol from
reciprocal Seaside so this is a
um a Quantum equivalent to computational
Seaside so they rely on CRS plus random
molecule but they are not round optimal
because they require four rounds and
finally there's a recent work by
orphania at all uh which came out I
think last month so they rely on
discrete log C side
um which is like the one-wayiness of
Seaside but they rely on knowledge of
exponent assumption for the reduction
and they are around optimal but they
only obtain relaxed UC security because
they get knowledge of exponent
assumption and finally in this work we
build from computational suicide which
we wanted to go and we get it in two
rounds so we actually get UC security so
this is a typo this will be UC and we
get it in the CRS plus random Oracle
model
so our contributions is as follows uh in
the setup model we obtain a two round UC
rot in CRS plus random Oracle from
computational Seaside
and we also obtain MPC by applying the
results of bl18 and gs18
and now I'm gonna talk about uh our
results in the plane model so in the
plane model there are three Works uh
which obtain
OT protocols so this uh word by alamati
at all they are two rounds they they
only obtain semantic security they don't
get simulation security so they only
have indistinguishivity-based security
where you get Center privacy and
receiver privacy but not extraction so
uh this is not full simulation so that's
why they can do two rounds and there are
words uh there's a work in TCC last year
where we construct a four round OT
protocol in the plane model and we get
full simulation security and as a result
we get MPC and this is four round this
round optimal in the plane model and
there's a work by uh kurana at all which
uh by applying the result of admp20 you
can get a four round plane model OT from
decision on C side so as you can see the
literature is open for computational
free site and in this work uh we
construct a four round plane model OT
and MPC from uh in from computational C
side uh so this is our second
contribution so we get a four round OT
protocol in plane model uh which uh
simulation sound uh simulation secure
and from computational Seaside and we
also get MPC by applying the result of
bl18 and js18 and finally we also get a
we also show an OT extension in to show
some efficient results uh our base OT
requires four isogenic computations and
this protocol relies on reciprocal
Seaside which is computational
equivalent to computational Suicide uh
Quantum equivalent to competition C side
so these are our main contributions now
I'm gonna briefly talk about isogeneous
preliminaries
Simon has already introduced them in the
previous talk so this is a group action
a group action consists of a group and a
set and a function uh star over here
from the group and set to the set and
you need an identity element such that e
star X is equal to X and the group has
to be a billion and also g dot h start X
should be G star a star X and
um for any two set elements x and x
Prime there exists a unique G in the
group such that G Star X is X Prime
um next uh there's uh something called
effective group action which Simon
introduced in the last talk that is you
can efficiently compute G Star X for any
G comma X in G cross X and you have
efficient a guy instantiations from
Seaside with known group structure and C
fish and this is not broken due to the
recent attacks on its ideas family of
isogenes there's also another
abstraction called rega which is regular
group action and in our protocols do
work in that
regular group action framework but in
this talk I'm not gonna talk about it
due to uh to keep it simple
uh so these are the computational
assumptions so first is the discrete log
C side assumption or the one-way AGA so
given a random group element G from and
a set element x uh and given X comma G
Star X it is computationally invisible
to compute G so this is like one Venus
and then you have the weak unpredictable
AGA uh which is like the computational C
side so this is somewhat like the CDH
variant of C side so here given G and H
and X comma G Star X and H star X you
cannot compute like an adversary
computationally bounded adversary
compute G Star g dot h start X so this
is the computational C side or like the
CDH variant or C side so our Protocols
are in this uh from this assumption now
the second one
so now I'm gonna talk about our OT
protocol in the setup model
so we start off with the two round semi
honest OT protocol so here uh we assume
that the sender and the receiver will
follow the OT protocol like when if when
it's corrupted by a adversary so in the
CRS you have three set elements x x 0
and X1 and now the receiver has choice
would be it samples a random group
element R and it computes the first OT
message as R star XB it sends over this
Z to Sender now the sender computes two
random paths by sampling k0 K1 from the
group and capital y 0 if K 0 star x0 and
capital Y 1 is k1 stud X1 and then the
sender uses this k0 and K1 the
randomness to encrypt the messages m0
and M1 so the sender computes t0 and T1
which is Hash of k0 star v x or m0 and
T1 is Hash of K1 star Z Exon M1 so this
H is random Oracle and now the center
just sends y 0 y 1 and t 0 t 1 to the
receiver
now the receiver can compute uh MB which
is cbxr Hash of R star y b so just given
this Randomness R and y y b and TV it
can compute MB so if you work out the
algebra then you can find out that MB is
what it is so this thing works out and
to argue that the receiver's choice
would be is hidden from a corrupt sender
we can show that this choice would be
statistically hidden so assume that b is
equal to 1 that means V is R star X1 and
you can also write it as R Prime Star x0
where R Prime is a function of the
trapdos of the CRS so R Prime can be
written as r g 1 G 0 inverse so you can
express Z as both and
um both as a first message corresponding
to bit 0 and bit one so that's why the
choice bit is hidden and now for
standard privacy we can show that if the
receiver computes M1 minus B then you
can break uh the weak unpaintable AGA
property and for the reduction we need
to extract the r this R from a corrupt
receiver
so this is semi honest and now to make
it malicious uh we need we can show that
uh this this protocol already satisfies
security against a malicious sender that
is you can extract m0 on M1 when the
sender is malicious but when the
receiver is malicious you cannot extract
B and R because recall that it was
statistically hidden from so we need
some additional Primitives to get uh
input extraction for a malicious
receiver
so to do that uh we introduce I mean we
uh get help from the literature we use
the the firmative called non-interactive
witnessing distribution proof of
knowledge or navy so here there's
approver who has an NP statement tax and
witness W and the verifier has the same
entry statement X and now the webrover
sends a proof called Pi which is uh
there exists W such that X comma W is in
the relation and now the completeness
says that verified outputs want if x and
W is in the relation soundness says that
if X is not in the relation then verify
output 0 and witnessing distribution
says that if Pi 0 and Pi 1 are computed
using two different Witnesses then Pi 0
and Pi 1 are indistinguishable and proof
of knowledge says that witness can be
extracted from an activity group so we
are going to use this perimeter to get
security against malicious receiver
and we also build this from wiga in the
CRF model
so this was our uh semi honest protocol
from the previous slides and now we uh
uh like Incorporated these Navy
protocols where this receiver uses a
Navy to prove that it knows R such that
these are static 0 or these R star X1
and it sells the Navy proof and the
sender verifies the Navy proof now uh
coming back to receiver privacy and send
a privacy uh the receiver privacy
follows that choice would be
statistically hidden and the pi is uh
witnessing distinguishable that this
does not leak about whether it's from x0
or X1 so uh this is which is individual
and for sender privacy
we again uh relying on this pi to
extract the r
um and this relies on Pi sound and
extractable and then we reduce to our
semi honest sender privacy argument
and to do input extraction you can
extract from the Nui as I said before
and for standard input extraction uh you
use the CRS trapdoor to extract both m0
and M1 so this is our two round
malicious secure OT protocol in the
setup model
and yeah and now uh I'm gonna discuss
our plane model OT protocol so before
doing that I'm going to discuss the
interactive variants of nivi and zero
knowledge so in zero knowledge you again
have approver who has input statement X
and witness W and the verified as
statement X so it needs to satisfy
completeness soundness zero knowledge
and proof of knowledge says that a
witness W can be extracted from an
accepting proof and in addition we need
an additional property called delete
input that is only the last vka protocol
message depends on the approval's input
statement X so the first three protocol
messages are independent of X so this is
an important property for our protocol
and we build this from wiga as well and
next another primitive is delete input
wi proof of knowledge so this is same as
the interactive zero knowledge except
this is wi uh witness indistinguishable
and not zero knowledge and we need like
three rounds
and this has to be also delayed input
that is only the last wi protocol
message depends on the statement so this
is uh delayed input wi proof of
knowledge so using these two Primitives
we are going to build our plane model
ody protocol uh and we also build this
uh protocol from we AGA uh in the paper
and so this is our
two round semi honest protocol which is
like the first protocol so if you
remember the receiver had a choice would
be it computed uh r and v and it sent it
over and this was the second OT message
and x01 X1 was a CRS so in this
maliciously secured plane model OT
there's no CRS so the sender is supposed
to sample the CRS x01 X1 so this is
going to be ot2 message and now I am
going to briefly fill up the other four
OT messages
so first I am going to
incorporate the wi primitive from the
previous slide so you are using the
double interactive wi the receiver is
going to prove that it knows an R such
that these R start at 0 and Z is R star
X1 so re see that uh like the first two
messages are just like the
pre-processing or the uh like the here
we need the delayed input property of wi
because we don't require rely on the
statement over in this two first
messages so this is a three round delete
input wi which are using here and the
verifier will now verify the wi in the
third round and then it will compute the
fourth round which is like this to
second round of the semi honest OD
protocol and send it over
and then uh to prove uh for like now to
uh consider as malicious sender we need
to uh ensure that this x0 and X1 is
correct and we also need to extract the
g0 and G1 so that's why we use the
delayed input ZK protocol the zero
knowledge protocol which was four round
so the first three rounds are like
pre-processing independent of the
statement and the final round
protocol message from the sender to the
receiver is dependent on the uh
statement and it sends it over and the
receiver now verifies that so after it
verifies it now it computes the message
so this is our four round plane model OT
protocol which is nothing but the two
round semi honest protocol Plus or three
round wi and a four round V K so that's
how we can interpret our four round
malicious we secure OT protocol in the
plane model and now to argue input
privacy we can
see that b statistically hidden and the
wi and
I or what is B and this ZK protocol has
to be found uh and because if this uh x0
next one is badly computed then you
might be able to leak stuff
and finally uh and finally uh for sender
privacy if our compute M1 minus B then
we can make w a ga and we also rely on w
w i sound knowledge
and then for input extraction we extract
R from this uh Pi wi and we extract B
accordingly by setting Z dot x b and
finally for input uh sender input
extraction you extract g0 and G1 from
this um
and then you compute uh M1 and m0 using
the trapdos g0 and G1 so this is our uh
simulation security for the plane model
and finally we build these Primitives
from wa because there are known uh
constructions of these Primitives from
weaker Primitives like injectives
chapter one way function and
statistically hiding commitments two
rounds so you can build them from wa
so to conclude uh
uh we uh introduce we constructed the
first round optimal OT or MPC in the CRS
plus random molecule model from
computational Seaside we also built the
first round optimal OT plus MPC in plane
model from computational Seaside and we
also have a OT extension based on
reciprocal Seaside which is efficient
and to conclude with two open problems
uh can we build two-round computational
fee site based ucot which is like you
need extraction for corrupt receiver and
corrupt sender without relying on random
Oracle so in our paper we need the
random molecule to extract the r for the
reduction but that is not really
required for the simulation so can you
remove the random Oracle and still get a
ucot
and finally can you build a two round
ucot from computational Seaside where
you incur constant number of isogenic
competitions so our protocol uh recall
that has a new e inside it for the two
round malicious secure OT ucot and that
requires order of K isogenic
computations so that part is not
constant is so can you do that uh from I
mean yeah can you do that from
computational Seaside without uh
requiring security parameter number of
file functions so thank you
it's
uh thank you thank you for talk uh my
question is what's the difference
between UC security and simulation
security and which one is stronger uh
you think already definitely stronger uh
what's uh the UC security is definitely
stronger uh but in the plane model you
cannot get UC security
so
um simulation security is weaker uh if
that makes sense so you need some kind
of setup assumption to get UC security
uh but you cannot get that in the clean
model
okay
because I mean you have rewinding so
that is like you see incompatible maybe
we can talk
after let's and here's a question
okay so let's say you speak here again
okay
and the final talk for today is entitled
generic models for group actions by
Julia mon Dominique Hartman acre kills
Sabrina quartzweiler Shona sliman and
during Reaper and shonassi's here
whenever you're ready
all right can you hear me yes very good
all right so this will be yet another
talk on group actions
um so there will be some overlap with
the previous talks so bear with me here
um first let's start the talk with some
motivation and for this we take our
favorite characters Alice and Bob they
want to have a private communication
over an insecure Channel like the
internet and therefore they have to
assume that there might be a malicious
party Eve that eavesdrop on their
messages and may read the secret and of
course that's nothing that Alice and Bob
want
and of course we know how to solve this
problem right we can just use encryption
for this and as long as Alice and Bob
use the secure encryption scheme uh if
you cannot learn the messages and in
particularly not the secret
uh this has worked very well in the past
but since recently we know that there
exists this notion of a quantum computer
and in particular if Eve has access to
such a quantum computer then she can
um break almost all the public key
cryptography we use today in the
internet
um and of course then Alice and Pop's
messages are not secure anymore
um we know how to solve this problem
again
um we can use post Quantum secure
cryptography for this
and there exist various approaches to
this and I guess the most prominent one
is based on Nazis they have very very
favorable trade-offs they are very
flexible and they have been recently
standardized by the Mist so we are
pretty confident in their hardness and
in their security
however it's not completely ruled out
that there's not some clever math that
completely breaks that this is right you
can never be sure about that so what we
like to do is we like to diversify so we
want to build protocol space and
different assumptions such that if one
of them gets broken then the others
might not
and one of these popular alternatives
are cryptographic group actions
um they come again in various traits and
forms but the most popular ones are
based on misogynist and this talk will
be exactly about this cryptographic
group actions
um now let me quickly give you an
introduction to group actions you have
seen this already but bear with me here
so we first need a group for our group
action and also we need a set which we
call X and we assume that this set is
more or less structuralized and thirdly
we need a mapping which is called star
here in this case and this mapping
should fulfill some basic properties
um well first of all we take a group
element and settle them in X and this
mapping should map us to another set
element G times x
and of course the identity should act
trivially on the set so this is one
property
and we want compatibility with a group
operation this means that g times H
times x should be equal to g plus h
times x and I assume I see we use
additive notation in this talk so which
is a bit unusual but I hope you get
along
there are more properties but I will
skip them for for brevity here
and if you have no group action then you
can Define some pretty standard group
action assumptions uh the first one is
discrete lock so given X and G times x
the task is to compute the G
uh the second one is CDH so given given
x g times x and H times x tassels the
compute G plus h times x
and the third one is ddh so given x g
times x and H times x and some set
elements that decide whether that is g
plus h times x
and again these are pretty pretty
standard right
um we are we know of a Quantum algorithm
solving these um and in particular
solving discrete log which is the the
cooperberg algorithm it has
sub-exponential uh time complexity
um but this is thus far the best attack
we know so
uh we are pretty confident in the
hardness of these assumptions
uh however you can also Define some uh
non-standard assumptions in the group
action World
um for example a strong CDH
in strong CDH you are given basically a
CDH instance so it's very similar to CDH
um but you're given additionally access
to these oracles so these TDH oracles
where you might note that the the first
input is fixed
so it's not quite the Gap problem we we
talked about before but uh it's uh it's
very similar
and this is not a esoteric assumption I
came up with for this talk this actually
analyzed the uh the active security of
the seaside key exchange in the quantum
random Oracle model which we showed at
last year's Azure Crypt
uh so it's very very important
assumption
now secondly you can also Define strong
Spirit inverse CDH
um which says that while given X and G
times x the task is to come to compute
such a tuple here where the first input
y can be chosen by the adversary but uh
then the adversary also has to compute
2T times Y and minus 3 times y
and again the adversary has access to
these ddh oracles
and here again this analyzed the
security of the group action based
password authenticator key exchange from
crypto 2022 and also in some mild
variation analyze the security of the
group action based oblivious transfer
from Europe 21.
so here it's not really clear how hard
these problems are right because the
intuition is that these ddh oracles
shouldn't help you much when Computing
the CDH or when Computing this Tuple
here for example but you could also
imagine having Quantum access to these
oracles right and then it's really
unclear how hard these problems really
are and whenever you're faced with such
a situation at least in the prime order
group setting what you would do as well
if you cannot analyze them directly in
the standard model then it would Resort
back to the idealized models where the
analysis might be a bit easier and then
you get at least some confidence in
their hardness
um
of course these models don't exist in
the group action setting yet and that's
actually what this work is about so we
first Define the generic group action
model which is based on the generic
group model by Shoop
and here you can show that in some cases
this model is actually part of the
generic group model by Shoop
and also we can show classical lower
bonds for all these problems we saw
before like discrete log CDH and ddh
however note that classical here really
means non-quantum because we can further
show that Quantum lower bonds are
impossible at least in this model
and secondly we Define the algebraic
group action model which again is based
on the algebraic group model where
things are now much nicer in the quantum
setting because we can now Define give
classical and Quantum reductions between
these non-standard assumptions and
discrete blocks
all right so
um let's first start with the generic
group action model and here the idea is
that we give the adversary access to a
generic group action that has no further
structure now how do we do this well
we take our group action and also Define
a labeling function Sigma that maps from
the set X to some bit strings and this
labeling function is drawn uniformly at
random so
these labels are also uniformly random
and now by concatenating these two we
get a generic group action on these
labels and the the intuition now is that
while the adversary only sees these
labels and for the adversary it does not
matter whether the group action is
implemented via esogenes or codes
because he doesn't see the real set
elements anymore he just sees labels
that are uniformly random
so um uh he cannot come up with these
labels himself because the the labeling
function is part of the of the setup or
of the of the model so in particular he
cannot compute the group action himself
anymore
um
and this is of course an issue we can
resolve this by giving the adversary
Oracle access to the group action so
this Oracle or X to compute computes the
group action for him
and this works by appearing the Oracle
on a group element and a label for some
set element X
and uh the Oracle then returns a label
for the set element of G times x
and again the idea is that the adversary
cannot come up with this label himself
uh the only thing you can really do with
these labels is check for equality
now of course you could also extend this
model with further oracles but I will
not do this for the sake of Simplicity
here and lastly I want to mention that
this is an information theoretic model
so in particular we give the adversary
unlimited runtime and only bound the the
number of Oracle queries more or less
right so
he can do whatever he wants like
inverting hash functions solving lwe
but he cannot freely compute in the
group action anymore because that's
what's what we bound
and this really models that the only
source of hardness in this model comes
from this from this group action and in
particular this also means that we have
an easy discrete block problem in the
group G because the adversary has free
access to the group G and you can
compute discrete logs in as much time as
he wants and this also matches our
intuition because groups are inherently
pre-quantum right and we don't want any
hardness of the group action to come
from a group right
all right so that's the model what can
we show on this model well first of all
we can show that if the group order plus
one is prime then the generic group
model by Shoop actually contains our
generic group action model and uh this
condition here on the group order is a
bit weird
um but actually comes from the fact that
in the generic group model uh we have
a multiplicative structure in the
exponents right so if you exponentially
it multiple times then you get a
multiplicative structure and in our
model we have an additive group instead
which is for technical reasons and this
mismatch caused this this weight
condition here
now as an easy crawler we now get that
under this condition uh discrete log is
actually hard in in our model so for
every adversary a in our generic group
action model against discrete log we can
bound its success probability by Q
squared over n where Q is the number of
Oracle queries that is the runtime of
the adversary and N is the group order
and this is exponential so this in in
sum is negligible
um actually by adapting the same proof
techniques as in the GTM we can also
show that this holds unconditionally
even though the group order plus one is
not prime uh and then we essentially get
the same Bond there's some some constant
Factor here involved but uh for
Simplicity we we leave it out here
right what about the quantum version of
the the generic group model then group
action models sorry
well in theory this is uh this is easy
to Define right we just allow Quantum
access to to the Oracle however there
exists an algorithm by adding an huia
which is a generic Quantum algorithm
solving group action discrete log
um it takes exponential time which means
it's not a real threat to group actions
however it has only polynomial Oracle
complexity meaning that in previously
Oracle a polynomial amount of times and
then has gathered enough information
such that it can only solve a local
optimization problem so to speak and
well this takes exponential time but in
our model this is free computation right
because it doesn't take place anymore in
the group action
and uh therefore not even discrete log
is hard in our model which of course is
kind of bad
things are now much nicer in the
algebraic setting
um here we give the adversary concrete
access to the group action so no
labeling function involves anymore
however the adversary has to behave
algebraically and what that means is
well uh
when the adverse replace a game for
example then the game might provide the
adversary with some initial input in
form of the settlements here
and now whenever the adversary comes up
with a set element himself and in this
case the set element y it also has to
provide an explanation for the set
element meaning a group Elementary and
an index file such that g times x i
equals y
and this of course also works quantumly
and lastly we measure the runtime of the
adversary in the number of unit
operations so classical runtime analysis
now what are the results in in our model
um I only show one in the interest of
time
um remember the strong CDH assumption
from before we can actually show that
this is uh as hard as discrete log at
least in the quantum algebraic group
action model so for every Quantum
adversary a
um we can confine two other adversaries
p and C against discrete log such that
the success probability of a is
essentially bounded by the success
probability of B and C
and therefore these problems are uh well
they imply each other
right so this is the end of my talk so
in summary we adapted the generic group
model and the algebraic group model to
the group action setting actually in our
paper we include further algebraic
properties of group actions like twist
in the air such any case
and we improved information theoretic
lower bounds on standard assumptions in
the generic group action model
and further we get algebraic reductions
between
non-standard assumptions and group
action discrete log
and with that I'm happy to take your
questions thank you
any question yes
um I think in one of your slides you
mentioned that the generic group action
model is contained in the generic group
model right uh could you define what
exactly you mean by contained
um
well you could think of it like this so
in the uh generic group model you have
uh the uh like multiplicative Oracle
where you can multiply two group
elements but then again you can also
have like an exponentiation oracle more
or less by double and like uh Square
multiply right and this
um this exponentiation Oracle is
actually a group action right so
um in certain in a certain sense if you
remove the the standards group operation
Oracle and just include the
exponentiation Oracle in the GTM then
you get a group act then you get
basically our generic group action model
so that's what we mean
um uh wouldn't if you were to include
just the exponentiation uh Oracle in the
gdm wouldn't it still just be the GTM
because you can just set the exponents
to just one and one and have a standard
operation sorry can you repeat the
question if you were to have just the
exponentiation Oracle in the ggm
wouldn't it still just be the ggm
uh no because you cannot multiply to to
Google elements anymore you're seeing
like separate exponentiation and
separate right we have one orator for
adding inside the exponent of one for
multiplying in the exponent and you
mentioned that this is based on Shoop's
DGM right and have you ever thought
about like uh Morris and like how that
would translate
um that's a good question I think
uh yeah I never thought about that
actually thank you thank you
yes
uh hi uh Knight Rock uh so how do you
model the twists because
um yeah
oh
um The Twist we model as an extra Oracle
here
right where the Oracle gives back a
label for minus three times x
because twisting really means like
taking the inverse of an element and
because we are an additive we have an
additive group here we just take it
sends over a label for uh three times
three times x and gets back a level four
minus G times x but twist is like a
public operation right so
I mean
if the if you model it as an oracle then
you assume that the Computing The Twist
is hard or
um
yeah well
maybe we can talk you could say that yes
but uh this this doesn't affect the city
uh reduction a lot okay thank you
thank you for a very interesting talk
um can you give some intuition about uh
how you approve the final theorem
which final period so on the next to
final slide of the presentation or
something like this Oh you mean on uh on
this one yes exactly
um yeah I can um so because we are in
the algebraic setting the adversary
always has to uh has to provide these
explanations right and when he solves uh
CDH for example then he has to give like
a relative D log to either x g times X
or H times x and from that we can
extract uh more or less the discrete
lock of of one of the elements
and
um the the the the other part of the
bound here this one is coming from
simulating these oracles right we have
to somehow simulate these Oracles in
Quantum superposition and for that we we
use the one way to hiding them and
therefore we get the square root Bond
yeah
thank you all right okay one more
question
so let's thank the speaker again
so that's it for today we have a dinner
in one hour approximately
hi everybody uh dinner at six
in this area
other than that take time enjoy Atlanta
we're done for the day