ready so
first talk of this session it's on
homomorphic secret sharing from
polynomial modulus lwe and Pedro
copper Tower give the talk
thank you for the introduction uh I'm
happy to be here to present this work
with Thomas hatima and Elisa Cole about
homomorphic secret sharing
so HSS is a type of secret sharing which
allows parties to locally compute
functions over their shares so in the
two-party setting you can imagine we
have
um a secret X shared between Alice and
Bob
and uh given some public function or
program P Alice can apply a homomorphic
evaluation procedure to her share XA to
obtain an output share y a and Bob on
his side can do the same thing and in
the end there is a reconstruction
procedure which obtains the output P of
X of the program P evaluated at the
secret so in terms of security we just
require that each of the shares
individually hides the secret X
and uh this reconstruction function is
typically additive so uh the output
Shares are in some group and
um the Reconstruction function simply
adds them up together
um this is quite a useful form of
reconstruction because for example it
allows you to do linear post-processing
of the shares
but uh in our work we are actually going
to consider a more general form so more
on that later
and um just to give you an idea of HSS
uh the the simplest example we can have
is for linear functions in which the
secret
um is shared as an additive sharing so
two random shares that add up to the
secret and to evaluate some linear
program P homomorphically we simply
apply P to the share and reconstruction
here is also additive
but of course we are interested in
getting HSS for a richer class of
programs which in this case is going to
be the class of branching programs
um which you can think of as arithmetic
circuits so we have the operations of
addition and multiplication but there is
a restriction which states that a
multiplication always has to involve an
input value so we are not allowed to
multiply two intermediate computation
values
um and there is an interesting line of
work on obtaining uh two-party
homomorphic secret sharing for this
class of programs from different
assumptions such as ddh learning with
errors
um by encryption and the starting point
for our work is going to be this paper
by Elle Boyle Lisa Cole and Peter Scholl
on obtaining HSS from lwe
so I won't go into much detail about
this bks construction but I just want to
give you an idea to motivate the main
problem that we are going to be focusing
on
so um recall that we want to implement
two types of operations to have
homomorphically addition which is going
to come essentially for free by
linearity and restricted multiplication
so uh here we have an underlying
encryption scheme based on lwe and our
input values are going to be encoded as
ciphertexts and our intermediate values
are going to be additive shares so Alice
is going to have this value and Bob this
one which add up to Y times the secret
key
and so uh when we want to
homomorphically compute the
multiplication of an input value X and
an intermediate value y we just have to
compute this inner product which by the
properties of the lwe-based encryption
is going to give an additive sharing of
this expression
but what we would like to obtain is the
sharing of this expression instead so
this would be the representation of x
times y
um and so the main technical question is
how to go from here to there and uh this
step is called share conversion and it
actually shows up in some of the other
works that I I mentioned for example for
ddh it's about
um converting multiplicative shares into
additive shares
uh and so let's take a closer look at
this problem with some simplified
notation so uh suppose we have this
initial equation so Alice holds a share
u a and Bob holds the share u b which
add up to this expression Q over P times
a message M plus some error or noise
um
and what we would like them to do is for
Alice to locally convert or share UA
into some value z a and Bob to convert u
b into ZB which sum up to m
so in a way we want to convert this
additive sharing of a noisy encoding of
M into a simple additive sharing of M
so this is the the main technical
question
and uh what they do in the bks paper is
split this transformation into two steps
the first is called rounding and it's
going to give us an additive sharing of
Pam modulo P and then a lifting step
which turns this into a sharing modulo
queue so what are these transformations
rounding over share U is going to scale
it by multiplying it by P over q and
then it's going to round it to the
nearest integer so here you have a
visual representation of that operation
on the outside in green you have the
ring of integers modulo q and on the
inside the ring of integers modulo P
where in this figure p is equal to 2.
so you can see that any value in the top
half of the circle of the circle is
going to get mapped to zero and any
value in the bottom half will be mapped
to 1.
and then the lifting operation is even
simpler it basically does nothing so if
you have some value in z p represented
by an integer you simply get the same
integer as a value in that Q
uh this sounds good but do these
operations actually work do they get
this uh result we want and the answer is
yes most of the time so let's see what
can go wrong uh suppose we have our
initial equation here where our error is
bounded and suppose that our message is
zero uh and let's say that Alice has her
share UA here and Bob has UB over there
now what's going to happen is that since
Alice's share is in the bottom half of
the circle it will be mapped to one and
Bob's share is in the top half so it
will be mapped to zero so in the end if
we sum the shares after rounding we get
1 plus 0 which is one hence not our
original message M which was Zero
and this can happen whenever one of the
shares is in this red bad area
um and the probability of Landing there
is this expression which is proportional
to P over Q
and a similar type of correctness error
can happen in the lifting operation so
overall uh the error probability for
each multiplication operation is going
to be
um of the order of p over Q which comes
from rounding plus b max over P which
comes from lifting where B Max is a
bound on the values that the program can
take
uh and what do they do in the bks paper
well they just say that they choose the
parameters such that this probability is
negligible so uh that means choosing Q
which is the the lwe modulus to be super
polynomially larger than the plain text
modulus p and p to be super polynomially
larger than the bound B Max
and in our paper we actually show that
this is the best you can do if you
insist on having additive reconstruction
so now let's see what we can get if we
relax this restriction
so let's consider an alternative method
of rounding
um in which is asymmetric and now uh
Alice is going to again scale her share
by multiplying by P over q but instead
of rounding to the nearest integer she's
always going to round down
and Bob is always going to round up so
if we go back to our previous example
where Alice had her share here uh now
her share will be rounded down and
mapped to one and Bob's chair will be
rounded up and mapped to one as well so
we get one plus one which is zero as
intended so we have solved the
correctness error we previously had
um but of course this method cannot be
perfect instead of failing in the red
area it's going to fail in some other
area but observe that now we have two
methods one which works everywhere
except the red area and one which works
in the red area so let's try and combine
them and uh let's imagine for a second
that we allowed communication and then
we just one bit of communication we
could solve this problem uh by having
Alice tell Bob whether or not her share
is in the bad area if Alice's share is
outside the back area then they can both
use the standard rounding procedure that
we saw earlier and if it is in the bad
area they use this alternative method so
this uh prevents the error but of course
in HSS we do not allow this type of
communication uh because homomorphic
evaluation has to be local but now
suppose that we were to sort of push
this communication down to the end of
the protocol into the Reconstruction
phase
then Alice could just round according to
whether or not she is in the red area
and at the end she would tell Bob
um if she was or not
well on Bob's side he also has to
perform his homomorphic evaluation and
he doesn't know what Alice is doing so
he has to prepare for both cases right
he has to do the standard rounding and
the alternative rounding
and this is a problem because then he
gets two possible values and for the
next multiplication operation those two
will turn into four and so on and so
Bob's computation cost is going to grow
exponentially in the number of
multiplications which of course is
something we do not want
but now the crucial observation is that
Alice and Bob's Shares are actually
correlated because we know that uh their
sum is very close to a multiple of Q
over P so in this case their sum has to
be either close to zero or close to Q
over 2. so um we can notice that if
Alice's share is in this red area then
Bob's share must be in this slightly
larger yellow area
or in other words if Bob's chair is
outside of the yellow area then Alice's
share must be also outside of the red
area so without communicating they both
know that they can use the standard
rounding method without risk of an error
so uh this is what we use in our
construction so Alice is always going to
check if her share is in the red area
and use the appropriate rounding method
and Bob uh if his chair is in the yellow
is outside the yellow area he knows he
can use uh he knows Alice's share is
also outside so he can just use the
standard rounding but if it is inside
the yellow area then he doesn't know
what Alice is doing so he has to compute
both possible values
but we note that the probability of
Landing in this case where Bob has to do
additional computation is given by this
expression which we can make very small
while still having better parameters
than the previous work
and uh pretty much everything that I
said for the rounding operation also
happens for the lifting operation so
there is a similar type of correctness
error and we can address it in a similar
fashion
so I already mentioned that uh our
reconstruction is not going to be
additive so what does it look like in
the end well Alice is going to have a
share of this form
um an integer value and a sequence of
zeros and ones denoting when she used
the standard rounding and when she used
the alternative rounding
and uh Bob is going to have a list of
shares of the same type one for each
sort of computation path in in the
computation tree
and the Reconstruction function is
simply going to
match the the sequences of flags and sum
up the corresponding integers so as you
can see despite not being linear this is
a relatively simple function
so
um to to summarize our results we
construct a two-party homomorphic secret
sharing scheme for the class of
branching programs from the LW
assumption with a small modulus which in
particular is not required to be super
polynomial and we do this using a new
technique for uh correcting or
preventing errors uh with which we
obtain a perfect correctness
um at the cost of variable running time
because as you recall uh Bob's
computation time is going to depend on
how often he lands in his yellow area
we have a relaxed form of reconstruction
which makes our protocol particularly
suitable for settings in which there is
no security against the party doing the
Reconstruction
um so you can think of private
information retrieval and similar
applications and finally our
construction is more efficient than the
previous work we computed some concrete
parameters based on ring lwe and even
for a rather large programs uh our
Shares are shorter by a factor of four
or five at least
that's everything if you're interested
please check out our paper and thank you
very much for listening
foreign
questions
so one thing I wanted to ask at the
beginning you were talking about each
multiplication has to be connected to an
input was that for the previous scheme
or both for both yes we we our scheme is
for the same class of programs okay yes
and there's
I guess they are just multiply or why
why does connecting it to the input
somehow make just keep the error small
even if it was growing I guess I don't
quite see how the arrow grows in that
yes so it's it's not necessarily about
the the error
um
so this allows us to having this
restriction allows us to
um encode the the shares uh in this form
so we we sort of have you can see here
we have a special type of encryption
where our encrypted value is uh X the
secret x times the secret key so you can
actually generate this ciphertext
without knowledge of the secret key
um and um this secret key is going to
sort of be used up on each uh inner
product so uh that's why you always need
a sort of fresh Cipher text which comes
from an input value
thank you
thank you for the question other
questions anybody
okay if not well thanks thanks speaker
again
and next talk will be discretization
error reduction for high Precision
Taurus fully homomorphic encryption and
Kang Hoon Lee will give the talk
once his microphone is set up
ah
thanks for the introduction uh I'm
kangali from Korean University School of
cyber security I'm here to present our
paper uh discretization and reduction
for high Precision Source volume of big
encryption this is doing work with G1
Yoon who is my advisor
foreign
introduction about homework encryption
which is an encryption scheme that
allows to operate with encrypt data
without decryption so the server or the
cloud gets the encryption of X with the
user secret key and they evaluate the
circuit the circuit for f so they will
cut they will evaluating they will they
will get the encryption of FX without X
revealed
then the user will get the encryption of
FX and then decrypt with his or her
secret key and retrieve the effects
so when it comes to fully homework
encryption uh based they are capable of
evaluating circuit with arbitrary depths
in order to support arbitrary devs they
usually comes with a recryption
procedure called bootstrap
these are the notations we are going to
use throughout the presentation and some
important notation is the large n which
which I assume to be a Power of Two And
I'm going to use it as the ring
Dimension parameter
and the next parameter is the new there
is uh which I call it the extension
parameter uh I'm going to explain it
later
so our work is based on the tfhg scheme
which is a scheme introduced by
julote
its security is based on the learning
with the errors problem and it's worked
with three different Cy protect spaces
namely the Taurus lwe Taurus ring of we
and the tourist ring GSW
I'll just exclude the term Taurus from
now on for Simplicity uh they all the
Wayside protects encrypts a Taurus
element n and it's actually a n plus one
dimensional Vector up towards elements
instead of being a w e server text
encrypts a Taurus polynomial and on part
from these two polynomials the ranges of
server text encrypts a integer
polynomial ZX but in practice they
usually just encrypt a single integer uh
just like PSI the secret key of the user
so tfbg is famous for his uh fast
bootstrapping based on the external
product
uh it is a simple multiplication between
the ring jsw and the regional to
receptor text
so after the external product it returns
a regulatory server text encrypting the
MX multiplied by the interior polynomial
CX
So based on the external product those
tfh bootstrapping homomorphically
decrypts tail to be Cy protects by
calculating the controlled North circuit
for every element in the l2e Cyber text
the control mouse is actually a
homorphic selection algorithm to select
between the rotated accumulator
or the original accumulator based on the
value of Si
if the SI encrypts one it selects the
rotated accumulatory accumulator
multiplied by the X to the power bar a I
or if it encrypts zero it just selects
the original cumulate
after the evaluation the
the the after the evaluation it Returns
the Renault WWE surface encrypting the
rotated MX which is rotated by the
amount of the message to LW exam
protects holes
uh so we Pro uh I'm going to introduce
our major contribution of our uh paper
the extended bootstrapping for tfhe
so given the function f over the tourist
the functional tfh bootstrapping is Con
is actually a series of these four
algorithms starting from the l2b
ciphertext the Taurus elements appeal to
server text are converted into a
insurance based module to n
during this conversion surrounding
errors are added to the Cyber text after
the conversion the homorphic decryption
circuit which I which we call the blind
rotation are evaluated and then the
extracted then the lto reserve protects
are extracted and the key switch back to
its original key
so the user so the cloud will get the
encryption of F M Bar
so our work focus is on the mode the mod
switch and the blind rotation algorithm
in order to reduce the rounding error
that comes from the most which the uh
that comes from the monster
uh we first observed the Precision the
change of precision in kfhg bootstrap
after some homorphic operations
including a addition or duplications uh
the ciphertext is ready to be uh
bootstrapped and at first it is first
mod switch to the Z module two in which
uh which incurs a severe Precision loss
during the
conversion so it's like uh looking up to
the most significant log to m beats and
this
uh this makes us to use a small message
procedure a typical choice for n would
be a 10 to the power of 2 which is about
1000 and in that case we can only use
the message precision as like four to
five bits
so what we aim here is to reduce the
Precision loss that comes from the most
switch by modifying the blind rotation
algorithm and the mod switch at home
so we can use a large message space for
our cycle text
there are some approaches that that aim
to reduce this error uh one the first
approach is to reduce the Hamming rate
of the secret key uh secret key of the
LTB surface
uh the second one is to increase the
ring Dimension and that is we look up to
more bits of the ciphertext uh our work
aims to uh
increase the efficiency of the second
second approach
so enlarging the ring Dimension has its
pros and cons some advantages can uh
will be uh will be able to use a small
standard deviation for the window to be
separate fixed and like I said we can
reduce from the module switch
uh severe disadvantage will be the Quasi
linear growth for the polymer
multiplication uh and since the tfh
bootstrapping has consists of tons of
polynomial multiplication it brings a
severe slowdown for the tfh bootstrap
so our first proposal is a cybertex
intention to a smaller Dimension to a
large servant so our extension parameter
comes here so
okay so if we use a new as zero it will
be just be a simple identity mapping but
if you like use new as one uh we are
sending the polynomial Dimension and 2
times 2N uh which uh in which the
the coefficients of the power of X will
be all zero and the even the wave
coefficients up to even power of X will
be exactly the same as the original
polynomial
so with this zero padding we extend the
Ring of w e and the ring just W side
protects into a larger Dimension uh 2 to
the power of Nu n
so we use the notation sub x to the 2D
node that these polynomials are extended
by a zero pattern
the nice thing about this zero padding
is that the external product naturally
follows to the ring dimension of 2 to
the power of Nu times n
so we can evaluate the control mode
circuit still on this larger ring
Dimension while we while we set the
parameter as n
so in this case we can model the switch
to a larger Dimension 2 to the power of
Nu plus 1 times n
thereby gaining an additional new piece
of precision during the ball switch
however this external product on a
larger Dimension needs to perform the
polynomial multiplication on Dimension
due to the power of Nu times n so it is
quite inefficient
so we introduce our second proposal the
parallel external external front
it is based on the modularized morphism
we call it Tau which place the
polynomial into Vector of polynomial
subtimage n
uh
so we like both the large green LW type
into a multiple being l2b ciphertext of
dimension
with length 2 to the power of Nu
sadly uh the external product does not
follow naturally in this case so uh we
have to uh there so the public key has
to satisfy some conditions uh just
condition one and two so the though both
ranges W cyber text and the ring Adobe
side protects has to be encrypted by the
extended key
also the ring just W ciphertext has to
be an extension from Avengers topic of a
smaller Dimension and and this is the
most important condition that the GSW
separately has to encrypt only the
integer not the integer polynomial
but this condition is quite common in
the official literature because they are
their ordinary Works their ordinary
Works in FIB uh only zeros and one
so we can split the external product in
a larger Dimension to a independent uh
external products in small in smaller
Dimension n
using this parallel external product we
can build a parallel controlled box
circuit that's shaped like this
so each row are independent to each
other and can be parallel and can be
computed in power
so a one zMAX circuit evaluation on the
dimension to 200 times n is equivalent
to running two to the new seam of
circuits of Dimension and Imperial
so in summary we propose a extended
bootstrapping in abbreviation I call it
the EBS for the tfhe so when we even if
we use a small n for the ring we can
always
enlarge the end during the bootstrapping
and gain additional new bits the new is
a negative integer so you can uh Cloud
can always select which uh how big the
new is
and also we are able to keep small ring
Dimension and ring Dimension ends so we
do not have to implement a uh High
Precision fft to support a large
dimensional polynomial multiplication
also our plane rotation is parallelized
so we can also always enjoy the low
latency of the tfh bootstrapping as long
as our computational power allows
so we provide some experimental results
uh we implemented our Eds on top of the
tfpg library along with the three
state-of-the-art full domain functional
boost tracking algorithms they all uses
the tfhg function bootstrapping as a
solve algorithms and the codes are
available publicly at our GitHub page in
the link
and this is our experimental set
so these are the parameters we used for
our paper uh we in this presentation we
are only going to show the results for
the upper half but there's the time
limit uh and the first three parameters
are shared exactly the same parameters
except for the ring entwist
uh we did this to compare whether uh the
selecting small n along with using with
our EBS is better or just selecting a
large dimensional type large dimension
for n is that
so this is the performance of the first
three parameter set which is non-parel
the y-axis uh represents the latency in
milliseconds in the lower remix lower
rhythmic scale of Base 2.
the x-axis uh represents the log 2N plus
the extension parameter Nu that starts
from 0.
as you can see uh using a smaller
dimension for n and using our EBS is
slightly better than using the large
dimension for the ring damage
so this is the performance result for
the parallelized EBS uh we can also see
that our EBS fully benefits from the
proper parallel parallelization
to see that the Precision actually grow
we evaluate some function a simple sign
function over the domain minus 64 to 64.
so we evaluated this with the full
domain functional bootstrapping
algorithms and the red line here is the
max is the maximal Precision we
estimated with our error estimation
formula
we can observe the Precision in the
y-axis
shows a linear growth in precision as
the extension parameter new
in the x-axis rows
they
don't take any questions
can you say again for this extension
parameter how do you choose it or how
does it
extension parameter is a it's just a
non-negative integer that you can select
freely uh so you have to select uh
uh by calc by estimating the error from
the bootstrapping and the mouse so the
uh so using a non as using a positive uh
integer for the extension parameter uh
decreases the mode switch errors so uh
you can increase it as long as the mod
switch error is larger than the
bootstrapping error
and you can calculate that with a error
estimation so what what are like typical
values that you choose for it
um
it's it's really different from
parameter to parameter yes so you have
to manually calculate the matches what's
the range in the in your experiments
what
like oh we used uh zero to eight in this
experiment oh that's the bottom yes yes
and can you talk about it asymptotically
also or is it just is it really it's for
implementing and
uh sorry is there an is there a way to
describe it asymptotically how you
should choose it I mean you're saying
you compare it to the two errors but
you're saying yes I guess not it's
complicated to to calculate where to put
it yeah
okay
any other questions
no thanks speaker
the next talk is verifiable capacity
bound functions a new primitive from
kamogorov complexity and the talk will
be given by Danilo oh boy uh from Kathy
yeah
thank you for the introduction uh this
is John worked with Joseph
uh so let's assume we have a machine
that executed a function on some input
and we want to measure the efficiency of
the function
what we usually do we measure the
efficiency according to the resource
usage like time space and even energy
consumed by the machine
uh we usually want to minimize this
usage but in this talk we're going to do
the top the opposite so we're going to
talk about function that waste resources
to get some kind of production
so let's have an example suppose we have
a database in which we store the hashes
of some passwords now if you get hacked
you can start doing a blue flow an
offline Brute Force attack and you
extract the passwords so a way to block
these attack is to use a research
demanding function so a function that
weighs resources so now if that battery
does have enough resources you
you are safe at least some of the parts
cannot be extracted
um now according to the time we can have
some kind of example like time lock
encryption
for space we have memory card then call
that function a lot of space to be
computed
and also for energy we have an example
that is boundary heart function so it's
a function that waste energy uh while
you you complete a function and we're
gonna see um
then
the intuition behind the construction
ladder so but let's change the setting
now suppose we are in the decentralized
setting in which you have an evaluator
that computes the function and then the
functional the output is sent to the
verifiers to check the validity
this could be like a proof of work and
and the protocol is a blockchain
protocol
um so in this setting you want to
protect yourself from a malicious
Evolution that's for example tries to uh
try different inputs until you find a
particular output that gives you some
kind of Advantage like predicting the
next block of the blockchain
and also on the other hand the verifiers
as the honest parties at least the
majority of them
so you can use for example in this
setting the resource the money function
again but now you have a problem that
the honest part is going to waste
resources because you need to check the
validity by running the function again
so the idea is here is that some
sometimes we need some kind of public
verifiability property that the we need
to verify the correction of the output
without wasting resources so the
verification must be resource free let's
say
so we have an example for time that is a
verifiable belly function uh so uh for
space and energy the recent and what we
do we introduce the notion of verifiable
capacity bound function that is mainly
an energy demanding function
but it's closely related with space as
we're gonna see
so the intuition is that on evaluation
we are going to consume a lot of energy
and the verification is almost energy
free
and now the question is how can we
measure the energy consumed by by your
machine even if we have different kind
of architecture that waste they use
different amount of energy when you do
some kind of computation
so the intuition comes from the Weber
abundant heart function that
show empirically that they have a
bottleneck called that detection and the
bottom is that when you read bits from
the ram either because you move the bits
the cache or to the CPU to perform some
kind of computation you're gonna waste
by unity of energy and the unit is more
or less the same across the all the
architecture we have including Asics for
example
so the idea is for the function is to
maximize this amount on evaluation and
minimize the same amount of verification
uh we we propose some definition to
Define these properties so the first
property is called minimum capacity so
even if you precompute the function if I
give you an input and you compute the
correct output of the function then we
know that the best is going to read and
distinct bits from the memory
and this is this is knife because now if
your cache is of size B you can preload
that must be beats in the cache and now
you're gonna read at least n minus bits
from the main memory and that's the
amount of energy you're going to consume
uh on verification uh we want sound rest
so you can give a proof to check the
correctness of the output it should be
hard to convince the verifier when the
the output is not correct
and also we want the efficiency that
essentially says that the verification
requires really deep bits from the
memory and DC is way smaller than M
where m is the minimum capacity of the
function
so with propose a construction that we
go from come over from Plexi to measure
the space requirement to evaluate the
polynomial
and then we use this polynomial to build
the function
we Face some problems I mean the
construction that we have at some kind
of limitations that we're gonna see
later uh
but I mean the the intuition of the work
is to light the ground of the function
and the definition
so the first part is the following so
let me introduce come over complexity uh
we want to measure the description of an
object
so an object of binary string and a
description of an object is a pair so
it's algorithm T and an input Alpha and
this is about the description if t on
input Alpha outputs the object
now we can look at T like at the
compression algorithm and Alpha's at the
compression of the object for example
now if you fix T we can Define the
column of complexity as the length of
the smallest string that on input that t
on input the string Alpha gives you an
input option it gives you an output
option
now the problem with this notion now
that depends on the algorithm but we
would like to have some kind of
universal estimation of the complexity
especially when we want to prove
security and we can do that by using vs3
machine so we we set the university
machine as the the turing machine of the
complexity so now the description is not
appearing more but it's simply the input
of the universal turing machine
uh so from this notion we can define a
scene compressibility so an object is
incompressible if the golden complexity
of the object is greater or equal than
the size of the object minus C
and the cool fact is that in any given
set arbitrary set if you know the
cardinality M we also know the number of
incompressible objects in the set so
this is the amount that you see on the
slide that is that depends on both
uh the cardinality m and the factor C of
this incompressibility
okay so that we know this notion let me
Define what's the problem we want to
tackle uh so polymer evaluation we have
a polynomial of degree d
and now we have a machine that takes an
input some points and uh gives you an
output evaluation on those points and
what we want to measure is this
bits that you need to read from the
memory to correctly evaluate the the the
polynomial so intuitively what you're
going to read is an encoding of the
polynomial
so what we show in the paper is that
suppose you have this machine on the
right that uh takes in input D plus one
points and reads A String Alpha from the
memory if the machine and assume that
the machine is giving you an output the
correct evaluations so we can say that
Alpha plus the points is a description
for the polynomial because you can
simply take Alpha the inputs
run the machine takes the valuation and
then do interpolation to reconstruct the
polynomial
so this means that Alpha the size of
alpha is related to the golden
complexity of the polynomial and that's
what we show so we showed that if the
polynomial is incompressible then
uh for every table of D plus one points
that are all different then we know that
if you correctly compute the evaluations
then the size of the string that you
read from the memory is more or less
greater than this value here that is D
plus one times the random minus L minus
C so D plus 1 is the number of
coefficients you have Lambda is the size
of a coefficient
the minus L is a loss proportional to
the input because that's part of the
description
and minus C is the loss of this
incompressibility of the polynomial
so now how can we use this to build
verifiable capacity Bank functions so
these are the properties I'm going to
talk about minimum capacity mainly
and the definition that I'm going to
describe here is a weaker definition
than the one that we want to achieve
we're going to see the limitation later
so suppose we have an evaluator that has
access to Taiwan Tau T strings
and each of these strings of size m and
the correct way to interpret the string
is that each tau is an information
encoding to the memory that you can read
interpret and perform a correct uh
computation on it
so in this definition you is okay so
towels are pre-computed by looking at
the function
and now you you get a random point you
can read one of them
you can put the output and now we say
that the function is secure if the
probability of getting the correct
output
it's utmost Epsilon and this is nice
because I suppose you have an upper
bound on T then the only way to compute
the function is to read something that
is greater than m
that's what we want to do
uh so now if you fix the function we go
to the polynomial we
uh we can prove the following so if T is
equal to equal to one then we can use
this theorem we can set m equal to the
size of alpha of the theorem and now we
are guaranteed that when you read the
Tau you can answer mostly points because
the Y is contradicted theorem and since
the point is sample random you you have
disadvantages so it's D over the input
space
the size of the impulse pane
uh now if you have more strings you your
advantage is going to be multiplied by T
simply because you can read only one of
those uh those styles
uh the missing part is that we need an
incompressible as incompressible
polynomial and uh so we know the number
of seeing compressible objects in a
given set
the set here is the set of polynomials
and by playing with the parameters I
mean this is the number of
syncompressive polynomial in the given
set
and by playing with the parameters we
can show that for large enough C but not
too much we can get
a scene compressible polynomial by
simply a random from the set
and this means that the function is
going to have a setup to honestly
generate the polynomial or
honestly because we need to be to have
an honest sampling of the polynomial and
this is reminiscent from the PDF also
that has a processor
um
in this definition we can prove that if
you read M bits what m is close enough
to the size of the polynomial but not
exactly the same then your advantage is
going to be negligible even if you have
an exponential amount of tiles that you
can read you can choose from
now the problem with this definition is
the following now I'm talking about
tiles so information that you can read
from the memory but to use this
definition and practice we need to have
an estimation of the memory not the
number of information encoded on the
memory
so we would like to say like if your
machine has a one terabyte of storage
then there is no way to read
less than n Bits And correctly compute
the output
so we need to find a way to transform
this T into a memory size
and this turnouts to not be easy simply
because for example Tau 1 and Tau 2 may
have a common pattern inside and while
you could encode this information into
the main memory by not repeating the red
pattern
and then you leverage the random access
to the memory to reconstruct tau1 and
Tau 2 when according when you need it
so the question is I mean again what's
the relation between T and A Memory that
is of size n that it's going to encode
these informations
so uh what we show is that I mean what
we can show is is the following so we
use accounting argument and we count
according to the number of Random Access
you do to the memory
and we can achieve this definition that
is the final one the one that we would
like because we have a memory of size n
with the following parameter so we have
M and plus before Epsilon has before and
now this parameter hold if you have a
memory Access Financial site but under
the constraint that you do only cost a
number of random access to the memory so
you jump into the memory and you read
all your custom number of times
now if you do a non-constant number of
Random Access where non-truster means
that depends on them now we have a very
loose bound on n and technically we
don't have a clear estimation about this
unit of the function when you do this
kind of strategy
so uh
the question is if you can improve the
estimation of the memory bound when you
do non-constant random non-costal number
of random access to the memory while
keeping M close enough to the size of
the polynomial because we want to
maximize the number of bits we are going
to read
um there is a barrier and the bar is
this algorithm uh so there is this
algorithm that takes a polynomial and
pre-computes by building another
structure and the little structure is of
this side so n is going to be
D over 1 plus Delta or Delta is a cosine
times random more or less uh at least a
synthetically speaking and uh so it's
more than the size of the polynomial but
not too much
so it's polynomial essentially and then
on evaluation we can uh evaluate the
polynomial by using a non-constant
number of Random Access and reading this
amount of bits so polylog D times Lambda
that is way smaller than the size of the
polynomial because it's poly log in the
degree
So asymptotically speaking what I'm
saying is that we cannot go over these
parameters but maybe concretely but play
with the cost that we can get some kind
of concrete uh estimation
um very briefly regarding soundness so
what we show is that we can we have
soundness by using verifiable
computation
that is probably verifiable and public
deductible so on setup we also generate
some keys the key allows the evaluator
to produce the proof and the verifier
can use the same keys that are public to
verify the proof and regarding
efficiency what we show is the following
so we know that on evaluation we read
and beats close to the size of the
polynomial at least when we do cost and
number of Random Access
and on verification we can show the if
we use this verifiable computation here
from sfvcs to 2016.
what you're going to read from a memory
something that is proportional only to
the security parameter so independent
from the and that's why we get the
asymmetry
oh okay that's uh that's the end of my
talk thank you
questions
we have probably five minutes here so we
can if you don't have a question I'm
gonna ask a question it's maybe a little
more basic so I'm not so familiar with
this I was wondering if you could just
say again like uh what the different
parties do there's this Capital act that
you're working to make it hard to
evaluate right is that against the
so we want to build this function that
uh when you evaluate it we have a lower
bound on the number of energy
electricity you're gonna use do you have
a picture with the that describes the
general like just the basic setup with
capital F I think you had one
you mean this one
yeah
so like what's the difference between
the left bottom picture and the right
bottom picture like how can somebody do
verification versus that's a separate
protocol or how no it's the same product
so that when you evaluate the function
you you evaluate the function on X and
you produce y but together we why we all
you also produce a proof and the proof
is going to allow you on verification to
check if that is correct or not okay
it's similar to PDF the syntax so then
on the left this is on the left is the
defining a proof
like what's the what's the I still don't
quite figure one on the left yeah it's
minimum capacity there is the security
against uh an evaluator so here we're
gonna say that when you validate the
function if the output of the function
is correct then you're gonna read m
distingues
now the syntax of the function also
appends a proof and then the proof is
used on verification only so on the
right part now now we'll talk about the
verifier and we have sound rest and
efficiency so that part's easier so that
with the proof it's much easier than
yeah the problem is the minimum
capacitor and how do you estimate the
memory yeah yeah okay and then how does
someone use it initially if it's hard to
compute or I mean it's something that
you can compute yeah the problem is that
uh we yeah you're gonna use resources
that's that
and then what's code hard at this I saw
that as one of the uh Code art it's like
I think the clear example of code art
it's like a function which
on setup I mean I have an example so on
setup you
you you build like a random table
and I give you the random table and then
I'm gonna ask you give me this entry of
this table and since I'm gonna select
the entry of the table are random you
need to store let's say
the entire uh I mean the majority of the
database because otherwise I'm gonna hit
one that you don't know so that's called
that okay
thank you
any other questions
um so I think you you mentioned the
evaluation function is a polynomial and
uh that with high probability it is
actually energy demanding so is this a
random polynomial or is it just a random
number I mean it's a random polynomial
for Simplicity but technically if you
have a set of polynomials of where the
cardinality of this set is large enough
it's sufficient to sample from that cell
at least
and the the degree of the polynomial was
this D that was yeah it did fine so that
you need to set D according to how much
bits you want to read because that's the
only parameter we you for which you can
play with so the higher the more they
agree the higher the demon the mature
you have more coefficients and that's
they're gonna read more confused now
okay thank you
any other questions no thanks speaker
again
so in the last talking session is a
holistic approach towards side Channel
secure fixed wave polynomial sampling
and Marcus parks we didn't talk
okay
so hi and welcome to my talk about side
Channel secure fixed rate polynomial
sampling
so what is fixed rate polynomial
sampling it's quite a simple problem
actually we want to generate a random
bit string of length n and Hemingway's W
and for example with n equal to 10 and W
equal to 4 we have a bit string of links
10 where we have four ones and six zeros
and this bit string represents a bit
polynomial with 10 coefficients
and we call this representations a
coefficient representation but we could
also represent our bit polynomial in the
index representation where we simply
store the indices where
um the bit is one
and this is index representation we can
also rephrase our problem so what we
want is to draw W random elements from
the set 0 to n minus 1 without
replacement regardless of the order
so why do we need this actually we need
it quite a quite often and post Quantum
cryptography so there are some relevant
schemes that use this with some variety
and the most important parameters are of
course n and W and the resulting ratio
of w compared to n
so for bike and hqc for example we have
big n and small RW resulting in a very
small ratio
we have a medium sized n and for Andrew
and stream them into Prime then is small
and W is greater resulting in a ratio
that is close to 50 percent
so now you might be wondering why are we
talking about such a simple problem so
turns out if you want an efficient and
sidechain and secure implementation it's
not that easy yeah so side channel
security
when we when we talk about side channel
security we first have to evaluate uh
which values are secret and sensitive so
which values do we need to protect
against the side channels and for the
fixed rate polynomial sampling you we
have as inputs some Randomness and the
output is the polynomial
for other schemes
um this polynomial is a secret value so
our sampler must not leak any
information about the polynomial
but for some of the schemes we have an
additional requirement so the randomness
is generated by nprng and the seed the
input seat is a secret value therefore
the randomness is also secret dependent
and therefore our sampler must not
reveal anything about the randomness
foreign
so when I talk about side China security
talk about timing side channels and for
this um our common countermeasure is
constant time programming but in this
work we also focus on power side
channels and our content measure here is
masking
so a quick reminder about a constant
time program programming we basically
have three Simple Rules there
branches memory accesses and
instructions with Opera independent
runtime must not depend on any secret
values
and for the fixed by polynomial sampling
in memory accesses
um can be quite a problem
so for the power side channels as Chris
pikeout yesterday already introduced we
can use masking and the ideas here
secret values are split into random
shares and for first order Boolean
masking for example we would end up two
shares that we can combine with an XR
together original value
and as Chris explained the challenge
here is when we have non-linear
functions and they can be quite
expensive
so what are the methods that we can use
for fixed rate polynomial sampling so
they're basically six different methods
and we can put them into three distinct
categories
the first category is the rejection
sampling it outputs it polynomial in the
index representation
and then the next categories what I call
Setting bits randomly it works on the
coefficient representation and the last
category is shuffling it can either work
on index or on the coefficient
representation and they all also differ
by what I call this heat security so
what I mentioned whether it's possible
to implement them in a way that the seed
is not a lead virus High Channel
so let's jump into these categories so
rejection sampling is probably the most
straightforward solution for this
problem the idea here is that we sample
uniform random values from 0 to n and
reject a value if we have a collision so
if we already sampled the value before
and we just repeat this until we have W
distinct values
obviously this is not seat secure so
this would leak the seed or the random
method we are using because it
determines how many iterations we have
to do but we can transform this message
and to make it seed secure
and we call this a bounded method so
what we do here is we determine an upper
bound B of iterations in which this very
high probability enough distinct values
will be sampled and then we do exactly
always these B iterations and for each
value we always iterate our whole index
array to keep the current count Secret
and of course this adds some overhead so
this method only makes sense in a
scenario where we require this seat
security
so the next methods the setting random
bits there's this repeated ending
message the ideas here that we start
with a random polynomial of length n
and then we adapt The Weight by ending
or ordering random polynomials until our
desired weight w is reached so basically
we make use of the observation that we
when we and to
um random bit strings the way it can
only decrease not increase and if we are
to bit strings it can increase but not
decrease so when we make let's say a
clever combination of this ending and
ring to get to our desired weight
and an important observation is here
that the runtime is again
um depending on the randomness we get
and also
um if our ratio of w compared to n is
close to 50 this message can be fast
because this is like the expected rate
we get from a random bit string but if
our ratio is far away from the 50 and
then this method can be costly but we
have a solution for this yeah for
um for situations where where our ratio
is far away from the 50 percent we
basically you have a generalization of
this idea we call it a comparison method
therefore each coefficient we set a bit
with probability p
is include equal to W over n and then
basically resample the polynomial until
we get one with the desired weight
and we approximate P with a comparison
of a random L bit string
um
or basically our our p is in a range
from 0 to 1 and we scale it up with 2 to
the power of L and then if we take an L
bit string it will be in this range and
we compare it with a threshold and if
it's below the threshold we set the
coefficient to one if it's above we set
it to zero and in the Mast setting we
can do this bit slice so it's also
parallelizable so very comparable to the
ending method actually
last methods are the shuffling methods
the ideas here that we start with a
fixed polynomial of length n and the
correct way to W and then just apply a
random permutation yeah so for example
we set the first W
um coefficients to one and do a random
shuffling and then we end up with a
random polynomial question is now how do
we do the shuffling
and one solution is to do it with
sorting so when our method is to pair
each coefficient with a distinct random
number and then we sort the pairs
according to the random number and then
we get the random permutation of the
coefficients
and sorting can be somewhat efficiently
be done inside Channel secure
and now you might be wondering why don't
we use Fisheries shuffling well we can
use fisha Yates but it's usually not a
sidechain secure it's leaking the
permutation via the memory exercises but
we can transform it to make it scientist
secure but then it becomes quadratic but
there's still a use case for this the
idea is now that we start with an array
of the values from 0 to n minus 1 then
we apply a random permutation with
fisheries and then we take the first W
entries as a polynomial in the index
representation and Fisheries can be
stopped after the first W entries are
set so our runtime is predatric in W and
not n
yeah so these are all the methods that
at least we know and we implemented them
all
um
arbitrary order masked
and bit sliced in C and evaluated on a
cortic M4 microprocessor
so these are the results for the first
order I'm asking and let's look at the
Sorting approach in the middle
for bike in hqc we actually weren't able
to run it on the macro processor because
it requires too much Randomness and for
make a list for example it was a medium
sized end we can see it's not very
competitive approach yeah because it the
runtime really depends on n
and for Android and stream entry and
streamline Enterprise it's somewhat
acceptable
then for official Yates we can see for
example for HPC and make a lease
so runtime is very competitive because
it depends on W yeah
um and then the rejection method this is
not seat secure so we cannot use it for
bike and hqc but for the other cases
it's one of the fastest methods and for
a bike in hqc we can use the bounded
rejection methods
um and but this method doesn't make
sense for the other ones because it's
always lower than the rejection simple
rejection method but what we can also
see is that the bounded rejection method
is always lower than Fisheries so
actually there is no use case for the
bounded rejection message
and then we have the ending in
comparison methods they are also not
seen secure so not usable for bike in
hqc
um and they are also they can be the
fastest methods and what we can also see
is the comparison method is especially
faster in the case where we have a ratio
or make at least for example where the
ratio is two percent so very far away
from the 50 percent
so the outcome basically of our work is
yes we we can we have Solutions yes I
can secure solution for the use case but
actually they are all um very slow yeah
so these numbers that you see here they
are kilo Cycles so we're talking about
at least a million cycles for such a
simple operation
this is way more than we anticipated and
the way more that we would like to have
so we are actually actually still
looking for a viable solution and if you
have any ideas let me know
thank you
thank you questions
where I am
all right well it's thanks speak
foreign
ER buses 5 30 and 6 o'clock
hope to see you at the aquarium
yes
shuttles back
the second one back at 10.
I'm not sure what the first departure
time will be but
and we'll be meeting just the nice like
drop-off area right outside the hotel
lobby