everybody this is sam pfeifle content
director here at the International
Association of privacy professionals
better known as the I a PEP we are happy
to have you join us here for the speaker
orientation call or the ia PP Canada
privacy symposium which I see is very
pink this year we used to be more of a
red but it seems that we've gone pink
I'm not sure if that's our screen here
if that's reality who knows anyway hope
you guys all like pink so what we're
going to do over the course of this call
we thank you very much for joining us is
just go through some operational details
so that there is no confusion on the
where when that sort of thing and then
we'll introduce some people that you can
reach out to if you need help in any way
and then we're going to talk just a
little bit about our expectations for
presentations at our events the feedback
that we've gotten from our members who
attend and just some sort of general
tips on giving a good presentation and
being successful with your presentation
at the symposium so before we get too
far I want to introduce the people that
may or may not speak on this call there
are four people in this room we are in
the great state of New Hampshire in
Portsmouth New Hampshire on the floor
former Air Force Base so you know we are
well fortified here in the warehouse
bunkered down nothing bad can happen to
us so across from me is Dave Cohen
someone you might remember from our web
conferences also helps us with speaker
programming say hi Dave hey everybody
next to him is Amanda Charbonneau who
has a wonderful French last name so
should be familiar to you she will also
be a speaker manager for this event the
person that sends you email say hi
Amanda hello everyone and far far away
from our conference
so you probably can't hear them he may
or may not be in Afghanistan is Rick
abeba hello everyone rick is a
well-versed in performer so has a nice
hearty voice you may or may not hear
from Ricky as our speaker manager for
all of our events so he is often
somebody that can help Amanda on this
event he may have cyl you for a head
shot or a bio or anything like that but
we will get to those things so Dave let
us proceed all right so first I'm going
to turn it over to Amanda she is going
to handle the operational details
portion of this presentation hello
everyone enough so if you've attended
our symposium or spoken before you'll be
happy to know that we're returning to be
a joining Metro Toronto Convention
Center and intercontinental hotel in
downtown Toronto I've included a link to
map and directions as well as rates for
parking we're actually going to be
distributing this Web con along with the
slides after the call so no worries
you'll get the links and all the
documents post call so what is going on
on Monday May fifteenth is the training
day only Tuesday May sixteenth is going
to be a training day and workshops
Wednesday May seventeenth is going to be
day one of the main conference and
you'll also notice our privacy soiree on
that day one great networking
opportunity and just a lot of fun on
Thursday may 18th you've got day two of
the main conference and if you'd like to
participate in any of those trainings or
workshops just know that this is going
to be an additional fee on top of your
complimentary speaker pass look at the
slide action that slide action we are
fancy and owning it so for hotels and
accommodation like i mentioned we're
going to be at the intercontinental
toronto centre hotel there's a map and
directions including the slide we do
have a room block available it's going
to be two hundred and thirty nine
dollars per night make sure when you
call if you're looking for a room to
specifically mention the eye apt and do
note that this offer expires on April
twelfth so if you know you're going to
need accommodations
please do so sooner the better and then
Metro Toronto Convention Center is where
the actual conference will be held
logistics and demographics so we're
expecting over 500 attendees financial
services public sector and health care
were the top three industries in
attendance from last year the average
attendance per session at symposium is
63 people and a list of organizations
who attended last year's symposium is
going to be circulated by myself after
this call you're also going to want to
check out the online schedule just make
sure your session looks good find out
the time the rooms make sure your name
is Tyler crack those are all really
helpful for us breakout rooms range in
size from a max capacity of 62 to 80 and
then in regards to registration some of
you have been asking about this and i do
want to let you know that the IPP is
actually taking care of your
registration as a speaker program chair
so you'll receive a complimentary pass
for the main conference important to
note if you have any dietary
restrictions if you can please email me
that would be very helpful and some
rules that are important if you have to
make any changes to your panel speakers
content it's really important to run
that by us just for the integrity of our
programming process so if you know
something's going to be changing if you
could please email me that would be
wonderful and also new this year if you
are using a PowerPoint for your
presentation please please make sure to
use the eye appt ended PowerPoint which
is going to be included in this
slideshow that I distribute post call so
what is due now if you could send us
your headshot as soon as possible as
long as along with your bio this would
be wonderful you can check if we have
that information on file by visiting our
website which the link is in this
presentation and you'll know that you
need to send me your head shot because
you will have a sad grey of faith by
your negative haha please send us your
headshots will even take your iPhone
selfies at this world so
your bio is missing or outdated also
please feel free to email me I'd be
happy to update that for you bio should
be a hundred words mass also another
important deadline is going to be April
seventh so this is when you're going to
be reaching out to your program chair to
have them review your abstract along
with any presentation drafts and
handouts that you may have some people
have been asking me what constitutes at
the draft this doesn't mean you have to
send your entire draft presentation to
your chair we just want to make sure you
have something to discuss with your
chair to make sure that they understand
the flow of your presentation and
overall what that looks like our program
chairs are content experts who can
assist with your presentation along with
any questions you may have April
twenty-eighth is going to be a big
important deadline you need to remember
this is when you send your final
presentation and special easy needs to
your chair so this is going to be your
final cleaned up polished presentation
that you send out to the chair if you
get this to us some time we're able to
post this actually to the website so
conference attendees can access this and
it's just a very handy thing to have
just four speakers if you need a place
to prepare for your session go visit the
co workspace it's a great space to
organize your materials and meet with
your fellow panelists the co workspace
will be located in High Park and it's
available during the maze main two days
of the conference Wednesday May
seventeenth 8 25 30 and then Thursday
day two on the 18th 8 2 for 15 and then
last but not least audio and visual
information like I've mentioned a couple
times because it's important please use
our IPP branded PowerPoint if you're
going to be utilizing a PowerPoint for
your presentation if you're on a panel
please combine panel as presentations
into one deck you're required to bring
your presentation on a USB key and our
standard AV setup for each session room
includes the following items if you have
something you don't see below let us
know by April twenty-eighth and we'll do
our best to accommodate your needs this
includes projector screen audio laptop
podium podium mic cable mics and a slide
advancer and i'm going to pay it back to
Sam to tell you a little bit more about
how you can promote your session that is
wonderful Amanda that might be the best
operational details have ever been
presented on our last call absolutely
spectacular so I want to just emphasize
a couple of points there one is the
deadlines the sad gray non headshot is a
real thing right so I'm deciding which
one to go to and I click on the speakers
and I see the sad grey head shot there's
no way I'm going to see that person
speak because who wants to listen to a
sad grey head shot speak that's awful so
it's in your own best interest to get
your smiling face up there unfortunately
if you're attending this and you put it
in your calendar you're probably one of
the people that got us a head shot so
i'm probably speaking to people who
follow the rules but we're going to
emphasize that anyway more importantly
is the deadline around getting your
presentation in the reason we ask for
this is because we post all the
presentations that we get so that people
can download the slides in real time as
they are watching you present should
they should they want to this will keep
people saying hey we're going to get a
copy of the slides can you email me the
slides you'll be able to say right in
your presentation go right online click
the download presentation you can have
it immediately it is it's a great way to
keep people focused in the room and make
sure they can take notes and all that
kind of stuff yeah this is dave i wanted
to also jump in and underscore something
unless mentioned a moment ago and that
is to review your session description
online one piece of criticism that we
sometimes get following the conference's
is that I went to the session I walked
in the room I sat down and I was
expecting to hear one thing and I heard
something very different so please know
that people do read those session
descriptions and they use them to decide
what sessions they want to go to
oftentimes when they have two or three
they want to go to they choose yours
because they really want to be there and
they're expecting to hear what was
reading up in that paragraph so that
paragraph doesn't matter so please
review it and make sure that it matches
the content as close as possible to
deliver in the room great point day that
is certainly high amongst the list of
criticisms we
the panel wasn't what I thought it was
all right so we want to make sure that
you as volunteers also get sort of as
much exposure and benefit as you can
also if you want to drum up attendance
that you can do so we have a number of
publications here at the IEP p that you
can take advantage of dave as i said
earlier heads up all of our web
conferences if you think there is an
ancillary web con topic that would help
kind of set up your session or if you
think there's a deep dive after the fact
that would extend the message there dave
is always looking for web conferences
especially in Canadian realm yes
absolutely we need to check that box for
our CIP PC holders that they can get
their CPS this is a great way to do it
is to use some of these Canadian
specific presentations you can present
to the 500 people who show up at
symposium but then you can also present
to the world at large it can make sense
similarly privacy perspectives is our op
ed page if yours is opinion focused you
might want to tee up your presentation
that way the advisor is more of our
how-to operational piece privacy tracker
looks at the progression of laws and
moves to the system privacy tech is for
as you might expect the technology that
drives privacy if you think your
presentation could be Twp or augmented
or anything like that please let us know
and we'll get one of our editors in
touch with you and we'll get that ball
rolling the other thing you can do is
you know if you're one of those social
media types don't tell Facebook but I am
no longer on Facebook myself because it
was making my life demonstrable worse
but should you be one of those people
that enjoys the social media experience
let us know about that too because we
actually have it as part of our social
media plan to you no call out and
welcome as many of our speakers as
possible to our event we want to use our
privacy pros at calais on twitter or our
facebook page to link up with our
speakers and draw attention to the great
work that you're doing so
you know hit us up with an ass on
Twitter or tag us on Facebook and we
will return the favor you know what
we're definitely if you've got a handle
on Twitter and you and you're using it
off and let us know about that and we'll
get our social media team working on
that so I've just we've just rambled for
a little bit there is a QA bar right
there on the right-hand side of your
screen that's where you can type in
questions and we can address them now is
the time to type in any questions about
operations or leading up to the event or
PowerPoint details although I'm going to
go a little bit more into power points
in a second if you've got any questions
feel free to chime in and I will address
them as they come in so do know that
that's an opportunity for you so second
half of our piece is you know how to
have in a successful presentation at our
vet one of the things that we get a
question on all the time is you know who
are these people what kind of people
come to your event so to set the stage
we get you know a lot of variety and the
people that attend especially in Canada
we have you know a lot of first-time
attendees people who are have to go
figure this privacy thing out and we are
the largest privacy event in Canada so
they show up we also have veterans who
have been coming for the entirety of the
ten years of the conscious existence
there's a wide spectrum as you saw we
are very heavy in the public sector we
are very heavy in the healthcare sector
so you can expect to have those sorts of
people in your room and one of the
things that we encourage people to do is
write out the back i'ma do a check of
who is in the room do we have a lot of
veterans do we have a lot of rookies
that might help you sort of frame your
event frame your presentation and the
other thing to do is use those veterans
if you see them in their the IEP is
very tight as a membership organization
our veterans love to help and take part
you know use them if you see veterans
raise their hands use the Socratic
method to call them and ask them about
their experiences ask them to you know
augment something you're saying with
seeing whether that jives with their
experience that that's something that's
usually pretty successful in rmx so the
full points are seeing a pretty
self-explanatory will move forward from
this here so you know ask those
questions at the beginning to figure out
who they are you know one of the things
that we do get often is I couldn't apply
this information it was a little bit too
basic I wanted to get a little deeper
into the specific details people love
real-world anecdotes if you can take a
general sort of policy idea and make
that practical and show about how that
plays out in the actual sort of
workplace that's what people want right
so you know we've seen the eye appt
volved quite a bit in the last five
years it's it's moved from the what is
privacy how do i create a privacy policy
to how the heck do i actually do this
how do I staff up whose job is that
which person is in charge of that who do
I talk to how long is that going to take
what form do I use you know all those
nitty gritty details are where we are in
privacy right now especially in the
Canadian public sector where they've
been doing privacy for a little while
now this isn't brand new stuff they are
going to want you know tips of you know
very applicable quality yeah let me let
me jump in and just emphasize what Sam
was just saying again this is did you
can't say this strongly enough we
another complaint that we frequently get
as Sam mentioned is it was too high
level or even worse I just spent an hour
sitting in a room hearing people lay out
problems that I know existed and that we
all know existed really what people want
to hear are your anecdote
and certainly of course your success
stories ways you've found to overcome
the obstacles you have in your day they
work but if you're willing and
courageous enough they also want to hear
your fails right I want to hear what
what what we're wrong what you did about
how what you learn from it seriously we
get some very positive feedback when
people are willing to say hey this is
something that we tried to the problem
we encountered didn't work quite right
we were able to tweak it and make it
happen eventually and so those are the
kinds of things that people really value
we have a few questions coming in let's
take a look at those forward move on
interaction think of splitboards yeah
people definitely use flipboard's from
time to time if you see your panel being
you know very interactive that's
something that we can get we you know
generally have those available providing
our key to so there will be a Navy
person in each room so just bring your
USB that you know kind of stand there
awkwardly at the front and the AV person
will come and take care of you we have
laptops set up already ready to rock and
roll in each room so you just throw that
key in there drag it down try not to
give us any special malware that we're
gonna have to deal with later but that's
no problem at all see yes we went
through the uniform presentation
template because people were showing up
with the wrong aspect ratio their fonts
were breaking and flipping off the page
you know it was just ugly stuff in our
technicians we're having to scramble or
speakers we're having to scramble to get
everything looking right if you would
like to put your organization's logo in
the corner that the IEP p logo is not in
that's fine that's something that people
do but of course you know we are keeping
ourselves as far away from a sales pitch
as possible you may or may not have a
sponsored session and we understand the
goal there is to get in front of people
but as you're going to hear me say later
anything that smells like a self
promotion or sales presentation is going
he frowned on there that last question
here is I was able to get a wireless
Mike so not stuck down the podium yes we
do have handheld wireless mics that
shouldn't be a problem those lavalier
mics that clip on to like you know your
collar are a little bit more expensive
so we try to avoid those but the
wireless mic is fine just kind of hold
it up to your face and everything seems
to work pretty well oh and not it
possible to get a breakout room near our
presentation room so you can split the
group up in two to four case studies now
we can't have a second room we just
rooms are expensive so they're all full
up for sure can we see the setups for
the pre conference ahead of time and
change to facilitate the session yeah we
can show you how the room is going to be
set up for sure generally we have them
set in rounds for the workshops but we
can look into that Larry reach out to
watch your reach out to Amanda and
she'll get that information for you
because we do set up the rooms
differently and if it's a way that's not
good for that we'll figure it out
alright so let's let's keep moving
through the making the session more
advanced so this is a something that we
get feedback on a lot is even though it
seems kind of silly sometimes having
that agenda at the beginning of the
session so people kind of know where
it's going to start middle and end and
what you're trying to accomplish
sometimes that seems pretty obvious by
the abstract but we do get that feedback
fairly often people want to kind of
orient themselves know where they are in
the presentation this third bullet point
is really important if you're working
with multiple panelists a to emphasize
Amanda's point earlier there's one slide
deck we're not changing slide decks in
the middle of a presentation the days
where you know he was even remotely
amusing that you were bumbling around
with your powerpoint at the front of the
room are long over
right we want this to get up and get
going none of this homo I can't figure
out how to do this now that's things so
make sure they're all smashed into one
amanda can help you with that if need be
also you know make sure you've
coordinated with all of your panelists
even though each of you might be
speaking for 20 minutes and you you know
really have three separate pieces to
your how long presentation just make
sure that you're not rehashing stuff
that someone else has covered it's
always nice to get on a call so you have
a little rapport with each other and you
know you kind of have some idea of how
things are going to work and again we
are happy to help coordinate those
conference calls if you need them to we
have a conference line and we are happy
to coordinate speakers if that's
something that you need to have happened
let me jump in there quickly saying that
just say that we are actually very
willing to do that so take advantage of
that obviously we have a lot of
experience with these things and we're
happy to host that call and to give you
some feedback and some advice in terms
of how long a person speaks and how to
mix up the voices etc etc so take
advantage of us as a resource here and
do reach out if you want some help
coordinating your panel alright let's
keep it moving here uh so these active
learning techniques are not going to
spend a ton of time on them their most
relevant to our workshops presentations
that are you know more of the three and
four hour variety than the one our
breakout sessions but I want to put them
in front of you because you know the
research is out there it is almost
impossible now for people to pay
attention to someone speaking from the
beginning from the front of the room for
more than 20 minutes right so if you are
speaking without interruption at the
front of the room after 20 minutes
everybody is checking their phone there
is not a single person listening to you
anymore they have checked out they're
seeing what's ali's up to with a soccer
game and you know slaking their team at
home it's really important that you take
some time even an hour break up session
to reengage people and to check in with
them these are some ways to get people
active I'm not saying that all of them
are practical for an hour but perhaps
you can
take a little bit out of it so the
teacher practice and game it this is
just giving people a chance to sort of
work with it themselves right so if
you're talking about plain language in
privacy policy you might show them you
know a good example of plain language
then you might have them practice taking
something that's legal gobbledygook and
turning it into plain language and then
maybe you have a contest to see you know
whose plain language is voted by the
room as the most plain you know there's
a variety of ways to do that but there's
really good educational research that
shows giving people a safe space to
practice and then having them do some
competition is a great way to reinforce
learning having them talk to each other
if you can just take three or four
minutes in the middle of your
presentation and give somebody a
question to ask their neighbor and have
them talk amongst themselves for three
minutes and then bring them back
together our people love that right as a
good networking thing you know
especially you know at a conference
where maybe people don't know each other
hey it's an excuse where I have to talk
to somebody they get a little human
interaction the Socratic method the
personal favorite of mine you know point
somebody out in the front row and ask
them what is this what they experience
or where are they from or what did they
learn from you know X experience that
was bad or good that happened to them
bring them out of themselves force them
to participate put them on the spot you
know maybe their ears go red for a
second but it's a great way for
everybody to reengage even if they think
gosh I hope he doesn't call me next this
idea of listening teams this is
something that's really going through
the educational circles is make them
into active listeners with a job right
before you present a specific topic tell
one half of the room that their job is
to listen for poking holes in your
argument and the other is listening for
the job of summarizing what your
argument was they will listen to
differently and they will report out
different things and that can force them
to think in different ways and they're
listening with a job they're not passive
they have a plan of attack and they
they're listening for certain cues and
what you're saying this can be a really
great way to engage them the host with
the most this is one of my favorite ones
is use superlatives somewhere either in
the middle or the end to have some
questions what's the most interesting
thing that we talked about what was the
the newest thing that we talked about
what's the most irrelevant thing that we
talked about that will get them thinking
sort of in different ways about what
they learned not just what they learned
the let's get physical or visual this is
just a reminder that everybody has
different learning modalities some
people learn well visually some people
learn with some physical interactions
some people are very auditory some
people learn better if they repeat it
out loud you know one of the examples
that I use here is you're talking about
privacy operations management have them
start out by drawing a picture of a
house that represents their privacy
program is it's small does that a lot of
rooms in it is it broken down is it
well-funded is it made out of brick is
it made out of straw you get some really
interesting things they're kind of spurs
them to talk about what they're doing
the quizzical is to ask maybe halves of
the room to come up with you know if
they pretend that you were making a test
to ask people what they learned in this
session you know what would you ask have
them come up with the quiz questions
you'll often be interested in what they
focused on and then finally I know that
role playing you know if there's
something that's going to get you to
roll your eyes it is role playing you
know we've all been in an awful HR
training where we had to do this however
it's very important to get people to
think about the other person's shoes
right so put them through a very brief
exercise where one person is the CP oh
and the other person is the regulator
how do they come at the issue
differently
or one person is the customer and one
person is the CP oh how might they
interpret the law differently but the
more you can do to get people into you
know other methods of thinking the
better I know that was very quick but if
you have any questions on that or you
want some tips on how to work those into
your presentation let me know alright so
we had a lot of questions about
PowerPoint PowerPoint sucks we all know
that however you know it can be a
helpful way to present some information
you know what's the sort of state of the
art with powerpoint now again use our
template don't try to get anything too
fancy that's going to break on you know
whatever machine we happen to use no
need for like the transitions where
things blow up my daughter is a heavy
PowerPoint user now in the eighth grade
she really likes the confetti that you
know everything blows up to and
transitions I think that's great for
eighth grade powerpoints maybe not for
you know business conference any longer
you know keep those bullet points nicely
focused like you see on this slide here
the one caveat here is if you are giving
a PowerPoint presentation in Japan I've
learned that if there's not 50 valid
bullet points on there they don't
consider it real or at least that's my
impression from going to presentations
in Japan they loved and heavy detailed
2.5 m it all on there oh they love it
let's keep going the other thing is that
you guys can read this here but we get
this question a lot do I have to have a
PowerPoint no absolutely not if you're
just doing a panel discussion don't feel
like you need to have a PowerPoint at
all introduce yourselves and have a have
a great discussion and give people some
information no problem however one of
the reasons we do encourage powerpoints
is because people do download them after
the fact this is a way to give people
information that they can use after the
event so you see this last bullet point
here an additional Reese
sources slide is something that our
attendees really welcome just a list of
links where they can dive in deeper or a
link to some videos where you know maybe
you've presented in more depth on a
certain piece of this topic that's a
great reason to have a PowerPoint even
if it's four slides and the last one is
an additional resources that can be
something that's really helpful for
people so that they can get a little
more sort of bang out of there one hour
breakout session buck yeah and on that
note I want to also state that we do get
a lot of requests for the slides after
the presentation you might consider
thinking about the PowerPoint as an
ancillary resource to your talk so
making reference to it like you know
there's some there's a lot of stuff up
in here you know feel free to peruse it
after the program i'm not going to go
over it in great detail but there's some
great depth further depth here in the
slides that just multiplies the richness
of the information that you're
presenting think about it as a resource
to be looked at after the presentation
exactly all right so that is pretty much
the whole shebang it looks like we have
a couple of questions here our
presentation wasn't listed in the
brochure is that because there are so
many yes the brochure is meant to just
be sort of a subset you know no sleight
intended if the marketing team didn't
decide yours would like the sexiest one
you know marketing people don't know
anything about anything anyway I'm sure
everybody's is the best and yeah that's
it so I'll twiddle my thumbs here and
talk out loud for another couple of
minutes of anybody else as and the other
questions as I was saying 50 times
earlier amanda is your point of contact
for any speaker conference and logistics
emails Dave and myself are available if
you have content questions your track
chairs are available if you have content
questions the thing that happens the
most often that we would really like you
to do this the right way is if you have
a speaker drop out we need to be
consulted on who that replace in person
is as soon as
possible we will not impugn your
character if one of your speakers drops
out on you we know that happens you
would be shocked by how many
grandmother's died every conference it
is countless dead grandmother's we but
we need to prove that or speaker
replacement surely the person you've
chosen is probably fine but we keep very
careful metrics on the male-female ratio
of our speakers on the organizations
that our speakers represent on the
number of speakers that we have so it's
very important that if there are any
issues with speakers we just are
consulted on that all right that was a
lot of jibber-jabber and I don't see any
qas coming through anybody else have any
topics that I have not covered that you
would like to make sure that we have
covered nobody's shaking their head all
right cool so we really do appreciate
that all of you have volunteer to speak
at our conference this is something that
I sincerely believe which is our
conferences are nothing without the
quality of our speakers the IPP
community is very very lucky to have so
many people willing to volunteer their
time and share their expertise with
their peers and with their community
there's anything we can do to make this
experience more enjoyable for you more
effective for you easier for you
anything at all that is literally Amanda
and Rick's jobs they exist for no other
purpose whatsoever exactly they go home
and twiddle their thumbs until they can
come back and say is there a speaker I
can help right now and if there isn't
they drop into this alternate to spare
you know they can't really move the
ellipse barge over leaves helped a trick
and a matter right you don't want them
to be bored or anything so thank you
guys very much hopefully you have a
great rest of the day and that spring
comes to Canada because it hasn't come
here it's New England yet we'll get it
eventually everybody have a great day
and we'll see you in May in Toronto