bye
[Music]
I got my start in private he nearly 20
years ago to us as the internet and the
world wide web were really beginning to
explode and take off back then I was a
prosecutor focusing on internet fraud
and cybercrime throughout the FTC I
worked on a variety of laws regulations
trainings and workshops and ultimately
in 2006 followed the now-infamous VA
data breach where a laptop was stolen
with over 20 million veterans data I was
appointed by the Chairman to be the
FCC's first chief privacy officer I had
the responsibility of building the FTC's
privacy program from the ground up I was
responsible for the information of
literally hundreds of millions of
Americans and other individuals that
were collected maintained and used by
the Federal Trade Commission being the
Federal Trade Commission's first chief
privacy officer was both challenging and
incredibly interested in part because
the Federal Trade Commission serves as
the federal government privacy regulator
and therefore I had dual
responsibilities I certainly focused on
the FTC's own practices and collection
of PII but it also worked on the FTC's
enforcement regulations workshops and
consumer education relating to issues
around privacy technology and innovation
it was an extraordinary experience that
gave me frontline views of privacy at
the ground level
I was incredibly fortunate at the White
House at the Federal Trade Commission in
my other career opportunities to work
with extraordinary people because
success depends on having great team
members but it also depends on having
support and leadership from the top and
I have that at the White House with the
president in the OMB director I've had
it at the FTC with all the FTC Chairman
I had the pleasure to work for and in
other avenues as well
I left the White House in january of
this year and a lot of people been
asking me what's next I haven't decided
yet but I can promise you that I will
remain actively engaged in the world of
privacy because these are the issues i'm
passionate about issues such as
technology innovation data analytics
artificial intelligence I want to work
on all of these issues I want to help
transform privacy from a compliance
issue to an issue that is about risk to
an issue that helps us promote
innovation promote the white feel
adoption of Technology and helps
consumers embrace new technologies
because that at its core what privacy is
truly about and it's my hope that all
the opportunity to work on global issues
because privacy in 2017 is a global
issue data does not respect
international borders and therefore we
need to work on addressing privacy so
that we have a coherent regime across
the world so that all industry in all
countries can do business and innovate
and bring the great new technology that
we need
anyone who knows me knows how passionate
I am about privacy technology innovation
data governance and responsibility and
therefore receiving this award from ia
PP is both personally and professionally
meaningful in part because there are so
many other individuals who are deserving
of this award this year and to be
selected among the many many capable and
talented people out there in our
profession is an honor I believe that
privacy is the greatest profession that
anyone can be in in 2017 privacy is at
the intersection of law technology and
policy getting the privacy issues right
enables innovation it promotes the
whitetail adoption of Technology it
fosters information sharing so privacy
today there could not be a better
profession and I look forward to the
future working with all of you