[Music]
all right
I hope the announcement was correct I
didn't understand sorry for that so I
work in a relatively large company and
this company releases quite a few web
products and updates them all the time
and that's such a large code base so
surely you have to secure it so that
company employs quite a few security
engineers so people who you know look at
the code and try to make our products
secure and I work in such a team so we
do several things to secure our
applications first of all we try to
write hardened libraries and make our
front-end developers of which there's
we're talking about you know thousands
of developers use them then we try to
make sure that they are using only those
security eyes and not something with
codes on their own so we use for example
all those static analysis or dynamic
analysis of our code base and we also do
security reviews so some people look
manually at the code and make sure
before launch that's it's not vulnerable
and finally we also run our bug bounty
program in case we actually miss some
vulnerabilities so we think about
security from the very early stage of
the application to even after the launch
right so we try to protect our users
using multiple multiple mean multiple
means and that surely means that our
applications end up being secure right
well unfortunately this is not the case
and especially it's not the case for the
cross site scripting bones so this is
the data from our vulnerability rewards
program in last year half of the
payments that we give our external
researchers for finding bugs in our
software is about web bugs in specific
and out of those wet box cross-site
scripting remain
it's the best rewarded let's say
vulnerability type right so it still is
a problem not even for say a simple web
applications but even for applications
written by companies that you know
employ multiple people who are whose
sole job is to protect you those
applications from bugs like this and
yeah I imagine this is also the problem
in our applications in the data other
applications and the data surely shows
that as well so this is I believe from
hacker 1 yes this is from hacker 1 XSS
is a top vulnerability type being being
reported and then rewarded by by those
respective companies also Mozilla
cross-site scripting it's a top
vulnerability now surely there is a
problem now what is this problem in
specific first of all I would like to
narrow down the conversation a little
bit because I'm only talking about the
one subs subset of exercising abilities
which is the Dom base vulnerabilities
the ones let's say introduced on the
client and after looking at this data
after trying to you know reason about
that after trying to understand what is
the landscape that we are talking about
we think we know why democracy still
happens even if you try really hard to
eliminate it first of all don't base
cross-site scripting is very easy to
introduce and second of all it is very
hard to detect especially when we are
talking about complex code bases loud
applications now first a little bit of
refresher if you don't know Dom base
cross-site scripting it's essentially a
property of a JavaScript code so
everything is there in the client in the
browser and you have some flaw
essentially there's data that comes from
the user who can be the attacker so this
data is usually in some strings within
your code base and this data gets passed
around to one of the functions that are
called the Dom XSS things and as soon as
you can you have a chain like that so
data comes from this attacker control
source to the sink that same will call
your web application - well essentially
executes JavaScript right so we have a
remote code execution equivalent in
JavaScript and this is an example right
so a location hash is something that the
attacker can control it's a very common
source of Dom XSS payloads and the inner
HTML property of an element is the same
and once you know this data this data
gets connected the full variable in this
case we have a Dom XSS now I would say
that don't exercise is very very easy to
introduce in your web application this
is part of the problem right first of
all this is obvious as soon as anything
user consult gets passed to this inner
HTML property of the element then you
very clearly you have like this textbook
example of of XSS right but so you could
tell your developers for example well
maybe don't ask user data to in HTML and
then the problem is solved maybe you
want to grab your source code for inner
HTML and make sure that you review every
time something is passed in HTML and
then you have clearly solved on exercise
right well not really because there's
it's not just in HTML right there's a
lot of other things and in each of those
things user data should never have been
passed to them unless it was properly
let's say treated sanitized or escaped
however you want to call it now is this
even a feasible problem to solve like
can you teach your site developers to
you know take special care when
interacting with those sources I would
say it's not really a very easy task and
it is obvious mistakes will happen even
if you do some sort of you know even
gripping some automation around checking
for those things but there's also a
second part of the problem which is it's
not just easy to introduce which can be
exemplified by the fact that probably
the very first web application that you
have ever written as soon as it does any
sort of user data interpolation
you probably have just written an XSS in
your web application right this the web
is full of examples like that but the
second part of the problem is it is very
hard to detect for security
professionals even and let's do a very
short quiz show of hands do you think
this code snippet is introducing a dumb
exercise like raise your hand do you
think it is yes at least one person is
paying attention so yes this is a very
clear example of Dom XSS of course but
what about this one like is this one I
don't exercise yes exactly and this is
actually the coordinate problem
maybe it isn't of exercise you have to
pay additional attention there's some
additional analysis to to figure that
out right you need to know where the bar
comes from now what about this one is
this one of them exercise and the kids
were you wrong
it depends what foo means because if
food for example is a script element
then surely inserting interest into you
know the text body on the script element
you have an equivalent of eval isms
right so yeah this is also problematic
how about this one then can you tell
anything about this line of codes in
isolation
you have no idea right because if buses
use a console or bus is somehow sets to
say inner HTML then you have the
original first problem and obviously
these are just very simplified example
but the problem I'm trying to show is
that to find it on XSS you need to
understand the entirety of the
application every potential line of code
can possibly be using a chain of between
sources and I think that introduces an
XSS so in order to make sure that you do
not have dome exercises you need to
review all of it like you can't just
ignore parts of your code base but that
brings us to a question how do we make
it easier how do we maybe even eliminate
the exercise from the web platform can
we even do it and I would say that yes
we can do it it won't be easy that we
already have
a proposal in place let's say and
solving this requires us to think about
introducing an API that first of all
reduces this attack surface such that
not every line in your codebase is
potentially introducing a dumb exercise
but only you know small parts of it
should be for example reviewed or
analyzed deeply and you could completely
ignore those other parts of the
application and second of all is also
crucial which is making security
explicit so the rules that you use for
example for sanitizing the data or
processing it somehow or filtering it
are parts of your application code you
have to write them essentially and then
they could be reviewed right such that
no no magic is happening for example you
can't pretend that well this data is
actually sanitized because it's very
apparent by just looking at the code
base that some escaping for example is
not being done and the API that is
designed around those principles is
essentially what I wanted to talk to you
about and this is trusted types so
what's the main idea the main idea is we
take a look at all those things that I
mentioned before and we make them
strongly-typed before in the Dom all
those dumb things
say for example in HTML accepted strings
and the strings the problem of strengths
is that you do not know where do they
come from right you need to analyze this
whole code base to make sure that you
know they were not attacker consult here
we shift this problem we make an
abstraction of this problem and we are
trying to address new democracies
through this abstraction so first of all
we make sure that the for example in
HTML doesn't accept strings anymore and
instead we could use object objects to
to pass to inner HTML function the fun
part is that the Dom API already behaves
like that for well years since probably
its inception and you can see a code
exam
of that so for example if you pass an
object that happens to have a two string
function to innerhtml this two string
function will get executed and then the
resulting string will be actually
assigned to to the innerhtml property so
we use this trick essentially but we
introduce those trusted objects those
special types of of the objects that
embed the security information with them
and those three objects depend on the
context because exercise is a very
contextual problem because you need to
sanitize for example URLs you need to
sanitize HTML differently and you may be
you want to control what gets passed -
for example - evil or the script bodies
right so with at least three contexts
that we are talking about so what we
propose is that there will be three new
types of the objects the trusted HTML
for inner HTML and say for example
iframe source doc trusted script which
is something that you usually pass to
for example eval or that you make a
script body from an trusted strip URL
which is fairly obvious this is the URLs
of the script that your application is
loading and once we have introduced
those types you can put all the security
rules and all this meta data around
those types let's see how first of all
we can look at the situation of how a
web application would behave is trusted
types are not enforced right so there is
a support in the browser for trusted
types but the application didn't opt
into being secured by them so what
happens is thanks to this trick that I
showed earlier that you can still use
strings with the things obviously in
this particular case having an XSS but
you can also just as well use those
trusted objects so a trusted HTML
instance can be passed to in HTML and it
will be silently or implicitly unwrapped
by the browser and you will get whatever
was stored in the instance of the object
instead right so your application still
works if you introduce the types
- you're dumb six but you could also
just as well start enforcing it to
actually maybe get some protection so
the way you control trusted type-c is by
integrating with the content security
policy header and there's something in
the CSP lingo it's called the directive
right so you have a trusted text
directive and then there's some data
ignore the data for now but essentially
what happens once your application uses
this CSP header is that while it still
accepts those typed objects it stops
accepting strings right so what happens
is there will be a safety violation sent
to your reporting server for example but
also you will simply get a type error in
your application this is actually a
pretty big property of trusted types
meaning that you can start treating
security bugs in your program in your
program similarly to all other
programming parts you can debug them
using the same tools you can for example
set up a chrome debugger and you know
try to find out why does this error
happens in my application so this is how
trusted types in practice get enforced
in in the browser and thanks to being in
or integrating with the CSP we could
also have a property that is called the
record only mode right so you can get
warnings when strings get assigned to
things that do not break your
application but you still get some
visibility and you can progressively
migrate it to using the only trusted
types but here obviously comes a very
crucial question okay so yeah types cool
idea but how do I actually create those
types right this is this is what the
secret sources and the way you create
types stay with me for a second is you
create policies so we added policies in
your content security policy so we have
like two layers of policies now what
does it mean first of all you use the
trusted types that create policy
function and each policy has first of
all a name more on that later but
a set of functions and those set of
functions define the rules of converting
a string into a given trusted type
object so in this particular case I have
created a policy that will run my custom
sanitizer on the data and only when that
sanitizer says the data is ok and you
know I removed for example all whatever
in line even hunters and whatnot then
you will get an instance of a trusted
object and this happens like this so you
have a reference to the sanitizing
policy variable you call its create HTML
function the sanitizer gets called and
whatever object gets returned from this
policy has the sanitize data inside it
right so the security rules are solely
in the body of this of this policy in
the first example and later on of course
you can use this trusted HTML with the
innerhtml function and now the crucial
part in your application using this
whitelist at the very bottom you can
simply say that in my application and
only accept trusted type policies of the
given names what that means is that only
the code within those two policies has a
capability of introducing Dom XSS to my
application everything the rest of the
application code base cannot possibly
create trusted types so cannot possibly
call the dongsaeng's and therefore
cannot possibly have or cause Dom XSS
there's a couple of caveats
the talk is really short so I will just
ignore them but feel free to you know
talk to me afterwards there are some
questions I can show you describe it in
more details now this becomes a problem
right because this approach means that
you have to migrate all of your
application or at least all of the parts
that use or write - Dom - trusted types
and that's simply a large task now can
we do something to make it simpler to
migrate yes we can first of all
policy but second of all we have created
a concept that is called the default
policy so this is a policy that you can
create on your own and it will be
implicitly called by the browser the
moment you are actually still using
strings with the sink so this is like
this last last best efforts to convert a
string into a type and obviously this
policy better be secure because this is
probably where at least in the beginning
of the migration most of the data will
come through but the logic here is
arbitrary right so for example you may
decide say for example you develop an
environment that I only wants to log
what is happening what is going through
the default policy and fix it as as it
goes right as ID bug this problem and
yeah you can also just whitelist default
policy in the content security policy
and there's also one other thing we
noticed that while a lot of
vulnerabilities Dom XSS vulnerabilities
are being exploited by using the
JavaScript arrays payload it just so
happens that the web applications use
URLs a lot who knew and not a lot of
applications are actually using
javascript to arise in their code bases
at least the modern applications tend
not to depend on them and use other
means of well executing code when
someone clicks on a link so we decided
to just get rid of the JavaScript URLs
and by default if your browser wants to
navigate your JavaScript URL and you
want you are trusted types compliant so
you have this content security policy
header with trusted types then a default
policy will be called on the value of
this JavaScript URL and if the default
policy for example doesn't exist or
doesn't allow for creating trusted
script objects then nothing bad will
happen but this is also a very nice way
of introducing some potential
carving out of certain URLs from from
this policy like for example here I
allow javascript:void 0 which is
harmless but no other payload can
we execute so this is present in the
browsers now this is this is in Chrome
hidden behind the flag and we started
using it in our applications and it the
results are fairly optimistic so how can
you deploy trusted types in a web
application well first of all you try to
migrate the libraries that actually
write to the Dom in your in your web
application that's not a lot of code
that usually is somewhere around where
you have client-side templating
libraries maybe some HTML sanitization
sometimes dynamic script loading only a
couple of places of the web application
actually touch the Dom or process the
data that later on reaches into the Dom
most of the application code is actually
business logic that has no need of
writing to the Dom in practice so first
you migrate those individual libraries
to that that's right to the Dom and up
trusted types to them
second of all trying to do some static
analysis more elaborate or less terrible
elaborate in Google for example we
compile our JavaScript so this becomes
very easy to ascertain but you can also
just as well use some graphing or some
code lenders to make sure that no one is
calling in HTML for example with with a
string right so you know that to the
best of your abilities to the best of
your knowledge your application is
trusted type compliant and then you
start checking that in the browser so
you are the report only policy with some
trusted types directive that star allows
for any any policy names to be created
and then you observe violations because
maybe you missed something and then you
debug and once you debug you actually go
to two so you have to migrate additional
libraries a little bit and then as it
narrows down the violations dropped and
finally what you end up with you can
start enforcing trusted types and what
is a very nice property of it
that maybe you have reviewed this
application for security at say tomorrow
it will also be secure the next year
because no matter what new code gets
introduced to your web application
without changing a cotton security
policy the policy header
no one can add a new policy to your
application therefore no one can even
have the capability of introducing Dom
XSS
let's see some demo so as I said this is
already implemented in the browsers so
this is a chromium the Chrome Canary
browser and this is very simple example
application right so we have an input
text field and you know some buttons
that will use either jump unified HTML
sanitizer or just inner HTML something
right so obviously if you click in HTML
there's a personality cuz this payload
contains JavaScript let's see now if I
sanitize obviously don't purify is very
nice of removing the actual value right
the scientist oh well more on that later
actually
but essentially what don't care if I did
is it removed this on error equals alert
and the data is safe to include into the
Dom now but that happens without the
trusted ties now the problem we are
facing with I want to ascertain that
every time something writes a string
into the Dom don't purify will be called
to sanitize it because I really trust
say Mario hydrate too it will have
written don't purify in a way that you
know Ramon JavaScript so let's start
enforcing this just reloads the page
with the content security policy header
and the moment I call inner HTML or get
a type error right so in the console I
can see that you know inner HTML was
just with a string a little bit so
therefore a vulnerability exploitation
has just been prevented but also my
application kinda broke so that's not
ideal right just to demonstrate if I
sanitize it it's still okay now why is
it okay because I used on purify with
this special mode that we added a couple
of months ago which is called Vita and
trusted type
so don't purify uses its own policy to
create trusted HTML values on the
sanitize data and this is exactly the
property that we are using here so as
you can see it does work with we've done
purify let's say out of the box now if I
try to install a default policy and try
to call this inner HTML function what
happens this is this callback gets
called and I can do any custom logic I
want in this particular case I call Don
purify so let's see that in action
yes the output is actually you know
sanitizing every string data that is
passed in HTML and similar things in my
application so I know for sure that as
long as don't purify is okay with
regards to sanitizing for Dom XSS I have
no no mitosis problems in this very
simple application but obviously this is
not this is just a toy example right so
let me show you something on our actual
application so contacts that google.com
already has some JavaScript code that
uses trusted types and we can see that
in action here right so I can see what
policies were actually created in this
application well there's like seven
policies of various name a little bit
and we think everything is correct we
spent a couple of months migrating all
this code base to tuning HTML and you
could click around for the application
everything seems to work but one part so
if you take a look let's try to edit
something and it some contacts show more
here and try to use it's in report only
mode right so I'm not actually breaking
any code but once I try to do this you
can see that there's a report on the
violations sent and thankfully trusted
types is you know part of your program
now so you can debug it as your regular
violation
so I can click through this and see
what's going on
it seems this function was actually
causing the violation like here I I
guess creating a script and just
assigning any string value to its source
property but I can immediately see that
this is some part of the Google Maps API
based on the address of the script so I
know that we have to now migrate a
Google Maps API into trusted trusted
types which is what we are actually
doing behind the scenes data and of
course on top of all of this you also
have the content security policy reports
being sent in this particular case you
can see that yeah there was something on
this page that violated it just a type
directive which looks like this there's
quite a few names here but it actually
will get simpler later on this is only
the first stages but you know that inner
HTML was assigned this value and this
was the origin of the script let's post
the violation and you know line number
number what so trusted types are usable
on real web applications just as well
and they seem to give really nice
properties with trusted types you get
very nice control over the policies so
first of all you can control the policy
creation and again only by creating the
policy you even have the possibility of
introducing Dom access and by default
you do not have that possibility so you
can control who gets to create the
policy by just using the whities of the
names and of course no duplicates are
allowed by default in this white least
such that no one can just you know
create the policy that whose name was
already allowed but you can also control
the policy usage which is also a very
nice property for JavaScript code
especially which means that even if you
have a policy that's let's say insecure
you can lock it down to only certain
parts of your application and then you
only know that only only the parts of
the code that actually have a reference
to the variable representing the policy
only those parts can introduce Dom
bicycles and scripting so we can lock it
down in a mascot module or inside some
local function
so you can definitely narrow down which
parts of your application can
potentially be vulnerable right and by
reviewing the code of the policies you
can realistically ascertain that your
application is actually secure so what
are the benefits of this approach first
of all it is
it makes web application security fault
and you get tremendously reduced the
attack surface and also review surface
essentially because every data flow that
potentially comes from you know attacker
control sauce and reaches the Dom sink
now has to pass through the policy
because this is the only way you can
reach the don't sink and that makes it
very natural to limit access to creation
of the policies and limit access to the
policies in the first place and helps
you restructure the application in a way
that makes it super easy to review and
this is sort of natural to the
developers and this is what we see
happening already in our code base so it
does isolate the security sensitive code
from the rest of the application and
makes it very easy to support it and
review it for security but also looking
at the offensive side it makes it very
easy of spotting it and reviewing it for
bugs which is cool so you get this very
nice properties and that lets you reduce
the attack surface which I believe is
the main advantage of this and similar
api's we you can already start using the
trusted types with say react you just
have to recompile it essentially
changing one one property you can use it
moved on purify worse many other
libraries that we are working on
integrating and this feature is
implemented in chromium you have to use
enabling features with trusted Dom types
there's you know w3c specification draft
so we are you know working on getting
this adopted as a web standard there's a
polyfill burst documentation so I think
by now we have a chance of stopping Dom
XSS as a vulnerable class completely and
our early results show that this
approach actually works so take a look
at the
repository on github find some bugs some
of them that were reported by the bug
hunters were really amazing so do take a
look
start maybe using it in Chrome and see
how it goes give us feedback maybe we
can work on something maybe we can
improve this API but so far it looks
like for the first time since 18 years
we actually have a chance of fixing Dom
XSS which is nice and this is the end of
the presentation I will happily take
some questions
[Applause]