[Music]
hi hello everyone my name is Johan or
minin and this is app set as default RC
client for the next 45 minutes or so I'm
going to be talking to you a little bit
about electron scheme handlers and how
to exploit those in apps to gain remote
code execution this talk is based on
research I started working on in early
2019 and this is the first time I'm able
to talk about it publicly but most of
the vulnerabilities you'll be seeing
here have already been fixed some of
them even before I ran into them the
interesting thing about that is though
that electron hasn't really published
any advisories about them so developers
mostly aren't aware that there are any
issues and there's no incentive to fix
those outdated apps and so old versions
of electron are still being used in the
name of transparency I should also
mention that literally a week ago I
joined one of the companies building one
of the apps named in these slides so
they're sort of a sort of a conflict or
potential potential conflict of interest
there but all the research was made
before I joined the company and that
hasn't really affected anything I'll be
presenting here today let's start off
with a quick introduction to electron
and neuron now that may sound like
nuclear physics or something really the
only thing these two have in common with
nuclear physics is the end result if you
don't know what you're doing I'll
demonstrate that a bit later on but
basically no one likes a nuclear
meltdown so anyway if you're not
familiar with electron what it is what
it essentially is is just a hybrid
desktop app framework it lets you write
HTML and JavaScript and make web make
desktop applications using those web
technologies without going into too much
detail it's technically just the Chrome
browser bundled with no js' and some
custom API is then there's also mirin
which is well originally started as an
electron fork with better security but
it's just a fork of electron and the
unfortunate thing about that is that
even though the original intentions were
good
they wanted to hold an electron the muon
fork is no longer now maintained and
that means it's hopelessly on outdated
and vulnerable to all kinds of things
so while electron is certainly more
popular of the two new and still has its
users also and those users aren't
getting any security patches so a while
ago in 2018 electron patched a CVE I
conveniently named CVE
2018 1 million and 6 and this was a
remote code execution vulnerability that
was affecting Windows and at the root of
it was an API call named app dot set as
default protocol client invoking that
function app set as default protocol
client would register your application
as the default scheme handler for a
particular URI scheme and you could use
it for example to set your application
as the default mail to handler
for your email or you could use a custom
scheme to support deep linking in your
chat app that actually seems like a
fairly common use case deep linking but
the way they play actually does its
trick is by looking up a tee in the
Windows registry based on the scheme
handler that's being registered or the
scheme itself and then it sets a value
to point to the executable that should
be executed when one of those types of
links is clicked in order to pass the
actual uri to the the executable it uses
a simple format string where here you
have percentage one which would just end
up end up being replaced with uri itself
so that actually means that because it's
sort of naive replacements if you
include any special characters like
double quotes or spaces in that URI you
end up injecting additional command-line
parameters a switch is what that
actually entails for your application
depends on the command lines which is
your application supports but in the
case of CDE 2018 one million and six it
turned out that Chrome which is bundled
with electrum natively supported
launching arbitrary commands from the
command line so you would have a remote
code execution vulnerability simply by
clicking a link in practice the way it
would work you'd have crafted URI URI
like this one which points to the
vulnerable URI scheme and it contains a
double quote space and the dash dash GPU
launcher switch all that needs to happen
is for the user to click on this link on
on
a machine that has the vulnerable
application installed and you know
electron just does the rest that happens
so really simple this would obviously
back patched already way back in 2018
but the way electron decided to approach
the patching was somewhat interesting
the original patch was actually nothing
more than a blacklist of all known
command lines which is that chromium
supported natively that was over
thirteen hundred switches and it's just
a list of those switches in the source
code and that was obviously very easy to
bypass there were plenty of bypasses and
have been already and some have some
have been found later let's look at some
of those bypasses in just a moment
just a second my slides froze yeah let's
look at some of those in just a moment
but before I get to the actual meat of
this presentation I just want to credit
some other folks who have done research
in this area so Dorian SiC were probably
the first ones to actually bypass CV
2018 1 million and 6 they have a public
write-up of it of the bypass on their
blog they also published this tool
called electronegativity that's
available available also online it's
open source there was also a very
interesting talk by Thomas Shadwell at
infiltrate 2019 he talked about modern
desktop applications so the scope of
that talk was a bit wider than mine is
here but it's worth looking it's
available on vimeo if you like to see it
afterwards and then there's talk from
Andrea's link from security fest 2016
where he talked about hacking matter
most which is actually actually one of
the applications are this talking
talking about
anyway back to the matter at hand as it
turns out in February 2019 when I
started looking at these apps plenty of
them were still vulnerable to something
awfully similar to CV 28:28 in 1 million
and six and what I have for you is three
separate cases sort of examples
two of them are specific to certain
applications and one is more generic
affecting electron as a whole so let's
start from the top
the first one is matter most matter most
is a chat app sort of like slack but
open source and self hosted and whatever
and like slack it has a desktop client
that's built on top of electron there
were three things in that desktop client
that led to RC when combined first of
all the matter most desktop app has a
command-line switch that allows you to
specify a custom user data directory
this is where the application stores all
all its local data including
configuration files and and anything
that's stored locally there was no bug
here but it's an important part of the
export chain anyway secondly because
we're talking about Windows here UNC
paths are supported universal naming
convention or UNC is just a different
way of specifying file system parts but
their twist to that which is that unlike
local paths UNC supports network paths
so SMB shares on remote servers and
Microsoft even often refers to UNC
process as network paths thirdly the
application was loading configuration
files in an insecure way so that
you if you're able to to inject
malicious stuff into your configuration
files then you could gain code execution
this was actually a bug and this has
been fixed and matter most has also
implemented some additional mitigation
but I won't go into those in too much
detail so these are screenshots from the
source code of the matter most desktop
clients these are from the same source
file from a piece of code that loads a
configuration file and tries to restore
the options of a previously closed
window so at the top you can see how
it's accessing the file system and
loading a bound info that JSON file and
then parsing that using the JavaScript
native JSON parser at the top at the
bottom you can see how it's then passing
that object directly to the browser
window constructor there's no validation
in between it's just being read from the
file and then being passed to the
constructor the idea here is to set the
dimensions of a window that's been
previously closed so that you can always
have the same sized windows but if you
look at the electron documentation this
is from the browser window API
documentation there's something that's
rather concerning namely that the
options parameter here which was just
read from a file and then being passed
into the constructor without any
validation it supports plenty of other
options besides just window width and
height so for example there's web
preferences and web preferences is an
object that contains another property
which is called preload and the preload
property while the documentation for
that
says that any script that the preload
property refers to is loaded
automatically and executed which is sort
of really bad but then it also has
automatically access to all no jsap eyes
regardless of your sandboxing settings
or anything else
so these preload scripts always have
access to to the privilege shape the ice
and nodejs means native code execution
as well so to put it all together
we started in we be crafted URI the URL
contains a double quote space and then
the injected command-line switch which
is attached - data dir but then the
value of the lease which refers to a UNC
path on a remote server on a on an
attacker controlled SMB share so when a
user clicks on this link the application
starts up and starts loading
configuration files and writing
configuration files that those aren't
local those are actually on the network
on someone else's SMB share and the
boundary info Jason file is loaded the
bouncing for file refers to a preload
script named payload Egeus and that's
automatically executed which means you
know you just got owned
the next app example number two I
unfortunately can't name this one they
didn't fix their vulnerabilities in time
mainly because they're still using muon
which is an unmaintained fork and it's a
pain to migrate away from that so yeah I
can't name the application but I still
talk about the interesting technical
details here so the attack starts with a
fairly similar pattern the executable
supports a command-line switch to
specify the user data directory just
like the previous app and it accepts UNC
paths so you can specify a network path
but what's different here is that there
wasn't anything in the configuration
files that could be used to trigger code
execution directly so I had to come up
with something else
I turned out interesting was that the
developers had made some assumptions
related to how Windows processes local
paths so Windows is fairly restrictive
when it comes to file system paths you
can't can't have too many special
characters in directory names for
example but when you have UNC paths you
can have files that are somewhere remote
and the remote server doesn't have to be
a Windows so what if you have a Linux
server that's naming files in a Linux
way and then you have a Windows client
that's loading those files and are so
assuming that your files can't have any
funny names that's where things go wrong
so yeah suddenly the developers
assumptions no longer held here's again
a screenshot of the source code this is
from the debugger I've had to alter it a
little bit so that I wouldn't reveal the
name of the application but it's pretty
easy to spot where the actual injection
here happens the code is calling
PowerShell directly and then passing the
user data directory into a PowerShell
command as is without any validation but
the interesting part is that before this
code was executed there was there were
file system operations happening locally
that were using this path so if that
path wasn't the valid part then the
application would crash earlier on and
that meant that you couldn't inject for
example double quotes or the dollar
symbol because those aren't valid as
local path names but they are valid as
UNC path names because UNC paths can
refer to Linux servers so let's exploit
this one again we have a crafted URI and
we inject the user data path but now
also the user data path contains an
injection it's referring to a remote
server and it contains a dollar symbol
and parentheses and a character exe so
when a user clicks on this link config
files are being loaded I know written
into but there's no actual injection
there or anything like that
only if it can't write the config files
then the application crashes those sort
of server still has to be there
but there's no injection happening there
instead later on the application does a
separate call to PowerShell which then
you know this happens so yeah be careful
with UNC paths going forward case number
three this one was a bigger problem
because this is all of electron so it's
fairly common convention for
command-line utilities and everything
that can be called from the command line
to support this sort of - - syntax for
separating or rather ending the
processing of command-line switches so
if you end your command with - - and
space than anything you enter after that
isn't considered a command-line switch
and electron supports that supports that
as well and actually one of the main
workarounds mentioned by Electra and
developers - as a workaround to CVD 2081
1 million and 6 the official workaround
was to include this double - in your
invocation of the app set as default
protocol client API that way you
wouldn't allow an attacker to pass any
additional parameters but because the
original touch was based on comparing
command-line switches a list of command
lines which is against the invocation of
the app it would also make sense to stop
processing that blacklist once it found
the once you found the double - that's
supposed to end your processing of
command-line switches so that's what
they actually did the only problem was
that well
electron sort of supports those dashes
because chromium supports those dashes
but electron consists of chromium and
nodejs and no js' didn't support those
dashes so no js' parsing continued after
the delimiter which meant that well bad
things happened this is from the
screenshot of the back list earlier on
and you can see the blacklist
starts with two very dangerous notes
which is these two switches enable
remote debugging so a remote attacker
would be able to remotely enable remote
debugging so yeah that's way too many
remotes this was patched in electron 3.0
and the patch was also back ported to
two point something we decide thing
about that is that electron doesn't
mention effects in the 3.0 release notes
at all it's actually tagged as no notes
the release and the 2.0 point 9 release
notes only mention this patch has
something related to DNS rebinding which
doesn't really make sense at all so it's
not surprising that you'll still find
these applications using 33.0 you know
electron so yeah there's no public
signal that would indicate that there's
something wrong
and yeah boy was disease eg exploits I
went through the electron application
directory they published this list of
applications that are built on top of
electron I went through that and looked
at some of the more popular ones some of
the more big-name ones I ended up with
our Series in VK messenger in postman in
the epic remain yet in hyper which is an
election based terminal emulator and in
missive which is an email app and by no
means did I comb through everything so
there's hundreds of apps in the
application directory I only looked at
maybe 20 of them and I found five apps
that were vulnerable to this out of
twenty
for for one last time let's go through
the exploit flow here's the crafted you
arrived this one's for became messenger
there's the double quote a space two
dashes and then the inspects which we
are binding to zero zero zero zero in
order to make the debugger public and
once you click on this the value of
inspects gets passed to the no GAF
debugger so that starts listening on TCP
port five eight five eight which comes
from the command line and just waiting
for the connections to arrive the
attacker who has a remote machine
connects to the IP address of the victim
and uses the chrome dev tools protocol
to launch an arbitrary command it's just
that simple
now I have a couple of demos let's see
if those work because this is a live
demo
I have them here so this is a Linux
server or rather a representation of a
Linux server virtual machine it's
actually Kali Linux and then I have
another virtual machine which is the
Windows victim let's start off with the
matter most exploit I have here my SMB
configuration I'm setting defining a
share here in the matter most directory
making it public and making it writable
I also have here if I look into the
maximals directory if I look into the
matter most type directory I have a
balance Jason puncheon for JSON file and
I have a payload file I can also look at
the balancing for JSON file so you can
see it's referring to the payload file
and the payload is nothing complicated
it's just requiring the child process
and executing dot exe so the way
this works is I have a malicious web
page here on the victims machine it has
a link a link pointing to a matter most
URI which when I click on it edge will
ask me if I want to open matter most
sure I'm just trying to visit some chat
window or whatever let's open that and
it pops up the calculator in the
background it's making a SMB call to the
server and loading configuration files
and then executing from there
the victim would never know that
anything like this happened the other
demo I have is for VK messenger this one
works a bit differently so the way this
one works is I start with the link I
click on the link first and launch VK
messenger and now it's already silently
in the background listening for incoming
connections from my malicious server so
let's let's make that happen I have here
a tool which I've written I have node
dev exit which takes as its parameters a
domain name or rather a host name let's
specify that and then a port and a
payload and when I call but suddenly
here B okay something's not working as
expected
demo effects
let's try that again
demo effect
oh yes the hostname was wrong yeah five
eight five eight and Kappa the exit now
that should work suddenly we have the
calculator popping up here so that's as
simple as that now let's go back to
these slides if we can somehow
yes
okay so you saw there was a command-line
tool I was using that's actually just a
simple wrapper for a chrome remote
interface which is a publicly available
client for the dev tools protocol you
could obviously do the same thing using
the dev tools integrated with the Chrome
browser but using the command line is a
bit quicker especially when you're
testing multiple apps in a row the tool
is available on github already so if you
memorize the URL URL at the bottom of
the screen you can actually go there and
download it now but if you don't want to
start memorizing that you can just
remember eyes my username instead and
I'll make the gist public after this
talk it's private at the moment but I'll
make it public after afterwards
anyway my work obviously didn't end when
I managed to hack all the apps that's
not how it works
someone had to fix those bugs and that
meant coordinating disclosure and
talking with vendors and you know I
tried to find the easy way out and just
that just ended up with me doing twice
the amount of work here's a few lessons
from that so I haven't been in contact
with electron but they've done quite a
bit sorry
okay let's yeah let's go through this
one first so as I mentioned all of this
started in February 2000 19 I was
casually poking at one of the apps when
suddenly all hell broke loose and I had
seven arsons on my hands disclosing all
of those privately one by one would have
been a huge effort especially when many
vendors still today don't publish proper
security conducts and don't you know
even behave politely towards researchers
I wanted to come up with some better
strategy so the obvious solution was
Trend Micro's zero day initiative they
by research and reports vulnerabilities
responsibly to vendors so that would
allow me to have a single point of
contact and let them take care of
contacting the vendors so that's what I
did
if I connect contacted CDI and reported
these two to CBI
I submitted my reports near the end of
February and just a couple of days later
I got a response already it just wasn't
quite what I had hoped for so without
even looking at the exploits or the
vulnerabilities GDI had already
determined that they weren't interested
in five out of the six apps they just
didn't want any anything to do with
those so they wouldn't buy those
anyway the usual response was super
quick but one app was still remaining
but they didn't comment on they didn't
say anything about being a messenger so
apparently they were interested in that
one unfortunately the process from there
onwards was not as quick as the start
had been so it was basically complete
radio silence from zdi for the next
three whole months what was more
disappointing was the response I finally
got so in in June
GDI emailed me and told me that they had
tested the VK messenger exploits and
they had come to the conclusion that
this doesn't work it's not a valid
exploit
it's not working and what had happened
is that three months had gone by and
became messenger had already upgraded
the version of a lecture and they were
using it was no longer exploitable CDI
was testing the latest version and that
had one ability anymore
so since ZT I wasn't interested in any
of my exploits I had to report them
individually to all the vendors anyway
and I had to retest everything because
it had been so long since I originally
found them that others might have six
tears as well luckily VK wasn't the only
only one who had implemented fixes so I
didn't have to contact all six different
vendors
I just had to contact a couple of couple
of them and they ended up with me
working on one of those apps full-time
as a security security professional
product security engineer so all's well
that ends well
so since since 2018 since even 20 18
months 1 million and 6 electron has done
a whole bunch of things
the original blacklist
they implemented is well it's been
updated and it's been updated again and
now it's you know it's no longer 1300
items it's zero items now they're no
longer using the back listing of
approach at all they've also twice
changed the way they handle command
lines which is the good thing is that
I'm not currently aware of any any way
to exploit the origin ability so I think
they have it in sort of a good order at
the moment the bad thing is that they
still haven't published any advisories
about this after CV 2018 1 million and 6
and URI handlers are still being
registered in the same way so they
haven't addressed the root cause of the
issue they've just changed the way
they're sort of mitigating the issue on
top of that
but anyway developers still don't know
that there was something wrong in the
original touch Microsoft has also done
some things so the major thing that you
might notice that if is that if you try
one of my exploits here on an up-to-date
Windows 10 machine you can no longer
open any of the malicious links from
Internet Explorer or Microsoft edge
because those no longer allow special
characters in URLs instead they
automatically silently escape percentage
encode special characters so that for
example space becomes percentage 20 you
can still open those types of links from
other apps though so so the windows
patch isn't foolproof for the developers
and security people who are probably
here in the audience there's a couple of
interesting takeaways from this so first
of all the app got set as default
protocol client is a very dangerous API
and scheme handlers in general are a
very dangerous attack surface it's
difficult to even spot all the things
that can go wrong with them
and if you find find yourself using one
of those or looking at the code base
that does use one of those those you
should probably think twice that he says
this be something that really has to be
here is it actually necessary and if
it's necessary is it being used
correctly secondly platform features
like Windows support of UNC can have
really unexpected side effects if you're
not accounting for them even if you're
working on a cross-platform application
on the platform in ten independent
framework
you should also aim to know the
platform you're actually shipping those
applications on otherwise you might end
up shooting yourself in the foot
and finally electron has this bad habit
of not publishing security issues and
sufficiently informing the developers
about them so it's critical to keep your
frameworks up to date even if there's no
publicly documented vulnerability in
that framework since May electron has
also adopted this 12-week release cycle
whether release a new major version of
electron every - every 12 12 weeks in
order to keep up with six weeks cycle of
chromium and so that means that because
they only support the last three major
releases if you're deploying an
application now you're going to have to
upgrade the framework in around eight
months or you end up with an unsupported
version
that's all I had thanks for your time
amazing thank you you have poured the
presentation