[Music]
so hello I'm in which is result and I
will present some other exploits today
on SB such too and I hope you will enjoy
so I'm almost always limited by the time
the money and sometimes my skills too
and I try to publish some results here I
come from the offensive side and I will
focus on other and lot of Elvan urology
no affiliations of course so it's time
to play now so Jen three points few
months ago I decide to investigate into
the ESP search tool it's a well-known
system on chips today release in 2016 by
a specific angle company it's widely
deployed today as I sold a lot of
devices more than 100 millions they
became the market leader of wireless
seems us free market and they claim to
have state of gia security and they
support obvious longevity commitment so
it's quite nice and you can find these
chips in a lot of IOT devices and
sometimes you can also find these chips
as wireless peripheral to add
connectivity to existing devices so
target is this one it's ESP search tool
they manufacture the chip in 40
nanometer technology packages - 6 basis
millimetre 48 pins and this is some some
features I will not detail all of the
features of course
but you have an integrated modem
supporting Wi-Fi and Bluetooth
it's ultra-low power it's based on
extensors Jolla cost LX 6 you can rent
until 240 minutes a lot you have roam of
course as RAM but no CPU caches and then
they support a lot of interfaces GPIO
touch sensors different the SPI a lot of
you are to even internet can but no USB
so you will find this platform most of
the time in a system in package module
so it's very easy to integrate in any
design you just need to footprint your
PCB and then you solve that this it's
nice because you have already the flash
storage which is integrated its FCC
certified and it costs maybe two dollars
if you just buy one so you can imagine
if you buy 10,000 something Island but
for for the test I will prefer to work
typically on different kits so because
you just plug a micro USB and then you
provide the chip you have a little sail
to USB interface you have also some
expose pin pin eaters it's quite quite
useful and it's really low cost it's
about just $15 about software now there
from Rocky is open source on github they
based the attention on extensive ESP
such 12 they provide also a set of
Python tools to to deal with the
firmware to flash it easily so it's
quite convenient quality of
documentation is pretty good
you have the datasheet technical
reference manual available so quite nice
they support Arduino core but I don't
use it because I don't like a
pre-compiled libraries and this chip is
also unofficial amazing iws IOT platform
so you can run free
yes mongoose was everything you want to
us and let's talk about the agenda today
we will focus on built-in security so to
do that I just grabbed the data sheet
and then I can see four points stop it's
about crypto of an engine or oxalate
sauce
it's about secure boot it's about flash
encryption and it's also about OTP so we
will try to focus on these points so
let's start real things now but before
starts of course we need a plan so
context it's yeah I mean I will spend
three months to investigate
approximately during my spare times and
along nights sometimes my object chief
is very simple to break one by one
two security features previously listed
I will use physical access I bought the
government kits and today it's plausible
attacks a nice to have physical access
in IOT devices so yeah I will probably
use all the techniques like Fault
injections side channel maybe my cross
of the rings maybe some view
modifications reverse of course and code
review so let's talk about Fault
injections I mean I will not detail too
much but I will I choose to focus on
very simple techniques which is voltage
glitching
it's a well known still efficient today
and very low cost for the injection
techniques you have a lot of public
resources about voltage increasing today
on on the web so I put some reference at
the end of the presentation for you the
goal of a voltage breaching is to
perturb the power of the chip during is
critical operations to inject a fault to
inject a false behavior
and you can expect the different things
for example you can skip an instructions
this is pretty common to to bypass a
checks for example you can also modify
data modify instructions this is very
cool to to attack a branch for example
and sometimes you can have a very very
unpredictable behavior so especially
with the complexity of architecture
today's we talked about cache is
different you can have different effects
it's also about CPU pipelines so yeah
it's hard to predict and it's why this
techniques is quite powerful so when we
talk about voltage pinching we have to
talk about power domains and in into DSP
such - we have three different power
domains so as the i/o power domains is
not interesting for us we will focus on
air to see real time clock domain and
the CPU domains of course CPU domains
each has two different power signals VDD
CPU and VDD RTC and this is quite not
not common way to power up the port the
chip but it's that design so I mean I
will do with that and then we can also
see some low dropout regulators this
kind of little blocks they are used to
stabilize internal voltage and this
maybe can have some filter effects
against my glitches I don't know and in
documentation they also specify a pro
now detectors this is typically used to
detect voltage under voltage or over
voltage values and they clearly indicate
if the beauty detects voltage drop it
will trigger a signal shutdown and even
a message on UART so yeah maybe this can
detect the glitches I don't know so I
did some tests of course and then yeah I
mean I received this message so
is it effective but it's only effective
on VDD RTC so consequently I will I
decide to glitch from VDD CP only to
avoid this detection so now I will
prepare the target it's really easy
I took the module I remove the shield
and then we can see DSP 32 and need to
do SP 32 a little SPI flash is the
external memory storing the firmware and
also configuration I mean yeah PC PC
screen is not it's not present but the
schematics are available so it's quite
easy to reverse so I decide to remove
the capacitors connected to vdd CPU and
the VDD at C so we can see if you
compare the two figures you will see
some missing little components and then
I have to modify the PCB a little bit so
three steps to that first I have to
expose the VDD CPU tresses it spins such
is seven I kept the trace using little
scalpel and then I sold on my glitch
output to be disputing and of course to
gng and then I can control the dis this
power signal now so at the end the ad
was set up I did my own major glitcher
it's based on max 46 19 I had some
passive components and also some SMA
connectors to to be able to to plug and
unplug of easily some some cables I
synchronize that by by scope and also I
trigger that by a signal generators so
then I can send USB commands using my
scripts to set the delays that weeds to
save voltage so it's really easy to do
that and again it looks like that I mean
it's a little setup no nothing nothing
too much important but yeah man I have
full control it's fully automatized
and then I can run that during days it's
it's very cool so we I need to be sure
about the effect of voltage glitching of
course before to to pay for my test and
we can see on the on this cup screen a
very very load bigger drop out on you at
0 P and you are 0 this channel one
monitoring signal it's powered directly
by the V dispute so it's mention inside
the chip I have the same effect than I
saw in the scope so it's I mean it's the
effects is looks pretty good so it's
time now to to choose an easy target
so it's why we are going to to begins by
the cryptic or cryptic also called
sometimes crypto accelerators that in
fact is just a peripheral to speed up
the competition like yes che ever say so
I mean what is interesting to pawn
because to accelerator is used by the
crypto lip of the vendor but it's also
used by default by a embed GLS and
bachelors today is the ungrate or
library and all IOT are using this
library it's open source and is done by
a PI arm so principle to investigate I
think my goal is to focus on the CPU
crypto interface so typically the crypto
driver and I don't find I don't expect
to find pure software vulnerability
because I mean it's open source and it's
well it was reviewed since a long time
by also security researchers so it's why
I'm I'm going to look by and to find
vulnerabilities trigger by fault
injections so yeah it's time for code
review
so first time in the datasheet I look
for the details about an IES operation
by the chip we can see four four steps
one is to initialize the different
registers load the keys loaded the
plaintext and then you start your your
is Anja engine you wait until the end
and then you read the result on these
IES text registers but yeah it's a
little weakness inside the larva design
because the the registers are used to
store the plaintext but also the
ciphertext this is called encrypt in
place and sometimes it can be risky
because if something goes wrong during
the AES call ordering the die as
competition I'm pretty sure I can retry
what you acquitted the input and I mean
it's pretty cool and a very simple proof
of concept to exploit so let's try to
bypass this is we look in the in the in
the code and we saw exactly the same the
same the same than the four previous
steps I mean they use man block array to
store input and also output so I mean
the previous weakness is confirmed
and now I have multiple spot to trigger
for fault injections I can I can try to
fall to the the call I can try to fall
to the the while condition at the end
and I can also target the for loop so
yeah here is the proof of concept so we
can see the first one is a good one but
the second one is not a good one because
the output is equal to the input so this
was a very very simple
venerability so convenient relief is
about yes that key salsas very cool and
simple to exploit so here is the coda
and we can see the load two keys inside
the crypto engine without a security
it's a very naive implementation so the
loop isn't protected so typically using
fault injection I mean I'm pretty sure I
can I can bypass the lot of the key so
consequently I obtain a wrong cipher and
with the little Python script I verify
the value of the key I use to obtain
this ciphertext
and we can see when the key is set to
zero I obtained the same ciphertext so
it means the is that she was a setter to
all zero and this is pretty cool because
the key is arised and it's a persistent
fault and the K will stay until the next
set functions and this is really nice to
exploit is CBC for example so crypto
code conclusion yes crypto engine
doesn't not improve our security to
match of course we we know that already
so I found six or seven volts with wisp
you see yes sure so I am to the to do
trillion library with rare impacted of
course the liberty of the vendor but
also am crap talib I went to responsible
disclosure because I mean today we go to
responsible disclosure and I didn't
obtain too much transfer from expression
harm during one month the bug duty of a
member jealous is a fake one so I was I
decided to not sharp inner ability with
them of course and during this time as I
try to salon patch into the van der try
to silently patch me and this I don't
like that too much and now I'm a little
bit in furry and I'm going to
super nada
so level two is secure boots the rollers
the secure boot today I mean the
well-known functions is to protect the
fill my authenticity it's to avoid a few
more modifications because it's easy to
flush a new film where to to to an
external SPI flash of course are you we
can talk about here see protections but
just is not sufficient today so the
secure boot is here to create a chain of
trust from the patron which is the first
code executed by DSP 32 to load the
bootloader until the final application
done by the developer it guarantees the
code running on the device is genuine
and of course it will not boot if images
are not properly signed so first secure
boot is normally set during the
production in the SP 32 they define a
key called the secure boot key this key
is burning to infuse this block number
two it's a special memory inside y es
Posada - I will talk about that a bit
later and this secure boot key cannot be
read out or modified because it's a read
write protect protected memory and it's
also of course this key is used by the
boot ROM to perform is 256 GB and then
the developer has to also create ECDSA
kata he will use the private key to to
sign up and you will integrate the
public key to the bootloader
images consequently if you reverse
little bit the boot Rogerson signature
it's a 192 Eaters located at 0-0 in the
in the flash memory layout and the first
128 bytes are pure random and the 64
bytes are the just the digest is a shove
512 of the encrypted
images of the bootloader plus the CGS
al-baqi encrypted by the security of
course so now once the the ESP sata2 is
on the field the boot process is the
following so reset vector the run starts
load and checks the boot images
bootloader starts below the load and
verify the application images and then
the application is running is running so
we have yeah to verification mechanism
one is the stage level done by the boot
rom it computer digesta with the secure
boot key and it compares with the 64g
just you previously flash in the
external memory and then it will it will
compound if the iPod they will go to the
stage one and the stage one is an ECG sa
verification done by the boot roller for
that they use micro ECC it's open-source
elliptic curve cryptography of course my
goal is to focus on stage zero because
it's a symmetric cryptography bootloader
and this is not very very secure today
to use a symmetric cryptography for
signature and as a critical asset of
course is to secure boot key because if
you have to secure boot key you will
break the secure boot but this key
unfortunately for attackers they are
storing in fuses and it is protected you
cannot read out so I decided to set the
secure boot so it can be done
automatically by abide by the framework
but I prefer to do that manually so I
send some commands using the vendor
tools to burn the secure boot key and
also to set the secure boot by a burning
one if uses ugliest own agenda I read
out a diffuse map and we can see now we
cannot read you cannot have access to
the data inside the
lk 2 because it's read white protected
by the by by the platform and then of
course we can see here if you look at
the shiitake fuses I didn't burn in
purpose we will see that later I mean
it's always it's always a good thing to
have the burger interface so now in
action secure boot very simple I develop
a sign hub very simple a low water and I
of course I use the secure boot key I
flash it and then it runs of course I do
the same but with an unsigned a hub and
I modified it a bit of code you can see
the printf yeah I flush and then it
fails on stage zero because the
bootloader is not signed by the secure
boot key so typically the boot ROM will
refuse to to jump to the bootloader to
be executed but for me it's quite a
perfect situation here so bypass out to
bypass the secure boot and why first but
I mean it's a real simple is to have a
codec section today if you want to face
this you have to you have to obtain code
execution how my goal is to first USB
SATA to to execute and then sign boot
loader to load and in sign hub ok to do
that I have to focus on the boot rom
because boot ROM is always nice to
exploits and it's always a difficult to
fix boot ROM vulnerability so I need to
reverse the boot rom but first I need to
dump it because without them you cannot
read us so to them the boot ROM I look
at the boot ROM in the memory map it's
some 4000 0 0 0 0 but now you remember I
didn't burn the G tacky fuses so I use a
little border $20 based on FTDI chip I
use a pen ocg I use also extensor gdb
and then I have full table access and I
can land it directly on the reset vector
so I have I have I can step in in the
boot from I can do whenever I want and I
can of of course them to put from easily
so now I have the binary of the boot ROM
and it's based on extensor extensa is a
very exotic architecture they have the
system of register windowing I will not
enter into much detail that is quite
quite crazy stuff and they evolve says
they have also different the lengths of
instructions and it's quite painful to
reverse but unfortunately the
instruction set architecture is
available so I will use either of course
plus an plugin from the mad inventors
called the iodide sensor and was really
helpful
I also a grep and found a secure boot
edge which is listing all the ROM
functions this is very useful but they
deprecated since I call my my friend to
check my mass of course always always
good to have friends
Disgaea and then at the end it's not
perfect but it's curly to able to
reverse extensor and as you can see in
the images I start in the beginning of
the boot ROM as expected so I will not
tell too much a reverse of the boot ROM
I will just agitate the view and then I
located the ETS secure boot to check
finish functions I mean it's quite the
name of the function is quite useful and
just after that of course we can see we
have to branch the left branch is the
sexual boot check failure printf we saw
we saw we saw previously and on the on
the right side we will have a product
section we locate the
this little instruction the branch if
not equal immediate and the result will
be a tip and will depends on the on the
sec boot check finish return value so
and this is tour in a ten registers so
my goal is to make the PC jump to the
right side at the 4000
75 c5 to execute the bootloader of
course so first I have G tag access so I
will develop a little exploit based on G
tag just a little script to set the a-10
register to 0 and then I will execute
this branch not call imitate instruction
so here's the demo yeah
so I'll uh I launch open Oct then I send
a little script to gdb and then I wait a
little bit and then we can see on the on
the upper left side my code is executed
so I validate the neighbor ability using
G tag of course but now it's time to
pawn for real because in real life you
don't have it she tagged G tag is
normally disabled on secure device and I
could not find a way to exploit this Vil
by a software-only so ya fault injection
is my only way so I decide to modify a
little bit my setup to glitch on VDD CPU
and on VDD a 3 because V DD RTC is used
when the chip is a blue chip app so on
and I also promised BMOC signal to have
a timing information because the fault
injection will be will be very very
dependent about the timing now so I do
some some some tester we can see here on
on a scope screen of course
previous petrm reverse is really full to
determine the timing and where you have
to glitch exactly so I assume in the
specific windows we can see the you are
signals providing information and then
on the channel 2 we have the SPI frame
which indicate the end of the bootloader
load the the end of the load of the
bootloader ok but as a result we can see
that the secure boot to check fail so it
means that the secure boot was not was
not bypass during this this attempts but
with a little bit of time a little bit
of of settings yeah yeah is another
screen of course I assume inside the
Maya interesting windows and here we can
see on the CL the the reservatrol puta
it has been modified by the by the
glitch effect and then we can see the
the bootloader and repo entry point of
the Buddha so the CPU is jumping to the
entry point and the bootloader has
executed so I mean it's done and of
course for concept is important and then
we can see that on the on the on the
shell directly so you wait a little bit
then at one moment I have my own sign
hub which is executed because I load an
ensign bootloader using voltage
glitching thank you
so sorry for the children it was a it
was late so suitable conclusion so it's
a sexual would bypass exploit in stage
zero trigger sugar by fault injection
good from good from a vulnerability of
course it's not persistent if the reset
occurs but the good things is you have
no way to fix without Rama revision so I
went to responsible disclosure I sent
puck in June they release the security
wizardry on September 2 they request the
CV mean ok no problem and they decided
to patch by a flash encryption always
enabled so then you cannot use secure
boot only you will also use flash
encryption plus secure boot I mean it's
it's a valuable patch I think and
another security lab called the risk you
found the same vulnerability so it was a
join a disclosure so no silent patch
attempts at this time so was a good good
progress but of course now I go to flash
encryption because I mean it was on my
to-do list the role of the flash
encryption is to protect the former
confidentiality is to protect against
binary instructions and the reverse
without flash encryption it's really
easy to extract a sensitive data for
example I did that a little bit late
earlier this year on light bulbs so it's
really easy to dump and then you have
access to sensitive data after of the
vendors
sensitive that of the users I mean it's
not really good to to toast this kind of
devices today and few more encryptions
is become more and more present today in
IOT but also on other devices and it's
really security by obscurity but
I mean it says it's a choice of funnels
as perceive recommend secure boot and
fresh an option for maximum security so
let's review the flash encryption now
it's pure hardware is encryption
decryption block in flash memory contra
so this block will fetch the key from
infuses and also the parameters and it
will use IES to decrypt and encrypt
instructions and data into into caches
and the discussion you don't have access
by software so you cannot you cannot
read the values of course so yeah the my
main focus is the flash encryption key
of course because if you can obtain this
flash encryption key you can decrypt the
firmware and then of course these
critical assets so how to set the flash
encryption in SP 32 you bound the flash
encryption key into BL k1 this time you
activate the flash encryption doing some
settings flash click config and then
also you enable the the flash go to
content which fuses you flash the
unencrypted firmware into USB SATA to
previously a compiled and then you of
course you verify to issues a map and we
can see now block number one and block
number two impossible to to read out of
course because it's requite protected
and you can also see a digit a ger is
disabled here I don't
and yeah I verify my firmware is a
pretty well encrypted so yeah it was
prettier to see maybe a good how to
break the flash encryption so I did a
lot of tests and but I did not find a
unfortunately particular weakness to
access the key it was pretty well design
how to attack by differential fault
analysis which is a common technique to
break first encryption
so I was a little bit sad and my last
hope was a side channel analysis to
target the bootloader decryption during
the during the bootloader process and
then so I achieve a little such a new
set up but I found some difficulties
because spi bus is producing a lot of
noise during my acquisitions and I
cannot control the SPI frame properly I
try to use a SPI emulator from from
Vanderpool but it was a big fail I mean
I was not was not was not good I tried
different such an analysis attacked the
PSP a but I didn't have a very nice SNS
not noise ratio I didn't find a nice
good spot to twelve leakage so I find I
spend a tonight and nights but for zero
results and yeah I mean I was a cow so
the conclusion here
it came is clear I lost I mean sometimes
you don't success but I mean I decided
to to read some advices about fatal fury
and and to follow that because if you
watch your opponent techniques very
carefully you can find that the witness
so in the weakness I found it in the
mode in the OTP fuses and this is I'm
going to disclose today so OTP Hughes's
is the sexual memory it's a one-time
program programmable memory based on
infuses it's like electrical fuses in
your house I mean but this is inside the
ESP such - and infuses can be programmed
just one time from zero to one
once burn you cannot change the values
of that you cannot wipe it because it's
physically done it's
the organization is the following 1 BLK
zero is for SES passatti to
configuration lk 1 flashing shonky of
course lk to take your boot key and the
belicus who is reserved for user
applications or custom max for example
other data and according to 2 expressive
DC fuses they are retried protected and
cannot be read out modified once
protection bits are set and about the
fuses they are managed by your nephew's
controllers it's a dedicated piece of
hardware inside the ESP SATA 2 which is
in charge to manage the load the program
nation of this uses array so let's
reverse the fuses if we can and then it
really because it's only treated to two
functions reading and program but these
functions they are just used during a
special a boot mode and this is I found
that a little bit interesting because
the boot from during the normal good
model doesn't touch OTP values so it
means only the issue this controller has
access to this one-time programmable
memory is the pure hardware process and
of course he has to be set before the
boot rom because the boot ROM used the
secure boot key so let's talk about the
special boot model this model is a
management model to flash the firmware
to set fuses to set configuration of the
of the of the platform and this you can
enter in this special mode by a ground
grunting the usual okay and then you
pull up and you will obtain this message
on the you are 0 ok and now you can use
some Python utility tools done by the
vendors to talk to the boot rom directly
and to deal with the fuses with the two
previous functions we saw
so let's talk about the fuse protection
as we as we know any attempts to read
the BL k1 and relocate to return a zero
accessible
I try to Road amp this and you as we can
see bill K 1 and BN k - it's all 0 but I
need to identify the right protection
bit and this I found it in blk 0 in the
security configuration of the chip after
little bit of reverse I identified two
bits and these bits are the read
protection bits
so here where is the room I mean I'm
sorry but I have no film yeah but I know
the boot from does not manage the fuses
and obviously the issues contrast was
the job before I know I can use a
special boot model and I also locate the
heat protection bit so the idea is to
glitch the if use controller
initialization to change to modify the
readwrite protections and then I send
dump commands in special boot model and
if I'm lucky I get back
BL k1 and be ok too so let's see that
now on the screen so here's the scope
scope visualization and then I do little
bit of simple power analysis and I
identify a very very interesting process
it's pure process I assume inside and
yeah I mean I saw the current
consumptions and I decide to glitch
inside this identified our process and
after some some attempts I can obtain
this kind of stuff and this is a full
readout of bill k1 and k2 so typically
as we can see these two keys are
critical
I send that to the vendors on July 24
and I was pretty happy about my my
attack
thank you but subtly I need to do one
more step because when I look the dump
values they are not exactly the good one
and I I know that because I found the
key so I do a little bit of offline
statistical analysis on a certificate
template values and then I just keep the
most recurrent by T is the for the
security analysis which is the same for
fresh encryption key and at the end I
mean one byte is still unknown
and as we brute force I mean when we
talk about is 256 key brute forcing one
byte
I mean it's not so bad so the food the
full exploit is the following one first
we have to decrypt the firmware so we
dump the encrypted firmware in a maximum
security - we can dump that by the
download mode can dump by directly
probing the flash spi flash and then we
have to perform this fatal glitch to
extract a set of fresh and efficiently
and secure boot key values we run the
statistical analysis and then we confirm
the true flash encryption key by
decrypting the firmware of course I mean
and once the family decree decrypted
nicely we found out this fresh
conclusions it's a really important to
respect
despite order when you write this this
software commands because as I change
the the organization of the of the of
the bytes but it's not a big deal you
have to know just that and then the
second step is to sign now your code so
now the film where is decrypt
we had we extracted the 128 bytes from
the flash because it's the random bytes
we have to keep that we extract the
bootloader images at the 0 X 1000 in a
flash memory of course and we confirm
the true a secure boot key by computed
by computing the digest and yeah yeah I
located the rotor to the previously just
and when I obtained the same I mean it's
because I used the real secure boot key
and then I would I put false like that
the last bytes
now I write my code so maybe a little
while back though I don't know and then
I compile a G's I use fresh encryption
key secure boot key and then I can
Russian ephemera and this is a really
odd to detect on the field so here's the
conclusion of this fatale attack yeah it
leads to an expression of the secure
boot key and the flashing shonky
breaking secure boot impression crucian
an attacker can decrypted the firmware
so it can access all the IP and
sensitive data it can sign and run is
all 9 cryptid code persistently because
you know the keys and then it's it's a
persistent ephemeral modification it's
low cost low complexity it's really easy
to reproduce no way to fix
so although SP via such two versions of
venerable but Van Doren reacts of course
so I went to responsible disclosure
again I send on July 24 CVE requested by
the vendors I just closed today
but they say they were faster than me
and they they provide security edges are
number one and it's funny because
the expense they cannot fix but they
propose to pay a new cheap version so
pretty cool if you have already a lot of
devices on the field yeah
so it leads to a lot of venerable
devices on the field for the Comenius
and so yeah I mean we're going to buy
this now I mean the previous one we want
broken platforms so final conclusion so
I I do this disclosure for the
developers because I mean if you have a
start-up and you have a business model
you can you can be aware about that
occur with physical access can
compromise
yes p32 pretty badly so the you have no
current fix on ESP 32 the chip will be
broken forever but you can also buy the
next version which will be protected
maybe I don't know I didn't test it
identifies the world companies using the
ESP such two security features in the
product I will not disclose the name of
course yeah general message for vendors
I mean you don't palette on patch
silently it's not good and it's better
to reward and security researchers so
new results coming soon so stay tuned
the other reference and thank you thank
you for raising the lady thank you for
your presentation