then it was democratically decided
that being the one who understood the least
of the subject of the talk started
the introduction and as Marco rightly said
let's start for a moment from what
the bbs were on a personal level for us it
is okay as usual to be
the old  wise
I remember when I spent half a million to
buy the acoustic cover I
use war games and I connected with the bbs
that is not the beautiful vbs fidonet
own mandate of the
bbs browse and monet users experts I managed
a bbs in florence that had a single
switched line then  we connected
one at a time it was a 2 euro plus apple
that had been created to mount not
two but four 160k disks and
the source of immense satisfaction to
meet these
high-level IT facilities
even if you had to spend the nights
on the phone  urban tariff
justify bills etc.
etc.
the dream of the time the dream of the time
to be able to connect  and the university
of essex where there was the first
multi-
user world that everyone was talking about and no one had
ever managed to connect why and it is
limited to 50 users who knew it
all over the world and that
at most it was handed down
traditionally I remember one  once
I managed to connect at the time
of boot he
receives the message the world has not
yet been created because on that bass
we launched the program then
obviously the line dropped
because the usual x25s had
the reliability they had and therefore
good peace of the  'computer science bbs to
summarize quickly for me it remained
a myth little practiced due to probably
total technical inability
then my experience and how bbs
started in 1994 with a modem 2004 that
bad weather was absolutely not the top
of the range because it seems to me that there
were already modems for sure  14 4 maybe
even something faster but it was
what I could afford as a
kid I started connecting
practically exclusive  mind the
main bbs from my city there
were 23 but only one noteworthy that
was moderately important not only in
fidonet but also in some other alternative networks
what was fidone in the meantime
but out a few words that maybe who is
not there  era will not know if shouts
interrupts issues so I explain it lido net
and still because there is still a network
of bbs
that use standard protocols
more or less based on cp to
exchange mail which can be both
personal mail and mail of the
message areas that you  call vico mail
at the time
I was a sewer node a user node
called point because the
fidonet addresses were something like
name.surname
and then the node number in my case
was 22 points 3 32 bar 20
6.10 what all this means
was the number of the zone europe there was
one united states and
oceania 5 africa 4 I don't
remember south america if you remember it oh well
332 was the Ligurian network and 206 was
the n  umber of the node here I connected I
was point number 10
the sidone environment let's
go into detail later I
continued like this for a few years
in the meantime after two years I started
to connect to the internet via
ucp only posts and newsgroups and then I am
other things arrive like the dsl first the
telephone flats for which slowly the
world has moved on to the internet what
remains nowadays of fidonet in
italy practically nothing
there is my node that a few months ago I
put up for a
we produce retro computing experiment
that is,
and
then
let's start from before at a certain point
I had fun setting up my
node number reachable only via the
internet
at a certain point even the most reluctant
had realized that this thing of
making phone calls
does not  it would last forever for which
protocols were studied for
exchanging fidonet mail via the
internet also because the phone calls
still continued to have a cost.
The structure of the network was
completely hierarchical so that each
node called the regional node with which it
exchanges mail and how which in
turn called a national node which in
turn called a European node
and all this with telephone
calls largely paid by the stops
for  as far as I know there was not much
much between king active at the time in
fidonet although someone had
ever told me if you have
different experiences let's talk about it
for which there were discrete costs
from yes software to exchange mail
and then
precisely it was  invented this
also different system to exchange mail
via the internet
at one point I had set up my
node which was also a gay stone towards
some newsgroups dedicated to this but
for various internal reasons and fidonet that is
mainly there were hard core this
is hot  they said is but if the mail
is also available through the internet
no one will ever connect to my
bbs again
and unfortunately they did not understand that the  what
was important was the community and it would have
been useful to keep it alive
regardless of the technology
perhaps guaranteeing it a
smooth transition to a different technology
that would have kept it together but the
attractions of the internet were still
too great for people to
continue to use the bbs a  once we have
reached affordable internet connections
we do not talk about adsl etc. so
over the years I have always obtained
this node
reachable via the internet which in the end
was practically the only
Italian node there is me who am the
national coordinator at this point
being  left alone and another
half active node
this summer
decided to do a retro
computing experiment if any of you experience
with things of dos like the manager share
point ex let's talk about it we will
introduce I installed
what was the program I used
as a point to manage routing
I asked you about the post called fasti co
I desco who developed it at the time of making
me a registration key for the
new node because the shareware and then I
installed gold and the program to
read the messages
and this living as long as yes and then there
are directories shared with the
incoming mail in  output that is
exchanged via the internet
at the moment
this is the state more or less all over the
world there are countries with more nodes with
fewer nodes maybe countries where
a radical cleaning has not been done as in
Italy because of no deaths but
apart from the  'former soviet union
where there are still many thousands of
nodes even if I don't know exactly what
they do because there is a
very strong language barrier for the rest in
the rest of the world fidonet is
practically non-existent there are
some people having fun  to keep on
your node or linux or emulated in
some way, however, all the
technology has gone ahead and the community has
not remained together
language barrier the boat
good morning  everyone
is a euro always a meeting of
anonymous alcoholics more than but in any case
I am not anonymous
then no the speech in the meantime I thank
there is an invited to do this
because in any case this year it is twenty
years since the 94 of the Italian crackdown that
then maybe someone  has read someone
there was someone knows
I also brought things I thought
it was because we had not clearly defined
what this brisk would be
anyway in the end I still have an
active bbs that is no longer connected
no network even if it keeps all of them  the
configurations I came out of fidonet
with the eagle earthquake because I
took the mail from gino legino lucrezi
who remained the bbs under the rubble
for which we hardly organize then
I tell you the technology because I around we
were organized to get the feeds
from  foreign with which I also explain
how the evolution of our bbs was the
bible if that of the metro graphics
I think you know it as bbs dot
lo gr  aphics punto org still active via
terne
tu my experience of that of those
years the thing is complex because I could
talk about it for hours but I don't think it is the case
since on the morning of the 10th
I started
this adventure in the theme that today
pays me the mortgage
in the  second half of the 80s with
300 baud modem connected to the
door of the commodore trying to
connect to the one who was whistling
on the other side no
acoustic couplers in Italy I have not seen any
personally I have only seen peaches and
self assembly cards of modems 300
baldi
yes yes I have to tell
you clearly you have to frame the thing
in the historical period there were computers
that we say personal computers
were affirming the ibm pc's are
affirming they came from a period in
which everyone had the spectrum the texas
instrument the comfortable l  'friend the como 64
that sells worlds that did not speak to each other
begins to come out the first
80 86 the first 28 if then because those
in my opinion have made the  difference
there was a whole scenario of bbs who
leaned on the world friend who
had their own way of living
and doing graphics the demo dinner of the time
etc.
there were a whole series of bbs
starting to set up knots
strand therefore with a very
strict policy on what was to pass or
not there were the diasporas as they are
today as there have always been there are those who
wanted it cooked who wanted it raw who
did not want the pgp pass for the one
after but who  he did not want
certain contents to pass through who
I wanted to talk about so on the pole
just jump years is that I am here
and on the technology he described
very well before marco then on the
ftn technology this type of mail exchange was still called
with these protocols
similar to the cp  for the exchange of
basically e-mails and
newsgroups even if they were called
aerial co also files if desired ago the
problem is that the random files
had certain  dimensions and therefore it
was necessary to bear the costs but
there were file distribution systems
for example my bbs was the
world coordinator of a huge network
of exchanging porn images
anyway
that is not my personal one and the one to which
I connected
therefore c  'they were a series of realities
around the world of bbs
meanwhile it was not called mail
matrix or net mail at most the most
advanced ones but 24 hours he says around
polling but reaches it was fine
against italy 24 retro also two
otherwise
anyway in short  this world I
was point me connective then to other
bbs in 94 all of a sudden they arrested everyone
for a
kidnapping they remained nobody in
reality if this was a series of bbs they
left two
because I train those who had a modem were not
always seen in a
good way yes there is  it was always this suspicion
in 93 the law on computer crime came into force
which was not there before
but the Italian scene was quite
varied there was  those who just
connected videos of the itit pack pierced
doing so entered the bucks etc.
there were a series of bbs who made
warez they
took software from abroad they
resold it for a fee then there were
all the world of bbs instead fidonet
who were at least had  a
clean facade then there were those who were consistent with
this and those who do not break for a
legal clarification there was no
law on the league line conflict until 93
exact means that there were some
bbs in a totally open way they were
exchanging illicitly copied programs
it was not a crime  a well-known
Italian provider the owner of a
well-known Italian provider at the time had
this huge bs for amiga they
had sued him for
unfair competition not being able to find other
legal footholds another stop I
knew
ran a bbs in the united states not
paying for the phone calls
in  feet I entered into force the law
on computer crime then thought oh well
I dedicate myself to fidone
si fa  ceva boxing there were calling cards
there was a whole world so boxing was
the use of some frequencies to
unhook the carrier on certain
telephone exchanges of a certain
period is in Italy for example the
Italian ones have never worked in
this technique, however, could be called
central is the last Montevideo era that
I remember working so you could
call
the switchboard of the direct with the
abroad send tones with the
captain grange the one who came to the
mocha was good at these things
anyway yes  they sent tones that changed
you took control of the central
you could redo phone calls
by dropping let's say the billing of
that phone call or use
American colin cards usually anti-
perfect therapy because this software was
often
imported from North
American South African North American BBS
a '  alternative and the use of
x25 networks that were widespread at
the prevalent dale level  entity that everyone had
no one used practically were devoted
to consumption like a telephone line if
you try your hand in possession of the
entrance code there was not even a password
through left-handed people typically
working
in the structures you could give them connected
to anything else perhaps with it on
x25
however to do wireless it was not good
that it was a thousand notes it was good to
make connections publicly to
try to connect with exotic bbs
to do the ass that it took this
outside the networks numerous are species
had this
no this is what  it was called
courier it seems to us a [ __ ] reason that
it was called curios
anyway going back to the bbs because that
is a period we were talking
about so many things we are also mixing them
the world of bbs had us for what
I remember a series b bs  who
did hacking and wireless activities
sometimes for a fee they wanted fees
because clearly they had costs
there  to be able to download this
software or simply the ratio, that is, the
more you applaud you pirated software the more
you can download it then there was the whole
world of trust networks of the fidonet network
which instead was
apparently very strict on these
policies who wrote the fidonet policies
currently in charge of the
vatican ced therefore in short,
the framing of
the network actually up to half had an
at least public official
very very very rigid setting which then led
to the creation in Italy of many other
technology networks that perhaps not everyone
knows the first cybernet then  decoder the
types of decoders of milan together with
other 10 m detach themselves from a fidonet area they
create their cybernet network with
the same addressing but instead of
yours starting with 6
the world of roles of role-playing games
is created its network  rpg network is a
group of crazy Neapolitans the p net
peacelink that still active as
an activist movement had made its own
network  the scouts are in fact their
network to the technology trend so there were
many Italian networks with this type of
technology that exchanged messages
I what I always say even in
metro graphics in the end nothing changes
30 years have passed 25 years but
in fact  with this stuff you do
private messaging
discussion groups chat and file exchange
so that it is facebook or that it was the b
bs of 25 30 years ago the things you do
are these then the contents change the
technologies change and the way of
approach  they change you can do it with your
smartphone but in the end we always do
what
we throw we talk about messages one by
one we talk about topics in
open public groups we exchange photos files and
programs
basically so the underlying
technology has changed but to come to
us  briefly in 94 from point
after the crash they gave as a
reaction created the association to give
a poly look and the motif of the meteor
free that here  they arrest us they seize
the computers we have to give a legal guise
to this activity because the law has
now changed and therefore we no longer understand
anything so we do the bbs
neuromancer my first bbs in 94 I opened it a
month after 11 May there  it was the crash
from an early June we
inaugurated neuromancer which I then
set up and remote access south or
if there is remote access fa stico goals the
programs he said only for boss
a line a bbs no multitasking
end of the computer used to make the
bbs
then the association m lo graphics is created
around this bbs we do a series
of things clearly in 97
we merge 2 bbs from Pescara in the meantime from
a pescara one of the pirate bbs who
exchanged software codes for
boxing and  it is taken is
seized
only the active vivanet bbs remain
those a little more so we open this bbs
after three years I change everything we do m
graphics bbs which is the pbs that is
currently still online and  there with a
vision a little different from what
he said we tell ourselves I didn't make
a small investment at the time which
didn't help because the
internet had spread by now we bought
or cut which was a program made up of two
American steps  the santos brothers who
had us wild card for dos had
brought this stuff to windows nt so
a really multitasking system that
also worked together with other things
a frontend always made by them
which is called pixie like the
processor the standard mail and so
let's say first  attacked the modems and then
gradually removed the modems
abbs we reached the internet and
coluccino we had agreed to use it to
use a small program called
trans peak made by a madman who
simply takes mail packets
in fidonet format he attacks them  in
an e-mail luhmann on the other the other
takes these e-mails, processes and
puts them back into the normal glories hunchbacks
xmen and que  this stuff went on from
97 until the earthquake so I ended up
in the sky had until the earthquake the pbs
still online I honestly got
back to it these days because they
asked to do the surgery if not I
connect like once every twenty years
about that I do anything else and therefore she
is there she lives her own life
sassoon serverino with
256 megs of ram
it still works
and I know it but we were powerful in the
years once 7 I put it graphics it was
in full expansion so it
could do all  these things
no that came after the ram
there have been some hardware upgrades
over the years so no no it was not and
therefore those who want to see it still there can
see very well with terminals like in the
facts I had prepared everything
because the graphics indeed  from all of
these of these standard tennet it is
disgraced so it does not make it not have
rim porn implemented well but it
still works even on
modern windows and you can see
discreetly I had lawn this
then oh well and therefore nothing there is a
museum an open-air museum we have
not left it I did not understand why you are
interested in this stuff from 20 25 years ago
the first question I asked him
when I put  maker what the [ __ ]
do we have to do a talk on bbs I personally am
an entrepreneur co2 grown up children I
play basketball I go with a bicycle
I don't understand the reason for this
interest in a dead stuff from
various pluses yes well
then
technologically this story is dead
I'm  completely contrary to any
form of attempted exhumation that is
not for historical memory that is I repeat they
are the bbs online so it is not that it
is a sort of museum but there are
several that is csec bbs still active
there are many those of the brothers
center o  via internet register they
reach several bbs but I do not understand
the interest we are in 2014 there are
privacy problems problems of
any kind please
revive
me then instead  and to talk to you about
technology and then I will be brief
I can tell you that for me
personally it was one of the most
beautiful things that has happened to me in life
really because
I found myself in a
historical moment in which I was about 20 years old
and  with in hand you
felt at the time that this stuff
had a
monstrous mortal potential that
a revolution would happen I felt every day
I woke up at night I saw if we did
the ing while I was going to piss
I saw if the bbs because the users  he
needs my mail I warned
I was not clear what could happen
but then I also made other
making steps in the internet world etc.
etc.
there would have
been communication in many to me
caught up on things they
believed in i.e. I think I lived
the pioneering years  i of telematics
and that do not come back because
those were the years not thanks to us but
because we simply found ourselves
in the right place at the right time
while these things were happening we
perceived that I was being taken for a
ride because now in earners they are in
fashion  but at the time I can't assure you that
in the late 80's 95 final I can
guarantee you that in the late 80's nerds
and they weren't [ __ ] fashionable and that is
we were caught people
took my ass they said what the [ __ ] you do
all day in front  on the computer cheering on
[ __ ] of this type even
heavier then
here is the problem he knew the problem
was that who intuitively
tried to do a bit of evangelism and
then went to his cousin doctor from
his cousin student of nuclear physics and
tried to explain to him that there were
newsgroup that you could post a
question by
sending an email and within two hours
the world's leading expert gave a
detailed answer  what worked the
first is that it was unthinkable not responding
to an email in two hours because it was a
very serious insult
after ten years they almost all
told me actually I was taking you for a
fool is an extreme synthesis
they told me dear people with whom
what  However, they accepted this
scotoma of madness of mine because I told them
things that weren't together with the
interior then they accepted after the
flat modem connections
became common and therefore a few
hundred thousand people who
had heard me speak suddenly
entered  on the internet in Italy
I had these small satisfactions
given I was not so pleased by 10
years I thought he was so stupid but
in short, it is the synthesis and the synthesis of
the moment it is
at a social level up to a social level
what was happening thirty of us are  were
the children of the sixty-eighths ok so,
as always happens, we had
quite libertine parents who, however,
have  anza castrato then
chased and we arrived in a period
in which however you take into account now
you connect you have friends that I know
in america in australia we are close to
mars moon and so on but first
everything was the small ancient world linked
to the village to the city  I live in
avezzano in the province of L'Aquila
and obviously the friends were the ones
you met at the bar you saw and so on
the same thing if you had to ask
for some information have
some doubts about something or the
mimeographers insisted that they came to you once
a month but it has  a name etc. in the mail
or in any case you had to stick to the
zebedees because there was no way to
go and find a quick way to
exchange ideas so as soon as
the bbs arrived for us and an incredible [ __ ] world opened up
that is I can
talk  with one in america in an
unthinkable English and that's what
those answers me as well because obviously
we didn't have google translator
veram  ente condition or letter for the
three I then I had done French in
middle school so imagine writing in
English and then let's say the
social impact was enormous as he said
when I bought my first
computer it was the zx80 550
thousand lire and 550 thousand lire  that for
inside about half a million
what they were now is right then either
an employee a moped ok I get
home
this is a computer takes a
fake keyboard but here a k of ram
that is an exceptional graphics
64 by 44 pixels white and  black
obviously attacking the television and
there were bad things understood for which
even being able to finally reach a
level of hacking that is before I was
geek with
electronic savior in hand start
working on a computer weld
it weld it and program it too
machine language and obviously being able to
connect with a model that is really
scrauso to
connect with the whole world and
therefore have it within reach of  i hand understood for us
a really message that he sends away and
after two days he would return the answer
is [ __ ] he did immediately it was a
lightning understood now for you i am still
not answering 10 seconds that i send it to
him look at my girlfriend up here
whatsapp
understand what it is  the speech for which it
was really a disruptive thing
so imagine you that maybe you
have always been your garden in
your kindergarten in your really
little ancient world at some point
you can
obviously travel through the internet else
you now have my low cost flights
us  this case, that is, hello, but Italy,
that is, going abroad was really
a business but from the thread I understood
or really where to avoid
backpacking and struggling around so
this here is significantly
freedom the internettian sexual freedom is
not  more to go in
search of porn magazines
maybe left in the woods but finally to be
able to download the images  ini
directly from the internet
I do not have the syndrome of my time
but I realize that I am like my own I
remember my grandmother who went
hungry during the war that when there was
food but they loaded and we had
this type of  approach with food that
is different from those who have not been hungry I
have chosp the text everywhere that is me between
300 bars me if this the 4g I always have to
see how much more and more gang makes me more and more
band that is never enough for me in the cie  from
10 gb i'm happy i always do
ispi tess this is a disease that exists and
i don't live i don't say that once no
i don't i don't like to say in my time
because i live contemporary i am
an entrepreneur of a small company
that  IT security is also
fairly good but this
approach with the band for example that
I realize that
people who are a few years younger than
me do not have because for them the band is
discounted for less that is me if this is
in fact one of the 4g  things of which vol  evo
talk is that
you who have never used a modem in
2004 do not have 300 boo or worse,
however I have never used
a modem to connect via fidonet you
have no idea what the
pressure was to save resources
1 because they were
technologically limited  2 because the yes
tops paid their bills out of their pockets
to exchange mail for which there were
beautiful rules
beautiful habits now a bit lost like
the senseless quotation of emails and one thing
that I have learned fidone in fidonet and
that will be useful to me throughout  life and that it
would be nice if many more people
knew that you do not reply to an
email at the top because microsoft
decided it a few years ago
and then since the top paid
their bills out of their pocket
there was also a
very strong social control  on the contents because they said
I marry your mail follow my
rules and there were different networks with
slightly different rules fidonet in particular in
particular in Italy it was
particularly restrictive
In fact, on certain issues, other networks were born with
slightly different objectives, however in
general there was this habit of
staying on topic
in a certain area of discussion
avoiding talking about one's own business,
wandering etc. and this allowed to
maintain a very high quality that
now it has been lost practically everywhere,
however, they seem to be positive to
make people understand the impact that the quoti nng
for example had in my life
still says the signs on the back of the
moderators who took you back no more
than twenty days ago a month ago my
14 year old daughter  I said something at home and
she told me dad this ti quoto because
now ti quoto has entered the
common language they also use it a little inappropriately
no because we used it only now
entered the common language of the CEI
guys to say I'm d '  agree with you you
say this i quote this thing
put me my 14 year old daughter so
i mean this [ __ ] that we felt
powerful did those  work on the
revolution there has been mass diffusion
there has been seeds to be a bit
but in the end at meetings of this type
we are always the usual 100 150 I
assure you that we have been 150 for at least 25 years it
is so and so we are always 150
people change is but in the end the
number is always the same the base has
increased a lot of those who
now approach technology have
practically everyone today from the
elderly to the very young have internet
in their pocket but maybe those interested in
these things always an
extremely small circle of
sorry people I quickly reconnect with
what he said for a different reading
many of you were there last night they
enjoyed the talk of miami rebus they
saw matthew broderick
and with the girl around an accomplished and
fake that we had built
for the occasion  it
was a very funny thing
because he saw it as a final comedian
at that time having a few years
more I was already studying I worked together  I
was doing the moonlight programming
a hotel stand for example on an apple ii
with 48k and they sold it to hotels
and I had the acoustic copy I had
the computer
I could understand by ear what
the modem was doing when it makes those curious
noises and if  he would have taken a line by
listening to the notes to those who have dropped
speed can not fall
the important thing is like this but without
anyone having explained a musical ear
applied to technology
the problem was that he did not have a
blonde girl who insisted on
coming and seeing  my computer turned by
touching the various equipment
that is actually world games had a
profound impact on my need
for the world no I have not yet come
to understand everything, absolutely everything, however, the
acoustic hp cesano one thing that we have not
said because we are talking about details
and I think  that if I say this everyone will
know each other at that time it was not so much
the fact that we had had access to
one thing  that it would not change
the world it had changed it from us to me it
changed my life I found
myself dealing with virtual reality
suddenly you doing these things
here it is because the cinematic special effects
were there even once it
is
like that  it happened it happened that I
lived
isolated on my skin the first wave
of information overload once I
started a book a manual to put on
an armchair you read it from the first
page to the last then the region there
also because it deviates a friend maybe
unfold what you did not understand
or talk about in an email and this is an
event that marked a week a month
of your life but deeply I had
understood one more thing from algorithms more
from equal data structures and go-to
programs to the manual of the little program that
did  strange things
every access to information
changed your life you had to look for it how to
go to the library look at the
tags those of narrow
drawers for  r find something and spend the
morning with it and because you didn't find it
well this had been an information
had them before you could absorb
all the information that existed for you
in the world that you could find
because you were the
bottleneck not  he managed
from newsgroups onwards suddenly you
realize that you will not be able to read
everything you want because
hundreds of emails keep coming to you in the 12 15
hundred newsgroups myself and at
some point you have to throw them away
you will never be able to read them that is this type of
creating problems  at work
at the time I was already working that they see you
it was not so normal that one was
always stuck behind a computer
once you still wrote on the notepad
which having the computer on your
desk can create problems at work at
some point the super g  somehow
this is an experience that our
generation
let's say who at the time from 14 to 20 30
years had to overcome in some way  on
his own skin, perhaps not even knowing
how to tell exactly how it happened and
this what computer scientist who is a
shock and informative instead all the
others who have had
different technologies have not had to overcome it not
because of the technologies as
neuro rightly said but simply
because  from something that only
very few knew it had become something that
you could ask your desk mate
so the new generations let's call
things sorry they didn't have to experience
the shock of a flood of training
that is to spend
hours looking for hours looking for a book in the library
up to say I can not subscribe to
this penny I can not go and
read this thing here because I do not have
time all this for me meant
tearing my heart is thrown from
that other side because it is inconceivable
not lectern and all that are
curious shiver  puts in the hands
call of the forest is too strong if
I tell you right away that  I think I am for
the klondike but apart from that I
lived it all from the beginning to the end
I too had the acoustic tower couple and
I will say more that today it could also
be there and that I never went to
bologna otherwise in a warehouse  in
bologna there was one I wanted to take him to take
a handset of the one that is attached
from cell phones and try to make a
connection to 300 because 1200 in
my opinion would never have gone
from the other stage, however, a
call to see what you said that there  he
did it at 300 he does it could also
be a pity that I did not go to those
from bologna as a result and I do
n't even know if he still had it in the
warehouse because he had to see so
initially I too had so I have
86 and all that  who was
behind the modem 300 as ask why it
cost less than the external one so it's
all such a thing and after which
I practically used the classic people for the
call on the first
internet connection it was with  a manager who
praised for free that italy online and
ran a script at night i
heard his the big computer
sounded see [ __ ] connected with
mosaik i saw my first page that
was not google because it is not that see
not c  'it was and therefore practically it
was my first connection with the great
satisfaction that you knew that you are
doing it for free that this is a great one
because precisely with the fate of the
absolute economy you did not know that you were doing it for free
then over time it happened that I too  I
opened a part that I connected to the
nodes I signed connected or that has
a bologna stand which was a beautiful thread knot
and actually the first
thing that they understood that who the real
cool was not only the fact of drawing
the jpeg porn files etc.
but  the real cool is the fact of the newsgroups
that is the ones that are today forums and
newsgroups evening from which the rules are then derived
because in fact the rest
came out with the blog there is because you
realized and  ffectamente to
broaden your circle because then
you say that you are an expert that I
know I deal with databases I
do not know you in my area that
database expert four cats at my level on
that type of specific area here
are others I am  respect in networks others
are web experts high everyone has their own
experiences meant that suddenly to
widen the circle of 23 people
more or less your level of competence
to a circle of 50 60 100 people of
which there are at least thirty as many  which
are a hundred times more than you and therefore being
able to talk directly then with
a mechanism whereby if you ask the
stupid question there is the one who wants to show
that he knows it and answers you the same if you go
to super intricate question to greater
satisfaction that  that will be answered by
respondents and this mechanism is
what then in the end was really the
difference because then in the end today the
blogs, forums and facebook also dressed
the cassata practically  and they are all
derivations of this logic here and there he
had understood it first about
what little but certain then another thing that
had happened to me that practically some
point covered even a small bbs
just a very specific theme because it
had neither  works in a company that thanks
to geomechanical geology I worked
with probes and then we did one thing
to the theme no burned a program to
run under dos and practically
managed this little bbs then over time
what to do when the internet started
I said castro do the  provider and
internet in ferrara and then you make the
first internet provider in fact it
moved me when I saw a sport for there it is
supported that it was an amazing modem
because the other was the one for rich
that other was a little less rich
but it worked like a god  it is practically
then how did it give
connectivity no you went from the
sip then there was the sip tells him it's
about I need sixteen
telephone lines  he down 16 telephone lines
had a battery of modems which of
you were turning around because the problem was that
the type of switching that there was you
had the first way in which it worked
from morning to night that could
catch fire is the last one that did not
he never worked so every now and then doing
the rotation of the modems but the
one starts and so on after the whole story
went on and actually when
I finally started sc flat lines
everything changed
but we had already understood that
logic ii and this did
difference because then in reality those
who moved then many were
precisely those dino of trust and therefore
they already knew what they were expecting
on the other side and then after everything
else another thing went on the
copier and
had some LEDs  this picture of the
beautiful LEDs and caught fire with a
certain ease and then had another thing
is
then the copy leaves the place the
acoustic tour couple was used because
also  and not only for those who did not use the
world instead of from but also because if they
had to transfer files for example
I had to not know how to download a data from a
probe I had to send it what do you do you
connect the wifi network but what the [ __ ] there
is no wifi network what exists  the
phone booth with the tokens then the
more an idiot arrived with a box
as well as with the computer etc. you
take a copied view and made the
call and when if tvb bob rock trac
game or call 300 because
hoping it would go maybe you did 23
attempts and what  maybe you made the
second attempt while you made the second
attempt
on the other side in the company phoned
a lady on the other hand heard
on the modem
lady took no one you in the meantime
call find busy and then after
a chain occur that for which afterwards
in the end  in short there goes 56
calls 10,000 tokens and then you see the
guy is
leaning on the handset click click
grid techniques and there and there watching the  The return
warning he makes it he
makes it now he makes it
today another world
is another thing that
is not written anywhere
the computer industry of the time already
existed that is we are talking about the
bbs world that goes  go on with the blow that
olivetti gave with the m24 which has
become the best-selling pc in the world
i was lucky enough to end up
working in olivetti and to find myself at any
moment to beg the gang
somewhere to have  an e-
mail address because all idea or idea was one
of the twelve hosts of nfs net so
I found myself in one of the three places in
Italy maybe you want the university where
everyone had an e-mail
address and everyone used the internet
too  if it wasn't called that,
there was no coupling the
computer industry and we call it telematics
who had experienced much less experience with bbs
like me suddenly
found himself at an advantage because people who
understood all
the ttl circuits knew how  throwing a
pc in front of the trivial use of the line
needed you to explain it to him
i ended up at any moment
as the system administrator of
one of these places where there is
direct access and internet and so i
said cabbage  and they even talk to me
no just because love saw that we are
making history we make history and the
speech of the business of computer science
of the bbs gave a big hand to
these gentlemen who were then
bought for example of the tricom la
zeit sel that it was not  no one started to
do
so part that one who puts his name
on his company for the names I am
sick the association m lo graphics from
a book
the company quantum leap from a computer
then these have named the
company us robotics which is the  'company
that makes the robots in the asimo trilogy
did de standardize in the sense that
if the standard was undoubtedly 2004 it was
24 bis with the protocol correction they
did
what went 96 hth tsh th n  I do not know
a protocol that they had
invented for which
discount after a
strong discount result if they bought the
courier what they had to buy in
such a way that then users were
encouraged to buy the sport ster
because it supported the 9600 because everyone
went to 24 with the  standard modem and but
we are talking about stuff that cost
millions
over the years the end of the eighties
annual cost 1
million lire
and therefore also there a whole business had been created
clearly related to
numbers and
also a whole series of bs software that
also  if shower, however, good or bad we
paid in some way also to
support the thing is to talk about money
among other things even knowing the exchange rate
the devaluation does not convey the idea and on
my shot bio it says that at a certain
point I had to  decide if birthdays
the car or an apple with compensation from the
computer and I chose the personal
computer the price of the same 4
million and a half of the
poor I all  'era I was 16 years old
no more or less I was at my house I
bought my internal trust 14 4 which
cost less than the one there
I was a student I didn't have a penny
the telephone
line the telephone line was the one at home
there  it was my mother who
called relatives in the evening so I
could not use the phone for the bbs no
it
is not clear that this thing goes so
I had put on a bbs that was open
from 10 in the evening to midnight and 13
says midnight  and my mother knew that she could not
call but if you tell her at
midnight the bbs was turned on i
watched people
connect to us i could not connect to the bbm from 10 o'clock
i connected at seven o'clock with my
mother head on the phone I heard  the
casino bellagio the line I cursed
cheerfully so it also caused
some familiar shows this thing
this thing here was
the form in solutions my trusty
admits I have seen it enough with binoculars
having something that could be connected
like this  coli otherwise I had a friend
who always ran on fidonet was called
deus and maybe he knows why he
wrote everything in capital letters because he was
14 and he felt the coolest on
earth and was pardoned and while
the operator
who took him for this let's say
in short  they don't always tell me more as an
excuse illicit how you have to write
things but
on one thing, however, what I ask myself
but if here you had all the bbs hands
what the [ __ ] are we talking about when
we are telling it they are expected to
hang on us like  as usual months
invitations about money
about money no my first portable
laptop and they weren't brought it was a
portable one because it cost much less
than the laptop you don't know
what is untraceable then you have
this as an air one of how I was a tbm
that  did not
then someone thought the case
we make the portable version we make
the video so
then the video so we fit it
alongside there was id  e slots for floppies if
you had money you could also have a hard
disk
practically the keyboard closed
in front
and is doing from a height of about one meter
by one meter in short, it is a
consistent stuff with an equally
heavy weight it is all a [ __ ] vision
yes so it wants to  to say that from that money
he took from me
you buy used and attention
later after then after having changed
the notebooks came out and so on and so on
and when the company bought
the toshiba with the plasma screen
and then there was the  other cool the
famous hercules card who has seen the card is who has
used the card they read and you
just had a great resolution how many
the resolution of the hercules sori
here yes facts that then go beyond
the 6 40 x 480 and practically  black and
white is however now let's not exaggerate then
it wasn't even a black and white
green phosphors to the blazer era
but I still have
the video of my first pc 80
86 gold still working in the warehouses  na what when you turn it on it does
have
a bit like the groping you put I don't know
if it would explode now it would use it
to put the air from that do
and height is however I guarantee you that
I still have it there and I think it is
formally one of the last ones left
on the face of the earth
a note of color we talk about
coupler
acoustic couplers
modem at 300 baud I have never
tried but there were people who,
whistling, managed to negotiate the
carrier
legend legend no no it's true it's true
no that's another thing for  boxing
because in the United States the
communication between the exchanges took place
in bands, i.e. on the same channel on
which the phone calls were made, so as
on which he moved by voice as he said
there were also
mechanical whistles then subsequently
small electronic devices that
they generated these tones and
therefore allowed to control the remote control unit,
however, if for love because this is a
written legend  everywhere that it is
true that the whistle that came out with the
fries of captain cross, however captain
france told us personally that it is
a half legend in the sense that it is true
that that whistle
comes close to 2006 which was the
first tone 2006  it was the first 12 they
also did the magazine etcetera etcetera
but a search on however said that it
is a bit of a legend let's say it is part of the
legend it is part of the legend
however yes let's say the tone that hour
2006 on the waves shakey yo personally
or I think it may  be counted among
the urban legends
almost the hand on fire
a legend instead that is pure reality
because I managed to do it too and
in Italy we had telecom that never
passed the tone selection but
still had the charge solution that is  a
switch that opens and closes
rather than a couple of tones that
defines a cisa and if working in
companies that had the first PBX
switchboards had to do with it
the interface you had the phone the
wheel that someone was taking care of
you saw you in the landfill to take
control of the external line you did
zero when the wheel came back
because the impulses were made
when you go back give a
tap  ring road to the wheel you did
the eleven not the zero it was the 10 of
western and international so
some of these things are not legends after
italy as regards the bills present
here in italy there was before the was
a single rate
and therefore let's say  there it went
pretty well then the
so-called tariffs began everything but urban
always in urban it was whole urban it
was never reaffirmed I swear to the
urban it was really an
incredible blow that is in the sense
my mother who is Venetian I am Abruzzo wine
that she  I phone every day from the
wind so you imagine the bills
were already expensive and of course she was
pissed off as it was said why
obviously those who had a telephone because
not everyone had a telephone in the
house there was only one and obviously there
will be no cordless phone that happened
to be trying to find in the evening because
maybe there was also such a
reduced rate for which my mother calls
in the evening instead the
phone was always busy because in the afternoon
if the fairy tales to the kids for at least 3 4
hours in the evening some bbs was attached
goodnight to the bucket
on this we can do a seminar what
still the serious bedini free urgent
onwards who was there  architect with the duplex
there are people who obviously then
also made money with the
telephone tokens were these tokens which then
at a certain point no better link II
year was I think it starts in the
eighties present from 50 lire have passed
at 100 lire for which the famous boys
went around with boxes full
of tokens to be put in bursts they
found their capital doubled
there was d  we have one as per neutral
for the tariffs a bit of clarity there was
the sip there was nothing else it was from the
state and it was a public company and had
a single rate for local calls
, i.e. within its own
telephone district  and you did not have to
do the prefix that is, if you call them in
pescara 085 you did not make
the number only
if called outside your area code
based on the region where you were calling there were
trains they made three pages
on the list that explained what
we knew  all by heart
then at a certain point they let in
the all-time urban rate
then they are the campaigns to abolish it the
suit was an ass because for those who did it
also for not only because she had the bbs
but also for the mother who spoke five
hours at the  phone with my aunt because before
there was a click after which instead and the
rates varied according to the
call times for which there was
a low-cost time slot which was the night in which
all the  call
the problem what was that if you were a
site of a network as a net wire
what I mentioned earlier
you who were the site did not make
local calls because you had to get
the post at least in the district you are
next to me I have to  call the eagle
and teramo to send the mail we can the
perticara to get some networks from
samuele samuele called me and there was
a whole night scheduler of calls
and I called gino lucro and marco
cipriani who was lab 600 abruzzese
so it was he who  he had the mail and
therefore there were all built-in
mechanisms to make this mail
run well and spend as little as
possible but I assure you that all over
the world because then all this stuff
was one there were pyramid calls
at the beginning  and then pyramid calls in the
morning in such a way that the mail
to the sent everyone sent it
sent to the Italian lab that sent it
abroad and all took back the
usual mail for the
gera structure  rchica that there were
but the rates were fundamental and I
assure you that having a b bs
then as regards this type of calls
which is not that box box avi to call
cipriani it was not possible where to make the
prefix of those calls cipriani
pay then box  ali if you wanted to go to
composer see things for other
things you could save but on these
things here it was a loss-making investment of
course you suspended the money point of
bills were bills also were
bills also salty in fact then
there were financing campaigns of the
bbs  there is someone who asked at times
only simple donations at other
times there were private areas with the
software to be financed to
finance all this hobby
this to get a little clear then at a
certain point they privatized it
became telecom kept the  all
for a period after which the
privatization there was what you
know
connection fee
how many 3 no I don't know
I think  that is not a k
the scene yesterday's world games scene
you see the characters appearing one
at a time on the screen those
perfectly matthew broderick puts the
handset in a mega he copied the
acoustics that went to 14 and 4 i think
it is l  'the only one in the world that went to the
one that never sold but
when you went with an applicator with an
acoustic copy that could go to
a maximum of 300 booms sometimes it
went 110
more to see the characters one at a
time forming on the line and  when he
went to head he finally says away what he
will say in the line after this is another
thing that perhaps was not cleared
another thing that perhaps is not the
clarity was this that before the
speech bbs if you have to send a file
somewhere c  'was the problem that
had to be agreed that you had to
have a line scanned no wait for the
call which then after the way in
answered then you called the other
always answered that in the meantime he did not
call  your grandmother or things like this
then start the transfer even after
there was the famous z modem a great
evolution because you didn't have to start the
game immediately it averaged the
speed it did some things but the
great coolness of when the son of node was born
trust that in reality you had
a third party who was always there so in
fact you could send this stuff there and
the other one went to get it seems like
a beast but it's a big difference
because you didn't have to have on the other side
then not only  sometimes maybe you made
the call it went down maybe the line
was poor
I don't know what but after two or three calls
maybe ended up on the decent channel for
example the thing that capital from
crisis providers could the first modem
for example so even if you called you
felt that it answered then it did not go  a
cabbage
maybe after a couple of calls you ended up
on another modem and here at that
point things worked and for the
season this is a nice thing because I find
ourselves  vavamo the bible is full of stuff
also interesting
of one thing that speed and at an
exotic hardware post it was ok there was the porn
there was the images but with the resources but
how did they get the images
into these systems we do not chat
and  the photos in jpeg
I had a comfortable 64 with the modem and
I also had a somewhat strange device
which is a digitizer practically
in the same way as 64 you could ok connect the
modem attached the bbs try more
attack the visitor which is a
black box with two  white wheels
where careful brightness and sync
sticks off a camera
with composite video and has to appear
over four nearly dot-to-
dot lines and completes veils and
completes the big picture after
ten minutes standing there for  take
a photo of you or point something
you had the whole image is then
that of being able to send things so
I think the famous ones are squares the
teams then they think it happened
and  then so
I don't know but once it was done so
there is scanning point by point and then in
via v with modena
so a couple of things neuro answer
why and why we are here talking about it to
me it seems personally an episode of
rai history in the  sense that anyone in here
niche that sadness
rai story rai
exact story but not only the nice thing about rai
story was the contrast we are giving
to it that is all those above the door
without effort
tell exactly what
happened as in the black and white movies
black of the 60s in which speech and
attention
before 85 in red so
communications did not exist
what he said so in practice
you could only know something about your
city he lived there you were in person and
the library was your point
reference if cooperating a book
abroad
was a business the credit card
sending a fax to america was
impossible there was something for which if
you want something you have to do it  ttare to have it
and and they arrived already versa
if you did arrive etcetera
is the discourse for which we are
used to a logic of
we have had the
opportunity to communicate one by one and
one to many no longer in the same place
with the mimeograph but to  distance which is
something that is now taken for granted
absolutely for granted once if
I wanted to say something to him I had to
call you and agree to
be in the same place for a
beer if I pass something a paper pack
yes
no no but you become  mental ventilation of the
greens health a slaughterhouse as well as going
abroad interrail rather than
ryanair are two things
exactly was that and then
we say that in that way we have
experienced we have understood how
to make the most of a device of that
wonderful kind with the given field
rather  that and there is a number of
different dynamics with respect to
consumer electronics which is
given from my point of view then
another side passage another side topic
to this since in any case
for me
despite having to download a
driver you would telephone that is to try to understand
where it was from the
telephone numbers of the magazines of the
foreign magazines the colleagues and the bbs of the
of the zeit sel rather  that in america
and you download the file from there trying to
bypass the switchboard in the company
casino della madonna it was definitely
impossible to
get such rava or even if on the
computer that I read irregularly
because I could not box every
day what amigas were used for for that
because  a much better sound card
6 my side jump
at the time when I too was arguing with
that technology was when there was
another reality that was communicating
one to many one by one and between
data traffic in an equally way
experience of 1200
was the homeland 3 god was the radio
twenty five years ago 25 leaf took the
license of the radio vapo  re and I had
moved some of my
traffic to that channel like
how many coaches did
then when it came online video
everyone moved beyond so the father
god and teletype all the form of
transmission we had done  beyond was
the economic answer to this in fact
they tell you how far away then talk
to your radio I can call my uncle
in australia and I draw exactly and if he
can download the files with
what the vintage radio package was
one of the  alternatives and digital natives
are you lodo instead saw they
gave it to others this native appeal of
who the [ __ ] is digital native you are
digital native not the guys
demonstrating what they are
considering wait always wait we will be
the digital natives
waiting for what here I can  to say one thing
about digital video is
a bad word bordering on insult
that is it does not mean ignorant but in short,
semi-illiterate s  simply because but
ignorance is right it means you don't know you
are not an [ __ ] if you have never
needed to deal with
technology you take it for granted that
the finger and rightly what is
underneath moves
another note neuron  neuro sorry you have
become very good over time with an
eye because I remember
that there were stop responding via an
amen on a message in a forum
quoting everything
and replying I agree that
person there was taken home if yours
daughter said ti quoto ti quoto
explicit and says major major
major major I agree it did not
pass but I had joker comet come
point all the pictures how many [ __ ]
times I had to put it from a considerable
if I was to be good for folic  of the
nails loris of the mini logical how then you
reasoned impossible
if with good force I had to be or if not
I have to close everyone then from everyone and
then one thing is what is left of
this city then qu  a we are
all doors in short I would say more or less he
no he no you see it is a lot here then
next year I will practically 30
years doing this job and I
like it as I like it from the first day and
I enjoy the soul as you do  I enjoyed the first
day and I think what we have
in common is probably that if we are
here it is also precisely because so I
wish you in thirty years
to have the same situation that is to
go to the haq meeting of I don't know where that
will be done in  so who can not even in the
least imagine given the trend
but here is probably on mars I do not know
what you will connect the space station by
piercing some site because that
way you spend less etc. etc.
I do not know but the concept is that I
hope this continues as it was
for us a great satisfaction
and then not only because you don't believe me
the other day I gutted that
they looked at all the [ __ ] you
did but you don't think
you have cash  we made monori that obviously
there was once upon a time with the tools of the
time and the idiot did it in a
different system today the yachts you make a
more advanced system but the idiot continues to
be an idiot and this is one thing  very
positive we left a tradition
you can also tell us a little bit about the
passage that has been there because until
now we have talked about what
there was and we know what there is the
passage
in the passage there are some
dramatic things of the type that there are  the
moments when you realize that
everything that is studied on a certain thing
you don't need a [ __ ] anymore and this is
unfortunately a constant in the work of
happy computer scientists now I do a ass like this to
learn what I know abel when you talked
about the doss each  of us there were the
wizards of the conflict point ssis and of the
outback point bat
where everyone has his
satisfactions studied is your great position of
power collapsed miserably and so
on evolution the  transition between
amateur telematics and the internet was
gradual and in some ways
even many passed over without
them noticing
many of us with this thing
they made us a profession
now I am a little younger than the
average so I failed to  a hair the
new economy instead of being
an entrepreneur at the time I was a
student but many bbs have become
internet providers key b more
successful than less for example ng
which is now quite a power mc
link that even if it had some
peculiarities I was a bin node  very
important
galactic the third I wanted to mention and
what else
agora rightly agora and in any case
many made a profession out of it at the time
there were still some
amateur or semi amateur systems with
internet access there was saab link that
had organized itself to post news  with
ucp first from the netherlands then from the united states it
was basically a
cooperative provider competing with unit chi
was the only Italian commercial provider
several stops at the time had become
providers at the time there were no grt
obviously one could order a trunk
of telephone lines from the sip
a pile of modems on a
metal shelf from the cellar a bit of servers to
attach them to a
fractional cdn type 128 256
kb of an ai
164 to start even how many users there
were in 64 kb it
cost from several million per month
and in this way many have become
small local providers then the adsl
have wiped out this reality
for various reasons
now  this thing is reviving
in another way with various
wireless operators who come from another world
that of antennas often
do they
make new small local providers
at the time many bbs had become
these I then two years later in
95 I had the  my first
internet connection in the newsgroups i met
other other people i already knew in
fidonet and this thing here went
on even  a for about 45 years
after which
flat connections
for internet and revenue sharing began to spread for which
you only paid the time rate however
then the adsl arrived that
definitively killed every every bbs
because obviously it made no sense to
connect a bbs  when there was the internet
that had technically
better protocols a better speed
there was much more freedom amp almost real
time or even real time but there was much
more freedom than in the management of trust
which had its advantages and disadvantages
but in any case not  aims let
's say the total anarchy of now but there were
still for example the newsgroups that the
first years had an
important quality so there was this
gradual transition people slowly
disappeared lele bbs slowly closed
for example I don't  I remember a certain
moment the coordinator of rome of
lazio closed all within three
days because he was hired by
italia online I think that's all  ra the head
of security of jol
we have to close they tell us about
Reggio
however I have a recommendation
recommendation simply because for
the various vicissitudes of life it happened
that following the collapse of the
olive groves I have been a trainer on technology for years
those of you who have had  the good fortune
to reproduce and therefore have digital natives
in the house
do not try to explain the technology
for charity do not talk to them about the
punch cards of the acoustic companions
to the limit with an excuse but you to see
the world games and then start from there but
if you want that  can understand something
of what happens in the world of
telematics even if only interested in the
latest iphone
explain the history the technology
let you make a conscious effort
not to whistle like a modem and try to
explain to them what it meant at the time to
be able to talk to the  abroad where you
appropriate things simply
because they could not be bought  re even if
you had money you wanted to buy yourself a
connection x25 you could not do it
there was no category of private use of
information technology try to explain
this because it may be that they are only
interested in the thing and do not
take you for fools that is the situation
normal that happens when someone
tries to explain something that in
quotation marks we can call a piece of
history to people who have not lived it
to my mom