ok hello everyone i am ma i'm gpl big
shot we have as special guest guido
bolognesi di zen who wanted us
instead of who we asked to
tell us about his experience with
trick 8 and then maybe he also tells us
a bit how he built and we are  remained
at last year's talk for who was there
I don't know if you remember it or if you saw
on youtube how not to build a
quadcopter last year we didn't have
a working quadcopter yet
the good news is that this year
we have it
after that talk finally
the propellers we had ordered arrived
someone remembers practically we
bought the tv before the material we had
bought only four propellers obviously
just finished assembling it first thing
he did he overturned and broke a
propeller so they could stay me
external one month to wait for the propellers
9 from china but now we have a
box full of propellers so not the
problem does not exist so remember
if you do a  quadcopter to take more
than four propellers at a time well after
lesc the first suggestion after les that
we had made a quadcopter
with the multi this card here we had
said to eliminate it is called the
kkk but managed to make it work even
if the one with the display we  we had the one
without display in our defense and
we chose the multi wii because it
was a little more complex a little more
complete it had all the
real-time information of the
quadcopter you could see the
status of the sensors and the whole
configuration is represented in one
which very nice they asked for a bus
of engines and therefore already with the
ground quadcopter you could understand more or less if
when we turned it on it would
overturn and that is a great step forward
so as soon as we finished assembling the
quadcopter
here we were already with this frame this
here is the wood trend that we
made we went from an
aluminum frame which was the first that not
it was fine because the arms twisted to
a frame in sheet metal tubes like those
of the camping tents but that
was very good and it was very light
but when it fell they bent and
knew and we decided to switch to
wood because it is very easy to
work  blasphemy if it falls it breaks it costs
very little not very little because it is very
flexible and does not transmit vibrations it
performs very well the vibrations of the
engines
and it is very easy to work and cheap
so super excited and happy to
have a working quadcopter
we started to do the first  tests
with go pro and video from above
and the first problem arose it is nice to make
the quadcopter go up
there at the bottom there are the mountains then it
turns and then I was at the shutter that
explains it to us big shot who is a photographer
actually I don't know how to explain it to you very well
I can only tell you that if I remember correctly it
depends on how the
sensor of a room is managed and
some strips are taken  sce at a time so if
based on the frequency of this I was
in
the inter the frequency of rotation of the blades to
the effects and imaginative
ok here we are flying we started
from here we were at the bottom when
we started and here we had already lost
sight  the quadcopter and I'm trying to
get him back home with little success
because they didn't see him I could no longer
find him here there is venice among other things
we are this euro where I live more or less
forty minutes by train from venice and
therefore here we have lost quadcopter
obviously the commands of the quadcopter
respond with respect to the nose of the
quadcopter so as soon as it turns
a bit if you have no eye contact and does not
know which way to turn the commands go
backwards at a certain point I decided
to turn off the engines and luckily let it fall
into the  fall
we appeared noticed he saw it fall
and we saw what had happened and then
we were able to fish it out and go and
retrieve it after seven minutes of
walk
ok damage few
actually did not suffer major
damage success had broken an
engine support that are made of aluminum
the arms were completely internal
the support of the go
pro was slightly broken but nothing serious
we did an account from the height
we  measured the time it
took to fall in theory it was more or
less 100 meters and in fact this here is
the same frame that happened and there is
practically nothing at all the frame
itself electronics no problem the
battery has hit hard and it is
inflated and we could take it to
blow up analysts but we
forgot and broke two propellers the first
two propellers not even serious after
this experience
we thought it best to inform us for a
moment what is generally done in these
cases there is a function called fail
safe which  usually it activates when it
is turned off when the helicopter no
longer receives commands in this
function generally can be programmed  ata for
example in this case to make it
land then by the little
accelerators so that slowly terry alone is
possible instead with buying a gps
put a 66 a bit of complex that
brings the quadcopter back home
automatically when it loses
the remote control signal
so we have  rightly decided to buy a gps
there are different brands of
gps
the cheapest ones are not enough there are the media
techs that are the first that it is not that they
were used because I blocks that
were still a lot
now instead the blocks are for 10
15 euros so  and it is better to buy
those and they are the best
and finally there is the alternative of the k networks the
k networks is a gps a little more complex
in the sense that there is a gps on board the
Quadri Cotter a gps at the base at the
station where where  the quadcopter is launched, they
communicate via radio and
information is exchanged on the difference
in position with respect to the
fixed station and the
moving object and with  This technology needed the
accuracy of 45 centimeters maximum
error is the cheapest commercial
costs about 1,000 euros and also open source
and among other things, however, there are modules
that have recently come out of this
for 25 euros each, therefore with two  modules is
a radio module among the transceivers
in theory it is possible to do something by
spending little we see if the
open source community decides to commit itself from
this point of view and develop
something they will certainly contribute
so we have the multi wibro after a while it
began to stay tight we  decided
that we wanted something more and then
we took lardo pilot arru pilot
this ticket here is the most used it is
practically the most widespread ticket the
most widespread autopilot among all of
them and it is always an open
source project born from 3dr robotics that is
committed  to develop it is this here is
the second version
now the version is available
always mounts a micro based on arduino there is a
nati meg  a
cortex m4 based version has recently come out which is
called px 4px hoc which is a tronic
developed by the university of switzerland
something like this is even more
recently
andrew tridgell who is one of the main
hardware developers of this
announced project who are  working
on a kate on board for the beagle
bonn and then using the
linux-based bi golborne system insists to make
the autopilot announced that there was the
first flight of a drone let's call it so
indeed for all intents and purposes hall with
based on  bigon black and at an
amateur level first based on linux then
ok
among the interesting things that
lardo pilot can do is the programming of
waypoints so you can program
a whole series of way points to make
the drone go which is now a
drone because then  it will have autonomously you
can make it run paths you can
specify an area a rectangle a
polygon on the map to be scanned and the
program the software  of flight labase
station that I do not have in which installed is
the bay station calculates in a
cancer range all the path you need to do
to take the photos from above
all that area to map the photo
with the photos like google earth
there is  a very interesting telemetry
in the sense that by buying telemetry modules it
is also possible via
telephone with a usl cable or tg usb otg
connect the radio receiver 403 meyers
and have the information in real time
on the phone you can drive the phone drone by
telling it  pressing a point
on the map
and and sending sky there is another
interesting function that linz of tracking
so we have our gps on the
phone and the drone follows us and beyond the
telemetry on the model soldier this
here is the first we did then
we did  another later and
we also put in we used on
this an open source
rs remote is always 430 mega hertz and this is
a remote  penn source
always developed by the community of 3d
robotics and and this is a remote control
that has a transceiver module
that also allows you to integrate
telemetry and has a range that can
reach up to tens of kilometers
with good antennas and beyond that
on the other drone we also put
the camera for the pv axis with a
normal 5 8 gb transceiver that
you will find that you can easily find on the
internet
so we have made in addition to this
another quadcopter that I do not have here but
in short at home because unfortunately yes
crashed the other day a month ago more
or less and not that all a bit of
repair and that crashed because
a motor cable was disconnected and
then in flight
that quadcopter overturned there before
crashing it had to become an hex
cotter then with 6 propellers and this
would have saved me from pain but
unfortunately the engine did not arrive in
time and therefore I did not have it not
yet  mount
so if you want redundancy you must
have at least a crush
having two drones we also bought
from remote controls it is an interesting thing
that we can do with this setup and
connect them via a 3 mm audio jack
and a half and it is possible to use the
remote controls in live masters so a  an
instructor in full control of the drone
while the student in control only
of the basic functions and the
movement of the limited sticks in order not
to avoid damage and the instructor
after correcting at any time
among other things if you want to do some tests
of this kind
next week next
weekend and between two weekends in ferrara there is
the balloon fair and there is
marco robustini who is one of the beta
testers the italian developers very
important to me for the ardu
copter project and you can do some tests  with
its drones that are a bit more serious than
ours
so we decided to dedicate
this helicopter to training for pe  r to
teach those who want to fly the
drone and to use them a bit as
toys in fact we have
some challenges among us
one of these is to enter the bathroom of
our acrid space with the
quadcopter challenges that are not always successful
for now  no refusal to enter the bathroom
this is a bit I say it is a
relatively narrow corridor
we go on and on the mountains because we are
short of time without gps because we are
inside the house
the bathroom door that
always ends well on the right and in any case we
have enough to have fun
then what do we have to talk about
well after the code paintings I feel
like experimenting on other vehicles show
quadcopters worth helicopters are
similar in type of control they
can still stay still nine
languages so we switched to
something different
she is a modeling classic
so  documentation is finished I thought
maybe a little simpler so I
got carried away and a friend  who
here in the room gave me a beautiful
model recovered from the infamous areas
with balsa wood I started to repair them
a little bit but the investigating judge rightly
advised me not to start as models below
because if they are destroyed
from the low
I worked for nothing and we are aimed
at  obi and the super easy we
arrived at albi king known site where
too much money is spent and we bought
this bixler that the basis to
start learning to use the rings by
the way quite easy is not too
fast to a good autonomy and well
we took it came from man
humanity in a field near ours
for expenses did not make the first
launch attempts because it launches off the
cuff takes off with the wheels this we
crashed the first ten
times with various with various problems  and
you appear as you can see from the American master
and okay in reality all
I can tell you is
that unlike a quadcopter that in
case you have  some doubts about how to
continue to command it you can leave it
still in hovering in some way it
helps to regain control
this here comes towards you or
it is moving away there is no way to
stop it you have to be just a little more
ready and it is much easier  make it
crash than any other
multi-doctor helicopter for which
our policeman tried to
put a pilot here too because
the art pilot provides three types of firmware
for the many doctors for the planes and
also for the nine the first test
we did it with the pm
we totally wanted the nose
we just refitted so this
is where we are now
it's the latest possible update
so it's a lot of fun jared yesterday it's
pretty exciting because they go
away they
travel pretty fast  but they are
very difficult later instead he wants to
tell us briefly, give us two minutes
in case you want to start me of
course  I have nothing to teach you
because I started in September
of last year so it is not that I know
very much
some things are quite important
for safety
now I know that it is a break of
browns but then these them that here
seem absolutely harmless are
extremely sharp  and they are
quite hard plastic so there are
very funny pictures on the internet of
people with a series of spots on their
forearms for example because they were
doing the electronics tests
they started a motor with the propellers
attached ion strained half of a
forearm
me  myself I inadvertently put my fingers on it
more than once
until I had some small propellers
still okay with these here I
kept a beautiful bruise on my hand
for let's say a week plus the cut
obviously the batteries of these objects
are hypo batteries  the hypo have
an annoying feature they are a bit
unstable so they tend to be a
pack of  explosive inside a battery
a battery of these is a not
very expensive object 20 30 euros
this is a 4 amp battery which has
a dump capacity of 20 times
its nominal capacity so it is
four amps by 20 this means
we to the object that  able to
deliver a peak 80 a lost no more and it is
clear that from the electrical point of view
for example you have to stay a little bit
because in case I miss a short
this here the bouncers 80 mwhy a
decent kick nor the other thing is the
piloting that is where you find where you
play until it crashes is the least
of the problems
that is when a quad has crashed
when a trio crashes we know where
it crashes and it is there typically the
real problem is the opposite that is when an
object you are testing  takes and
squirts off this stuff here it
serenely runs 20 kilometers per hour
the three I have not yet measured but
in my opinion it reaches around 40 has
an autonomy of 10 minutes fifteen
minutes  it goes very far before the battery runs out
if for any reason you can no
longer control it so be
careful
in theory an enac regulation came out
not so long ago that is
foreseen for the control
then you tell me when I have to cut that
if anything  let's go on out that it is intended
for the control of what they
call
remotely piloted aircraft the aprs the aprs are
objects are those are the real drones
that is, they are the objects that you
program and are able to go
to such distances that  who launched
it is no longer able to keep the
distance visual control
theoretically these models
are out of the control of this
legislation which speaks of objects for
critical operations therefore
television shooting support for
civil protection operations and things of this type
this does not mean  to say that they are
harmless objects
that is, if you jump in your face a 30 per hour
is an object that weighs a kilo with some
propellers spinning strong so
I personally
recommend insurance but simply because
legal disputes maroni breakages to no end
second what I told them about the hypo and
the hypo are a bit delicate in they should not be
loaded too much if they are damaged and yes
swell means that part of the
internal chemistry is damaged this
means that they develop
potentially flammable gases
if you overload a hypo that
explodes the lithium burns which is a pleasure
and therefore it is difficult to extinguish them
with water they do not go out so you
would need a bucket of  sand
in short, inquire about the
last thing the limits I told you
the enac does not provide for legislation at the
moment in Italy for objects of this
type because they are considered radio
models radio models means that they
are objects that you check on
sight
everything that is c  I mount a
video camera and buy the goggles, the
screen and look at what he sees,
theoretically he won't  they give more a pr
because you don't make it a pr in the
sense that you are not checking it by
looking at it
if you decide to play with these
technologies always get someone
who is with you and who keeps an
eye on the model because sometimes it is
very difficult to  what he sees
understand where you are because clearly
the perception of spaces is very
different from what we are
used to a park you know
seen from 30 meters high is very
different there are limits also for
model makers so also for  people that
those models are 70 meters high and
200 meters radius from where you
are
if you have the valerio modeller's license
I think it extends to 150
meters high and 400 away I
assure you that an object of this
size
if you don't have very,
very cool electronics that have functions that
make your life easier and I don't have them and at the
moment I think they are practically there
in the sense that the gps went that I do not
already have at 30 meters it is very difficult to understand
how it was shot and its
reference system is never yours the
forward is
not necessarily back and forth is not necessarily backwards
on the  remote control and therefore also
correcting if you are not clear how it
is shot is complicated it is an
extremely fun hobby be careful
that unfortunately we have not
brought our types alone explode
this is what happens
we do
modify it become so
then you no longer
have to use it you need a  lithium
battery a lithium battery is not soft a
lithium battery is hard if pressing the
case it becomes soft it means that
there is gas inside
so I know it is ugly it is expensive to
give up a battery costs in emotional terms
but I would avoid if I were  in flight to
play with it because it is dangerous for your
hands and dangerous for your home
so typically when the battery
charges it where it charges it at home in  garage
somewhere difficult to
load it 30 meters and a half to the garden in
a sandbag, however, what
we have seen wrong the batteries of
dubious Chinese origin of dubious quality
after the passive around alone so
or it turns off a little more  you take it two
so it doesn't formally forward you forever
it's not a good question
no question
yes
now it's a little bit that we
built it this one maybe they said
well there is a moment ahead
but above all the face close when it
is forming amount done one  estimate
last year with the previous monster
talk I can tell you that they built
probably cost you a party
hundreds of euros among 400 of material
it is not so if you do it for the first
time it will make many mistakes to understand the
sizing of the alias engines
that  are the controllers of the motors and
propellers and many other things for which we the
first time that they have spent a
thousand euros from the final the inclusion of a
radio control is exalted  to me
then already all of the sensors on board
lardo paolo will be able to the gps the mind that
conceals you which is a separate module and
in the latest versions also the
magnetometer has been taken out
because it suffers a bit of the various
possible interference so
mount it a little distant from the
electronics that passes, having seen its
operation well,
other otherwise okay thanks bye bye