calls I call then well I'm rick
I'm part of the forum and I just wanted to
discuss in this talk so
discuss it will not be just me
talking about the differences between the 2 the gpl
version 2 readable and gpl version 3 and
to do so obviously here is a little
austere  of what I will deal with but do not
think that it is faithful to what I
write and I am never faithful to what I
write first of all I wanted to start
with you with some questions
first of all I wanted to know if for
example between patents patents
copyright are the same thing in your opinion
because  they are different
would you know me answer
ah ok yes but it does not count as an answer it does not
count as a respect
I foresee the author to foresee the peak
becomes so also the patent I am alone it is
only a legislative thing that is not an
invented right but then I can say
congenital behavior among the  various states
then I'm sorry to disappoint you but it has been
standardized for several years then
first of all if copyright is
patent  or both start from a legal basis
, copyright is not not covered
by the law otherwise we certainly are not innate
in the sense that it arises when you conceive
the work but it is not in place in the sense that
in this sense in the sense  who has the
copyright in theory would not
need a registration for now
something different to say that in the act you save
but I need to create a work is already
protected by copyright
the patent must be registered but it is another
procedure protect the  same thing both of
them protect an idea but
copyright protects it no
both have paternity protects the as
tool less prime the form of your idea
the patent protects the industry lita
of your exact idea
are transferable  two of the two rights
are not transferable the moral rights are
transferable the patrimonial rights
tell me tell me but it is done on purpose
this wrong of to provoke
the moral right is not transferable in any case if
you are always recognized as the father of the
your work
no no it's not like this because in any case we
have implemented the latest regulations it may
then be on the various states I don't
know how to tell you
in Italy or in the United States the
moral right is always with the author
so much so even in patents  so much
so that you cannot change s.to
extend in the united states the owner
of the patent el applicants the one who to the
patrimonial rights you can not
get them at the moment of the registration
of the patent there is at the moment write me
of the viscous extension at the moment
registration with the European patent office
only afterwards, therefore the link between moral rights is very strong,
so the
United States and Italy are
always yours moral rights are not trainable they
are not transferable
no patrimonial do us what
you prefer best of  who is it that
defines the author as the inventor but can
you tell me there is a rule a paragraph that
tells me who the inventor is who is that
gives me a definition of author or
inventor  and go go go
it has nothing to do not
rightly for the word but always a
patent for something that we do not
care exactly today
there is something that is said who aiel who is
the inventor that the author an article of
law one  sentence something
according to you there may be
no someone who defines who the car is
the concept of author or inventor
I tell you no there is no law does not
establish who is the author the inventor if he
does not give a certain definition he declares
author the inventor what he can do
we have already seen what it is in this framework
what is the license according to you we have
seen that there is an inventor who has
rights who has rights that are to
start ideas that are protected
or  with the patent with the copyright
the license how you get into all this
game
exactly is the use exactly is a no
to mess up here there is samuele here
thanks I loaded the countdown damn it
but terrible that a misery if I
put the chick  pia while pole then
give  po then the license license for use
establishes how you can use my
work
and what exactly you think is a
contract copyright patent what they
are instead
you are complicating too much
what are the property
titles essentially property titles
copyright  from the law, however, the
form of ownership the patent is a
form of ownership encoded in an act
that is then approved as it is
approved etc. it is good
here is what we are talking about it
made me a small mental map of
what our
reference  we have the inventor is the one who
generates the creative work to the
invention what this are his title
deeds who gives them to these titles
industrial property code copyright law
this is ipr intellectual property
rights are all and  two
industrial property rights
are ok for them, however if we talk about the
so-called digital right management, the rights management
system of  gitali
and on both of them
then we talk about industrial property
we are in this field here we are talking
about copyright we are in this field
here ok these protect an idea in
its realization the exclusivity of the
patrimonial rights linked to its
use in its production
these  these the diffusion
obviously simplifying it all
night much more but simplifying it
let's say the diffusion of a work ok and
the license agreement and as an action on the
right the invitation as I make
others enjoy payment or for free
his problems
here are these tough this take  at least
three four minutes mystical body to mechanical body
then if I sell you a book
ok what happened
what I passed to you but
also the work but there is but now I
ask you another question to understand I pass you a
cd with a  operating system a
proprietary cd that I paid does it to you we do
not see what is lawful or
illegal I do not pass it to you
no it is lawful to pass you cd with the system
or  perative you can install it on your
computer that operating system takes away
the theory no it cannot install however the
cd that exclusions no no forget it
you are getting too specific
we stay more than minutes so I have to
cut and these are important to
understand the differences that  I am there I
pass you a cd ok the ownership of the seal
italo past or not of the cd
physical support exactly the mechanical body I
pass it through the property the
mystical body is not necessarily passed in the
case of the book that also passed the
mystical body yes it  you can read yes but
because there is a law that says that the
patrimonial rights there is a law in
the ritual text that the patrimonial rights
on the work are exhausted in the first
sale within the
community territory are you could light
so the program  no but why not
because the property that is because it is a
license I pass you I sell you a
property Chile has acquired
illegally and it is all
yours  program no because the license and
remains the center I have not passed you the
ownership of a program
and know immediately by
simplifying to bodies you always buy
the mechanical body never the mystical
body mystical body for example in the book I have it
with trip in quotation marks only because it
c  'it is a law that says that after
you can affect it well this is a bit
because when the gpl was born but
I think you all know it better
than me 89 for the case is max m salman
had changed the emak code  he knows,
however, is but it was then sold by
goslin from uni press which then had
closed it anyway and therefore was
forced to rewrite the code is
in fact it was released without
restrictions and had involved a
change in the distribution of this
software of the license d  I use it and I
have been a bit imprecise here comes out 2
and finally comes out born in 2005
remember that there are 14 years of
difference and we see it exactly and
we see it so we know g  ià what
the gpl establishes the freedoms to
modify receive and distribute the
code recognize the copyright they
recognize it so much so that in the gpl
version 2 of the preamble it is written that
only thanks to this license you can
make that software if there was no
license
all rights reserved by default you
pass with all rights reserved
the definition of rights for
the user in a positive way
is not like in the license that you who are
written in the copyright that I
believe you can not do this if  not etc
no you can do this this and this
in these ways you have to redistribute it in
this other way you can configure
economic aspects but let's go
here for a moment la3 la3
first of all it is an alice there is the
so-called transaction and identity
or when you take a
company asset which includes LPG assets the
license remains ok case it is but the
situation of the piece of furniture that has
arisen with the 9
article 11 is patentability quest  o it is
a very very very stringent article
in the sense that while in ii it was
simply said you can patent but if you
patent your distribution must
be compliant with gpl version 2
so beyond this it is also said it must
be variety all over the world
impossible not exclusive there  it can be
free from royalties it can cost us and must
guarantee the possibility to create use
sell offer for sale import and
modify programs containing
the taxpayer version but
remember the true virality of
the gpl license so if I am a start
up or a patent now gpl nobody  for
example I will never buy a software
protected by the gpl version 3 x which necessarily
forced to take this poo
by premising that the first is
unattainable
I have worked many years in companies that
patent noe and exchange patents to
live and realize the first point the
others  they are very very difficult to
make
in the act pra because they just are
string  however, let's go further on the
mtp we will then talk about the tive case that
was the case according to which the
problem of the license version 3 broke out I estimate
what was active was a device
that whose software released in gplv2 open
completely open you could write
do prevent etc.
put them inside tivo tv did not
make you work it did not work because
because there were the rom in which
there were digital signatures of
approved programs inside your digital signature was not
within that the system did not
go  this is a limitation but
we talked before about the
mechanical body of the mystical body
let's reflect there is not a moment here on
the active case
I think
how to do it
sure
exactly you if you are able the sip
of the digital signatures you can really
remove it exactly is the property
exactly  however, such a clause
can put in crisis so much so that it is
a user product for a consumer market and
for a consumer market for merc  ato
business in fact the business market
is in fact excluded because in any case
equipment that requires a
certain certification they say how
I can not put my signatures my
signatures
I certify this asset and I
charge not so much on the license as
precisely on the fact that I  I certify
and therefore only the
concept of user product was created we have 33
seconds fast
so
then in that case it depends on
welding the chip for in that case there
is unfair competition to another
thing because you exploit a sea you resell
that brand branded as a branded joint
sorry without the chip but
you exploit the name of others
as a user exactly by a user you can
obviously if it is not protected by a patent
you can copy how the matrix is made
redo it if you exclude certain things put
others sell your grandmother this  this
you can do big is not covered by
patent and not using
the name and yes or even the form factor then
it depends on there it depends a lot on the
protection that exactly depends on these
things here but in theory if there
is no other
industrial property or intellectual property title
that blocks you
yes why not so much given the ownership of
that asset and your software  no okay yes
there are other questions
yes yes to stay talked to sodium
already little
I know
no
while jumping I can not say
if the pressing key math to have
players is actually the fact that
on theside of the
mysteries
we are the hardware
these  you leave united
no
one thing that I with xavi
exactly is a risk that you accept
that is when you go to take that asset
you know what it is going to face knows the risk that you
run not to have for example another
encrypted backup somewhere else
this is  another matter
the information then it is a different matter
that the problem brothers mercatone
not between you and the producer could also
have done a course to the producer and the
producer  has not informed you about the
concept of the internet and using the
internet to use the forums to
bother anyway also for
people to come various hack meetings
etc. it also serves to inform themselves to
understand
the case of fraudulent information can happen
however I
am both that it does me
how it does
this if the manufacturer does not know it
specifies but it is something else it does not fall
under the copyright does not fall within the
patentability it falls within the
customer information if it is a consumer market
if it is the business market it
is always necessary to the information but
we are talking to a professional
while in the consumer market to talk
as if there was a fool ahead of the times
so be very
clear
vital ppm
if
but the point is
cisco
one thing I had
if the sam producer published he
still explained what  makes its
product to the so-called datasheets more
does not have to tell you in the sense that it is you who afterwards
have to evaluate whether that product  to
that is, you have freedom of choice in the things you
understand and also in
the information if the information is not adequate,
the counter with the manufacturer will occur for a
certain reason then it is not done but it is a
different kettle of fish
but in theory you could do it if
he sold you one thing for another the
scam exists and is criminally prosecuted
understood but not
if I had to be a healthy kitchen
if something happens they will not let us
remain
a trace
but you
but knowing it you can choose
this
by doing the first alcohol tests
me  I know that that
card
gentlemen I have to stop you just enough is
enough