we will quickly explain
we will see what peering is what it
means how the networks parts of the internet
exchange traffic and then we will see
how the traffic exchange between
Italian networks
is organized internet is a set of
independent networks without any particular
formal or substantial coordination for
everything about routing, that is,
the exchange of information on the
directions that the traffic must take,
you will find the other, as there is no one
higher than the others that coordinates
this, there must be
typically bilateral agreements between the
networks so that a network of ca all  'other
for which one entity
tells the other for which networks in the sense of pp wants to
receive traffic to do this
technically is the bgp protocol is used
the border gateway protocol version 4
with which the border routers say
the one  the other on my side there are
these re pp I can receive in traffic
the other side can decide
okay I accept I accept that you m  i say
that these networks are on the other side
eventually then i will send you the traffic
which are subsequent decisions there are
different possible types of
interconnection per second depending
on the relationship between
the entity in question for example I
can have a customer who pays me
because  take away its traffic
stop of the internet that is trivially
a square any
ADSL access connection etc.
but also in general practically
any operator must have one
possibly more suppliers what
is called transit i.e. forward
their traffic to the rest of the internet
transit providers provide
this service their customers
where this chain ends
transit supplier customer may have
other transit providers in turn at the
top of the pyramid there are 12 15 networks
that are called taiwan that
exchange traffic entirely pre of them
without  have none without using
any other network to reach and
others
this is called peering and exists both
at the upper level
of the traffic pyramid, but also at
the lower levels, two networks can
agree to ensure that the
traffic between them does not pass through a
transit provider but through a
direct interconnection  this traffic
can be exchanged for free
or in exchange for money as
appropriate, peering is an agreement that
governs both from a
technical and a commercial point of view
if there is an exchange of money which
traffic is exchanged between two networks  it is
precisely a bilateral relationship because it
concerns two networks that exchange
traffic exclusively between
themselves and that of their customers does not
replace transit to the rest
of the world
because it concerns traffic
to the other network and their customers not
to the rest  of the internet in general
can be either an informal agreement cc is
met and it is said well let's exchange
traffic  or or it can be governed
by a contract that is in some cases also
extremely complicated for example the
dozen or so Thai air one
between them have extremely strict peering contracts
also because each tries to avoid
that its competitor is in
some way an advantage and  there may
be clauses such as for example
we have to exchange traffic in
four continents in seven of these
nine cities on circuits of certain
dimensions that will always be maintained
with a certain percentage of
free capacity and so on
instead generally between the
smaller networks  no
formalities of this kind are necessary simply
we agree to exchange
traffic at present from an economic point of view
the peering can be either sepia while or for a
fee
in the case of peering settlement free
it is decided that both parties
agree they agree on the fact  that it is
currently useful to exchange
traffic so I don't think  It is not necessary
for one party to compensate the other
otherwise if one of the two parties
deems it does not have a particular
advantage in establishing a
direct connection with another network
then it will decide that if this other network
wants to have a direct inter connection
with it
always to exchange  your
traffic can be paid for from a technical point of
view there are basically
two large categories of interconnections
there is public peering in which
all interested parties are not internet
exchanges arriving with their own circuits
and connecting to the
internet exchange switches where c  'it is more or less
than an ethernet network in which your
routers are connected to each other
speak bgp not necessarily everyone
speaks to everyone
this is a platform that allows you to
meet
each other and then decide with whom you want to
talk the alternative is the  pierre in
private you take a
direct circuit between two locations of the two
entities  à that they exchange traffic and in
this regard only they are not
lost there who participate in this
one choose one the other solution
mainly according to
technical reasons for for quantities of data
let's say relatively small
it is not convenient to
create a new each for
direct connection instead  you see an inter in the
backstage there is no particular
relationship between trucks in public and private and
paid peering per night
these cases can be
easily mixed in various combinations
because you are peering there are excellent
technical reasons for peering with
a  'other network
meanwhile the local traffic from one city to
another from one nation to another
remains local does not make long routes
this means that the traffic between the
two networks will have a lower latency which a
useful thing for many applications
we think gaming holl did tera  but in
general it is also a useful thing for
web traffic
at this point and we know the latency
of the of a conne  ssion affects in a
certain way the speed with which
the web page finally arrives in the
browser so there are some entities
I cite for a trivial example google who
want to get as close as possible to
those who visit their sites in order to
offer the best
possible performance  It is also interesting to note that as
long as the local local traffic lives in
other jurisdictions,
if the traffic to get from my
network to another network maybe goes around
Germany for the United Kingdom
for France as it can sometimes happen
unfortunately it means that with
traffic  by train to another country where
perhaps it can be intercepted according
to the laws in force in that
country but not only if my traffic between
me and another network, even if it does not leave me out of
Italy, is conveyed by a
third carrier
which however has  based in another country
this company will be regardless of
what the Italian laws are it will
also be subject to the laws of that other
country it is useful ten  It is always present
from a technical point of view,
however, it is a good idea to invite
your traffic to pass through the networks of
others
this allows greater
reliability
there are fewer points in the chain
that can break which can
cause problems
direct traffic on occasions of
generally there will be this then it
also allows greater control over tg remakes
the traffic
I could decide that my traffic
to a certain network suits me more
that I take a certain path
within my network of its network that
another in this way I know  exactly
since it is only the two of us who does ciro
and I can decide it in case of problems
since it is always me and the other network it
will be much easier to investigate there
because we can talk to each other directly in the
meantime we know that there is no one in
between when there is  is someone in between I
assure you that it can also be very
complicated to investigate an
end to end connectivity problem
everyone must ini  to put in the
field technicians of their own
transit provider who will have to convince themselves that
there is a problem that does not depend on
their customers but perhaps depends on
their own network or on the network of another
transit supplier with whom they
turn to which I will not be able to speak
directly  since they are not their customers,
this risks making them
waste a lot of time the public pirin is
very convenient because it arrives at the internet
exchange I pay
what is the cost per sun is a member in
italy in the internet exchange are all
consortia that are substantially if
without purpose  for practical purposes
and the consortia to the GDP
in general are all non-
profit and may have different corporate forms
but the practical effect this
each member is and affects the
decisions that
regarding the organization after having
paid I carry the  my cable is connected
to the switch to the switches depending on the dl
of how big the network of the inter  net
exchange more or less redundant and I am
ready to exchange traffic with
anyone who wants to exchange it with me and
convenient because in this way I do not have to
organize to bring on the circuit
to each of the other networks with which
I want to exchange traffic and it is also
cheaper in the
meantime it allows me  to save a thousand
two thousand euros of network port for
each circuit with which I should reach
the other operators
instead I only need one port or more
depending on what my
dimensions are and then it also allows me to
size my circuit with which it
arrives  to the exchange on the basis of
what the overall traffic peaks will be,
however, kit of the networks that
I see between me and them while instead if I
arrive with an independent circuit
towards each independent network
I will have to provide
additional capacity on each of these
circuits in order to cope with the
sudden and unexpected traffic peaks and
this starts to add up with a lot of
space b  go that I have to leave free
for possible future eventualities on the other
hand if instead with a network I exchange
so much so much traffic then it
can be economically and
technically convenient a direct interconnection
are things that are evaluated according to
the needs of each among the
advantages of peeling  we do not think it
contains economic
this because the costs of transit from
2000 onwards have really collapsed in
2000 has revalued a to the cost of living
as a megabit per month which is the unit
of measurement of the cost of the internet band
that is a megabit for the duration  purchased
for the duration of a month it
cost 2,500 3,000 euros now always
a mega biped traffic for a month
costs me between 50 cents a euro and a half
so
the cost varies depending on how
much capacity I undertake to buy
these from my supplier  pairs of
values are respectively the prices of
a gigabit of 10 gigabit traffic
then there is also a certain variability per
second  and in supplier to the other of
its quality and other issues which
market is it clearly costs me less to
buy band in Milan than to buy it in
Palermo where my supplier has to
arrive with longer circuits where
maybe it will have much less market for which
less economies of scale and so  on the
other hand, the cost of peering is lower
than the cost of transit which is one of the
reasons why peering is done, however, these
are truly
negligible savings for a small network
.
this is not why people do
peering do peering for the reasons we
have seen before
improves the quality of traffic
allows you to better control it allows you
to intervene more easily in
case of
problems there are three main internet exchanges in Italy
I am a mix of Milan that even the
oldest na mix of Rome and Topix of
Turin later present because in Turin
also in all the other provinces  and in
Piedmont there is a ring of fibers
provided by the Piedmont region that
interconnects the various offices in this
way possible to connect in
different points this is used by
many local operators that make wifi and
operators of a specific area that
have their presence only there
this  it is very convenient because it
allows him to interconnect without
going directly with a
dedicated circuit in turin as well as in milan
other exchanges are tix di firenze
at the headquarters of the tuscan region of
six in padua from mix of in bari mi knapp
that the exchange is alternative of  milan
managed by me and a mix of palermo that
none of you probably know
because as soon as you arrive I don't even
think there are already active networks the first three
altogether between them
before the beginning of the summer they did
250 gb of traffic others is negligible
in  comparison 250 gb
said between us there are not many
compared with the large European
markets where there is a traffic exchange  both
national and international
beck x9 priest rabbit hamsik a
little less
links two once linz and hamsik 5 6
years ago they played the first
place then there was a big
slowdown of the internet in london
trivially because the space was run out and
docklands it  space the current until
new data centers have been built
in these s inge a lot of
traffic is exchanged because not only
national traffic is exchanged but there are also
many foreign networks that arrive
there to exchange traffic with other
foreign networks for example the company for
whose work has a connection to
hamsik the kinks but a lot of traffic
because many networks arrive from eastern
europe from russia also links arrive
many networks in down tubes they arrive
rapidly to the middle east also from the
united states also in the italians
some foreign networks arrive
however for how  the internet market works and
in europe they come to italy to
exchange traffic with non italian networks
to exchange it among themselves for evidently geographical reasons they
prefer to exchange it in more central places
there are also private pierins in italy
however mainly for the
largest operators in telecom italia
assures me surely because
he has a direct knowledge of it peering with
wind and fastweb and batteries  xvi netter wind
and fastweb have private peering between
them
google has private peering with
practically all
medium-large access networks
including the race to say they
are not necessarily symmetrical if you
try to make sure that one side can and
the other this that is  this means that
the traffic does not know how to say together it passes from
there
but in another direction I will do another
round maybe for a transit
this can be trivially due to configuration errors out-
of-
date configurations that need to be
revised with the evolution of each
network  but also for reasons of capacity if
I know that on a certain circuit I am a
risk of saturation then in the time
it takes me to be able to organize
the upgrade make sure to take away the
traffic send it to another part
in Italy also missing in all the
Italian networks they exchange traffic for
theirs there are cases in which
for example,
mobile operators in particular are not seen directly I do not know
why but they do not exchange traffic
three of them probably do not
consider it useful because mobile
phones for what is the state
of mobile technology rarely make
traffic between them
so for example  I saw that
vodafone and three see each other through their
respective transits in this case it
seems to me to be level 3 also fiscal Italy
not peering with some of these
operators fishing Italy up to two years
ago had a very
restrictive peering policy in the sense  who practice
was peering with no one because it had
become at some point 12 15 years ago
part of pi skal international a
gl network  very large obale with a
very restrictive peering policy
so he had closed all peering
with practically all the Italian networks
after which no one for a decade
has ever bought him transit again because
everyone is tied to his finger this
thing but these things happen  the
networks
i small ve while instead for a year and a
half now it has started
to ping again because a few years ago
tiscali international had been sold
it changed its name 3 4 times in the meantime
now an independent network that no
longer has anything to do with either  on
the
other hand, the smaller tensions networks
are well connected with one another,
even three pure france
change namex and mix is generally because
a presence in piedmont always
topix too because a presence in
piedmont topix is extremely useful
because a platform that is used
for how is a platform that is
used both for peering but also to
sell transit because co  However it is not
forbidden two networks can meet
on the topix switch platform
and decide that one provides transit to the
other and then last July
telecom italia has very few
interconnections with the other Italian networks
this due to their decision to
close most of them.  of these
interconnections on the basis of
unclear criteria never
explicitly defined but which were
explained to us by our sales representative because
we had 4 interconnections with
telecom italia at the time of exchanging
stories at this point they decided to
want to exchange traffic only between
networks that  they can be like them who
have many customers intended as
ADSL customers access networks and
brunini practical similarly an ADSL and
asymmetric a provider that has
substantially ADSL customers or in
general circuits in which upload and
download do not have the same ability to
consequence it will have asymmetric traffic q towards the outside of
its network
his already to think that this
criterion perhaps has some problems
all in a more rapid way means that
for telecom it intends to
peer only with the large
access operators substantially only with those
with whom it already did private peering in
fact the decision had also been made
to disconnect from the
internet exchange the problem after they
noticed that they cannot disconnect
from the internet exchanges because in Italy
there is something managed by agcom and
the ugo bordoni foundation which is called
internet measure
you connect to the downloaded site a
program that measures how well the
your dsl works how much bandwidth asia
problems etc.
this program connects to the food servers
that are in the internet exchanges for which
those who actually remained in the
internet exchanges exchanging
traffic with practically no one but
their initial idea was to have only
private full just for the  their new
peers have said they want  only
private pirin and only paid peering
obviously not free if you are not
part of that small group of companies that
we have discussed and it is interesting to note
that the peering costs that have been
proposed for this product are
greater than what it would cost to
buy transit, i.e. access to  the whole
internet instead of just
telecom italia customers by telecom
italia sparkle which is the
international network the backbone
of telecom italia's international the year one
is also interesting that this
price is actually won because trying
to discuss the issue with  the
telecom salesmen
are so eager to sell the
product that they give it to you that they
give it means at no cost but it
means I will give you a
corresponding discount on another thing you
buy me that a very common thing in
negotiations with telecom italia I have to say
in  anyway we don't know exactly
which networks
qualify for pe  ering set while with
telecom italia national that the
assistant tone 269 because they
never published them they never explained
it clearly
telecom italia a2 tone system note
system is a concept that defines a
group of ruperts who have a common
routine policy  this is the
definition more in practice in this
case telecom italia 2 ott non system x
269 that the national network what was
once called in for business and 6 7
6 2 which is
international network for telecom italia
sparkle which is a suit go a
huge very important backbone
that covers the whole world has a
particular penetration in
latin america and towards the middle east and beyond
itself in the interconnections not for
national telecom italia there are
certainly for private individuals with wind and
fastweb who were here and ynet who were
already those
I know that there is an interconnection with
vodafone which from my analysis I believe
is a peer and in private
there are peering on the  masti standing at
namex there is the one congar immediately the
telecom executives thought they were
proposing paid peering also
agar I would have liked to be present
when they proposed me then
someone I think he pointed
out that they would not receive a
positive response  so they didn't even
try and then with the part of bp
which was the former dawn with suspicion that they are
still in question because sooner or later he
has to end up defending himself with the part of
bp that was the former inept so for now
they have the sand a  instead it has always
had full and private and therefore that
they have left things so waiting
for technical developments and then telecom italia
some networks and of
significant size that are their customers are
their customers even historically not in the
sense that they use them to
interconnect as  transit to
reach the rest of the world but
who give him money for this
interconnection ciampi and privately
infracom and aruba I know for sure  that
there is a relationship of this kind
interoute
no one is quite convinced and even
tiscali italia instead telecom italia
sparkle has a rather particular peering policy,
meanwhile it is a very restrictive policy
which is completely normal for a
one by one suit tends to peer with
very few networks  very large in
their size or a little less
but telecom italia sparkle does not peer
in italy online than ever then
historically no then napapijri that
italian corep because that knew and
telecom italia national has always done
very little peering in italy for
their strategic decision  that I was
told in these terms I do not want to
give access to the Italian market to these
other networks I want them to take a
longer tour passing by me this because
there is an interconnection between telecom
italia national for the like italia
sparkle which is in milan
if  a customer of telecom italia sparkle
from palermo there are several are
that  them who arrive on their
submarine cables from the middle east
interconnect wants to receive them and wants to
send receive send traffic with a
national telecom italia customer in
rome in southern italy everywhere in italy
in any case their traffic passes through
milan because this is their only
interconnection once there was a
rome but then for their internal reasons that
do not create completely even their
staff had been turned off so what
are the interconnections between telecom
italia sparkle and other suppliers of
tailleur lunches or have similar in italy
c '  it is gpp the ex pinete xing bellico in teak
skal international ex di scalia changed
not the masters over the years in milan
but he has a problem there are four for 10
gigabits the circuits and are full they are
full for about two years abundant
telecom italia cannot
has  refused for a long time
to upgrade they continued to
open their interconnections
all over the world
in Italy but no to me  lano did not
talk about it until one
of the tinet commercials told me this and I have no doubt
that it is true they asked for a certain
amount to be able to upgrade the
Italian interconnections a certain
disproportionate amount that was not
accepted as far as I know  in fact
traffic stages 3 cpp and telecom italia
passes through milan part passes through
frankfurt part part passes through paris
lpp level 3 are two new entries and the
ppi arrived last year on the italian market
before it was not really present as
a npp connectivity provider  it is the
Japanese telco also this is a
very important suit one entered the market
or and after a while it was able to activate a
bearing with telecom italia because
for reasons of reciprocity it works like this
ndp to give peering to telecom italia
sparkle and in other parts of the world it was
able  expect to have peering
with telecom italia sparkle and also on
the Italian level trick market and instead
also their US supplier in
extremely important place that is in italy
in thaksin pre about it did not have a peering
with telecom italia and in italy while
instead of course in the rest of the world they
are the year one they exchange traffic
between them except that in italy they
managed to have peering with with
sparkle
in may april the logo our
sales of level primo explained
with the same thanks to the same
reciprocity method to make sure that to
keep their peering and in other
regions
telecom italia sparkle had to
agree to do pinning with them too
in italy then there are sprints that belen
wireless from telecom that are not
suppliers cuts for relevant on
the italian market but for two
historical reasons you another year peering with
telecom italia sparkle and milan but
this does not make them companies from here
it makes sense to go and buy  of the
transit inter instead of the big networks
extremely important with the gent global
crossing skins to the Swedish incumbent
from  t another Indian the year one not
years interconnections with telecom italia
and in the rest of the world not in italy
because they are not strong enough to
be able to obtain an interconnection in
italy as I said between the two networks
telecom italia national telecom itali
international there is a single
interconnection  I think 8 by 10
gigabit in milan
this means that all the traffic
between the outside and telecom italia national
passes from in to golf and there are
problems
as now the traffic no longer passes
through mix and namex it happened
so I did a little  list of
cases that I have personally verified but it is
probable that there are also others
that I have not heard about we
go from simple things like
packet loss in an interconnection between
telecom italia sparkle ntp after having
activated it last year  it was
immediately saturated and for a long
time I was not using their customers
the npp customers used other
routes because that one  it was that circuit was
full it was completely impossible to get
traffic through without having
complaints from its customers there
were not one but also several cases
of packet loss in the various
interconnections between telecom italia
sparkle
egp pp skal international a
rather interesting case black o l  'ing between
telecom italia and telecom italia sparkle
the direct traffic certain p did not pass
and that easy for us I am not a customer of
one or the other
means that I have to contact my
transit provider who will speak to
telecom italia sparkle and so on
alternatively  I have to tell my client that
maybe some servers on my network are a
telecom italia adsl look to
call 187 and explain that in this
point of their network the traffic no
longer passes see a little test if you can
then then let's see in the meantime I move  me too
because I don't expect very sincerely
from that side for 7 10 February
some
telecom italia sparkle circuits broke in ge  rmania
then it seems to me that the details had been
explained to me informally in retrospect and the
traffic between cogent which is a
very important transit provider in italy
in general of the world and telecom italia
sparkle
I was passing through the united states like 20 years
ago when we were all  the clients of an
ep and we all saw each other in virginia
because there were no interconnections in
italy and in general not many in
europe other cases of congestion 11
march
particularly interesting and I mean
interesting in the chinese sense between couples
dpa my case and telecom italia  traffic did not
pass I had some customers
who had servers completed on my
networks of laurel ip adsl telecom and similar things
certain more were reachable certain no
worth explaining to the customer what is
happening and that it is not my fault if the
traffic does not pass other cases  of
congestion we have always noticed that
the telecom italia sparkle network does not
have all this redundancy
when something breaks down it can c  let
another circuit become saturated having
said that peering is not
mandatory each network decides
who it wants to peer with this is a
very important point I do not believe in the peeling
required by law I do not think it
is a good idea
but we must consider another
question of position  dominant
telecom italia has 55 per
cent of the ADSL access market in Italy and the
like number one to have, like all
the others, a dominant position on
this access market position
certified as a guarantor for
competition, etc.
position among small them relevant in
certain other markets
for example it has a noteworthy amount
of colocation hosting customers but
not very high has a completely
negligible position in the cloud market there
are other companies instead of but even
if they may not have a
dominant position  however, they have
significant market shares in the hosting cloud market
etc.
this is called it is called the
adjacent market compared to that of
connectivity now if the shares of telecom
italia strong of its
dominant position in a certain market
cause disadvantages for its competitor
in an adjacent market
get a lawyer friend to explain
what it is called  this thing
telecom italia traffic on empire in public
the huge join we know that
most of the traffic what is
peer to peer video etc.
this kind of traffic does not tend
to be directed between an access network
is the kind of  and of companies with which
the facts of in private with google are filled in public
because youtube new
amounts of traffic in hands even if
telecom italia does not have a peer in private
with google and then traffic is exchanged
between the access networks  because
their customers use peer to peer a to
exchange debian cds around 20c from
vip and traffic
last year was is plus or minus 10
percent of the  traffic exchanged on the
internet and Italian seats of these 20
giga lippok hominids half were the
traffic of acam aia topix akamai has a
one-way topix node at one of the
consortium members
of the turin internet exchange that
moves a lot of traffic and memory was
particularly much towards  telecom
italia because telecom never wanted to
have the akamai servers that are cash
that provide part of the traffic all
the traffic of their customers' sites
on national this as
a strategic decision in which they believe
very much while instead they have you on
the telecom network  italia sparkle
this means that telecom italia
national had to pay
telecom italia sparkle internally
the cost of that traffic that
arrived on what is their only
transit after 2 peering what
happened
telecom italia makes folds only with the
subjects we have seen  i am
reasonably sure no
one no one bought their
pierre product in privat  o they have
not even sold to a customer the traffic
from most of the Italian networks
out of 15 are contained servers etc. to
reach telecom italia in any case
pass through milan if all goes well if the bad
passes from abroad which is almost always
frankfurt or paris  where there are the
closest interconnections with other
thai air one do
you see if you think that this has
led to an improvement in the quality
of the internet network in italy
i feel like saying that in any case it
is not possible that this is ganso there
was globally  an improvement
on the other hand not even huge problems
apart from all the reliability issues
we have seen when there are
no contingent problems
everything works the same no
customer of mine has ever said and but it takes
15 thousand seconds more because the
traffic between us  goes to frankfurt
no one has ever complained on the other hand
another company I know that those who work
and not in a different market always of the  a
co hosting location but a different type of
customers in particular to many
gameservers on their network and
their customers had told me they
complained about this because the clamp
had increased that an important thing
netgaming was worth it I say  it
is clear that no one has earned it
then telecom italia has not sold
anything even if it had sold a
very fast account but if it had managed
to sell transit to half of the networks with
which the first peering cruise it
would not have returned to the costs of the circuits
and  of the equipment that he would
need to establish all these
private PRIs the same account is very
amicably confirmed to me
by colleagues who work for telecom
italia so we can be
quite sure of this as regards
the Italian networks this operation is
economically a loss  net for
telecom because he actually
installed some routers to the mix to
be able to do  private peering with other
people willing to reach them
privately not on the peering network
of the mix but I understand that they are
completely empty because all this
would need a whole other
presentation so we do it shortly it
has been clearly said by the managers
responsible for this idea that
they could be paid by two types
those over the top
the networks that provide services over the
internet have been specifically mentioned
however facebook akamai
is missing apple the telco historically
since these companies have appeared that
have started to make big revenues
thanks to the internet
nobody very envious because
the connectivity business with
very few margins at tiny margins you
know how little an ADSL pays and I
assure you that the little in the end as
revenue and very little remains for the
operator who provides the
service but beware of trump the revenues of
google facebook etc.  they are the
same as having  a large turnover
the turnover of the over the top is in
any case tiny if compared
worldwide with the turnover of the
telcos of the access providers
this means that even if the over
the top ix thought a lot of money
from their earnings
anyway in any case they do not  they could not
significantly change the income
statement of telecom italia and other
similar subjects because this idea is not
that they invented it in the skin like
there are many others who have tried it
before comcast and in the united states and
leaders of this thing to get paid by
those who have content for the privilege of
showing them to their customers who
have requested them from Italian providers you will
work Italians in these are
exclusively collateral damage
were hit but the targets were very
different
if you download these slides then
you will see some articles some of mine and
others of others  which explain these issues in a little more
detail
what is behind them and their ties  ono
with the network neutrality no questions
are saturated
but in them because of this big
yes we are talking about 20 gigabits for
pressing 10 and we also write akamai that
a particular case that was largely
in topix we are talking about 2010 gigabits and
csen amex prizes are one  amount of traffic
negligible and for what is the scale of
telecom italia yes then the speech
you made can certainly make sense
but the more I can say I can say no
the real reasons that have been
explained in part the public in part
in private are those  that I have listed
those of and to try to sell not
so much to me but to others and I
ended up in the middle too and like me many
others and peace worse for him
no I was not clinical
I certainly agree that I am not plausible  he was
excited because there are these but there
are these reasons that are much
stronger in my opinion is amply
sufficient to justify what
happened said to no one there have been
endless discussions among other
Italian operators various things have been evaluated
in the end
practically its problematic stuffed areas
this situation because we
have seen the economic difference to give
money to the mit sana mix to move this
traffic rather than give it to my
lunches because maybe in  some cases and
telecom italia sparkle does not
particularly move my economics so
from the point of view of the price no hello
strong incentive to fight against this
from a technical point of view I
have mentioned some problems but they have
been annoying for my customers but
if they have made a reason not customers
who have left who have
threatened me that they have said at least to
be annoyed with me for this
situation
from the discussions I had with
some competitors it
seems that for them everything is even more
beautiful and therefore if they have  many
have not told me about the problems
they also have other different relationships
with telecom it  alia, for example, they sell
adsl they are telecom italia customers for
that thing there and they don't want
to sue telecom italia for that
considering that in any case there are not
many holds apart from a cohesion of
competition it has been evaluated to
take legal action in general
something with agcm guarantor for
competition on the basis of what is
the dominant position in the
access market for various reasons it was
deemed not to do anything so I do
not expect that there will be differences in the
short term
maybe sooner or later someone will  fed up
will buy the peering from telecom italia
I personally tell them I can also
accept the excursion we
agree on what is a price that
suits me well active inhibit private individuals with
telecom italia I don't make a
question of cost if they cost me  a
little more than a transit semi
solve problems I have no alternatives I
accept the fact that I have no
alternatives if this proves
necessary l  o I find it annoying for various
reasons but I have to take what is
the most advantageous decision for my
customers
I pray
if there was and difficult to say because
the network separation would affect the
purpose of the services at a lower level
than the IP transport so  at
that point there would be various
telecom italia operators, others who would buy
from the company that owns the
network access to the twisted pair to the optical fiber
on which to provide ip services
so if telecom italia remained the
one that is less than the physical network it is not
obvious  that something would change even if
in reality the matter is much more
complex than we can deal with
at the moment
if telecom italia perhaps broken up into
several parts maybe it would remain on the one hand
that the internet on the other hand the data
centers
perhaps could review this to
be incentivized  to revise
this theory, however, this is unlikely
because the problem is not that
someone wants to sell it  space in
your data center with the purpose of
having more customers in your telecom data center
it was declared
by the executive the public registered by the
executive responsible for this thing
we have two things to monetize
our network our customers
so if they are the customers the ones to be
monetize that those who manage the
access network which is the only point to bring
for the traffic that their customers have
asked for them is the one who dictates
the conditions
other questions then all thanks
could already download the slides from
my site now