so I introduce myself my name is paolo
that only a very complicated surname is not
that name they go up with my German
anyway from ferrara I am part of the fra
jul del ponti professionals like some
who will come maybe in the next days
that I know
I am also part of the only one in short
I do  made a few groups so as to make
the computer science banality of the serious
started in 85 I work more in the
management field that I do a lot of
database analysis etc. so here I am an
accomplice based on these things here but
the concept I think is important
so I asked to be able  to make a totti
on the subject precisely because it seems to me
that the subject is absolutely
important among other things it was abolished
very well with regard
to today's meeting my
intention was to come and talk
about something that is  happening that
could be enough with
quite heavy consequences and therefore
we try to have omitted 21 thousand euros
there  they are
quite heavy consensus sequences with disc
therefore let's now try to explain
some things it is clear that there are some
topics where some things are very
skilled others maybe a little
less and therefore usually my talk here
is prepared for also to be able  support
people who maybe what I know do not know
what a double symmetrical key is
thing of this type
here I will try to travel a little more
on these things and I immediately say about I leave
immediately with a thank you with a
certain they are not second choices andrea
colangelo
this  it is his blog which at linux
day fed of 2012 made a talk that he
recorded and that I accidentally found
on youtube
anyway you can find it on youtube where between
time
the face is so that American becomes
so definitively finished
practically witnessed he made a
beautiful  meeting on the topic
explaining well all the concepts of self
coreboot evf etc. and from there or derived a
lot among other things  in an available
way so if you then have very complex questions to pay
on the subject, etc., it is
probably better for you to turn it
directly that it is much more prepared
than these things must keep 1
point of the European start with some
very minimal concepts as a second
very simple thing to whom  standards are needed
and clearly we know
very well that everything that came out a little bit
today so the
same internet the same the brake for
example extreme the
power supply the mobile phone power supply you see that
today there is this usb connector is
something a  bit strange in the sense because it is an
important thing that we usually say
so the innovations related to the
standards are related to the fact that there is
someone who sponsors them crispin g and
there are groups that we say that the
lobbies that usually push these by
being  alle l'ispano go ahead for
market reasons there are some things that
by their nature are against the market
this one  it is something against the market
because obviously until now it was much
more convenient for companies to try to
sell you when I bought the mobile phone
where the compartments the new power supply
buy the new wire for
the cigarette lighter so 10,000
billion attacks of two power supplies than at a
certain  point did not intervene
saying [ __ ] at least on the side beyond
the heel must be vs b then later
now there is also the reasoning
on the other side and therefore this is a
case in which practically something has
prevailed because being a point we
thought more about the  common good that has the
push of the lobbies on certain things and
the problem is that on a thousand other things
there is this situation here there are
things that for market reasons were born
like because the internet itself if you go
to see the internet does not  was born to
do the good of the people
then it had that side effect as a side
effect but it was practically the result
of an evolution that we say
market convenience has led to  then a
result that in the good of all therefore
in other situations this does not have as
much as possible this for it becomes the
premise for those good all is the
most to the minister the speech
of the easy feeder the easy word
and the drama of these
practically of these  years today
anyone any user you know go
on with on on on on we
live the civilization of the bank ahead
on whatever is in the middle
rights everything is fine
to reach the purpose that interests
you what is in the middle you will find out
dojo but this  it also applies to
regulations and this is not a small problem
because if I have to explain a
difficult concept you want an
easy concept and much more face also write
the phase I give an example we
talked about that disk encrypted before
but in a normal person  to have a
pinch of elbow in my opinion the
rip off because because the first time
something happens to me you those
the activity  united more outside not even for it
seems unless they remain between those who
can be spent and 500 euros so
probably for the normal user of
discovered kato it is more a rip-off than
anything else but it is much easier to
pass rather than this concept
as the concept that I you  i offer
something inherently unsafe and
that car offers a sure thing
is a much simpler concept my
system is safe he tells you so
because his number is a simpler concept
here people are more likely to
accept that concept  there and there are therefore
from the end of the aspects that concern the
advent of these standards they are not
purely technical they are technical aspects
are aspects of marketing pd how
these things are presented and how
people say finally perceive them and there
are aspects that are purely
commercial  linked to the fact that there
are lobbies that push etc. so
all this chaos must be made of the
polar laws that make c  homodo
to people so he had to digest
the famous easy concepts and then
let's see a little bit there are new
standards so now I am
finally calling to talk about these things of
this world the standard is called poets
that will take the place of the bios that breathes
the machine and  those first
program that starts when the system
is loaded we will talk about 6 core mood
which is a start mode made
just this wef in we will also talk about
the certifications of a company
but I don't know what because we will see
that this is what creates the casino no  and
we will see it later because in themselves these are not
negative things here eh the set
that creates a negative situation
we will also talk about a system i simply
wi fi system in bus stalls you have
never seen that speech for those said
with the key is one  standard for which he
started with the key automatically
in the loaded role system asks you
if you have not seen it because it does not exist
then let's go  forward
the bots but I guess here you know
how to do it apart from bayern alias the old
bay I am now part of the web to recall
this master boot record that 512
practically does not fit into it
anymore so consequently it
debuted there that is another
position  it is practically made for
which it starts the expenses so on
in short there is practically a chain of
software that is linked to the other
and this chain here potentially
dangerous because someone could have
replaced what I know
master boot record with something else
could have put in the master boot in the
body of the other or have put in the
boot loader something else that did not
have everything insert a virus
inside the kernel and so on
so there are inherent dangers
beyond the fact that when parked that
they do these things are very few
but potentially certain risk okay
here is an asymmetric double key explanation
I hope that sand
usually does it with  an explanation
just mentally a second you never know
if someone does not know it I say okay to
in fact a kind of signature generator
no practically a machine that of
guardian genus you do not have in a
signature generator the other in a
verifier of signatures you exchange
keys eto'o practically this mania
you can verify from a distance if what
I gave you with form what you had
learned of great advantage that these
things are not physical things they are
practically code and in practice you
generate keys  with this
key system you are the guarantee that what
actually sent you is
what I sent you it
seems like a thing if instead but the idea
was brilliant
then let's go and see this
famous wake that takes the place of the bios
then  in the meantime, you can see that he has already seen it
graphics must be quite another
thing
before it was all a blue thing
etc. In the meantime what was born
let's say the end of 2003 from int  el who
later passed it to a hi fi wi fi forum
is made up of very big companies amd
apple of the capibile month but they are
all evident in the face book among the
runtime services and also uses its
own drivers 15 its own drivers see inside  do you
remember how I said the beginning before it is
a deal that is better
I am sometimes not able to do that it was
512 bytes this to do here dine to
take a linux distribution pull
away the dredge everything is smaller than the
wef
practically an operating system
all effects under the machine that is there
at the beginning on windows vista service pack
1 windows server 2008 second and four
suits this was already very
detailed specifications in 2012 were already more
than two thousand pages tells me a common dad
so that he explains in detail  what
should your famous web do and therefore the
question is but what a baggage that has to
manage just over 2 seconds
practically as big as linux
already this in short that a bit strange
massacre as they say  or giving it less there is
also the fact that however it happens that the more
regulations mean the more mechanisms and the
more peculiarities you insert, the more
likely it is to find
loopholes to play games even a
command shell and so
system information is organized in tables  in
a file service and against them I tried
graphic teams
then after then apple has been using it for years as
an exclusive system for their computers
since January 2011 all the new
asus motherboards implement beyoncé we
will speak in all machines that today
come out with windows 8 point 18.0
they have compatibility mode its will be
doors so there is the possibility of
making a truth go that someone
calls go in a way something
like this that practically allows you
wanting to return to the old bios and
run it with the bios code written in
c is not written anymore  nor always per cent
and therefore even more easily
but do not keep by the company
ask that the companies that fan account  no
the wi fi they are the ones who rewrite this
program it is only they who know
what this program
does so it is not an open program even
if there is an open code wanting
to power on the force and download
let's say the main structure
but the fact remains that  however the
package that package proprietary
communication between devices with
specifications on the protocols so it is
in short it is essential here this is
an important point indispensable to
generate professions of more than 2
terabytes
if not you do not do it and use the cpt then
there is also the speech  on 11 of the
partitions that you can create all
these things here there is no more speech at the
party in the main bars expenses so
in short there are innovations and
this probably the
most visible innovation in some ways is in fact
when you load the partitions you take
to  sea maybe a gem even sent
the machine with windows 8 on went to
see that the situation partitions
you saw there is an esoteric partition
such as I don't know partition that people will read
later because the distribution of
these systems changes is both your book
manager attention f to your ebook
manager so not the group
theoretically should no longer be there
because you should have confiscated it
at the
he who defines the priorities
no and we will see then that this also of the
consequences makes it easier to
manage the PC servers remotely 15
having the drivers having everything
practically there is the possibility for the
constructor to update maybe bios or
to  do who knows what this then
only he knows because obviously being more
closed you cannot know what to do in the
future it should be open made of
putting new diagnostic
systems data recovery systems the services
that photographers and integrated functions for
the management of consumption and  so on all the
things that one can put in to those
belloli of these system expenses
operated  vo parallel that is underneath
us then we now want to see only
one aspect that of the second
so you see that the wi fi is a thousand things
behind and it is not all crap there
are also things that make sense
for which actually it becomes
quite difficult today to justify
not to continue without using the web, however,
inside there is this discourse of the secur
book that perhaps the most crucial point
of the whole matter
or as already said that they will be able to the
system we make sure to certify the
whole chain so that from the moment
you are leaving  the machine at the moment
it arrives running let's say your
login in your login page all the
chain siena certified chain
and here it enters all the stores if the
keys which is heavy enough because
why then the concept was to avoid
the famous all cool  and then it
means these virus programs that
could potentially lurk but
this is played with
scam mechanisms  key bi 5 o'clock when I
realized that he had put here a moment
only tries to solve how the fate of
keys done so
in practice there is within the web there is
a key that has been certified and
this certified key must be
then in the other modules so if you have
a boot manager it must be inside good
manager which must be its same
key that you have inside the web
then you must have it if you want to certify then
also certify the kernels because I
tension the web and in the specifications it does not
say that  it is mandatory to certify the
kernel and because they stop only at the first
stage practically because that of
let's say no longer becomes in quotation marks
relevance of del wef is part of
subsequent specifications potentially
so in fact you could also just
authenticate the boot manager enough at
this point then after d  'alia deletes the
justification the kernel and attention
there are also used more elements
of the caen
because if you have modules they must be
c  you also certify those not so it must
be all
digitally signed
stuff.  these manufacturers different
buildings according to you because they should
put the key of linux or
microsoft or any other manager
then microsoft we will see how to get
their key put in the
problem is that for there it is not much more
difficult to get myself  that you have
inside and we will see the effects that
this thing who manages the keys
this is not told at the web level
are in fact certain fiction authorities
so I would say that this is a
fairly obvious thing
then there is the concept I said
before having to sign the  modules that you also create
problems because you imagine having to
sign the modules for example that are
introduced d  to virtualbox or from
envy drivers or almost of this type
so there is also this problem is
that it is not a monolith with which I have to
do it is clear I can also very well
decide not to start my
consecutive system there is a sea without a second  you
is the problem does not exist then from that
point of view the manufacturer decides the
keys he wants to load so I have
produced hours it is I who decide the
keys I want to load and the over coat
how I do it there too is all to be
seen because now  then there are all
if the problem then maybe we also talk about
the motherboard that from you so on no
oh well the pc in the shopping malls
will have all the functions enabled
who or which I can tell of all
the colors because mounting renounces even
in the latest versions of I guarantee  that
you see of everything of everything third
protagonist
this is a logo that you find on the pc is not
exactly the same it is slightly different
compatible on the pc
if you want to see this pa  stooped
if you want the stamp the microsoft what does
it do you stick it says you can
certificate the
machine very well then I make
you the stamp you bring me the car and
I see if it meets the requirements it has given me
here is the nerve center of the
question the requirements  that
microsoft gave if you respect these
requirements I pay you so not only do you
bring me the car I say okay and then
you can attach your directives fries
of my windows 8 that to the pachino and
therefore it is certified but I also pay you
for this thing is  but obviously and
if you let him certify then what do you do I
sign the contract and first thing he
asks you to enter my
plan key then the microsoft key
in machines with windows 8 is necessarily
there but there is not only that for example
I specify that you are smart it must
be active by default disabled
but active by default
this is a devastating thing because you
call a friend and tell him now you
put us on linux
see if he succeeds because he has to find out he
knows how to enter the setup is that there is no
standard button complaint in 70 of the
times or at the eye flash c is sees it in
some cases even with the fresh one with the
money nothing 20 shows  absolutely nothing
so it must go to google
give me model ac to the three press f2 then you
arrive at the 12 there is a writing that says
I want to go in mode if it is not curved
no there is in safety mode perhaps in the
version such as there is mode  or it
happens as a machine less
a brawl where there is
absolutely nothing written I say but how the hell
is I go to see on the internet purpose there
is no problem just put the password
in to enter the bios as soon as you put the
bios password  this you are able from the
writing that says with this then of the
veils alice coreboot [ __ ] how
did I do not think about it that is you see that is
unspeakable filth brought to normal
the second on arm to this cortege on
arm must be active not disabled at
all  on page that can be enabled because
security for all you know that there is
nothing more dangerous for
security than a weapon device I know from
what it did but I don't say at least I think I
know why it did it
probably because if they had ever
done the  same thing on this side
what abuse of dominant position was
certainly no here they do not have a
dominant position to a residual situation
consequently potentially it becomes
difficult to sustain what you
look at here the problem is also this
that here the problem is that these things
just change every two  days not
we will see it for example with
linux distributions these things change in languages
days for that problem is also that
days even if very informed about
what is happening because the
casino is happening now and linux
this was the first
justified reaction the first to  be
justified because it creates a mess
because there the very fact that linux
is by its nature does not mo  nolitico is a
mess to be able to donate one says oh well I do not
activate the security systems but in the meantime
an excellent one arrives by default
then I go to explain to your friend them who
says scott a migliaccio windows 8 and
I want to put on linux
no eh well disability security but
how  linux was not a safe system
I have to disable the security to
start my system I don't even think about it
but to explain the easy concept it
says exclusion concentrated with the
easy concepts the easy concept I
take away the security for the security
they want to explain if  you are a man then
what happened this was the first
who ventured into this
fedora thing that obviously and to the
distribution we say that then also
that of reda practically the first
who faced the problem saying
in short somehow to solve
this problem what  did they
bought the doctors key you
can't imagine but the fact is that
whoever made that choice was not
ac  retino is one that has not found other
solutions
and the problem is probably other
better solutions right now
maybe there aren't any
debian ones and since 2013 they are
fighting over deciding what to do
they still haven't supported because they don't know
what to do because  probably this
right now is crap but
probably the only solution
right now because microsoft has a
passive quoted system of
keys for who are the manufacturers who
have to sell the car with the
bologna it is turkey fault above so it
is they who are  go get it key
no you can't do the same thing with
linux
so this is a mess and therefore
how obviously a popular revolt arose
after which after the first
moments of td of anguish discussion
etc. they realized that
actually it is not a
rash choice  let's say it was a bad
horrible choice but it was not a windy choice
of 99 from the dc meeting you want I
understand eg  riodi sell a key that
attention can also change because if
microsoft decides to revoke its
key because actually even in
good faith a cazzaro took it at
all disasters no I am forced to
change the key I trigger the
mechanisms because web to allow a way
to make  trigger
key change mechanisms change the key
immediately placed there it no longer works
no after which you too will have to chase
the change of the call in linux
etcetera treta and if a war happens
that I block all the PCs because I
change you clear it is not a thing to do
little
fedora filmaker in and modules with skis but
now let's see what this
came out one is practically it is accompanied
not done the same practically it was
a later invention that they
sought a little bit of let's say to
find the pieces in quotation marks we need
the wedge is  practically what they have
done from the moment in which the
system part from the choral moment goes to load
the lo  g manager basically loads a little
program that he manages the keys and
that he goes to insert because there is the
possibility for a little program to
go and change the key never serious his
keys of practically fedora inside
the web
and after which he continues with those of
fedora which is a bit of a spin
and so on but let's say that it is a
little more tolerable situation
because at that point the management of the
glass keys but the golden key
obviously this thing has to do a little bit of
all of the man later after
everyone has it  said of all colors
some point ubuntu also had to
move on this plane because they too
felt the need to do
this thing because the problem is that the
machine move in all of them like this and therefore
it started first to see if there is a
loophole they have not found a
loophole does not pull unfortunately said
the way is that there we are
forced not to take it key from microsoft
and it does the same thing s  and not that they
discovered a catch that since cru 2
had to have it digitally signed if
you went to see practically the gbl
there was a fairly questionable point of sale
because you in fact do not
distribute the source as it was but
manageable with the key attached
microsoft for which in fact it was not all
transparent so disputes could arise
and a discussion was born for
which in the end they are even allowed to
do something other than cranes 2
precisely because now me what did not
have
anyway let's say we did something
different from q2 on purpose  to avoid
running into problems of this type if
the wrath of god was unleashed because it is a point
they were not just any institution it was
practically the most widespread and
consequently free software foundation that
she who who has the gpa of which
practically manages in fact has  said
but as abandoned you can not use it
for that absolutely there are no
problems from this type
from this p  anointed of view etc. so
there was a return back no
point and then clearly at the end
all the peace and love but an endless war was born
if this thing here then arrived I think of
sousse begins with the
braille version the tete a tete  same
key microsoft loading a
library of keys into sci because
he said well in short, the idea of the
disciplines bad but perhaps made a
little better you could make a
library of practical keys the
oedipal speakers database declare is so
beautiful that at a certain point fedora  he says
well you did a good thing we too do
not it is practically the situation more or
less this conclusion
we go on finally the
cutter that fondation moved and what did he
scrutinized he wanted to exploit a
specification after all this practically
exists the possibility  potentially
to start a coreboot system in itself and
deny it a moment later that is to say
since I see that the step suc  cessivo
is not authorized no because
it is actually not digitally signed
if you want to go straight I press the
function key from such no that says go
on the same I don't give a damn
and practically they managed and in fact
they are made sheen them no with
this  option for the attention that
this option is excluded within the
famous microsoft certifications which
instead says you can not do
moreover that the situation for which in
fact the moment in which you speak so the
second you as not even there was for which
in fact those  all the vague mosaic
security chain in short it is a
devia debian casino imagine having to
take the key of marx that is one
thing in itself if you go to see the
presentation of colangelo the end says
that the distribution of vip is a
differently fast distribution
obviously we have  all maximum
respective this is supported on debian
but the fact remains that having to digest
the fact of taking it never ask  so
said it is not a very easy thing in
conclusion they do not support it yet they
support wife i no but they are not
willing to endure according to the result
this graph
obviously this graph someone
anyone of you could do it in your own way
never do it on the graph absolutely
relevant as it cannot be demonstrated
the result of conjectures of my sick mind
then it is the concept is this this is
the percentage of users who are
able to move to mount linux by
themselves no I which dates you can not
move but in any case the concept is
this you know that there  he gave the
wages not on a decrepit car
we were also on a 486 he called me a
loser
and yet I don't tell you the miners the hardships
because there was no my technique face of
life there was nothing that 2t wifi does not exist
it is practically a delusion so the
older the car, the more it struggles
because at the beginning there was no
problems and then later the drivers
began to have  there were the
last drivers that gave some
problems were for example those of
the video cards then there are the keys
for what I do
the bevels because everything seemed to
be fine then the
keys came out and usually that was the
problem they had  all no
then now the problem of the keys is also solved they
solve the problem
finally they are installing the machines
of the last 5 6 years but we say as
soon as they are bought and looking for no problem
in my opinion it was the machine just
bought they are silent in the use husband
next to one  out of ten for printing one out of
ten and this is not a small problem
because at the moment people do not
pay much attention to it because they are re-
conditioning old machines but whoever
finds himself installing linux a
new machine has the problem and how
and here the problem is big it must
be solved in some way the
problem is that not only do you see a
solution because at this moment  the
solution we should not give it to us
should be that famous power
supply you saw at the beginning where at a
certain point the international techno intervenes
that says them white
nothing
at this point the problem is big and
big is the only solution what it
could be  to buy machines
without the windows 8 patch 18.0
if you find it we have found another
disability solution in the following but
you must be able to make people understand
that the tory alemi those
safety mechanisms is not to remove the safety and
this is another problem  not just
the other possibility the moment in which I
entered with this mechanism of the
century butini then inserted in a
hitch is because for example I have
the habit of putting two
linux distributions side by
side so that I know  asked the
projector then I started with the other one and
went to see it because you share the disc
what happened that
practically if I did it, parts
c  follows a hole and after one does not
see stuff the others and so on
no then a thousand other problems then
derived from the fact of a
push safety system because this
push safety system justified in
certain environments is justified then two
three things that I will show you  as a
consequence of this thing here I will
show you for example this now I
am not extracted a bit from my blog
the goal on let's say problems and we
love each other more from the new technologies I know that
in the stands
certainly never seen but then
ok
but let's see there  the water in here
I am brought so why so I
do not even need to connect with
here it is if then this is fine it is
also up to those eight players then
never the with the open files are those
it does not then disc give you s
but this this  ok this
then of the center so
then we see again you are coming
ok if you see it here I will show you
for example what happened with
hewlett packa windows 8 and pa  ck also the stories
of ordinaries and protections but the story of
when I went to recondition an
epaca machine beautiful fast villas
of angel and music hall a minute away
then I didn't understand anything when
I was very fast practically this
machine here after unspeakable problems
at the end  v6 discoveries with a bang not
deactivated anything you went to
install linux that of the versions that
support the second one entered
everything perfectly
if you did a showdown as soon as
you did the show giving at that moment you
kept errors at the start
because it said like the processor or something
like this  like if you want to go go and
read
there is the detail of the whole thing how it
went i tried to give back the
car dealer told me
you can't see it back because the di
changed the operating system or look for
i called the brawl beautiful  pat slime
said I say look here is a
problem of your wef that does
cazz  ate response to the packard bell
we do not give assistance on the machines
where you have that puts the operating system
but excuse a moment I am not
asking you for assistance on windows 8 I
am asking you for assistance on the wi fi that
you wrote that makes cassate
here is this  here is another another
was with him a detach the two packs
what does he do we said that the groove
decides which partition is the
group that finally the group does not manage it at the
level of the
perfect web then I say I want to start
the first one  you can not because the function
inside the west that says which is the
operating system the game before did
not put it there because windows must start
but you can do fe no me if
you do f9 you can say that within
that list  there is the groove and start
the group that makes you start and this is
all that happens to hand over
the management of the web both of the companies
that give you in the third of the I have not
yet seen a screen of the setup that
allow you to go to command lines and
put your hand on the web that
is potentially there so practically gave me a
pig in a poke someone who manages
it as you please
this is reality and you don't even
know what
we guarantee an apple supply chain
poisoned or potentially belen to you it
's okay to
close the matter and if you want to go and
see on the site and I also made a
small one that I called the wifi at the cup
nefarious where I tried to explain in
human terms for people not of the
trade
no the question but not  it is easy to explain
why it is complicated
I hope you need something for the
rest I leave room for the logical one
I apologize if I stole games