here we are then I said we are here to
present linux is a wireless
community network born in rome precisely fa
bis came from dani nuxe rome i am from
linux verona the idea is to create a
new network etc. and we create it a bit
according to our canons a bit  like how
we like to do because someone would
want to make a new network for example
because we like to tinker we can
be precisely have the passion of
systems engineers linux ari programmatore
even if the radio amateurs and want to
do our thing that works under
our control to play a  po
or to have more performance type if
we want to make a connection between us
and our friend in another neighborhood
passing for example on a
game server in australia the performances
will be painful by making a
direct connection we cannot
have both more bandwidth and less  latency
or we can do it for activism for
example I consider it a way to
actively defend the freedom of
communication  nor, that is, not on such a network,
we can prevent
what we do not like from
happening that happens on the internet, for example, the
shutdown of the internet as in the
Arab springs but also obama wants the
possibility of being able to do
it censorship we can study a network
in which  it is impossible to censor it is
impossible to turn off in which the
network neutrality is
guaranteed enough by design in which the
physical structure and also the management is not
hierarchical like the one we see on the
internet but is carried out from below in
an equal way and obviously use
an open source software  if these
are our reasons
or we could do it out of paranoia
create our servers with our
open source software to instead of
sending our data to the cloud
take back control of our data
and also of the communication line on
these data transit we can also do it
for  civil protection we have an
example in linux in reggio
Calabria of one of our friends who is
trying to make a linux network
resistant to earthquakes therefore
battery packs that last that keep
the device on for tens of hours
solar panels and things like that
or against the digital divide for
example a person in a village  of
mountain expects a
commercial provider to bring him the commission
could wait tens of years I
just need to put an antenna pointing
towards the city and its connection
less because the provider follows
commercial logic that
will never make it convenient to go to the
mountains to bring  a cable ok how
can we make the network and let's say that the
network the network and passes by as
definition
comes from the bottom and starts from a group of
people in fact they are called wireless
community so at the base it is not so much
the network but as the people in
what the network must be according to
our point of view has
shared ownership everyone must be the master
manager of the p  roprio node therefore there is
no mr linux that one day someone
can go intercom to mr linux
ask and ask let's say explanations
and therefore as such how inter works
is based on a very
fundamental principle that collaboration there
are group decision-making dynamics is
in  this environment
let's say the network is born in these
interconnections of personal relationships
even more you need the network for
your own network to talk in short for with di
for it therefore shares the two the two
concepts of community and networking
feed each other as we
said  from a practical point of view
we put devices on our roofs
we can also put them on the balconies but
we prefer the roofs because the network
must and spread go definition so
have maximum visibility on when it is
possible
around the point where
the node is installed will allow the network  of
ladder to climb and you climb on the roofs
in this also quite pioneering
you use  licenses are used
devices that use free frequencies
so the 2 gb 4 the 5 gb or even
if you want even the 17 giga from the last from
the legislative point of view has been removed
and the constraint of crossing
the private land so it is possible to
pass  on the sun on public land and
therefore it has become in effect
let's say legal first there is a
regulatory hole with the latest
communications code this situation has been remedied
and therefore it is possible to
connect with wireless bridges even
between private excesses
our homes ok this is this was
one of this is a work of art
the work given in the garden with which
an access point was placed but man, however,
let's say that we use these devices
more or less than the ubiquitous of the micro
tico any vendor for they have an
excellent value for money so they
are quite cheap
in the end when building a node
the most expensive part is not so much
the antenna as the wiring the p  ane
tie rods all the carpentry that we
do not want to go to the roof every day to
fix but making a knot that lasts over
time is something to be done click
the experience you also learn to do here
and now the software part or rather the
firmware continues I just in  these
antennas are
real routers year of the
proprietary firmware of 15 euro s micro tic
router ose so on
and however to make
a mesh network we need and say
open we also need
to be able to fiddle around because it
could be done  everything with rob is
proprietary but that is not the
spirit so devices are based most
of the time there is open caps
which allows us to install all a
series of particular utilities those
for routing because it is not that we say the
routing part must be done in
intelligent automatic mode the network must
learn by itself to vote
ok and then obviously it must be configured everything must be
configured on this as
obviously the obie  It is not effective to make the
network only between super technicians super
geeks the various islands to the various groups
therefore the various groups
also work to customize the
god firmware for derivatives from a
guerretti of the pre-configurations
according to their island and therefore
also facilitate those who are  first weapons to
install their own node and among the
many let's say 33 many versions of open
boretti we tell us this project
that gets sick pre match involving
both linux and wi fi that in another wants to
bet on catalonia or argentine alter match
and want to talk  all fish
ok
in a nutshell how much we are this
is a typical example of an area of a
mesh network
we do not say full match so not
all common calls with all
we assume that there is that the node from the
arrow I want to reach the resource
that is there  it is in the red dot that any resource that is
started ok the
routing protocol finds the
best way and reaches its destination the network
to be  we say yes how the network
wanted in dynamic some no later it can
have a faith it can be switched off then
the routing protocol re converges
finds its way again and with a time that
depends on
the type of protocol used by the
performances it reaches
its destination again  it stopped ok
so I have what software manage the
routing each island let's say as a
linux project maximum freedom in the sense that
beyond the rules that you find dark on
our site to start a
wireless committee that are let's say
such as adhesion to the pico peering
agreement and  the open manifest let's say
there are not every community decides the
protocol to be used
within its own island so it can use or
lsr batman bmx babel is the only
thing that if the islands have to talk
it has to find a common protocol and
in our case, let's say no, the way of
art has been used for the
islands that we want to interconnect
using let's say internet
uti  we lizziamo bgp using tunnels
in how many today as configured years
nuxe linux type in rome florence and cosenza
we use all sr then
routing protocol so we are at layer 3 level
with two customization the names from us
picturesque smurato nor fart 1 and
derives from the aero sdk  and if when he
released it again then modified then
he stopped releasing it and then we
start configuring the nodes with a
customized version of open vlt
codenamed fart in pisa use
batman which is a
second level mesh protocol so it works at
level  max in verona bologna mesh book
and at the moment the islands are there is a
think-type vpn that
is in rome there is server st romeo
we all say all the other servers of the
strange vpn everyone is an island and we
exchange routes
obviously there are no dp conflicts
although we use
private addresses libre match which uses well then
free in the closed two
routing protocols at the two uses ba  tman banque syz
that precisely at the year I have to say that
routing based on mac addresses
completely difficult to remember there is
layer 3 if there is ipv4 ipv6 is the same
and we use
this for example in the philosophy of books and never
used at  inside a group of
fairly connected nodes that can be seen
quite well with each other both
locally,
the interesting thing is that precisely all
the clients that connect to a
group of wireless devices that
use batman advanced as
a routing protocol turn out to be
in the same as if they were attached
to a network switch that is to say they are seen
directly at a distance therefore
all kind of more local sailing all
these things work as if we were
attached directly or at most a
switch and even broadcasts travel less
and the problem of  batman that it seems that
in the memory of the devices there can be
at most type up to a thousand
nodes which is a dimension that for now
I don't care, however, the firmware is
designed to scale better up to
larger numbers
so another
routing protocol is added which is bmx 6
this time it is at layer 3 and in fact it is
used to group various
local batman islands by
making this game in which  we install
bmx 6 on the devices on the border
between the two between the two groups it is only
batman within each group
we can get a network that scales
enormous dimensions such as those of the
internet in short ok the network scales well
then for example why should I do myself
linux what services can you give me of sounds
nuxe makes the network that is our purpose is to
create the network so it
may not have anyone it
may not have services the services that
are there are those who decide to
put in the participants for example they
can  there are shared folders
can store my data on
my friend's server that has more
disk space I can have backups spread
over several co  mputer within the
network and taking advantage of the low latency
I can have game servers I can
host local TV radios that
want to stream from their headquarters
or from an event around the
city using the coverage that linux provides
in some  cities like rome can
stream using our network
without putting us with the
phone keys or you can do voip you
can be there
by email in chat video conferences
precisely videoconference because we have
a good band these antennas
we use have wireless n so in
theory we have  a nice band another
interesting thing to have interesting services
at a local level i.e. for
example local social networks or
tools for collaborative writing
one of the services if someone
shares access to the internet but it may not
be there if none of these
nodes of the  network advertises itself as the gateway
to go on the internet connection  the
internet is not there is our network remains
separate other services limited to the
imagination I connect to what
ilario said before so the purpose of inter di
linux is not to bring the internet because
it does not aim
to replace itself with an isp then and  this is
the first misunderstanding when but why
should I do when maybe I talk to
someone let's say don't convince him but
I have to talk to you about linux we said that the
internet is well reported at home
no it's no because it's another spirit
indeed there
may be useful maybe then you see not
how could it be a network where
you want sky I can transport like
sky at home the house at home in the country
I don't have it ok I put the sky transport node on it
and then the rules towards
let's say towards the
inside decide the community of which  above for
example in pisa in pisa absolutely not in
florence in florence on the mistress florence
absolutely not
in rome it depends on the community you go
customs you find
let's say it's not it's not a point of  the fact
is that being a network and in the
case of rome
we say a fairly large network
we are also very rich we say we are
known in the context of rome and
we have managed to enter the nup
in rome at the namex
as we have public ip available
we have  the possibility of
announcing them and then peering
peering with other networks other networks which
in the case of Rome are on the root server
type content manager type contender
network type google to karaj or
we have with research networks and
this following we see why
we fortunately also have the
possibility of having
a pool a 48 bar of ipv6 so it is
someone who gives us cipher from upstream
tv6 in ipv6 and therefore from the point of view
in the ipv6 network we are a piece of
internet in ipv6 because we
also have public addresses ipv6  and
anyway in rome a public ipv6 or in addition
to the network what the community does the community
I speak to you from the experience of rome but in
any case also the  and other communities of
firenze di pisa we
develop open source projects type no
of shock which is also developed in
collaboration with google summer of code
of google books match with having been
developed some plug in of hall sr
we do mentoring training of courses
or in ours  thursday nerd doing
tutorials these things here
this year linux is part of the god is
part of the project is part of the
research project with find which is a
European project that uses the
European wireless communities to build test beds
for research in the field  of
networking so instead of researchers
do tests on simulated networks they
can test on
real networks networks are those
of wireless communities maybe the
details of this project with find
maybe those interested in power we
can talk about it at our banquet
we are always there and  Legal After As
I mentioned earlier there is a collection of
laws advice how to argue with and
the condo administrator  minio in on
our site
so a little bit of a map hurts
no because we say these devices are
low power they have the final 27 of bm and
are very directive so even the
mobile phone reaches 32 but let's say about
thirty dbm and there  we stuck to the
ear as our antennas
let's say radiate in a
pretty narrow angle and away from our
brains so it hurts less than
cell phone
definitely so ok so this is
a photo taken this year in November
then last year where we  we
all met all the various islands in
rome
to talk a little about the prospects
let's say about nilox in italy and to
exchange experiences a bit like this
situation here the map with all the nodes
and the inter but for new york
who is interested in the project  it is an
excellent starting point because one
puts the placeholder sees the
neighboring contact placeholders through the map serves
says that nice if you are interested too let's
connect then  the
typical question of these days that we have been
sitting there has but but how do I
connect you come
we did not have we come to our
neighbor if you like the idea of wars
foams united united make the community it has
begun to build the network
the technical part  and secondary
the important thing is the people because
we have experiences that when the
base of the people for the communication
of the people is missing the desire to make
people
the network collapses miserably and there is
no toll-free number to call and say
linux does not work
I think  that it is venice when you arrive in
venice
ok i think that's all if there are
questions 17 24 and
how easy it is for a normal user
let's
say then at the base of the pdc the
whole project is very documented so
on wikis you on the site all the
information  so there are firmware
how to install if you go to the blog are
also the photos of we earn to install
the nodes then the advice of the
same advice is valid  star maniano dell'open
source that is the help of your neighbor
we from rome we go we have helped
those of florence those of florence
have helped others in short we help
each other you help you exchange experiences
I would say meetings like these are there  a
transfer of know-how
we here in this one in the east
there are many networking gurus we
have met we are
the networking scoundrels but we like to do it
so anyone can try their hand at
learning the question in the sense of whether in a
village for example yes  wants to create
an island yes it's ok there are a couple of
geeks who can manage
it
how simple it is then if we want to
put it in any case even this
thing means
the problem is that it is the same if
those two people remain and the others do
users do not scale dies here 11
moves for work one leaves the
village as happens most of
us
the network dies if every house for example
a antenna maybe a  shorter range
even non-directive
at 360 degrees and here or using a
router then each house and if the
mind is cheap for each person it
enacts laws are those two three people
who succeed it is not the principle of the cell
you are making a provider has buzzed  that is
the common wireless provides for the
involvement of the community in the
management of the network absolutely because
there is if one disconnects if you put it to the
lady who maybe does not know what the hell
we are talking about, that is if she is not in the
least involved and unplugs you
and maybe that  it is a knot of
passage to the truncated the s in two so it
is only for geeks
no because I can tell you from experience
that there are people who are not geeks but a
minimum a minimum a including the
let's say the concept is capable of doing a
minimum  troubleshooting
maybe it gets to a point where it says I
don't know technically capable ok at that point
there is someone who writes a mailing
list guys to this problem we will
help you that  but there must be a
personal hicker on the thing that is it is not
that otherwise it does not it is not for linux
it is not for everyone that is at that point because
if you want a storage solution if you want
a game server solution
whatever else you can find  it
costs less if we put it on the point of
seconds it costs less to do it on the internet
you make a connection you make a
connection if it breaks calls the
toll-free number that is the point of view that is
after the point of view of
the use of the thing is  different it is as if it
were so let's see it as a social network only
it is a social network and at level 7
application see facebook no this here
is at level 3 at level 2 at level 1
I know if I have made the idea
ok there are other experiences like wi  fi
that they mentioned before the network in
catalonia that 24,000 ways where
many people on the network are seen as
a very distributed ISP and there
are those who are in the ways the nodes for a fee
that solves the problems there are users
who fans  no users there is also in this
regard the network municipalities have a
minimum common denominator which is very
restricted and that is to live together
according to the rules of neutrality
with respect to the network then there is a way there
are different ways to live it here is  rome
for example the culture that everyone
must feel at least
involved in the management of
their own way that there is no nuance
as you can imagine rules between those who are
able to stop at the ping and say which
is my car does not come out  out of my
way and who maybe makes you collect
they send it back to me explains the tests of
not at all and in any case on two people who
then need someone
else's help we have to escalate the
problem that there is the approach  as he says and
very localized and very localized it
is up to the intelligence of those who decide to
do this thing and then let's say how
everything that must leave must have as
when making bread you need a bit
of yeast to make it  grow
so if there is no core that makes
this thing rise it is difficult for it to
take on its own so if you want to do they had
started to make a network start to
make a network two three friends
start broadcasting the ssd starts to
show you and the  network grows and the network
enters people enters also
people who want to do maybe
they don't know how to do anything about you network but
for example, what do I know they are very good
at communication they are very good at
designing interfaces you are good
at writing what they do too  part of the
various tusk that can be useful for
notes are decapitating me so
something on the fly insert some mechanism
let's say of direct convenience like a
bit like with logic for example that
was used for example fonera so in
fact you
by virtue of the fact  that shares some
of the bandwidth that you have on your wifi then you get
the free check
point as long as you attack the ces point
of that other in  that moment yours
is on ok but it supposes in one in one in
a community in which there is
no exit from the lan from the
man is the problem was less case the
push is much more motivating and knows
how to say then you can use  the internal services
however there are a lot of service
oh well anyway all these discussions
and we refer them to the banquet to we are
there to chat when you want to
come and disturb us there are we there