ok you all have experience some more some
less those virtual machines there is
no one who does not know what virtual machines are
he ends ok very well he
saved me a bit of introductions so
first of all before explaining
what sheepdog is, I'll explain what it is not  chic
dog
we start from a pc or a server where
we run virtual machines
until our pc goes well in short
we have a disk if it breaks patience if it
is a server that we have on
customer data etc.
we must avoid that in case of failure
of a  disk let's talk about the data obviously
then what do
we do we put the disks in raid and this gives us
a bit of fault tolerance then however
what happens in a computer
other components can also break the hard
disks we know therefore to be a little more
delicate but we could fish
network the ram is worse than the whole
motherboard then what happens that maybe I
have a motherboard failure or my
laughs
maybe with controller and  I have to
physically move everything to
another motherboard you need another motherboard and restarting
it is not something that you do in five
minutes or if the backups of the day
before
do the backup stories put everything back on its
feet and go on
in short, we talk to each other like  they
say however however we have a time
of from a high in case of
hardware failure well another
solution is to say ok it
would be nice to be able to launch a
virtual machine on any server
instead currently we have said
relegated bound on those  disks that
are on to save them
then I could move them for example on the
nose a shared folder
simplifying in this way
simply a server dies I
start the machine the same
virtual machine so much the disk is shared by
another machine and my service
restarts practically instantly
time to simply start
it then this is a good solution
what the problem is anyway if i
s  i breaks the nas i'm all over again all
my front end servers become
useless so in my mind before i
stopped a server and i had those
virtual machines stopped now i
stop the storage or all the machines
stopped then how to do it right yes it does me the
redundancy among the nas which then will not be a
strange little smarter machine and therefore
a greater redundancy comes into play
and this picture is made for
example with rb of which a tool
that works well caused or in the company
that among other things we have  used for
example on quad core servers with 4gb
of ram
we had two etc. it happened that
the motherboard broke one day I would have
died that act became primary
everything continued to work so I
can assure you that a good product
works but we have  two quad
core servers with a total of 8 gb say normal
that you turn your thumbs so there is a
hardware waste in this just
here they start talking about cig dog this
is the structure that we can  ò come to
mind this here on a slide among other things
I found on the official website they
used those monitors there to represent
the virtual machines they are not beautiful but in
any case they are virtual machines they are not
displays and we have a structure that
you can see equal to the difference
of  this where we have de salvo of the front
end and of the storage here each server does
the same thing it does both as a storage and as
a front end servant
what it means that the data is
simultaneously on all the servers and
the virtual machine can be launched
on any one  some sarvar as much as
if we had a shared storage this
here how does it all work because
you think gee but it's a raw file a
file sews a vmdk file which is a file
how can it be distributed on multiple
machines
then usually I do the analogy  of a
torrent file you all
know it torrent file what it does takes a
large file it splits it into chunk and you
downloaded chiang da from other peers to
other c  computer
the idea is practically the same we have
a large virtual disk point file
is broken up into what are
called object in in the case of the stream
less thematic even in the case of dogo
unless they are called object but the
concept is the same and are distributed
on the various  server
what is the problem with this you know
for example if you have a torrent that has
not downloaded completely that is, you
are missing pieces of file the file you
cannot use it ditto if you have a
virtual disk of a machine
even a small piece remains there
there is no information to have the
virtual machine disk
then for each there is also for each
object a second copy is made and it
is obviously distributed not in the
same way so for example a
piece puts the second copy on the first node
I don't look at it to put
on the same way the goal on
any of the others
in this way one dies the first node I
however the sky information does not  I
lost it ok now I go for a moment a little more
in detail how
sheepdog works this
I did it I simplified it a bit we have
qm ok bohemian kvm which makes some
requests to write to disk
I have to write something  in the disk of
the virtual machine the
write request is intercepted instead of
being taken by the linux kernel it is made
directly is taken is managed
by the web or blog driver and is
passed to a software the
software sheepdog sheepdog will
take care of breaking it up
distribute it and  then to say to which mou you
look I wrote I did
and in this way we have the
redundancy we need
on more nodes we have another component
which is what you see in the center that the
cluster manager
the cluster manager is the guardian
let's say so is that  who notices you
are a node is alive and dead sheepdog of
passion does not when it does we have
a cluster manager who can be Zucchi
for or can  to be choir singh there are
also others but these are the two
that are used the most that notify for
example if this dies the cluster
manager who runs on these here
notices it alerts them and they take
actions what does it mean if this had
we do  fake 50gb of small pieces
tells him look the one of the is no longer
active there are 50 gb of small pieces he
asks that they are missing then the others
begin to replicate each other
in such a way that there are always at least
two copies of each piece this is
a scheme of  what I have just
explained to you this precisely the
representation of a file where the
risk of the virtual machine is
divided into blocks of four megs each
square
would be this this let's say
square examples show me the parts
that are really written this is
this second today  this and more
this is a cross there is one where
there are no written parts where
we simply have a part of the disc that is not
allocated sheepdog crafty enough of
that there I am not going to lease the
space I do not know if you have experience when
you do unallocated allocated disks
you can make a disk even from three ground
on a disk of 500 yes yes
virtual space 3 tare  as long as
physically there is no write 3 land of
data you are not filling that space
there and therefore this is my list of
objects I have three and it shows that the
block
the block device is represented
in this way here by myself  I said
for simplicity the speech of two copies
ok because they are easier to understand but if
we have 50 machines, a hundred machines
can happen that more than one machine dies
in the same period of time, like an hour
from each other or even two hours  one
from the other
if it happens I do not miss it
I miss too much data I can no
longer get information and therefore the
cluster should stop
then what happens may decide to
increase the redundancy I say ok for each
piece  o don't make me two copies hungry the
three families four families 5 what
I decide obviously the more the redundancy increases the
lower the performances
because it takes longer to write
describes more things it takes longer and
the default redundancy
when you do a sheepdog cluster is  of three
couples that for me is already quite
high are three copies it
means that at least 3 sarvar can
die one with five men at
any time
nor can a second die so much
Sardinian parons burst this what
it also means sibello but it also takes me
away a lot  space in short if we think of
a gathering that eats me an entire disk
this would be a raid 1 plus 1 hopefully
used sum so it takes away a lot of
space then they thought they
added quite recently it seems to me
nine months in short not a lot is a
new feature that is called  he was on his
shield man that slide you see little
you can see better these two here are red
you can hardly see here on the monitor they hang
one of  these blocks
ok which is four mega and if you
tell me for example these 4 mag amelie dvd
in four then you make me 4 pieces from
one emili scattered on four
different machines obviously at that moment it says
a machine dies or I pass all
my data  but I tell him then you make me
two more pieces of redundancy and you put me
on two other servers those neely pieces
of redundancy allow me to
lose even two nodes
at the same time example just
these two or all the information one
of these recovery from one of these here
however  in this way I use much less
space and I can how to say I can
decide this level of
redundancy is not necessarily 4 and 2 it can
be 8 and 18 and 38 thought of c5 so
this maybe a little specific but if
it is not a very thing  very interesting
because a raid 6 is exactly
equivalent to a raid 6
if instead we do for example 2 and 1 it is
the equivalent of a radi 5
but I repeat we do it more widely  or
we have
100 machines I could decide to do 8 and
38 and 5 in short, very interesting this
thing well let's go on
here it is practically the same scheme as
before with some more details
above you see represented the cluster
manager called coro sync here we have
represented the virtual machines  to the
processes, however, they write
these have intercepted it from what is
called gateway in the specific
language of sip dog the gateway
speaks to the other sheepdog servants and
distributes them the olive data to take
they need fair there is all this is
a web command that  launch a normal file let's
call it so that it is nothing more
than a cook file at 2 could be
medicated
the syntax changes very little I
just have to say sheepdog colon and the name
of yesterday's tv v is not a file that you
see you can manage it  see the list of
disks I created and via a
command that we will soon see as good
as starting the sheepdog daemon
once  installed I can launch it even
without arguments and he goes to use a
default directory but the best thing in
fact I say fundamental is to
launch the command giving the dough a
mount point so that we have
a device dedicated to the city at least one
device
this instead  it is a more real example
where we have the daemon that is
launched that the enne option used
to increase performance uses the
first folder for metadata and this
instead is a hand point touch a
separate device then here I
refer to a cluster manager  which is
different from the sync chorus I tell him which
nodes actually have to
communicate with each other which are the
guardians in quotation marks and over all
here I said ok I have my sarno there is a
network card
dedicated to the sheepdog input output traffic
what does it want  say I receive data
over the network on a virtual machine no
they pass me through an interface that
has a bridge and are written to
disk when I  a node stops
in short, something happens
the missing data is replicated
so it means that there is a
data passage between the nodes and this can
slow me down the virtual machines gives us back
a dedicated network interface
here is that all this data passage does not work
to affect the
performance of the virtual machines less than
you can black on a
separate switch so I do not even go to clean
the network traffic of the dl of the whole
network of my data center
here before I was telling you for example to
see the dvd that is the disks
I have in my cluster I use this command
here dog means dog vdi list and it is
quite intuitive it is not that the front
dog withheld tina or not a bbb dopu of
liszt dog cluster info for example it gives me
information on cluster dog cluster
format from  only it makes me redundant with
the three couples you use this belt you
say you use the reasons me dvd
pieces in two
you make me one of redundancy which is
the equivalent of a ra  id 5 dog we
beautiful shows how many nodes there
are they also tell me their
ip address this is how I create a
virgin woody so I start from a cluster
I want to create an
empty virtual machine disk new this command here
that even this intuitive
does not  they are a thousand and one dashes to be used by
woody straight to erase a disc it is
very interesting thing
I can make snapshots to make more
dvd snapshots at different times
then there is another string but I
save money and from we play we talk a little
more about the dc9 features
well in the meantime it is a free free
software project open source is hosted on github
its features are auto
disconnect of disks when there is
an error
what does this mean for us we can
work without having a hardware raid controller
we can not even need it
use mini media to make me a king of
software
I give him the devices dough when a
device starts giving the accused terror
he unhooks it from the dal  cluster and
replicates missing copies authors
balancing data
dies me the nodule automatically
replicates the data to me those that have been
lost on that world there authors
web ship connection for any
reason for a moment
what happens that mou is no longer able to
talk to the demon ship because the
machine is busy with
anything whatever as soon as they manage to
communicate again with each other as if
nothing had happened and he continues
while the previous versions what
happened the machine was used and
you had to kill it kill it and relaunch
it it happened to me  recent among other things that
for a switch problem it is one of the nodes
but top time it was released from the others
by itself then it came back and continued
to work in short without even
needing my intervention was
snapshot plus roll back for easy
snapshots can  go back also the
state of the snapshot incremental backups
we have our virtual ones
here there is a snapshot or  days untied
tomorrow move the backup
of the entire virtual disk example 50gb
between yesterday and today have changed into gb of
data faces incremental backups you
put me on 1 gb of data
I can then do the complete restore
of the file made initially I add
the increase  and I'm okay so without
putting away the whole make backups
at cluster level every time
this is convenient if instead of copying
12 risks of skins the virtual brands
I want to do it of the entire cluster
plus it does it in a clever way
using deduplication and therefore space  it
takes up less space deduplication means
that for example on the same object it is
used several times it is just one mind away
several times you put it only once and
then re-uses it when I want to make
stories to support excavations that non-
standard very used level
redundancy as explained above can be
decided by the administrator if I
need more space for more servers
just add them and he
automatically s  Iri data balances or
new machines available to
launch virtual machines this email
received this morning integrated today
in the slides because now we have seen
let's say a little finished the technical part I
talk to you a little more about the history
of the project of the current state of those
who follow it  of those who do not follow the
founder let's say that the project a
few months that does not follow him anymore and there is
another muntain and then I asked
him please to give me some information
because I intend to make a
wikipedia page and I asked him why
the project was born and he answers me
because oh well if the oo.ss based as in
parma twas and take them and stage the time
practically there was no software
that did this open stuff
then his company started to
develop
it I don't know if  do you know or for star chef chef
he will make us do the same thing as sheepdog
are two parallel projects
initially I had also tried a little
chat I did not find myself so well
at  now or a little more this
project is perhaps a little more mature I have to
say this but I have not tried it very
much so I do not put it so it can
certainly be
a platform
here this is I have not tried it that
much  so you know maybe you
do not know or for the fs it is a file system
this thing you are talking about
I did not know this there is another
that now the name blue star escapes me
a rooster fs
here are anyway this is not  it is a
file system rif he was born to do
abstraction of a block device for
poems then in reality we are there to put it
with iss cases you can also use it with
another kernel module that was
created a few months ago which should
be a bit  more performing this cases
but the concept is the same you have a daemon
is an attack client
you will practically feel it in devices cases
you mount it
then there is the nbd one which therefore has
holes then mount for example a
spoon but then mount a  disk dog and
then there is also ship ss instead of using
a liti syntax mount one of the
partitions of the virtual disk what
you want it was still a little bit so I don't
spend more than many words on it
then I asked him but it was your project
or a commissioned project
from your company he replied that
the company he commissioned is called
ntt lab to ask but why
did you start creating this new
storage solution he says that rb point
of excess were not at the beginning
too the first people involved in the
project were he  that pumpkin kazutaka
morita and tomonori that is what
should be the current maintainer of the
target iss case and oh well then he tells me about the
pun practically the name
of the project that sheepdog where the sheep
are the
servers and then there is the dog that  that of the command
that what the minister
here are the references the excursion page well
surely where you find everything everything here
there is the whole project there is the wiki I
know  there is no documentation there is the
source code there is the master branch master which
in my opinion can be seen a bit like
the beta ok the patches and you find them there but
they may not have been tested and then there is
the version instead  stable that
downloaded it in tar.gz format and the stable
in short, like all stable not
new things, new things are not put
in the strip, however, bugfixes are brought back
and then there is instead
sheepdog turkey project point jorge è
a showcase site so it's not so much
aimed at programmers it's under
development
I'm trying to get some
stuff on it but there is already a
sheepdog manual I wrote it is quite
complete just in the manual there is no one
heart spoke of the redundancy
was circus of but the only thing missing is
fundamental the mailing lists there are two
developers and user I always write on the
user so the developer also read it
so and then yes of that other that
of the developers this or that  of
which I am  o I am mainly involved
in the project I am not a programmer
I know a little bit about it but not that much
testing testing and bagarella reporting
that is very important and I have
found it in short or that it is but all
projects when in short they are always
development cheaters then we have
tried in mind in a production environment,
not an example, we
ran the virtual machines of the
customers upstairs, just loaded giga and
giga of data every night and see
how it behaved then we
put stress in an environment just after
not being  simple test in two fi test on 5
gigabytes by rob suggested several
features
two stupid examples when he launches vi do
cluster format tac he did it
independently if the class was
populated no maybe a tired one writes from the
cluster format speaks everything in a second
without even giving the  confirmation in ten
minutes but made peace and a mass
another example recently added is
the woody l  ocking so there is a
virtual machine is using a disk on one node
a virtual machine on another node
cannot use it same disk
until recently yes and this was spitting on you the
disk they put vdi locking and I
realized that however if  the woody was
blocked he could still do v he says that
a kind of spelling which should not have
been done and I reported it and they
also fixed what I then did
two parallel projects one is called
due to a simple beige writes that
I download i  midi sources compiles and
helps me to configure it without knowing much
about the configuration
files syntax of the configuration files and
then another vm design here that
instead of launching a handwritten or
practically a
complete virtual machine configuration file I
start this machine not  I tell
him where he manages to get it started on
any node, for example, he checks
if there are the necessary resources and
maybe he also shows me the  good and 5
therefore a parallel thing that integrates
with sheepdog this is a criticism that
I can make to the project now is that
precisely if you go see you not
as developers or expert users but
one who does not know anything goes to see the
page of  gita bank did not immediately have
an idea of what the project is, how it
works, what its qualities are
and so I would like to try to give
this information more easily for
non-expert users and this translates
into the creation of the site
we have seen  first sheepdog between up to
project point org
I would like to collect information it can
be a useful thing to create a
foundation because sincerely you always
hear about the mozilla foundation
of the free software foundation of the
peace fondation they are organizations
that carry out their software
then I would be curious to understand if  it is also
possible to create a foundation
for this project and how to
look for maintainers to create the
pa  cchi packages of the various
distributions fedora percent on debian
media is already boom to
etc. integration in cloud meaning that it is very
used integration of prox mox that
we have already done in part but
only as fiscal targets
the real site just mentioned
update publication of
documentation so far  I created a
manual and added a small article on the
wiki and in my opinion it is a very useful thing
then if the creation of screencasts then
a video where you practically show us
what you do specifically is by no means
just a presentation that
shows just how  a cluster is initialised
and as a virtual machine is born
it enrolls in something it
is relaunched elsewhere
the wikipedia page that I told you
before,
here I thank you and if
someone wants to help me in
collecting this information knows
people who  I'm a
package maintainer or who knows other people
they know if they give me some counts
I would be very grateful to you and last thing
this is my test cluster are two
very nice hp mini servers that
carry small drawers and then
instead these here are
monthly coupons so on the fly with some intel atom and
two gigabit network cards are
processors  low consumption but to
do my tests on more than enough
questions
the traffic to sell
thanks
depends on the level of redundancy you
use then keep in mind that when you
write something you
describe a part of the local it prevents a
part from sending it to others
wishing it could still have  a node
that is that your only what it means
without disks that everything that writes
it sends it to the network on the others in this
example takes this example because it is
easier to understand your channel is that
of the network card so a gigabit
if you do  two copies perons write
your write speed is
halved so it's a gigabit divided by two
if you make three copies it's a gigabit divided between
then  go on 30 mag per second on the
contrary never on 50 60 megabytes per
second instead with node it is normal with
sata disks equal impact even aci more
because it is a userspace process so they
impact a little more but I have
then seen values reach  between 80
90 megs per second and with powerful machines it
can go even further
I speak with two copies so it can
vary a lot but good here do not
forget the hyphen n option for the
senses do not use with the option there he does not
use any type of  cache not even the
disk cache so as long as
it has not written on the metal it does not say ok
I am done it is a little yes used nfs
essentially the sync option is to be
shot in the mood and very slow
of a virtual disk you ask me a good
question
though  I think we are talking about petabytes also I
have seen that they were talking about a thousand
knots
these things I do not know how to answer you in case
apples sign and I investigate this on
this question here that may be
interesting
companions
yes an
integer  rface you say yes this was born it was
born just for openstack but
personally there is still no hand
for stark so I can't tell you but
this point has other features
that is not even mentioned precisely
that it supports the openstack amazon protocols
I recommend you go  to
read on the site it should be a
great openstack cool but staying one
level a little further back also prox
mox a very nice distribution eh
already it is already in short he fully gr
with the excavations but you can do here on
which juice on this need here me
at work I created the vm
clip because in fact I had broken my
balls to do so many times if it
sticks to launch the scripts here or
to see the good and remind me of the
channel the display on which the
virtual machine
is  created that little cliche
in short, quick to do these jobs
I have not tried it on hundreds of no
hundreds of nodes but I think you
try it on 5 6 nodes it was fine
probably up to about ten 20 nodes
go then it is also convenient that
just technically but there where
the developers are asked to
share a file share a know
that there is multi paties cases if it was ok
but that is another thing that is you have
two virtual macrì that need
a shared story
ah I understand I understand what the question is
for example a template machine and
above it is above that I want to launch
more instances
of this I can't answer you I
can't tell you this I can't tell you this  for
example I created my windows windows 7
or configured it with a web server
whatever I want I take a
snapshot I make the clones of the snap
shot the anci the virtual machines
as long as they do not start to write
has not taken up any more space
not  now I have not replicated the disk n times
yes I know if this thing can be useful
but let's talk about that
thing there else ok thanks