only she is fine guys good morning
i hope if you wake me up
well enough i'm vittorio
fasciani acab all then you have already
seen our 3d printers in the silos
3d printing theme had to come mixing
don't talk a little about printing criticize
what should be printed 3d that  weighs
strips kills shoes cp and
so on
but we say everything that
those printers do the art lacks a
particular fridge of subject what
presents the guys from the east and
we hear it something different we
present a printer that does
something innovative that  sounds of
course if you are turning on now
yes I hope you can also hear on
the other side what this printer is doing
the mind printing the
bracelet
the tracing often led flash has a
fairly simple and repetitive geometric shape
so what you do to a
kind of  mantra of starvation
matteo then makes a noise like this
there are many objects that when
I come  no printers falcon this
quite repetitive noise for which what
I apologized max and the
noise dress could modulate it in order to
transform
it what would happen in is more
like how you could do something
like this
let's say that someone already has it  thought
a 3d printed is nothing more than a
numerical control machine the noise
you hear are the stepper motors
which obviously are over-powered and
create this noise which is nothing more than
the given by the speed in which
the head moves in the asics of the  flat in y axis
obviously you never understand that you can't
stay if it slowly creates a heavy tumor
it went faster it creates a tone
just ok so looking a bit on the
internet there is a group both in the morning and
if there are some guys from
directly  of the maker
above it took us a while to 50 years to
build that
amen python system that could take
what a source midi file find all
the notes  and divide these notes into
musical frequencies and south in and obviously
transform the musical frequencies into
movements to be given to the 3d printer the
so-called cycle is equipped with 7 instructions
that uses 3d slopes you are just a little
shot but I am still slightly drunk
from yesterday evening euro shortage
of sleep that i fine but you too
in short I remind you that you were
quite awake tonight so that
's okay this which is the mind already
seen all these days so them at
our stand
enough we are fed up enough music
stop the peak plus 6 published by
printer
and  this point
we pass directly the software part
ok to do this then we will use
method excuse we
will use a
printer control program directly from the
computer
the graphic interface obviously everything is
open source runs on linux more than anything else
because it supposes python on windows in short it is
a  a bit of a [ __ ] here let's face it
ok
very well I do v  ed very
quickly the program that comes is
nothing more than a program written in python
with some libraries
is right because there are geeks
we have ready a program is called you
tell me cnc that is nothing more than the
program that defines practically
decodes what the  midi file
transforms it into program on date 7
g.cozz destructions to be given to the
printer
obviously there is a whole syntax behind
that was created of this
kind
she
is so
then okay but it is definitely people
on the other side fail  to see,
however, the definition of the
graphic resolution of the projector is not perfect minute,
however, let's say it is launched
mind through python this program
made to cnc dott file it is told the
type of machines that is
used in the command line in this case it is
a power uasp  otherwise there are about
five types of types of machines
because obviously each machine has
its own peculiarity as far as this is concerned  to be
extruded from plastic and obviously also
piano dimensions
we obviously have a command that
defines which midi file we have to
take in this case we had
thought of a music file suitable for doubts and
its situation we say sentimental that
now we will see
we have set what
the out should be  file that obviously has an
extension of .gi cod then
let me use the
classic old Basque van karaoke
because we obviously have the
midi file is nothing more than
a file that uses the various audio channels
to play musical instruments and
maybe not  all musical instruments
played by a 3d printer that
obviously currently two axes can
be good
the technique is that of 8 bit music
present in a four
quarter beating the notes are inserted by
dividing the four quarters for each
note that comes out so both
this  this this similarity with the
music 8 coveted once in this quest  or
case for example taken what because it already
did not work a moment
sorry
yes obviously one downloads
any midi file that he finds on the
internet if he has to process it because
obviously it will have a series of
music channels obviously intended as
classical music usually has a one
two or  three maximum music channels for
which quite playable at least
fundable in one channel only two channels
only music let's say rock or other
things perhaps requires greater and more
difficulty as if the only thing
after playing it is
obviously 5 amstrong of a second  does
everything worked perfectly
the beauty of the direct lends
itself remains undefeated in the silence sorry
sorry for the curvature
yes of
course
obviously the tuning of the instrument
on the frequency of the note depends on
everything then of the set that you give it
the speed settings of the
printer that it can reach  in what he
did do
here this one I don't know if I could
hear it is pre 21  she dedicated herself to doubts
ok it's a funeral march obviously to
see so there are various channels
usually this the first channel
problems to exclude them see if the
music is still catchy so you
may like it so we can also maybe
work on it
what you can what  at
this point you have to manually count
which are the channels to be inserted and
enter them as channel qua
channel 1 and 2 we only use the
first two channels so at least we break
our balls understood by launching this
program in python what comes
out always stopped because  the
wedding march actually seen a bit like this
on the boxes all you do is create
a queue program that we give the
printer of
course and you need an
intelligent printer understands that the
wedding march is not to be done
yes and for which it will do something more
interesting  yes
enough passion
is not exactly wedding march but maybe
someone will recognize the music
this is the music d  the star wars this
that francesca incappati who perhaps
did not recognize her
what you hear previous
is the main theme of star wars
reproduced by the 3d printer obviously
the matter of the
wedding music was a joke
the printer here does nothing but
interpret the  gico di in this sense
obviously has transformed the struggles the
movements and said and quickly when
you have to make a high note and go slower
when to make a graham note and is based
on a pattern for definite that famous
with was said in the upper and
lower limits  is of the screen comes
back and in this predefined packard
insert some noise which are the small
vibrations that you get by doing
that you get by making the
head move the fars print bed and to
reproduce the sound
this and pressed what as I
said obviously using  this
system we can at this point
create download our midi files
define certain channels  there that we want to
listen to the most significant ones
of a midi file and at this point
we can get various types of music
example
you want to give you want to give greetings to
someone make him do the music wing
of the happy birthday
okay
you can know the version quite
hello  but this is a classic of
obviously classical music is
much better than then the speech
this classical music obviously
at least instruments for which it is easier
to play
we can also possibly give
a fusion temperature an
extruded command this object to make it do
a  3d printing of what obviously
of this pattern and that the printer
creates which is given as said by a pattern
and predefined in which the
noise of the tigers nature is inserted he we will see the
weight of the thick lines where there are
heavy notes and lines  thin
where there are high-pitched tones because the
printer head will pass much faster
in this m  I hear what we are able
to do there is a
graphic representation of the music itself
now waiting for the moment it reaches the
temperature the printer could have done
it before for example if we launch here
yes no its written by the noises
step by step obviously that noise that
hear when the
3d printer does the printing they are nothing more than
noises that we can modulate at
this point obtaining that the noise is
more serious when it goes slowly
not the same lying on the surface
is given by a predefined pattern to
make it move in some way  the
3d printer more than anything else because perhaps
certain music
would still insist on only one point the flat
surface would bring the head to
reach the end stop from one side
to the other
in this way instead we
still manage to have a control of the
pattern of the area of  printing of the
printer and being able to insert what is
the noise
that obviously if we call it noise but
in this  case it becomes in the sound understood
let's be careful ture
they have removed my permission
yes reprap then there is the makerbot hiding
last ker
the wasp now but I hate to say that in
any case it is anyway both then there
are settings that if personally that
are 66 the  you say what the 0 and 6 max
is what is the upper limit on
the other side and you really get the whole
print plane yes
the circular inter-plane head
there we haven't worked on it yet what
you now hear is present the minute
of mouthpieces
I hope that  feel a little everyone
wanted almost now to printer
to me when plastic on
what we are doing the
greeting
are partners
which way
we show
but it is obviously not excluding
the printer in the evening
nothing more
with this let's say enough and unique
logic that is  in the sense that frey the
one on the foot out
tied to the music
the printer so what we
have
24 would be this painting is the
representation  and graphics of the minuet of
mouthpieces as the printer sees it
you see that it takes if you
notice there is the default pattern that
brings the fine head better however
its way it carries from right to left
from an upper limit to the
lower limit and then returns  back
obviously what it then does is
create some noise here it seems as if I had
printed badly but it is only vibrations
created by the movement
the head in playing the music itself
so it is something a
unique graphic representation of the
music
that we have the  minuet of
mouthpieces printed I would have had
another object
this someone else for
cult lovers instead the present
imperial march of star wars
here is obviously always interpreted
by the printer of the power one in a
certain way in short you think I know
a room more printer than  this
genre that each plays a
musical instrument synchronized with each other
can create  re an
art installation and then maybe someone can
even say yes having a crazy
[ __ ] is crazy [ __ ] but maybe that
fact of having made a
3d printer sound already in itself and I sing in
disgust or if you like
the importance yes  and I remind you that
more or less
fifty people have really worked for which about
fifty excellent minds in mine
obviously worked to
create this little program so that
obviously I walk around on all the
cnc machines on all the machines let's say
noisy cables transforming them  in that
subject just to say it I had
created it because my girlfriend hearing the
black music print let's say how cute
how beautiful we are would be our
music printed with the 3d printer
so I created nickelbacks far away
directly with 3d printing
what happened and then her husband
who sucks but gave up so if you have
girls do not show them these things
because there is a little price
ok more or less this is the talk i'm
even look in time
sorry the plushy tongue would tell me
fantozzi but really just crack very
ok so much to repeat the same things
also intends to tell me
in theory drought that is wait from these
tracks here you say
in theory yes that is  you should be there to
see the deformation as that
starting from a record in microgroove and
arriving at the music transform them neither d
hiver dub is the leader in this case 5
no wait wait in this case he
lacks the time because he still lacks
it he cannot understand  what is the speed
of displacement maybe in certain
directions so it's a bit difficult
while maybe the microgroove record instead I
sign in 45 rpm and then go read
the various roughnesses and maybe you can
come back to this maybe yes that I
'm a bit in some alien technology
it seems to me that they already do it is that from
da facen tauri yes but I hate let's say
removing the parameter does trying to
make sure that the knurling is
pe  rpendicular to the pattern then if
we can reconstruct exactly what you are
certain site
and at that point it is elia and modular in that
case we would have a fixed pattern so
we already have a constant from them to be able to
extract what information
so it would be a good example of
steganography hello you  gift this
small picture then maybe it contains those
born to build a nuclear power plant
in iraq
in short, maybe we have some
computer forensics who could be
interested in a house tomorrow today
we are not at all cautious so other
questions or in any case oh well so much we
will see each other there too we will make some other
music at  true that anyway the
music you really want a sequel a rocket
with excuse me the term that is a fact
star wars people go to google and
you have not even moved dddd indeed white is
true that the true
yes yes yes yes yes
maybe we could possibly do a
some music says
maybe wait
no this is the trees now for
mario you know some  n doctors have
problems to be decoded at least
you have to cut them out like for example
monkeys island but given a really
hard time
here I make him feel right for
francesco grabbed because he is monti
sen
that is for himself drool here we wanted him
as bait music
who  is that we know even if it is far away
and monkey island
ok
there is really all the inter or the b
is more iniqui de filippi ok
you have this is a program that you need
to be able to connect it could was printer
do this thing to remove the seats
put it is  the game of wrong and
incorrect
but here are three channels
yes because obviously you use
8 bit music with that while trying to merge
more channels into one channel by dividing into
four parts and guards or three
ah if it would have been better kept if
sometimes there  it is really some problem
because in any case the movements so
fast that those that are
specific to the printer are worth it are free there are
almost four months who  ne production
that maybe does not recognize in this sense
wait what happened here we are
late really we want with this here
is enough here is some music from the
30s it is fine with this music couple I leave you it
is right the link to the software just
search  mi di tucci lc with the 2
you find all the information
johnny b.good