there is a project
wait we talked about it first of all
if what I told him more or less at the time
globaleaks is a project that aims to
provide a kind of framework for
sharing information and
sharing validation of
information that can  being in the
public domain, however, of public
utility is not a good definition bad
not bad especially for the definition
of framework because well
globalist in synthesis born after
we understood that illustrious blogging
was always trying something more
interesting and significant in the
society of the future
as  so many data although significant
for public opinion and these data
could easily be kept
hidden rather than could
arouse many people to hear of
many ministry professionals never
knowing and after the bowl gate case it
became clear that a
wikileaks mechanism could never
work  because he had done
something a little too much  o big for anyone and the
natural defense of the structures in the
network is to distribute yes therefore to be able
to create many small elements that
can devote themselves to
specialized things and no longer have the
centralized element to almost all
refer to this was the idea
initial but instead we discovered that
these blooming and is much more is not
only the technical-political activism
of wikileaks but it is a lot of support
for investigative tourism like the
traditional one that has always existed and a
lot of corporate transparency because even
within small  medium and large
companies
there is the fact that
yes what are they bad and you should
bring something bad to your boss
but maybe it was he who
had been going badly because he is corrupt
because he is bullying, however, being
able to talk about it in a confidential way
someone from outside  internally can help them
and thus also applied to the public
administration so as
we have discovered these things  here he
said well I loved to see that louis blues swing
is not a julian assange instrument but it is
something much older and in
fact it was, however, to be discovered everything
gradually and this we take down for which
framework is perhaps the proof that most
enhances our work  and now he passes
the word to arturo who will continue from
one thing to add is that between let's say
the limits that we have identified in
wikileaks there was also the fact that
wikileaks was in charge of doing many things
went from managing the infrastructure
developing the software that is  behind
this infrastructure there is then the analysis
of the tip of the materials that are
collected through their
submission platform then has the publication for
which we have actually decided to
deal with a more specific
more technical aspect to develop a software that
can then be  managed by
other people still other people can
deal with the analysis of the material that is
collected through this platform and
then some  n other, perhaps even different
from the three previous actors, takes care of
publishing it and making sure that the
analyzes of these documents reach
the public and at this point I would
show a little how how
globaleaks actually works among the
technologies at the basis of globaleaks there
are the  tori del service
this means that those who manage a
globaleaks node can also choose
to remain anonymous
this means that there is no ppd
machine that I can attack or which I can
connect to
a natural person this means that
a system that collects information
perhaps on the  mafia where the person who
manages the node could potentially
risk his
life can do it safely they are
anonymous but still facilitate access to
this system which otherwise would remain
reserved for only nerds and
people who in short already know thor is
exposed on the network  internet through
another technology we develop which
is called wrong we  b which we will then talk about
later which basically deals with
creating a transport between the darknet
thor network and the normal internet network so
when I visit a globaleaks site
I don't actually have to
enter the onion point but I can also
visit an address in  clear https
no thanks
then that's the point this i answer with
microphone bottom with microphone respect
as that is wrong web and the software is a
software that like thor can be
used by various users on the internet
to form new web pie to
make sure that if  they take down our
web wrong our let's say
main node our way of this
software there are also others known as they
could be to make a
parallel example of the other exit med of tor
of the other entry points and in this case
wrong web which are not of  of hermes but they
are of other users around the web
who should pull down all
those who to succeed yes
absolutely like yes but que  I am happens
through a series of web twisted nodes in
which you to be a twisted web and
therefore an entry point between the internet and the
deep web install no install the
web torte software that it takes someone
who runs the strong web software to
allow  people to reach
these well series is the opposite of a
pie med exit is an
internet entry tortures itself allows you to
reach the known who would
otherwise be inside the darknet
so rightly has to who has a client
or what is relevant is that
our architecture has foreseen a
pato mechanism on the back end and clai and
front end so we have a back end that
speaks of the most airest and of a client
instead benetton javascript which is
only exchanged on these guides
what I was showing here was an example
of the  epia and basic that throws you between a
knot this because he will have to think about the
fact that the knots do not
yet have co, however, they are
single initiatives that are created  and from having
users where is the list of
globaleaks initiatives here on wikipedia
for the moment any way these nodes that
want to advertise themselves must do it
autonomously
imagine that instead in a
fairly close future because obviously I
melfi with the new line of development of
next 18 months it
will also be possible to have an index of
nodes that exist so that it will be
easier for those who want to look for an
appropriate way of this blogging or who
as a journalist wants to offer
to review some documents to
find all the existing nodes to understand
what the
corresponding keywords the languages supported
the tor jali rules that the various nodesses
give and this thing here will be an element
released by an ep ai public which
can therefore be more easily
collected in an index is verified
over time how a node behaves  and
party etc. so we imagine a
future in which the whistle blower who has
something to report to gods
documents to some material knows something
does not have to make so much effort to
be able to find the
best recipient for that type of information
but can directly query a certain
service and say I know this
something to who it is that I have to go and
mark it to that  point will get an
answer perhaps even with a
reputation system of comments feedback
etc. and will then be able to choose the
most pertinent globaleaks node to his
type of submission to the type of material
he has to send
I would like to return to the topic on his
motivations that led us  to
develop globaleaks and then see if
we have if what we have done is
that we initially thought then
it applied in practice when we
thought global we started from
wikileaks from a centralized model in
which it identifies we identified a
problem and mainly from a technical point of
view because  the centralized knot and scent
was easily
attacked under goes  re points of view
simply from the
financial or alt point of view for which we
thought about how we could suffer from
this problem by creating something
centralized initially even the
first ruminations were about
how to achieve software decentralization by
thinking about making a
distributed database  or anything else
then instead it was really understood that
this decentralization of
centralization of a rather
cultural type in the sense that it goes balich
wikileaks received material
from all over the world but very much allows
because of this it has received material has
centered on if even the enemies of everything
the world
while not knowing how to
specifically analyze the material that received
example had received mafia
or camorra material how could it have
discerned what is good and what is
wrong so precisely the idea
was to create a site where
decentralization was implemented
allowing  that various initiatives
may arise  and in an easy way here and there
in the world and among the various
decentralization concepts that we have inserted
in the software
we have inserted a decentralization
based on different types of responsibilities
in the node so in any case we have
foreseen that there was an administrator
who is that person or that  group that
pulls on the initiative and that does not
even have the visibility on the sides that
this person receives simply yes
I do not know what we can show how
you could slide the knot remo this person
trivially admitted on the initiative in
some way has made an
advertisement of the initiative
depending on the resources at his disposal
if he is an anonymous person or
he allowed me to put flyers on a
bulletin board
here and there by not signing himself in any
way if he is a person if instead he is a
media he may have used
media channels such as newspapers such as  the
newspapers rather than the
televisions and christa then
the administrator puts on the knot and the
spritz  in addition to doing this
the administrator configures on the
node those who are the recipients of the
material what you see here for
example is our demo node where
damn it is possible to create a
receiver called m center configured
with an email from the group or a
specific journalist  in this case the
name one of the members of our
association
just so to make the recipients on
who receive the material of the way the
only ones authorized to receive it the other
user the application and the whistle
blower that is the one who ends up on the one who
browses the  application once he becomes
aware of it through one of
the media channels he accesses it and can
select those who are the
recipients of his report of
his report
this because because again you wanted to
try to allow him software
to send your report
to the  person who he believes more capable
of handling it because a wikileaks
all the material came au  in the only
organization and there was no way to
know if what was the outcome who saw the
material and how he managed it instead here we
already want to allow him on the
web to select the one that is the
most useful group to receive  obviously
reporting
on these this simple
configuration model where there is an
administrator rieti are the recipients
lends itself to being able to launch various types of initiatives
you could show the slightly more
peculiar ones to see how this
configurability that we have foreseen
is then applied in reality  for example
there have been very simple
initiatives such as Italian initiatives such as pd
hicks where some
pretty smart investigative journalists have set up a
node to manage reports of acts
via investigative journalism for various
areas such as the
food sector and
they have configured a  simple node
where they created their own a simple
receiver intended to receive all the
material  that is received
is this one of the simplest cases of
globaleaks installation paradoxically
instead there are very diversified cases
this is a very simple case because
they have configured a single receiver
destined to receive all the material
marked hard in the meantime it
shows a much more articulated scenarios
were those for example of
public an organize in the Netherlands an
organization has created a special
foundation in the public foundation
deciding to create a node in which the
recipients are all the Dutch media
you can also open it for a while that
loads all the myths and  Dutch after the
whistle blower where he is a blogger
browsing the whistle blowing site he
can select which specific media to
which specific media to send his
report because I wanted to show you
this directly because this
software with these simple
external characteristics
has probably given space to  a very
interesting case of a day
rather innovative lism because you can
see that the whistle blowers
available the possibility to report
select which media
the material will mark and these media I
don't know do not even have the same
political color and despite this they have
signed an agreement which requires that
if two  paradoxically, media of two
of different political colors receive the
material are forced by an agreement to
collaborate your report
also they have established a way of doing
good journalism and therefore do not give results
to simple reports to simple news
they have signed an agreement and where
they have regulated how to manage the
material  received something that
was not there in wikileaks for example in this case
they decided that a report
cannot turn into a news before a
period of 15 days so that
a good investigation can be followed up
so not a simple
news but has  a
story of formation is therefore never
published  do automatic it is made
available that it has selected there are
two possible features there are two
possible features or you configure the node
to be selectable and therefore you
can
choose it or it is fixed and not to
choose it depends on the organization
how it is structured
of an editorial office in which there is a
working group that has three separate parts inside
and these parts forcibly want to
work together then it
may be the case in which they are all
not selectable
but in all cases in which globalism
used to  moment there is the
discretion on the part of the whist
blogger to choose who is his
interlocutor contributors
yes of course every look I would say no but it
cannot be held by the software what
we can do to the maximum as
software is in but for a journalist they
wait for what to say  a promptly if one
every journalist must in any case review
what he receives and this is part of
his journalis practice  tica
if then the next boffo case was
received not with the false dossier in the
newspaper but with the right newspaper this is
an abuse of the journalistic position
which was then sanctioned at least
as regards the specific case of
boffo sallusti so abuses can
excuse me can  to exist I do not depend on
technology what we try to
do is always on whether we have to give
support to explain that some criteria are
ceased and the necessary tour policies
if instead someone uses
software senses we no longer know it and
they adopt it even badly there we cannot
anyway  preventing this abuse is another
way not to solve but
partially mitigate the entry of
garbage-type information such as what
is what we say that is
used in the more traditional world
of whistleblowing which is not
directly linked to journalism but
often linked to the compliance of the
contrast to corruption these things here
where they are defined in a much
more pr  apart from
the type of information on which you
want
I say that you can take charge
which can be environmental abuse or
corruption depending on the category to
which you are making the
report ask the whistleblower for a quantity of
information of high quality and
inadequate quantity which means  that if
I ask you about all the people
involved their data
tell me when the fact happened
tell me what is the economic damage that
was done ask you how I can
verify what you said
then maybe unroll twenty or thirty
questions
so not a  free form write
what you think that leads you to make a
more detailed and more
qualified report then raise the quality
of the information it is obvious that if I
also optionally ask you many in
many requests many questions and to
answer me only 3 and  then they write me a
long story in the description but without the
term also indicated how I
could verify the veracity of
this thing is an indicator of low
reliability of the report
here this these are things that in the
work that will be done later
will be more and more embedded within
the software even with
default questions to facilitate this type
of information quality filter and
precisely and  implemented an
exchange function possibility of exchanging
information
there is a system in
messaging quotes no between the whistle blower and the
receiver with in the middle however this layer
of anonymity that serves your business
cicada facilitate this type of
operation here so
check the  information that is not a thing
it is not a unilateral channel but it is a
channel that, if desired, a bilateral communication can be established
specific questions to the taste blogger who perhaps
lives a very contextual situation
wants to explain himself better but
the journalist or the person
who receives cannot explain himself  he can ask him questions always
protecting him
always Fri  derive it anonymously and verify that
these people people are not
invented the stuff but have other data they
can circumscribe the issue
so from the vote we like to say that it is not
like another boss another anonymous box
in which he puts the data is hard nishi but
when you do its mission
start your business augusta blauer
which will be completed only when it was
the data will become news in practice
this
at the discretion of the node of the
node sector that chooses who are the people who
should be part of the network reveals
however let's say so  this is clear
globaleaks a free and open
source software that anyone can download
install that is in the sense it is not something
that we control in a global
ict and then we decide an irpi yes
public snow etcetera etcetera
anyone can do his own way of leaking of
course  if, however, he asks us for support
in the installation and troubleshooting
of the installation, etc., etc.
in the customization, he does  we have
a skimming that is that I know
how to work as we are working with transparency
international it is clear to us that it is
good and right
and now we have started a
collaboration with amnesty
international also on these we say
that the doubts about a cube bit are few if
instead  the p2 night arrives which is
completely unknown to us maybe
we do an analysis we try to understand
who they are we try to understand if those
who are for their purposes of linking are
the purposes that we say we marry
or
we do not know and they have not even
contacted us  we only got caught by
google alert and they started
an initiative that saw the
smiles deshaun plugin then asked for
information on let's say secret activity
with fiduciary activity and based on the
banking secrecy of the isle of man is a
tax haven but who the [ __ ] I am
these and what they do to us with this
information not only do we not
know but it is not even publicly
no  to in the sense they say we
prefer to keep our animated and
not say who it is because a ska activity it
is obvious that behind an initiative
such as mais leaks which thus seems an
absolutely beautiful thing and maybe they are
also very well motivated people but who
you know you don't know who they are they tell you you were
sending the secret information on
the banking system of the isle of man
that is, it can be incredible incredible gear,
I could be the anonymous
who started that initiative, get
my information and then go and do some
nice ones and  blackmails what the
bank account or the
offshore company has
so there is a whole sensitivity
around depending on how you do things
publicly, that is, how your initiative proposes,
how you expose it and how it
works this is a  example on which there
may be legitimate doubts, but then it
is right that we do
these doubts like anyone else, that
is, it is only the initiatives that we have
supported  must necessarily be considered
right
ask yourself your questions give you your
answers independently in fact
relaunch with the creations of the boys
here one thing in my opinion develop
open source software which in any case always
last but often presented
open source projects children and technical point of
view  however, who then promote them
because they use it so the
most interesting part then perhaps also find
the way to make this project be
adopted by media of a certain
importance because the three-year project
and the brutal tear was very slow and
now I  on the other hand, it seems that you can
have some collaboration started to
be able to move some of us
who spend a part of their time
if not all the time they give, let's say
of the association in following the new
prospects, that is, in those who are the
new we help them follow them and  let's go
and see them pamper them a bit to
make sure that initiatives are born
at least the most important ones that is if
amnesty tells us come to bangladesh
we take the plane that is because
amnesty many African countries on
investigative journalism issues therefore
in short, however, limit a different one on the
theme that sat v.to we have
now obtained a usable product from  a
non-technical band with an extreme effort
because what I had learned with the
Italian community
unfortunately in source is perhaps to create the
interesting technology that is cool technology
but then that cannot be stylized
by the end user because it really lacks
the aspect of the experience of the  product
management and the constant of software
localization in multiple languages
the fact that the software is stable in
even in a few conditions such as we
are giving only on ubuntu far
lawn tennis to bring stability and
nevertheless also study live to the
types of use that we  they are the
proper documentation and the hardest part if
you want for folks like us
who are anyway  of programmers is
this here is just the part of
innovation that I feel we have done and
that you clearly notice that maybe even
thunderbird enigm ale for how much it is
implementing cryptography in
public in the most instinctive way
possible has caused that people who do
not want to puzzle because they lack
does an asymmetric cryptography work
do not use it would have tried where
possible to make some considerations
security 106 a security issues
this risk these types of assumptions
we can make them for you
where we can make them we take away a
choice from you so as to simplify the process
where we cannot  making them choose the
administrator node that the person
closest to the context of use
then also bring a
high security level to a usable level it
was really the difficult cig ment and
with which I feel that
something new in fact cost a lot of time
because doing wordpress with report is spam
was easy  mind feasible in a month but
what we got but the level of
security we can now give there is
also a
particularly
nice encryption mechanism that manages to ensure that every
landed file that agitates you that travels
from put the channel and thor is then encrypted
with the public key of the recipient
without ever touching the file system in
clear text despite the fact that it can be
even 10 giga files because there is a mechanism
that will now explain john or rather he will
explain it after contorto web 15 august there
is precisely the most difficult part of
our  project produced
but a question the discussions
answered when a very simple question
me from the journalist that is as a whistle
blower I make a submission
anonymously how you contact me you do not
contact you but we tell the whistleblower
how to return to your report and
see any comments you
have  so i don't have a mechanism there
isn't a push mechanism of the response
but i have to ric  order me to come back
because if I keep my news on a
ticket
yes yes exact this this figure between you will
mark with to address book on your
mobile your mission lasts 180 of
time because one of the security events
also the from tri nation policy every
submissions cancel in which to  days
or then it extended over duration, however,
ideally nothing well preserved in the long
term because if it is managed it might as
well be that any type
of trace that has been deducted
between taste and bloggers and journalists or
recipients of the ticket needs a place to
return to the  his submission exchange
comments land new files so if
there is this
web support and maybe I do it later
then it can be
exact it is precisely the speech
that instead sutor tweb
comes to me I think that if I
wanted to do an anonymous mission auction
that is, whoever made a bull did not think about
the todd webb mechanism precisely for a
safety issue because whoever
manages the torture node sees the  my ep
my traffic then I can have a thousand vpn
but it is honestly if I had to do
the mister blog and I would stay on a tour
because my isp does not have to know where
I am going that is I would like that before
the sp there was already the traffic
around and me  one thinks that this
simplification can cause
problems for those who want to run such a
service only to aggregate
information, however, I repeat globaleaks
is not a software with a
precooked configuration that enables any node to
globalize to be published through between
two but globaleaks is a
configurable framework  depending on the type of
initiative that I have to start and the
risk scenario because you can also
have a super-secure software made
accessible only with
a strong encryption back with an autograph but it
will not be used and whoever needs to
start an initiative will do so with a
wordpress without https and whatnot or
whatever we say is up to him just to
try to evaluate  what their
risks that its risk of default
globaleaks is not exposed via the wrong
web so when it is installed and
can only be accessed via the ben
service then the admin can choose to
publish it also via the wrong web
it displays a huge  warning
saying attention
the dead unicorns could start
raining from the sky
if you click yes okay I want to continue at
that point is activated for or in any case
when the whistleblower visits a site and
not the status
a node globaleaks and is visiting it
not by finding it is
displayed  a warning message here
attention is not using
thor we advise you to download it from here
and when he goes to make a
submission he is told again
attention we are not joking
really you are not anonymous we explain
what it means that it is not anonymous yes
knows that the twisted web node could
intercept the data of its submission
etcetera etcetera
at that point the v  he is asked a question
that is insert the sentence that is true
between the following sentences if he answers in the
wrong way he is not allowed to
make a submission if instead he answers
with the right answer at that point
we understand that he has actually
understood what the risks are  and in that case it
can continue and carry out its mission
banquet another thing
tortù web must be considered in two ways on the
one hand it is necessary for globaleaks
I could also expose situations in which
they had not animated but on
confidentiality and in the other case it is
a strategic event for the diffusion
of thor because the inter services store
suffers from a phenomenon born in the
networks for which there are less known and less if they
create a network it tends to become a
monopolist of itself therefore thus
creating the railway network
the distance  and binaries then becomes the
de facto standard to consider telephone
the mechanism with which we speak is the
world standard of internet telephony and
the global network and  the first leeden
service is not a global network network
used by a strong ignorance this
strong minority knows they have a great
need for security to get to
expose their services anonymously
but we have seen that it can be useful for
anyone to expose services in a way
attributable to itself because if you trace a
priori or because it is the only guarantee that
your users can
communicate in a confidential way
but this thing here must be explained must be
explained and if he managed to create an
activity around these iden services and
tortures it becomes necessary therefore why
even people outside thor
can understand that tower is useful is
simple and can act to spread
your browser bundle which then makes you
sell part of the top 20 account that the
bander overhead and torture where it says
used bowser bundle the better
the earthquake te percent of the purpose dr
tweb ensure that content that does not
lend itself to add that reaches the world
faces excellent plant so be it p
more sure it will be faster and it is better
so do it sorry I wanted to answer
what you said about one thing and we
often talk from a computer point of view
barrack ok but
people think differently just
what does it mean that we do a
million mind whacks about
safety so let's say how do you like headlights back to
me the answer they have to go
pole in pushing thing like that i
judge i was the protagonist in
spite of myself in a winston boing speech
and in the end the reporter tells you
something one  let's see each other because it is a
mentality that they have that with such a
tool they have to change
ok absolutely
two thousand it seems mental for example you have to
contact me but not with the email you have to
use encrypted systems etc. but I
assure you that in the end if it is something that
really burns them  they say where but
i send you a ticket let's
meet in kathmandu in the square in front of a coffee
but they want to see you as if  to
give some guarantees on the news brawl,
however, it is a big problem of
mentality that even the journalists must change
because otherwise we will
make 2000 it seems, however, then we
find ourselves in a situation like this,
then you had sent things away tor one
see the comments and  then who says ok where
we meet and the stage falls for you until
now we have not said what the
web cake is someone knew but the
others think now they do not think
the transport
is okay anyway
thor is a software that allows through
a technology  call tori den
services to make anonymous servers that
are in the one called deep web
to access these servers it is
however necessary to install the tower itself
and this may not be easy for
all users also thorne not
thor server names are not public
indexed by  for example to
search engines for which if a user wants to
reach a resource that is in the deep
web he must know it regardless
in 2008 aa  ron swarz thinking about this
problem since he strongly believed in
free information, he thought about how to
solve the problem and thought about
creating a proxy and then
creating a software that allows you to provide
a web server if you are requested
to  requested
contents that are in the art this
retrieves them and provides them to the user and
then he thought of starting
a node with this software assuming if he the
responsibility of following contents that
in fact are the alarm for this
was initially born top web  .org on
which there is a setup of this
hardware software and later we tried to
find other volunteers who would run
other nodes then distributing among
them the responsibility of running
a service of this type
this is the reason why we
wrote about it  somewhere on the wiki there are
other nodes like tortue dot org chat
web dot fia in finland there is a
tu point and there are other t  All followed by
different types of volunteers we
collaborated with aaron in writing that he
knows software and we then included it in
globaleaks to achieve the same
goal, that is to ensure that it is
a whistle blowing initiative born
by anonymous people that can be reached
by users who  they do not have in their three
models therefore their scenario the risk the
need to be anonymous
themselves so in global if we have allowed
different scenarios to be configured
the risk that the application
is reachable only through the toro network
or even through the tweb editor
what is the advantage of publishing a
node through reeling because
the user can find the initiative
directly indexed on and I would
add that while we say once upon a time
web had to be this software
that one runs to expose
the whole network and darknet thor  with
the use of wrong web for globaleaks
then one puts on a knot of wrong
web we are interested in neces  sary expose
the entire darknet thor maybe he
is only interested in exposing his
node globaleaks in this case it is
possible to configure torto web to
forward traffic only to a
specific idem service so one can
have a web node managed by himself on a tortoise node
therefore still trusted it is  however, do
not incur all the
risks derived from allowing anyone
to access any good service
in the darknet thor
look
no it's better
so it also works in a certain sense
from a discovery system that is who
allows you to discover the address of the
point everyone starting from a domain
sorry one thing a little less technological
no no active bulls are not many
not intended I do not speak globally
I say let's take a city a country one
do not think that the very fact of
having active service attracts the  attention
but it still depends on there are
more than 45 million users every day thor understood
however in the world let's say a city
how many there are in venice
here at this moment you pull that is this
potentially creates some
potential elements probably to be
controlled
this is why the concept is if aitor
there is probably something to hide
this type of prejudice used
by the productions this gesture given how much
I am abused  even with him bull or happens
to linux journal
then maybe you are a techno terrorist
so let's say that I hope it becomes
clear in the intelligence of the next few
years that it is a bit of an atypical procedure
Italy has some analyzes I did
was the second country for the  '' use of
thor in the sense of second country if we
take the number of connected users that
re official statistics given to tor
divided by percentage by per million
so many connected therefore having the first
place uf6 which has many more citizens
connected and less relevant than
having them  in italy where the percentage
of use then in practice the highest
we were second only to saud saud  eng
they did those tests
when the motivation that we had
asked ourselves why there were
spiders and one of the hypotheses
we will make
you said there is a question
it is returning to the speech tortù returning
to the speech tortù web globaleaks fortwo
and it is  basically an entry point
for the tor network
this means that if I do an
installation of global leaks on my
node where uniten service runs it would turn me
in a tower configured in day service below
I will have the right global ict framework
let's say that when globaleaks stalls
to the ground and services dedicated
and then the option that you do not accept
connection that arrive at the wrong web
because when you arrive scort web
an eder is put in the connection with
hicks torture be true and you by default and
do not accept that it can cause
disability  accept one can communicate
with you ok I wanted to understand precisely this
thing if how the discourse
of inhibiting access was managed through the
entry point tram nodes  ite the ssis in this
mechanism because luck had
however put a given application and a
web http connection since in
practice strictly web not also other
types of connections that instead may
exist in the silver network and and this
is the application available here if
too many that  he wanted to succeed at all things
69 but did not check leather torture and
therefore accepted that the user arrived
given art lab also constructions
default node 2
no node tweb node globaleaks node
globaleaks node well if you don't have a
data encryption mechanism on the disk that
what compromises is the database part with
application data inside the
default files would be encrypted for the
recipients as long as the recipients
have put their public key a
red warning tool as a house
careful this way is not recommended
because a recipient has not configured
I was able to make it his key to
make the
journalist responsible for putting it in spite of it
one could also ignore it and say the
data is so the nice thing about the tower
that in any case hides the
geographical allocation of the server of consequences you
have exposed the node via thor all to
reach through torture however
where geographically st this serves with
which p is connected to the internet not  it
is not is not known so the only possibility
of registration is an attack through the
globaleaks software and luckily
we have had three
different tentation testers reviewed by three different tentation testers who have
carried out both architectural and code analyzes and
on the web side that the ato  python
therefore we could keep reasoning
safe that we are not exposed attacks from
remote place of zero day on twisted that
may also be possible
certain
to build that a license plate and disabled
there was still captured and it will be
beautiful
christ
in reality what
claudio described  is the current state of the software
for implementation reasons currently
the server was only encrypting the fi  with
the silver cameras and not the answers given
applications the forum answers that
he was given only afterwards but it is in the road
map of the next 18 months to implement
the entirely client side encryption
in this case it will no longer be possible to
read even these data during
the  'installation of global hicks the setup
the configuration assistance tools
provide help
to the user for the creation of a
clean system redo and to avoid side
there is in the tax or things of this type for
which all the traffic independently
passes through thor  as if it were thales for
example or not for now then
back end side all eventual requests
that the back goes to the internet
are all worried about the territory
you asked if
we give suggestions we start with the
product I love so that I have palix
that of  simplify the adoption therefore
no no the left reflection is yes yes no
oh well but the global leaks
editors application that terrified but a  application level
in a brutal way
but if they have broken through the car by
now that they have broken through it is not
what you can do you are not the
disqualification could be among the
when we will contain with totti