memory manipulation is a technique that
has been around for a long time it is
used for both security and malicious
purposes today i'm going to cover some
of the malicious uses of memory
manipulation of windows and how we can
detect them
my name is connor morley and i'm a
senior researcher with secure formerly i
was a threat hunter for four years and i
published multiple white papers and
detection pocs i have also presented a
number of conferences on security
related issues
today we're going to be looking at what
exactly a memory manipulation technique
is then we'll be looking at inline
hooking for exported functions then for
private functions and the detection
issues associated with that we'll then
look at kernel level hooking on legacy
windows systems heavens big hooking for
wow 64 x86 processors and finally we'll
look at vectored exception handlers and
how they can be used for memory
manipulation techniques
first off what is a memory manipulation
technique
so memory manipulation revolves around
live process memory so we're not
focusing on files or file system
manipulation we're only focusing on
alterations made to memory that is
currently running within a process
changes to this can affect the control
flow which allows for various uh
activities to occur which can
change or siphon off information it can
prevent functions from occurring it can
prevent
checks on integrity
it can equally execute malicious code
changes over the past few years have
seen that malicious actors have moved
away from the idea of manipulating
memory within victim processes and
instead within uh to
changing memory within their own
processes the reason one of the primary
reasons for this is that monitoring of
uh alteration to memory of remote
processes using virtual uh remote alike
or anything like that um is quite is a
long-standing security concern and there
are security vendors are quite hot on
detecting this and as such issues
sparingly because it is so readily
detected
instead attackers started manipulating
the memory of their own malicious agents
or payloads in order to prevent
detection the reason for this is that
manipulation of a processor's own memory
is not malicious in and of itself and a
process has full access permissions to
all of its own memory space which means
you're not running into some of the
areas that you encounter with remote
processes
this can be used for two primary
purposes one to prevent monitoring or
two in order to redirect the control
flow now redirection is normally done in
order to try and muddy the waters about
what is happening so you can call one
function which will then hook and call
another and you can you can make it
quite complicated which can make reverse
engineering uh quite painful
but we're going to be focusing on the
preventing of monitoring by security
vendors
in this case
to that end i will be covering four very
specific uh areas now when as i go
through these you'll you should notice
that the techniques that i'm outlining
can be used for other activities besides
um just uh evasion techniques where the
hooking has been implemented or the
memory manipulation has been implemented
other activities can occur with some
development choices and some alterations
but today i'm just going to be focusing
on evasing detection using these
malicious techniques to that end i'll be
looking at
etw event prevention using dlls or
libraries
library manipulation
prevention of etw telemetry via kernel
memory manipulation interception of x86
or wire 64 cis calls in order to evade
detection
and finally vectored exception handler
or veh specific bypasses that can be
used in order to circumvent some
security vendor techniques
so first of all let's look at inline
hooking for exported functions now first
of all it's important to know what
exactly i mean by hooking so hooking is
the alteration of a functions and start
op codes in order to perform a secondary
action so imagine you called a function
which
uh let's say it creates a file
now if you know where that function is
located in memory if you
change the first set of commands to
instead jump to a different
function
that is what we would call hooking so
what it means is that every time that
function is called your hook or your
alteration to the memory will cause
something else to happen which changes
the control flow of that function in
order to perform a secondary action that
you have implemented this is used by
security vendors and malicious actors
for security vendors this is normally
done for telemetry collection so again
let's say a security vendor has a
particular function they want to monitor
for because it's high value or it's
something they know is used by
particular
attacker groups now by placing a hook on
that particular function anytime a
process executes it the security vendor
security software will get a event
generated or telemetry generated with
process that called that function what
they were trying to do and when which is
very valuable
attackers equally can use the same
hooking for the same purpose in order to
monitor system activity
but equally they can use it in order to
prevent the function from executing or
they can redirect the control flow to
malicious code or shell code and there's
lots of ways that malicious actors can
use this and it is very simple to do and
it is extremely effective
one of the things to note is that the
export address table or eat within the
pe header of libraries makes
very easy so the eat basically outlines
all the exported functions all the
functions that are variable to external
processes from that library and where
they're located in that library
this means that if you wanted to develop
a hook for a particular function looking
at the e80 would give you information on
where it's located in that library's
memory which allows you to target your
manipulation
specifically at that dress making it
very easy
one of the other things to know is that
dynamic information on modules that have
been loaded into processes can be
acquired either by the process
environment block or peb
and through native libraries such as ps
api by examining
these by either using ps api's functions
against a particular process or by
examining the peb of a process you can
actually enumerate all the modules that
are currently loaded and their base
address within that process
which allows for the
eats information to be cross-referenced
to find particular functions within that
process is instance
of that
library or that module
which is which it makes development very
easy for hooking
let's have a look at how this works in
practice so in this case we're trying to
target etw event right which is located
within the ntdl module or library
now etw even write is a core function or
exported function which is required for
etw event generation
so
one of the things to note here is that
ntdll is loaded into every single
windows process it is not optional but
this is just an example to show you how
this could work
so first of all a
attacker would determine
where the process or the function is
located to do this they can do it in one
of two ways they can either use the load
library and get proc address functions
in order to load the library of ntdl and
then find the function address using
getproc address against the
handler generated by load library
or they can enumerate the peb of the
process to find the base address of nt
dll and then cross-reference against the
pe header of nt dll in order to find the
um
in order to calculate the rva of where
etw event right will be located for that
process
either way the result should be an
address in this case of 7ff 8916500
once you have the address of where the
function is located you can determine
what you want to do how you want to
install your handler so in this case
because we just don't want etw event
write to work because we don't want etw
telemetry to be generated we're going to
install an opcode of value
0xc3 which in x64 stands for red or
return
now if you patch or hook the start of
ecw event right with a return command
what happens is every time the function
is called
the first op code returns control to the
calling function so if your function
decides i want to generate an ecw event
cause etw event right as soon as it as
soon as it calls that function
the calling function is returned to with
the stack all uh corrected and and and
resolved and it thinks that etw event
right has been successful but because of
the hook that's been implemented or the
rep that's been patched in
we know that the etw event right has not
done anything and as such you prevent
all etw telemetry from being generated
for that process
so
now we know how this is implemented how
do we detect it
so detection methods are all to do with
knowing having a known good and being
able to compare what is within live
memory so the first thing to know is
that all volatile memory begins as a
file so
all the loaded memory that's in volatile
memory came from the past system to
begin with and the file system has an
unaltered version of what is in volatile
memory now the loaded module file
as we've said before the information
that can be found dynamically primarily
through the peb now what's interesting
about the peb is that it provides a path
to the source file within the file
system
for the library that's for the module
that's been loaded the library that's
been loaded
now
let's say you wanted to monitor for ntdl
etw event right you could use the peb to
find the source file which would be
located in system32 you could then use
the pe header of
ntdl to find the offset of where etw of
mri is located within the file systems
version and use that to calculate the
rva address within the running process
and then you can compare what is in live
memory at the address you've just
calculated for the rba against what is
within the file systems version and
check whether there is disparity between
the two
if there is a disparity you can say that
a hook has been implemented at the start
of the process and this can be done by
by by comparison so if an alteration
occurs within the first 100 bytes or
something to that effect that may be
excessive but you get the idea you can
detect whether a deviation has occurred
due to editing and this is very
effective at detecting these types of
hooks
but targeting is required for such
operations the reason for this is that
um inline hook or inline patching can be
done legitimately as we've said before
this can be done for security purposes
but equally there are some processes
such as firefox which do this
legitimately to a number of internal
functions so unless you are targeting
specific functions of value you may get
a lot of noise on a lot of false
positives on particular functions that
aren't of secure security interest
so as such targeting does need to be
done in order to make this accurate and
equally to make this resource manageable
private functions within um modules pose
a different problem and they have some
detection issues so whereas with
exported functions
where the export exported function is
defined within the eat which makes it
very easy to locate um private functions
are not exposed to external processes in
any way they're not in the peb the pe
header or any index
and as such it makes this much harder to
find
but one of the key things to note is
that exported functions from a module
will
almost inevitably rely on at least one
private function in order to operate
this can be to do with argument
integrity check formatting checking or
you can do with initial connections or
anything to do with that sort of effect
and if you know that the exported
function that you want to prevent
utilizes a private function it can be
just as effective to instead hook on the
private function instead of just the
exported function although it takes a
bit more work
adam chester research adam chester did a
great example of this using dns curry
under school a which i'll demonstrate
now
so in this example you identified that
the
private function you wanted had a
specific code signature by scanning the
by using load library or enumerating the
peb he found the
base address or the memory address of
where the module was loaded for that
particular process and then scanned the
module memory address space until he
found the corresponding code signature
which gave him the base address for the
function
in that module
from the above we can actually see that
the
internal function that we're looking at
when put through a debugger is an
internal symbolic function and as such
it's not exported
from this we know that it's not going to
be in the eot or the iit or anything to
that or sort of effect so without code
signature or pdb
which i'll come to in a minute there is
no way to know
that this function is there unless you
already have the code signature now the
code signature was acquired via external
reverse engineering and looking through
the
call stack of what happens before this
performs a cisco um and uh and just i've
actually found that this particular
private function could be hooked quite
effectively
now
in this case um you can actually patch
the
um
[Music]
private function with a rect command
again the reason for this is that
the uh function in this case
subsequently calls the etw publication
so the private function in this case
actually generates a event template
which then hands off after two functions
nt dll
event right transfer
but by performing by
hand
by putting a hook here of rhett you
prevent the template from getting
generated and the etw event from being
generated within ntdl and the calling
function doesn't know the wiser
as such
you know we can see from the bottom
window that the red command has been
implemented within the specific va for
where the um
post signature has been found which
prevents the etw from being generated we
didn't click on the exported function we
hooked on the subsequent private
function which was called by the
exported function which from a detection
point of view
creates some problems
the primary one being their private
functions are there's no information on
them that's inbuilt into a process
they're again they're not in any of the
header files so that you cannot
enumerate them from an external process
i.e they are private the only way to do
this is to have a program database file
or pdb now pdbs are generated at
compilation time and they do provide
symbolic um address and symbol
information for private functions the
bdb files cannot always be guaranteed to
be acquired the reason for this can be
there could be third-party um
module files where the pdbs might not be
available or you may be in in an
environment where a connection to the
internet and the subsequent windows
symbolic server where windows pdbs are
available cannot be accessed so unless
you have a large database of pdb files
walking around with your detection
system it can be hard to
attribute or find
where particular memory addresses are
located to private functions
secondly there's a double dependency
issue so what this means is that each
module can have an iit or import address
table as well effectively what this
means is this module relies on a second
module for functional capabilities now
because of this
if a
module imports other modules you
therefore and that module
let's say that your first module calls a
second module in your second module has
the function that you're looking to
monitor for
any point in the stack from the first
module to the second module any function
within that stack can be hooked in order
to prevent that second function the
function within the second module for
being executed and as such all potential
paths against all the double dependency
modules need to be monitored in order to
prevent hooking at an earlier stage in
the stack but because of this the
resources required are exponential so if
you look at the table in the bottom left
you'll see that the number of internal
function symbols for um the average uh
module is around
three to five thousand but the dependent
modules can be as high as 806 with an
average of 583
now because of this when you start to
count up all the internal functions that
you're potentially going to have to map
against all the
modules that they're now dependent on
that number rises very very very quickly
which can create a big resource problem
finally it's to do with the module
version so between module versions some
internal functions can become
obsolete and they're removed which means
that all the addresses are subsequently
changed so
when you're monitoring for module
private functions you have to have an
accurate model type and if you want to
attribute it you also have to have an
accurate pdb version as well otherwise
you run the risk of misattributing a
alteration to the wrong address which
can be very problematic so instead of
just having one pdb per module you know
i have to have every version of pdb for
every potential version of that module
which again creates a resource issue
so as such it becomes much more
difficult to detect these private
functions being hooking and there's no
real reliable go-to method for
monitoring these they tend to be context
dependent
the manual manual mapping dependent on
the primary function to target function
also needs to be ascertained the reason
for this is that
different parts will have different
values depending on their security
vulnerability and this needs to be done
unfortunately manually because all the
potential paths can't be mapped
automatically um
and in order to assign resources to
those of the highest value this will
need to be research when you need to be
conducted however because as i said
before this needs to be context focused
you tend to find that this is either
going to be inaccurate due to the lack
of pdb or it's going to be so resource
intensive because of the double linking
issue that it becomes ineffective and
very slow so there tends to be a balance
between the two depending on what is
available
kernel hooking on legacy systems so this
is to do with systems pre-build one
eight nine five zero um post one eight
nine five zero microsoft actually
targeted this particular vulnerability
by uh adapting patch card and removing a
particular kernel variable which was
susceptible to manipulation
now
in order to perform kernel level hooking
you need to use um
a vulnerable kernel driver or an
insecure variable type as we just
mentioned um the insecure variable type
was something that microsoft patched uh
specifically um some of the versions
some of the examples of this are ghost
in the logs or gi gitl by bat tech
infinity hook by everdocs
and kernel driver utility kvu by h
firefox so let's go into how these all
fit together
so
kernel level patching first of all uses
the kernel driver utility or kvu in
order to um
effectively use a vulnerability within
vulnerable kernel drivers to have
ambiguous memory access to kernel space
now the vulnerable drivers are are still
available in windows 10 and kdu does
still work the drivers have not been
removed this is something that's
important to know because what kdu does
is it allows you to write a malicious
kernel driver into kernel space by
basically piggybacking on one of these
vulnerable drivers so in this case a
malicious executable will load a
vulnerable driver and then by using the
vulnerability with the associated cves
which are available it will write a
malicious driver into kernel space and
load it now the malicious driver
will then start to get to work now using
infinity hook the kernel driver the
malicious kernel driver will check the
etw debugger data for a um for the entry
circular kernel context logger and now
this is to do with
um a log an array of loggers which run
within the kernel and they all have
different id values now the circular
logger has an index id too now this is
important because the circular logger
will run as you might guess circularly
on every single um
sys command that's sent to the kernel
and it creates a log for it now by
finding this
entry within the etw debugger data
the
object has a wmi logger context object
attached to it and within this is an
object called get cpu clock which
unfortunately is the type pointer
now once you've found the circular
logger you can overwrite the
get cpu clock uh pointer within the wmy
logo context
in order to point to hooked context now
once the hook is in place what this
effectively means is every time the
logger is called and it tries to grab
the current time it will instead run the
hook content that the malicious driver
has installed
typically this means that the argument
data and the cisco context will be
siphoned off into an evil collector
which will allow them to monitor system
level activity but one of the really
interesting things about infinity hook
is that it actually has the capability
to run
any syscall by
by using this hook capability
and the reason for this is that the
circular logger actually um
runs before the syscall is executed
actually just before so once the hook
has been called
within the logger it can walk up the
stack
find the uh function point of the cisco
that's been targeted and overwrite it
with any cisco the malicious actor wants
and from this they have kernel level
cisco
operational capabilities by using this
hook which is extremely powerful
roasting the log
works in the same way but where the hook
has been implemented it only monitors
one particular
cisco
function for anti-trace event pointer
now when it detects this it instead
diverts
it creates it will divert to um the
hooked function
and the hooked function will determine
against an ioctl or i o control flag
from the user space
whether or not publication to the nt
trace event will occur now this is
important because motion logs allows for
user land control of a kernel level
monitoring element effectively using
ioctl a userland process can ambiguously
decide
um yes generate an event or no i want to
keep this secret and this is important
because what it allows um for the
prevention of
no data detection so whereas with the
previous examples where you can just
prevent etw events from being generated
at all for a process um you can
therefore actually stand for lack of
data um
so if you find that there's a process
running but there are no etw entries
for that process you know that
manipulation or malicious action is
taking place but by using ghost in the
logs you can actually prevent that and
publish the nine events and keep secret
malicious events from a user land
control to a malicious hook that's been
implemented which is uh really really
cool
detection for this again so it's post
windows 7
but it's pre build one eight nine five
zero
and any system between that window is
susceptible to this um this kind of
level hooking
now as we said before first in the logs
relies on the kernel driver a utility or
kdu in order to utilize a vulnerable
driver in order to load its malicious
driver into memory in order to utilize
infinity hooks and then install
its um ioctl based um
etw prevention now but there are some
other
uh
evasion techniques like by pg or by
patchguard which rely on um the kernel
driver being installed via a different
method so kdu can be used but it is not
the inbuilt mechanism so although um
kernel driver installation and service
installation is something that can be
monitored for it won't necessarily use
keu to do that
but because ghost and logs does use kdu
it's quite easy to detect thankfully
the reason for this is that kde relies
on a list of known vulnerable kernel
drivers and services in order to allow
for the ambiguous kernel memory access
this is the full list but the ones in
red are the ones that goshen the log
uses specifically so
now driver rt core 64 gdrv
atscio and msio64
what's interesting to know is that the
intel ethernet debug debug driver tends
to be the go to for
kdu and gi and ghost in the logs um and
it is still present on the most up to
date windows 10 system so it is
something to keep an eye on but by
monitoring for any of these kernel
services being installed or um or ran
you can actually monitor for any of this
activity because these are not run
typically so any interaction with these
services can be seen as malicious and
it's very easy to detect
alternatively at the kernel level by
using a return level driver with
appropriate capabilities you can monitor
for the wmi logger connect
object instance with an entry logger id2
and check the get cpu clock pointer
against a known good um or simply just
check that it um
[Music]
it doesn't point somewhere it's not
supposed to
but by monitoring this you can you can
equally check for infinity hook and
black peachy
so heaven skate hooking for x86 so this
is um heaven's gate is the element that
switches cpu modes between x32 and x64
when you're using wow 64 or for x86
processors
the reason that this occurs is because
if you have an x32 process running on an
x64 host the x64 host obviously only has
an x64 kernel
but if an x32 process decides it needs
to perform a syscall it needs to be
translated to an x64 cpu mode and x64
format before the kernel can handle it
and so because of this all syscalls have
to go through heaven's gate in order to
be translated and switch between cpu
mode x32 or 64
over to the native x64 cpu mode where
the syscall can be handled
and because of this hooking on this
particular element means that you can
monitor all cisco events from an x32
process running while 64 regardless of
what it is
um so instead of being a targeted hook
for particular functions instead you're
hooking every syscall that that process
is
making as you said hooks elsewhere can
be stealthy as we've saw earlier you can
hook on particular functions on
particular exported functions or private
functions
that sort of thing but heavensgate gives
you a
subsystem wide for that process
monitoring of all the cisco's it's gonna
um
go into conduct which allows you to
prevent particular cis calls from
executing you can hijack the information
you can manipulate the information
effectively allows you to do whatever
you want as long as the appropriate
hooking is put in place
so let's have a quick look at exactly
how this works so on an x64 system an
x32 program will say okay i i need to
call a function that's going to perform
a cisco so typically that will go to nt
dll the wow 64 version of nttrl what's
interesting is x32 processors running
while 64 actually have two versions of
ntdl um i won't go into that but first
of all we will call the wow 64 version
the cisco will then need to be
translated and then it will hand off to
wow 64 cpu which will which is where
heaven's gate resides
heaven's gate will then perform what's
called a long jump which is done by a
code segment change from the x 32 wow 64
cpu mode over to the x64 cpu mode wow 64
cpu module
once in x64 cpu mode it will then hand
off to the native
ntdl instance the x64 instance which
will then handle the command running to
the kernel and the cisco will be handled
the response will be then fed back down
the same pipe a long jump will be back
into x 32 back to the nt dll 64 instance
and then back to the x32 process and
that's rudimentary how heaven's gate
works and how while 64 cisco's are
conducted but if you decide if if a hook
is implemented on heaven's date within
wow 64 cpu
all of this becomes compromised
now at this point as soon as the cisco
is handed off from ntdl to r64 in order
to jump cpu modes
um the malicious hook can do anything it
wants it can change the school that's
being implemented siphon the data jump
to malicious code uh ignore the cisco
and just return and not do anything
there are lots of things it can do
but because of this it does mean that if
it doesn't matter which function it's
calling what module it's calling from if
it performs a cisco
it will have to go through wow 64 cpu
and perform and go through heaven's gate
and looking at that gives full control
and full access to all the cisco
operations
so how would we go about detecting this
before i move on to detection it is
worth noting that heaven's gate um in
this instance is done through the
inherent native heavens gate but there
are alternative functions to heaven's
gate where um the long jumper that i've
i've uh mentioned within wow 64 cpu
which constitutes chemistry can actually
be implemented manually in order to
conduct the cpu mode transfer without
going through the native module now this
is a malicious technique that can be
used for
evasion and is something that can be
developed into a system but it isn't
manipulation of existing memory so it's
not something we're going to cover here
it's just something i wanted people to
be aware of that heaven's gate can be
used um by a manual method being
implemented within malicious x32 code on
a wow 64 system
so talking about detection
first thing to know is how do we know
where heaven's gate is how do we know
where we want to monitor well huangburi
actually found this in his research on
wow 64 processes and found that the tib
of well 64 processes actually has a
field filled at offset 0xc0
for fast cisco and this is actually
the exact address of where heaven's gate
is stored relative to that process now
this is interesting because um jeff jeff
chapel
found that in the same office if you
look at his
repository of information but the same
offset is actually wow 32
reserved
now this is interesting because they
obviously correlate to the two but have
um slightly different names either way
in a wow 64 process this offset within
our tib corresponds to heaven's gates
address which allowed you to highlight
from any running process where heaven's
gate is located and where to monitor
so
x86 one of the things to note is that
the gate location is at an offset of
xerox 7000 from wow 64
164 cpu's base address and it is not
changed legitimately the reason for this
is that while 64 is actually loaded at
the initialization stage of all well 64
processes so similar to ntdll although
for very different reasons um while 64
cpu
unless forced will always load in the
same location um
for a running process
and from that you know that the gate
location is going to be the base address
plus the xerox 7000 offset and you can
scan it very confidently
this can be forced
but it is very hard to do and it's not
common
the other thing to note is that x86
processor y64 processors do legitimately
change elements within well 64 cpu as
well
in the example below
you can see that uh the offset is seven
seven three six five thousand so it
tends to be a modification just prior to
where heaven's gate is located but only
modifications to the actual heavens gate
offset which is the one that's in the
box are found to be malicious through
all experimentation so although
modifications may happen elsewhere in
164 cpu only at the offset for heaven's
gate are we are we concerned um to keep
track of
in order to detect this um it's actually
quite simple with the fast cisco
information from the tib the reason is
that heaven's gate is only nine bytes
big now if you have a known good process
you can actually take uh you can
actually you uh collect the tib
find the fast cisco address extract the
nine bytes and use it as a template for
every other process that is running um
you can't as with previous examples use
the file system version the reason for
this is that heaven's date is
dynamically allocated and so the values
in the file system are never going to
correspond to what is within virtual
volatile memory so you can't compare one
to the other you have to have a known
good well 64 process in order to create
a base against
but compare it by comparing only those
nine bytes which as you can imagine is
quite quick allows you to detect any
malicious hook on this particular
element which can be so nefarious
once if a malicious hook is detected you
can therefore look at the memory address
where the hook goes to and analyze its
content by memory dumping or you know
code analysis or anything like that um
and one example of that would be uh
would be this example so the by sequence
is actually in reverse uh in this case
uh the malicious
hook was detected and the uh hook
content was dumped out for analysis one
of the other things to note is that uh
in order for
heaven's gate uh hooking to work
trampoline has to be implemented now a
trampoline is effectively where the
logistima uh heaven's gate code is
stored elsewhere that the malicious uh
hook will know where it's been moved to
and the reason for this is that the
when the legitimate heavens gate win the
heavens gate legitimate location is
called the malicious hook will then be
called which will perform the magistrate
action and then after that it can then
perform the heavens gate cpu road jump
by simply jumping to the trampoline or
wherever the legislative code has been
moved to um just an extra bit of
information but by useless in this
nine-byte check um during
experimentation it was 100 accurate um
and the information produced was um
it gave great um
great data for further analysis
finally let's look at vectored exception
handlers so first of all let's look at
how exceptional handlers work so try
catch code blocks are an example of
exception handlers so effectively a try
catch block is a frame so these code
blocks um
where you have to try code that code is
within the frame of the cache that
you've implemented and what this means
is that
as as programmers should know if an
exception is happens within your try
block and it corresponds to what you
have specified in your catch statement
the exception will be handled by your
catch statement and this effectively
creates a frame
for that exception now the exception can
either be specific or general
now exceptions actually originate from
the cpu
not from the program itself the cpu will
notice the exceptions happened it will
then prompt the colonel um in order to
with relative information which will
create the environment context exception
records and all this sort of stuff which
is then handed back to userland for
handling within the program itself
the kernel determines uh what kind of
exception type it is and what handling
mechanisms are required based on the
data that's issued by the cpu the kernel
does nothing it simply interprets what
the cpu is telling it and then hands it
off to userland to actually handle the
issue um this is typically done through
nt dll in new zealand
let's have a quick look at what this
looks like so after the kernel has
handed back control i won't go into how
the kernel handles the cpu information
and translates it into a trap frame and
then the environment and um exception
records and all that sort of stuff we're
going to look at the user land so once
it's handed back control to um
userland from kernel using an iraq
command the trap frame environment
contacts and exception record are all
available within the user stack but the
trap frame will have an eip which will
trigger the use of ki user exception
handler within ntdl
this will subsequently call rtl dispatch
exception which uses the information
from the environment context and
exception record provided from the
kernel by translating information with
the cpu to know
what frame the exception has occurred
from within which process
and from that it then scans the lowest
frame again provided by the environment
context and starts to check the frames
outwards and effectively what this means
is if the first frame attribute
adequately handles the exception that's
been specified it doesn't need to go any
further but if not it will move out and
out and out and out and out through all
the frames containing it until it will
reach the end of the exception frames or
the exception lists and if it does that
it then turns into a general exception
which normally causes the program to
crash
so
i've been saying um frames and
exceptions but frame based exceptions
are actually what we call structured
exception handlers or seh so a try catch
block is an example of an sch it is a
friend based exception which is very
specific
but whereas with the try catch block
again if you have a try block and a
catch but the catch doesn't check the
exception it will then move to the
surrounding frame to see whether that
can handle the exception and move
further and further out as i just
explained
the sch adds to a chain
so the seh list uh is actually connected
one after the other and it will do it as
again from a
lowest frame and it will start to move
outwards
um if the chain is exhausted it will
move to a general handler which is
normally at a kernel system level which
normally causes the program to crash and
if not the program to crash it can cause
the operating system to crash so it's
not something you want to have haven't
then that hence why exception handling
is is quite important um
well programmed to crash not likely the
kernel depends what you're doing um
but what exactly is a vector exception
handler so vh are not frame specific so
where is sch or um structured exemption
is said are very frame specific vector
exception handlers are the alternative
so instead of being friend specific they
override the priority of seh and have a
high priority and effectively the
exception that is generated from the
kernel within the
exception record will be checked against
the vectored exception handler first
before it moves to the structured
exception handlers
for that process
this was introduced within windows xp
specifically to be able to override the
seh from a developer standpoint so they
instead of having to find a particular
exception frame you could just install a
v8 and it would overwrite the
exceptionalities you had in place but
because of that veh has an inherent
higher priority and will run first and
the way it did this or how uh microsoft
did this was to install rtl cool
vectored exception handlers
within the um exception handler process
within nt dll so rtl dispatch exception
which we just saw handles hands off and
starts to scan through the frames
instead we'll call rtl callback to
exception handlers and scan the vectored
handler list
first now this is very important because
this means that no matter what you do
vector x v h vectors from channels will
always have a higher priority and if an
exception is deception handler is found
for that exception type within the veh
um it will handle the exception
regardless of whether an seh exists
now each handler instance can handle
multiple exception types so whereas the
seh you normally have to have a specific
exception type or a general exception
type veh can handle multiple specific
exception types and it does this by
within the handler
actually do a comparison between what is
inside the exception context against
what is within the vector extension
handler for what it can what it can
handle
um and this is important because vex
exception handlers can handle
vast arrays of exception types depending
on how they're built which can make them
uh quite clunky but equally you can make
them
um very uh sort of like a catch-all
which is quite nice um adding to the
list can be either be done at the front
of the end um at the user discretion so
you can either have the highest priority
or the lowest priority depending on how
you perform the veh but as you can
imagine from a malicious access
standpoint you're going to want to be at
the front of the list so that no matter
what exception comes in your vehicle is
being checked first but what's
interesting is that you can add a veh
on the command just before you know
you're going to do something nefarious
which will cause the exception so you
know your exception handler is going to
be called first
a vh list is circular uh this is
something just to know that effectively
when he reaches the end of the list it
will go back to the start so there has
to be a check against what um vectors
exceptional handler entry id it is so
you know when you've reached another
list and finally the handler function
pointers are encoded using a process
specific cookie
so only by using the process-specific
cookie can you actually find the
handler's uh legitimate pointer address
and find the handler code
so let's look at some of them are just
malicious uses so as we said veh will
always be done first regardless of what
seh is in place and vh can be added at
any point um because of this it can
prevent code integrity checks
specifically with pageguard which i will
show you a great example of in a second
it can perform force jumps this is to do
with how vetted exception handlers are
added to the veh list and it can also
suddenly bypass functions now this is
where um the security
um
malicious memory manipulation is going
to take place and i'm going to give you
a great example of that uh in a minute
so vh can hijack the acceptance change
because it's a higher priority than seh
um and it can need to be done against a
victim process as long as there is
adequate access or it can be done
against a malicious program simply just
to
remove any visibility um by security
vendors by um checking for these uh for
if there is
exception generated behavior
so let's look at code integrity check so
this is actually from a researcher shen
um and they violate the page guard
exception and then effectively use vh to
they install a veh seconds before they
violate the page guard uh page card
which creates a status page guard a
guard page violation exception
but their vh effectively goes
okay that's happened but don't worry
about it
because their veh has a higher priority
um
the program just goes yeah that's fine
the exception's been handled what they
actually do is inside their veh box they
reassert the uh
guard flag of that particular page so
they violate it have the exception
reassert the flag within the exception
handler and then hand back to the
process saying yeah everything was
handled so from that they're able to
basically
um violate pageguard
as they see fit as long as the vehicle
is in place to handle it which is uh
which can get around a lot of integrity
checks which is quite cool
force jump um as i said this is to do
with how effective handlers are added so
add vectors exception handler is the
primary function for adding veh to a
system or a running process
but add vector exception and that
actually only requires a
um handler pointer or just a pointer to
be uh to be uh added as an argument so
from this you can allocate memory with a
bunch of malicious shell code and then
hand it off to a v and then add it as a
veh and then as soon as an exception
comes in as long as you put it at the
front of the queue your shell code is
going to get executed so you effectively
found an exception based shell code
execution mechanism by using veh which
is
pretty cool
sounding bypassing is um the one that
we're really going to look at so veh has
the capability so when a handler
when you when you're generating a vh
handler
it can when it's handing an exception
type
it has two results it can either have
exception continue execution or
exception continue search and what this
means is continue execution means uh the
exception has been handled hand back to
the process continue execution continue
search means my handler wasn't able to
handle the exception generated move to
the next in the list now because of this
if you deliberately generate errors or
you know that an error is going to be
generated
as with the page card you can actually
just say
hey this has happened don't do anything
about it and
move on with the process but equally
what you could do is you could say okay
i know that a function is going to be
called in a second but i don't want to
happen so let's say i did a divide by
zero which we'll call it an exception um
and from that i'm going to change the
function pointer to go just after the
command that i don't want to occur and
then hand back to the running function
and it'll work um from this you're able
to basically jump around
malicious the code that you don't want
to execute or by basically
deliberately triggering uh exceptions as
long as the veh is in place because it
will have a higher priority um which
which is
very very cool
detection of this relies on a number of
things but primarily you need to know
where the veh list is so uh prior work
done by researcher dimitri uh forney um
did some really great work
and he found that the veh list was
actually stored in ntdl and it was under
the pointer ldrp
vector handler list and what he found
was is that by scanning heuristically
for a particular pattern
within a known ntdl function you could
find this pointer and from that you
could extract the list of veh and
enumerate through it um really recommend
reading his work he did some great
examples of this
and a lot of information on how the
heuristics work
but effectively the list is not exported
is not externally available so you have
to do this um
reach into the ntdl systems in order to
find the pointer and extract the list
which is which is a nuisance
the other thing to note is that the
handler point as we said earlier is
actually encoded by the particular
process cookie and in order to decode
this you have to use a combination of
query information process and roto right
64. um ollie whitehouse over at ncc
group did a brilliant um poc on the veh
enumeration where he actually solved all
of these problems and allowed the
handler pointer for x64 uh process
handlers to be decoded and attributed to
their um modules and process spaces uh
again really recommend reading that work
um it really jumpstarted everything uh
it was very impressive do recommend
reading that um
but one of the things that's important
from a vected exception handler
detection standpoint is what exceptions
they are handling so although you can
see when a veh has been generated and
what module they're attributed to that
that that's great but unless you know
what they're doing within the handler or
what exception types they're looking for
um
it's not necessarily going to provide
that much value um
but by checking the exception type you
can actually check for again as the
example at the bottom of the window
shows integer divided by zero so if
you're looking at a divide by zero which
is in a
randomly named process you can say that
this is likely going to be a
vh malicious instance now this can be
done using opcode heuristics by checking
for comparison operators um because all
handlers will have to check the uh
exception context exception type against
a known exception type to see whether it
matches and to know whether it needs to
be handled
which is a really easy way of finding
what exception types are being used and
from this it allows you to do a process
to exception type comparison to see
whether there's a mismatch and this is
especially true about certain debugging
exceptions um which is actually key to a
case i'm going to come to in a second so
when it comes to detection criteria
um pointers outside processor module
space i.e virtual along just anywhere
for shell code pointer to anomalous
module functions so again if there's a
randomly named module and this vh is
pointing to it pretty suspicious um
pointer location has cow in legislative
modern so this is to say
copy on write which is effectively a
page modification a shared library if uh
the process if the va is pointing to a
process specific memory page within a
legitimate module only that page that's
pretty sus and should probably be looked
at to make sure that that particular
function hasn't been hooked um in order
to prevent further malicious action by
basically triggering off from that hook
point to location containing shell code
again this can be done through
memory dumps of the
handler code or just through general
heuristics
an event type handler is unusual again
as i said depending on the process and
the handler type you can actually make
an association between what handler
types are standard off for that process
or equally standard for a system
so the example for um edr bypassing
using beh is firewalker so firewalker
was developed by mdsec back in 2020 um
and it it's a brilliant um poc
effectively what it does is it stands
for
edr hooks on
known functions
um for their telemetry gathering for
security purposes and steps around them
using veh um
it does this by scanning for point point
to duplication or func scanning um and
trap frame single step generation five
registry manipulation i won't go into
those um the second part about trap
frame single step effectively they
manipulate uh one of the registries to
trigger a single step uh exception which
is what triggers their va or malicious
veh into working
which is the bottom example of vh
exception single step handling and
that's where we're going to look
so operation is it creates a vh entry
for the exception type single step sets
the tf flag uh in the registry in order
to make the exception single step
exception uh
uh
because on each individual execution
that's done it then caused the desired
function knowing the single step
exception is going to fire then it uses
the veh to scan each subsequent
inspection to see whether it's a jump
command
or a hook command and if it is it then
scans the memory to see whether there is
a subsequent duplication or basically a
trampoline back to the same code which
would indicate a hook um if it is found
it then replaces that jump with the
trampoline and then it basically jumps
itself back into the adjustment process
without executing the edr's hooked
function so it scans so you create a veh
you trigger it to make these exceptions
on each subsequent command you then run
the process you want and you check to
see whether it jumps to uh it
does a hook or a hook jump and if it
does you then scan to see whether it's
duplicated and if it is you just jump
around it and avoid the edr um telemetry
acquisition altogether um and then after
that you can just remove the veh um
reset the tta flag and continue your
operation
a brilliant a really really really cool
um concept and
although it has its limitations a really
cool con really cool capability
but one of the things about detecting
this is the fact that it uses veh now as
i said earlier the exception types that
are monitored for is one of the things
that can be really easy to detect on so
exception single step outside the use
inside a debugger
yeah that's something that should be
flagged and really easy to basically say
something's not right here and it needs
to be looked at um and as i said the
vehicle type the process nature
easily equals detection uh again if you
have a calculator doing um you know uh
buffer overload exception handling um
but then there's got like three
instances of it or two instances of it
not going to be right especially in the
vh because that should be something that
should be sch so it's something that can
be easily monitored for now people would
say that this could be handled by seh
but again because um
sch could be used instead of the eh in
fire walkers mechanism but because vh
has a high priority and it's easy to
code and it has it's just more dynamic
attackers will tend to use vh over seh
simply because it has it's much easier
to use
one of the final things to know about
veh is the x86 issue uh namely that the
veh4x86 process is stored within the x64
nt dll and as such cannot be accessed by
uh x86 processes which when you're
enumerating them and trying to process
the handler and see what's inside them
makes it very difficult you end up with
this memory access violation where
you're trying to access 64-bit memory
from x86 now this is a physical address
extension issue which can be addressed
through the kernel mmr but it goes
beyond the scope of what i'm going to be
covering today um but it is something
that
um is known to exist and the only way to
do this is to take the physical address
or the virtual address of the x64
translate it to a physical address and
then translate it to a pae of x32 to
then we ran through the x32 handler
or you have to bridge between manually
between x6 actually 2 and x64 cpu modes
in order to validate what is inside the
handler for the x32 process um which is
quite complicated um this is something
that is still ongoing but the best
method that i know of is to use the mmr
within the kernel
so in summary
memory manipulation is it's not it's
never going away it's been here for a
very long time and the capabilities that
are being implemented with the new
they've been introduced by the operating
system iniquity the
um change from tactics to
victim processes to their own processes
is something that shows that they're
always finding new ways to utilize
tweaks inside live memory in order to a
detection or just execute malicious um
malicious commands
but monitoring is always a fine balance
between accuracy and resources ideally
we'd love to monitor every single memory
change and uh be able to 100 and
accurately say you know this is
attributed to this process and these
bytes are going here and all this sort
of stuff but the resources right
required for that are just way too high
so it's always a balancing act between
the two and you have to decide where is
the best place to monitor
finally is the capability to avoid
detection in unrestricted operations
makes this a high value and what this
means is
memory manipulation
provides a window to malicious actors to
effectively size depth detection
multiple ways so it is never something
that they're going to give up on it's
always going to be something they're
going to keep trying and keep finding
new methods for and although the methods
i outlined today are interesting there
are obviously a lot more out there um
and it's best to give you instagram
because this is not going to stop
thank you for listening uh if anyone has
any questions do feel free to email me
at my works email and thank you for
listening