welcome
thanks for joining this session of
bluetooth village project obsidian
incident response and huda loop
my name is julian and i will be your
guide for this walkthrough
it will focus on the udaloop and how to
use it during security incident response
and illustrated by two alert cases of
the same incident
this is part of a multiple walkthrough
around incident response but also
forensic threat intel and various other
aspects of cyber defense we encourage
you to at another session be it in real
life or virtually
one of those is around triage and
scoping for which we will do a very
quick reminder
our agenda will be a quick introduction
the udaloop some key questions for
incident response
or two alert case
a lesson learned and conclusion
for incident response
you will start with the triage on
scoping
this is developed in a different session
but as a reminder the sixth phase of a
security incident are preparation
identification contentment eradication
recovery and lesson learned
and
as a fundamental part
always keep in mind that you should
document document and document what you
are doing be it for your colleague bid
for an auditor it for your management
this is
necessary for any security incident
response
please note also this presentation and
the corresponding notebook will be
available after defcon
let's move to the ooda loop
it's the huda loop has been developed by
us colonel john boyd from the u.s air
force in the 60s following his
experience of co during the korean war
it was initially for dogfight but the
concept is widely applicable
most notably for us to security and see
that
what does uda mean
observe orient
decide and act
it's a quick sequence
of
steps that during a dog fight helps you
to assess the situation and evaluate
where you are what
action you want to take and take the
action
and
it's usually operated multiple times
inside a dogfight to help you
win against your attacker ideally
because you are operating this loop
faster than the attack
it's kind of similar to the dimming
wheel in iso standard the famous plane
do check act but more at the micro level
versus
the macro
level of iso standard
obviously
all the observation
orientation decision
will be based on the context
of outside information of
cultural
information and past experience
whatever has been analyzed during this
event
key question
during an incident what is very
important is identify
what you know and what you don't know
to quote donald trump cells they are
known nouns they are known unknowns and
they are unknown nouns and unknown
unknowns
the usual start
is often is it a false positive is it a
non-legitimate activity
non-testing be it a pen testing or
something else
do we have enough visibility to assess
the situation and at a sufficient
confidence level
that's
very essential to say
we are not making
confirmation be a bias
and
mis-evaluating things because we have
just for example one source of
information
which
would maybe not be reliable
we want to be sure that evidence can be
preserved
to be ensured that your colleague can do
the same assessment or
if things go to court
that court can evaluate the same
situation with the same information
we want to know obviously which users
are impacted
which role and permissions they have
same thing for system
we want to know what stage of the attack
it is and is it live
active versus
the attacker has left and you are only
doing basically the cleaning or
preventing the attacker to come back
how did it start
who or what is the patient zero
the lateral movement occurred do we have
just a single system impacted or are
there many
which data as accurate as access
with some legal impact
and
last but not least what is the business
impact
where the service and availability some
information disclosure or data tempering
move to
an earlier yet
as part of project obsidian
team has simulated
different scenario and kill chain
now we will see
what happens is during an early level of
this attack
we got
a notification
in this case user brent sasham got an
email notification that he logged in the
company jam post but he didn't
in a very good
company member a notified security
you are security what are you doing
so identification phase
i said for the huda loop
we will do some question each question
will result in one or maybe multiple
observations those observations will
orient investigation and result in
decision and action
one quick reminder as a start for any
incident or alert
have a ticket where you will document
things
acknowledge the alert to the user when
it's a manual report and
share the ticket reference
depending on the context you might or
might not share more information
document what's known what's unknown
what's your understanding of
the initial reporting of the alert
it's important
to know that not all users are reporting
things the same way and one user can say
can share a lot of details when another
will give you
my computer is crashing and
you you will have to ask the question to
say yeah okay is it a secret incident
and why
what into you to make a security report
following this documentation and as part
of avoiding any bias
you want to regularly have peer review
first iteration of zeoda loop
from an observation perspective
we
look at the ad authentication log
which show
a password spray attack has happened and
multiple accounts were compromised
we can orient ourselves by reaching out
to it or lds to validate there is no
related activity pen testing testing or
similar that could be associated to this
behavior
after we want to decide do we want to
move to the next phase or to more
identification
let's review how we can do this
authentication
as part of our jupiter notebook
we are using mystic pi library to do a
splunk query
as an example we collect successful and
failed logon
per user account and source ip
if we try to visualize this data we have
a nice
chart on the idiot identification
by user
and
we can see
this line
which is
nearly
always associated with the password
spread
so normally this graph is interactive
inside
um the presentation mode it does not
render as well as we want but
we can change things
let's see
a snapshot of the rendering where we
have more the user but we can see that
all the user of the company basically
has
an attempt to log in
on the chart we don't see if it's failed
or successful
but
if we review another visualization
per ip
user
versus ip
we can
see that
all those logins are coming from
a single ip address which for some
reason i can't
change in the presentation sorry for
that
with all the information it's easier to
say
from the log
i want to get all successful login from
this identified attacker source ip
which
from your
security documentation and or uit
documentation you can confirm if this
source ip is related to your company or
not
in this case we can find that
from a single ip we have five different
users that have login and it's a public
ip so it's likely that the attacker
is using
this as an entry point
just with authentication log we know the
attack vector is a password spread
we have the source ip of the attacker
maybe there is a single one maybe there
is more
and
we have identified there is not just one
account compromise but five
it's important here to have not jumps
again compared to the user report where
if you had actions that directly you
would have only one user
contained or disabled
and
which would not have blocked the
attacker because there were five access
on a few things we don't know
also account privilege
are there any other entry point and
what activity happened after that
for further iteration of the udaloop
we can check if there are
where password reset if some mfa change
happened if some
cloud app token change
we may want to collect more information
be through a vm snapshot or more
granular artifact collection like
process activity network activity or
tolerance
depending on your environment we may
want to add telemetry if it's missing
host agent log collection network
collection like ids ips
and
depending on your assessment of the
incident
notify management
in depending on your company that may
happen earlier that happen later
depends on your process
we won't dig further in this early alert
case because
we will review in the later last case
now moving to the contentment
contentment
should be proportional to the type of
incident and the business impact
you
are unlikely to stop a service that
brings millions of revenue if you have a
small phishing from a nigerian president
and
if you are if the attacker is
exfoliating your customer data or your
company intellectual property it's very
likely that actions should be taken
immediately
those questions should be asking you to
your leadership early on and ideally in
preparation phase not during the
incident
first typical action for contentment
lock disable the affected user account
we may re-evaluate is it enough if it's
not enough
we can decide to content or isolate
compromised system or suspicious one
if email propagation is used we may want
to freeze the mail server queue or
recall or delete some email
that's only a few of the actions that
may happen or may be needed during an
incident
following contentment we are doing
eradication
normally we always want to rebuild
compromised assets because from a
security analyst perspective that's the
only way to ensure that an asset is
clean
sometimes business will decide otherwise
because
the asset is a legacy it can't be
rebuilt or it will take too much time
ultimately that's an executive choice
decision to balance between the risk
after any rebuild you should ensure that
the system is functional and protected
depending on the assessment
we ensure that patch or configuration
has been fixed to ensure it can't be
attacked and we obviously want to be
sure that the business service is
operational
for recovery
we declare return to normal service
validate again that
service are functional normal monitoring
is functional no abnormal behavior
observed for some
grace period
ensure attacker is not coming back
let's move to the letter
we are more at the end stage of the
attack
the previous alert has not happened or
maybe was missed or
misclassified
we have an automated security alert
raised on the company jam post
titled mimikat's execution detection
what are you doing
let's do a quick reminder of what is
mimikabs it's a very popular
security tools that allow to extract
plaintext password hash and value
secrets from memory
and
it can perform various type of attack
including puzzles as the ticket
and
it's very
often
used by attacker as an open source tool
we start again from identification
we talk
about i.t staff or business staff
it's very important that you have a good
documentation between inventory identity
matrix network matrix that will help you
a lot
but
clearly it will never replace helpful
stuff you still want to have
documentations that will
most often
make your work easier and faster
versus trying to wake up the engineering
on call
or wait somebody on a bridge
first iteration of zoodalup again we try
to validate is it a pen test or a
legitimate activity
by iit or buyers some non-user depending
on your company
you may have user
more normal or more abnormal than others
and doing some activity which may
resemble
an attacker
it's
part of the knowledge and the baselines
that you build over time in preparation
of incident
next we confirm that the mimikats
execution is not legitimate
we want to know which credentials were
stolen and are they reusable as is
typically is it end user accounts
service accounts some cloud accounts
if it's local credential versus domain
credential
are the domain admin or are they
standard user
um are there some group policy object
restrictions in place typically to
prevent
the use of a domain admin
outside of certain system
are you using labs which is a microsoft
tool to ensure that
only
each local administrator password will
be unique and this way they can't be
reused to attack another system
we want to know what attacker action
occurred and whether data exfiltration
active or not
let's come back to our notebook and to a
spline query we try to check
the process activity
here two example query with either event
id 4688
native process command line auditing in
windows
or with sysmon
event id1
which is an extra tool but often
recommended by security people
from a visualization perspective when we
build the process tree of the jump pose
we can see various activity
attached to one of the user which is
named
pat resus
sorry
and
you can see that there is a cascade of
activity
that's mostly related to
poor shell but we will see other
activity
more on this screenshot where
you can see some task list call some run
dll32
with the minidump argument
some who am i common
what we know from this process tree we
can say
reconnaissance activity has happened we
we have some umi task list possibly
other command
we have a process memory dump
which is unlikely to be any
time legitimate the who am i your task
is maybe your csi means can be
responsible for it
but doing a process memory dump
very unlikely
and we know that lateral movement
occurred
the cascading of powershell and csc with
a computer list argument
is a result of postploit invokport scan
the csc is because powershell is
calling a command let which is using
c-sharp and as such each call is
resulting in a csc
children process
that
will
do this
live compilation
of the blog
one thing that we
don't know or we don't see in
this process three
was
mimi cats
or some ps exec that
you you can be in in the foreign
there are there can be various reasons
but
one thing obviously the data can has
been tempered by the attacker
or inadvertently it can be a wrong
filter by the analyst it can be a
software bug or configuration is
issue
that's one reason you want to have
multiple data source and validate they
all
goes into the same direction
if we review another log we have
identified that
the activity is occurring on the rdp jam
post
sick was deployed in this environment we
can try to filter
some of the activity
either
by some top dns
list top 1 million top
10 000
and say
what are the domain left
from some filtering action we can
identify those domains interactsh.com
file pizza financial magnum
campusfinancial.com
webwormhold.io transfer.sh
what we know
likely the attacker has done an
excitation or maybe he's on
doing it currently depending on on your
timeline
the only case and that's where it's
important to know your company context
is maybe there is a legitimate
legitimate business use case
but
usually
it will be for one series
seeing four different service
is
less likely to be legitimate
we also have seen some typo requests on
company domain magnum tempus financial
which suggests that the attacker was
doing a manual execution
sometimes it can be also
a way to mislead the analyst by the
attacker
but at least as a first appreciation
that seems the attacker was doing things
manually not an automated or at least
not a fully automated data
you can review the forensic station
walkthrough for more
on containment
depending on the pace of your
investigation you may stop the attacker
before during data exfiltration before
data destruction and log wiping
again
we want to lock or disable affected user
account
we may also want to restrict network
access bit by domain ip address to block
command control
access or to prevent exfiltration of
data
that will depend a lot of what are
the options available in your company
if for example you have a proxy or only
an ids
if you
are arriving very late during the
incident and
you already observed that
we are on a stage where the attacker is
doing event log clearing
on many servers including domain
controller
which means that they basically own most
of your network
it's time if not already to escalate to
crisis team
this will usually include someone from
each executive branch legal
communication hr
potentially more
if you have not already done so but
hopefully it is done in formula
management
we may want to unplug from the network
or shutdown impactor system
unplugging from network is usually
preferred as it will help to preserve
evidence most notably in memory
but it will depend a lot again on your
context and what can you do especially
in a re
remote setup
in worst case
more global network shutdown typically
at office or data center level maybe
something needed
you want to switch to out-of-band
communication
usually if an attacker has control on
your domain controllers that means they
also have control on
your exchange or mail system your chat
system likely
you want to involve external partner
your insurance
your external returner which may be
required or recommended by your
insurance
law enforcement
information sharing and analytics center
okay isac
and nationals or sector cert
those last two are
very important because they help
structure your the sharing of
information and
eventually share things in a way which
are not
liable for you and
share this information in a way which is
not
necessarily identifiable
it's important that you can help that if
other
companies have made similar threats you
can get more input to react faster
typically to
to do the containment or to um
know that this threat actor
is
respecting
their
engagement when you pay them or they are
not respecting though
you want to validate your backup
normally that's an early recovery step
but
especially in a ransomware case it can
influence contentment meaning results
should be non-only early if your
attacker has destroyed your backup or if
your backup are corrupt or i've never
been tested
you probably have no backup and as a
result you probably
want to make more care on
protecting system preservative evidence
keep a copy of encrypted data if maybe a
decryptor is found maybe in a month
maybe in a year or whatever
ultimately a very hard decision in a
ransomware case is
do you want or not pay around somewhere
that's a very trolley problem or
cornelian
that you should think carefully and
discuss with relevant parties
there is no right answer from a security
or law enforcement perspective the
recommendation will be always
not pay
but obviously
if
your company's life is a stake
that's a harder call especially if you
are at risk to finance terrorism or
cyber criminal
you also want to monitor internet
the different various media and forum to
ensure that
your incident
is not leaked too early and that you
have time to prepare
communication
eradication phase
we want
like previously we built assets but
in ransomware case
you have
probably a very high number of system
impacted and
first you need if you have not already
prepared it
establish a priority for service
recovery what should be repaired first
is it your business system your payroll
system your active directory whatever
else
ideally that's come from your disaster
recovery plan or business continuity
plan and it's done
before any incident
but if it's not the case that's your
first step
after rebuilding assets
next like in the pre previous case we
want to validate system are functional
and protected we don't want the attacker
to come back
recovery
stem done previously return to normal
service validity
finally the lesson learned
you should have a final communication
to close an incident
and it should
either include or be followed
by the incident report
this should include executive summary
key findings with recommendation
what went good what can we improve
a high level timeline
depending on your organization alignment
with miter attack miter shield
nist sp 853 or iso 27
may be good addition
and part of all recommendations should
feed your org risk register and be
visible to
decision maker and executive
you don't want to let an incident and
use
each incident is an opportunity for
improvement if you are not using it you
leave the door open to an attacker it
could be the same one or it could be
another one
more will be developed in the final
reporting walkthrough
as a conclusion
security incident response is very often
a marathon
you need to take care of your team and
yourself plans for overload plans for
helper be it internal or external
preparation is key
establishing process
trust and collaboration take time train
early train like you fight and fight
like you train
re-evaluate situation often during an
incident
if you have better situational awareness
than the attacker the better know
yourself know your enemy and you can
fight 100 basel without disaster
udalup is one method
to structure this
last make it easier for you and your
team structure and automate
the work so decision can be taken better
and faster
jupiter notebook is one way to structure
to automate things and it helps to
document and show the reasoning of
investigation and avoid bias
this is the end of this walkthrough
thanks a lot for attending it
i also want to thanks all the
contributors to
blog team village project obsidian and
to project jupiter notebook panda mystic
pie open source research
enjoy blue team village and defcon be
virtually or in real life
thanks to you and
join the conversation on
all discord