hello thank you all for joining us at
another wonderful car hiking village
courtesy of defcon 30 recovery mode my
name is kamel and today i'm going to be
talking a little bit about bluetooth and
the rf com protocol in particular and
why you should consider it next time you
go on a car hacking adventure
before you just get started i just want
to give a quick basic disclaimer all the
views shared in this presentation are my
own and do not represent the views of my
employer or any other third parties
uh of course gotta get that out of the
way so starting off uh with a very
simple who am i uh so i'm an automotive
cyber security technology architect at
white motion which is a subsidiary of
the international automotive tier 1
supplier morelli
white motion is a special team within
morelli that specializes in automotive
cyber security carrying out penetration
tests for our parent company and
external companies alike
and contributing to the automotive
security industry overall by providing
car hacking training and legislation or
standards compliance
i'm an active member of the automotive
security research group or asrg
and i love participating in car hacking
communities so on and so forth even
outside of my professional duties so i
volunteer a little bit here and there
among my recent areas of interest when
it comes to security work uh we've got
you know bluetooth which i'll be talking
a little bit about today the usb
protocol general rf stuff and reverse
engineering the firmware update process
for some really obscure taiwanese
microcontrollers but thankfully that's
over i don't have to do that anymore
but besides the technical stuff and
outside the office or garage i suppose
i enjoy playing fighting games and
cooking and i also love exploring new
places so whenever i get the chance to
go somewhere i always make sure i get
lost once or twice before i go home
so
let's go over uh very briefly the table
of contents for today's talk so i'd like
to say that the overall objective of the
talk is
isn't only to talk about the rfcom
protocol to say but to familiarize you
with the complexity of the bluetooth
specification as a technology and
highlight how many different ways it can
be viewed from a security perspective
to that effect i'm going to start off
with a short recap of what exactly
bluetooth is including a look at how
it's used in vehicles and talk a little
bit about some scenarios or cases very
very short case studies where bluetooth
has been used
uh to target vehicles in the past from a
security perspective so we'll look over
some some past research by other
individuals not myself
that have been more or less
prominent parts of bluetooth's history
in the automotive security landscape
after that we're gonna take a closer
look at the star of the show the rfcom
protocol and then i'm going to introduce
a very simple tool that i made called
the rf comrade that you might be able to
use yourself on your own rfcom testing
in the future
and finally i'm going to talk a little
bit about the bluetooth ctf that we'll
be featuring at the car hacking village
this year at defcon
excuse me just a disclaimer i haven't
hidden any flags in the presentation
itself so don't feel like you'll be
missing out on anything if you're not
like paying super close attention and
taking notes on everything screenshoting
every every every slide that there won't
be anything like that so feel free to
just relax and and enjoy the talk right
so
let's get started
so you probably already know what
bluetooth is entirely independently of
any technical understanding of how it
works and that should be a testament to
how widely used it is and that's really
great you know all end user technologies
should be easy to use even if you don't
understand the technical details behind
them and bluetooth is pretty widely used
uh to that effect
it's in your phone it's in your
headphones maybe it's in your fridge
your microwave
probably not your microwave
maybe your coffee maker and it's almost
certainly in your car
but what exactly is bluetooth so
the official definition is that
bluetooth is a common cable replacement
technology right found in virtually all
smartphones computers and many wireless
iot accessory devices worldwide
it is
designed to simplify short-range
wireless communications by providing a
uniform framework for connecting devices
to one another
it operates in the 2.4 gigahertz
frequency range which is the same as
wi-fi and as a result you will get a lot
of wi-fi chips that are actually bundled
together with bluetooth functionality
just because they can use the same
uh radio frequency band
but of course like we mentioned you know
bluetooth is used in a lot of devices
wireless headphones medical equipment
sensors interactive lighting you know
even used for basic data transfers
between devices you can do
file transfer protocol over bluetooth or
so on and so forth we'll see a little
bit more about that later
and then since bluetooth low energy came
out especially it's been very popular
with
things that you would set up in a
outside environment something like a
like an environmental temperature sensor
or
a humidity sensor that needs to stay on
for long periods of time maybe doesn't
have access to direct power supply but
runs on a battery and you want to save
power over long periods of time that's
when things like bluetooth low energy
come into play and are very helpful
and you know obviously you know as we
mentioned
bluetooth is pretty common in cars today
if it wasn't i wouldn't be giving this
presentation here i'd be trying to give
it somewhere else
but in a vehicle bluetooth is usually
used by the infotainment system or the
head unit or whatever you want to call
it right the thing that has all the cool
flashy buttons that you can play with
and play your music through
bluetooth is used primarily originally
in cars for making hands-free phone
calls so while you're driving the car
you can answer answer a phone call and
play it through your your car's speakers
and microphone
and it's also used to import your phone
book from a phone for quality of life
you can see you know have all your
contacts listed so you can know who's
calling you
and some cars will actually even let you
import your entire text message history
uh so you can have all your text
messages stored on your car so you can
go back and look through them through
your car's console
i've even seen some phones that are
excuse me some vehicles that through a
bluetooth connection can actually let
your phone send out a text message right
so essentially you know if i'm driving
obviously i'm driving i'm not trying to
answer a phone call if i don't have the
opportunity you know if it's especially
if i'm going you know down the highway
or something i can push a button that
will tell my phone to respond to the the
caller with a text message saying sorry
i can't pick up i'm driving right now
and so it's it's you can get very
creative with how this uh seemingly
simple
application you know just an extension
of your phone can actually be used right
uh more recently though bluetooth and
bluetooth low energy or ble have been
used for more advanced functions in cars
so ranging from things like updating the
firmware on key fobs there's been some
research on the tesla key fobs in there
from our updating process over bluetooth
uh to things like passive keyless entry
systems and
excuse me we'll look at a case where
this was a a big target for a security
research group in just a second
but before we go into the full technical
details like i said i do want to go over
some of the more notable pieces of
research that have come out regarding
bluetooth security and vehicles over the
last few years so i've got two i'm not
going to talk too extensively about i'm
just going to kind of run through them
real quick these are very
uh
well thought out research
pieces and i definitely recommend you go
and find the original source material by
whoever published them to get the full
details on what exactly they were doing
but i'll just be quickly summarizing uh
for for the sake of this talk
so the first example i want to touch on
is some research disclosed by tencent
keen labs in 2020 so the researchers at
keene were able to fully compromise the
head unit of a lexus vehicle by using
bluetooth of a bluetooth vulnerability
as the initial compromise vector right
so the
first thing they were able to do is
exploit the bluetooth stack on the
vehicle to get some remote code
execution and from there they were then
able to you know expand their reach of
influence throughout the vehicle's
infotainment system to establish a wi-fi
based backdoor
the reason for this was wi-fi is
generally you know a longer range
technology than bluetooth so this gave
them the ability to
get their
reverse shell as you might say on the
car from a farther away range and then
they could continue their their
exploration of the vehicle at that point
uh so they had set up a essentially you
know some persistence in the vehicle
where when it booted up it would
actually phone home it would actually
connect back to the researchers pc and
they could then open a shell and
continue exploration and exploitation
so
due to the fact that there were no
firmware checks in place to prevent
anyone from
you know flashing unauthorized firmware
to other parts of this infotainment
system
the researchers were actually able to
flash other components inside that unit
and essentially unlock can bus access
the can bus was obviously available on
the device however it was intended to be
kind of filtered or locked off so that
you couldn't just send and receive
arbitrary messages at your whims but
because of the ability to rewrite the
firmware due to the lack of firmware
checks they're actually able to bypass
this and they were able to kind of
expand their reach a bit further at this
point there are further possibilities to
pivot within the vehicle system
for example using diagnostics to
potentially reprogram other parts of the
car but the researchers didn't quite go
that far in the publication they
released of course uh this will be
linked in the references section at the
end you're free to
encourage to read up their full write-up
it is incredibly educational and i think
anybody uh could benefit from giving it
a look
the last attack i want to talk about is
much more a little bit more recent uh
this came out earlier this year in may
of 2022. so this was some research that
was disclosed by the ncc group after
they found out that the passive keyless
entry system used in tesla models 3 and
models y i believe are susceptible to
relay attacks right
so a relay attack
is not something new to vehicles right
the idea that you can pass the
signal from a key fob on to a car and
unlock it without having the key fob
within the intended range
is is kind of a theoretical attack
that's existed for a while but these
researchers were able to perform this
over bluetooth low energy
so the challenge to getting the attack
to work on the tesla's pke system was
that the key exchange had to be done
within a given time frame there's like a
timeout in place that's designed to
kind of prevent against this kind of
relay attack because the communications
have to happen there's cryptographic
information exchanged and the idea is is
that all right if there's someone
sitting in between these two devices the
actual car
and the um
and the intended user's key right their
phone
the added latency of passing the
information between several devices uh
may you know exceed that minimum time
frame that you have to actually perform
these operations and would make it much
harder but uh
the
researchers were actually able to figure
out a way to do that they would use one
cell phone to kind of go near the target
human being right the person with the
actual phone to unlock the car they
could then sniff this uh bluetooth low
energy signal
over the air and then pass it through
over the internet like an ip network
just like anything else uh to another
phone that was close to the car
and they could actually perform these
cryptographic chain checks uh over the
internet and this you know very close
range communication between the the two
attacker cell phones in a time frame
that allowed them to bypass
the uh latency bounding in place so this
essentially gave them the ability to
unlock the car and then the car thinks
well i've got the key inside me i should
unlock all functionality
and well the next step obviously is
going to be uh
a room room right so you can break off
with the car and all of a sudden you
know you come back from your shopping
trip and your car is missing and what
happened right so again uh the link to
the actual publication for this research
will be in the references section at the
end so i encourage you to go ahead and
give it a full look
so the next part is going to be the
bluetooth breakdown i'm going to give a
brief brief explanation of how the
different protocols that make up
bluetooth work so
this uh picture is pretty ugly so bear
with me for one moment um and it
represents
a visual representation of some of the
different protocols
that make up what we know as bluetooth
and this is important because you know
the way i see it bluetooth is not one
protocol it's a bunch of smaller
protocols
standing on one another's shoulders all
wearing a big a big coat right
pretending to be just a one-on-one
protocol
but it's actually a technology standard
for short-range wireless communication
and each of these sub-protocols has its
own specification
and
the all of these you know
of of which are managed by the bluetooth
special interest group or the bluetooth
sig as is easier to call it uh so this
is a group of companies and
representatives of these companies that
manage the bluetooth specification make
edits to it manage security bulletins
etc so on and so forth and the
specification itself is you can actually
read it for free it's available online
um but while the specification itself is
managed by the bluetooth sig the actual
implementations of these are not right
so this is this
the source of one level of bluetooth's
complexity as a protocol right each of
these protocols can be implemented
differently and many of these protocols
are implemented on the chip the
controller they're entirely invisible
to the end user and so it sometimes
makes them hard to analyze from a
security perspective maybe this will
give you a better idea of what i'm
talking about
so
hopefully things look a little bit nicer
now
uh you can see here let me pull up the
laser pointer uh we have
the
bottom part here which is the red
protocols these are what we call the
controller layer protocols then up here
on top you have the the bluish ones
these are the host layer protocols right
so the lower layer represents the
protocols that are controlled by the
actual controller this means that these
functions are controlled by the firmware
on the bluetooth chip itself
and the operating system that's using
this bluetooth chip
has close to no visibility into what's
going on down there
this is why low-level protocols such as
the hardware focus baseband and radio
layers operate
uh and as well as the link management
protocol have such a bit of a like a
mystery around them because it's not
easy to see what they're doing right
because the firmware will be implemented
differently based on uh different uh
vendors of these chips right
because there are so many manufacturers
each of their own unique compositions
sometimes different architectures they
use
special you know commands we'll talk
about hci in a second it can be quite
complicated if you wanted to like first
engineer these for example
also some companies you know example
companies that make uh bluetooth chips
you've got broadcom you got qualcomm
cambridge intel these are all
different manufacturers you could find
uh that have implemented their own you
know
version of the bluetooth specification
on this chip right and the middle layer
here this purple one because you know
it's a mix of like the blue and the red
uh is the host controller interface
layer this is the protocol that's used
to allow the host to communicate with
the controller there is some
standardization around how hci commands
are implemented but there can also be
vendor-specific instructions based on
the vendor of the bluetooth chip again a
lot of the stuff is going to be
different from under defender which is
another one of the reasons a little bit
complicated
if you've ever used bluetooth with linux
before for example you know you might
google okay how to use bluetooth on
linux and one of the first commands
they'll tell you to run is hci config
and that's a pretty standard linux
bluetooth tool and it stands for you
know host controller interface
configuration this will give you
information about the bluetooth
controller that you're using right any
bluetooth controllers that are
registered on your system you can see
information about them with this command
right another one is hci tool a couple
of really useful tools implemented with
the hci protocol right to read or write
information on your bluetooth controller
run scans lots of things you can do with
it
these tools work by sending standardized
messages from the operating system to
the controller to which the controller
will say oh you're asking for this piece
of data okay let me get that for you and
then it'll feed it back up to the
operating system
and then finally the protocols on the
top half of the screen are what we call
the host layer protocols these are
controlled by your operating system
right so the host in this kind of
equation is is your computer your
operating system and the controller is
the chip running the the firmware
implemented by the vendor right
depending on the system you're using
they'll be implemented a little bit
differently so for example there is the
blue z stack right blue z is the
official bluetooth stack for linux uh
but it's not the only one that that
being said
uh it's used so
widely that
you'd have to have a really specific you
know use case to bother with um coming
up with your own bluetooth stack for
linux environment and it's not seen very
commonly so
it's not a an exaggeration to say blue z
is on like you know 98 plus of linux
systems that run bluetooth in the first
place so
yeah bluesy is great and then i'll talk
a little bit more about that in a bit
but in the host protocol pool
we find the logical link control and
adaptation protocol i'm not going to say
this acronym again because l2 cap is
just much easier to say
this is the base protocol in the host
protocol pool side and everything else
is more or less built on top of it
this is because you know alt2 cap is
developed to be a generic multiplexing
layer of the host protocol stack it
receives information from the higher up
protocols
and then
passes them on through to the hci the
host controller interface which then
processes the information to be sent
to the controller side of things right
so a look at some of the different
protocols we have here very briefly
we have on the right we have the sdp
right the service discovery protocol
sdp is used to allow bluetooth devices
to learn more about one another someone
two devices connect they kind of ask
each other all right so what can you do
you know oh you're you're a phone book
server well i'm a phone book client i
might ask you for some contacts right oh
you can play audio well let me see if i
can you know stream some audio through
you this communication and establishment
of what devices are capable of is done
through sdp
right so it's a very important part of
bluetooth communication because it'll
also give you
uh information about oh this service i'm
interested in this which rfcom channel
is it using and we'll talk about our com
channels in a bit because that's kind of
what this talk is about but again this
all ties back to
sdp interestingly enough stp is always
unencrypted it's just supposed to be
freely available and you can usually
query any bluetooth device for sdp
information so no matter like what the
security settings on your bluetooth
device are sdp will usually be
you know just unencrypted communication
because it's not supposed to be secret
you're supposed to share it with anyone
that asks right interestingly enough um
but and then rfcom as you can see here
on the left of this of the screen has a
lot of different applications or
protocols built on top of it you have
things like point-to-point which you
know can can go into things like ip and
tcp so you get like your basic you know
traditional networking architecture
built through bluetooth and then you
know on top of rfcom
you have serial port profile this is the
the spp one right here you've got pbab
this is the phone book access profile
you have object exchange or obex vcard
ftp we'll talk a little bit more about
these um
a little bit more detail but there's a
lot of stuff that can be built on rfcom
because rfcom is built to be very
flexible
so let's give it a quick look rfcom is
designed to emulate an rs-232 serial
port over the l2 cap protocol as
literally as possible it actually
includes features to emulate all nine
pins of an rs-232 serial port which is
really interesting
and
this is true to the extent that the
rfcom protocol
actually specifies this
outright so if you open up the rfcom
protocol you'll see in like the
introduction section
it'll actually say
this document does not contain a
complete specification instead
references are made to the relevant
parts of the gsm 07.10 standard so they
really just telling you like we just
wanted to make you know
gsm 7.10 uh serial ports available
over over wireless communications so
rfcom is literally you know a radio
frequency com port is kind of what they
designed it uh to be
so
um it was designed to allow devices that
already had rs-232 capability to be
easily ported to wireless applications
by simplifying the process of adding a
wireless network interface you didn't
have to change all that much you could
just you know
readjust which interface it's talking to
and the rfcom
channel would take all the information
that would be sent to a regular serial
port and move that
over the you know the unguided medium
that is the wireless communication and
that 2.4 gigahertz uh frequency band
right
so in a practical sense though right the
practicality of rfcom right don't worry
too much about the specification yet
that's if you want to read it it'll be
linked in the end right but
um rfcom channels work pretty similarly
to tcp ports so
like tcp rfcom provides some basic
guarantees for reliability uh and it's a
point-to-point connection you know
communication uh
style right the contrast to this would
be something like l2 cap and udp uh
where udp is usually you know considered
connectionless uh but you know l2 cap
can be connection based or
connectionless it actually supports both
both types um rfcom has way fewer ports
available
you know they work like ports but we
call them channels i'm not the one who
came up with this right it's just the
way it is excuse me
but uh whereas tcp has you know like 65
000 different ports rfcom only supports
30 channels the specification states
that up to 60 simultaneous connections
between two devices are possible but
with only 30 ports to work with you need
to kind of be careful when you allocate
rfcom channels to your applications so
when you're writing an application you
might say all right specify to use
this rfcom channel or
random first available rfcom channel
these are both options you can use
and just you know may want to keep in
mind how many you have left when you're
writing bluetooth applications um i've
linked both here and later in my
references of course you can see the
link here uh an old it's it's pretty
dated it's like i think from like 2000
like the early 2000s like before 2010
it's a guide it's a very helpful guide
to programming with bluesy uh you may
remember i mentioned blue z is the linux
stack uh for for the bluetooth stack for
linux excuse me
um but
it is a little bit dated but it's a
great introduction to programming with
bluetooth and i would suggest anyone
looking to make their own bluetooth
applications either for testing purposes
or just to learn more about how the
protocols work so you can give it a look
right but just take it with a grain of
salt it is quite old so you might have
to change things to fit you know more
modern you know python packages or
versions uh that are available right
but then one final you know useful
parallel between rfcom and tcp
is that much how you might use nmap or
something to
do a port scan right kind of see what
services are running on a device over
the ip network
excuse me you can use the sdp right
service discovery protocol to
do more or less the same thing over
bluetooth and this is an rfcom specific
uh this is more of a bluetooth thing
overall but let's take a look here
so so since the service discovery
protocol is designed to let the
bluetooth devices understand the
capabilities of the other remote devices
it makes sense that there would be you
know a way to see right ask a device hey
what do you do
how can we communicate let's find
something we can do together
sdp tool for example is a basic linux
tool
that allows you to browse the sdp
servers of remote bluetooth devices it
can do a lot more but browsing is kind
of the easiest way to use it for
starting off it lets you add services to
your own devices as well for example or
you can
you know search for a specific
bluetooth service on a target device if
you have something in mind right
shown here on the right is part of the
output from sdp tool when browsing on my
samsung galaxy phone i use my own
personal device for this i didn't want
to get in trouble by posting some some
customers stp tool outputs right that
would that would that would be bad
um but you can see here that there are a
couple of applications running on my
phone that are tied to rfcom channels
with information on the type of
application and which rfcom channel is
in use
so for example on phones obviously phone
book access is something you would
expect to see because my phone is used
to sharing my contact book if i if i if
i wanted to i usually don't but
when you connect to a car you can import
your contacts to the vehicle right so
that you have access to your whole phone
book you can use caller ids and so forth
obex right i talked about object
exchange earlier
obex is a communication protocol used
for sharing files between devices and a
lot of like the things like the ftp and
the phone book access sometimes are
built on top of obex right
interestingly obex was originally
developed for infrared communications
right and it's actually managed
by the infrared data association but
it's just kind of been adopted by the
bluetooth sig and it's just you know
very common to find
obex in in bluetooth devices to the
point where you would a lot of people
assume opex is initially made for
bluetooth when it's actually in you know
it was originally made for uh the
infrared stuff
and then like i said things like ftp and
phonebook access
can be built on top of obex but they
don't necessarily have to be right this
goes back to the idea that a bunch of
pieces to bluetooth and you can kind of
with some degree of flexibility you know
assemble them however you like right
so uh just kind of like visualize this
you know with a very simple example
let's just say you have you know an ip
network two devices connected to the
same ip network you can see we've got ip
addresses associated on the left we have
a host user you know a computer
right side we've got a server or
something maybe they're running a some
ftp service on port 21. well when you
want to use this service you would
address the server you want to talk to
by its ip address and you'd specify the
port on that server that you want to
communicate with right in this case you
know we know the standard socket
notation is shown up here we've got the
ip address colon port number right
pretty simple
similarly when using bluetooth you would
address the device you wish to use
uh you wish to talk to with the rfcom
channel that it's using uh for that
particular service i've got two dummy ip
or bluetooth addresses here please don't
look these up they're not going to give
you any interesting results of course
it's one two three four five six seven
eight a b c d f g
right um but one thing i would like to
know is the convention i'm using here by
the way uh you can see here you have the
bluetooth address and then you have the
rfcom channel this is by no means like a
standard convention for
kind of displaying a bluetooth socket
per se i just
wrote it like this so so if
this is not this is not there's no
standard here for
like like you would have in the ip
network for like a common way to
designate a socket we don't have that
i i just kind of came up with it but it
more or less works almost the same way
and so you could have a similar service
running over bluetooth and likewise
you'd communicate targeting that
bluetooth address and the rfcom channel
that is hosting that the uh the target
host is tied to
that application right
and lastly you know before we move on i
just wanted to share that uh the rfcom
specification
has not been updated since november of
2012. and maybe that's a testament to
how well um put together it is that it
has received you know no updates in the
last 10 years
um
but i always find it interesting to see
something that's still so widely used
everywhere you know in different
industries not just cars like i said
medical
you know other iot industries hasn't
changed at all in the last 10 years and
granted it is an underlying transport
layer protocol so it doesn't
maybe doesn't get that much attention
but it's always worth you know poking
through the specifications seeing if you
can find anything you might be able to
use or reviews
but anyway on to the next part of the
talk i'm going to introduce rf comrade
so what exactly is rf comrade so
rf comrade is a tool to assist in the
testing of rfcom protocol on remote
bluetooth devices i built it in python
and it uses the pi blue z library which
makes it very easy to get set up on any
linux system pi blue z is a python
implementation
of the bluesy
software stack for linux
its main feature is the ability to
connect to an rfcom channel on a remote
device and basically flood it with a
user defined payload you set up a
payload you say hey
i want to target that rfcom channel on
that bluetooth device i just want to
hammer it with as much data as possible
it's very very simple it's not it's it's
nothing like uh like a guided fuzzer or
anything i'm hoping to to improve it in
the future but what i started with was
just a basic flooding attack
excuse me
um but you know it can essentially work
as a dos attack or a denial of service
on devices that don't have fail safes in
place to deal with volumes of large data
large volumes of data
than they're then they're prepared to
expect right if the rfcom channels in
use on the target are not known there's
also a basic service discovery feature i
added to the tool that will actually you
can say okay i know the bluetooth
address but i didn't run stp tool i
didn't feel like browsing it
if you just run it with a bluetooth
address and no rfcom ports specified
it'll actually return to you which rf
com ports are you know up on the machine
that you're targeting and some
information on what applications are
tied to them
so the why would i make this dual so the
motivation for putting this tool
together is as often as it is is because
i couldn't find another way to do the
same thing with someone else's tool i'm
not a very good programmer i i'm not a
developer i don't particularly like the
program so i try to avoid it when i can
but sometimes you know
you you force your hand right so during
a penetration test of an automotive
navigation unit we wanted to test the
device's bluetooth implementation and
its resilience against receiving large
amounts of unexpected data this isn't
the only test we performed retarding the
bluetooth
technology on the device but we wanted
to test it from a bunch of different
perspectives so it made sense to do just
some you know brute forcing of the data
flooding
and after doing some research we found
that this kind of remote flooding test
has been done in the past but the only
publicly available tools i could find
weren't
exactly what i was hoping to find some
older tools like l2 ping for example
which is usually installed with blue z
by default
only works with the l2 cap layer and it
doesn't provide a lot of flexibility
on the content of the data that you send
it's just it'll send pings and you can
you know enable it to flood the opponent
opponent
excuse me remote target device uh with
data
but you can't exactly control the
contents of the payload you really can't
do much
about that and because it is only you
know targeted at the l2 cap protocol i
felt there might be some benefit in in
targeting other protocols on the device
and then there are other tools such as a
tool called a bluetooth stack smasher
that allows you to fuzz a remote
bluetooth device with random data
but again this one also only targets the
l2 cap protocol and it doesn't have the
features you would like in a modern
protocol fuzzer so
it wasn't quite what i was hoping to
find
you're welcome to give it a shot if you
like though it's freely available on the
internet um there isn't much control
over what data gets sent and when and
sometimes recreating crashes or other
issues can be difficult i found
so we wanted a tool that could interact
more directly with the rfcom channels
themselves and the applications
operating behind them so uh i used the
pi blue z library to cook up a simple
script that would let us connect for
remote targets rfcom channels and just
toss a bunch of data at it right just
like i explained
the idea was we could identify any
applications that were tied to rfcom
channels that weren't set up to handle
large volumes of random data and might
you know be able to invoke a crash of
the bluetooth stack see how the target
device responds excuse me i'm gonna take
a quick
water break
sorry about that all right let's go on
almost done
uh and so did it work all right that's
the next obvious question and to my
surprise yeah it kind of did
i was able to reliably crash the
bluetooth stack on a target device by
connecting to one of the services hosted
on the rfcom channel
and flooding it with a very simple
payload right just
i just i didn't want to do anything
complicated just wanted to test it out
uh for about five seconds
and i was able to confirm this because
the target device would actually display
an error message saying oh
bluetooth
stack
or started like the bluetooth function
had essentially just entirely crashed
and then
had to boot up again from zero
so any devices that were already
connected to the target over bluetooth
say my cell phone or another target you
know testing device i would be
disconnected and whatever bluetooth
operations they were carrying out at
that time would be interrupted
an analysis of the application connected
afterwards by
by us revealed that the function wasn't
properly handling the large volume
unexpected inputs and it actually
resulted in a buffer overflow that would
cause uh the the pro the application
running on that rfcom channel to crash
and it ended up you know causing the
bluetooth stack to have to restart
there's potential here for a a further
exploitation of the application right if
you have a crafted payload if you
actually reverse engineer the firmware
running on the device find out how you
can you know further compromise this
target there's a lot of potential for
for more uh wrong doing uh in the place
here so
we didn't really feel we need to go that
far but
maybe someday i will take another look
at it but i felt that since the dual sid
did something kind of useful others
might find some benefit from having
access to it and that's what motivated
me to apply this uh this little tool of
mine to the call for papers here at
defcon
and just keep in mind at the end of the
day it is just a very simple python
script like i said i'm not a very i'm
not a very good programmer so
forgive me if it looks really ugly like
why didn't you do this why didn't you do
that i did my best right
so
you know
even my own little efforts might be uh
helpful to somebody somewhere out there
because
and you know even outside of the
automotive industry
because bluetooth is by no means an
automotive specific technology there's a
lot of
excuse me
a lot of other devices out there that
maybe could use a good rattling right so
uh where it's publicly available you can
find it here at this github link go
ahead and download it give it a shot see
if you like it if you don't like it
criticisms comments etc
always welcome uh i i do hope on making
improvements to it in the future
actually so as with any project you know
i want to take it somewhere higher maybe
improve on it
uh so the first step to that is
hopefully to add meaningful
fuzzing
um how should i say
fuzzing capability and i want to
increase the scope to other protocols
too obviously we can't call other
protocol fuzzers or flutters rf comrade
because they're not rf comp anymore but
we'll figure something out right
uh so when it comes to the fuzzing i've
been looking at scape for a little while
to kind of get ideas for how to
fuzz the bluetooth properly but in my
experience there's not as much
documentation on using the bluetooth
functions in scapy as i would like i
just haven't had enough time to kind of
dig through them little by little so
that's kind of the first step is to see
if that's
a viable
next step the next step is to find more
next steps right that's kind of how how
this goes when you don't really know
what you're doing um but i'm happy to
hear any suggestions or criticisms of my
little project you know i'm all yours
i'm always happy to listen so if you
have any feedback by all means please
hit me up
and then finally the last part of this
talk we're just going to talk very
briefly about the
ctf so
the ctf isn't meant to be incredibly
challenging it's a bluetooth ctf but
it's mostly designed to force you to
learn a little bit about the tools that
are available to you as a bluetooth
security researcher these are ones that
are it can everything can be done with
free tools you don't need a special
bluetooth adapter you don't need an
ubertooth one you can put that away it's
not going to be any help i promise it's
just basic bluetooth stuff but there is
a bit of a challenge in some of the
later challenges so
most of the challenges can be solved by
simply downloading a tool that's
available for free online and simply
reading the documentation to learn how
to use them and how to read the output
from the data you receive from the
target right
it's all running on one raspberry pi so
you just ask it for information it'll
give it to you and you find the right
information and put that into your your
ctf portal right
so
the only flag i would really consider a
challenge is the last one
for which you're going to need to have a
program
that can send bluetooth data to the
target device right
and then be ready to receive data
because you will find the first piece of
data you have to send as one of the
other challenges
then your task is to send that data to
my device successfully
and prepare your device to receive data
in response because the data you
excuse me
the data you receive in response will be
the last flag and that's the one that i
think is is the only really challenging
one you will have to write some code
to get this to work um but you know even
if you haven't coded in bluetooth before
with bluetooth before if you've done any
python work i think you'll be able to
figure it out
i would recommend to anyone you know
especially if you're having trouble with
that last one
take a look at the examples that pi blue
z provides
they're very useful and they were a lot
of help for me when i was first figuring
out
how to customize applications for
sending and receiving bluetooth data so
hopefully uh that's enough of a hint or
a tip
to have you staying here with us worth
your time for the ctf i know uh it gets
very competitive sometimes
um but yeah that is the end of the
presentation here's a quick look at some
of the references everything here should
be you know pretty easy to see i will be
uploading these slides to the github as
well so if you want to remember go back
to that github page there's the link
right the slides should be available
there soon
um but yeah i am all out of clever
things to say
so thank you so much for your time and
i'll be on the floor at the karaki
village throughout the entire event so
if you see me and you have any questions
or you want to call me some call me
names or something by all means come
through i'm always happy to answer
questions over email as well or if you
want to look me up on linkedin that's
fine too searching kamalgali will
usually uh lead you my way but
you know like i said my email address is
there
feel free to reach out at any time so
thank you so much and yeah
yeah i'll be easy keep on hacking hack
the world
yeah
you