come to security like the 80s how i
stole your rf and we'll be exploring cve
2022 27254 and more
so who am i
my name is iphone rajesh and i'm an
aspiring security researcher and a
student at the university of
massachusetts dartmouth
you can go visit my website or follow me
and reach out to me on either twitter
and you can also go check out my github
repositories and the co-author for this
is papa mikhail also known as scott
he's a sub gigahertz architect for
flipper devices and you can reach out to
him at telegram
or even check out his github repo
so
these are the
videos
that introduced me to the very concept
of cyber security
uh so huge shout out to sammy conker
hack five and even defcon for teaching
me what cyber security is and which even
got me interested in the field
um and it's been almost seven years and
it's insane that i have this opportunity
now so quick disclaimer
no key fobs are harmless making in the
making of this presentation and please
don't try stealing cars this
presentation in no way is to encourage
vehicle theft
so story time how did i get
this so this all started off for a
class in college last semester
which was ece 488 cyber security
cyber threats and security management by
professor liu
and we had to do a project for the class
and
i thought to myself why not take this
opportunity
and try something new something that
i've been wanting to do for so long
so
i
was searching around and i came across
the cve
for a 2017 honda crv and i thought
um i have a honda civic it's 2018 it's
not mentioned here
and why not try it myself
so i went through the repositories and
um
i saw two
uh links which was to a github
repository by hacking in your heart uh
his name is blake berry and the
vulnerability was first reported by
uh victor cazares another security
researcher
so
i went on facebook marketplace
found a
hack rf for about 200 250
got it and tested on my car and
it worked
so
what next i realized that the cv only
mentioned a 2017 car and i thought why
not build on to it why not try and add
to make a complete list of the vehicles
that are vulnerable to a simple replay
attack so i submitted a cve
got this email
so
we were credited for this cve and here's
a picture of it on the website
so
that got me quite a bit of attention i
didn't expect it at first but then
um
i had the opportunity to be interviewed
by fox 11 la
um and we even featured on it
i was also interviewed by abc's good
morning america which was an amazing
even
so getting into the deck so keyless
entry systems have been there for a
really long time
so
over 72 percent of the cars after 2014
[Music]
for this attack we'll be exploiting
the remote keyless entry systems onto
on on vehicles so it was first
introduced by renault on the renault
fuego in
way back in 1982 and it also operates at
315 433 or 868 megahertz depending on
which country you're in
and which brand you're going for
so
the way remote keyless entry works is
that it's just one way
something interesting that i saw on an
article where to quote mr clements where
he said it's similar to yelling your
password across the room and hoping no
one happens to be listening
so
unlike passive keyless entry where
there's a challenge response this is
just one way and that's why this is
possible
so what next we need to know what
modulation is it's the way the message
is sent
through radio signals so you have
amplitude key shifting frequency key
shifting
and face key shifting which is ask
fsk and psk where data is transmitted
either in the amplitude the frequency or
the phase like the name suggests
so static versus rolling keys i'm sure
everyone's seen sammy conker's fixed
code and rolling code attacks on the
open sesame
and many things like that so over here
what we're exploiting is a fixed code so
like the diagram mentions the code is
always sent as x
and it doesn't it never expires
but what's supposed to be good practice
for this is rolling codes where
every time
the button is pressed
the car
or any other device whatever it is it
rolls to a certain code
that's determined by the pseudo-random
number generator
and
so does the key fob
but in in this case it's clearly not
so what what tools are we using
so over here we'll be using fccid.io i'm
sure everyone's heard of it in all the
other talks and
it's really useful because you don't
need to know anything about the key fob
apart from its fccid which you can
google
and then you need an rf transceiver
either a hack rf usrp flipper zero or
even a yardstick one and then
gq rx or spi sdr whatever you prefer
based on your operating system and
universal radio hacker as well as gnu
radio
so fcc id or io so you can either open
up your key fob or even google
what key you have for depending on your
car and for this honda civic 2018 ex
it's
krv52x and then once you go into fccid
to iowa
success so we know roughly about where
it starts and ends and just visually we
can tell that
it's fsk
so
it's frequency key shifting which is
important to remember
and i'll explain that a little later so
getting into rf transceivers so
a hacker f flipper 0 and yardstick 1 and
usrp 810 are great
um devices you can use to
try this attack out yourself it's worth
mentioning that the hakka rf and usrp
are
what are known as software defined
radios
unlike the zero and the elastic one
which are computer control data devices
so one main difference in both them
is that sdrs can
simply capture anything
and
it will simply transmit what it hears
although for
the flipper zero and the yardstick one
you need to know exactly what you're
looking for which means the modulation
as well as the
frequency
unlike the sdrs where it only cares
about what frequency
that the
device you're trying to capture is using
and another big difference is that the
hacker f and usrp go from maybe one
megahertz to six gigahertz depending on
the daughter board present in it but the
flipper zero and yardstick one are sub
gigahertz devices but that's perfect for
us because all we're doing is attacking
from 315 433 and 868 megahertz
so here's a short video on gqrx of a
real key fob capture so you can clearly
see that it's speaking at about 433.6
as well as 434.1 ish something
so
we now know that it's not only frequency
key shifting but it's also transmitting
at two separate frequencies
and here's a video of s by sdr as well
so in the video you can see that it's
telling you exactly roughly about where
the frequency is so
i estimated it to be around
433.65 ish and
434.18
which is good enough for an sdr because
we just need a rough indication of where
the signal is playing
so universal radio it's a great tool
that i recommend if you're new to
wireless security it's really easy to
use you can demodulate and capture
and you can even analyze everything
but
i prefer gnu radio
uh
just because it's
i'd like to learn more on how things
actually work so it's built in c and the
way this works is that you just drag and
drop blocks
and feed in parameters and it works so
this is the real
capture flowchart that we have used so
you just have an awesome com source
which is actually our hack rf where you
just feed in the channel frequency
and your sample rate
and then what you do is you put it into
a file sync in order to save it and the
qt gy sync is just to show
where the peak is so if you see clearly
there are two peaks at 433 as well as
434 roughly
and here's the real
uh flowchart for transmitting
so all we're doing here is we've already
saved
the files in and
it's either file lock start and unlock
and then we can just enable
whatever whichever one we like
and then just create it into the sync
which will transmit through the hack rf
so enough theory let's see a demo
so as you can see in the video we first
used the start file capture after which
we use the unlock capture to not only
remote start the car but also unlock it
and then next up is my favorite
so new england weather in the summer can
be really harsh and it's really hot up
there and having a black car doesn't
really help so i use this feature almost
every time before driving the car just
so it can cool down
but just imagine if
someone was listening with a
with any of the
rf transceivers
new england also has
a lot of snow so just imagine if you
were to replay that as a prank of course
on
okay moving on it's time to get serious
so
that's the key fob which uh we've opened
up and then
if we want to extract useful information
out of this the best place to refer to
is the data sheet so once you know what
pin you're looking for you can look up
the data sheet
which over here is the pcf
uh
line
pcf seven nine 900 and then you just
connect
um
you just connect to the key fob via spi
so
um scored from
[Music]
flipper
sorted everything and then using spi
analysis
uh we were able to extract a lot of
information out so
spi which is serial peripheral interface
was developed by motorola in the 1980s
and it's it's you can use three wired or
four wire as well
and the
this particular chip supports both so
the way this one was wired up was um
was three wires
so
spi consists of
serial output
mossy which is
master output slave input muso which is
master input slave output
and s-clock which is serious serial
clock sorry
and over here we can find the good stuff
on the knee so
so
here's here's the information on the me
so so it's 0b 0 1 1 zero one one and you
might ask me what the hell does this
mean i mean that's that's the first
question that that came to my mind when
when i saw this it's just numbers right
but to quote uh professor vial it's in
the data sheet
so then if you look carefully if you
see 0b011011
is
0 1 1 0 1 1 which
is each bit and after checking the data
sheet you can find out exactly what it
means
so in reality the screenshot that you
saw previously
was for selecting the baud rate and
here's the
useful information that we have been
able to extract only some of it so
the
so zero b 1000 0 100
actually correlated to
the frequency low which gave us the
information that one of the frequencies
that it's operating at
is
433.657070 so like you saw in the
previous gqrx and
um s5 videos we did estimate it to be
about four three three point six five
but this is obviously more precise
and the same with four thirty four point
one seven six nine uh four eight where
we estimate it to be somewhere around
four thirty four point one eight ish and
then something that's also very
important
is
what modulation so obviously we could
see that it was fsk but then this is a
guaranteed
value as well because we know exactly
the deviation of the same now
and going into the baud rate selection
we were able to find out that the
board division is 51
and
we with a little math we can find out
the the baud rate itself which came up
to about
15380 per second
so
what next
so we have manchester so we we did find
out that
the device uses manchester encoding
which is a way of
encoding the data for transfer
and
we didn't know much about it so
and in fact the chip that we had the rf
end of the chip selected it as selected
the encoding as nrz
but the the previous chip had manchester
encoding so the rf chip only transmitted
what it heard which was actually
manchester although it thinks it's nrz
so
um
here's how you calculate that
so
remember the 62.81 microsecond in the
previous slide
so that's the shortest distance between
the
peaks so
you divide one second by that which
gives you about
7961 kilobytes per second
um which is really useful because in in
case we need to demodulate it we need to
know
the manchester bit rate
so here's how you do that as well so you
just once you get that number
you feed it in
and
it will demodulate it for you and gives
you all the information you need
so you might ask
why did we do all of this when
universal radio hacker can do it for us
like really really easily
and i have the answer to that as well
so i'm sure everyone's heard of the
flipper zero
so
out of the box it cannot support
locking unlocking or doing any of this
but with the help of scorp and
through this analysis and the
information extracted we can program it
to do so like i said earlier it's not an
sdr so you have to program it so for
this
uh he added the frequencies for 433.65
434.17 and even added a special
modulation called honda one there's
honda 2 as well which is more sensitive
but that means it's more noisy and but
honda one works perfectly
so
real question
does it work
looks like it does right so here's a
picture of the key fob capture and the
flipper zero capture as well
so
you can see that
the flipper zero capture might be a
little noisy and that's because of the
cc one zero one one one zero one chip
which we already know is pretty noisy
so here's a video of it working you
might have seen this on twitter and
here's how we actually make it work
okay next up
a civic with a laptop is the most fear
thing in the car keeping you take and if
you don't understand it google it
and this is a pretty sick picture
someone managed to get linux running on
their infotainment system
so
we already know that a civic with a
laptop is pretty dangerous but imagine a
civic with a laptop and a hacker f1
isn't it the ultimate wardrobing setup
okay enough about that so what's the
solution
so obviously i've recommended faraday
pouches
and
we all know that it's not the solution
because it's just a temporary fix but we
all know there are a billion people to
overcome it
so
rolling and rolling keys is the only way
that a simple replay attack like this
would not work right
that means
rolling codes the safe word
right
no
so after we release this
my good friend kevin
carhacking village
managed to break ruling code encryption
as well and he published his research
calling it rolling phone
so
there you go so it looks like even
rolling quotes had been hacked as well
here's here's his demo
[Music]
uh
so there you go
rolling codes have been broken into as
well
and
he did report this to the automotive
company at first and they straight up
denied it
until he reached out to rob stumpf from
the drive
and he confirmed it as well you can go
check out his
page on
twitter and see the demo for yourself
so
after all of that they did acknowledge
the issue and they said that it's not as
easy to exploit and
yes
they're right car thieves are obviously
more sophisticated than all of us and
they've been doing it for years they i'm
sure they must have found a billion
women which are more efficient
so in response to that
honda came up with a statement saying
that our vulnerability has no indication
that
you can actually drive an acura or a
honda vehicle
but i think everyone already knows
especially at the car hacking village
that once you're in a car it's yours
because you have access to the canvas
and
yeah so this vulnerability alone cannot
let you drive away with it but we
already know we have key programmers and
it's already known that car thieves do
buy these things and they can program
new keys for the car it's like
this so when honda came up with that i
said challenge accepted
[Music]
that's perfect
you wanna try driving it yep
wow
so there you go
you can drive away with a locked car in
just just under four minutes and that's
insane right
something alarming is that these devices
cost anywhere between 3 000 to 4 000
and i also learned that in the state of
massachusetts you actually don't need a
license to go ahead and buy one of these
so
just for a video buying one didn't make
sense but if you were a car thief it's a
great investment i don't encourage it
and obviously
but
it's very much possible and it does
happen unfortunately
so
in the future obviously we know that
canvas attacks are a thing
just imagine
anyone can
reverse engineer such a key programmer
code into
a great tool like jtella scan taught
and
just defeat the immobilizer or make it
program a new key
you can you can do it much quicker than
four minutes as well
so
quite recently about two weeks ago even
senator
markey uh sent out about 20 different
letters to the other to all different
automotive companies
um asking them questions about security
in remote keyless entry systems or
keyless entry systems itself
which i think is a great thing just
because
many of these systems are vulnerable and
i've also heard from other researchers
that
car companies either acknowledge it and
say that oh it's fine
but
i don't think it's fair um to know that
you have a vulnerability and don't fix
it at all especially
fixed codes
the first time i heard about it was
about seven years ago through um
sami kankar and that's why garage doors
now have rolling codes so why not a car
it's it's the least that can be done
right
and in fact the nhsda
only for 2020
approximates the cost of stolen vehicles
to be about 7 billion dollars and that's
a huge number just in the us
and that's from 804 000 vehicles stolen
in 2020 alone
so what next
you can join us on this journey
if you want to show your support please
grab a free sticker for cve 22
2022-27254 or a rolling pond sticker at
defcon's car hacking village
this is what they look like
and also
if you are interested in this
is
this is being done by woody who you guys
might know him from hack five
um kevin uh two six hundred of course
and me
so
and also if you do want a copy of the
flipper zero custom firmware do stop by
the car hacking village we will have a
qr code there that you can scan and we
also include a video on how to
flash the firmware and
guide you through how to do it
so additionally we'll also be doing a
live demo so you if
if you guys want to try this out
yourself please do come by the car
hacking village and we're going to have
a 2018 civic there as well
so come try it out yourself
so a huge thank you to the umass cyber
security center and umass dartmouth
the flipper zero team especially
scorp and pavel
and my friend avishi for the stickers
you can scan on qr code to go to her
portfolio
and my professors from umass dartmouth
professor kaslingam fiondela professor
liu zao and
professor vail of course
and also my mentor
mr sam curry who not only taught me a
lot about cyber security but also taught
me a lot about soft skills and
guided me throughout the process of
giving interviews to the media which was
really helpful
and also my mentors from ncipc
both the mr kumars
um
also
a huge shout out to
um
defcon car hacking village
especially
robert justin and
jerry
kevin 2600 woody as well as conor
mclaulen
as well as
magnus india and east coast chip keys
for making this happen but most of all
sami is my hero
and here's a few more references
or if you want to
learn more about this you please feel
free to read through all of this and
also
everything after the talk will soon be
published on my github repository so
please do look out for any of my tweets
or you can go to my portfolio website
and we will have everything open sourced
for you to learn as well
you