hello and welcome to the projects
obsidian
uh endpoint forensics kill chain three
walkthrough uh before we go through
the actual walkthrough uh i'd like to
draw a little context around what this
presentation is
so first of all what is product project
obsidian
obsidian is a project that the blue team
village has been working on for a few
years now
it is designed we created a fictitious
company
we staffed that fictitious company with
employees
and then we had uh the red team the
project obsidian red team attacked that
that network
and from there we did incident response
forensic examination malware reverse
engineering cyber threat intelligence
and cyber threat hunting this
presentation today
is really the endpoint forensics part of
it so the forensics team uh will have
several presentations this one is kill
chain three
and it covers only looking at the
endpoints from a forensic perspective
to do that we did collections on the
machines in the environment after the
environment was attacked
i'll show a little bit of a timeline
we're not going to focus on the timeline
because mostly what i want to show in
this presentation
is the artifacts how we would look at
the artifacts how we would uh draw
conclusions from those artifacts
and then a small demo of
what it looks like when you would
actually do the analysis
uh here we're seeing the timeline we'll
see several slides and i'm not going to
really cover these but i just wanted to
cover
the kinds of things that we'll see in
today's presentation we'll see some
some bloodhound being run in the
environment smb scanning uh connections
from a machine called rdpo1 to domain
controllers
we're going to focus mostly on three
machines uh
rdpo1 which is the source of where
the attacks came from and then uh
some activity on the domain controllers
we'll see some malicious admins being
added via automation we'll see some
evidence that the actor tried to ex-fill
some data some lateral movement dumping
of credentials via dumping lsas
and then
ntlm downgrade to allow
less secure hashes to be dumped which
could be cracked offline
and then security logs being cleared
excuse me so let's see the first piece
of evidence that we notice in this
environment
one of the things that we look at very
often when we're looking at a possibly
compromised environment is the the 70-45
message
and this one does not disappoint on the
domain controller
dc.mag tempest.financial
we see powers
ps exec
being run on that machine
via the psx service
and
and furthermore uh
we don't see any additional uh 70 45
messages but but this is uh something
that we'll keep in mind as we
as we look more at the data one of the
things that we do when we analyze a
machine is we look for
for files that look like they're hostile
now actors don't always name their files
obvious this is a hostile file you know
txt but
in this case we did see
uh several files that that
looked like they could be uh created by
the attacker one of them was this
bloodhound zip file on patrice's desktop
we saw several other files indicating
that powersploit had been run and the
invoke port scan
module had been run on the machine
in addition we saw some files that
indicated credential dumping
and
evidence indicates that the first one
was using the task manager
lsas memory dump and the second
using a technique
to use run dll and execute com services
dll to dump
lsas
in addition we find some other very
interesting on the brett social
desktop
four files called computers.txt
one.txt2.txt3.txt
and diving into those files a little
further
we identify that there are a list of ip
addresses now this is important because
when we look at these files as an
investigator now we have
some
evidence to decide the next set of
machines we should look at now those
four files were used by ps exec on the
rdpo1 machine to automate adding
[Music]
uh hostile users to
the local uh local administrators group
right we see the addition of combo
security
uh
a user id called jimbo the user id
called hass and a user id called andy uh
using psx and automating that using
these four files
so diving into some of the evidence the
first place we're looking here is at
patrice's uh
powershell console history and
again we see
that they used uh
the bloodhound
tool
to
scan the environment find
vulnerabilities in active directory
we also see
just as an aside
this lsat stump that we had talked about
earlier
this is coming from
running running chainsaw against the
sysmond operational
event log
and
chainsaw
identified this activity uh
event id 11 as lsas memory dump file
creation
looking further into some of the
evidence
we find
in
uh pat reese's
uh console history powershell console
history uh execution of port scan uh
running against uh
the subnet one seven two one
sixth
looking for
evident uh looking for
port 445 being active
again looking further at this evidence
we see evidence that
the
invoke share finder module was used and
uh looking a little bit further down
at the log we see evidence of
memicats being run in the environment to
uh dump the uh
to dump the hashes
elsas hashes
um
next looking further at again pat
reese's uh
console history in powershell console
history we see
this dump file that we had identified
earlier console history doesn't contain
dates and times in it but
going back to the creation time
that we saw earlier of this dump file we
can get an idea in our timeline of when
this
activity took place
looking further at browser history we
would identify
we collected browser history using
velociraptor and then taking that
browser history
converted it to a csv file and then took
that csv file and put it into a
reporting mechanism
that i use called ach report uh using
this uh and i'll show that in a little
bit
we see that uh this machine reached out
to
file.pizza and transfer.s8
indicating that the actor wanted to take
the data from the machine and x fill it
out we also also see uh it reaching out
to interact.sh now
this one might
say that this could be evidence of
exfiltration interact.sh
is actually an out-of-band detection
mechanism it's used uh when you would
when a hostile actor would execute
an attack and then this
interact.sh is used to report uh on
whether the attack was successful or not
in this case
we don't see the typical
url we would see from interact.sh so the
actor reached out to interact.sh and was
likely just looking at it
probably not being used for
exfil looking further into the evidence
again we see in the sysmon logs uh event
id 13
and power shell i mean uh
chainsaw
identified that this was likely an ntlm
downgrade so this is
at 1909 and at 2054 we saw the actor
uh execute an ntlm downgrade
the idea in an ntlm downgrade is to
force the machine
to allow
insecure
uh
hashing
uh and then those credentials can be
done those hashes can be dumped and
they're easier to crack offline
so we see evidence and of that activity
and if we wanted to we could actually
look in the user's
registry
actually not in the user's registry in
the machine registry hq local machine
and we would find
the evidence uh in lm compatibility
level uh ntlm min client sec
and uh restrict sending ntlm traffic we
would find
evidence in those keys
uh that
the
uh
nt that ntlm had been
set to to allow downgrading looking
at this activity in uh chainsaw we also
see further evidence of power shell
being executed in the environment of
kind of just an added thing we were
really looking
at the ntlm downgrade but this is what
you'll find often when looking at
evidence is other pieces will pop out
you'll take note of them and then add
them into your timeline
here we're seeing uh evidence of ps exec
now this is important because what we
see here is the two machines
that are being attacked right we see
dco2 and rdpo1 so we see rdpo1
authenticating to dc02
and then we see
dco2 running
ps exec running the service that allows
ps exec
and you'll notice that all of the time
stamps are 8.59 so this is a strong
correlation that rdpo1
uh
authenticated to dc02 and ran powershell
i'm i keep saying powershell ran ps
exact uh on that machine
uh again we mentioned earlier
that
uh these
files found on the desktop this desktop
computers.txt
1.txt
2.txt and 3.txt were
used to automate powershell
to
add
hostile actors to the administrative
hostile user ids to the administrators
group and here we see that evidence in
the sysmod logs
again extracted using
chainsaw and formatted using ach report
so these are
event id one that
we saw chainsaw identify
as
hurricane panda but
really what we're looking at here is
powershell being used to automate
adding
hostile administrators to
several machines that are located in
those txt files ip addresses located in
those txt files
uh on the machines themselves here we're
seeing on
dc
the commands being executed
and
we see combo security being added with a
password of b4by metal
an important piece of information
because now we can go to that machine
and we know both the
hostile user that was added and its
password uh we also see
here later on
in this log evidence
that the event log
uh
the event logs were cleared application
security and system
another piece of added information
that we can add to what we know about
this machine is we saw we see now pat
reese's in his console history that uh
mimikatz was run invoke mimikatz from
powershell empire
uh and these
hashes were used uh you'll see the hash
being used
to escalate
this machine to
administrator
as mentioned earlier
we see now uh using chainsaw
chainsaw identified
that the event logs had been cleared uh
this would be an important time in our
timeline because it would
define
the point in time where we can really
uh we really
won't know
uh
about what happened so
once the event logs were cleared
um
data previous to this would not be
available to us in the event log so we
would have to look to other
pieces of evidence to identify
activity on this machine
okay
that was a real quick run through
of
you know the evidence that we looked at
uh actually
um not a lot of pieces uh
are not a lot of artifacts but a lot of
information being gathered so
let's take a look at some of that data
in its in its native form or in the form
that you know we
we would review as we gathered
information about this machine
first on the dc system uh i mentioned
that we were looking at the 7045
messages so here we're looking at
uh the system
event log
in this
case probably the best way
to look at this data would be to filter
the log
looking for 7045
and sure enough
as we mentioned in our our
walk through earlier we see
the evidence of
powershell
the power shell
service piece
being run on the on the domain
controller
we also mentioned
on rdp01
let's see we're looking at dc here
rdpo1 this is the
the the report tool that i use um
this report tool does not
do a lot of the
uh
of the parsing of the data it does some
parsing but mostly it's used to put all
of the data to run the parsing utilities
uh and put them all in one place so what
we're going to look at is we identified
that bloodhound was running the
environment
and here we see
that
velociraptor
collected the
console history powershell console
history of patrice's and
this reporting tool simply shows
the
the activity
uh that that was
uh
that was
in that console history and here we see
the execution of uh a bloodhound and
then
the file name that it was saved under
and
this gives us uh information on if we
look at that file
when
that was run now that's not an
indication of the first time it was run
it was it's really an indication of of
what is available to us so bloodhound
could have been run five times four
times it could have been run once uh but
what we have in this evidence is that
bloodhound was run and that it was run
at a specific time
we also identified
that a port scan was run
so
again looking in
this
console history we identify
that uh the port that
port scan was run
from uh
from power supply
one of the things we previously
identified
was
the dump file
uh created by
running com running com services dll
through the through run dll uh creating
this dump file which would be a dump of
lsas
now if we look at
that uh search for c column backslash
dump we also find here is when that was
run so looking at rdp01
we see
uh that don't file being created
and
uh
in the
in the uh
cismond
event log um
chainsaw identified
this activity and uh reported it and we
just we just take that and put it into
this reporting format
another thing that we saw earlier
was
evidence of
at least attempts to exfiltrate data
so looking at the activity around that
time
we see
the actor reaching out to file pizza
transfer.sh and if we look a little bit
further down we also see
the actor
reaching out to webb wormhole dot io
these are all
evidence that
the actor
was at least
interested in exfiltrating the data out
of the environment
one of the other things we saw
we mentioned earlier was an ntlm
downgrade attack
so here looking at the chainsaw output
we see what we had seen earlier which is
the ntlm
chainsaw identified this as ntlm
net ntlm downgrade and
again we could go to the registry itself
if we wanted to have some corroborating
evidence we could go to the registry
itself
and
show that those register keys had indeed
been modified
uh furthermore on
dc02
uh we also identified that
powershell
that powershell the ps exec had been run
on that machine also
we see that in
a
event id of 11.
so let's look for event id11
and we saw that activity at about
at 2059. so
as we look through this data
go down to 2059.
and we see
the evidence that
ps exec had been run on this machine
at uh 2059-57
all right
so looking further at our reporting tool
um
we see
on rdp01
this evidence on rdp01
that
ps exec and again this is you know just
what we had seen
uh in the
screenshot but here we're looking at the
evidence itself
event id 1
identified by chainsaw as powershell
exec automating the addition
of
combo security
to
the administrators group on that set of
ip addresses in the computer.txt
1.txt2.txtn3.txt
files
as we look at this data we could then
look around it uh and see that
the actor had also done
some uh discovery of the environment
running who am i
and
other activity
again we see the the dump of lsas so uh
looking at this data in context uh we
can identify the times that this
activity happened and we get a better
idea of sort of what the actor was doing
on this machine
and that can help us draw conclusions
about what the actor was after what they
were interested in uh and
uh what they uh accomplished or and
sometimes what they didn't accomplish
so uh looking at
uh the domain controller
right we'll see the
evidence that
that
activity was successful on the domain
controller so let's do a find
and let's look for cable security and
here we see
that uh
on the actual machine
that net user combo security was run and
and again uh we're able to draw some
context around
around times and activity
on this machine
moving back to rdp01
we also saw
the pass the hash escalation or
elevation activity um and again
looking at
pat reese's
console history powershell console
history we don't have times
but we do have
a good picture of
what the actor did
uh using powershell not entirely not all
the things the actor did but but the
activity that the actor
did on this machine uh when using
powershell
uh the other the last thing we're going
to look at of course
is this evidence
that um
the actor cleared
the event logs
we can see
not only
the
execution of that
uh command
that the event logs were cleared but we
cannot get an idea of exactly when that
happened
right by looking at
what is left in the event logs uh after
they're cleared
okay so
recapping
what we did on this machine to
analyze it and to draw some conclusions
we had
an environment that was compromised
we ran velociraptor
on the machine to gather
telemetry and artifacts
sysmon was running on the machine so we
used that
as the basis for
a lot of our
conclusions we ran chainsaw
on the machine
to look at the event logs
and
identify
hostile activity chainsaw uses
sigma rules to identify
hostile activity we took that data and
we put it in a reporting to tool ach
report to put all the data in one place
to make it easier to kind of
draw context around
times and activities
and we also use a tool called mft dump
which
takes the
mft
which velociraptor collected turns that
into a comma separated values file a csv
file and then ach report can ask
that
file questions about
files that are identified
on that machine and this is where we get
we got some timestamps of when those
hostile files were created and
how they were created what tools were
used to create them
that concludes uh our walkthrough of
kill chain three uh
to learn further about project obsidian
about blue team village uh please join
us on our discord channel join the
conversation uh we'll be releasing all
of this data as open source we'll be
providing it to the community for
lots of reasons um
one is so that you can walk through the
data using your own tools or or the
tools we used um to learn more uh and to
gain some hands-on experience of you
know how your workflow
would uh would would go when you're
analyzing data you're learning to
analyze data
the second thing is that we hope that
this will be used by people with with
uh new tools so as new tools come out
new blue team tools are always come out
coming out
this data can be used to
test those tools to see if
the same conclusions are drawn or if
those tools find other information that
we may not have uncovered
and also
you can join the conversation
on
twitter we're at blue team village or if
you want to learn more about the blue
team village
you can go to our website
blueteamvillage.org