hey everyone count zero here welcome to
blue team village at def con this is uh
project obsidian and today we're gonna
talk about incident response
specifically final reporting made
exciting
really this is a way to discuss why this
dreaded yet critical part of incident
handling
is so important to the overall process
of incident response
so with that let's talk a little bit
about the incident response lifecycle
um
you've probably seen this if you've got
any of the other talks or pre-recorded
videos content for project obsidian so
far
but just kind of letting you all know
where we are in the incident response
life cycle
final reporting falls into the post
incident activities so that's where we
are now this is where we're going to
wrap up
the
information that we've gathered
throughout the
incident and the activities that have
been performed as well as making sure
that we successfully communicate
the
needs
and any after action activities that
need to occur
so what actually goes into a final
report
so these are some of the items that
we'll cover in this discussion these are
some of the key components to be sure
you include
not only for your executive levels or
your legal team who needs to understand
what occurred and what the business
impact may have been but also to
cover some of the technical details as
well so that your peer groups and
detection engineering with forensics
anything of that nature can be
used to
improve
the uh security of your organization
so we'll talk through a little bit of
each of these items and how they relate
to
what goes into our final report so the
executive summary detection analysis
we'll talk a little bit about
containment actions eradication recovery
and then finally lessons learned
so when it comes to the executive
summary portion
this is the
the hook this is what you use to get the
attention uh and this is often what gets
seen most uh by your executive
leadership teams uh you know the folks
who are controlling the purse strings so
that's how you
get some help if you need help in order
to deploy new products or get some
staffing
or make some changes to the security
posture of the environment
so a key thing here is to understand for
each one of the sections of final
reporting what is the audience
what are the components that go into
that
and how do you really
successfully communicate those needs
so for the executive summary portion of
a final report uh your audience is the
executive leadership team primarily
so you really want to make sure that you
write to to that level and help them to
understand what happened
in
straightforward and simple terms
so that they can communicate that
successfully and make informed decisions
so for the components that go into this
you want to
ensure that your audience understands
what you're trying to relate
and then relate that back to your you
know either business operations or or
functions depending on what the
organization is
that will tie your
incident and your
investigation into you know business
language or into legal language that is
consumable by those folks who are making
those decisions at the highest level of
the organization
another key component to the executive
summary is a high level timeline
the gory details you can save those for
later in the
report to communicate with your peer
team so that you can build detections
and you know other actions that may need
to happen at that level
but for this initial timeline you really
just want to go over the high points
so the leadership team understands what
happened and when this gives them the
understanding of
how to communicate potentially even with
the media depending on what is in play
or with you know
external legal teams as well so this is
a critical piece to to highlight that
time frame and the actions that took
place during that time frame to show
when
something occurred
what actions were taken to
mitigate or contain that risk and then
finally
what was done to
close the entire loop
from there you'll move into some
recommendations
it's good to define these
recommendations in both strategic and
tactical levels so at the strategic
level you're really going to communicate
with them about
large uh large changes or potentially
expensive changes depending on the
recommendation that comes to to mind
when
the incident is investigated
for the tactical tasks
looking at some simple things that may
be able to impact the security posture
maybe it's as simple as
if we just change the event log sizes
for our security log we would have had
more data to see what happened
during the course of this incident
or some simple um
actions that could take place on the
particular things that are being
recorded in your event logs so keep in
mind those things and try to define
those in a level of priority that is
understood by the executive leadership
team
and as you can see here some of the
things that you want to put into
particularly maybe an appendix or even a
separate document is like the full
timeline as well as the
indicators of compromise or iocs
so moving into the detection analysis
phase um
whenever you talk about this in your
final report think about your audience
as the technical leaders so maybe your
i.t
systems administrator leaders or network
administration leaders
and also your peers in your security
teams
it's the components that come into this
detections so
what
was detected and how did that come about
um you know was this a user that
reported a phishing email was this an
external report that came about from a
vulnerability that's new in the wild
or was it an alarm from your sim
so understanding how the detection
occurred
or if no detection occurred and you got
it reported in some other fashion that
all feeds into that final reporting and
betterment of your program so you can
take the information and say
we didn't get an alarm for this but
could we have and then you
are able to build on that
finally the analysis portion so
documenting the actions that are taken
and again you'll hear us talk about this
especially in the uh you know incident
response incident handling uh
part of the project obsidian
task that we've taken on is looking at
how
important documentation is for all of
these different facets of incident
response and digital forensics
so in the detection analysis portion of
this specifically you want to document
any of the actions that were taken how
did you dig in did you look at event
logs did you look at firewall logs did
you pull triage from a system and work
with the forensics team in order to find
out what occurred
in
user browsing history so there are a lot
of different actions that can be taken
during the course of an incident
especially with the investigation
portions so taking that into account and
truly documenting that well is a
critical piece and this is where you
communicate exactly what happened
another important thing to list during
this as we talked a little bit in the
detections portion opportunities so what
could have been done better
and what would have helped
with your detections next time
as far as what could have been done
better that could be process you know
that could be
better documentation on using some of
the tools that you have available
another thing to keep in mind is you
know detections so maybe your team is
the operations team and you're
responsible for the initial triage of
the alert but you've got a detection
engineering team that you can rely on or
some security engineering folks that can
help you build better detections in your
sim or in some other reporting or
alarming tool that you've got
so keep that in mind document those
things and it's really important to
write those down as you're going through
the process so keep a note of that while
you're doing your
investigation and that really helps
whenever you come back into
this final reporting phase you've got
those notes taken you've been
documenting what you've gone through and
what your thought process was at the
time so you don't lose that chain
so we'll move on
into
the containment phase
so when we've moved into the containment
phase for final reporting again you're
still going to be talking mostly to your
technical leaders and your peers
so this is the area that you want to
specifically discuss how did you stop
the bleeding
so how did you
take that action did you lock accounts
did you isolate some hosts or some
network segments
being able to define the exact actions
that you took and when
uh is an important part of understanding
the containment so this again feeds
directly into those timelines and that
critical communication that goes all the
way up to the executive leadership team
and as always
talk about any opportunities here what
would have helped in the future to stop
the bleeding faster how could you have
contained this more quickly
and whether or not that is a limited
pool of
people resources or if there are some
missing tooling in your environment or
missing logging in your environment
these are all of those opportunities
that you take
to communicate to the folks that hold
the purse strings who control the money
to
help them understand
we could have done better if we had
x y or z
and y
so putting that into that language
putting that into the business terms
putting that into impact is a critical
piece of this and understanding how
these containment actions take place is
a good way to translate that and again
this gets your technical leadership on
par with you and helps them understand
what you need to do your job and then
they can help to push that message up to
the executive leadership team
so moving into eradication
so after we've contained the incident of
course we're going to move into
eradication how do we get the adversary
out of the environment
again this audience is going to be
technical in nature
documenting your actions
continues to remain the critical piece
here so
documenting how the adversary was
removed from the environment
so did you need to reset passwords
did you need to
rebuild the system and how were those
actions taken
looking into that a little more deeply
for these opportunities in the
eradication phase and how you would
communicate needs there or opportunities
there
again
do you have a solid process in place to
rebuild systems do you test your backup
so that you know you could go back to
a pre-adversary action backup and
restore that and everything works fine
these are the critical pieces that you
can learn and you follow through with
the closure of this incident when this
final reporting phase to understand how
those actions need to be adjusted if
they do or if they work very well that's
also important to highlight so
highlighting your wins and highlighting
your opportunities
is a
critical piece of this reporting
function
and as always we'll continue to talk
about thinking through and thinking
through the future what are your
limitations what are your successes and
communicating that back up the chain
constantly so it can highlight what
you've done well and what you need help
with
as well as helping the leadership
communicate that again up to that
executive level
so finally we'll move into the
recovery phase and in recovery this is
really where we're getting back to
getting back to business
how do we get the organization back up
and running and
how did we test that those things are
actually functioning so this is where
you can communicate all of the things
that went well and the things that were
of issue again with this recovery phase
so this is the important part to help
the business understand here's what we
did here's how we got you back up and
running and here's how we're now serving
our customers or our constituents you
know whomever it is that this particular
organization serves
what you'll see is a lot of these phases
we have similar types of
details with the actions taken and the
opportunities and the reason that we
suggest breaking them down into the
incident response lifecycle pieces is
really to help you understand at each
one of these levels how this is
occurring and to make it easy to
communicate across the board with the
different functions that may occur in
the in the environment so you may be a
small team and everyone does all of
these things together in the small
security operations team or you may be a
very large team and you've got these
different components that can
take place so maybe you've got a malware
engineering team that can help you dig
deep into that or a service
or if you've got a forensics team that
really focuses on the deep dive
so keeping that in mind and
understanding how to communicate through
this final reporting process is a
critical piece of that
supposed to that activities so this is
where we are
in our incident response life cycle
so
this phase really
goes through not only your executives
but your technical leaders and your
peers as well so
this is where we're talking about
final reporting today looking at
all of the above
wrapping that all up into a an easy to
consume
document
potentially even a presentation
and being able to pass that along and
develop those
strategies and tactical recommendations
that may need to occur
with that we'll talk a little bit about
some reporting pro tips
so use a template
and
one of the things that we've got
developed is some some basic templates
for a lot of these different functions
so you may have already seen a
template on scoping or note taking
previous prior to this presentation
and the reason that we suggest templates
is
it ensures consistency and completeness
so
why does that matter so consistency is
important
to your
peer groups and your leadership team
they start to understand here's what to
expect i know where to look for the
important parts that
you know i need to focus on if it's that
summary in that timeline for your
executive leadership team they know hey
here's where i go and i see
what happened when and here's a quick
timeline so i can easily communicate
this
and completeness
this way you don't miss something so if
you've got all of these you know fields
or or
sections in your final report template
that you know need to be completed you
can take a look at that and it gives you
that opportunity to think have i done
this did i think through this part of
this final report and put that into
action
another important piece is you know just
the facts
in
incident response we really must
concentrate on understanding
what we know and what we don't know
and
trying to move from that hypothesis of
what happened into what we can actually
prove that happened
there are going to be times whenever you
don't have all of the data available to
prove that
so stick with what you can prove and
then highlight the things that you can't
prove
and why
that's where we come in with our
opportunities to improve
what's happening and what's uh what
what's happening and what processes we
use in the environment
as you're going through
your investigation
whether you're reversing malware or if
you are on the forensics team or if
you're on the operations team on the
front lines
write out your findings in report format
make good complete sentences
drop your thoughts into those notes
for
the steps that you're taking during the
course of the incident
this comes in
very very handy whenever you get to the
final reporting phase because then
you're mostly
copy paste and
you know do a little bit of wordsmithing
to make it read better
or you know read more clearly and
you're good
it really helps you to solve any of
those cases where if you've been working
on a particular thing for a while
you finally figured out the right you
know syntax to find what you were trying
to hunt for
and
you don't take good notes about it you
don't really show your work and then
your peer group
can't replicate the actions that you
took and so then it becomes harder to
define that and if you've forgotten
about it because you've you know been
working for a long time and have slept
since then and then that kind of went
away in your brain
so
keeping those those notes writing them
out in in report format so that you can
easily communicate those to others
will help sync that into your brain as
well as
translate that data over to something
that someone else can use
this can become a critical piece if
you're talking about building a new
detection so if you have found a way to
find
the evil and you can communicate that
over to the detection engineering team
or if you are the detection engineering
team and you need to do that later after
you finish this incident response action
you can translate that and remember what
happened
finally
normalize your time and map to a
framework so normalizing your time utc
utc utc utc it's the only time zone it's
the only time zone we don't need to
worry about any other time zones um
the reason this is so critical is uh
whenever you're trying to
put together a timeline so everyone
understands what's happening you've got
to understand
where your data sources are coming from
for the investigation
and what happened during those periods
well if you're trying to chain
events together and you've got something
that is in pacific time and you've got
firewall logs that are in utc time and
you've got server logs that are in
eastern time in the us then
how do you map all those things together
and if you're trying to normalize that
into a sim
maybe there's challenges there too and
you've got issues with
you know communicating what happened
when and trying to follow the chain of
evidence
so really think about trying to get
everything converted into utc and then
it's okay to display in different time
formats but when you're doing the
incident analysis and you're doing
forensics
try to stick with utc and try to get
everything converted to utc if you can
mapping to a framework helps you
communicate the bits and pieces a little
easier as well so if you're focused on
you know nist or if you're focused on
miter attack framework
stick to that learn that and use that
it'll help with the
clarity of communication amongst all of
your different teams
so those are some critical bits and some
some pro tips for reporting
so finally
let's take a look at uh just a small
snippet of a final report and what we'll
do is show off the
basic template that you know will be
provided as well and help
help you understand you know some of the
some of the look and feel for that and
then hopefully you can take this and
use it for your own needs
so now we can see
this demo template and so what we've
provided is just a basic word document
to
highlight some of the sections that
might be critical to to your
investigation and putting that
information together
this happens to be in a microsoft word
format a docx format but this also works
in things like libreoffice as well
so if we scroll on down we'll take a
look at a basic incident summary
and this is
just a little bit of detail for kill
chain 3 which is mostly being discussed
during
saturday here at defcon
and so we'll look at you know what we've
done with this
very broad uh summary so far again this
isn't fully complete that's on purpose
so that you can have fun with the data
that's going to be released as well
but it kind of starts to give you an
understanding of how to
well communicate
some of this information for your
executive leadership team so we've got
some specifics on a date um we've got
some specifics that say there was an
alert that was triggered uh and you know
maybe
the security investment was a security
investigation was delayed and why
so this can be used to communicate back
to your teams to say hey
you know we had some we had some trouble
getting to this alert because we had
some other alerts that were stacked up
ahead of time do you have some issues
with people do you have some issues with
um
you know resourcing or or is it related
to uh you know cleaning up some of your
alerting so again do you need some
people to be able to
process those alerts more quickly
again we
throw the details out quickly at the top
what was happened
you know system was compromised here's
the time that it happened we've
confirmed data exfiltration here's the
time that we believe that occurred
and also a few more of the technical
aspects of
what
happened during the course of the
investigation and the course of the
incident and then some of the actions
that were taken to
contain that so here we see we've
blocked some network access we've done
some other things to to kind of stop
that bleeding
and then
giving them some tidbits on you know why
did this happen what are some things
that we could have done to
better protect this in this case we see
well it seems to be this is a password
spray on some internet exposed systems
and the fact that we didn't have
multi-factor authentication rolled out
to our end users
there was no
second layer of security kind of
protecting those accounts so the
adversary was able to get in
and we're going to kind of wrap up with
you know what are the
actions that need to be taken in this
instance we're saying you know what we
we can't trust our active directory any
longer due to what happened here so
we're going to have to you know rebuild
this and make sure to throw out some
you know
estimates for this looks like it's going
to take us you know a couple of weeks so
we're saying 14 days and
what does that mean to our you know
users so maybe office email is going to
be impacted for a while so
um
you know in in our instance fortunately
we've got the company website maybe was
hosted off-site so that's not impacted
right now because it wasn't connected
into our active directory so we can you
know post some messages up there to let
customers know hey we're going to be
delayed for a little while and getting
back to you on some of these actions or
some of these you know business
functions that we need to do so this
just kind of gives a quick highlight of
you know using this template and
and putting some things together
um some of the other items that you can
see here so we've got a call out to the
timeline so if you look at the incident
tracking you know spreadsheet that's
going to be thrown out along with some
of those other templates that we're
providing as part of this project
you can type that and tie that into here
so you can put your
you know detailed timeline you can put
like the summary timeline and throw
these contents into this final report to
make that easy to discuss
another option uh or another item that
we want to cover is the adversary
actions and here we're we're mapping to
you know the miter attack framework and
we're calling out some of those ttps
again this makes that cross
communication amongst the teams and also
amongst you know peers out in industry a
lot easier and a lot simpler so they
understand um
the actions that were taken and what
happened
so that just gives a rough idea of some
of the template actions that we've got
in play and as always you know use some
good headers use some good
incident report
contents so that way your executive
teams and your technical leadership
teams can click through this and you can
update this as a field in word or if
you've got
something like libreoffice as well this
comes in as an index and again the
update process is very similar
so with that we'll be wrapping up this
discussion shortly so we'll move back
into the presentation
so wrapping up with your recommendations
again talking about strategic uh versus
tactical
and making sure that you highlight those
quick wins
so strategic
in this case um if we're talking about
you know multi-factor authentication
that may not be a simple um
to execute a thing in your environment
there's
a lot that goes into that as far as you
know cost and implementation and you
know what systems may or may not work
with mfa
looking at anything that is policy
change related
again that's a bigger picture item that
the executive leadership team needs to
take into account uh you know there may
be legal implications there may be
um staffing implications that come into
policy changes on how things might occur
during the
setup of your security program and
finally staffing
staffing often is something that is tied
directly to budget because it has to be
paid for somehow and so that usually
ends up falling into that staffing or
that strategic portion of your
recommendations
just a quick hint on this uh you know
tactical recommendation so talking about
enhanced logging
if you've got a windows environment that
could be as simple as
starting to test deploying sysmon on
systems again it's something that's you
know free and is potentially low cost to
implement and manage depending on how
your system is set up or it could be as
simple as updating your gpos for your
windows hosts to enhance the logging
that's already built into the operating
system
again highlighting these quick wins in
this communication for the final report
is key
so that your technical leaders and your
executive leaders understand that you're
thinking forward about how to better the
environment and communicating that well
for them to understand and take action
and with that thank you very much for
your time we truly appreciate it and we
hope to see you in the blue team village
discord and you can jump in the discord
and ask lots and lots of questions uh
regarding project obsidian and again
the data sets that we've used to build
this
training content and these templates um
are going to be made available to you to
use at your discretion and hopefully
you'll learn some some things and be
able to implement and
better your security posture thank you