[Music]
welcome everybody my name is omar santos
i'm one of the co-leads of the defcon
red team village and here with me i have
ryan dory from optiv and first of all
you know thank you so much ryan and
thank you opti for supporting the defcon
the red team village not only this year
but throughout the years and you know
all your support goes a long way
so um
if you don't mind ryan can you tell me a
little bit about yourself
about what you do adoptive
yeah absolutely thanks for for having me
and having us again happy to support um
my name is ryan dory i am the practice
director of the attack and pen team
inside of our larger threat management
team here at optiv
we have about 50 dedicated uh pen
testers inside of attack and pen i've
been with the company about 10 years now
and i've had the the privilege of
calling attack and pen home the entirety
of the the 10 years
uh once upon a time i was technical and
delivered the the fun offensive security
services and attack and pen but uh now i
have the the privilege of leading with a
bunch of other solid leaders here uh on
the team and and primarily a business
focused of with regard to attack and pen
excellent thank you so much
and
i am very familiar on how you
continuously contribute to the community
and you sponsor so many events and you
actually have
different events
that have been very well attended in the
community but can you tell us a little
bit of about why
it is important to actually foster
that community and why you are
sponsoring
the deaf congratulations this year
yeah absolutely we uh historically i
mean to be honest it's something we
could have done better in the past and
really been trying to work hard to give
back to the community in different ways
go uh you know going forward uh one of
the ways obviously is sponsorship of
specific events such as red team village
or other um you know maybe smaller local
uh security conferences
uh another thing that we've
gotten a couple going so far is a
collegiate involvement so um i believe
that's actually the connection that
brought us to red team village
ultimately traced that back but we've
partnered with uh cyber security
collegiate programs
and done technical talks uh at those
events um as well as like career
mentoring or even just like personal
one-on-one mentoring with some of the
aspiring cyber security professionals in
those college uh uh scenarios and
also i mean i'm actually partnering with
my local college and and doing a cyber
cyber camp for a local high school or
for high schoolers actually next week so
it's pretty neat to give back to
community
to help foster you know those those
future pen testers
and the last thing that we're really
starting to to get some momentum and
steam going on is our source zero
presence to give back to the industry at
large as well so
what that is is we have a technical blog
for red teamers and blue teamers uh
where we release a lot of new articles
as far as cves to ttps to even some
basic stuff as well
on our source zero blog um and
accompanying that is we just completed
our second year running of the source
zerocon so it's a completely free uh to
attend security conferences i think this
year we had three separate tracks over
three days um with a whole bunch of
different talks and and sp
individuals speaking to a broad range of
technical topics
and to go along with all that we also
have our open source tooling um that's
partnered with source zero right in our
github as well to give back
to the assessors in the industry
excellent that's actually perfect segue
for my next question
which is
what are your top three recommendations
i know that there may be a lot of things
that we can recommend for people that
are getting started but if i'm getting
started today and especially in
offensive security what are your top
three things that i should focus on
yeah that's a great question i get asked
that quite often and it usually in my
opinion skips a couple steps people ask
like hey how do i hack things or how do
i get into hacking or you know the cyber
security offensive security space
um in my opinion the the formula stayed
relatively the same over the years and
that it requires a deep intimate
understanding of the underlying
technologies and so what i mean by that
is understanding how something works
really really well before you can
manipulate it in say an offensive or
malicious way right um so understanding
how active directory works uh how linux
works uh how networking uh functioned at
a very deep and comp you know you know
in-depth level right um web apps etc so
you need to have those fundamentals
fully intact before you can go into the
next level of say again manipulating
them
um other things uh sit in a similar vein
is once you do get into the security
space and maybe start doing a little bit
of work there
do it as manual as possible a lot of
folks like to get into automation and
rely on tooling heavily
do it as mainly as possible so you
understand the actions that you're
taking and what the cause and effect is
of those actions are on say the
environment the operating system or the
application as compared to a tool that
you just point at at a host and hit go
and you have no clue what it's doing so
um do it as manually as possible be very
leery of tools and understand what
you're doing and then lastly get
involved with the community
postcode is more true than ever um it in
that it could be virtual versus say your
local you know whatever meetup uh
location but get involved in the
security community make a bunch of
friends there's multiple benefits there
first of all you're going to have the
opportunity for great knowledge share
and learning opportunity but then
there's also going to be a great social
um the social aspect of probably getting
a good career opportunity as well just
by way of you know knowing folks in
industry
and another very good point that i
assume that you guys are hiring as well
and if so how can people find more
information about any job postings that
you may have
and you know i'm assuming that you're
hiring yeah yes absolutely we are very
very busy here and i am actively hiring
um that is taking up a whole lot of my
time we're hiring across all of threat
management that includes things such as
appsec and eim et cetera but
specifically attack and pen i think i
would take 10 to 15 people tomorrow if i
could find them so um you can find the
open uh wrecks or positions on optiv.com
um i think it's slash company slash
careers but there you can specifically
apply and see some of the specifics and
get in contact with our talent act team
excellent i'm sharing the link in the
bottom of the screen here
so once again thank you so much for your
time and thank you for sponsoring the
red team village and you know thank you
everybody for attending today thank you
sir