hello my name is stephanie barnes
and this
is my presentation entitled
cryptocurrency a bridge across the
digital dubai
before i begin i kind of want to go
ahead and excuse myself
um i've been under the weather
i
probably sound very stuffed up i sound
stuffed up to my ears
uh my voice uh may be a little hoarse
because i'm still getting over that
but i'm trying to do the best that i can
but i wanted to apologize beforehand
that being said let's move along
so who am i
as i said before my name is stephanie
barnes
i
am a recent master's graduate
with a degree in cyber security from
excelsior college i also have a
bachelor's degree from excelsior in
information technology
before that i had a psychology degree
from florida a m
i've been in the infosec field
for
about four years now working in a
security operations center as a sock
analyst
excuse me
so of course i want to start off with
um an agenda
so that you guys can keep me honest so
that i can
keep myself honest um we're going to
talk about the digital divide
i'm going to talk about black people in
cryptocurrency slash the blockchain
cyber security and cryptocurrency the
digital dollar
and a cycle i think as a people uh we
should avoid
so
this is the webster's
definition of
what the digital divide is
it
includes
not just educational but social and
economic inequality disparities between
people who have computers people who do
not people who have
uh are readily have
online access and those who do not
you can think that this could be a
simple thing and maybe
20 30 40 years ago it wasn't such a big
thing but now
with the way that our lives are
interconnected with computers
with digital media and
with the internet
not having um
something like a computer at home
are computers in your schools our online
access that
is unlimited
limits your possibilities it is the
difference between somebody saying that
they've been coding for nine years and
somebody's saying
that they've only been coding for 29
years
the kind of portfolio that you could
have if you had that 20 years head start
is drastically different from somebody
who just started yesterday
and to not
see that or not recognize that disparity
disparity does a disservice um to us all
so
a lot has been said and it's been
written about digital divided and it's
been spoken of
even
in our
kind of hiring practices right that's
why people have
diversity
and inclusion
personnel
that's
why we we try to provide avenues for
historically underrepresented
communities to have access not only to
computers and and be online but to also
have access to
the programs that will put us on
equitable footing
as others that already have that kind of
access
so breaking off that did you know um
this is all coming from forbes
uh african-american households only hold
less than four percent of the 116
trillion dollars in wealth in the us
it's a very very small percentage like i
can't give you the exact amount
but
knowing that it's a single digit is
enough to know that it's very very small
but despite this despite only having
four percent of this wealth
we are the largest demographic of
cryptocurrency investors currently and
that 23 percent
is set to double
but even with having already four
percent of the wealth and
being a large percentage of the
investors
13 of our households are unbanked and
when it means unbanked it could be from
from historical banking practices so
that they they can't
get um
a an account
um
or could be because there's not a bank
in the neighborhood it could be because
the bank in the neighborhood is
inefficient
are
it can be
something like there are still predatory
banks and still predatory banking
practices there can be that there's just
a distrust of of banks
but for whatever reason any of those
multitudes of reasons and more that i
haven't even spoken of 13 of
african-american households are unbanked
so this all feeds into each other
because it's all about our wealth it's
all about how we spend our money how
we're saving our money if we're able to
save money or do we have the
institutions in our neighborhoods that
would assist us
to
to save our money to build up our
communities to put the wealth that we
may have back into uh african-american
communities
so how does that feed into
cryptocurrency
in
my research and in my view
black inbound people have a history
of making their own way when the way
forward has not been equitable and is
not
about equality we've always been able to
kind of read the room and
invent
our way out of the situations that we
might be in
are
develop
a new way
right
so
for our communities
it really is where there's a will
there's a way
many
black people in
cryptocurrency and the blockchain and
even now in nfts
see the potential that these emerging
technologies have and it's appealing
and it could be because it's something
new
it could be because
we've seen in the past where something
like bitcoin has really skyrocketed and
we've wanted a piece of that
and maybe because it's something new
and it's not burdened by all of the
past problems and the
past inequalities we see that it might
have a more likely chance of
being successful
for our community for our individual
lives um because they're not tied to
the banking institutions or to the
government that we might be distrustful
of so i can see why
we would have that 23
excuse me that 23
that is investing
into cryptocurrency because
it doesn't have the ties and it doesn't
have the historical
baggage that something
like
a bank
or
even regular
everyday investing might have it also
doesn't have the cost
barrier
where you can put pennies into a
cryptocurrency
and then with the right
turn of events come out a thousand error
or millionaire in some cases
you couldn't do that
with the access that we have to
something like a market account or
investing in stocks
it's happened yes but usually there's a
higher barrier
for entry initial entry for
those kind of accounts as opposed to
cryptocurrency
like i said we've been there from the
beginning it's not something new
that
there have been black people investing
in
are developing in cryptocurrency
um these four people are just a small
pool
of pioneering
black people
in the cryptocurrency
realm
um
first we have in the green so i'm
starting from is cleve
uh the cider and i might be saying her
name incorrectly and if i am i apologize
um
but she leads the national policy
network of women of color and they
advocate for diversity in cryptocurrency
markets
next we have vernon j
and he's the founder of equity coin
next to him we have deidre ramsey
mcintyre who co-founded
the
support and advocacy advocacy group
black people and cryptocurrency and then
last is sean wilkinson the founder of
storage
s-t-o-r-j
which uses the blockchain
um to
[Music]
aid in cloud
storage so
there are black people out here that are
making their own coins they are
building on the blockchain there are
people that have advocacy groups that
are teaching
others in the community about how to
invest in cryptocurrency how to use a
black trade how to develop how to
use these kind of emerging technologies
to build up
right
and
there are other black pioneers than the
ones that i have on the screen and there
i continue to be more in my opinion
because
we tend to seek out emerging trends and
build our own
off of those trends because we've seen
that they can be successful
for others are like i said before it
doesn't have the barrier of entry
that
odor
avenues have
but with that and with building
on these emerging technologies we also
have to take
into account security
um not just for ourselves but
for the community
for anybody that's new entering in
but also because
in this day and age security goes hand
in hand with
everything
we have to be more security minded
when we build digital
devices
digital technologies because if we get
to a far ahead in development
before we think about
is it secure
how secure can i make it
there's just a lot of backtracking that
you have to do but if you build
something secure
as you are building that thing
then security is always the first step
they always go hand in hand they always
are developing with each other
excuse me so that being said what are
some of the cyber security implications
in cryptocurrency
and all of these
boxes
are a way
that cryptocurrencies have been kind of
targeted
for
attack
there
have been
illegitimate exchanges that have popped
up that will get
not just people's money but also
a lot of their personal information
because in many of these exchanges
especially now that there's been more of
a governmental eye on it
they will ask you for personal
information such as you know your name
or even your social security number or
something to identify you may be a
picture
of
your passport or a picture of your id
card
and that can be used to
impersonate you you know in the wrong
hands
then there are some of these exchanges
that the only way that you can
get
the coin or access
um any of your investments you have to
use like a third-party
application
and
you know as well as i know that the more
kind of parties that you have to have
into
the larger the attack area the larger
the surface right
then because these technologies are
still new
there's still a lot of confusion
from the end user on
what they're doing
how they should do it is this correct
does this sound right
um if i press this button am i making a
trade if i press this button am i buying
something am i giving them too much
information am i too excited about the
possibility of making more money that
i'm making a misstep
and without the proper guidance there
you could be and it could be
insignificant or it could be
the difference between being able to pay
your rent this month
um
and then there's of course fishing it's
always there's always going to be a
target fishing for anything that's
popular any company really
i barely have any crypto and i receive
phishing emails about crypto exchanges
all the time exchanges that i've never
heard of
but
there have also been
cryptocurrency schemes out there
such as uh
one coin which
turned out to be just a multi-level
marketing scheme
and besides just these things that i
have on the screen there have been
recent attacks on things like uh nft
stores and
cryptocurrency exchange there have been
cryptocurrency exchange that have
kind of lost solvency and
not wanted to give people their money so
that they
so that they wouldn't close down um to
avoid shut down and that kind of thing
and because
it's so unregulated or not regulated to
the extent that it probably would need
to be
what's the recourse
um other than you being upset about it
what can who can you really call
to help you
but the unregulated nature of
cryptocurrency was the thing that pushed
its growth
it's the thing that gets the coin
shooting up there to thousands
and thousands of dollars
but it's also one of its most worrying
worrying
attributes
and when we have that
that's where we get the push to have a
digital dollar or the
central bank digital currency as they're
calling it right now
and
this talk of it has been going on for a
while
but with the current administration
they've actually
put a little bit of money into
researching it
into seeing how we might have a digital
dollar in the united states what would
that look like how would it work
and in their press release for it they
say that this is supposed to
help
the people who don't use bank so
ba as we still have our 13 that's
unbanked
this is for those people
if
excuse excuse me
but it also affects the people that are
using cryptocurrencies and the people
that
are reliant on fintech
and are banking online
because it's not just a change in
whether or not you can
just use your digital dollar
for things that are online instead of
putting in your bank account there's a
lot of gray area maybe even a lot of
black area and how this would work and
that's because it's just in its
researching phase but it's something
that you have to think about
how will this digital dollar work right
how will it affect the cryptocurrency
that i have now um is it the only thing
that they're looking at
just creating this digital dollar i know
for a fact that that's not true it's not
just going to be a digital dollar just
this morning there was an article wired
about
how the united states and europe are
looking at ways to regulate
cryptocurrencies and that's quite
possibly because of all the recent news
of falling prices and again of
um
infosec concerns and
breaches
and excuse me um
excuse me infosec concerns and breaches
and things of that nature that have
happened with these exchanges that now
that there are more people that are
investing
and have money tied up in this
hey
we should make sure this is secure for
the people
or even if it's not about that and you
think the worst that you're just like
they just want to over regulate us to
death it's still something that they're
looking at right it's still gonna
change the way these things operate and
we have to be able to either change with
it or fight against it
but the only way to do either one or the
other is to understand
what's going on and keep up to date
about
what's happening
so what's the difference between the
crypt currency and the cbdc
cryptocurrencies are decentralized right
they're peer-to-peer base
and the price and worth fluctuates like
i said that's one of the things that
drew a lot of people to it to begin with
is because the fluctuation
for a lot of people in a lot of uh coins
it meant coming up on a windfall if
you if you cashed out
at the right time
with the cbdc it's government control
there's less price fluctuation and it's
one to one with the dollar however much
the dollar is worth that's how much the
digital dollar is going to be worth
regardless
you know
it has pluses to it
especially if you
are somebody that feels that regulation
makes you safer
right
um it's not something where you would
get that windfall it's just
a translation of however much money you
have if you have five dollars in digital
dollars you're gonna have five dollars
in real life if you have five dollars in
bitcoin
up until i mean even now if you have
five dollars in bitcoin it's a
significant amount of money
but
it could also be five dollars in less in
a month in two years in three years a
dollar is always going to be a dollar
it's not going to be worth a dollar all
the time but it's always going to be
equal at least
so all those are both digital they're
not the same they're not interchangeable
but they both impact
our community
the development of both
um
and
they both
have some sort of a power some sort of
usage
for us
but
why should we care
right
if you're not if you don't have any
cryptocurrency cr
currently are
if even if there's a digital dollar and
it's just like oh that's just it just
means that i can use it in cyberspace
that's great
why should you care about these things
if you don't have any holdings and a
digital dollar is just
a thing that might exist because it
doesn't exist now why should you care
right now
for me it has more to do with something
that could lead to a bitter cycle of us
as a people being
more
oppressed are
in a worse standing
economically than to begin with
and i say this because not only are we
the leading investors in cryptocurrency
are not only are we significantly
unbanked but we're also the leaders in
using digital wallets
we lead in banking through our phones
and using fintech applications like cash
apps your venmos your paypals we lead in
those kind of things
quite possibly because we're unbanked
you can hold large amounts of uh cash
in cash and cash app
um or you can do all your business
transactions
for
your your small business
through paypal or square or something
like that
and we've taken advantage of that
right
but
with the move towards digital currency
those kinds of exchanges
are interactions with these digital
wallets which you're banking through
your phone or being able to just send
money with an app on your phone
is
likely to increase
because we're gonna be
possibly more reliant on a digital
currency if they have
a one-to-one ratio that you have a
thousand dollars in your bank so that
means you have a thousand digital
dollars that you can use with a push of
a button it's ease right it's more
likely for you to do it you won't have
to go to the bank you don't need to have
a bank in your neighborhood because it's
all right here on your phone and you
always have your phone right we all
always have our phones
so it's more likely to increase the use
of digital services but the problem with
these services currently
is that they have been rampant with
complaints with
the services just closing closing down
accounts
and taking people's money money and
scamming and there have been
data breaches at them they are not
regulated like banks are because they're
not banks
not all of them some some do have uh
banks
attached to them
excuse me because
cash app technically would have a bank
attached to it now that it's bought
what is that credit credit karma now
that they bought credit karma and credit
karma has a bank
uh our banking apparatus to it
cash app with or at least that bank
apparatus would be subject to some kind
of regulations but a lot of these don't
have
banks attached to them so
you have your money
that you've never
touched physically
and you're
unbanked and it's just
in the ether really
like it exists
but if this
tech company decides that you've broken
some arbitrary rule are
going against their terms of services
that
nobody reads because it's such small
print
you've lost
your money
and for somebody that is economically
sound
it
is a blip on the radar
but
for somebody that's historically not
economically sound it's not a blip
anymore
and
that's the kind of thing that concerns
me
because
there is this research for doing a
digital dollar it is supposed to help
the unbanked but it can hurt them
um
so if we are utilizing these services
more often
and these services aren't as regulated
they're not
banks if there is something that's
negatively happening it hurts those that
are
in a less equitable or are
equal position more than somebody that
is not
right
and we want to avoid that we want to
avoid getting into a cycle where we're
i don't know excuse me early adopters
and early pioneers of this kind of
technology because it makes our lives
easier
um and
it also
is
helping us in a way to have thriving
small businesses are to to send cash to
our family members
it just makes like i said it makes our
lives easier
but
because of the way that it's not
regulated are
because of the way it's not
run by
somebody that has our best interests at
heart it's a business you know it's not
it's not about helping the little guy no
matter how much they say it is right so
if it's if it's if it's set up and it
might hurt somebody it's gonna hurt
those who are at the bottom the most
so what do i think is needed um i feel
like
there should be a focus on education to
avoid exploitation it's how you get away
from users being confused it's how you
get away from people thinking that they
could put in
a dime and make 10 million
right um it's not just about educating
about cryptocurrencies and about
investing in cryptocurrencies but also
having community kind of outreach which
some of those peoples that that i taught
peoples some of those people that i
talked about
um
on the pioneer page have those kind of
advocacy groups and
other kind of groups that educate the
community on
what to look in
what to look at um when you're trying to
invest in cryptocurrency
or this is how the blockchain works are
this is what an nft
does and i've seen
that there have been a lot of
outreach
especially in schools to teach the
incoming generation about these kind of
technologies and that helps
that's how we use education so that when
you get older and you can
invest your own money or you see that
this could be an opportunity for
economic freedom that
you won't be exploited
because you might be able to see the
signs and you won't let others be
exploited because each one teach one
that's the community thing that we've
had for forever right
um
but also there should be diversity in
development and that's not way for
somebody to say hey
we want you to fill this space but
making our own spaces as well
it shouldn't just be an investment
vehicle but also
like the maker of equity coin and
i know that there was another coin that
was started by a brother it was um
guap coin i think
like developing your own coin
not in a in a scammy way in an actual
way where we're we're doing the
programming all right even if we don't
go that avenue and
it's more of
how can we make this more secure or
what can we use the blockchain for
other than
coin other than investment
like
sean wilkerson did with storage and used
it as cloud storage
how can we use this emerging technology
to develop something new to fill in a
boy to
[Music]
make something that's going to last
right
and then if there is going to be a
digital dollar if there's going to be
the government whether it's here whether
it's in europe whether it's anywhere and
they're going to say we're regulating
this and we're going to do this this
this this and that to make sure that
it's it's more safe for everybody to
invest
and use these exchanges if that's what
we're going to do we should advocate for
ourselves
even if they're not going to regulate
the coins that are already out there
which i sincerely doubt even if they're
just going to come up with additional
dollar you can't
help
the unbanked without speaking to the
unbanked this
isn't a nanny state that's not what we
want what we want is equity we want his
justice and if you want those things
and you're committed to having those
things come to fruition
then
those
people that are you that you're talking
about that you're advocating for helping
should be able to say this is what we
need
and we need this because
xyz this is what would make it more
equitable this would
is what would make it more just and more
fair if
these things were provided you know it's
not just about having a digital dollar
that doesn't help the unbanked if the
the transmission of that digital dollar
is subject to shut down at any time it
doesn't help to have a digital dollar
if
the
applications that that are popular that
they're using
um
can't exploit them
right
it turns this bridge that
we we
tried to pioneer that we've tried to
grow that we've invested in
into something that's just another way
for us to be
oppressed and exploited
and that's not what we want right
so if we're not part of the development
if we're not focused on educating each
other and not just looking at it as an
investment vehicle but actually as an
avenue where we could spin off into
something else
or develop something new
that we're just putting ourselves in a
place where we can be exploited and
we've already been exploited and
disenfranchised enough
so
for me
this is some advertised further reading
if you're interested
in cryptocurrencies
and
black america in the
blockchain revolution
in banks and
why cryptocurrencies
might be appealing to disenfranchised
people
this is some further reason there's more
books that are like these but
these are the ones that i recommend
personally
so i'd like to thank everybody for your
time again i can be found on twitter at
barnes underscore sn
i also have an instagram blue team book
club where i just talk about blue team
books
really all the time
um i'll just like to thank bick blacks
of cyber security for giving me this
opportunity
it's been awesome they are awesome
um
and everybody that's helped me
told me that i should do this even
though it's kind of nerve wrecking and
everything
i appreciate you guys
are there any questions