hi guys thanks for attending our talk
we're going to talk about uh biometric
system hacking in the age of smart
vehicle
so who are we um i'm kevin 2600 and this
is my teammate wesley say hi
okay so um we are secure researchers
from a star we lab and we have
researched and found many interesting uh
vehicle-related bugs and presented and
some of them are defcon in the last few
in
past few years uh and if anyone wonder
what car hackers lab looks like and here
are some pictures for you okay um just
like any other labs we got lots of
interesting equipment and most
importantly we got actual cars to play
with
so
okay so here are the contents for
today's talk
we are going to talk about uh biometric
authentication and then facial
recognition spoofing and then
speaking a speaker recognition spoofing
for the vehicles
okay so biometric
uh authentication
and this is a definition of multi-factor
authentication basically uh you will
need to
you will need two or more factors like
something you are and something you have
and something you know to achieve the
authentication
so something you have usually this means
our key fob for the cars the key fob is
a very common device we have for the
vehicle and in the recent time some car
company
start to replace the physical key fob
with a nfc car
or just a mobile phone to access the car
for example this is a key file system
for tesla in the beginning tesla only
provides the nfc card and mobile app to
access the wic
but later tesla has provided the
physical key fob but still it based on
ble and nfc
okay something you know now
interestingly some car company like four
they
provided a feature that we can unlock
the door with the pin code so we need to
something to always remember this
right
and something you are again some model
for not only
using pin codes to unlock the door it
has also provided a fingerprint reader
that means we can point our finger at it
and to unlock our car right
and some company uses face id for access
the vehicle has become a new trend too
and also the car companies like bmw and
hong kong prefer to use our human voice
print and integrate with a smart speaker
to control the cars like honda here and
with the
okay
now let's move from how do we do a
speaker recognitions movie
so
the definition of speaker
recognition is the identification of
person from characteristics of voice it
can be used to authenticate or verify
identity of a speaker as part of
security process and this
definition i took from the wikipedia
and the development history of speaker
recognition can be traced all the way
back to 60s
the speaker recognition
algorithm has started with a template
margin and then moved on to probability
model like gnm and gnmupn
and a feature classification like defect
d-vector and x-factors and so on
so the speaker recognition system
generally consists two categories like
feature extraction and feature matching
in reality
the
extracted features are matched
with features of people registered in
the database and then the identity is
determined based on
similarity
of these two features
so for the content to be recognized the
speaker recognition system is generally
divided into three categories
the first one is a fixed vocabulary
recognition it means
voice print recognition through fixed
vocabulary strategy has hey siri
and second one is fixed voice plus
random content recognition it means the
fixed con the fixed the random contents
combined together such as hey bob to 600
and to 2600 is generated randomly by
their system
and finally the random content
recognition its entire trade phrase is
generated randomly by the system
now
as you can see the speaker recognition
system are already everywhere
from exact control system in a voice
assistant in the car
but what could the possibility go wrong
then
here we list lately the some of the most
common smoothie methods for spherical
recognition
yes the one is called either an
impersonation attack
the attacker tries to
impersonate the
victim's
speaking turn
to disable the target system but this
attack can be easily detected by the
speaker vaccination system
and there are more effective and
let's say the attacks
causing the replay attack
speech
sentences wise commercial conversing
and
the adversarial is the example of attack
we are going to talk about those attacks
in more due to
the later leader
now
let's target duke replay attack is mini
in the either system of
fixed sentence
verification we can use the recording
device to record
the fixed sentence
of the victims
and
replace the recording the sentence
during verification to deceive the
spherical recognition system
as we can see
from male spectrogram
the uh similarity
from replay the wise
compared to
a genuine voice is high this is why the
replay type is very simple
yes
very type effective attack however this
simple method may not pass the speaker
authentication system with the yc
anticipation
now let's see some demos there are
already plenty of
third-party apps
can control smart cars like tesla using
siri this is a video demo for the
reflect attack on siri and
because some of the
magazines like uh unlocked blue is
authentication like pin codes for the
for this app
we can only open the chat port
with it
yeah the door currently is is locked
yeah and then
yeah the port is open
however we have found at least one app
that doesn't need to
extra
casing and we can
unlock the tesla very easily
not
oh sorry
yeah it works
okay
now let's take a look at the speech
sentences
text to speech
aggressor
let's take
google's ass way to tts as an example
the entire switch sentences can be
divided into three parts the speaker
encoder
module is responsible for
extracting
attracting speaker features from short
sentence
the synthesizer module is responsible
for
combining the speaker feature
with text to
generate a male spectrogram
that integrates the
specif by the speaker features into
the speech
corresponding to
the
specified text the
recorder measure is responsible for
generating wise they died
with male specular gram
which is the audio
data we use for tts type
and the
further
as with foreign tti's which open sourced
by google
in a
perfect
situation
it concludes wise in just five sec
seconds
to
generate the
rc speech in real time
and
this is a demo for the speech synthesis
attack
the first demo is to attack the battle
smarter speaker
the battle smarter speaker has ideal
antisprouting enabled
but we can use ttis to spool it and
impersonate as other people
and the second demo is to attack the
t-mode speaker well it can also be
spoofed by tdi's attack we can't go even
further by impersonator someone else to
purchase something online
nice
so this is a fixed
vocabulary plus random content
so without modification we cannot
bypass the system
so now we're using monkey bird to
generate
this random content number
and replay to the team mode speaker
and we try to find the right angle to
the speaker
as you can see we may try a couple times
in order to get a work
yeah we start the purchase step so we
actually successfully attacked
adversarial example attack means
a
attacker has intentionally designed to
cut the machine learning model to make a
mistake from speaker recognition's
roofing attack the minko has to attack
the speaker recognition algorithm
or
by adding some
perturbation that has been
calculated
to the switch
data
to make the speech be
recognized as a genuine victim
to dissave the acidic syndication system
this is a whiteboard
impairment
for switch vaccinations
attack
on
on our
open source the project called decoding
the deep speech
we first play a
genuine recording
and
it can't be
recognized successfully
then we play the
crafter recording
under a deep speech translated
differently that means our attack
exercise
so let's
summaries our smoothing methods about
speakers recognition as we can see the
fixed
vocabulary is the
easiest
one to attack a simple replay will work
just fine and further
vendor contents we still can't use
speech sentences or adversarial example
to the type
okay
so
um okay time to move on the facial
recognition spoofing
the facial recognition is a technology
capable to matching a human face from a
ditch to image or radio frame against
the database offices
usually it can be used for a syndicate
user through id verification servers
and the facial recognition technology is
constantly evolving it was based on low
dimension characterisation
and then nowadays it has involved the
three three dimension phase recognition
and there are already many applications
implemented the face recognition for for
example the face id to unlock our mobile
phone and iphone
and boarding the plan in the airport
and operationally the car company has
started to use face recognition
technology for driver monitoring system
and also use face id for driver profile
to improve the driving experience
and of course
use the human face to authenticate the
owner of vehicle is indeed a very
convenient way
and here are the four stages of face
recognition
procedure the first one is phase
detection so basically the system need
to know if there's a human face or cat
face
and second is a life needs detection aka
face auntie spoofing only
this stage played a very important role
in the face recognition procedure and
third and fourth is a feature
instruction and a feature matching
and at this stage the system will try to
match the face features from the
database
and let's take close look at the phase
recognition procedure
but this time without anti phase
spoofing
first the input in the input data is the
image
the system need to determine
whether it's a human face
once the system is about a human face it
will try to extract the features from
this particular
human face
and in the final step the system will
match the phase features to see if it's
in the database
and next let's talk about more about
phase on this movie
as we mentioned this stage plays a very
important role in the face recognition
procedure usually we need to do some
action like open our mouths or shake our
head
for a system to determine whether the
human face is presented is a real human
being or just piece of paper
in addition the system can do a silent
face anti-spoofing which means no
human action required it will determine
based on things like human skin texture
or different frequency of motion and so
on
and this is a phase recognition
structure from the diagram that we can
see
there are many other entry points to
attack for example later in the talk
we're going to share more real life
cases such as trash hold value and
feature value attack
so what could possibly go wrong
so here we have listed the six most
common methods to spoof the facial
recognition system for example the photo
attack and more advanced attack like it
was adverse serial example attack we're
going to talk about this attacks in more
details next
so this is the face photo attack we can
print weapons written
photo on a piece of paper and as you can
see it's very easy to to to do
even kids can do it right see they are
very happy
and this is what we call mr orange
attack basically we draw a human face on
orange
and in order to test the target system
phase detection function
and as we mentioned human face detection
is the first stage of every
phase recognition system simply draw a
human face on orange we easily spoof the
fish the facial recognition system when
the system does not have good phase
antisporting mechanism
okay so
our first target of smart lock from
xiaomi
let's play the video first
okay
as we can see from the radio recording
when we presented a orange to lock we
will not just detect it as a real human
even but even think this guy is 24 years
old
and we also test the xiaomi lock with a
face photo attack and adversarial
example
attack and as we can see every tricks
will work
the picture from the left is a real
human vector
and xiaomi lock has detected correctly
but when we present a phase photo which
is the one in the middle
uh
and this adverse serial example mask
this one here
it will also detect it as a same
victim so that all works
but this type of attack can be easily
prevented because some more advanced
system it will come with the um infrared
camera and this is what it looks like
from a facial
recognition system on foot wheel as we
can see if we presented a human face
photo or video on a mobile select one
here
on the right and to the infrared camera
you will actually see nothing at all
um usually we need to do some action
like open our mouths or shake your head
for the face
onto spoofing system to depend determine
whether your face presented is a real
human being or not but what can we do
well what we can do is cut a hole
and
in the eyes or mouse area
to bypass the detection
and we even can buy a customizing face
sculpture
to to bypass the system which lacks
detection on a human skin texture
so here's the video demo for the face
sculpture attack on
huawei p30
pro
hey
so it's worth it
uh as we mentioned early on the
principle of adversarial example attack
is a attacker as intentionally designed
girl to cast a machine learning model to
make a mistake
as we can see when we added a small
product perturbation to the hana picture
the
machine model will have
99 on three
percent
confidence
to think it is
even instant and this is a classic
adversarial example type
and based on various
characteristics adversarial example can
be
a divided into three different attack
methods such as
with a without target
white box
or black box attack
and
one step of multi-step type
we mainly use the black box
adversarial example attack method for
testing
the stressful ability
of the one serial example is
guaranteed by john
training of multiple models
the normal model training process is to
try the
parameters
of the model of the
data set big data set
the
uh adversarial or simple as chinese
symbol under the condition of fixed
parameters
which
continuously
makes the output of the model close to
our
expectations
at the basin aerial
fluxing has a big impact on the attack
without recap id
we can add perturbation in different
areas on the face but based on a
research article
ramu chinhua university
the
pertinent area within the eyes and the
nose
as a
parents
success rate
so once we
made the uh
the serial example based mask we can
present
to some online face id
algorithm for testing
one interesting fact is even we use the
same mask because
because the human face skin and
shape
are different
one person may have more success with
than the others
as
if the picture shows only 73
the
similarity and
the picture on the right have 89
percent
okay so
this is a video demo for the adversarial
example attack on huawei p30 pro face id
login system
so first this is a real person
it can be
login successfully now
the attackers come in
it doesn't work at the first time
and then he starts wearing a
adversarial example
mask
straight
right so
and this this is a video demo for the
adverse serial example attack on wema
welcome face id system
so again
without a mask
it doesn't work
so now we start wearing
a
modified
mask
let's try again
regarding
and this is another video
uh the demo
but the target is the car which we
cannot disclose the name um but this car
actually
allows us to turn on the engine
and drive off if we bypass the face id
system
so
it's kind of scary uh
if we can bypass it right with the
adversarial example mask
so we need to continue you see them
we can need to try
and yeah eventually it works
so
okay
so now we have the clear idea of
principle of
adversarial attack is we can add a small
perturbation
to cause the machine learning model to
make a mistake and during the research
we have found by putting a target face
image on the attacker's face uh it can
come it can cover attack phase partially
and we can deceive some of
our face recognition system with the
higher successful rate
and this
this is a common limitation for 2d
face recognition system
so this is a radio demo for the feature
replace attack
and we test it on xiaomi note 9.
so
without a mask
it won't work
then i will gonna wear this
special mask
always works all the time
um well of course
when system center rule so tight and
like very high threshold value we won't
able to bypass it easily
and this one is the face id system for
banking
login system which we will file to
getting
good funding and for us right
and so
the threshold value this is car where
pen tested before which you cannot
discuss the name
but just like a lost smart car
uh it has a android based ivi which we
were able to get in
uh in the engineer mode and then we once
we're in the engineer mode we're able to
enable adb connection
and once we got a db cell
uh we are root straight away so what we
what would you do when you got a rose on
ioi
um
maybe you replace the new screen feature
maybe
right
see
pretty cool
so and this car also gets a
face id function however the anti-facial
spoofing is so tight so good so we
cannot spoof it with the tricks we were
just mentioned above
but we are roots on the system remember
turns out the threshold value configure
file is stored locally on the ibi so we
can actually modify it to a very low
value in order to bypass it right
so here's the video demo
for the attack
so first we saw modify the threshold
value
and when we tried to log in
it failed
try again
yeah it won't work
so
then we start to do some magic like by
changing the threshold value
and
once we change it we need to uh reboot
iui system in order to get it from
working
so
once the system uh is rebooted itself
and we can go in to try again to see if
it works
so
now system reboot it
okay
so let's try again
you can see the season
yeah it's working see
sinking sinking thinking
yeah
cool
similarly this is a face id system we
have come across during another pen test
ops
but this system has two human features
stored in the database once we got root
in the system we can replace one feature
for our own
and then the system will verify any one
thing for logging in successfully which
means we can log in as a victim
victims still able to log in as in
themselves
which means nobody will even know we
were there
okay
now
what if we cannot get a
cell on a target and then the rules of
face id is so tight
and
are we our option yet
let's take a look
see
the door is open
so yeah a simple rf replay attack will
work
because
uh those access control system usually
have multiple features enabled
so it turns out our target can also be
opened by a fixed
code radio remote controller just like
people said it's not a bug it's a
feature
okay let's summarize some of the
technique we have seen
so far
for the face detection it can be spoofed
by a mr orange attack
um phase photo attack and phase
sculpture attack
and for the face anti-spoofing
the feature replace attack and the
serial example attack will work
and for the future matching feature
value attack threshold value attack is
always a trick we can always try
so in the end let's not forget those
extra function attack by re using the
hacker if or something to
uh replay right
okay
here's uh some uh references if anyone
like to look to know more
and
see we can for the research we have done
a lot of readings right
um
yeah i think that's it thank you
you