okay
so
this talk
is about the importance of sysmon for
investigations i'm extreme paper clip
who am i exactly
uh digital forensics nerd linux geek
infosec dork lifelong student of
everything
amateur history buff
spice fanatic
loads of fun
can follow me on the twitters but i'm
probably not that interesting
okay
what this talk is and is not about this
talk
is not an advanced guide to sysmod
what it is is basically just a simple
intro to sysmon
here are a few things we're going to
talk about we'll talk about what is
sysmon
an overview of the sysmon events
what is the sysmond config
we'll go over installing sysmon
and
some examples of my favorite sysmon
events
and some sysmon examples
for an investigation
okay
so
you're probably asking
really just cut to the chase and tell me
what is sysmon
okay here's the tldr sysmond creates the
logs that should exist in windows event
logs by default but do not
sysmon creates very unique
event logs
specific
for security
think of it that way
here are some more facts about sysmont
so sysmon was created by mark
versinofiche and
thomas garnier
sysmon is short for system monitor
it's a part of the windows sys internal
suite
sysmon was released in 2014
it's
both a device driver and a service
and it creates logs specifically for
security you could say
a very brief history of susman so it was
first released in 2014
and it initially only had three event
ids
event id 1 which shows a process created
event id 2 a process changed a file
creation time
and event id 3
network connection
this little snippet right here i took
from web archive
so
let's do it an overview here of the
sysmon events
the latest version of cisvan has 26
event ids
it's version 1334
and you can see there that it was
released in may
of 2022
note also there's also a version
for linux this is a recent thing
uh i'm not gonna go into it on this talk
but it's something you should check out
okay let's go over all the events don't
worry we're not gonna
deep dive into these
uh so
let's do an overview of these events
event id one
uh like like i said earlier is process
creation
um some of the things that are really
interesting about event id one uh of
course
two things in my opinion
uh you're gonna see the command line
and you're gonna get a hash
of the process
it's very useful
uh i'm going to go a little quicker here
so event id 2 the process change the
file creation time
event id 3 network connection
very useful
uh event id4 sysmont service state
changed you can see in the logs if
sysmon was stopped
and of course event id5 the process was
terminated
event id 6 a driver was loaded
this can be very useful
event id 7 is image loaded now think of
an image not like a picture uh in the
world of cis1 an image is basically
an executable
event id 8 is create remote thread
uh
event id 9 raw access read
event id 10 process access now event id
10 can be very useful
uh for example at
finding evidence of
mimikats
event id 11 file create
also very useful you can see something
like if a
somebody ran
a query to
spit out
bloodhound.zip you're going to see that
that file was created
event id 12 these are you could think of
these as the the registry events here
this one event id 12 talks about an
object was created or deleted
in the registry
event id 13
shows you the value that was set
for that registry event and event id 14.
it talks about the key and value rename
event id 15
create stream hash
um i'll be honest
this one hasn't really rocked my world
um
event id 16 service configuration change
and these two below are the pipe
events
so you can see a pipe created event id
17 and event id 18 pipe connected
this can be very useful in malware
hunting
event id 19 wmi event these are you
could think of these as the wmi events
here
you can show event id 19 shows activity
detected
event id 20
shows uh
the
consumer
event id
consumer to filter
fun stuff
okay event id 22 dns event very cool i
love that one
event id 23 file deleted
uh
can be
useful it can also be noisy
uh event id 24 clipboard change
uh i'll be honest this one
kind of baffles me uh event id 25
process tampering
a good example of that is
if you
hollow
an executable
let's see there's a tool called shelter
that can help you do that where you can
insert a payload for a shell code
event id 26 file delete detected it
could be good and it could be bad
because it can be very noisy
okay those are the events so
let's talk about
the sysmon config
the sysfont config here's the tldr the
syswan config
is an xml file that defines what gets
included or excluded in the sysmon logs
it's a big deal
why
why is it a big deal
well okay so it's a big deal because if
your sysmon config is configured to be
over inclusive
you could end up with a lot of garbage
data
that can make it hard to analyze and and
sift through
and uh on the other hand if you exclude
too much
in your sysmond config then you're
probably going to be missing valuable
log data that could potentially contain
evidence of malicious activity
so
here's
a few facts about the sysmond config
here's a little example um
so in
right here you can see in the xml file
some things i'll just point them out uh
the rule group is like a simple way you
can group the rules
for a specific event id
uh and note the way that the in this
case the group relation uses the and to
define how the rules are used an
alternative to this would be an or
um okay process create
let's see is an example of
basically event id one
and this rule right here is going to
match on include
image like i said is is the word used
for an executable in this example the
image is timeout.exe
command line
uh is one of the fields
in event id1 and in this example it
shows us that the command line simply
just contains 100.
a little more about the system on config
as you'll note in the sysmond config
there are conditions you can use you can
see here in this little example that's
uh
and
or condition
equals is
or condition equals
end with
or begin with
so
you might be thinking
where do i get a good
pre-made
sysmond config that i can start with
yeah it's a great question
so
i would say that
olaf hartong has a great system on
config
and he makes a great modular
sysmon config that you can use
to easily customize your rules
for each event id
it makes it very easy to
manage
big thanks to olaf for making such a
great cis1 config
okay let's take a little look here
so
here you can see
a little of what his sysmon config looks
like
um
olaf's sysmont config is pretty darn
great uh but you have to understand you
will need to spend some time getting to
know the sysmon config and adjust it to
your specific environment
it's a
big part of it a big deal
to help you with that
you can go to the trusted sex system
community guide which is
quite wonderful
and written by
carlos perez dark operator
a note about carlos pretty much
anything he writes or creates
is amazing you can learn a lot from him
okay
now let's talk about
installing sysmon
it's quite easy you just follow these
steps you basically download this sysmon
unzip
grab your sysmon config make sure you
save it to the same folder
and then you're going to run this
command
right there
you note you can also do this with the
script of course i'm not going to go
into that for the sake of time but just
know that that's an option
so after sus1 is installed you should
see this
and if you want to go see the cis1 logs
you can open up
event viewer
and go to applications services logs
microsoft
windows
sysfon and click on operational
and then you'll see the logs
okay now what
you might say
okay i have installed this one now what
well now you need to send these cismod
events to a sim
and you might ask
wait what is this in
a sim is basically a security
information and event management system
and it's think of it like a cen it's
basically a central place to send all
your logs
so you can analyze and search the data
and here are a few uh examples
splunk
is they have of course a paid version
and they have a free version but
note that the free version allows up to
500 megabytes per day
which is actually not a lot of data
you might be surprised how quickly you
get to that limit
uh security onion is great it's free
it's a great community but note that
you're on your own to set it up and get
it running
and the same is true with the elk stack
by elastic
so
let's talk a bit about some examples of
my favorite sysmon events
since spawn event like i said event id
one
process creation
is just fabulous
uh sysmon event id3
network connection
also fabulous
sysfon event 22 dns event
fabulous
let's talk about them
so
in sysmon event id 1
i wanted to show you here a little
example of some of the
fields that it captures
uh
so in the field
rule name you can see there i just want
to note uh olaf's sysmon config contains
miter attack ids here and that's very
useful
uh note the image which is the
executable
in this case it's notepad plus plus
uh let's see
also you can see here the command line
that's
the greatest that's wonderful
you can see the user in this case it's
just username is just an example
and this is also very very important
you get hashes
so you can see the sha1 md5 hash
it's cut off but you can't see it but
over on the
right you can also get imp hash
note also at the bottom you can see the
parent image which was the parent
executable
and the parent command line
wonderful
okay
event id 3 network connection
uh here's here i show you an example
here i just included it
note in the rule name you can see right
there
what olaf's
sysmon config has for the rule name you
can see the
miter attack id
wonderful
and in this case let's see you can also
see the user
you can see the protocol
source
ip
source port
destination ip
destination port
absolutely wonderful
so valuable
so
event id 22
dns event dns query
uh this is such a great event uh
one of the greatest parts about this you
can see the query name right there in
the middle in this case it's
some google
telemetry garbage probably
and you can see the image the executable
firefox and it shows you the user
okay let's get to some examples
of sysmon used during an investigation
so in this case you can see sysmon event
id1
and we're doing a query for
uh the command who am i
this can be
either
completely
harmless
event
or
it could be an attacker that ran who am
i
to understand what kind of uh privileges
they have because they had just popped
the box and they're
so
very useful
and here
we're looking at sysmon event id 3.
this is just a general search really to
look at
the processes source ip source port
destination ip
destination port
these can be
very interesting
for example if i was to
specify the destination port as 445
that would be very interesting showing
smb
okay
this is spawn event id 22 this is a
really good one it's really fun uh this
is rare
dns queries
so we're looking basically at one
machine in particular
and we're looking at the rare
dns queries that it ran
this can be very interesting very
helpful during an investigation
okay
some closing thoughts
so
what what do you see here yeah
these are some typical answers i've
heard when i ask folks who work in
incident response
if the companies they work with
resolving an incident
have sysmon deployed in their
environment
so i see things like rarely
never
hardly ever
this is a good one yes but not
configured to send to the sim
so i guess
i just want to say you know
if you have never
deployed sysmon
in your environment
please do
install sysmon and make sure you send
the suspend events to a sim
could really help everybody
in an incident
that's it thanks
join the conversation uh meet up with
the blue team village
discord.blueteamvillage.org
i'm extreme paper
clip thanks
and you're clear