i got someone special here a sponsor i
really like to talk to you i know
everyone's going to be interested a
really big part of the community
infrastructure services in general um
talking more about it i have keith
hey keith how you doing
good john thanks for having me on today
no thank you for your support and really
excited to have you guys
i guess quick intro uh can you introduce
yourself and uh talk about what you do
at ngrok
yeah absolutely so uh my nickname is
danger but my actual name is keith casey
i tell people my first name is danger uh
conveniently enough my email is
dangerngrock.com
uh but what i do at ingrock is i make
sure that we are we're telling stories
that are useful that we're sharing
documentation that's useful that we're
uh
using use cases or sharing use cases
that are useful making sure we're
solving real problems for people as
opposed to convincing them they have
problems they don't actually have
very cool awesome so um yeah again thank
you for uh supporting red team village
just wanted to know why you wanted to be
involved and
like what are your ties to like cyber
security
yeah absolutely so uh myself personally
a good number of people on the ingrock
team
spent years at octa doing single sign-on
identity management so there's a lot of
deep identity and security routes there
uh ingrock itself we are we're an active
participant in the ecosystem we've got
millions of users and unfortunately some
portion of them are bad actors if you
caught the trend micro report a few
months ago you know we are a fishing we
are often used in fishing tools uh which
is unfortunate and we're trying to stop
that we're trying to work together with
different teams uh to prevent that from
happening so we looked out for guys like
yourself or teams like red team village
and everything to be able to say what
are what are people doing like what's
the bleeding edge of stuff how can we
learn what's going on and we want to
meet the responsible researchers out
there work with you guys more regularly
more
more quickly so that when patterns
happen we can we can go ahead we can
step in we can interrupt them uh we want
to you know work with some of the best
and brightest see what they're doing see
what we can learn see how we can
mitigate things and more than anything
like learn about what you're doing in
your day job even outside of ingrock uh
totally unrelated to that sort of thing
because yeah you know we we are a major
player in the ecosystem and we want to
be a good citizen about that
definitely yeah no uh it's a great
product really uh nice to use
for
good security practices it's just
unfortunate it's been abused but
it's it really goes towards the
accessibility and availability and how
how awesome the product is the the
tunneling the edge service so um yeah uh
i guess if you could talk about um
you know it's gonna be interesting
discussions with with your team and uh
some of the participants but for someone
that isn't really entrenched into cyber
security
uh what would you uh say your top three
recommendations are for like starting in
there
oh getting started getting started is
always one of the the hardest things to
think of because i try to rewind back to
when i was doing it
i'd say right now a good principle
career principle in general not just
cyber security related is always be
learning uh pick up see what people are
doing see what the latest news reports
are when you when there's a breach that
happens there's one going around right
now related to sms and uh second factor
read about it learn uh dig into the
postmortem see what's going on see how
uh see how it was perpetrated on the
flip side see how it could have been
mitigated so with the like the sms
attack going on right now uh you you
figure out pretty quickly that otp codes
are not always the best option and in
fact are often not a good option at all
in different circumstances right so
uh so it's it's learning and then
understanding what works and what
doesn't work and then me personally one
of the things that's always served me
well is whenever i'm trying to analyze a
system whether that system is an
organization or whether that is a an
application or whatever i try to dig up
the assumptions
what assumptions did somebody have when
they're building this when they're
designing this this operation
and what happens if those assumptions
are wrong
so how can we test each of them how can
we figure out if this assumption is
wrong what happens then and frankly it's
so much fun because people think oh yeah
this is always going to be the case or
this will never be the case
and then you just tweak it you see
figure out what happens now
awesome yeah no sounds it is fun stuff
and um i'm happy that uh
that's kind of like the
the motto you guys go by and i'm sure at
n grog it's a similar uh mentality um is
ngrok hiring if so
how can people find out more information
yeah so uh we're hiring just across just
about every team we're about 45 people
right now uh we're looking at 20 to 30
people by the end of the year uh that's
in marketing and sales in engineering
and we're looking actually for a couple
application security people uh so those
are obviously top of mind for this crew
but just go to ingrock.com
careers and you can find everything
there
in addition we're on twitter ingrockhq
um you know find us on linkedin we're
we've got a great team and we're hiring
across just about every team and happy
to talk to everybody
yeah awesome no after talking with you
and your your teammates uh really great
people to work with and uh excited to
work with them during the the con and uh
yeah thank you so much for your time uh
yeah you know i'll make sure if people
go to the careers uh
they say
danger sent me right so yes well i
always tell people when you need to find
me look for danger and i'll be there
all right you have questions about
ingrock specifically feel free to draw
me an email it's danger ingrock.com
all right well uh thank you again
[Music]