so our paper of the ultra long title
discusses the security of data on blue
with low energy devices I'm sorry Oh
should I speak louder okay discusses the
security of data on Bluetooth low-energy
devices when accessed by Android
applications so begin by giving a brief
overview on their taxes mechanisms with
Bluetooth Low Energy with Bluetooth Low
Energy unlike with classic Bluetooth
data is handled primarily as small
discrete values and these are referred
to as attributes there are different
types of attributes and the type that we
are most interested in are called
characteristic value attributes and
these are the actual data values of
interest so for example a characteristic
value could hold a user's heart rate
measurement or cycling speed it could
also hold the speed of a ble enabled
hoverboard accessing a characteristic
value is fairly straightforward you send
a request and you get a response there
are other access mechanisms but I'll
only be focusing on request responses so
while it could be a fairly
straightforward process there are
occasions where we might not want it to
be quite this straightforward because
the characteristic value holds data that
is either sensitive or critical so if as
I mentioned a characteristic value holds
a user's heart rate or glucose
measurement then that data has
associated privacy concerns and we
wouldn't want random people reading that
information if on the other hand the
characteristic value controls the speed
or the movement of a ble enabled
hoverboard
then that data has safety implications
and we wouldn't want random entities
being able to write to it and so there
are occasions where we would want to
control access to the characteristics if
we have to do this natively then we
would assign permissions to the
characteristics auto attributes in
general so there are three different
types of permissions and only the first
two are actually fully defined within
the Bluetooth specification access
permissions essentially say whether or
not an attribute can be read and or
written authentication permissions
restrict access to an attribute by
requiring that the access request come
over and authenticate an encrypted link
and the way we get such an authenticated
and encrypted link is
pairing and we have termed
characteristics which have associated
authentication permissions as being
pairing protected authorization
permissions are implementation-specific
and are left left up to developers so if
we take the most common use case
especially in the consumer scenario of a
ble device that interfaces with a mobile
application we ask ourselves where the
device has an official application that
it's supposed to interface with would
another unauthorized application
residing on the same mobile device be
able to access pairing protected data
from the ble device and to test this we
prototype the ble device using the
nordic development kit and our device
has a protected characteristic on it we
also develop two Android applications
one which is a good app and which is
supposed to be able to access the
protected characteristic and another
which is the malicious app which is not
supposed to be and I should say that the
two applications have essentially the
same functionality the difference is
mainly in terms of user expectation and
awareness so in the first unauthorized
data access scenario we launched our
good application and it scans for and
connects to our ble device and issues a
request for accessing the protected
characteristic because the two devices
don't have a trust relationship at this
point this will result in an
insufficient authentication error and as
soon as the Android operating system
sees this error it will initiate the
pairing process and at this point it may
be the first time that the user becomes
aware that this application is trying to
access data from their ble device and I
should mention here that I only consider
strong pairing mechanisms where I user
interaction is actually required so if
the user decides to go ahead with
pairing then the two devices will
generate keys encrypt the transport
between them and then typically go
through a process called bonding where
long term keys are generated if the good
app tries to read or write
the pairing protected characteristic
from that point onwards it will be met
with valid responses because the request
will be coming over the encrypted link
so now let's say our good luck
disconnects and our malicious
application scans for and connects to
the device what we saw from Android ble
logs is that as soon as the connection
takes place the Android operating system
automatically encrypts the link
presumably using the credentials that
were generated during the previous
pairing process this means that the
malicious application has this automatic
encrypted link over which it can issue
read/write requests for the pairing a
protected characteristic and get valid
responses and the thing here is that the
user won't be aware because link wray
encryption usually takes place silently
now this happens because pairing
essentially happens between devices
rather than between the application
layers and if in fact it happens between
the lower layers of the ble stack so
that means that the pairing is going to
be common to all the applications of the
requesting device a similar result was
identified for classic Bluetooth a few
years ago by Naveed at all but with
Bluetooth Low Energy a malicious
application is able to access data in
ways that would not be possible with
classic Bluetooth so that brings us to
our second unauthorized data access
scenario and we start afresh we remove
the existing pairing credentials from
both devices and we launch our good app
again it scans for and connects triggers
the pairing exchange and results in an
encrypted link as before this time
though let's say that the good duck
doesn't disconnect so while it's still
communicating with the ble device a
malicious application that's running at
the same time can issue a get connected
devices command and this will return a
list of the Bluetooth devices that are
currently in a connection with the
Android device the malicious app can
then select our cast device from that
list and connect or make use of the
existing connections it can piggyback
onto the connection and issue readwrite
requests for the characteristic so this
is a form of opportunistic data access
which is not possible with classic
Bluetooth in classic Bluetooth as Naveed
at all found an application creates a
socket connection to a Bluetooth device
and while one application is in a
connection
another cannot connect but with ble
multiple applications on the same device
can share the same connect
to a ble device another interesting
thing to note here is that the malicious
application didn't need to perform
scanning so if we go back the good app
scan for and connected to the ble device
but because the malicious application
uses an existing connection it didn't
need to perform scanning and this has an
interesting impact on the permissions
that need to be requested by the two
applications so because our good app
performs scanning and we consider
scanning without a scan filter it needs
to request the Bluetooth and Bluetooth
admin permissions and from Android 6.0
onwards it also needs to request
location permissions and because
location permissions are considered to
be dangerous permissions the first time
that the good app is launched a
confirmation dialog is going to be
displayed to the user asking them
whether they're okay with the fact that
this application is accessing their
location because on the other hand the
malicious application doesn't perform
scanning it only needs to request the
Bluetooth permission and because this is
not a dangerous permission
there will be no confirmation dialog and
from the users point of view the
malicious application is going to seem
more benign than even the good app and
this could influence the number of
downloads that the malicious application
can generate so we've seen that it is
possible for unauthorized applications
to access data pairing protected data
from ble devices so a question would
then probably be what would we do to
protect the ble data and ideally what we
want is a solution where protection
extends from the ble device all the way
up to the application on the requesting
device they show is that there are
multiple stakeholders within the ble
ecosystem and it's difficult to
determine which stakeholders should be
responsible for making the changes that
would safeguard data so just based on
the data access scenarios I've shown it
might seem that Android needs to be the
one to make the changes to for example
not allow multiple applications to share
a connection and also maybe to do
something like associate pairing
credentials with the application that
originally triggered the pairing the
thing is that pairing and the fact that
it happens between say the lower layers
of the ble stack
is something that's defined within the
Bluetooth specification itself and so
maybe the specification needs to be
modified or perhaps added to to
incorporate additional protection
mechanisms that extend all the way up to
the application layer in addition the
Bluetooth special interest group who
define and maintain the specification
also define things called profiles which
can be implemented by ble devices and
there are profiles for different things
so for example there's a heartrate
profile and a glucose measurement
profile and within these profiles
pairing is specified as the only
security mechanism so it would seem from
them that pairing is sufficient for
handling of a protecting sensitive data
and we've seen that it's not so in
addition to modifying the specification
perhaps the special interest group
should also modify these profiles as
well the thing is that ble has this sort
of promise of flexibility that a user
should not be tied to one application
that they should be able to download and
use multiple applications with their
devices if they want to and so any
protection mechanism they create there
has to be some way for them to allow
multiple applications that the user
specifically authorizes to connect to
their ble device while disallowing
everything else the problem is that both
of these like if either one of these
entities are to create any changes then
there will be some design and
development effort involved and it's not
going to happen in the immediate term
and so right now like it or not it's
probably up to the ble developers to
implement into and security if we want
our ble data to be safeguarded and that
brought us on to our next question which
was what proportion of ble devices out
there right now actually have such into
n protection for their data so we're
saying data traverses between a ble
device and an application and we want to
know how much of the data is protected
end to end and by protection I do mean
cryptographic ultratech sure and to test
this we could either test the ble
firmware or we could test the mobile
applications and android apk is in
particular are much easier to come by
and easier to decompile and analyze
than ble firmware and so we went the apk
away we developed a Python tool called
ble crip tracer which would analyze
Android apks and try and identify the
presence of a link between ble data and
crypto functions so the tool does this
by using and regard to decompile apks
and obtain the intermediate small e
representation it then identifies any
beta ble data access calls within the
code and from that point it will try and
trace through the code to see whether
the ble data hits a cryptographic
function on the way which would indicate
that the data has been cryptographically
processed at all does this in three
different stages and in the first stage
it tries to identify the most direct
link possible between ble data and
crypto functions and it does this by
considering only direct register or
field value transfers as well as the
results of immediate method invocations
and if a link is identified in this
manner then the result is given a
confidence level of high because we're
fairly certain that cryptographically
processed data will actually exist if a
direct link cannot be identified then
the tool will
in addition consider abstract and
interface methods as well as registers
that were used as arguments to
previously encountered methods and if a
link is identified using this method
then because there's some level of
uncertainty involved the result will be
given a confidence level of medium if
neither method actually produces a
result then the tool will look through
every instruction of every method that
was previously encountered which
originated from the ble data access call
and if any of those instructions contain
a reference to crypto then the result
will be given a confidence level of low
because there's quite a lot of
uncertainty involved we tested our tool
against the Droid bench benchmarking
suite which was modified for the ble
case and we found that in general the
results from our tool at confidence
level high were on par with other cain't
analysis tools but ble crypt racer was
better suited for that specific use case
of identifying end-to-end protection for
ble date
we also executed our tool against almost
19,000 real-world apks that have ble
data access calls and these are the
results at a high level because of the
uncertainty I mentioned with results at
medium and low I'm only going to focus
on those results that either from where
an apk was identified as having crypto
with high confidence or where no crypto
was identified at all and we can see
that almost half of all a peak is
actually don't seem to have into and
protection for their ble data we
analyzed our results further and we
found that more than half of the apks we
tested actually made use of third-party
libraries to incorporate ble
functionality so these could be wrapper
functions or they could be something
like beacon libraries and interestingly
those applications that use third-party
libraries were more likely to have
end-to-end protection with a ble data
than applications where the ble
functionality was incorporated by the
developer themselves in fact one
particular beacon library actually
accounted for over 85 percent of all the
cases where we identified crypto with
high confidence we then I am analyzed
our results in terms of the Google Play
categories that the AP case fell under
and we saw that interestingly AP case
that were on the medical was some of the
least likely to have into n protection
for the RB le data and this seems
strange because you would assume that
there'd be the most likely to have
protection but then we analyzed a subset
of these apks and we found that some of
them at least made use of the official
ble profiles in which powering is
Pradesh fide as the only protection
mechanism so that could account for at
least part of these results further we
looked at those ap case where ble
cryptographically process ble data was
identified with high confidence level
and we ran these apks through a tool
called cognitive and cognitive
essentially checks for cryptographically
correctness within android apks
and we found that in some cases bad
crypto practices were being used such as
the use of unsafe crypto mods or
hard-coded keys and this would imply
that even when ble data I supposedly
protected by cryptography sometimes a
crypto might not be implemented
correctly and the ble data might still
be vulnerable so in summary we've seen
that pairing protected data may be
vulnerable to unauthorized access by
different applications and this is
regardless of the strength of the
pairing mechanism so in our test we used
le secure connections with numeric
comparison which is one of the strongest
we've also seen that because of the
different stakeholders involved in the
ble ecosystem it's difficult to
determine which stakeholder should make
any changes to protect ble data right
now though Security's probably in the
hands of ble developers but it's
possible that the developers themselves
are not aware of this because almost
half of all the apks we tested showed no
evidence of into and protection for ble
data our tool is available on github and
we would welcome any feedback or
suggestions thank you very much for your
time and I'm happy to take any questions
so if you have a question for our
speaker feel free to come to one of the
microphones in the aisles did I for
everybody to sleep very interesting talk
thank you
one thing I've also seen an abscess that
they do enter an encryption between the
app not now between the device and the
server so the app would not do any
encryption or decryption how did you
deal with that in your statistics we
didn't actually because we can't and
then we did know that it's possible data
would just be shuttled through an apk so
that the the end-to-end would be between
a server and the ble device but there's
really no way of checking or accounting
for that because just because data is
transmitted to a server doesn't
necessarily mean it's being
cryptographically protected so we can't
say yes or no so we unfortunately had to
sort of disregard them thank you so I
actually have a question so it's clear
that there are a lot of weaknesses in
these applications but I was curious if
you were aware of any situation where
some party might be exploiting some of
this in the wild no we actually focus
mainly on benign applications and the
presence of crypto so we weren't
considering malicious entities at when
we were doing the previous analysis we
are doing some right now which may
produce some interesting results
we have we have one more question for
you yeah sorry that took a while for me
to go hey thank you for the talk very
interesting I was wondering um you
mentioned some of the malicious apps
that could sort of piggyback onto the
BOE connection I was wondering if there
are like not literary malicious but just
regular apps that could possibly do this
like accidentally and if you've
encountered them and sort of what they
might look like I mean I have seen
question I mean on Stack Overflow and
things where people do seem to want to
identify connected devices for some
legitimate purposes but they don't
actually mention the purpose and I can't
think of any reason why you would want
to use an existing connection especially
between two different apps so I would
say honestly just get rid of that
functionality if I have the choice cool
thank you alright so let's think our
speaker one more time
[Applause]