so thank you Matthias for the
introduction so my SM ray
I'm from the rural university both home
from Germany and yeah that's we
interestingly have developed
independently the same techniques
against fuzzing but I think we have a
different approach on how we did it
right yeah so so what is the motivation
why do we actually want to do this right
so let's say you are someone who does
not want their application to be out
there and people finding bugs right you
have a binary and you have some kind of
trusted party which is you yourself and
your team right so you have your own
security team who's hunting bugs and you
have also an untrusted party which are
people you do not know maybe and from
whom you don't want to find bugs right
so if this is your goal that they should
not be able to find bugs the question is
so how can we stop them from finding
bugs right so the first idea you might
have is to say hey if they can't reverse
engineer my binary they might not be
able to find the bugs right so you might
want to make that harder so they are not
able to look in this into your code but
in that case the question remains so
what about automated bug finding right
what about fuzzing
so obfuscation hinders manual reverse
engineering but if you have tools like
AFL it's still super easy and in our
paper we have shown that most occupation
techniques do not actually help against
housing right they will still be able to
find bugs and it's become super easy to
use tools like AFL so I had the student
who never heard of AFL before so he knew
something about fuzzing and in just one
day he figured out how to use it and
then found bugs in one major online
multiplayer game that's exploitable I
think even remotely I'm not sure so it's
super easy to use right there are also
projects like fast ex machina who took
the top 500
our clinics packages and then trust them
for a couple of days and in two days
they found several bugs that are
exploitable so this has become super
easy right you don't know but you don't
have to know much about security so how
do we impede fuzzing audits with that in
mind so what we want you to do is get a
diverse set of photos and analyze them
and the idea behind that is let's find
some assumptions that fathers have to
make necessarily and then break these
assumptions so what we did not want to
make what we did not want to do is just
target AFL specifically right we do not
want to detect is AFL running or
something like this let's find
assumptions that fathers have to make
contemporary fathers but also future for
us and then break those assumptions so
this should work universally so this is
the idea so what we did is we compiled a
list of contemporary fuzzing tools and
the ones with the black dot are the ones
that we actually looked at in our
evaluation and we tried to find out
assumptions which are the columns a B C
and D so we found four core assumptions
for these fathers and then we generalize
them to the to this list of 19,000 right
so they are all based on at least one of
the assumptions and then we break them
so what are these four assumptions so to
come to that I will use a demo
application to demonstrate the
techniques this is a simple one where
you just compare the first three bytes
of the input to elf and if that's the
case you just crash right and if that's
not the case you print out a warning
this is not a well at alpha right okay
so what are the assumptions that we
attack you so the first assumption is
coverage yields relevant feedback so
what does that mean you have to kind of
follow so in our paper we the courage
guided father
our fathers like AFL they use feedback
right and there are blind fathers that's
the name that we chose in our paper for
the ones they do they do not have any
feedback so both of them
they have some kind of input that they
mutate and both of them can see if a
crash has happened due to this input
right but in the case of the coverage
guided fada
we can also see if there was some new
coverage found and if there was new
coverage we can add it to the queue and
then mutated again later on to find even
more courage because find by finding
more coverage you get closer to
potential bugs right so here the
assumption is that the father's had to
make as that new courage means new
behavior if you find new courage you
fault new behavior that means you could
find potentially find new bugs right
this is a reasonable assumption nothing
wrong with this assumption works really
well but for us this is good to know so
we can attack it so what we did was we
added so there's a demo application
which a bunch of fake branches that have
some constraints that are seem
implausible that just jumped to each
other right so if some father is
observing this behavior it sees a lot of
jumping around a lot of new code code
coverage and the jumping around is based
on the input so the input is the seed
for the random number generator so you
just flip one bit of the input and it
will take another pass through this maze
that we introduced so for the father it
looks like every input is interesting
every input does something interesting
so the queue gets full of input that is
actually irrelevant but it's it's not
obvious for the father to see that in
case of AFL also as demonstrated earlier
the bitmap gets false you have so many
collisions you'd actually don't see
anything new happen so after you've done
that the father is actually blind it
rightly it can't use that feedback
measure mechanism any useful way but it
can still detect crashes so the second
assumption that we had is that crashes
obviously have to be observable for an
outside entity for the father and so the
idea is to just say hey why don't we
overwrite the signals and then at our
own custom signal handler that says oh
I've seen that we
she called me a crash has happened and I
will just gracefully exit instead right
so the outside entity just sees all the
application exited so there was no trash
there are also some other techniques
like detecting pee trace because that's
what hung fast users or gdb uses to see
that a crash has happened so this is the
one that you can actually add more stuff
to it if you if you know that more
techniques to detect crashes so now your
your father can't use the feedback
mechanism the coverage grandfather and
also can't see any crashes but also
there's a certain assumption that we
found out about which is that you need a
lot of executions per second to use
fuzzing in an efficient way so the
question that we asked ourselves why is
FL so good at what it does right so FL
is of news as a basis also in research
to build your own research on top of it
because it works so well right so there
are many reasons why it's good but for
us one of the most important is that
human knowledge is not necessary for FL
FL does not have to know and this is
this kind of application or what kind of
structure the application needs it just
knows this is a binary that I need to
fuss and coupled with there comes that
FL is just really well implemented it's
super fast it can do thousands of
executions per second even more and so
if you have these two conditions then
you don't actually have to be smart
about the code so yeah so the thing is
as long as you are fast as a FL as long
as you can introduce mutations and check
if the application part new coverage or
crash then you don't have to be smart
about what you're doing you don't have
to check like oh this is this kind of
constraint how do I solve it just add
more runs to just add more executions to
it and after a while most of the
constraints are solvable not all of them
so how do we beat this assumption right
so the bad approach would be to say
let's just slow down the application so
let's just add a slowdown of 100
milliseconds you will only get 10
executions the second but that's
actually bad because in
scenarios the binary that you're using
will also be slowed down by 100
milliseconds so what we ask ourself is
how can we do how can we do a better
version of this so we still want to slow
down the application so we only get 10
executions per second or less but what
if we can do this only when being fast
right but the idea is here to not detect
that you are being fast right not check
the environment like malware does right
not like going oh this is like sandbox
life this is AF Ellis running let's
let's introduce a slower but instead do
something a little bit more smart so
what we ask ourself is so what is the
implication of being fast where is the
difference of being fast and not being
fast and used in the real word pipe so
you know the answer because as I said
earlier they came with the same
techniques so what we can do is what we
observe is that most inputs while being
fast will be malformed right if you
start with an empty seat of course most
of the inputs depending on the
application will be malformed if you
took took lib traffic for example
started with an empty seat most of the
things that you trying at the beginning
will be malformed right if you start
with a valid JPEG file most of the
random rotations because a effeminate
most fathers don't know anything about
the application will lead to a malformed
input file but in real mad scenarios
again depending on the application
most inputs will be well-formed so most
JPEGs potentially that you find in the
wild will be well-formed right so the
idea here is to say let's just slow down
the application only if the input is
malformed so real words usage of the
binary will not be affected so that's
the idea so what we have done is to say
okay let's just go to the point where
the developer already decided that all
this is not a valid file and at a sleep
or something that it's maybe harder to
detect Allah to remove right some kind
of slowdown so it prints out there's not
a well Adel file and then it introduces
a sleep of 100
for example so we have broken this
assumption - so the last assumption is
constraints are solvable the symbolic
execution so as you have seen earlier on
the table there were some father's that
built upon this assumption not all of
them some fathers use symbolic execution
so the question is why do they do this
why would you use symbolic execution as
it turns out there are some constraints
that are just too hard to solve for FL
for example let's for example D word
comparison if you use plane AFL it's
just too hard to solve because you would
have to get four bytes of it at the same
time right it would take a lot of
execution to get that right but for
symbolic execution this is no problem it
can just tell you all these are the four
bytes that you need to solve this
constraint so it's efficient to use it
in that case so the Assumption here is
that there are some constraints that are
too hard to solve by random rotations
alone but symbolic executions can
actually help help you with that so how
do we break this assumption we develop
two techniques one of the techniques is
again similar to the falsification guys
we replace constant comparison by hash
comparison instead of saying hey added
three input bytes equal to elf we say
other is the hash of the three input
bytes equal to the hash of elf right and
the second idea that we introduced is
let's just put the input through
encryption decryption that does actually
nothing it's the same here it's the same
output but again for the symbolic
execution engine no the task would be
for the hash conversion to actually
figure out what was the correct input to
get this check to be right and in the
case of encryption decryption also to
automatically prove that the output
bites
only depend on the input bytes right so
that nothing happened and this is
obvious
so this pockets are symbolic execution
engine it can't actually give you any
results or it would take so so much time
that it's not efficient anymore so our
demo application looks like this so we
get the input put it through encryption
and decryption
then we replaced the elf compersion by
their respective hash comparisons so
yeah for the evaluation so the most part
of this of this paper was doing the
evaluation right so one of the things
that we did is we used a very simple
example a dummy application that just
checks for different bytes if they are
correct and if they are correct it just
crashes so the idea was if we can
protect this application this very
simple application from father's then
every more difficult more complex
application will also be protected and
as we can see here the father's that we
evaluated this on the assumptions that
we broke actually applies specifically
to those fellows that have this
assumption right that's all rely on this
assumption and we execute it then all
for 24 hours so they did not find a very
easy bug that was that they were able to
find in seconds or minutes before on the
plain binary and now with an tifa's they
are not able to find any bugs and then
we activated all of the features and let
it run for 100 hours and still they were
unable to find any bugs to observe
anything and - yeah so you might think
that yeah ok if you mask every bug if
you just hide the box of course you
won't see any bugs right so we wanted
also to demonstrate that this is not
just about hiding the back but also to
impeding fuzzing audits right so we let
it run for 24 hour 3 runs each and this
is one of the examples for binutils for
object dump and you can see that on the
plain binary it finds a lot of courage
in 24 hours the for thousands that we
looked at but when you protect the
application with anti fast it barely
finds more than the baseline right so
all the low-hanging fruit that you find
in the beginning that are too easy to
find those are the ones that you can
actually find so funding attempts are
actually really impeded by this so to
conclude this talk so what we did was we
had an systematic analysis of the worst
set of fathers and we found four core
assumptions that they rely on in the
hope that other father
in the future would also rely on this
assumption so we just break the
assumptions now and hopefully all the
other fathers that we do not know about
will also be broken so these are the
four right break courage guided fuzzing
just masks and just hide the bugs that
are still being found and then just slow
down the fuzzing attempt but not in
real-world cases and also boggle down
any symbolic execution attempts yeah so
this is what anti fast us and we
implemented it in a Python script that
generates a C header file that you can
include into your project and you can
find it here on our Rube Cystic page
yeah and yeah you can play around so
thank you for attention
any questions questions oh yeah sure
very good ask the same question no I
like this one so for your input
manipulation where you're looking for
what's considered a valid input and
invalid input yeah I'm assuming you're
looking at the program checks to kind of
verify that so let me say and at this
point this is all manually added by the
developer okay so we so the pacification
guys did the automatic finding of this
so we did not do this we said so the
developer knows where the past is the
file is now from it just at line of code
okay have you put any thought into what
type of file formats or input formats
would you no not really
this wouldn't be applicable to yeah so
we actually the the one that I showed
the object um it actually accepts a lot
of pellets things right so when we edit
the slowed down to this so most of the
times they did not do anything so I
could see the FLL output and it actually
could still do one hundreds or thousands
of executions right so I think there are
some programs that do not have any kind
of structure where it's not important so
in those cases it does not work but a
lot of applications we did not do any
evaluation
on which applications in specific in
particular but I think most applications
will have some kind of detection of math
on the input okay cool thank you thank
you
thanks for a nice stack I'm Mohammed
from UC Irvine my question is that did
you evaluate the effect of your work on
normal execution of the program yeah so
we had on the paper we had some
evaluation on the overhead introduced so
we protected the application with anti
fast and then we evaluated what the
overhead was on that application oh I
think it was so small that we couldn't
measure it so it's a really small number
great Huysmans yeah
so one question I had is if you're
relying on adding these delays to
uncommon paths then if this is like a
server application does this mean that
if I can make your server hit an
uncommon path path reliably I can cause
an ILO service this is a really good
point I should have mentioned that so of
course as a developer you should decide
when to introduce these techniques or
not and so application is a perfect
example where you should not do this
right so any kind of performance
critical application you should not do
any kind of slowdown but I also wondered
that as a as an attacker could you knock
out individual locations that you find
it slow down to fuzzing or use some form
of grammar based approach where you only
constrain the mutation to a certain part
of the program where it is valid so that
you get past all of these checks and
then can still find different kinds of
vulnerabilities deeper into the program
yeah so so in our case in anti fast it's
super easy to to remove so in our paper
what we actually said was that if you
are using anti fast you're probably also
using obfuscation and you should write
if you add anti fast and then you add
obfuscation on top so this is not easy
to remove so if you look just on an a
binary that is protected by an anti fast
you will see the ten thousand of fake
edges that you introduce right it's
super easy to remove
so at obfuscation and then it's all
based on the security of the
perfect any other questions otherwise
let's thank American
[Applause]