hi everyone today in this talk I'll tell
you about how we built an nmap for cars
so I start off with the question do you
know what's going on in your car well a
modern car consists of a network of
electronic control units or ECU's that
talk to each other to handle everything
from your engine and brakes to your
headlights
now as modern cars are starting to
include more electronics more wireless
systems it's starting to become more
increasingly important to know what's
going on in your car especially in the
context of security let's look at a few
scenarios so say you take your car to a
shady mechanic and he installs an ECU
without your permission in this case I
would want to know what ECU's are
currently in my car maybe you buy a
aftermarket radio from some guy on
Craigslist and that radio is actually
transmitting new messages onto the
network that you do not expect it to at
this point I would want to know what
devices are sending what messages and
maybe this guy from Craigslist wanted to
use that radio to shut down my engine
ECU using recent work by Joe at all
they've demonstrated they showed that a
compromised ECU that was capable of
receiving messages from its victim in
this case the engine ECU could shut it
down by simply sending messages in a
particular manner causing errors in the
engine's transmission and it will shut
down so in this case we would also want
to know what messages can an ECU receive
so what we want to build an automotive
network mapper using guided by our three
scenarios we have three goals for our
network mapper first we want to identify
the ECU's in a network then we want to
identify the message sender for each
message and for each message we also
want to know which devices are receiving
these messages so because we're building
a tool we have to focus on practicality
our tool should not require your car to
be on for several hours or days at a
time
we don't want to use expensive equipment
like an oscilloscope or our method
should work on the majority of vehicles
that are out there and we shouldn't ask
our users to cut directly into the wires
of their car and last and most
importantly we don't want to brick your
car because that would be the worst
thing ever
so the obvious strawman here is why not
ask the automaker right the automaker
has this information in a database file
of this message information however this
is strictly confidential even companies
that work with the automaker have a
tough time getting this information and
you might consider well maybe your
mechanic might have this information you
can go to an online mechanic
subscription but that only tells you the
wiring diagram of these ECU's and at
most the information you'll get is the
number of ECS in a car and the reality
is is that the network inside a car is
constantly changing and we've seen three
scenarios as to how this can happen so
in a nutshell we build canvas a network
mapper for cars that leverages
information from message timing and the
error handling mechanism to generate a
network map in under 30 minutes with
less than $50 worth of hardware so now
I'll give you some background about the
protocol cars used and some challenges
in mapping so the de facto standard for
the internal automotive network is the
controller area network or the can
protocol a can protocol consists of a
bus where each ECU is responsible for
sending a set of ID's these IDs are
basically labeled the data that an ECU
is transmitting but the reso the actual
purpose of each ID we don't know we an
ID could mean engine timing or vehicle
speed but only the automaker has that
information and each in each of these
IDs are sent periodically and each ID is
only sent by a single ECU in the network
so looking at a particular can message
the ID at transmission time serves
priority in the network and will decide
which message is sent first and there's
also a process of acknowledgment where
after message is sent it will be
acknowledged
simultaneously by the receiving ECU's
now unfortunately this makes the can
protocol makes mapping hard if we look
at the if we connect our tool to the
network and this is the information that
we get the ids and some time stamps of
the transmission times now if we look at
an individual message the challenges is
that this ID only indicates priority not
information about the message sender and
because the AK bit is sent
simultaneously we don't know who exactly
sent them at who exactly receive the
message it could be one it could be all
of the ECU's in the car now for those of
you familiar with the canned protocol
you could define receiver differently
and we talked about that at the end so
now let's take a look at the canvas
system so we combined our first two
goals EC identification and message
sender into a module called source
mapping and our third goal becomes
another module called destination
mapping for source mapping we take an
input the data log of timestamp traffic
that we see from the car and our goal is
to produce a source map where we have a
table of the ECU's and the set of ID's
that they strands MIT now the question
here is how can we link these IDs to the
source ECU let's borrow an insight from
prior work prior work for purposes of
building an intrusion detection system
they identified a they identified clock
offset as a unique characteristic that
could identify ECU's in the car now
clock offset is basically if your clock
is one second behind mine that's a 1
clock that's a 1 second clock offset and
by tracking this clock offset per
message ID and the network sharp changes
could indicate an active attack now we
thought well let's repurpose this
insight and let's look at us let's look
at a single ECU from a real vehicle this
ECU has 3 IDs and all sent at the same
period and by using a graph of clock
offset versus the number of the messages
in the in the car we can clearly see
that we can associate and cluster these
three IDs into a single source ECU make
sense
unfortunately we found that prior work
is not sufficient the first problem is
that it's not robust to noise in the
period which we find an automotive
networks and because it is period
dependent so an example of this period
dependency another real ECU from a real
car these three IDs are transmitted at
three different periods the only
conclusion I could properly draw from
this graph right here is that there are
three different ECU's sending one
message each which is not true so our
solution here is let's figure out which
messages could help us remove that
period dependence and our insight here
is let's choose messages at the hyper
period or the least common multiple of
the period for two different IDs so here
for two IDs that transmit at 18 and 6
we'll pick these particular least common
multiples and by tracking this offset
using these particular messages if the
if the offset remains constant then we
know that these two IDs originated from
the same ECU so our approach here is we
strip out the input log and just focus
on these two IDs and we measure over
time in order to reduce the effect of
noise and we do some clustering by based
off of these matches and we can group
these IDs in two sets of ECU's we also
see a lot of practical challenges where
we face messages that have deadlines and
messages that suddenly stop transmitting
and we talk about how we solve those
challenges in the paper so now going to
destination mapping the input for
destination mapping is the source map as
well as the as well as access to the
physical bus that all cars in the United
States are required to have the
diagnostics port the output we want to
generate here is a destination map where
we have for each ID the set of
destination ECU's that are receiving
that ID so if we go back and look at the
unmodified can unmodified can bus when
we transmit a message on to the network
we done and we see an act we don't
exactly know who act the message but
what if we could isolate an ECU
to guarantee that the sole device on the
network is the only device that's
transmitting that ACK at that point we
could we could fill out our destination
map so here we bar another insight from
prior work that was thinking of that was
using this error handling exploit to
dupe to perform a denial of service
attack what they found and pointed out
was that in the cans error handling if
you could cause a certain number of
errors of ECU will voluntarily shut
itself off to prevent itself from
further harming the network the thing is
is their method was not robust and it
was designed to be an attack it only
needed one success to be successful but
because we are trying to perform this
multiple times we had to come up with a
different approach and we talked about
this in the paper as long as real
limitations including ECU's that
autorecover and other examples so now we
look at our evaluation so for our
evaluation we have two different cars
one is a hand-me-down that the
university gave to us it's a 2009 Toyota
Prius and B and we saw we thought okay
well it's a Prius let's get a newer car
right we went to a salvage yard and we
got a really cheap 2017 Ford Focus all
the electronics are still intact we also
got some ECU so I'm ECU's from a
junkyard and we did all we did a lot of
testing on a synthetic topology using
Arduino dues which is also where we run
our canvas member so just some key
takeaways we built the system that has
that runs in under 30 minutes
it has let it uses an Arduino Dewey for
less than $50 it uses the standard Canon
implementation and you connect to the
on-board diagnostics port of your car
and any of the methods that we do
including isolating and ECU if you
follow the steps in our paper you won't
have any dash lights afterwards so now
let's look at two interesting case
studies where we actually could
implement or we actually saw situations
of the first three scenarios I gave you
so in this example we
are looking at the source map of the
2009 Prius by looking at the online
mechanic subscription we expect to find
these ATC use in the car now when we ran
our network map we found a ninth ECU at
this point we thought something was
wrong and what we but what we did we
looked at the history of this car and we
actually found that when the university
first bought this car they converted it
to an all-electric car and in the
process of doing this they added another
ECU that was now transmitting onto the
network and we verified this by
physically going into each ECU and
tearing apart the car and unplugging it
and we found that there was a ninth
device transmitting on to the network so
now looking at the destination mapping
for a 2017 Ford Focus if you look at the
on if you look at the mechanic
subscription for this vehicle you'll see
that there are certain functions that
are supposed to operate between a subset
of e C's for example these four ECU's
talk to each other for purposes of
engine function now with our destination
map we found that these messages were
also being received by the radio ECU now
if you think back to that scenario I
talked about theoretically if you had
swapped out your after this radio with
an aftermarket then someone could could
use that radio to enable the shut down
attack and in fact we found that both
the Prius and the and the focus had no
filter whatsoever on what messages and
ECU could receive so here are a few
limitations that I'll discuss I have
time ok so so first we have adversarial
evasion we've been asked us a lot we
thought well an attacker could thou'rt
our mapping right or even the automaker
could thwart our mapping because they
don't they want to keep that information
secret so at this point we would just
rather use an intrusion detection system
if there is an active attack an IDs
would be the best solution we are trying
to perform we're trying to do defenses
against passive attacks and people have
also asked us well why do
the automaker intentionally altered the
timing to defeat your mechanisms
well scheduling these messages for a
vehicle in real time is already a
challenging enough problem so that so
they have no incentive to alter the
timing and in the paper we talk about
how we avoid permanent damage and we and
we also talk about the method of
resetting dash lights even as you're
shutting off these ECU's these ECU's are
built to handle that in case a rat bites
through the wires or in case there's
some kind of electrical flaw because
this is not a permanent fault when you
sucked for most cases when you simply
turn off the car and turn it back on the
dash lights disappear or if you drive
around for a few for a little bit and
these ECU's when they go into this mode
where they can handle that failure it's
called limp home mode
so these eazy-e's are designed for that
and in the case where especially modern
cars they starting to have multiple can
buses in order to get access to these
unexposed buses we also talked about how
you can gain access to these buses with
minimal tearing up of the car by going
through the doors so this is also
another message acceptance filter is
another way that you could define
message reception and in the paper we
talked about how this is a vendor
specific approach and we give some ideas
about how to achieve that but because
we're trying to aim for a vehicle
agnostic approach we chose to define
message receive a different way and
finally by doing this isolation
mechanism we can actually detect non
transmitting ECU's and we've talked to
automakers and they said that this would
be a very potential use case for them
for using our tool so to conclude the
network inside cars is no longer static
we've seen three scenarios where that
where that can change and we've built
canvas a network mapper that'll tell you
what's going on in your car and we've
seen that can makes the mapping problem
challenging and because due to the lack
of source or destination information
that you might see in other protocols we
saw that prior work did not achieve
these goals when applied to the purpose
or the context of network mapping and we
haven't fast and inexpensive
with the focus on practicality we have
we've seen too real blow to real world
demonstrations in the security context
and we hope that our tool canvas can
serve as a basis for future security
applications thank you okay questions to
start up start us off it was curious how
do you think we might communicate with
vehicle owners about not installing and
trusted devices or who you think should
be making sure that doesn't happen
could you repeat that again where who
you think if it's not the vehicle owner
who he should be telling not to install
interested devices who might we talk to
so I would probably say the mechanic
should have a process of verifying
whether these this information is secure
or if you can like that potentially
counterfeit ECU's as well that's also
another issue that automakers have
brought up with us but even if we could
so if as a vehicle owner if we can make
this tool simple to use then they could
also use this as well they can buy
aftermarket parts connected and check it
especially as parts are now moving from
mechanical to electronic and I would say
1020 years from now the majority of
parts will be electronic thanks so
Justin campus NYU I know a lot of modern
automakers are increasingly segmenting
their can networks and adding gateways
that are also meant as security
deterrents and things like that I'm
wondering if you can comment on if that
trend continues what that means for your
work in canvas sure that's an excellent
question so in the paper we go into more
detail but for for gateways in
particular we the gateways are
connecting multiple can buses so as long
as you can access each individual can
bus and that there are no methods trying
to thwart our mapping capabilities then
yes canvas can last less for the future
great thanks I thank the speaker
[Applause]