thank you for the introduction my name
is rumba
I'm PhD student at Penn State University
and as you can see from my shirt today
I'm here to present some magic about the
burning this is a joint work with my
crab readers and other wiser from Penn
State and UC Berkeley modern software in
wet willy contents park to fix these
bugs an important step is to really
learn and find the root cause these
processes were difficult because of the
following two reasons first feed failure
or occurs at the post-deploy stage as a
stage the bad input is typically not
horrible second the information life
that's photo EGNOS is very limited in
fact over the past few years our
research community has developed many
tools to diagonals software failure the
information the commonly used is called
an eco dump is Saphir generated after a
program crash it contains information
like memory snapshot and register value
of a dead program recently the
development of new hardware gives us the
capability to treat program execution
therefore a code um also contents the
execution trees for training to the
crash process using the code um I
introduced above diagonals tools your EU
tries back warrant analysis to pinpoint
the root cause of a software failure the
PCA idea of backward turned is as
follows
it takes as input the information
contents in the memories in the code on
the the starting from a bad pointer it
will reverse the search along the
occlusion trace and pinpoint all the
instructions for training to the crash
to perform an accurate backward trend
analysis alias analysis is required as
you can see here I am accurate alias
analysis will lead to or 20 issue this
issue could jeopardize that
diagnose of software failure in this
talk
our first introduce is the existing work
of memory aliens identification
technique and show you the challenges
motivated by this I will introduce our
approach which leverage the magic of
deep learning to identify memory
readings and thus facilitate the root
cause of software will cause diagonals
weather site analysis is the most
popular approach from memory aiding
analysis technically it first of
partition the memory into three
destroying regions the it will determine
the regions tied to instruction by using
the following two strategies instruction
semantics and forwarding flow analysis
in particular for some instruction where
they could easily complete region
assignment based on the instructions
named semantics take the figure on the
reference set as an example as you can
see here were say kudos an instruction
language to stack region because of this
year ESP memory and Link instruction
land file to global region because of
this absolute address for some other
instruction USA performs a simple
forwarded for analysis to determine
their memory with their memory access
regions here instruction landfall
indicates a write to memory
yikes so a forward to the full analysis
was able to pinpoint that value of this
EOG's
comes from learn instruction land to
which is a web malloc function call
where they could learn determine that
this e x-- memory is a hip rock size
within each region that were they
identified it is estimate the franklin
region that each instruction a time
clock size as you can see here in this
table each instruction is a son with a
sweetheart hole it it shows the region
and off sides of a memory size
take this magnets one fall in the first
salon as I example it indicates this
memory cell accesses a heat step region
with offside one fall after a sunny
instruction to each region where say
could could father for sated software
failure diagnosed to be specific it
first utilized the region estimation
results to construct a confusion matrix
as you can say in this matrix aliens and
anon aliens relationship are specified
family we can perform backward analysis
under the guidance of the identified
aliens pair and as us pinpoint the root
cause in reward where she cannot
accurately pinpoint memory aliens as we
expect the reason is as follows as I
mentioned earlier the log of exclusion
trees where there are specific hardware
however this hardware have limited
capability to installing all the
instruction executed this means that the
execution trees Nikodim is surely
incomplete incomplete trees will
inference was a upon his ability to
identify memory readings in the formal
example as also shown here through
forward in full analysis where they
could determine that instruction learn
four books essays hip region however
result of a day of recording all the
instructions where they can no longer
trees where this valley of e^x
comes from as a result it cannot
determine which region does the e^x
memory refers to in the following error
introduced how it is our approach to
solve this problem over the past few
years there are many techniques that use
deep learning to perform binary analysis
technically they basically use similar
architecture this architecture this
network architecture takes us machine
code directly as input
I'll put the prediction accordingly
however as I will surely as I will show
later this network structure cannot
haywire high accuracy because they meets
the instruction information within the
execution sequence inspired by this work
we pop we propose to use a heretical
recurrent night for predicting memory
region title each instruction in
execution trace the diagram here shows
the entire process first which we know
in your network to be to predict regions
and then utilize the region information
to assist traditional West a in memory
region at the vacation and aliens and
vacations as to our proposal Network it
takes as input a bunch of key so
somebody machine code it will transform
the machine code with each instruction
into an embedding after this step we
will have a sequence of inviting and
each embedding encoded information
within each instruction you can take as
a hidden reputation or some other type
of it's just hidden repetition of each
instruction within execution trees with
an input this sequence of embedding of
instructions into an classifier and
obtain the predicted region for each
instruction technically or network
contents two parts the first part is an
embedding network it start with the word
inviting mechanism this world
environment Kingdom which transform the
discrete instruction into continuous
weather for further use though as I
mentioned earlier we will we will
transform each instruction into an
embedding
which we call it instruction embedding
here will utilize the beta rational or
as TM to perform this task the second
part of our network is a classification
model is also a better rationalized term
the take has input than instruction
embeddings on
I'll put the region out who the raging
information for each instruction in the
dress of this talk our introduced how I
evaluate our approach we first to
construct our data type for training
sites with like 78 programs in canoe
software package in particular we run
this program and gather that they are
execution trees along with the memory
exercise to test our train the neural
network we randomly select thought he
reward when abilities from Expo DB 4-h
to an ability which figure it by running
the POS a programs and the correct
execution trees along with some emmerich
sense it should be noted here that this
this one about freezes have limited size
because I'm as I mentioned earlier the
software have limited a buffer storage
at the hardware have limited buffer
storage
we didn't render and at I stubborn your
network by using the data side I
introduced of all we also compare it
with many other machine learning models
including traditional sequential model
such as hidden Markov model conditional
random field and some modern deepening
based on model it's just different kinds
of recurrent nights for them for iOS TM
and gate a unity recurrent in the
following I will show you the
performance of our approach from three
different perspective first I will
compare the model performance of our
model with some with the baseline model
I mentioned before then I will compare
Depot as a with where say in the
effectiveness of glucose diagonals
last but not least I will compare deep
USA with another existing glucose
diagonals to pump in terms of efficiency
for model performance as you can see
from this table that are both
significantly out performance
traditional ml model that is hmm and
see I have this is because that what our
model are all kinds of deepening based
model have higher model capability the
traditional models it means they can
basically learn like more complex atom
or complex who's hidden like it's hidden
within the the the training data you
have but compared to other machine
learning based models or approach
demonstrate that performance improvement
however it does not indicate or design
is redundant in fact even only pointone
percentage of improvement in either
precision or recall we could reduce the
amount of for supportive of us Nikhil by
thousands or even tens orders this
amount of improvement in regional
assignment will increase the accuracy of
aliens identification and thus help
through cost diagonals here is a result
of glucose diagonals first recall that
we only have limited styles of actuation
trees to evaluate the inference of trees
lands poor approach where were the lands
of instruction cleared to do cost and
recall the 918th relationship that
identified by our approach and the
traditional west a as you can see from
this figure we have first found out that
the execution trees learns indeed
inference the alias analysis accuracy to
some degree but more importantly will
cause all the settings our model
significant beats traditional west a in
aliens identification occurs in as a
result deep west a is small effective in
funding rule cost than traditional west
a as you can see in this table
d po sa put identify term module calls
than traditional where seen lots of our
knowledge i will compare deep osa with
palm as its mentioned before palm also
diagonals
program crush using alias analysis and
backward hunt
to be specific it's utilized do a
reverse exclusion approach to analysis
aliens relationship this approach which
is computationally intensive here is the
video to demonstrate the speed
difference between pump and West a the
screen on the right hand side is where
say and left hand side is pump as we can
see here after 9 seconds tsa finished
diagonals and pump is still running and
after about 19 seconds pump finished
actually on average depot si is 2 to 10
times faster than pump to conclude this
talk conventional West a suffer from in
arid areas analysis when executing trees
is incomplete West a combined with deep
learning to the improved alias analysis
in binary analysis and thus facilitate
software failure diagonals DPS a could
serve as an efficient and effective
diagonals to to pinpoint root cause of a
software failure or code and data as
well as thought our model can be is
published in this link thank you all for
the attention now I'm ready for the
questions
[Applause]
hi Brendan Dolan Gavin and why you I
hopefully didn't just miss this in the
talk but there are a lot of instructions
where they access many different types
of memory depending on their context so
like a mem copy might be called
different context access copies between
the heatman stack or things like that
so did you have to take that into
account somehow when doing your training
set analysis yeah we actually like
cracked our training size by using
different kind of program we believe
that it will cover the pace you just
mentioned we just make our training set
as diverse as possible and train the
neural network that we hope it actually
the new network indeed the kind like
memory or learn different kind of
situations that you mentioned before ok
any other questions yes I have a support
where we're where else would you
sprinkle like this deep learning dust
what are their analyses would you like
what's next like one of the analysis
would would you want to sprinkle some of
this mmm that's a good question I think
currently if you like we're only the
region right we only like what some
memory to each region but what we as it
is it can all only assign region but
also the object or not that step is to
try to use deep learning to identify not
only regions but also the object it's
like more fun grading tonight using tea
party alright let's take them again
[Applause]