hi everyone thank you for coming to my
presentation my name is Giuseppe
Savannah State University and I'm
excited to be here today to present
entrust regulating sensor access by
cooperating program via delegation graph
this work is a joint work with
researcher from the alan turing
institute in the UK the University of
Munich in Germany and also researcher
from Symantec research lab this work is
also sponsored by the Army Research Lab
let's start by talking about the
cooperating program our structure so we
are all familiar with this abstraction
because we have seen in current
operating system so we have a user that
is instant setting our voice commands
such as take a selfie and this voice
command is processed by a voice
assistant the voice assistant is going
to rely on a another program for example
the camera in this case and the camera
app is going to perform the operation
that was requested by the user and then
this program is going to request
permission to access the camera in order
to capture a frame for servicing the
operation requested by the user the
question is here is that what can go
wrong
so there have been several articles in
the research community as well as in
different technical magazine that showed
that application can collude and then
they can cooperate in order to leverage
permission that they have in order to
violate the user privacy as well as
there have been article mentioning that
voice assistant can be exploded and can
open new attack vectors so let's go into
the details of this we have seen the
scenario before where the transfer
assistant is going to rely on camera in
order to perform an operation what if
the camera is actually a Trojan horse
that is leveraging the permission that
has to access the GPS than the
microphone in order to record the
location where the selfie was taken ball
so record a short audio in order to
assist raid person
information in the paper we also
mentioned two more attack vectors that
are confused everywhere the voice assist
in this case is untrusted and is going
to trick the screenshot service in order
to capture a screenshot in a specific
context such as when the user is
accessing sensitive information such as
secure notes or other type of
information and then we have another
attack where we have a man-in-the-middle
attack that we are going to see more in
details in this presentation where we
have a trusted assistant that has been
used by the user to the Bosnia bank
check so the target here is our banking
app that is supposed to take a picture
of the Chacon and deposit the cheque in
a bank account unfortunately what
happened is that the request by the
trust assistant is intercepted by the
camera the camera app is going to take a
screen a picture of the check and then
send it to a remote server that is
controlled by an adversary so let's see
Adam of this attack I have it right here
so what happened here you will see that
the asset the user is going to ask to
deposit a check and then we will see the
banking uptick in the picture of the
check unfortunate I was showing the demo
that also the camera have intercepted
this request and actually the taking a
picture of the check that is going to be
sent to the adversary that is
controlling a specific remote server
so this is the banking up and now I'm
going to open the camera plans as you
guys can see the check is also present
as a picture that was already taken by
the application so what is this
afternoon right we are all familiar with
the first use authorization model it is
using current operating system and this
model allows to request access only at
the first time a specific sensor is used
by a program so to solve this issue
researchers propose a different
mechanism one is to bind the user input
event as well as the specific user
interface to the request of a specific
sensor example are like using
information such as is the application
ran in the foreground background is the
application presenting a specific UI
context to the user and so forth
unfortunately these allows to prevent
some of the tax but these models are not
modeling input event delegation where a
specific input is received by program I
but then is forwarded to program J in
this case the camera that is going to
perform the overage other researcher
also proposed to restrict and regulate
inter process communication but
unfortunately what happen here is that
an approach could be to reduce the
college permission based on the caller
but is defeat the collaboration
obstruction right if we rely on another
program to perform an operation you
cannot do what's the point of
restricting another approach is to
enforce this decentralized information
flow control this is technique they can
restrict our information from between
different programs
unfortunately this solves and our token
of problem of controlling our program
shared data no our program actually
access the sensor to collect the data
and then there are also machine learning
approach with researcher propose to
model patterns in our user makes
decision unfortunately our argument is
that the user needs to have the right
information to make the decision in
order to boy then trained
before I go into the details of what
I'll resolve this problem will have to
specify what are the assumptions we are
making here so we want to trust the
Veridian system that is builded securely
we also want to enforce mandatory access
control so that there is no direct
access to censor for user level programs
so user level programs are also isolated
via the sandbox mechanism and then we
use the trusted path we have a mechanism
that allow the user to send trusted
input to the operating system as well
the operating system is able to
visualize trusted out to the user we
will see later why we use this
assumption and then as a threat instead
we assume that the user can start
program from unknown sources and then
grant access at first use program can
communicate through inter process
communication can never this inter
process communication in order to
exploit the three attacks vector that we
have mentioned before I want to make a
point here is that the focus of this
work is to regulate our program access
sensors by its completely out of scope
while program share and collect data
because there are already other
solutions for this such as the diff see
a line of work so our insight is that we
want to track our input event our
delegate among cooperating program then
we want to expose the delegation
information to user in order to allow
the user to make informed decision about
the authorization and then allow the
user to restrict specific permission for
the delegated program that is the
program is actually requesting access to
the sensor unfortunately there are
several challenges too for this approach
because first of all we need to track
the input event from the time the input
event was generated to the time this
input event result in our operation
requests to access a specific sensor
there are also ambiguities they need to
be resolved because a specific time in
in a concurrent way a specific protocol
is in multiple event from the user bound
so multiple input event that are
delegated from other programs
and another problem is that we need to
allow the user to authorize the right
set of permission given a specific input
event so our approach is to track input
event allegation by modeling an input
event as a topology where we collect the
context where the user input event was
generated then we model also this send
the source sensor such as like the the
touch screen where the input event was
received and then the program target of
this input event and a specific
timestamp then we can model also how
these input event is delegated through
an end of event to another program PJ
and then finally we can also model how
the program PJ is going to generate a
request to access a specific destination
sensor be the result is a delegation
graph unfortunately there are challenges
because there are different ambiguities
as I said before what happen if there
are multiple input event a target a
specific program P I and then this
program Ti is going to generate an end
of event so which input event should be
associated with the end of event another
example is what if we have multiple end
of event at Argus P DV program PJ and
then a request
operation is going to be generated this
is hard to do but we found out that
since events are consumed faster than
how they are produced then we can queue
this input event for a specific program
VI and then deliver it sequentially so
that we are able to identify what your
event is as generating the request or
the end of event another problem is that
another optimization that we can do is
also a fan input event if an end of
event is not caused by an input event
from the user we can discard that end of
event because it's an invalid delegation
path for for this specific input event
so that we can identify the delegation
path so the approach is that we can
impute event that are generated by end
of event they are actually deriving by
from input event so our approach is that
once we have a generated the delegation
graph and then identified the delegation
path then we can model it for the user
right and we can model it for using the
natural language where we identify the
operation the sensor and also a specific
ID for the application is performed in
the operation and then we can ask the
user if you if the user wants the
operation is allowed or denied so going
back to the attack we have seen before
we see now that the user is going to ask
to deposit a bank check and then we are
modeling the complete delegation path
and then we ask the user if this is what
is expected so we can see your quick
demo how we prevent this attack so again
the user is asking to the positive bank
check and then a prompt show to the user
what is actually happening we have
evaluated our approach by implementing
prototype in our system in Android OS
and also tested on physical devices but
we wanted to answer a set of research
question or the to validate the validity
of our approach first of all we wanted
to measure the overhead imposed by
entrust or user since now user they have
to explicitly authorize the delegation
graph that has been constructed to do so
we have performed a field study where we
recruited nine subjects and we gave them
loan devices where they we pre installed
seven ten different application a five
voice assistants and they have been used
for seven days I can give more details
later we also wanted to validate an
intresting is backward compatible with
the existing application so we used the
Android compatibility test fit and we
tested it against 1000 application that
were selected among the most popular
from the
Google store and then we have also used
it five men to the reality gaming up but
the reason why this is we selected a
lamented religion gaming up this because
they make heavily use of sensors and
also they are very sensitive to delays
in terms of responsiveness for the user
another thing we have done is we wanted
to measure the performance implication
of integrating the entrust mechanism in
terms of generating the delegation graph
and also enforced in the delegation
graph so we have created a set of micro
benchmarks where we measure the overhead
due to the graph construction the graph
caching the graph enforcement and B with
the prevention mechanism that we have
seen before also we wanted to measure
the memory requirements how much memory
do we need to store this information
finally what we have done we also wanted
to evaluate if interest is actually
effective in preventing the confused
deputy the Trojan horse and the men in
the middle attacks we have seen before
to do so we have performed a laboratory
study where we have used sixty subjects
that were recruited by different from
different sources not only student from
our Institute and then we divided them
in four groups we have two groups that
tested the attacks for the first use
approach so the regular Android
operating system and two more groups
that tested our system and then in in
the first in the first group and then in
the third group we had people that were
not primont so we didn't tell them what
was the purpose of our study we just
that told them that we were testing some
voice assistant and application and the
other two groups instead both for first
use and and trust they were both
prominent user we told them that the
possible attacks were perform a attacks
were performed during the user study so
during the laboratory study we had three
attacks that are the three attacks we
have seen they confused every
the man in the middle attack and here
I'm showing the scenario we have seen
before of the men in the middle attack
so what we have done we ask the user to
ask the ghoul assistant to the Bosnia
bank check after logging in in the
mobile bank account with the provided
credential we ask them to deposit or
provided cheque in the menu in the
middle attack what happens that the
Google assistant launches the basic
camera that is registered for an intent
deposit bank check the basic camera runs
in the background capture a picture of
the check we have seen this in the demo
we exported spoofing the intent and then
launches the mobile app this is actually
as register - for the voice assist and
deposit check for the voice command
deposit check there is largely different
than the deposit bank check they
collected data is then sent to the
remote service controlled by the
adversary so here is what the - the
different group have seen for the first
use and trust in the first use you guys
are familiar with this type of request
that Android the Android operating
system present to the user and then the
interest instead we have seen what type
of information Trust is providing to the
participant of the study so what we
found out for this specific attack is
that only 47% of the user were prompt
with request for permission this is the
drawback or pitfall for the first use so
that means that they have previously
authorized this specific permission
through other interactions during the
study so they have used the camera for
other purposes and have accidentally
granted permission to the application
instead as we can see and trust always
generated delegation graph and identify
a specific delegation path and present a
specific authorization to the user so we
have an under percent of user where
prompt explicit allowed means that the
user have actually seen requests for
permission and they actually explicit
allowed by mistake
and we have seen
13% and 7% in case of interest and then
the attack success rate goes from 70 67%
for first use down to 7% using interest
this is forum prime the users a user
that were not aware of the purpose of
our study for primed user instead the
numbers are relatively different so we
don't have any explicit allowed because
they were prompt the attacks were
possible but still we have that for the
first use approach we have 53% of the
subject actually were subject to data
compared to 0% interest so what are
defining Centex way so first of all we
have shown that we can reach 47 to 67
percent improvement compared to the
first user authorization when trying to
prevent the tree attack vectors we have
seen and this is because we generate
delegation paths and then we ask the
user to authorize them then we have in
terms of compatibility we did not find
any discernible slowdown glitches or
crashes or responses in issues and also
we did not require any of modification
in order to for the application to be
able to run with our system in terms of
decision of a reading post to the user
for the new authorization model we found
that we know we don't have more than 4
explicit authorization for a specific
problem and then this is because we use
a caching mechanism where if a
delegation part is identified then we
can we can use the other is a pre
authorized delegation party we have in
caching we don't have to ask the user
again in terms of performance we found
out that if you compare the our system
with the Android system what we found
out is that we have only one percent
performance load on in terms of time to
perform a set of tasks that we have
identified and then we have a 5.5
kilobyte of cash required per memory for
each problem so this concludes my talks
and I'm thank you for coming and I'm
free for any question as
speaker I have time for one question
thanks for the talk I'm just interested
did you look at the Android 10 beta and
the background sensor access limitations
and how they would make this harder
unfortunately no but I will definitely
do that this is a little bit this is
Android 7 so I'm a little bit behind
here but I will love to see that some of
these have been implementing Android
time thanks okay next time speaker again
[Applause]