hi everyone so I'm here to present our
work on evaluating the contextual
integrity of privacy regulations or
parents IOT toy privacy normos vs. Coppa
and this is joint work with Sara Vargas
and Nick themed stir from the Princeton
University Center for Infotech policy
and I want to point out that Sara
Varghese I worked on this project for
her senior thesis was instrumental to
getting it here today so in 2017 the
Federal Trade Commission updated its
guidance on Coppa to indicate that it
did indeed apply to connected Internet
of Things toys and for the duration of
this talk I'm gonna refer to just Coppa
but oftentimes what I mean is a
combination of Coppa the Act or the
copper rule which of the FTC's
guidelines on how online services need
to handle children's data so devices
that we're thinking about here are from
a variety of types toys like Internet
connected teddy bears robots tablets
fitness trackers that are all built and
targeted towards children under the age
of 13 and so what we want to know is
whether the data handling practices that
the FTC is requiring through Coppa are
actually aligned with parents privacy
norms and expectations in this space and
even more generally we'd like to know
you know how do we as a community go
about testing whether privacy
regulations in any area are aligning
with the social and cultural privacy
norms of the affected population now of
course these questions beg another
question to begin with which is how do
we define privacy norms in the first
place and for that we turn to the theory
of contextual integrity which is a
privacy framework that was originally
developed by Helen Nissenbaum at Cornell
Tech which defines privacy in terms of
norms and information flow
appropriateness in specific contexts
that's for the that's pretty
philosophical so let's break that down a
bit further by saying that the context
themselves can be defined according to
five parameters you have a sender a
subject and attribute and information
type a recipient and
transmission principle so for example if
you consider this example of an
information flow of a doctor sharing a
patient's medical records with another
hospital for continuity of care you can
divide that into the five parameters so
the doctor here is the sender the
patient's is the subject the medical
records themselves are the attribute of
the information type the other hospital
is the recipient of the information and
for continuity of care is a criteria
placed on the information transfer also
known as the transmission principle so
given this very clear-cut five parameter
model of a context we can then use this
to construct surveys which allow us to
test whether norms are being respected
we've done something like this in the
past in our previous work we use the
contextual integrity to try to discover
internet-of-things privacy norms not
related to children or toys and so the
work that I'm presenting today is
building off of that now where we're
actually looking specifically at privacy
norms regarding a particular piece of
regulation and this is a six step
process and I'm going to go over each of
these steps in detail so the first the
first thing we do is we choose parameter
values for each of those five parameters
that are relevant to the regulation of
interest so here we chose as senders a
list of smart toys including robots
smart dolls walkie-talkies and others
for this subject in the attribute
parameters we chose different types of
data that we know that these devices
will collect in the wild things like
child's location audio recordings
birthdays that are often entered during
account setup and then as recipients we
we chose manufacturers and third-party
service providers which are actually the
two manufacturers sorry the two
recipients that are explicitly
distinguished in the copper rule as
having a distinct data handling
requirements then and this is another
distinction from the previous work we
pulled the transmission principles
directly from a cop a six step
compliance plan so these include data
handling requirements like if it's
privacy policy permits it or if its
owner is given
verifiable consent if it implements
reasonable procedures to protect the
information collected and others about
information storage deletion and
collection we also included a no
criteria transmission principle that we
use as a control to see how adding any
of these requirements from the law end
up changing the expectations that
parents have around their toys privacy
so once we've collected all of these
lists that were Manly generated of
relevant parameters we can then
programmatically generate all possible
five parameter combinations to come up
with a long list of information transfer
descriptions to plug into a survey in
vignette format so here we ended up with
thousand and fifty six questions where
each question proposed one particular
information flow and then asked the
survey respondents how appropriate they
viewed that flow on a five-point scale
in this particular example we're looking
at a toy walkie-talkie that was
recording the times it was used and
we're asking you know for the
manufacturer of the third party service
provider how acceptable is that
collection practice this particular
question uses the empty or the no
criteria transmission principle and then
in the following question we have the
same structure but we fixed the
recipient as the manufacturer of the
device and now we're asking for how the
appropriateness changes based off of the
criteria of the transmission principles
that we pulled from the law so once we
had generated all of these questions and
put them into a survey format we tested
the survey with cognitive interviews to
make sure that it made sense to
respondents and to do this we use a
service called user Bob which allows you
to post a survey or a website and then
work crowd workers will review your
service or website provide audio
feedback and you can record their screen
as they go through and do it so we can
watch these videos and we can see if
they're having any issues with
comprehension as they work through the
survey based off of these interviews we
made a few changes to improve
readability and decreased cognitive load
and then we deployed it out to 195 us
parents with childrens between the ages
of three and thirteen and this is the
largest survey of us parents regarding
privacy of smart toys that we could find
in the literature and we recruited this
particular panel of parents through Sint
which is a online service which will
allow you to specify participant panels
that you're interested in and and do
compensation for them accordingly so
once we have all these responses we end
up with a fairly rich data set because
each question asks about some
combination of the five information flow
parameters and so in order to start to
dig in and figure out what are the
actual things here that are they're
mattering and that are affecting parents
norms we group all of the survey
responses by various combinations so in
the first case we would take an
individual parameter I would say okay
here were all the questions that asked
about information transfers to a devices
manufacturer and then we could do some
statistics and see you know how do those
information flows compare to a different
set which maybe included all of the
transfers to a third party but of course
there's more going on here than just
individual parameter effects there's
really complicated cross parameter
effects that are going on and affecting
how parents are thinking about their
children's privacy so try to get at
these higher-order interactions we next
looked at pairs of parameters so we
would take all flows that had both to
its manufacturer and also if it's
privacy policy permits it and we can do
the same for any pairwise combination
and start as we go through and do these
comparisons to get a sense of you know
where are these interactions between
parameters and between elements in these
vignettes actually influencing parents
norms and finally we can do the same
thing with participant demographics to
see if there are subpopulations of
parents in our study that have
significantly different opinions about
privacy so we might want to look at more
closely and once we've done in these
groups we can compare the acceptability
scores that were given by respondents on
the survey so now once we have done all
that I want to go a little bit into
detail about the results that we
found so first I think it's worth it to
take a look at one example of what this
data looks like so this is a figure
pulled from the paper where we have the
acceptability scores of all of the flows
that are grouped by the subject
attributes and by the transmission
principle so this is a bit of an eye
chart and I'll go into detail about what
we can take away a bit later but for
example the the small box in the heat
map in the upper left corner is the
acceptability score overall respondents
who rated the question of flows that
we're collecting the owners child's
heart rate and using a transmission
principle about the that the parent had
given consent and so we grouped that
into the notification and consent
category so what do we see from looking
at this this graph well first of all
somewhat surprisingly we see that
parents norms are far more in alignment
with Coppa than we expected going into
this study so the two columns that have
highlighted over on the right are the
two columns of information flows where
either that particular flow was
disallowed by Coppa or it doesn't
include any indication of a data
handling criteria and for the most part
all of those data collection practices
were viewed as negative on average by
the parents but if you look at the rest
of the flows to the left of the two that
I've highlighted most of them are
positive and all of those included some
sort of mitigating criteria that was
drawn directly from Coppa whether that
was about a privacy policy permitting
the flow the parents being notified the
data being deleted after it was needed
etc and we went into this study really
expecting that even with those criteria
parents would take a fairly hard line
about data collection about their
children and that wouldn't be enough to
have a significant influence on their
perceived appropriateness of the data
collection and so the fact that we see
here that no those those criteria really
do change when compared to the control
how parents reviewing these flows makes
us think that you know to some extent
Coppa is move
in the direction that is aligned with
parents ideas even if there are details
about technical implementations or
enforcement problems that may be
preventing it from going as far as they
would like the general spirit of the
things that copy is concerned with is
aligned with the general spirit of
things that parents are thinking about
in terms of their children's data so
that was the the major takeaway from the
study but we also found many other
smaller results that we think are
equally interesting and I'd like to
point out so first of all perhaps
unsurprisingly we found that parents
really disliked targeted ads from data
from their children this particular
column that I've highlighted is about
flows with the transmission principle if
the information is used to serve
contextual ads and contextual
advertising is actually a specific
exemption in Coppa where only a certain
type of information is allowed to be
collected by children for contextual ads
we can see here generally that parents
view advertising based off of their
children's data as unacceptable
we also found in this case I think
someone discouragingly that transmission
principals based off of notification and
consent were more influential than those
based off of confidentiality and
security so generally in the in a left
category we have criteria around you
know parents being notified before data
is collected parents having given
consent before data is collected or in
the right category we have criteria
around prompt deletion secure storage
and encryption although we didn't use
encryption as a word we used some
unreadable transit or something to be
more understandable to parents and and
we found that this was sort of showing
that the emphasis on notification and
consent that has been prevalent not only
in our community but in the news and in
recent regulation like GDP are is
reflected in parents opinions and I want
to make sure that we emphasize that
there's not necessarily a causality
going on there it's just that parents
sort of are still viewing notification
and consent as primarily important even
though we know as a security community
that there are a lot of issues with
existing consent mechanisms especially
privacy policies and repeated request
for consent around technical issues that
parents may not understand also we found
that as has been shown in previous work
data collection by first party
manufacturers is viewed as being more
acceptable than by third parties and I
think it's important to point out here
as well that we chose these two
recipients rather than anything more
specific because they're the two
distinctions that Coppa actually makes
and we might say that given that parents
are making a distinction between these
two categories we might want future
regulation to be even more specific and
break down these further because you
could imagine that there could be a wide
difference in the appropriateness of a
particular third party getting
children's information than a different
third party depending on their
interaction with the device and the
purpose to which they're putting the
data to use we also found that parents
self-reported being familiar with Coppa
view the data collection as being more
acceptable we thought a bunch about this
so why that might be the case I don't
think this was not just a small fraction
of the parents around 60% noted they had
at least heard of Coppa in some sense
and we wondered of course at first
whether this was some maybe false sense
of security where they viewed the the
existence of Coppa being in place as
protecting their children's privacy
although if you followed any of the news
around smart toys over the past few
years you know that that might not
necessarily be the case and then finally
we found that older parents
overwhelmingly view data collection from
smart toys as being less acceptable and
you can see there's a pretty sharp
cutoff between the participant
categories of younger than 45 years of
age and older than 45 years of age so
once we had taken a look at those
results we'd like to suggest a few
opportunities for using this method and
applying it to other research projects
in the future so you think we think that
this general technique of using CI to
frame surveys in order to compare
regulation versus privacy norms on the
ground it can be fairly effective and so
we'd like to see it applied to other
privacy regulations like HIPAA and for
and GPR and we also think that it could
be useful for people who are drafting
regulation and policy makers to see
whether or not the things that they're
proposing are actually lining up with
the opinions of the people who that
legislation will affect and this could
better inform policymaking in a more
iterative way or than having to wait for
someone like us to do the study after
it's already been in place and then
finally we'd like to repeat studies like
this over time because a lot of times a
regulation is created not necessarily to
align with existing norms but to try to
push populations toward viewing
different things as being acceptable so
you could imagine that if we were to
repeat this study a few years from now
after a smart Toys had become more
prevalent we might see that the
overarching population norms have
started to shift one way or the other
and would be interesting to see how the
presence of different regulation or
different products in the market can
start to move people's expectations on
one way or the other
so just in quick inclusion we use the
survey to compare complet of parents
privacy norms and we found that
generally the data handling requirements
that were put in place by Coppa do
significantly increase the acceptability
of data collection from the toys however
we really want to make the caveat that
there are untested contextual factors
and there are technical specifications
that aren't in Capo which we didn't test
and you could imagine could go on and
further strength strengthen the
regulation and last but not least
enforcement matters so no matter how
strong copy is on paper if toys aren't
being held to that standard then parents
even though they may think they're
protected may not be when they go to the
store to buy things for their children
so thanks for listening I like to take
some questions and if you have any other
interest in work that we've done I
encourage you to go and check out on the
website Thanks
[Applause]
hi let me know from Google and thanks to
you for the great talk I have a question
about third party and the notion of
third party both in Copa and in survey
respondents sort of perceptions there's
this misconception sometimes we see in
the press and in early discourse between
what a third party is between let's say
if I'm a manufacturer and I use AWS to
store my data versus I put a tracking in
my app that will go to the extreme
advertising company what like what does
Coppa mean by a third party in that
context like is is a data processor a
third party and do parents understand
the difference between these two things
on a treaty right so at least in this
context we were interpreting third party
as the manufacturer of the toy so if you
purchased a toy from you know company X
and that was the company that was on the
box that was the first party for the
purposes of this study although you
raised a very good point about the
diversity of third parties and I would
like to see follow-up studies that make
distinctions between like crash
reporting services cloud services data
aggregators I think that some one
problem of going ahead too quickly on
that is that we start to get past where
parents and survey respondents actually
understand what those entities are doing
in the ecosystem and so you'd want to be
careful that you're not asking questions
about things that they don't necessarily
understand then trying to infer norms
off of that okay you need attached from
Google thanks also for a really
interesting talk I wanted to ask you
about your observation on the fact that
parents sort of preferred the notice and
consent model to the security things
like retention and deletion and that
sort of stuff so it's my own guess that
that's perhaps because they're less
educated about what those techniques
actually do or why they're useful but
users do usually learn these things over
time so I'm wondering if you were able
to break that down by age did you find
the younger parents for a little more
sort of happy or felt good about
deletion and that's what it's not
retention yeah I'm not sure about that
exact pairing offhand but I can I can
check and get back to you offline what I
do think though is that for some of the
questions about security that if the
criteria is not explicitly put in the
description of the flow that parents may
be assuming that some of that already
exists especially when the descriptions
of security get more technical it may be
the parents especially who are reporting
familiarity with Coppa and so they know
there's some government regulation
already in place even if they don't you
know explicitly read that the data will
be protected when it's transferred that
may not make them assume that it is not
protected well it's under answer
so thanks thank you Noah okay