thank you for being here despite this
being the last but hopefully not least
talk of the day so I'm Moritz and not
him
and I'll be presenting kumoi
synthesizing structure while fasting so
for this talk we have one overarching
goal and that is the one of finding bugs
in programs you can see here and
programs that expect the input to be of
a very specific structure right we have
a few interpreters a compiler I mean the
input must have a very specific
structure so we own the passing track I
mean what do you expect we are going to
use passing to hit that in a first may
be somewhat naive attempt we could be
using flying passing so basically we
just feed some input to the program and
monitor the runtime behavior right now
we can consider an abstract view of some
arbitrary program or rather its state
space so in the dark shaded areas in a
dark gray you can see interesting areas
so an interesting area is for us the
stuff that is deep beneath the surface
of the program but the interesting logic
is happening by the uninteresting area
in white might be some girly state so
before some check and as you can be for
blind passing on we are hitting read a
random I mean like the like point is the
seed at the small axis around them
mutations so we are moving but we are
not really moving anywhere
apart from those inputs I mean the
logical question is obviously can we do
better and I guess I'm not spoiling
anyone in here when saying yeah coverage
caddy passing will help us so we add
program instrumentation to the equation
basically we instrument the program with
the goal of having a feedback path so
that we know which coverage is achieved
by a single input so for each input we
can see whether it chief new coverage it
found something new to see interest
that we didn't see before and if that is
the case we want to keep that input
however if we buy some mutation create
another input that achieves exactly the
same coverage we are not interested in
that one so we'll discard this one so
that's basically coverage at the passing
a used mutation in here so let's take a
quick look at the type of mutations we
are talking about here
so we are talking about bit flips about
simple arithmetic where we add or
subtract some constants but our mutation
could be the setting of some interesting
well you may we set a byte to zero we
might have a havoc stage where we
non-deterministically apply various
random mutations or we repeat some input
or also we can splice two inputs
together so these are different mutation
operations however they have all one
property that is well at all of them so
they are only modifying a small part of
the input so they are read a local in
nature and that's why we will refer them
to as small-scale mutations for this
talk these mutations work quite well for
a lot of inputs so we might have a
program expecting an input that looks
like this one numbers byte whatever and
if we apply our mutation here it might
look like this and I guess it's still
valid right it looks good for us so back
to our abstract view these coverage
guided mutations allow us to move and to
discover other interesting areas in the
state space as you can see we have these
arrows allowing us these errors that are
mutations karaage mutations that allow
us to even cross small gaps between such
interesting areas and we discover quite
a lot here however you notice in the
bottom right hand of the figure there's
a small island that is interesting but
we do miss it still I would claim we
covered quite a lot of the interesting
stuff here right so
the problem here is that not all
programs are equal we might have other
programs that take inputs that look
largely there was something like that
maybe so coincidentally that looks close
to inputs that programs take that we are
interested in if you remember the first
slide and if we do use our small-scale
mutations here so flipping a few bits
adding constant values
it might come close to something like
that but that doesn't look like a good
input right that's not looking really
well it that's not what we want in this
case so what's the takeaway from this um
for this program we need to know the
input structure so that we can apply
reason Abel mutations right so if we hop
back to our abstract representation this
program expecting this different input
might look like that you immediately
notice they are way larger gaps between
the interesting islands right and our
coverage guided small-scale mutations
are not reaching anything meaningful I
mean like there are two islands goes
okay we see that but we miss a lot of
stuff so the question here really is how
do we cross these large gaps and
fortunately for us that's kind of solve
problem people came up with Kurama based
fussing so you can specify a krema
a formal specification and gifted to the
Fassa so that the fossa is capable of
crossing these large gaps because now it
has access to the input structure that's
cool looks good right we hit everything
here so what's the problem why am I
still talking the problem is that such a
krema requires human effort and that's
exactly what we want to avoid right we
want to passing to be a highly automated
process we want to make it accessible to
a lot of people
and we don't want to have a human being
maybe some expert we don't want to
require domain knowledge in this case so
that's where our paper starts our
intention is to have an approach that
crosses these large gaps in the state
space so that applies large-scale
mutations that modify the input to some
large extent without requiring a crema
that is specified by a human being
so basically cream or as our approach is
called learns the structure of the
inputs during it as fussing and with
this learned knowledge we then can apply
large-scale mutations to cross this more
these large gaps and hopefully profit
from that so the question is how do you
learn structure while fasting to this
end we employ a process that we adapt
input generalization so assume an input
that might look like this peopleand a
AAAA and what we want to want to know
about this input is whether it contains
elements parts of it that we can safely
discard to this end we split the input
we have various rules of splitting for
this example we split it into blocks of
two characters might be blocks of four
and then what we try is we try to remove
every input from this block and then
feed the rest to the fossa so let me
walk you through this example we remove
the PP so we end up with having rent a
as the rest then we sent this to the
fossa and look what is the new coverage
achieved by this input and the facet
tells us that is not the same new
coverage that the original in
put achieved this means the PP was
actually relevant to the input so we
cannot remove it intuitively that might
be clear in this example because P print
is a well that function and ruin doesn't
look like right so with that knowledge
gained we do keep the PP we go to the
next element we try removing our I ask
the fossa again and still we need this
element we can continue with MT with the
space and a pass trough it's all the
same we do need to keep them however
when it comes to the a it gets
interesting right as we can see here the
fossa suddenly says this is exactly the
same new coverage as our original input
this means it does not matter what we
put whether we send our original input
in the Faso at this one without a AAA
which is quite cool because we just
learned we do not need this block this
block so we do remove it but you
remember where we removed it and what
looks like there's a missing unicode
character is actually our symbol for our
gap so here we remember that we removed
something okay continuing with the next
block we also can remove the second AAA
obviously and the last apostrophe is
needed again so after merging adjacent
gaps we do end up with something like
that we have P print of some gap so we
learn from this original input that we
can discard everything between the
apostrophes which is marked by the gap
which is quite cool
let me show second example before we see
why this is cool
we might split this input on white
spaces that's trust a difference will we
apply and ask the fossa for every part
again the fossa then helps us learn that
we can discard the white space between
the bracket and the den and we can
actually
discussed the X equals free between the
den and the end so now we have different
inputs generalized inputs and why is
this cool what what can we do with this
intuitively this is cool because now we
can simply pick an input we can select
some arbitrary gap in this input and we
can just insert something and this is a
different input right so what will it
just it we mutated but relied on our
knowledge of the underlying structure so
let me show what the actual mutations we
use are the first mutation operation we
do use is the input extension basically
for two generalized inputs we can
conquer them
there are two possibilities so we can
press F the P print and the x equals by
after it for the other way round so this
notation is inspired by the inside that
highly structured inputs often consists
out of a chain of valid syntactically
correct statement so think of statements
in a C program that are separated by a
semicolon right the next mutation we do
use is the recursive replacement this is
the power horse in our asana and what it
does this we take some input or as we
can see in this slide we might take only
a part of a generalized input we do
extend it because we expect that in
front of and behind of a valid element
we can do put other stuff and yeah then
as you might have guessed we insert
another generalized input or part of it
we continue extending it so that we can
insert even more stuff and yeah we
actually insert more stuff and we can
keep that going actually in our
implementation we use up to 64 of these
steps and well for this example it's
only free leaving us with a new input
that is very different from our original
inputs so the last rotation operation we
do use is the string replacement this
one actually does not require our
generalized inputs but we simply replace
a keyword by another keyword and we
might end up with evil baa instead of
people in a and this will is quite
likely to actually generate a lot of new
coverage right so we have now seen the
different mutation operations we do use
and well the interesting question is
obviously how do they work out so can we
approximate a crema and do better with
our large-scale mutations than the usual
candidates a usual fascist do with their
small-scale mutations and as it turns
out yes we can we do outperform ffq
'some angora on almost all targets that
we have tested as you can see for lower
this is not the case
there's the interesting fact that Lua
does not only accept source code but
also byte code as you might be aware and
that's probably at least we get so the
reason that angora was it I believe
outperforms of despair anyway our large
scale
mutations are effective outperforming
the small scale mutations in most cases
the next interesting question is how do
we fare against a tremor based vasa
right so we are approximating a Croma as
only fair to see how a fossa really
working with a chroma perform
against us and unfortunately from our
point of view the crema based vasa
outperforms us and often by quite a lot
which is not that surprising because the
crema based pasta has access to the
crema from the beginning on right we
only start learning approximating the
crema when the passing process starts
so the crema base fossa outperforms
kumoi often actually that's one case
where this wasn't the case but in a
general case we open form so the
question is is crema of any help when we
do have a crema right and actually it is
what we did is we ran the chroma based
fossa for 24 hours taking the inputs it
found a seed continuum running the crema
best fossa and compared it to primo
so basically we allowed kumoi to access
the indirectly the crema and as you can
see kumoi founds finds more than akama
based vasa
which I consider quite cool to be honest
because we might find elements that are
not covered by the crema or the
implementation may differ from the
specification
let me conclude this introduction to
crema with following we have seen that
passing structured inputs is possible
but small-scale mutations such as a ploy
are employed by common factors such as
AFL are not the best for this task
luckily we have large-scale mutations
from crema based fascist
however the crema must be human-made and
that's what we want to avoid that for we
have created crema where we can learn
the structure of the input and based on
this knowledge can create such
large-scale mutations and yeah actually
this has real-world impact
- we found eleven CBE's so thank you a
lot for your attention ladies and
gentlemen
I'm happy to take any questions
[Applause]
perfect questions hi
so two short questions first for the
keywords for the string replacement
stage did you have any dictionary
involved there yeah so we do aesthetic
strings pass over the binary extracting
the keywords however in our evaluation
every pastor had access to the same
dictionary so we gave AFL and dictionary
to okay and the second question what was
it
oh the tokenization so how did you
determine the optimal length of the
tokens because like ultimately optimal
length would be just one character yeah
so actually we try we try each power of
two starting with the size of 256 going
down to one we try to remove as much as
possible and if that doesn't work out we
try smaller sizes so did you see did you
see the performance impact based on the
length of the token no I I can't say
much more than that is Eric any other
questions
everyone is ready for question so nice I
don't want it to end so quick so again
during the organization do you encounter
cases where you have to modify multiple
parts of the inputs in order to make a
change yeah so that's actually a problem
so think of XML tags right you have the
opening tag and the closing tag right
now this is not properly detected we
assume that can be fixed by some
heuristics however currently we do not
handle this that's a good question thank
you yeah that was also the question I
had and as my backup the like how you
could extend this to do some actual
grammar synthesis that can be maybe not
correct but at least useful for fuzzing
for different kinds of dependencies for
example the if T Nell's clause
you display this kind of similar because
some tokens depend on each other yeah
that's actually hot but we can
heuristically try to remove elements and
come always rely on the new coverage
comparing to see whether we actually can
remove two elements and they belong
together okay cool thank you very much
let's thank all the speakers together
[Applause]