okay so I'm Santiago I'm a PhD student
at NYU and today we'll be talking about
in total in total is the first framework
to cryptographically protect the supply
chain as a whole the software supply
chain now you may be wondering what a
software supply chain is well every
single piece of software that you have
in your machine right now was made
through a software supply chain for
example here's a very simple software
supply chain that's using four nodes or
four servers you have a version control
system you have a CI system that's
running tests constantly against all of
the commits in the version control
system you also have a box building and
build farm order or anything really
that's building your source code and
then you have your packaging step that
takes the binaries and then puts them on
a package this could be a Debian package
that's shipped to the users now we're in
juice Nick security so it wouldn't be a
surprise for anybody here that things
can happen in the software supply chain
hackers can break into the version
control system of our Juniper firewall a
flip pseudo-random c4a
for the IPSec stack and be able to
decrypt all of the IPSec connections to
all of the unipro firewalls boxes and
like this there has been many other
compromises on different systems the
same thing can happen in the build in
the real system
hackers can provide you developers a
temperate version of Xcode that will
produce the backdoored version of Xcode
that's shipped to iOS into the iOS App
Store and it compromises many many of
these users this is of course not an
isolated incident either the same thing
can happen in the packaging step you can
have a backboard version of PHP myadmin
sitting on a Korean mirror that's
targeting a specific set of people and
installing a backdoored version of PHP
myadmin on their box this is of course
as you may have guessed not an isolated
incident either and the same questions
arise when we're talking about testing
screw-top LED and compliance
there has been a case in which body
windows update was released and many
people were actually suspecting that
there was like foul play because it was
actually just bring these to a certain
portion of the population in Kazakhstan
as you may have guessed again this is
not an isolated incident now software
supply chain attacks happen as we have
seen very often as a matter of fact the
cement the semantic internet security
threat intelligence report said that in
2017 software supply chain compromises
went up 200% and in 2018 they went up
another 76 percent and I'm just stopping
here for a second because I want you
guys to see that in this very simple
very toy example site project type of
thing for server software supply chain
you have eight points in which is simple
compromise may be devastating for the
end-user and well I'll be moving on to
well you know that there's a specific
point solutions and and we're not trying
to fix this we know that there's a git
commit signing that can prevent hackers
from tampering with the version control
system there's things such as
reproducible builds that can help you
from backdooring compilers there's a
project such as notary in tough that are
protecting users every day now even with
those there's the element of well is the
security policy actual in place is it
actually being followed is this product
actually being shipped into the next
step and this this security policy the
same or as was expected and so on and so
forth now this is why we came up with in
toto we're trying to rethink a way to
protect the software supply chain as a
whole we do this with three major
principles the first one is compromise
resilience we want to be we want we know
that it's possible that attackers will
break into individual nodes and we want
to minimize the impact we do this
through a to two techniques one of them
is Rosa / separation and the other one
is having replication and key rotation
as a primary as first less primitives
the second one is all we want in total
to be all-encompassing we want to
protect from all the way
to the left and to all the way to the
right from the moment the first line of
code has been committed all the way into
the end-user installation advice we do
this through two very simple properties
one of them is being to let Gnostic that
allows us to be seamlessly integrated in
any supply chain and finally we don't
want to enforce any type of use and we
want the or system to be expressive
enough to be adaptive everywhere I'll
elaborate a little bit of this so we
have this software supply chain again
and we know that there's four actors
operating on it we have Bob that's
tagging and gate release we have Karl
that's building we have Aaron that's
packaging everything together and then
we have Dave that's testing we know that
compromise has happened and so it
happens that they've is compromised we
want that even if they've is compromised
we're able to still provide some degree
of security on the resulting package and
we also want to be able to take a day
ski-out or tapes privileges tests and
replace it with say a DES that we trust
that she can actually perform the tests
correctly the second principle is being
tool agnostic we know that this is a
very very common supply chain we know
that many of you recognize some of the
logos here but we also know that you may
recognize mercurial many types of
software are built using different
version control systems and by being
pool agnostic we're able to be
all-encompassing
which is a third property that we're
looking for now today this is how a
software supply chain looks at a toy
example tomorrow it could be anything
else and I'm trying to go like all the
way out here and let's think that gene
sudoc came out with a fingerprint reader
enabled fairy station system for every
single line that has been written and we
want in order to be able to wrap and
authorize the operations done that
specific step of the supply chain and
thinking of like farther down I'm going
crazy here let's say that the gene sudha
came up with a hypno attack in 2021 and
on 2022 he also came out with a using
security paper that detects the intent
of people so that we know that even if
there even at eyes they're not
committing anything malicious into the
server well we want
to be also be able to be protective
using Intel Oh so this whole this is
finally let leaves us to this like
expressive property that lets us pretty
much protect any supply chain out there
in existence and we've actually seen
that we can represent any supply chain
using our very simple domain-specific
language and a very minimal schema so
I'm going to explain how we do this we
have a three main goals one of them is
we want to verify we'll say what needs
to happen what are the steps in the
software supply chain the second one is
we want to verifiably define who is
allowed to make this happen we want to
define the author authorized actors in
the software supply chain and finally we
want to provide a tight binding between
the servers for the notes and software
supply chain this is a this is a chain
after all and we want to make all of the
links connect together properly so the
first element of Intel is policy
language what we call an internal layout
that basically contains the steps what
needs to happen it also defines the
public keys and the actors we call them
functionaries these are the people that
are allowed to perform operations in the
supply chain then we also have a way to
describe how the artifacts the inputs
and outputs of every single step it
could be source code it could be
binaries it could be container images it
could be packages it could be PNG s it
could be anything we describe how this
AR how this relate to their steps
themselves and finally we provide a
version to the language to be able to
type this together we want to say that
if there's a tag release with a version
with a version of the source code is the
same one that's used as an input in the
C in the CI system and it's exactly the
same one that's input into the build
system and so on and so forth now we
also want to have an authoritative
source of this policy so we expect this
to be signed by a project owner in
practice and we'll see later this could
be a release manager this could be a
security team this could be the
benevolent dictator for life on an open
source project
now that we know what needs to happen
the next element that we need is
information about what happened so we
built a very simple tool chain that
pretty much wraps any single possible
process or operation and this produce at
the station this at the stations are
signed with a private keys of the
functionaries in the supply chain and
they provide information about hosts
they provide information about the
materials that they use that the
products that they creative and any
other useful information like standard
input standard output and so on with
this we can actually verify that the
software supply chain has been integrity
its integrity has been not violated we
we use three elements we use the
artifact that you're going to install
back in our example it could be a Debian
package we have our policy and we have a
series of active stations of the
operations that were performed then the
verification is simple we want to make
sure that all of the other stations form
a graph and does this graph look like
the graph that we will have to scrub in
the policy language now we know that
this this is this verification can pass
now we want to make sure that this
actually protects against compromises
that we have seen in the wild well we
have a very simple very minimal no
threat model it's very encompassing but
it's a it's very easy to follow we
assume that anything can be compromised
because we have seen that everything has
been compromising the software supplied
a core infrastructure search as version
control systems package package
repositories testing infrastructure
build machines all of that can be
compromised we also assume that the
communication channels between all of
the servers can be also compromised so
if something is floating on an HTTP
connection they man in the middle it
they flip a bit and you're also
compromised and we also assume that they
can the attackers can compromise
developer keys or Fortuner keys our
compel functionaries into signing
different operations just for the sake
of keeping the security analysis simple
I'm going to ignore this for a second
and then we'll get back to it
so to quickly follow this is we know
that the policy cannot be changed unless
they
the functionary key the product owner
key has been compromised so they cannot
define your steps or they cannot remove
steps or provide a incomplete final
product we also know that these
operations are all the operations that
need to happen because they're described
in the policy and unless the attackers
are able to compromise developer keys
they won't be able to produce at the
stations on behalf of these
functionaries and since there's a hash
chaining mechanism that makes sure that
the artifacts that were produced and
consumed throughout the chain haven't
been tampered with
attackers cannot change the artifacts as
they flow through the chain now going
back to the key compromise we assume
that attackers can actually compromise
keys if if the attacker can compromise
fewer than a threshold we're back to the
example for if an attacker can
compromise functionary keys the effect
will be pretty much scoped by the
domain-specific language that we
produced and if more than a threshold of
product keys say that many keys of the
function eyes have been compromised or
the project owner key has been
compromised then we're pretty much back
to step 0 this is a compromise as if in
total didn't exist now this is payable
from the paper I invite you guys to read
it but it's basically just to point out
the three elements that are in play if
you compromise me from a functionary
that's in which the domain-specific
language allows them to create something
and that's something that's created is
being used further down then the
attacker can tamper with an artifact
that we call that product modification
and that's coped under the that's cooked
under their specific patterns that the
domain-specific language will will
define now to ground this a little bit
more in reality I wanted to go through
the integrations in total is being used
pretty much everywhere there's it's
inside of thousands of companies today
and you may be protected by this and you
don't even know it which is like the
good thing of security products I will
go into the data or example which
actually encompasses a bunch of all of
this other use
data dog is a cloud of servant agent
it's a matrix system and to do so it
installs an agent inside of all of the
different element servers in the cloud
this is very critical because if this
agent were to be compromised then well
it could do devastating damage to all of
this companies that you saw before in
order to the data dog agent to
understand the different workloads in
the cloud they have something they call
integrations which are pretty much
translation layers between the workloads
like an MySQL workload or an NG X
workload or an Amazon
akes workload and this translation
layers are installed into the different
agents that are running this workloads
in the cloud now this this specific
integrations are the ones that are
protected within Toto and they use this
very simple software supply chain to
produce the integrations they have
developers produce the source code they
use hardware token and they actually to
physically touch a hardware token every
time they commit a new version of the
integration and then this is pushed into
an entrusted CIA CD system that's
creating this up to stations as well as
the things follow-through finally this
is all pulled by the agent and the agent
inspects that all of the all of the
sources came in the package actually
came from authorized actions by the
developers or the CI this actually this
actually was pretty cool because we
found out that vulnerabilities on sip
extractors cannot affect this
integration because even if you're able
to bypass paths or change the sources of
everything the agent will be able to
track back all of the sources and all of
the paths to the original source that
was the developers using hardware tokens
now this is how it's used today we'll
use all of the information from the date
of deployment in order to explore how
costly or how data the how how in total
would perform we also explore
he´ll software supply chain compromises
that have happened in the last three
years would affect in toto
we found out that depending on how you
define the policy some of them will
apply some of them would not be
protected but most of them more than
three-quarters of them would be
prevented by in toto we also checked out
the metadata cost sometimes it
oscillates between 20 and 30 percent
there's special edge cases that are
mostly due to test files but in general
it's just a couple of kilobytes so users
don't mind paying the cost for the
benefit of protection and just include
in toto is a novel supply chain
mechanism that uses three principles to
protect yourself supply chain one of
them is compromise resilience the second
one is being all encompassing being able
to protect everything the third one is
its expressive enough to actually
represent any supply chain in existence
we're protecting through this we're able
to protect thousands of organizations
and companies and we're a vibrant
community of 30-something contributors
today from 10 different organizations
including Google Red Hat IBM and some
others that I cannot mention we invite
you to the Linux Foundation CNC fqq and
San Diego in November 18 to 21 we're
actually now part of the Linux
Foundation were under a non profit
organization we're actually hoping that
we will become the standard for its
change of software supply chain
information the future and finally I
want to thank all of my contributors all
of the people that make this a reality
it's been a three-year long process to
make this project be out there
protecting everybody for this thank you
[Applause]
hi couple Singh from IBM research very
interesting talk one question I had is
how do you incentivize different supply
chains for example if you are a lot of
work as you use open source from
different sources how do you make those
developers write the policies you
require and we are talking about
millions of libraries out there
Red Hat you mentioned Red Hat Red Hat's
one of the business model is to do
anyone verify those libraries so how do
you incent drys verification of those
libraries and writing the code or the
policies required under than a person of
these open source libraries well that's
a good question it there's a lot to do
with a cannot except open source but I
can tell you that we are actually
available in arch linux and and in
debian and we are actually if you read
the paper you'll see that there's an in
total transport to verify
reproducibility of builds in your Debian
packages today using different route
builders across the across like academia
and nonprofits and authors I think that
since this is becoming more and more of
a threat people are starting to awake
and go hey we need to actually take care
of this we are working with other big
companies have want to push one of the
mr. earth hat want to push this to be a
standard so you can essentially pull in
open source package that has all
information about the policy that was
followed and you can in like introspect
into it and decide whether if you're
going to use it or not I don't I don't
know what's the best way to push people
towards it I just think it's a it will
become a reality
thank you problem
this is uh this is really really cool
and I was wondering if you'd given some
thought to how the this might actually
also hook in future to the sort of the
what is operating on this in the system
what's afterwards running in the system
and at a stations of what's operational
right so so you already have some sense
of of the supply chain of where the
software was produced and now maybe as
you're running your system you're just
an administrator you want to know that
the things you thought you had are
actually running in the system hooks
into what's going on how you attest to
that and how you use some of what you've
produced to do that given any thought to
that so I'll try to answer as fast as I
can because we're over but there's a you
can recursively verify using in toto so
you can take part of the tool chain and
say hey this part of the supply chain
needs to be verified further down and
the other is you can you can use a
hardware base at station to like provide
like state of the system before you run
of all of the executions that's part of
the future work that we're looking at
we're going to call this function area
in a box okay thank you very much
and of course we now know some of what
gene sudoc is working on
you