I thank you very introductory my name is
Hawaiians mrs. Christian Dewar and we're
from to Adele's cyber threat
intelligence lab we are happy to present
our work on crypto jackin which is
called an event in it furtively making
cyber criminals rich and in this work we
will tell you how several criminals are
actually making money using your PC
without you being aware of it without
installing anything on your PC in this
presentation we will show how cyber
criminals deploy these attacks and on
which skill they are operating so first
of all how does a crypto checking attack
inside the browser look like well
nothing more than just this you're an
innocent web user and you're visiting
for example the Pirate Bay
the firebase deploy such a crypto mining
script and without they installing
anything on your computer without you
knowing it your CPU spikes to 100% and
you are now currently mining
cryptocurrencies in this case Manero
for the owners of the Pirate Bay so how
does this actually work let's dive into
the anatomy of a browser-based crypto
mining um you're an instant user again
you're going to a website by an HTTP GET
request between response and within this
response there's an HTML page which has
two interesting script tags first one is
a press the wrong button first one is
the script tag requesting additional
resources from KO knife bitches and
crypto mining service this request
fetches two additional resources one
being a JavaScript minor which
orchestrates the whole mining operation
on this website and the second one being
a highly optimized web assembly module
which is responsible for the actual
mining operation that takes place once
it is loaded is it it is initialized by
this function call which involves a site
key and the size is very important
because this site key is essentially the
UH narrow wallet or account ID or
basically the bank account of the
attacker to which funds made by mining
on this miner are being transferred to
and one says I'll initialize your
browser will set up a WebSocket
connection to a proxy which is in come
in contact with the blockchain for the
currency you're mining for in this case
one euro and then when it's all set your
browser starts mining for the owners of
this site key so cyber criminals can
deploy such an attack in a number of
different ways which we call attack
factors and the first one is pretty
straightforward website owner initiated
for example the fire Bay the owners of
this website were looking for new ways
to profit and they deploy the crypto
miner on their websites to let their
visitors mind for a narrow it is also
seen attackers hacking often popular
websites and doing nothing more than
just installing a crypto minor which
mines for them and thereby using the
visitors of this website as miners if
we've seen this at CVS Showtime which
was recently hacked we've also seen
attackers deploying crypto checking
scripts through malicious advertisements
spread by advertisement networks so
these advertisements include also a
crypto checking scripts and being served
over a large number of websites which
was for example the case as YouTube
which showed these advertisements we
equipped a mining script attached to it
to its viewers and last but not least we
have seen attackers abusing
vulnerabilities within the third-party
software ecosystem for example in
WordPress
they exported both vulnerabilities
within services like WordPress and
Drupal to install crypto jacking scripts
on these websites but it also pirated
premium WordPress themes and include a
crypto jacking script and by doing so
spreading their crypto checking
infection over a large number of
websites so this new cyber threat has
obviously attracted the attention of the
academic world as we've seen a number of
papers being published on this matter
but they are all primarily focused on
detecting these crypto jacking scripts
within the browser in a more most robust
way instead
focusing of understanding the actual
ecosystem additionally they estimated
the prevalence of search greater jacking
attacks by crawling the Alexa top 1
million list and there are
qualifications if air right by a factor
of four finally they have found out that
most prevailing attack factors were the
compromised websites and malicious
advertisements attack vectors well in
this work we characterize the whole
ecosystem of crypto jacking across a
truly random sample of 20% of the
Internet and quantify actor methods and
the used attack factors of these script
checking attacks so how do we do it
well we first need of need a truly
random sample of internet websites so we
took twenty percent of all websites in
the.com zone 20% of all websites in
the.net zone and across 20% of our other
1,100 theories so this result in a list
of 55 million websites which we fed into
our crawling infrastructure and we
actually crawled them twice first to
check if the mining was happening on
that web site we used the minesweeper
tool you published by Knopf at all last
year at CCS which relies on webassembly
analysis to detect whether there was
mining happening on that page
additionally we wanted to know how this
mining was taking place so we use
another crawler to extract psyches
WebSocket proxy connections initiator
files which start the whole mining
operation in order to do campaign
analysis afterwards so since the
equipped jackin landscape is evolving
pretty fast we deployed this on a large
scale on 60 servers in the university
network and we were running 720
simultaneous crawlers for a period of
three months
okay so the first thing that we now did
was we also looked at the Alexa
one-million because that's what previous
studies have been doing so far
and so the CCS paper from last year not
only he gave the crawler to detect using
web sembly analysis but they also
mentioned the size that were cryptid
checking so we recrawl up ten nine
months later and in order to see what's
going on here as you see here in this
graph most of the activity has actually
stopped most of the sites are no lone
remaining anymore and so this was
something that we also observed when
keeping crawling this so the reason we
we had 700 crawlers simultaneously
running we wanted to turn this round
every couple of hours and crawl all of
these sites so we did this every second
day and we saw that a lot fluctuation
happens yeah within these top sites
there's a lot of mining changing and if
you look at the total percentage there
was like this large variation and one
year later is even lower than that but
the alexa one-million is just like a
small part of the Internet's less than
1% it is a very privileged group so how
does this go in the entire Internet
well when you look at the random sample
of the Internet the 20% of everything
you see that crypto jacking is
relatively uncommon it's only 0.01 1% of
all sites that are doing this so if you
are looking at the alexa you're
overestimating the problem by a factor
of 5 when you break this down into
individual TLDs you see that this
average of 0.1 1 which is the red line
it depends a lot on which zone you're
looking at so for example in the Russian
zone or the Brazilian zone crypto
jacking is pretty common if you're
looking at a gTLDs such as the Pro it is
almost as high as the Alexa 1 million
but if you look at some other zones such
as top info org it is comparatively
clean so that's where other interesting
to see such a diverse manifestation of
this problem the next thing that we can
do is we can understand what kind of
services are being used now so there's a
number of different companies that
provide the toolkit the environment for
web-based crypto mining and we can
determine which service is being used
based on the indicator
on the on the startup so let's take for
example coin I've crypto loot and coin
in three of the major ones they all
provide a web assembly they all provide
in a startup file and it depends just an
API call on how what your going to start
up specifically so we can now turn to
all of these sides and see what is being
started and how does that work when you
look at this for the two datasets the
Alexa 1 million and the random sample
you see that the installation base is
relatively similar the blue bar is coin
hive which is the company that first
introduced web-based crypto mining was
the first on the market and they do have
by far the largest market share it's
about 40% in the top 1 million and it's
about 50% in the random sample the
relative ranking of the different
services and the market shares are
surprisingly similar so when you do
crawl the Alexa 1 million or the random
sample it doesn't really matter so much
however this is just the installation
base this is where the site was included
which kind of service it works ping to
however this doesn't really tell you
anything how much turnover there is how
much money they're making so here it
seems my coin hive is really the biggest
player in there in the market in order
to answer this we need to understand how
many sites
I mean users actually visiting these
sites and how much crypto mining that's
taking place in order to figure that out
we teamed up with a Tier one network
operator and we collected the daily
number of flows from client IP addresses
towards the WebSocket progress because
that's where they are calling in and
they're reporting found hashes for
retrieving the instruction files so by
doing this we get this 15 months
evolution of connections made to these
web proxy service and you see coin hive
starts that's happened in October 2017
very soon competitors enter the market
coin high for a while was actually a
dominant play around April 2018 and then
it has greatly overshadowed by coin iam
so if you recall the last graph you see
that coin and actually didn't have a
large installation base so it doesn't
matter that you have a lot of clients it
matters which clients you have and where
the
located what's also curious to see is
that there is a lot of transitioning a
lot of turnover happening I mentioned
previously we are doing this every
second day to understand how sides
switch from one customer to the next
look at the purple spike that is
wordpress manera plug-in that was
released in February 2018 it came out of
nothing became within a couple of days
the largest installation based allows of
service and went into oblivion just
eight weeks later towards October 2018
you see that there's a general down
client the Monaro price decreases it was
less profitable and you see a general
loss in this crew projecting activity
and approximately all of these services
are going towards the same the same
market share so if you want to make a
lot of money you are investing infecting
a site where a lot of people are going
to or what you can also do is you can
get a lot of sites and which are all
combined mining for your purpose and so
what we want to know is now how many of
these individual infections are
belonging to the same actor so we need
to link individual infections to
campaigns and we can do this because if
you are going to found this out too many
infected sites you're going to reuse
some indicators you're reusing some of
your infrastructure because you that's
the easy way of economies of scale of
doing this so we call a campaign when
there's at least five infected sites
belong to the same person and how do we
find a campaign well let's look at the
workflow here again if you get an HP
response and has the same site key it
must be the same actor because why would
somebody mind coin for a different bank
account so it must be the same person if
you look at the websocket proxy a lot of
them actually most of them run their own
infrastructure we can say that this is
the same person because why would they
run infrastructure for the profit of
somebody else and then if you look at
the JavaScript file like the way the
infection is happening and how it's
being called what configuration values
they are if these are similar identical
it must be the same person and we do
this by a bias tech trace analysis we
understand from which file the call
graph happened in which order in order
to have a high confidence value so based
on these indicators that we had we are
now starting a new crawl and we're going
to
target the scroll in finding campaigns
and we detected a total of a map of more
than 10,000 actively crypto checking
websites this figure clusters these each
dot is one particular website the color
says which crypto mining service that's
being used and in this force directed
play out individual points are being
pulled together if they are sharing
indicators so naturally you see the big
clusters those are the ones with the
same indicator file those other ones
were the same site key etc etc and you
see the emergence of very very large
campaigns all working together in total
we find more than 200 of these and
approximately half of the entire
ecosystem is actually organized and
powerful campaign and that means more
than five individual sites working for a
single actor curiously if you look at
this the largest actor that we found has
almost a thousand websites under their
control so last year's CCS paper to put
this into perspective found less than
that in total crypto checking in the
ecosystem so it's very largely driven by
organized activity by actors who trying
to make the most money out of it so
there's a lot of different campaigns and
you can analyze them more details of
this on the paper one of them I will
point out here and you can see what kind
of analysis behind that that is somebody
who's targeting the bit tricks 24
customer relationship management system
has found a vulnerability there and it's
infecting 850 websites the most
prominent victim was the Ministry of
Education of Belarus and what was
interesting about them is that it was
specifically targeting this application
and the Minor was swappable so they
could mine for two different sites and
they were randomly deciding which one to
pick at a given moment so they hid this
within the Beatrix core loader so this
was actually targeted attack they know
precisely what to go for the mining
script was pretty standard but they
included evasion techniques so when you
try to debug this they were immediately
dumping all the code that was related to
this in order to avoid any detection so
we analyzed all of these campaigns
manually and we also had our tool chain
that was now taking them apart and
understanding where the call graph came
from and how
tres looked like and what actually
happens and when you look at this in a
bigger scheme you see that most of these
infections are coming from third party
compromises so these are compromised
content management system templates so
somebody downloads the template for
WordPress and there's a minor embedded
these were extended scripts stretches to
jQuery and there was a minor in there or
a credit card validation script with a
minor in there or libraries that he
would use within the JavaScript
ecosystem as a matter of fact 60% of all
cryptid jackin was the result of
third-party software compromises so
remember previous works that that most
compromises happen as a result of
compromised websites and malicious
advertisement if you add this together
this is less than 30% by far the big
elephant in the room is third-party
software so why is this happening well
remember if you crawling the Alexa 1
million you're looking at a very
specific subset of the Internet these
are not sites where somebody uses
WordPress to run the e-commerce presence
and more foremost goes on the Internet
and download the shady template in order
to save money
well they would be running their own
dedicated ecommerce platforms they would
have web designers they would not be at
risk for linking to external linked
libraries in order to save some money so
therefore if you're looking at this
particular target group you are missing
the biggest attack vector that they
actually is that you can discover when
you're looking at the Internet at large
so what are the key takeaways if you
really wanna understand this criminal
problem of crypto jackin we have to
understand the ecosystem and in order to
understand the ecosystem campaign
analysis is a key technique to do this
and we do see this is necessary because
half of the activity that we see is
already related to organized activity
organized individual actors that are
doing this at scale what we also know is
that third party software is by far the
main attack vector that we need to be
worried about and that's actually very
difficult to to target there were many
talks of this conference that also
mentioned compromises in open source
software ecosystems and this is
extremely difficult for the average user
to do something about because they don't
have the knowledge they're just
downloading something so how can you be
sure that if you have a lie
that invokes the library that there's
everything clean around that that's
something that we as a community should
focus on and we have to be very
observant that if we use studies of the
Internet based for example on the Alexa
1 million as a top list we are looking
at a very biased sample because these
are specific companies they are
structurally different from how the rest
of the internet looks like so this was
just a quick taster there's a number of
additional aspects in paper
we have also looking into hiding an
obfuscation techniques there's various
levels and various sophistication levels
of hiding going on if you ever wondered
what Harry Potter has to do with crypto
checking read our paper we also see that
this hiding is much more prevalent where
they are trying to actively hide because
it's somewhere deep in the software tool
chain and we also interestingly see that
there's different market shares and
different prevalence for certain
services across different countries
during the end of the study something
very remarkable happens the largest
company that was providing these
web-based crypto mining coin hive was
ceasing the operation because it was no
longer profitable for that so what we
could observe was the teardown of the
entire infrastructure when the biggest
provider left the ecosystem and how did
the ecosystem afterwards react based on
that so what's there for the future we
found various sites we found various new
- new techniques these indicators have
been shared with online blacklist so if
you're having one of those plugins or
antivirus modules that protect you
against these kind of threats our
information is in there and and keeping
you safe as a matter of the study we
also found something very interesting
there was a fifth attack vector that we
happened on our radar when we started
this what we discovered was that there
was a cyber criminal group that was
attacking Internet routers and doing a
middlemen in the middle attack and
rewriting the HTML code wild flow
through the router and one router
manufacturer 70% of their devices were
compromised so this is an our upcoming
CCS paper the analysis of this and and
what concretely happened there and I
thank you for your attention and I
invite your questions thank you
I'm afraid we have time for maybe one 20
second question again start from you see
if I really liked your presentation I've
got one question when you when you talk
about elect someone million measuring
them a longitudinal study so there is a
paper and I'm I'm C last year that shows
that there's a significant churn in tell
Excel 1 million do you think that's the
reason why some of your result would be
different from CCS 2018 minesweeper yes
and no so the there are two aspects to
it
so exactly that that is one of the key
papers that analyzed this so if you look
in the Turner of overwrite of the Alexa
1 million there are bad days where you
have a hundred thousand two hundred
thousand sites being swapped out
especially at the long tail of the
distribution this is a part of this but
that's very difficult to measure
objectively out and the other part of
thing is that the ecosystem has been
becoming a bit more aware of this
problem and has also noticed that this
is not too profitable for their their
operation so I think it's a general
decline in this because the Monaro price
also dropped it is less useful and also
issues such as the Alexa 1 million
turnover but I think this should be
probably averaged out on a large scale
ok let's thank all the speakers again
[Applause]