so I'm Nicolas and I'm gonna be talking
about some lessons that we've learned
from evaluating the robustness of
defenses to adversarial examples
so the way I'm structuring this talk is
I'm basically going to be working
backwards I'm going to start by defining
adversarial examples then I'm going to
tell you about defenses to adversarial
examples then I'll talk about what it
means to evaluate their robustness and
then finally the lessons we've learned
from doing that so to make sure that
we're all on the same page with
adversarial examples the standard set up
goes something like this you have an
image which all of us recognize
correctly as a cat and indeed a
state-of-the-art neural network we'll
get it right with something like 88
percent confidence and it turns out that
you can introduce a very small
perturbation that basically none of us
as humans can recognize to get a new
image that looks something like this so
that this image here is recognized
incorrectly by the same neural network
that gets the other one right with 99%
confidence with the label guacamole and
so this is the problem ever so examples
is that these two images which are
indistinguishable to us as humans are
completely different objects as far as a
state-of-the-art neural network goes now
a virtual examples are not only a
problem on images they also exist on
text and on malware classification and
on audio but for most of this talk I'm
focusing on images just because they're
nice to show on a slide okay so why
should we care about ever so examples to
begin with
there are basically two reasons why the
first reason is we want to make machine
learning robust fortunately in the
security audience I don't really need to
justify this fact too much we're going
to be using these in security critical
situations ideally they should behave
robustly but even if you don't care
about the security aspects which
probably is none of you here you should
care about it just from the machine
learning side because ideally we would
like to make machine learning better and
episode examples give us a very nice
case study where humans do very well
the systems do very very poorly and if
you
see this gap is being something which is
worth closing then maybe you should
study adversely examples for that reason
only so there's one more reason to think
about episode examples so this is a plot
of the number of papers on adversity
examples over the last couple of years
this is growing almost exponentially and
so as a result all of you are going to
be working on Eversole examples within
some time in the near future otherwise
this trend can't continue so okay how do
we generate adversarial examples so this
here is a plot of decision boundary of a
neural network so what I'm showing here
is each point here corresponds to a
particular image so that this image in
the middle is classified as dog all of
the other blue points here are also
classified as dog and I'm going to add
one type of random noise in one axis so
that for example I get this image here
which is a noisy version of that dog as
I go and the other axis the same thing
happens I add random noise to get other
images that are perturbed and you'll
notice that if I were to draw like a
small box around the center it looks
like I'm safe everything here is
classified the same way and I think that
I'm fine the problem though is that this
is just a two-dimensional slice of a
very very high dimensional surface I've
picked two random orthogonal directions
to show this plot in but there are three
thousand other ones I could have
selected and so the question is why is
it the case that I can still find out
visual examples on neural networks and
the reason is that it turns out that
while in these two dimensions I happen
to be safe I can add random noise and it
doesn't really change the classification
for example I don't really think that
the image way up there is an adverse
example like it's it's far too hard to
recognize that object as anything as a
human I would like something which is
much less perturbed so what I can do is
I can just switch the axis that I'm
looking at sort of rotate this plot
through
3000 dimensional space and I can end up
with something that looks like this so
I'm adding the same amount of the same
direction of noise on the y-axis but on
the x-axis now I'm adding sort of the
worst case adversarial noise so that
here this image is now on the other side
of this ition boundary and this really
is the fundamental problem of
adversarial examples is that neural
networks make classifications where in
benign settings you can add lots of
noise and they're very robust but the
worst case Direction is highly sensitive
and can change the classification let me
do one more thing to this plot just so I
can make it a little more clear what's
happening and I'm going to extend the
z-axis up so that the z-axis now is
going to correspond to the confidence of
the neural network in the correct
prediction I'll say that one more time
so this here is the plot the confidence
is now of the correct prediction as
determined by the neural network is now
the z-axis so the initial image is
highly confident in the correct
prediction of being dog but you can
notice that you're sort of on the face
of this mountain and it's very easy to
just find the direction to go down and
use gradient descent to find an episode
example just by walking down the face of
this hill and very quickly you end up
with something which essentially is 0%
confidence in dog and is now very high
confidence and in this case the airplane
class so this is kind of what's going on
here with adversarial examples is that
in random directions the classifiers are
good in the adversarial directions the
classifiers are bad ok so then what do
we do with defenses to adversarial
examples so a defense is a neural
network with two properties the first
property is that it's accurate on some
test set of data we want the classifier
to be good on normal settings still but
we also want the classifier to be robust
to an adversary who's trying to evade it
so let me give you a couple examples of
Defense's that have been considered in
the research
space the first example is called
adversarial training this sort of makes
the claim that neural networks don't
generalize to out of distribution data
Abra so examples are maybe somehow out
of distribution and so therefore we
should train on the episode examples to
to become robust to them so the way this
works is fairly simple so in normal
training what we do is we take our
training data we feed it into some
training algorithm machine learning
happens and then we get out some
function f this is a classifier which
does well on the training data so now
what I'm going to do for adversarial
training is maybe the very natural thing
I'm going to take the images that I just
had I'm going to generate adverse
examples for each of them and now I have
these adverts or examples I'm going to
copy them back over to the training data
I'm going to give them the label of what
they originally classified as and then
trained on these along with the original
training data and this is going to now
give me a new classifier and then I'll
repeat as many times as necessary keep
on training on the episode examples of
the old classifier until eventually is
converges on something and the hope is
this something that it converges on is
robust ever so examples so that's one
one thing you can imagine there's
another second proposal from sometime
last year called thermometer encoding
and the claim here is that neural
networks are in some sense overly linear
that is that if you take the decision
boundary you can fairly easily
extrapolate in one direction what the
classification is going to look like for
a long direction and maybe this is that
why you should think this there's some
theory but this is the claim the paper
makes and so the proposal is that I'll
change the input representation so for
images typically we represent the input
as just a discreet pixel value from 0 to
255 maybe it's hard for the neural
network to learn that a change from 0 to
1 is somehow different than from 250 to
251 so let's make it easier
and we will do here is I'm going to
create a thermometer encoding function
of the input and I'll say that
thermometer encoding of 0.1 3 is a
couple of ones followed by a bunch of
zeros maybe of 0.66 is more ones
followed by few zeros and 0.97 is almost
all ones and now the hope is that the
neural network might be able to
disentangle the difference between
taking a small step at the low end of
the scale and taking a small step at the
high end of the scale maybe this helps
the final kind of defense that I'll tell
you about is input transformations so
the claim here is that perturbations are
in some sense brittle and so what I can
do is I can take my image I can
pre-process it by some kind of random
transformation men feed into the neural
network and then maybe by doing this I
can get a adversarial example become
classified correctly because it's been
modified in some way now you have to
make sure you don't add too much noise
that regular images are misclassified
but you want to add enough noise so a
visual examples are no longer classified
correctly you could also imagine doing
other things like JPEG compression or
you could try adding noise and I'll get
to some of these in a little bit later
okay so those are defenses to episode
examples and how they how they work now
let me tell you what it means to
evaluate the robustness and and how it
as we go about doing this so I guess the
basic question here is what does it mean
to evaluate the robustness and what
we're trying to do is we're trying to
figure out how accurate our classifiers
are in standard machine learning this is
very easy you know you take your model
you train the model on the training data
you compute some kind of evaluation
function to get the accuracy and then if
it's good enough then you say your
state-of-the-art
and if it's not good enough then like
you know tuned hyper parameters more
until it's good enough and and this is a
standard thing that is done in all of
machine learning so the question is what
changes on the
visceral example evaluations and in
particularly the only thing that changes
is this line is the evaluation function
so typically we have some kind of test
set that we can use to evaluate a
classifier on and as long as I don't
train on my test set that I basically
can't cheat in a standard machine
learning evaluation I just need to make
sure I train on training data and it's
disjoint from test data I test on that
and I'm good the problem is that no test
data exists forever so examples because
the episode examples are necessarily the
episode examples on the new classifier
that you happen to just train and so
that doesn't yet exist
so we're busting evaluations basically
turn this function of just a value eight
on the test data into something that
does this where now we have to come up
with some new attack function which is a
function of the model and then use this
to evaluate now there are other ways you
could imagine evaluating but in practice
this is what this is what people do you
take the same test date of the year you
would otherwise test on you come up with
an attack and you see how badly you can
make the classifier do on that test data
now there's a couple things I'm not
showing here for example I do have to
constrain that the adversary can't just
arbitrarily modify the inputs to make
them like all black because you know
then the accuracy would always be zero
so you'll have some threat model that
says maybe you can only modify five
pixels or maybe you can modify the low
three bits of every pixel but once
you've done that and you can put some
threat model down then this is exactly
what the attacks are doing you kind of
try and modify all of the images in the
test set to make them so that the
classifier is now fooled okay so the
question then is how complete are
evaluations that are written in today's
papers and for that let me give you a
case study of the defense's that were
accepted at I clear twenty eighteen I
clear as one of the three main
conferences on machine learning this
happened sometime last year so at that
conference they were a bunch of papers
were defenses to adverse or examples
accepted and I should say that to begin
with the authors of these papers did
make a serious effort to evaluate them
I've shown the papers here and I've
highlighted in red the regions that are
at the evaluation so by space most of
these papers are roughly one-half
evaluation the authors of these papers
are from places like Google and Facebook
and Amazon they're from universities
like Stanford and Berkeley and Carnegie
Mellon and UT Austin and Princeton so by
all accounts these are highly regarded
researchers they know what they're doing
so we we've elevated these defenses and
we placed four of them out of scope
these were defenses that had threat
models that were incompatible with ours
or that had some certified claim that
they could prove that it was robust
under some specific distortion model I'm
not in the business of doing proofs and
so we just said let's put those out of
scope two of them were correct I'll come
back to what I mean exactly by correct
in a second and the other seven were
broken so over half of the defenses that
were accepted at this conference were
broken in and six of these offered zero
robustness
they did absolutely nothing one of them
helped a little bit
and by correct for the other two what I
mean to say is that the claim that was
written in the paper was correct and we
were not able to invalidate it so I'm
not gonna say that it's necessarily
going to definitely be right but I'm not
confident saying it's wrong and this is
in some sense concerning that this they
were broken in this way and not only
were they broken in this way when when
we broke them it only took us maybe a
month or something to do this for all of
these defenses and so the question is
what was going on why is it that these
defenses were accepted at one of the top
conferences and machine learning and all
over half of them were easily broken so
I showed you this this picture
earlier this is the lost surface of a
neural network where on one direction
I'm going adversarially and in the other
direction I'm moving in some random
direction so it turns out that what
happened is that they turned this loss
function to something that looks like
this in case it's a little hard to see
what's going on let me zoom in on this
one region here and show you that the
function looks like this so imagine that
you're a gradient descent optimizer and
I say you're there which direction would
you like to travel to find the
adversarial example you basically have
no idea what to do you'll pick a random
direction maybe it turns out that you're
on the side of a cliff facing this way
so you step that way and then it turns
out that now you on the side of a cliff
facing the other direction and you step
back and you run for a hundred a
thousand iterations just randomly moving
around this space if you're lucky you
happened across the decision boundary if
you're unlucky you just don't get
anywhere useful and so this is
essentially what happened almost all of
the defenses that we looked at did
something that looks like this where
they made the gradients insufficient to
provide insufficient information to
actually know in which direction to
travel to find an adversity example and
so you may say you know well that's fine
you can't find the never so example
therefore it's robust but remember that
what the loss function actually looks
like is this and so while there may not
be an easy way to find it when you look
locally when you look globally in some
sense it's very easy this function looks
nearly identical to this one and so if I
somehow knew ahead of time what the big
picture looked like I could identify
which direction to travel and to find
the a vasila example it's just the fact
that with this very very local view that
the standard optimizers have they can't
find episodes now one brief aside this
isn't the first time that it's hot
and that a bunch of Defense's are
proposed and very quickly broken in the
space of adverse or examples so this has
happened relatively regularly over the
last couple months where people propose
defenses and very quickly they're broken
more often than not if a defense is
proposed and someone else evaluates it
it's shown to be wrong within a couple
months now I should mention that this is
not all of them but almost all of the
evaluations that are done in adversarial
machine learning on Defense's and so in
security we have this interesting setup
where one or two people write a defense
paper and then everyone else wants to
write the attacks for some reason in
machine learning it's the other way
around there are like 20 maybe attack
papers that try and evaluate defenses
and there are something like 3 or 400
defense papers and this is in some sense
a concerning set up to be in because
we've only evaluated maybe 50 defenses
ever and the other 450 maybe they do
something maybe they don't no one knows
and so that's its own problem ok so what
are the lessons that we've actually
learned then from these evaluations so
that I think comes in a couple pieces so
let me start with the first the first
kind of lessons is what types of
defenses are effective so the first kind
of defense that's effective is
adversarial training this is the first
one that I showed you earlier this is
one of the ones that we tried to
evaluate in and we weren't able to show
that it was not robust whatever skill
training does so this is the law surface
of a standard neural network what
episode training does is it makes the
law surface instead of look something
very ugly like this it makes it look
very nice like this so it really smooths
out the decision boundary notice it
pushed the decision boundary out so it's
not full
bust it's not like we solved the problem
entirely but I've made it much harder to
find episode examples and this also
gives me confidence that I'm not just
being fooled artificially because it's
hard to find them in some sense it looks
like it's easier to find adversely
examples in this setting than it was on
the standard of classifier but in my
easier here I mean I know that I've done
the right thing because the law surface
is pointing all the same direction the
entire way so probably it's not the case
that there's not going to be these weird
wrinkles in the law surface like here
now I can't guarantee that but that
heuristic ly seems like it's the case
and for everyone who's tried to
reevaluate these they found similar
results
so I personal training seems like one
good thing I should mention it's maybe a
little bit unsatisfying that the
solution to adversarial examples for
this defense is just keep training on
them until you do well you may have
liked a solution and I would have liked
the solution that said here is a system
that's better at machine learning
because it better captures what humans
do or something else and then section 13
of their paper shows and also it solves
adversely examples I view episode
examples maybe as a bug that should be
fixed not by just addressing that by by
addressing the root cause and if the
root cause is that they don't adapt to
new domains these machine learning
classifiers then this is kind of
cheating but it does seem like it's
correct so if you know ahead of time
what kinds of attacks you're going to
see in this machine learning space you
can just train on those attacks and
become relatively robust to them now if
the adversary changes the threat model
and now instead of distorting the low
three bits of every image of that every
pixel of the image now flips five pixels
the classifier is going to break so you
have to train on every new threat model
that you're going to ever see and
enumerate these seems hard but this is
one of the effective defenses okay so
the second class
of effective defenses is the empty set
the only defenses we have are the first
everyone who's tried to propose another
defense basically that isn't adversarial
training so far when anyone else has
evaluated it hasn't worked people have
tried lots and lots of other things the
ones which haven't been evaluated don't
work and as I mentioned there are
another 400 that people have proposed
that no one else is evaluated and so we
don't know if they work or not and this
is an unfortunate situation to be in
fortunately there are a bunch of you in
the audience who are all security people
who know how to evaluate things so maybe
you can help remedy this okay so the
second lesson from evaluating robustness
so okay I told you earlier that making
the loss of as ugly doesn't work and I
sort of appealed to the fact that if you
looked at the pictures then that it's
not very different and it looks like
there's an attack without actually
giving you what that attack was so let
me tell you what you can do so the first
thing that you could do to attack this
would be to like think really hard and
then write a differentiable
implementation of jpg and then back
propagate through jpg to compute
gradients and then everything works
that's a lot of work though because
there are lots of think functions that
are easy to write that have nice forward
passes that don't have differentiable
back passwords and this is how we
compute these episode examples if you
remember is we take gradients through
these neural networks so that's one
thing you can do and this is a very nice
solution if you're willing to think very
hard about each of them there's another
thing you can do in we wrote we have a
paper that shows that you can do this is
suppose that you have a very special
special type of neural network which it
turns out many things fall into this
category of so suppose that I'm taking
my image and I feed this forward through
a neural net
work that has some kind of layers that
are hard to differentiate through so
most of it is a standard neural network
but it turns out that you can't compute
gradients through one or two small
number of layers so what we'll do is
we'll do the forward pass in the
standard setting I'll do the forward
pass and I'll get some probability
vector of what the inputs going to be
classified as and now on the backward
pass instead of taking the hard to
differentiate through function I swap it
out with an easy to differentiate
through a function which is not exactly
computing the right thing but as a
closed approximation so for example JPEG
compression roughly satisfies the
equation f of X equals x this is the
idea of JPEG compression it shouldn't
change the image very much the gradient
of f of X equals x is 1 so I'll just
drop the JPEG compression pretend it
didn't exist now this is not actually
the gradient of the function it's a lie
but it turns out that it's a useful lie
the gradients of this are relatively
smooth and it means that it points you
in a helpful direction relatively
continuously it doesn't actually always
give you the right answer but it gives
you some kind of gradient signal so that
if you repeat this many many times
continuously finding a single step of a
gradient and taking a small step in that
direction and repeating with this lie of
a gradient then it turns out that's good
enough and you can actually find out
virtual examples this way and so this is
a one general way that you can find
adverse early examples there are others
and I would encourage you if you're
interested to go read the literature
it's very interesting but this is one of
the standard ways now that you can
differentiate through things that that
break gradients in this one particular
way okay so the third kind of lesson
from evaluating the performing these
evaluations is this so I should mention
this was all going to be from this paper
that we wrote on called on evaluate
adverse over bus'ness about six months
ago now that
basically a set of advice on how you
should perform adversely evaluations so
what I'm going to do is I'm going to
cover a bunch of things that you
shouldn't and should do when performing
episode evaluations for those of you who
aren't performing those evaluations
right now maybe this part isn't as
important for you but again I would
encourage you to just see what it is
that's happening in the space and the
kinds of errors that are being made
partly because many of the areas that
are being made are very basic and I
would like more security people to be
working in this space because I feel
like many of us would not make these
same kinds of errors the other thing I'm
gonna say is that I want to give some
actionable advice here and that requires
me being specific so I'm going to give
screenshots from papers that do the
wrong thing just know that this is
standard and I'm not bashing those
individual papers I'm sort of showing
the types of things that have gone wrong
in the past okay so the first thing that
I'm gonna say is that in order to do a
security evaluation you actually need to
do a security evaluation you have to
take the defense and try and beat it
it's not sufficient to go in generate a
virtual examples on some model save them
to disk and then say okay I'm gonna now
train some new model on some new data
with my defense and then test them on
the same data so examples that broke the
other thing this doesn't work I mean you
all know this it's not fine if I live up
to new crypto algorithm and said well
let me take the differential that breaks
md5 and I'll apply that to mine and it
fails therefore my cypher is secure and
this would be ridiculous
but this is what's done and maybe half
of all I've so example defence
evaluations is people don't actually try
and evaluate on it in an attack their
defense so this is the first thing that
that you shouldn't do when performing an
evaluation the second thing is that
there are some papers that go with are a
little better
they have like a section three point one
called effectiveness which is a page and
a half by the way machine learning
papers are eight pages long so a page
and a half is actually a relatively
large fraction of the paper
and so the way so they have this effect
in this section and and then they have
another section three point four that's
robustness to the white boxes hacker
which is a paragraph long in which case
what was this section doing this section
was showing that if you take someone who
doesn't try very hard then its robust
and to which I would say you know take
this put it in appendix good to know
that someone doesn't try very hard can't
break it and make this the remainder of
the paper so this is something that's
fairly typical as you'll see a very very
long section on it stops all of these
attacks when you don't actually try and
then we'll try a little bit for one
paragraph okay in machine learning this
is this thing called a held out data set
this is where you'd like take some data
and don't train on don't test on until
the very end
you can't hold out attacks that's just a
concept which doesn't exist
you need to come up with new attacks you
can't just like take some attack pretend
we didn't know about it before designer
defense and then run that attack in
particular against it that's not an
adaptive attack okay this is attack
that's called F GSM what this does is it
takes one step of gradient descent it
was designed to show that neural
networks are linear it was not designed
to evaluate defenses but because it's
only one step of gradient descent it's
very fast and very easy to write and
everyone uses it for evaluations don't
if you want to run against it that's
fine but it would be nice if you also
ran against stronger things that tried
harder than taking one gradient pass
through our neural network and so that
you can evaluate in twenty milliseconds
instead of half a second in particular
when performing gradient descent it's
necessary in general to perform one
hundred or a thousand iterations of
gradient descent to do these evaluations
properly you can get by with doing fewer
than 100 but you have to think really
hard you have to make sure that every
gradient step is actually doing
something useful to give you an adverse
for example and this takes a lot of work
it's much easier to think less and make
the computer
more work and just make it perform many
many many iterations gradient descent
and give you something which is mostly
going to correctly evaluate if you're
robust or not you should check that when
you do more work you actually get better
if you try a very weak attack in this
case FG sm one iteration of a gradient
descent and it is doing better so the
accuracy under this attack is lower than
the accuracy when you try many many many
iterations of gradient descent probably
it's because you've done something wrong
if you're trying harder and succeeding
less often
then you're optimizing for the wrong
thing probably and so this is one of the
other things to check for and the final
thing to check for I think is that you
need to make sure that if you run an
attack that has no bound on the
distortion then eventually it should
succeed so why should why is this the
case well if I took some image that's a
cat and I allows you to make an
arbitrary distortion to it to turn into
a dog in the limit it should just turn
this image into a dog and if it doesn't
do that then you know that your attack
is weak because if it fails then it
means it's got stuck in some kind of
local minima that isn't actually a
missile example and so by making sure
that you and you run it for long enough
that you eventually succeed then you can
at least have some confidence that it's
doing the right thing this is related to
this point which is that they also let
me show you this is some plots that
people have made of distortion on the
x-axis and how well the attack has
succeeded on the y-axis and in
particular all of these are plateauing
at 10% if I have undone distortion I
should succeed 100% of the time and so
it's concerning that they're all
plateauing at the same value of 10%
probably something is going wrong here
maybe it's it's more exaggerated in this
plot where on image net with a thousand
classes so the best you could have hope
if you had a random classifier would be
0.1% the strongest attack that can turn
any image into solid gray
with Distortion 128 / 255 that is this
point here means is only succeeds here
slightly over 20 percent of the time so
something is going wrong with these
kinds of attacks make sure this doesn't
happen it's also true that if you make
the threat model more broad the attacker
should succeed more often this is kind
of true by definition but it's not true
here just check for these simple things
in these evaluations and this is like
sort of regularly occurs is that you'll
have you'll give the obvious way more
power and they'll succeed less often
which is a little weird okay so maybe
enough negative things let me tell you
some good things that you can do in
these evaluations the first of them is
to evaluate against the worst attack so
if you pick ten attacks and evaluate
against all of them and one of them
that's very weak shows your thing doing
better and one of the strong so is your
thing doing worse your defense is worse
it's not okay and in this paper that
does that nicely it evaluates against
the slew of attacks and then compares
against the one that is most effective I
really like these accuracy versus
distortion plots because they help me
debug whether something's gone wrong and
so here you have a very nice example of
adversarial training that's supposed to
be robust up to Distortion 0.3 and you
see that it is robust up to 0.3 and then
as soon as you exceed the the threat
model that was defined and go about
point three the accuracy begins to
plummet this is a nice thing to see that
hopefully they've done the right thing
now because it eventually goes to zero
and it only gives you what it's supposed
to the other thing is that you have to
actually verify you've done enough
iteration to gradient descent I
mentioned earlier that maybe a hundred
or a thousand is good turns out
sometimes it's not and here's some
defense that these people ran where they
were still getting improvements in
attack success rate when going from a
hundred thousand to a million iterations
of gradient descent I don't know what's
going on here but I'm really glad they
ran this experiment and so it's really
nice to see these these kinds of results
and finally or maybe second to last is
that you should try something that's
gradient free all of the other things
that I told you earlier
gradient-based attacks these are attacks
that sort of look which direction on the
hill is down and go that way there are
other kinds of attacks that aren't
gradient based that are good to also run
because if you break the gradient
descent then it won't break these kinds
of attacks and that's a nice kind of
thing to know and maybe the final kind
of simplest thing to do is to just try
random noise so if you're not robust to
random noise you shouldn't be robust to
adverse all examples and some a little
bit theory that shows this and so in
particular all of the defenses that we
had evaluated earlier that we had to
work for a couple months to break turns
out they all perform exactly the same if
you give them classified random noise
and so this is not something there's a
sort of a very easy simple test to see
if you might be robust and I should
mention that the one blue line that's
the way up there is training on exactly
the kind of noise that we happen to test
on so that's not really a defense that's
the upper limit of what you could hope
to achieve and basically all the
classifiers do the same which is much
worse okay so that's all I have to say
about what we've learned from
evaluations so far let me briefly
mention what I think will happen in the
future or what may happen in the future
so I showed the slide earlier of lots of
things being broken okay so so the year
is 1997 the AES contest is going on
we're trying to design robust crypto in
the block and block ciphers and you see
a slew of papers coming out that's like
break after break after break after
break of things that are no longer
effective are you thinking like we're
hopeless these ones are all written by
David I know yes because I went to his
website and downloaded them because he
did a lot of them but yeah so right so
so should if we were in the 90s should
we think that we're hopeless and you
know if we go back to like today
you know this is now the best attack on
AES which is like almost 10 years old
and it's not even really effective um so
like we went from a time in 20 years
where everything was broken to designing
relatively good crypto and so maybe you
know you think you know are we crypto in
the 90s maybe we have the right kind of
thing that worth doing we just need to
to think a little harder and maybe we'll
solve the problem okay so I'm gonna
argue maybe not and I think I have two
reasons why the answers maybe not okay
so the first reason is something like
this so this is a plot of the best
certified accuracy with a proof that you
can get on imagenet today so these
people can write down a proof that says
that the accuracy on the classifier is
at least some twenty percent when you go
up to this distortion bound so attack
success rates in insecurity and this is
a slide I stole from Dave Evans I think
it's a wonderful slide so in crypto you
know we say that we're secure if we have
a probability of succeeding of like you
know two to the minus 128 roughly if
something's two to the minus 127 it's
broken run for the hills throw it out
try again okay and in systems you know
we want to to the minus thirty-two you
know you'll do a stat canary something
like this but it's okay maybe you know
broken is two to the minus twenty try a
million times and you can defeat us that
canary maybe that's that's a broken
defense and machine learning where like
2 to the minus one like the best
defenses succeed half of the time and
something's broken if it's two to the
zero so we kind of have a long way to go
before we can maybe call this a nice
kind of security okay so that's maybe
one reason why we're not yet crypto in
the 90s the other reason is that I
showed you this plot of how much we can
prove that we're accurate for these are
the images that correspond to the proofs
that we can be robust so we I can prove
that there's a like 10% chance that'll
classify this image here correctly I
can't really tell the difference between
those two images and so you know maybe
we still have a bunch of work to do you
know in particular maybe I'd want the
plot to look something like this and you
know if I were to extrapolate those
lines I'm like down to like negative a
thousand over here but it's in some
sense even more concerning than that so
this is the original image this is an
image that has an l2 distortion of 75 l2
distortion is one of the threat models
people consider this is the standard
Euclidean distance of how much
distortion I'm adding and I would like
to be able to classify this image
correctly I think all of us can get it
right I've added a little noise but not
so much that it's impossible to see but
it turns out that this image here also
has an LT restorin of 75 and so we don't
really even have a good definition of
what we want
like we know intuitively we want to do
something like the human does be robust
in some sense under some norms but we
don't actually know what we can what
norms we want now it's okay for today
that we're using these l2 norms because
we can't even solve them and so in
particular if I set a really small bound
then it's clear that a human wouldn't
change their mind and so we should at
least be robust under these small norms
and so I'm not saying don't work on this
space because these norms are bad the
norms are in some sense the best we have
today but if we want to succeed in the
future we can't hope to succeed by
focusing only on these these l2 norms so
maybe the claim is like we're crypto pre
Shannon you know and like crypto
free Shannon was people trying the best
they could to come up with defenses that
worked but they didn't really know what
they're optimizing for and then Shannon
came about and told us about entropy and
now we had something to talk about
and we could point to something and say
this is what it means to be secure it
would be nice in the space of machine
learning security to have something to
point to is say this is what I want to
be secure I don't think that we
have that today and without that I don't
think that we have any hope of achieving
general but robustness okay
so to briefly conclude then I think
we've come a long way to understanding
adverse overbust miss a couple years ago
we had basically no idea how to perform
evaluations in the first place now at
least we know how to perform the
evaluations so that's good but I still
think we have a long way to go in order
to be able to achieve actual general
robustness because I don't think we know
what the correct distortion models are I
don't think we actually know where we're
optimizing for but my hope is that the
lessons that we've learned from how to
evaluate correctly will help us actually
succeed in this general quest for
robustness so thank you and I'm happy to
take any questions very much deepest
any questions there's a microphone at
the center of the room okay well I start
with one question so it seems like what
you present is more from the perspective
of authors but I think half of if we
want to call it blame goes on some
reviewers they let this paper go through
so can you turn whatever you suggested
into like those add-ons for a viewer so
like check this don't check that yeah so
so what about reviewers so I mean I'm
not trying to blame anyone I'm just
trying to comment on the state of
research today I guess now it is a
problem that these papers maybe get
accepted but yeah okay so made it to
answer your question directly for
reviewers
I think the necessary thing is to check
that the people have tried hard to break
their own defense this is in some sense
the only thing that matters now so I
should say that like I don't expect two
reviewers to only accept perfect
defenses this is something you can't do
what I sort of the bar that I set for an
episode example defense paper is
convince me that no existing attacks
will defeat it
sometimes a low bar but convinced me
that in order to defeat this someone
will have to think of something new and
interesting that is publishable because
if you can sort of pass this bar at
least we make sure that it's not the
case that in order to break something I
download your code if you put code up
which you should and then I go take some
attack mental implementation download
that run the know an attack on the known
defense and that thing breaks and then
like we've learned nothing that
everyone's wasted their time by reading
your paper and reviewing your paper like
it would be much nicer if I had to think
really hard and Comp with a new
technique in order to break than their
defense and I think that's what
reviewers should be looking for is can I
convince myself that in order for this
to fail have to learn something new
about the world that's my bar that's a
good answer
hi I was wondering that in some cases
where you have a high modification
distance or l 2-norm or even
proportional like mean average error the
at some point it's impossible for a
classifier to classify this when you mix
adversarial examples and due to
catastrophic interference at what level
do you think it's realistic to expect a
classifier to be able to differentiate
those yeah what level should a
classifier be able to all of know why
you should a classifier be able to
correctly classify ever-so examples this
is I think one of the big unknown
questions I know how to pick images that
are very close to humans that are still
classified wrong if we could get those
all correct I don't know at what level
we would want things to be to actually
be correct like I showed this image
earlier of one way of what one example
of images that were l2 distortion 75 a
part that I would want to become
classified correctly I so that's clearly
in the set of things that humans
perceive similar but then there's also
this other image where you draw a big
giant box over it's the same that's
outside the set like in some sense I
think coming up with a function of what
a human think these images are similar
may be just as hard as coming up with a
function do the classification correctly
because if you had that image you know
if you had that magic classifier maybe
whose do K nearest neighbors but yeah I
would like to see more research on this
question in particular because in some
sense it's necessary I'll give one other
comment which is that in some areas it's
not the human Oracle that matters so
malware classification I don't care what
the person thinks about whether or not
this is malware either it deletes my
hard drive or it doesn't and so the
Oracle here is is it malicious or not
and the distortion model is maybe
anything goes and so there it's even
harder because you kind of have to be
correct everything maybe you can assign
some kind of cost function to how hard
it is to do attacks but I think
the visions setup might be different
from the audio setup might be different
from the malware setup it might be
different from the text setup and we'll
have to think carefully about each of
those thank you thank you thank you
you