so yes I'm in clearing and this was
joint work with ivan meyer and cannot we
from the TU branch my and let's directly
start so here we can see a source code
example and the question is who's the
offer so let's say we would like to find
out if it was Ellis and authorship
attribution can answer this by
identifying the author of a given source
code by identifying by exploiting the
individual stylistic patterns but what
if Ellis has not Britain that so maybe
the source code here is an adverse or
example and the fret of it verse well
source code examples has received only
little attention so far and my talk
today I will present it and how we can
generate such samples and you will be
surprised how well it works
and cause this domain the domain of
source code is so complicated
we will also I think learn a lot
interesting things how to generate add
virtual examples and such complicated
discrete domains because this is not a
toy example domain and it's quite
complicated to rewrite source code yeah
so let's sort you recap how office of
attribution works before encoding habits
manifests in a variety of stylistic
patterns so that we need an expressive
set of features for attribution free
groups are currently used in the
research field that are lay out lexical
and syntactic features and officer
attribution times this pattern by using
machine learning two notable examples
are the work by Calais Canada which has
the most comprehensive feature set and
we work by abu hamid at are that
performed a large-scale study with
recurrent neural networks so layout
features a simple layout feature can be
for example if we use white spaces or
tabs or the number of empty lines
between our functions and statements and
how we use comments and so on but code
formatting tools like C
format easily removed them and an
attacker of course can also easily
manipulate them so insert more empty
lines is quite easy the more advanced
feature can be derived from a lexical
analysis of a source code we can count
the number of functions I think it's a
quiet good feature because some
developers put all their code in one
function while others use more functions
to get a modular card code and moreover
we can tokenize the code and obtain
string based features that implicitly
describe syntax and semantics here we
see a simple source code example where
we're talking int occurs three times so
the developer may have the tendency to
use int
while another developer would always use
long as a data type in C++ or C such
features cannot be easily manipulated of
course replacing names is quite easy but
replacing data types is already more
difficult since we need to adapt all its
usages another class of features are
syntax and control for patterns from the
abstract syntax tree for instance we
could use the number of adjacent tree
nodes as feature so the joint occurrence
of the function and argument nodes or
the if and compartment three nodes and
again manipulating such features is
quite challenging without changing the
whole tree structure so these features
give us a broad view on the
characteristics of source code and as
most learning methods operate and on
vectors we need to map our features to
vector space and usually we perform some
feature selection and tf-idf waiting and
finally we train a classifier with one
class per offer and attribution works by
evaluating the score of each class and
then returning the class or offer with a
highest score so back to the question of
LS is our source code offer and now we
see that Alice has
not written the source code we
manipulated some specific patterns in
the source code so while here it's just
Ellis what if that verse we would choose
a victim like a real developer or a
company so it's essential that source
code attribution is accurate and robust
as false allegation could have of course
white reaching consequences for our
attack we assume an adversary with
blackbox access she can send a source
code to the method and retrieve the
corresponding prediction scores the
training data the features and the
learning algorithm are not known in our
paper we also test the transferability
scenario where but versa we has some
training data but not access to the
original classifier and it also works
but I won't talk about that in my talk
today I will focus on the black box
scenario with available classifier we
consider two types of attacks
the first is an untargeted one where we
want to change the classification into
any other developer and the more
sophisticated attack is the targeted
version where you want to change the
classification into a previously chosen
target developer and this is quite
challenging because we really need to
mimic the coding habits from one we have
to move through coding habits from one
developer to another developer to mimic
a realistic attack we also set some
constraints in the bursar the change
source code should be should produce the
same output of course for a given input
envers source code should be readable
and plausible so plausible corresponds
to the impossibility aspect from the
image domain when we create their
reversal examples we do not want to see
data and it was a real example so that's
why we do not simply copy junk code from
the target developer or use unusual
syntax we could for instance hide some
arbitrary letters and
until we get the wanted classification
Malthus would not be a very
sophisticated attack because we can
imagine that it's easy to detect and we
can easily remove code that is never
used and comments are also quite easy to
ignore by the classifier or when we
build features and last but not least we
do not consider layout features they are
not robust they can be easily normalized
through code formatting and even worse
they are easily too many palade and in
this way we evaluate our untack and are
even more difficult scenario because we
do not change layout features so we have
to change the more advanced features
like a lexical and syntactic features
from an adverse alerting perspective we
have a quite challenging situation here
which is different to image domain which
get a lot of which is getting a lot of
attention so we operate in a problem
space this is the real world with our
source code and the classic a
classification happens in the feature
space so if we have a target point in a
feature space the exact position to get
there is actually not really
controllable this is because we have a
problem of feature correlation even if I
could change one feature the tf-idf
waiting as a normalization across the
dimensions and would distribute this
change over all other dimensions and
second we observed multiple times that
even if we wanted to change one feature
value other feature values automatically
decreased so we wanted to increase the
value of one feature other values
decreased automatically and this is
coupled with another group of problems
so we have two main restrictions when I
want to change in too long for instance
I may have to change all the printf
commands where it is used so each tiny
change needs to consider the problem
space validity so at the source code
should
be compatible and the smaller smallest
possible change in the problem space may
already impact multiple features in the
feature space and firt we cannot control
the amount of changes so even if I
wanted to change the feature value just
by one or two maybe it is not possible
because of the problem our problem space
dictates that we you cannot change it by
one you have to change the value by
three or four yes so next the beach
feature map is not bijective so the
other way round if we have a feature
point it is not possible to find a valid
source code with exactly these features
in general at peace so if it's dilemma
is also relevant in other discreet
domains and I think it has not received
as much attention as it should before to
tackle this problem and to fulfill our
constraints we use the following
strategy which is also shown by the
figure by the way we implement the code
transformations we implement code
transformations in the province base so
we can move there we can modify the
source code and these movements are
guided by Monte Carlo tree search from a
feature space that helps us what
sequences or movements we should take so
in particular we implemented 36 code
transformations with flip tooling of a
compiler front and claireaussi line and
we used multiple program representations
such as the abstract syntax tree or of a
control flow graph and using the
compiler here is definitely the way to
go and not to implement some own
solution because we can get a valid and
full view on the source code let me
explain that with an example so we see
an API transformation to replace C out
by printf with printf to this end we use
the control flow graph first to find out
the position of C out command before
this is relevant when we want to print
floating point values for instance so we
set position 10 to Phi
how many zeros or how many values we
print and then in the second step we use
the ast to find out the final data type
of each entry and the C out command to
create the necessary printf string to
guide this transformation we interpret
the advert or example generation as a
game and use Monte Carlo tree search
which some of you may know because
alphago used it successfully I won't go
into the details of this algorithm but
in a nutshell we create a search tree
where each node corresponds to some
state of a source code and each edge to
a code transformation and we evaluate
multiple paths and in this way we can
evaluate the impact of different code
transformations so we evaluate different
transformations so we get a search tree
and then based on these information
misinformation we decide on the next
move to evaluate our attack we consider
two state-of-the-art methods from Calais
Canada Island a Bahamut a time the first
method uses a random forest and actually
layout lexical and syntactic features
but as I said we do not consider layout
features because it would make our
attack even easier and the second method
uses just lexical features and a
recurrent neural network in particular
in lsdm here we use the same setup as
both works and we use C++ sprites from
the Google coach am the benefit from
this dataset is that we have offers
which have solved the same problems
those of the same challenges and so we
can learn coding style rather than
problems and our data that consists of
204 offers which have solved the same
eight challenges and finally we use a
stratified and group k-fold
cross-validation where we use seven
challenges for training and one for
testing and the attack so our results
are that in our targeted scenario number
one target scenario we can prevent the
correct attribution for both methods in
almost all cases
while at the same time we only change
one to five lines of code and they've
been in the majority of cases an average
each file has 74 lines of code so this
underlines the very targeted nature of
our transformations in the target
scenario where we want to impersonate
another developer we can impersonate
three or four developers for both
methods and approached by apartment
Arliss is slightly easier to fool center
rests only on lexical features and these
are for example declarations or type def
declarations and so on and they can be
easily or there can be manipulated a
little bit easier so if we take a closer
look at the target attack we can see
that around 50% of the features modified
for Callie's Canada are and this shows
how this an alliance of a feature
correlation problem we have we had to
solve it is around 18% for AB mat and aa
on average this is because their
approach has a more dense vector and if
a feature is 0 it remains zero even
after changing the source code and at
the same time our final source code
again we have very targeted changes
around one to ten lines of code that are
added modified or removed so if we
here's a real-world example from our
evaluation and we can see that we do not
just add impossible garbage to the code
but the code remains quite normal
so normal as it can be for C++ at least
to my mind
in the first step for example we add
some type tabs to mimic behavior from
some developer who prefers type test and
then we also replaced a for block by a
while loop and we changed the output API
and yeah so it really showed that the
resulting virtual example is still a
norm
source code but now it is classified as
another developer we wanted to have so
to summarize the main takeaways we have
seen how to perform a blackbox
attack against authorship attribution
with realistic constraints second we
considered the problems feature space
dilemma we have seen the unique
challenges of adversity learning and
discrete domain and here the source code
we introduced Monte Carlo tree search
and the nice thing this approach the
Monte Carlo tree search does not depend
on the learning algorithm so it can also
be for random forests and this relieves
us from a burden to learn some other
learning algorithm to you some other
learning algorithms such a deep neural
network to as a substitute model and
then to hope that our advert will
examples from a deep neural network
transfer to random forests so here we
can directly attack the random forests
and yeah the approach is quite generic
so it's also applicable to other domains
such as text or PDF malware and so on
and yeah so one thing maybe just to
conclude my talk one takeaway should be
that our paper is not only introducing
another adverse or example problem now
for source code but we had quite some
wet some quite challenges to solve
because we have a discrete domain here
with some constraints and so we created
we gained some new insights how to gray
create adversely examples in some
complicated domains and yeah finally we
performed a large-scale study and we
concluded that current attribution
methods are not secure and we need novel
methods for authorship attribution so
thank you very much for your attention
and questions
[Applause]
thank you for the great talk my
questions in the backpack setting how
many queries do you make to the model
like the target model yeah we so if you
create the search tree the Monte Carlo
tree search then you need for each yeah
let me explain that so you can we create
sequences of transformations so we do
not change the source code by one
transformation and then put it to the
method and retrieve the score but we
create we perform five or ten
modifications and then we put it to the
method and I think around one to three
hundred cards are necessary for natural
example okay so it's not as much but not
so much but yeah yeah ok thank you ok
choke reset and why you really I'm
excited that you did this work thank you
very much
and but I have a question about like so
adversarial examples in the image domain
right when you transform a panda to like
to be recognized as a Gibbon but humans
would still obviously recognize it as a
panda so my question is here is that
when you actually go through these Co
transformations what the like the
original algorithms were recognizing was
the like the style of a particular
program have you transformed the code to
be in the style of the original
programmer or would like a human or some
other analysis actually think that it
was in the original style so is it sort
of a different qualitative class of
adversarial example than the type of
adversarial example where sort of the
human is fold in one way but the you see
what I mean
yeah I hope yeah yeah so actually we
stopped the attack when the classifier
classified by our developer so we would
have to continue our attack until we can
be of course clearly sure that we
completely transferred the stylistic
patterns from one developer to the other
that
yeah if you if your method changes the
features and so on of course maybe there
are some of course we have not changed
all traces from the original developer
so there are still but it still seems a
little different so yeah yeah so just as
a follow-up I think Rachel that I think
the analogy here is that the the analogy
would be that the transformation should
preserve the functionality right anyway
my question is I think it's a little
different what rachel was asking is
whether the adversarial example that you
produced if you showed it to a human
they would identified as the person that
you targeted or they would still
identify it as being from the original
author happiness if you showed to human
I'm not sure what he would I don't think
he could actually identify anything so
these stylistic patterns are somewhere
hidden and a lot of features in the
combination but of course when I looked
at my adversely examples sometimes I
thought okay it's a little bit it's
fooling the classifier just because I
see some characteristics of original
classifier developer but sometimes when
we performed a lot of code
transformations so 30 or 40 controls
meant actually we had mimicked the
coding style from a target developer and
I could not say if it's really the
target developer or that was an example
so it also fooled me yeah maybe one
suggestion to look into this would be to
use the same algorithm for a different
problem where you would have an easier
time of telling what the crowd truth so
this is a great talk to the two
dimitra's from the University of
Maryland so I mean in adversarial
examples people often you know talk
about robust features are there robust
features and what are the robust
features and
all that so in this problem authorship
attribution do you think there are any
robust features yes this is actually I
think the most important question after
now presenting the paper because we
created bad hack and now I think
researchers can create this useless
automatic attack this I think one of the
most important advantages we can run the
attack automatically and the features
we've changed were or I think a robust
feature should capture how we solve a
problem I think this would be a robust
feature because we cannot automatically
change something
for instance and think about how we
solve a sorting problem some of you
would use bubbles or some of your
quicksort some of you their own I went
so this mimics how how we think about
how to solve the problem and I think
this is not really this cannot be
automated of course a human being there
was some study about that I think people
will always be able somehow to
understand how you code but it will be
much more difficult and I think this
would be a robust feature so we should
maybe look at the control for graph how
we solve problems and then maybe we can
develop robust features but I think we
should not try to make our classifiers
somehow more robust but we should more
look at the features to prevent these
attacks one last question
Vinny Monaco Naval Postgraduate School
thank you for the talk so there's this
idea in biometrics that some users are
more difficult to identify than others
that the biometrics Menagerie did you
see the same kind of phenomenon here
where some coders were more difficult to
spoof or some difficult to modify yeah
definitely so some people you
for instance if a developer always used
some simple type deaths it was quite
easy to impersonate this person but
others had a very similar code to other
developers and then it was much more
challenging to our let's make it or yes
it was
there were developers that was that were
harder to impersonate and others not
let's thank the speaker again
[Applause]