good morning everyone today it's my
pleasure to present to you joint work we
did with cots University of Technology
on so called mobile private contact
Discovery first to get you up to speed
what is actually mobile contact
discovery well when you install a
messaging application on your smartphone
say whatsapp one of the first things
that happens is that the app checks
which of the contacts in your address
book are connected to the service as
well for this it could of course simply
tell the service provider which contacts
are in your address book and the service
provider then lets you know which of
these contacts are using the service
this brings me actually to the first
point of my agenda for this talk we will
look at how mobile contact cover
discovery is currently handled in
practice and why there are some severe
privacy issues as a privacy preserving
alternative we then suggest to deploy so
called unbalanced private set
intersection protocols and since quite
some demanding performance requirements
I will tell you how we tweaked all the
necessary building blocks to get great
performance we met a large scale and
finally I want to show you the benefits
we can get from writing native code for
secure computation protocols not only
for the server side but also for modern
mobile platforms now regarding privacy
concerns in mobile contact discovery you
have to be aware that trivial procedure
I outlined in the beginning basically
leaves your entire social graph now you
might say who cares I'm just a boring
PhD student but imagine for example
you're a journalist and are interacting
with confidential sources and impactful
whistleblowers the service provider or
any kind of agency monitoring that
service might find such information very
interesting to say the least
so our contribution when it comes to
examining and improving the current
situations are as follows
first we performed a survey on secure
mobile messaging applications showing
that none of them provides proper
privacy protection during contact
discovery therefore we optimized OPR F
based unbalanced private
intersection protocols with cuckoo fill
channel compression novel orgy
pre-computation techniques and a more
efficient PRF while even providing
security against malicious clients which
is very important in mobile contact as
curry since in principle every client
could run a modified version of the
messaging application and we also
implemented these protocols in native C
C++ utilizing new MBH instruction sets
for hardware accelerated crypto and
vector operations that give us a 1,000
times faster garbled circuit evaluation
and when putting these implementations
into the signal android client and
performing last scale benchmarks we get
that even for a database with more than
250 million users the online phase of
our protocols on a real LTE connection
takes only about five seconds regarding
this survey we looked at mobile
messaging applications that are secure
in the sense that they provide
end-to-end encryption and checked using
different analysis techniques how they
perform contact discovery here are the
results as you can see many of them
actually use the trivial solution I
outlined in the beginning here for
example what whatsapp says in its legal
info you provide us all in accordance
with applicable laws the phone numbers
of whatsapp users and your other
contacts in your mobile address book on
a regular basis the best thing some of
the ads do is to use a naive hashing
based protocol where the client only
sends hashes of the phone numbers to the
service provider unfortunately this can
be assumed to be almost as insecure
because such hashes are vulnerable to
prove false and dictionary attacks due
to the low entropy and phone numbers as
an alternative to do to these unsecure
methods we propose to deploy private set
intersection protocols
psi in short in general psi protocols
are cryptographic protocols with
provable security that allow two parties
to compute the intersection of the input
sets such that nothing but the actual
intersection is revealed the problem
with most psi protocols in the context
of mobile contact discovery is however
that their communication come
the online phase of the protocol which
is the phase where you actually compute
the intersection depends linearly on the
size of both input sets which is kind of
a showstopper considering that in mobile
contact discovery the server database
can be expected to have millions or even
billions of entries whereas the client
can be assumed to have let's say around
1,000 contacts only luckily there are
also so-called unbalanced psi protocols
that are designed specifically for the
use case where one input set is much
larger than the other one and these
protocols then have an online
communication complexity that is only
linear in the size of the client input
set and they shift the major
communication complexity to a setup
phase that can be run at an arbitrary
point in time before the actual
computation and usually is a one-time
cost when it comes related to work in
that area we can see three protocol
families first their protocols based on
fully homomorphic encryption that have
the lowest communication however when
running them at the scale we consider in
this paper the service provider would
have to pay for around 30 million core
hours every single day which is kind of
expensive then there's a protocol that
combines psi with private information
retrieval protocols however they need to
assume multiple non-coding server where
the two server version and external
server requires a full copy of the user
database which we would like to avoid
and finally there's a work by kiss allow
that brings multiple existing secure to
party psi protocols in a so-called
pre-computation form and that allows
these protocols to act as unbalanced PCI
protocols some of these protocols are
based purely on public key crypto and
some are based on oblivious
pseudo-random function evaluations from
all these protocols we close our looked
at two that can easily be made secure
against malicious clients simply by
using malicious
your obvious transfer one of these
protocols obliviously evaluates the now
wrangle PRF and the other one evaluates
garbled AES circuits and the reason why
these protocols can easily be secured
against malicious clients is because the
only messages to client sent and these
protocols are those for oblivious
transfer to give you an idea how both
selected protocols work let's quickly go
through the different phases first we
have a base phases completely
independent of any input and consists
mostly of of oblivious transfer
pre-computation and the server also
generates a secret key in the version
where we wanted to evaluate Gabbert
circuits and also and the server also
builds and transfers these garbled
circuits then in the setup phase the
server encrypts all contacts in its
database and puts them in a
probabilistic data structure for
efficient membership testing which we
instantiate in this work with a so
called kuku filter this Coco filter is
then transferred through and stored by
the client and finally in the online
face client and server engage in OPR F
evaluations where the client obliviously
obtains encryptions of its address book
entries under the server secret key
which is then can check against the kuku
filter so we took the mentioned o PRF
peers based psi protocols and looked at
every single building block to optimize
performance we now want to quickly
highlight two optimizations we did on
the protocol level that might also be
interesting for other application areas
the first optimization is a simple yet
effective compression technique for kuku
filters to represent a server database
even more efficiently if you don't know
kuku filters they are basically a very
nice drop-in replacement for the well
known bloom filters since they are more
efficient and you can for example easily
remove elements from the filter the main
main difference to bloom filters from a
data structure point of view is that
each bucket may store multiple entries
and instead of single bits we store
small hash values so called fingerprints
or tax
and for some reason all previous works
always transferred all bits for all
buckets whether they are actually filled
or not instead we suggest in the
simplest version to split the cocoa
filter into a bitmap indicating which
bucket positions are filled and the tag
list containing the actual content and
this gives you a compression ratio that
roughly equals the load factor of the
cuckoo fader and since in practice you
would never distribute a fully loaded
filter because you would expect a lot of
new users to register later on this
gives quite some nice improvements in
the paper we also described how to set
the cocoa filter parameters in terms of
bucket size and fingerprint lengths
properly so the failure probability of
the whole protocol becomes negligible
and we also described how to send
updates for cocoa filters with 4.3 times
less communication than in previous work
a quickly read literature recommendation
here after we had these results we saw
that last year some other guys proposed
a new thing which they called Martin
filters and they basically combine such
compression techniques with further
optimizations and are probably the thing
you would use when designing new
protocols in the protocol where the OPF
is implemented with garbled circuits we
also replaced the actual PRF AAS with
something more efficient and the
background here is that with the free
xor optimization for our GC protocol the
cost metrics in circuit design shifted
we now want to have as few and gates as
possible why we don't care so much about
the number of XOR gates and this is
where low MC comes into play low MC is a
highly power parameterize able block
cipher that was specifically designed
for use cases in MPC and fhe
applications and give us suppose the
possibility to tweak all these
parameters according to these new
metrics which has the different
parameter sets suitable for the contact
discovery use case all with 128-bit
security and shows a common
configuration where we require eight
point two times less communication than
AES as a next step we implemented all
protocols and since we wanted to
optimize psi not only
the protocol but also on the
implementation level we wrote them in
native C C++ the code is open source now
so you can feel free to play around with
it for our native implementations we
made use of newer Miege instruction sets
and two aspects for malicious security
extension protocols we rely on lip OTE
by Peter Randall
however this library is heavily
optimized for the x86 architecture so we
replaced our specific hardware
instructions with the arm equivalents
while still maintaining compatibility to
the counterpart running on the server
side and second when implementing as GC
protocol we know that the fixed key I as
garden scheme usually gives a great
performance boost due to the native a/s
instructions available in all half a
recent Intel CPUs however since the Army
aid architecture now contains so-called
cryptography extensions we can utilize
such instructions also mobile devices
which gives in this case a speed of of
around 35 times compared to standard
software implementations we can also
utilize the neon instruction set for
efficient operations on 128-bit
registers which makes it very convenient
to work with 128-bit wire labels in
y'all's GC protocol overall we can
report 1,000 times faster garbage
circuit evaluation compared to the Java
implementation used in previous work
okay and to demonstrate the practicality
of our protocols we performed some
large-scale experiments and the setup
looks as follows the client is a Google
picture - smartphone and a commodity
laptop acts as the psi server for the
network we use a real Wi-Fi connection
with the shown specs and we also used a
real LTE connection in Germany you would
probably have to declare bankruptcy
after the amount of experiments we
performed but in Austria you can do this
without any problems
[Music]
I don't know when looking at the
combined base and online face for
checking 1,000 contacts in the clients
address book we can see some great
performance and improvements both in
terms of runtimes and communication
please notice that these axes here are
in box scale and on this slide we
compare our protocols to the respective
protocols and implementations by kiss
that are executed in our benchmarking
environment and we choose their work for
a direct comparison because it is
actually the only one with an
implementation of unbalanced PCI
protocols on smartphones when looking at
the setup phase for Server database with
more than 250 million users we can see
the positive effect of the cuckoo filter
compression assuming a large factor of
around 70 percent here
however transferring about 1 gigabyte of
data at some point in time even over a
Wi-Fi connection can be seen as quite
prohibitive for the real world
deployment so in the paper we therefore
suggest multiple extensions to further
reduce communication the one I want to
quickly present here is a combination
with multi server private and from an
information retrieval and works as
follows first the main server transfers
the cuckoo filter to the second non
colluding store and here I want to
stress that the trust assumptions are
not as strong as in other protocols
because the cuckoo filter contains only
encrypted elements and in the case
collusion happens the security level is
still better than in the best currently
deployed methods and in the second step
the client and runs o PRF evaluations
with the main server and then uses a
multi server Pia lock up to check the
existence of the contact in the server
database and most importantly this way
the total client-server communication is
reduced to be logarithmic in the size of
the server database and becomes
practical even for services with more
than a billion users so let's compute
today we've seen the currently most
practical protocols and implementations
for mobile private contact discovery
the presented protocols are not only
suitable for contact discovery but a
general-purpose unbalanced PCI protocols
so therefore they could as well be used
from over an average detection and the
discovery of passwords just to give some
examples we also think that our native
implementations of the LCC protocol on
the Army attack attacker can be useful
for quite a lot of future secure
computation applications on mobile
devices there is one thing however that
I don't want to hide we contacted one of
the services on the survey list and
asked how they see the chances for a
real-world deployment of our protocols
unfortunately they gave us a quite
demanding requirement list where the
maximum amount of communication they
want to spend is probably the biggest
issue right now so and since we cannot
meet these requirements yet I can only
encourage everyone in this room to look
into this interesting and important
research area but this I'd like to enter
and I'm happy to take questions
thank you
any questions on this okay I have a
question so you mentioned that you have
two prfs and I you may have had the
result in there I just missed it what
was the comparison between the nor
Rheingold and the garbled circuit
approach so in our experiments it turned
out that they roughly have like equal
equal performance and ISO of course has
some overhead in the base phase because
we need to transfer these garbled
circuits so you might ask which one is
the one to choose I would say it's not
clear it depends on the use case the the
benefit of this is version is of course
that it's not only limited to like a
specific private set intersection but
you can also do this generic psi
computation where you could compute in
our arbitrary symmetric function on top
of the intersection result so in that
case I would suggest to use the the is
or lo MC version and otherwise they
turned out to be roughly equal I'm sorry
to ask two questions here but very
quickly because I know we have a limited
time are we gonna get to those
requirements in the next five years two
years and putting it down possible I
think if you don't if you don't weaken
some assumptions like this they also
said they don't want to have any non
colluding servers if you if you don't
weaken these assumptions I don't see it
coming that fast I mean there are other
approaches that are being explored like
using interest rates which is like a
technology preview of signal but has of
course other shortcomings so having the
same extremely strict requirements set
and having all these strong assumptions
I don't see it coming that fast
well still it's it's big progress
yeah all right one more round of
applause thank you
[Applause]