so I'm gonna talk about a study of
bandwidth denial of service attacks
against tor I'm Rob Jansen from NRL and
this is joint work with my colleagues
Tavish and mica from Georgetown
University so in this work we explore
the cost and effects of bandwidth denial
of service attacks on tor the most
exciting contribution is for an attack
that costs 3 gigabits per second and
costs anywhere from 140 to $1600
depending how you count we can cause tor
downloads to become 47% slower
across the entire network that's all I
have questions it's good to see you guys
are still awake in this last session of
the conference so anonymous
communication separates identification
from routing this is a system that
provides unlikeable communication
between a client and where they're
visiting on the internet they sits
anonymous communication systems protect
user privacy and safety online tor is
the most popular anonymous communication
system with between 2 and 8 million
daily active users it has 6,500
volunteer relays that transfer a total
of 200 gigabits per second in aggregate
because tor is popular and used by
people all around the world it's been a
target of anonymity attacks there's been
attacks website fingerprinting attacks
traffic correlation attacks and routing
attacks that have been published over
the years and continue to be important
areas of research but these some of
these attacks are complicated and math
is hard and so what I'm interested in
this work is looking at simple simple
denial of service attacks that can also
have a dramatic effect on the network so
our focus in this work is denial of
service we're not the first to look at
denial of service on tour there have
been a variety of studies over the years
in 2007 Borissov @l presented a
selective service refusal attack and in
2014 Gatiss @l presented a resource
exhaustion attack these attacks have a
goal of
causing clients to not be able to access
the network they've been a couple of
studies focusing on CPU a computational
resource exhaustion attacks these
attacks cause tort of conduct CPU
operations cryptographic operations to
keep the CPU busy there was an attack in
2009 called the long path attack where
you would build an infinite length tor
circuit as a means to consume bandwidth
and in 2014 the sniper attack was
presented with the goal of consuming
memory resources and causing a relay
process to be killed by the operating
system in this work we focus on
bandwidth denial of service attacks
using some techniques from previously
published work as a way to consume
bandwidth on the network so denial of
service attacks are not a hypothetical
threat this is a realistic threat
these have denial of service attacks
have been reported on the live network
in January 2018 there was a report of an
ongoing denial of service attack on tor
this led the developers to develop a
mitigation that I am a service
mitigation subsystem that would help
mitigate the effects of such an attack
so this is a real threat these attacks
are relatively easy to carry out as
you'll see and we need to be better
understand these attacks so we can help
develop better defenses against them so
in this work we explore three research
questions how vulnerable is tor to
denial of service attacks how costly are
these attacks to carry out and what
effect do they have on client
performance in the paper we look at
three different components of tor we
look at bridges the Tor flow bandwidth
scanning infrastructure which helps
produce weights to balance load across
the relays and we look at a real a
congestion attack these attacks have
various costs and various effects on
performance throughout the paper we did
these attacks in a private tour Network
we did not do them on a lot live tor
network for ethical reasons we use a
high fidelity simulation using the
shadow simulator we did some
measurements on the Tor network but
there were mostly client measurements
and we didn't store any information
about any users
so for the rest of this talk I'm gonna
focus on the real a congestion attack
and explain how it works what the costs
are what the effects are if you're
interested in the other attacks please
see the paper for more details okay so
the way tour works is when a client
wants to visit a destination through the
Tor network it builds up what's called a
circuit by choosing three relays in the
network and extending a connection
through each of these relay in a
telescoping process through this process
they create a shared key with each relay
so that they can encrypt traffic
multiple times and send it through the
circuit the client then instructs the
final relay to connect to the internet
destination so in this process after
this process no single point on the path
can learn both the client and the
destination so this provides unlimited
to the client so a real a congestion
attack can be launched by extending a
circuit from three hops up to eight hops
this is allowed by the tor protocol
previous work that explored long paths
and tour caused tor to reduce the
maximum circuit length to eight but you
can still build an eight hops circuit as
of today so let's step one build mini
hops circuit the circuit can be targeted
or indiscriminate
targeted means if you have a specific
relay that you're trying to congest you
can repeat that relay up to three times
in the same circuit indiscriminate you
just choose relays following tours
regular pass selection algorithm which
is the approach we take in this attack
so once you have your a hops circuit
you simply initiate a get request for
large files from some internet web
server and the web server will send this
data all eight relays will download and
upload as their forwarding traffic
towards the client step three is the
client can stop reading on the TCP
connection to the first hop relay
meaning that they no longer call the
read function in the kernel so bytes so
data won't be transferred from the entry
to the client however the client can
still write on this connection and this
is important because the client will
continue to send tors flow control cells
to the exit node which will instruct the
exit to continue sending data
data from the server and sending it
towards the client and this way the
traffic will continue to be sent through
the circuit and consumes resources at
all of the relays step 5
repeat you can build thousands of these
circuits at the same time important
things to note when you brilliant these
circuits is spreading them out across
different relays you can choose any
relay in the network as a first hop into
the network and each attack circuit uses
a different socket TCP connection in
order to have more control over the
attack circuits so as a result of this
lots of data from internet web servers
will be sent into the network the
network will send it between each other
eight different times and then because
the client is not reading most of the
data will get stuck at the entry points
okay so we implemented this attack and
we evaluated it in a private tour
Network using the shadow simulator
shadow allows you to do this in a
private network without harming any
users we built a 10% shadow tor network
which is about 10 percent the size and
capacity of the live network we ran
thousands of clients and servers in the
network to create realistic background
traffic and then we explore the effects
of attack we looked at various attack
strengths so various numbers of attack
circuits and we measured network load
attacker resource usage and client
performance during the attack so the
results are shown here the graph on the
left is attacker throughput so this is
how much bandwidth the attacker is
consuming during the attack and the
graph on the right is to a relay good
put this is how much bandwidth all of
the relays combined in the network are
consuming we're showing two different
attacks here the 20k circuit attack is
the same attack as the other one except
you the client is actually doing the
reading thing stop reading attack is as
I previously described where the client
stops reading from the entry point so
the first thing to note here is that in
the regular attack where you do the
reading
the bandwidth amplification factor
reached six point seven so the attacker
consumed about 200 megabytes per second
on average through the attack and caused
an increase of about 1.2 gigabytes per
second on the network during the attack
and then in the stop reading case the
attacker used significantly less
bandwidth because it's no longer reading
this data from the circuits from the
network it's still sending cells during
the circuit construction and and
downloading cells during circuit
construction and then sending these
periodic flow control cells so it does
use some amount of bandwidth
Eggar get really good put dropped a
little bit because some of these
circuits are timing out and the client
isn't realizing this so it's causing
some loss in efficiency but we still
achieved a bandwidth application factor
in this case of 26 which is quite quite
scary so in addition to the effect on
the attacker and on the Tor network we
looked at the effect on tor performance
so this graph looks at the download time
time to first byte in time to last by
across various sized files that were
downloaded during the experiment in both
the no attack 20k circuit and the stop
reading attack case the highlight here
is for the 20 Circuit of 20,000 circuit
attack time the first bite increased by
138 percent and time to last by it
increased by 120% across all the
downloads and then again in the stop
reading case this was a slightly less
had a slightly smaller effect this is
also less costly to the attacker because
they're not reading but we achieved 48
percent increase in time to first byte
and 47 percent increase in time to last
bite across all downloads ok so how much
does its attack cost the attack that we
did in shadow was as I mentioned on a 10
percent tor network so we extrapolated
this up to a full Tor network by
multiplying most of our requirements by
10 so for 200,000 circuits in the live
Tor network our attacker would consume
roughly 3 Giga
it's per second of traffic and would
require 20 IP addresses in order to not
trigger tours denial service mitigation
system that I mentioned earlier and then
how much does the bandwidth cost for
this question we surveyed the table on
the on the right table to shows a survey
of different providers and how much they
charge for dedicated servers with a
certain bandwidth quota and we surveyed
some of these providers and we came with
it came up with a mean amortized cost of
70 cents per hour per gigabit per second
of traffic and so we use this amortized
cost in addition to assuming that IP
addresses cost $5 each to estimate
conservatively a cost of one thousand
six hundred forty seven dollars to
conduct this real a congestion attack on
the live Network now if you want to get
a little bit more optimistic you can say
well actually VPS is are much cheaper
you can get a VPS for $7.00 I've used to
have one of these they claim to offer
gigabit per second although likely they
offer far less than that and the links
are probably shared so you might not be
able to achieve that but even if you
bought 20 of these VPS is to get the 20
IP addresses this is only $140 per month
so optimistically the cost of the attack
is potentially much cheaper than the
conservative estimate that we have in
the paper so another question is well
what if you use this three gigas per
second for anonymity attack on tour
rather than a denial of service attack
so we looked at this we compared our
attacks or how much you could do with a
civil attack where the attacker would
use this bandwidth to run relays in the
network instead and then use those
relays in the denial of service attack
or a diene anonymization attack so in
the denial of service attack the goal is
to get your civil relays to appear in as
many circuits as possible and then
whenever someone builds a circuit
through those relays you can just drop
the circuit or arbitrarily degrade
performance on it by slowing traffic
down etc so the question for the
attacker is how can I
what's the highest how could i get my
relays to exist in the most relays
possible and to do this
exit bandwidth is exit relay bandwidth
this as a scarcest in the network so the
best option for the attacker is to run
exit relays this will give them the
highest probability of appearing in a
circuit and with three gigabits per
second of traffic you can get you can
appear in a roughly 4.5% of circuits and
then arbitrarily degrade performance on
those circuits in the D anonymization
attack the goal is to appear on both
ends of the circuit in order to
compromise anonymity of the client do
you appear on one end you know the
client you appear on the other end you
know the server a previous work has
looked at this issue and found for a
given bandwidth budget the best
allocation of resources is to a five to
one ratio of guard exit a guard
bandwidth to exit bandwidth and this is
because it's more difficult to become a
client's guard node because clients
choose a guard and stick with it for
several months so it's more advantageous
to put more of your resources towards
running guard nodes in that case so with
this allocation attacker can appear in
guard as a guard in circuits 2.8 percent
of the time and as an exit in circuits
0.8 percent of the time for a compromise
rate of 0.02 percent of total of all the
circuits so compared to our attacks our
attack works across the entire network
on all circuits that are built whereas
these attacks are a little bit more
nuanced and Holliday function ok so how
do you mitigate the really congestion
attack I really the attack relies on
three main features one is the ability
to stop reading from circuits so I have
actually a co-authored tour proposal
called authenticated send Me's which has
been implemented in a recent version of
tor the way authenticated send Me's work
is every 50 cells that the exit sends
toward the client at the end of that
50th cell it adds a knots to the cell
and then the client needs to read and
return
from that 50th cell when it's sending
back the flow control cells to the exit
and if the exit if the nonce doesn't
validate the exit will drop the circuit
so this essentially stops the stop
reading part of the attack and will
reduce that bandwidth amplification
factor from twenty six down to six point
seven another thing our attack uses is
the ability to build eight hop circuits
tor only needs four hops in the current
protocol and so we could reasonably
reduce the circuit length to four hops
in the current network and that would
reduce further reduce the bandwidth
amplification factors that an adversary
could achieve and another issue is that
an attacker can use all the relays in
the network as the first hop and this is
actually a challenging problem because
towards a privacy-preserving network and
relays can't just store information
about users and share that information
with others from an anomaly perspective
viewpoint on this it would be easy to
detect an attacker who's connecting to
all the relays at the same time because
that's not a normal behavior but in
order to share the information across
relays in a way that doesn't harm
regular users this is a non-trivial
problem so this is future work
developing a privacy-preserving defense
against civil attacks and then using
that to detect if attacks are happening
in the network measuring how often they
happen and using that to prevent such
attacks so that's all I have again we
did looked at three attacks the bridge
congestion attack bandwidth authority
attack and a real a congestion attack I
only went over the relay congestion
attack here but the others there's more
details in the paper about the other
attacks and I discussed some future work
that's all I have thank you for your
attention
okay we've got a bit of time for some
questions and a microphone right here hi
thanks for the presentation really cool
work Bobo from Facebook I had a question
you in the cost estimation you scale by
10x in order to scale your costs I was
wondering if you knew that the
characteristics of the network that are
relevant for the cost to the attacker do
scale linearly like that it's also
wondering about the mitigation of every
50th cell having a nonce not sure I
followed that this may just be ignorant
on my part but can the attacker simply
read every 50th cell and discard the
other 49 and get most of the
amplification okay for the 10 X linearly
linear adjustment shadow was designed to
approp to match the bandwidth of the Tor
network like to match a distribution of
bandwidth in the network so 10% of the
bandwidth in shadow if you multiply that
by 10 you'll get back to the actual
distribution of tor traffic in the live
network so I think that's an appropriate
multiplier for your second question on
the authenticated send means the
attacker can't read every 50th cell
because it's a TCP stream and it has to
read all the data in order to get to the
50th cell you do selective reading so
yep hi rude really good really cool work
I'm Jerry from UMass Amherst so in the
medication method on the previous slides
you mentioned that we can reduce the
eighth hope circuit to the max ability
to four hopes but a one I'm wondering is
whether the attacker can just run
multiple work lines and do the tour over
tor tor tor tor tor attack yeah so
multiple tor clients just to set up the
proxy to each other's listening port
that's a great point that was one of the
attack variants that we had in our paper
I called it the tunneling strategy you
can tunnel tor connections through other
tor connections tor could feasibly
eliminate this feature by allowing by
exits not allowing exit back into
another relay that's running the tour so
you could prevent this this feature
which is why we didn't I didn't focus on
it during this talk but currently I
believe it is possible to do the
tunneling strategy don't you thank you
one more and while that can the next
speaker come up and start setting up I
Steven cheffy from Middle Tennessee I
was wondering
so with reducing the number of hots
possible possibly decrease anonymity and
could that be counteracted by maybe
limiting the amount of traffic you can
send if you're using a higher number of
hops does reducing the number of hops
reduce anonymity so it's currently most
users build three hop circuits so I'm
not suggesting that we reduce it from
that I'm just suggesting what the
protocol allows the protocol will allow
you to build eight hops but for any MIDI
regions we only really need three that's
been established in the research okay
and I think you might have asked another
question but I didn't quite hear you
something you could take that offline
cuz I think I'm out of time okay thank
you let's think Rob again
[Applause]