so thanks for the introduction so I'm
Ben and ow I'm currently at IBM Research
so today we're going to be talking about
the work that we did at looking at
self-contradictory privacy policies so
I'm sure everybody here has seen a
privacy policy at one point or another
reading it is clearly a different story
but privacy policies generally disclose
how companies collect and share your
data and these are required by various
regulations such as the Cal opah in GDP
are so below is just a little excerpt
from a privacy policy of an Android app
and in red it basically just states that
we collect personal information so when
using this app you assume that it's
going to collect some type of your
personal data but this raises the
question are all apps disclosing all of
their privacy practices in the policies
in the perfect world the answer would be
yes but unfortunately that's not the
case in large companies such as snapchat
Lenovo and an Android app developer
called the golden Shore technologies
that at 50-plus million downloads
we're omitting their privacy practices
or being dishonest about their practices
and misleading users and they were fined
by the FTC so we need a way to audit
these applications and there's been some
prior work in XE 16:18 and NDS s that
looked at creating these tools to audit
app behavior and make sure that they
comply with what they're actually
stating in their privacy policy however
when looking at the consistency models
that they use in this work we found that
they all have this implicit assumption
that the privacy policies themselves are
internally consistent and we're gonna
invalidate that assumption today
basically and we show that this is not
the case because privacy policies can be
self contradictory so if you look at the
rest of the policy that I showed you
earlier
it also says we do not collect personal
information so they say they do and they
don't collect personal information which
leads to ambiguous policies furthermore
these contradictions can occur at these
different semantic granularities so the
policy also states that we collect email
address so they say they they don't
collect personal information but they
collect email address email address is a
type of personal information story is
also contradictory
so why should you care basically so
other than ambiguous policies we also
found that self-contradictions can lead
to the identification of deceptive
statements which are enforceable by the
FTC and the DA's of the EU furthermore
in terms of tools that are looking to do
automated behavior to policy compliance
we want to check what the impact is of
this implicit assumption because they
may claim that a behavior is justified
when in fact it is not so we create a
tool called policy lint and the goal of
policy length is essentially to identify
bugs in a privacy policy and the bugs
that we're looking for in this case or
self-contradictory sharing collection
statements so note that the goal of
policy lint is the aid human analysis
we're looking to automate the approach
as much as possible but humans still
needed in the pipeline somewhere because
natural language understanding is not
you know there yet plus interpreting
some of the statements requires a legal
expert in some cases to determine intent
so to achieve this we have three main
technical research questions that we
answer here the first is as I mentioned
before these contradictions can occur at
different language granularities so we
need a way to automatically Reason over
these different semantics granularities
and we do so using ontology x' we
automatically construct ontology x' from
privacy policy policies because we
operate on the insight that privacy
policies themselves encode the
anthologies by giving examples of what
certain data types entails so for
example they may say we clocked personal
information such as your name so from
that type of statement we know that your
name is a type of personal information
so while one privacy policy alone is
probably not comprehensive enough if we
take a large set of privacy policies we
show that we you can build a pretty
comprehensive ontology and we actually
build two ontology a data object
ontology for reasoning over data types
so email address is a type of personal
information and the entity ontology so
that we know that AdMob is a type of ad
provider and we do so
using lexical syntactic patterns with
enforce named at identity constraints
the full details are within our paper
though so the next challenge that we
address is we need to extract
fine-grained policy statement tuples and
we need to mop a model positive and
negative sentiment so by that I mean we
need to know if they're talking about
sharing or not sharing or collecting
verse not collecting and we do so sorry
about that so we do so using a
grammatical structure and we basically
use the the dependency based parse trees
to extract this information to extract
this three tuple at the bottom which is
some entity collects or not collects
some data type and it's worth mentioning
that we also handle sharing collection
statements they get simplified down to
this form with a set of transformation
rules that are also documented in the
paper
so finally we we want to analyze the
what are the different types of
contradictions that occur and we
formalize this over the three
ontological operators the first is
semantic equivalence so this is
basically a synonym style relationship
so postal address is a type or postal
address is semantically equivalent to
mailing address D something operator
which is just below there it means that
X is a Y so email address is a type of
personal information and then we have
the inverse of that so based on these
ontological relations we have nine
different types of conflicting
statements we further subdivide this
into two classes the first are logical
contradictions and these are either
direct contradictions where it says some
entity is collecting and not collecting
that specific data type or they're
saying they collect some broad
information or they do not collect some
broad information but they collect
something more specific so these are the
statements such as we do not collect
personal information but we collect your
email address and we show in our
findings that these can actually lead to
the identification of deceptive
statements and then the second class are
the narrowing definitions so these are
when they say they collect the broad
information but
do not collect something more specific
these are not inherently negative
because they don't confuse the humans
trying to read the policy so for example
it can say we collect personal
information but we don't collect email
address but we don't collect your
address so it's narrowing the scope of
their collection practices but we still
want to measure these be as they impact
the the the accuracy of automated
analysis approaches so we performed a
large-scale study on eleven thousand
four hundred thirty of the top Android
apps in a September 2017 snapshot and we
basically wanted to explore how frequent
these self-contradictions occur we
actually found that around one and out
of every what is that one out of every
six privacy policies have logical
contradictions or narrowing definitions
meaning that prior what approaches
looking at behavior policy compliance
may make the wrong decision about a
policy about one and edit every six
times and this is only in terms of the
consistency model we show on the paper
that they could have an error rate up to
sixty percent in their information
extraction and logical contradictions
impact around fourteen point two percent
of policies and it's pretty evenly
distributed across the Google Play
categories some of the ones look a
little higher hovering at around like
between twenty-five and thirty percent
but we looked into the the outliers
there and we found that it was uh
basically multiple apps by the same
developer in it day a contradictory
policies which was skewing results we we
broke it down again by application
category by the number average number of
contradictions and we showed that
contradiction prevalence also does not
vary across the Google Play categories
showing that it's a distributed problem
again we dug into the outliers there and
they were skewed to based on some very
highly contradictory policies so we have
a CDF in a paper and it showed like the
the long tail hit like forty two
contradictions and a few other policies
so some of the policies were very very
highly contradictory we we couldn't
investigate all of the the nine thousand
nine
logical contradictions so we we took a
subset of this and we did so by
examining basically the heat map that
the top row there is are basically
contradictions where they say that they
do not collect personal information but
they collect some subtype so we explore
those cases and overall we validated 510
contradictions which took about a week's
worth of manpower so some of the
highlight highlighted findings were was
that we found some policies we're
stating that common types of PII such as
email addresses we're not actually
personal information which was a little
surprising because regulatory agencies
or standards agencies such as NIST
define it as such so there's an example
below of this play toddlers app that was
its target for children five and under
if you look at the top of their privacy
policy they say at play toddlers we
don't have small print and run at the
top of their policy it makes you feel
good by saying we don't collect personal
information however when you actually
read the small print in their policy you
see that they say when the user provides
us with an email address the user
confirms that this address is not
personal data or does not contain
personal data which was a little
shocking when we saw that statement and
it's arguably deceptive due to the the
the icons that they blast in your face
in the front we also found that services
that auto generate temporal based
policies we're causing some some issues
in producing contradictory policies I
think we found four to five different
templates so this needs further
exploration in terms of looking into all
of these different services and making
sure that they're producing high-quality
policies and not problematic ones we
also found that policies are considering
device identifiers and hashed email
addresses as non personal information
which raises concerns about compliance
with gdpr so for example gdpr considers
device identifier is generally as PII
but these policies a set of policies
we're not considering that and defining
them as non personal information
and hashed identifiers such as email
addresses they claim that that is
anonymous yet it's questionable if it
meets the require the pseudo anonymous
pseudonym ization requirements defined
by GDP are considering that you could
pay four cents an email for sense for a
hashed email to try to be reversed
because people build up rainbow tables
from data breach reports so we notified
the developers via the email accounts
that were listed under Google Play of
our findings we only received 11
responses I think that's about like four
and a half percent three said they fixed
their policies one disagreed with our
findings in stadia that email addresses
only email address or is only PII if it
contains PII such as your name while
they disagree with our findings I
actually checked their policy yesterday
and they remove the statement that it's
not PII so they clearly agreed with our
findings but just one in a minute four
claimed an outdated policy that we
analyzed some outdated policy and that
they send us the new updated link one of
the links that was sent contained a
reference to see our full policy for the
details and that was the one that we
analyzed so I request a clarification
and they never responded the other three
had updated their policy we ran our tool
again on it and they weren't
contradictory anymore so that is a great
thing in three responded back with no
comments or clarifications such as thank
you for the observation so general
takeaways from our work is that privacy
policies are frequently
self-contradictory if you're looking at
behavior to policy compliance you cannot
have this implicit assumption that they
are internally consistent and the the
behavior of policy consistency models
need to handle the cases of
contradictory policies and in general we
showed that the the current state of
privacy policies for Google Play apps
right now are not in the best shape and
they need more attention in inspection
by regulatory agencies such as the FTC
or DPS where applicable and even
potentially the application markets
so I wanted to wrap up by thanking my
collaborators from NCSU so semenya zere
mahmoud justin Whitacre brad reeves will
link my collaborators from UI you see
when you want au j and my collaborator
from IBM research kapil singh so I'd be
happy to take any questions at this
point
[Applause]
Indiana University Bloomington I'm
interesting work and Mike Ryan shooting
ontology construction alright and I
would like to know what is the size of
the Courant ology your construction and
how many human effort you put on it and
do you evaluate the accuracy of it and
where you publish it sure so starting
off in the beginning I think our data
type ontology was a maybe 2 to 200 nodes
in our entity one was about between a
hundred and hundred fifty nodes in terms
of a value uh evaluating the accuracy of
it we we didn't do that because we
didn't have ground truth but we did so
we extracted the Luxan of syntactic
patterns and we have an algorithm that's
documented in the paper on how we
actually construct it from those lexical
syntactic patterns that we extracted and
did you manually evaluate so we dumped
it out looked at it and removed some of
the bad edges that were extracted so we
basically drew the had some software
draw the ontology for us and looked at
what the relationships were and pruned
some of the bad edges but we did not
perform like an accuracy on it because
we did not have the ground truth to do
so and in terms of releasing this we're
playing on open sourcing and it's going
through the process right now ok thank
you lady in the back I'm Sarah with
square my question was are you going to
open-source it and you've just answered
thank you yeah yeah great talk by the
way thank you thank you yeah thank you
that was a very interesting talk curious
that these methods could be used to
evaluate other natural language require
it's you know like the C standard or
rfcs or protocol specifications or
whatever so while I haven't really
looked at like for example RFC's in the
language in there the the reason why our
pattern based approach for extracting
information works so well I believe for
privacy policies is because when people
are writing privacy policies they tend
to follow some structure
I assume that the RFC probably has some
structure and language that you might be
able to tap into to do the same type of
information extraction but I've been
really looked into you know what what
type of language how they're defining
things in RFC's so I can't answer with
100% certainty
okay thank you yep still have time for
one more question did you see any
indication
besides the template generators of how
those contradictions actually start
where do they come from is it just
simply that those policies are getting
too complex for a single legal person to
keep them all in their head do you have
any indication did you study that so
from from doing some of the manual
validation one thing that I noticed is
it seemed like a lot of like piece work
that the developers were doing so these
a lot of the findings well some of them
were from big companies but a lot of the
findings were from it looked like indie
developers that basically released a
popular app on the Play Store and they
mean they probably don't have that legal
team helping them create these policies
so in my opinion there needs to be more
research into automatically generating
these policies based on behavior
signatures or whatever trying to educate
developers and help them create good
policies okay essa Peka again
[Applause]