hello everyone my name is telegin today
I'll talk about our reporter to discover
input validation validation input
validation box in robot APO kospi our
control Ida testing so first let me
introduce what is the logo tpo Co robot
EPO code is a type of a cyber-physical
system interacting with the physical
world there are various types of
vehicles such as aerial and ground
vehicles and they can be used in the
burials of purposes such as delivery
however robotic vehicles have many
security issues which can lead to
crashing into the crowd and put in or
protected in protected places and even
injuring people and the people we
discuss the security issues let me
introduce a howl over the vehicles works
there is a loaded vehicle system and it
consists of work keyboards such as
vision module to handle command sent
from the ground control station and the
sensor module to observe the physical
vehicles the physical state and
controller which is the heart of the
logo typical system to stabilize the
blueprint along the six degrees of
freedoms and then this this controls the
mechanical models and then these modules
generate a property versus based on the
control aerodynamic dynamics of our
vehicle and the physics and control
surely then they add they adjusted
proportional process according to the
observer the vehicle state in six
figures degrees of freedom then let's
determine the six degrees of freedoms
controller and how much they are complex
so there is a six degree of freedom and
that each degree is controlled by one
cascading controller as an example of
k accesses cassidy controller it inside
of the circus scaling controller there
are three castrated primitive contours
and then the operation over such
contours are determined by control
parameter parameters or controller
module vision module and the sensor
module and then there are there are
hundred or above control parameters or
doors modules and then they are
dynamically configurable by ground
control station
however this convenient the control
interface opens up dot new secret the
hall then let me introduce such a secret
the host for people I talked about by
our or new secret Hall let me summarize
the two existing secret the hosts were
still one is physical attacks such as a
census cutting edge of the example
during on normal flight epidural
attacker who generate a noise too busily
the sensor all over typical start to
serve physical disturbance at the end it
caused severe injuries fortunately this
can be mitigated by control based
detection or built on mechanism and then
the other one is software traditional
dr. box and then such as a palpable flow
since the control program is also a type
of a program it inevitably has a
software box and each exploitation also
caused 6000 freedom controls tue-barbe
function we call this type of about as a
syntactic block and then personally this
is this can be also be related by
program watching and hardening and in
this work we introduced a new type of
odd semantic box instead of a syntactic
box we call this bog as a control
semantic box and then this is new and
has not what she has not disabled much
attention and then is not dependable
with the audible approaches so then
let's t go into control semantic box so
so this little is portable
by sending on balusters the parameter
change in command and then this is
possible because stitches to vehicle
communication such as bubbling is not
secure and then it causes and needs one
control to mark function and then we
believe that this is quite a meaningful
to even two attackers due to the power
in three regions first of all it is
remotely trickable by single militias
the control parameter change command
hence it leaves minimum footprint second
it does not lie on previous attend
mother the changes sends us cooking code
injection and the Trojan is fight
finally it is a lunchable even emptor
program is hardened against the
traditional his point then let's talk
about the nature of this system and
control somatic box so there is a
parameter P one and then on attacker
bait tried to manipulate this p1 value
with uh some invalid range that is
within the solid range however I usually
come to a control program usually have a
some defense mechanism to protect such
as a range the lead range values
therefore such trial usually prevented
buys built-in defense mechanism and then
as a result actually robotic vehicle
simply fly normally and then it is
similar is a signal to belittle value
setting so in this case if we set a
value within a green range which is the
tool belt value range it does not cause
any problem in physical operation
however upon attacker
bonnet manipulated this p1 value with
value within the
pink lanes then it all over the people
start to short physical disturbance and
the despite of this listen is it is it
passes through the built-in depends
because it is within the permitted range
so in this context our goal is that we
want to shrink that this permitted
implant into the true value range
denoted the edge of green range and then
also this is not only for single
parameter but also it must be done with
the other hundreds of all control
parameters also we have observed that
wind effect actually cause cause effect
the green range I mean the true value
range so in this case suppose there is a
parameter P and the it is that as a
denoted value and in this context
without any wind it does not cause any
problem integral equation however if
there is a wind effect such as strong
wind it's invalid value will be expanded
and then true value range will be
shrunken so tell Paul we should we
should also consider disability effect
during the test so to find this is
control cemented box we we can posit our
control program and then however there
are two main challenges first one is how
to detect the pedal control program lon
and then it is true that program crash
can indicate a traditional program known
however this is not applicable to the
contrary control program lon this is
because a true indicator herbal control
a better control on is not program crash
actually it is apparent of instability
supportive example support or contra
program is exploited by let's say
control semantic box even if I saw our
control program will still keep we'll
keep longing without any program crash
in this context contour surely comes the
last you
so we consider concern in stability
control instability agile where the
contra program lon and then we there are
two types of abode don't train gentle
diverges that is considered as a control
instability first one is the divergence
between leper estate and the observer
the state level state indicates desired
pitch pro operation on the other hand
observer the state indicates our actual
physical operation it would be prepared
your large and percent divergence
between two state all over TP awkward
start to show severe control instability
as you can see in the peer and then the
other type is divergence between
reference state and mission and then we
put there is a large and percentage
divergence between two between two
states logo TP aku cannot track the
trajectory at trajectory therefore we
rebounded actually with the standard
control properties and the formula is it
possible that is possible to detect such
a don't train gender divergences so the
other the other challenge is how to pull
the control programs how to purge the
control loops
actually cyber pitch persistent such as
logo typical system should I tell I too
late allele under control loops to
stabilize the pistol operation in this
in appalled this purpose
there are several issues first one is
safety
so specifically we may not want make the
other vehicles crash due to space
safety issues to solve this problem
we're average your hype identity
simulator which provide the Butcher
physical world this enable us to both
control loop safely the other one is
efficiency in fact there is a large
testing input space specifically there
are hundred over control parameters and
the large value range for each parameter
and there is a wind effect all of those
factors must be considered during the
test to overcome this issue we propose a
control guided be direct directed
approach this is based on the control
property that we will talk about in the
copper ovals light so here is the
overview oval RB butter and there is a
target program target binary program and
then it will interact with the simulator
and then it will stand and asleep and
control sensor input and the motor
output this studying enable us to is
cute control loops safely and then there
will be a ground dealer ground control
station software
Jesus doctor and then it is a connected
to the target program and then it will
send some control command while
receiving the control state of the
target program and here we put and
connect our control by the tester and
the inside of this tester there is a
control instability Tector to detect a
bad control program lon and then this is
possible because by monitoring the
control state and then there okay
depending on this detection desert the
controller idle in commutator we mutate
the variable parameter and then win the
configuration this
us to achieve the high efficiency in
testing so let me introduce plain how
this contour by the tester works with
with us simplify the single parameter
mutation example so let's start with the
testing with ballistic control game
parameter with value 1 if we tested with
this value and with parameter then we
can observe the to relate to the
physical operation first one is a
desirable realistic drone as a a gray
gray line and the actual velocity drone
as a orangie line and then as we can see
in the figure will actual velocity
tracks the desired velocity very well it
means that there is no control
instability then we can maybe test the
more d beta values such as 6 and then as
i described it in the period there is a
control instability then we can test the
value between 1 and 6 but in this case
we are not sure whether they are well
controlled with instability happens or
not but we can predict that
various larger than 6 called control
instability this is based on our
monitoring control property increasing
or decreasing the part valuable control
parameter will maintain or intensify our
control instability then we can keep
mutating the input value while
efficiently reaching the input space so
here is an evaluation dessert we test
with other pilot and the export which
are the both two popular open source
program and we found 89 box and then
during the eight days testing all of
them actually will come to order of the
cases and that independently the eight
cases were confirmed by developers and
the seven cases were patched by
developers until now
and that we were to know today we use
the open source program only to obtain
the ground trust but with our reporter
doesn't require source code and then so
as you can see in in this table
they released of large list of mobile
phone number parameters it is bound on
the autopilot actually there's more 4px
or and then according to variable each
parameter is short different page called
impact such as a crash or deviation bomb
the trajectory let me enter the to
concrete control semantic bubble
exploitation first one is to control the
maximum more power and then it will
either set as the value within a pink
range it start to short shiver console
instability this is because each
although it sometimes isn't necessary to
generate a maximum power above water but
due to that is limited the maximum Bo
power
it cannot generate the such a maximum
power and that the other parameter is
the responsible or angular control gain
and then it would dispel you it'll this
value is within a left pink range it
does it all over tip you will fail to
track the trajectory as you can see in
the figure so in summary we introduced
new types of a control somatic box by
sending a little achievable it is
exploitable by sending a malicious
parameter change in command and then to
discover this contrast Metapod we
propose a reporter or psycho-bitch code
system but in tow and then this system
perform controller I the detection of
where the control program done by
detecting
generic control instability properties
and it performs a safe and efficient to
control loop fudging by leveraging a
high-fidelity simulator and control
property as a lizard we bound 89 box
from the autopilot and key export
so is there any question I think that
was quite interesting can you can you
maybe tell me to which degree would
these bucks as you call them be specific
to the physical process so you found us
in control of software is that knowledge
specific to specific drone or is this
would this be a range or Barker as call
that that would essentially apply to you
to a number of different drones that
would run with the same software is this
like a problem that is are these values
specifically related to the drone model
I mean if you say is 0.8 is the minimal
thrust I can a mix the most faster I can
have maybe have a different drone which
has a different motor and it's a
different value no two which agree is
this like a bug that I can fix it in
general control software I'm sorry can
you repeat these bugs that you filed
with developers you said you found 90
bucks or something like this that that
you filed with the developers so I I
found 89 yes yes but these are specific
for one model of the drone or this would
be a bug which is specific which would
be in general for the controller
software which could also apply to
different drones maybe you are talking
about the weather this suppose bound
problem does some specific model is that
correct yeah yeah I'm wondering if this
applies to one specific model of the
drone or let's say you have whatever
drone more one and drawn model 10 or
whatever which is much newer with this
back be the you know you now say that
the maximum thrust has to be at least
0.8 or something is this this case for
both model one and model
the drone or is there something specific
to one drone and wondering how generic
these bugs are all these are super
specific based on my understanding I
believe your question is that whether I
found this such opposed from the other
pilot and then actually other pilot or
people actually support a lot of O
borders or put into the combination of
the other boarders and and then also
mathematical model also could be
different so it means that are the Palio
support a lot of many private over
borders but in my case I actually test
with one specific model that is
specifically 3d earth something trivial
quadrotor actually he sees the deport
borders for testing and then I found
this post and from the cheap water but
but and then also widely easier also
true that by desert only compound from
the teleport model but I believe our by
design images generally in Episode II it
is possible to find a box from the other
other control models yes if you would
like to leave it's the end of the
session but we can keep discussing as
well that's you it perfect good well
maybe I'll do what it says no one else
thank you
all right let's thank all of our
speakers again
[Applause]