so thanks so much for coming I'm
delighted to be here I come to this
conference a number of times over the
years and so I'm happy to come back and
special thanks to devdutta for inviting
me I am trained as a lawyer but do a lot
of technical work at the University of
California and have advised both private
clients and agencies about privacy and
security matters and so I thought I'd
talk about today is the things I've
learned along the way the different ways
of framing issues of presenting them in
hopes that they can increase your
efficacy when speaking with regulators
so let me start let me start in a
different place though I'm working on a
book on cybersecurity right now for my
cybersecurity class and so none of you
would learn anything from it it's really
for my students but the real pleasure of
working on this project is getting to
read all the literature in computer
security and going back to reports from
the night you know even from the 1970s
this report that was authored by Willis
where what am I at one of my CS Heroes
was extraordinarily prescient and you
know written in 1970 it has this little
nugget in the very beginning of it it's
important to influence design of
computers and so on so that security
controls can be installed before the
fact and as an integral part of the
system so I would say that this is one
of the things that regulators have
finally figured out regulators are
talking about security by design privacy
by design
Willis ware was able to get his
committee together and come to a
consensus on this recommendation in 1970
so that's that's pretty impressive
another paper from the literature that I
read recently sustaining and it's
prescience written in 1979 by lieutenant
colonel at the Navy Postgraduate School
it's called computer security the
Achilles heel of electronic air force
it's filled with anecdotes that anyone
even you know even kind of the
regulator's would recognize today about
the pathologies of software development
and the types of vulnerabilities that
creep in and the difficulty of
identifying those vulnerabilities and
doing something about them in and so
there's I'd say five different anecdotes
that you would you read in the pages of
this article and then you could think of
recent examples of these very same
problems occurring over and over again
interestingly and the reason why I'm
showing you this is that he motivates
the paper with a hypothetical and the
hypothetical is that the KGB is giving a
briefing the KGB KGB analyst is giving a
briefing to his colleagues and he says
guess what the Americans have put all
their most sensitive secrets into
computers and they they kind of know
that they're vulnerable
they behave in the abstract they
understand that their computers are
vulnerable but absent verified examples
of us breaking into those computers
they're not going to do anything about
those vulnerabilities and it's like wow
he really he really had the hypothetical
right and and I feel like this is what's
happened in the commercial sector with
cloud and a whole lot of other areas we
knew in theory that there were problems
but it wasn't until those problems found
an actual execution that we were willing
to to really grapple with them and do
something about them um if you're
interested in reading this article just
email me and I'll shoot you my copy of
it it's it's a fantastic a fantastic
read he talks about his Tiger teams at
at the air force but you know what we'd
call a red team today and how they were
able to break into everything and how
they would even find they he gives this
fantastic example of how his team plants
a small piece small bit of malware into
a defense contractors system and the
defense contractor can't find it even
when told about it even when told this
is what we put in your system they can't
find it not only that the defense
contractor min manages to replicate the
vulnerability and put it into other
systems
it's just astounding totally worth a
reading so and getting ready for this
talk and and having read these recent
papers I asked myself the question you
know why was it that Willis where are in
these other these other people most of
whom were tied into the military and the
intelligence community how is it that
they had all these insights and it's
taken us so long in the regulatory field
so when I say us I mean the lawyers why
is it taken the lawyers so long to
figure out these lessons that were
articulated for tea and and fit almost
50 years ago and of course I think um
we're familiar with the problem I mean
the overall problem is that computing is
so compelling and so beneficial that we
have to adopt it we have no real choice
and because we cannot fully manage the
security problems we deny them we say
it's just normal it's just kind of risk
we have to accept and we become resigned
to them I um there's a lot of examples
of where this has happened in in society
I car safety is another example for a
long time we conceived of car accidents
and driver deaths as inevitable
consequences of the car we didn't
conceive of the idea that more safety
could be built into them so what I
thought about today to talk about is
give some concrete examples of how we
could overcome this denial and
resignation to insecurity in the
regulatory community so I'm going to
talk about the legal tools that
regulators have I'm going to talk about
how the regulator's think about their
tools what their kind of psychology is
and then finally how you might use your
expertise to convince them to take
action in areas where you think it is
important so a lot of what I've a lot of
what I've written about is the idea that
consumer protection law the body of law
that we could call consumer protection
law has a profound
information security mandate so when we
talk about the Federal Trade Commission
suing companies for insecurity it's not
because the Federal Trade Commission has
an information security law it's because
the Federal Trade Commission is using
its general power to police consumer
protection basically the quality and
safety of goods and services and it's
interpreting that body of law as
imposing an information security
requirement so that's a that's a bit
like skiing on stilts right we don't we
don't have an FTC security law instead
we have this general body of consumer
protection law and so when the FTC takes
admit takes action let's say against
Facebook most recently or against a
company for having inadequate security
it does so under the rationale that has
the power to prevent unfair or deceptive
trade practices and you know guess what
there's no real definition of what these
things are it's kind of a slippery
definition so they're separate theories
that's one important thing to think
about
there's unfairness and there's deception
two separate theories but unfairness is
any practice or act that creates
substantial consumer injury right so
that that doesn't even really hang much
meat on the law because we could
disagree about what injury is but what
the Federal Trade Commission is looking
for is insecurity that causes
substantial consumer injury and some
other elements here you know there are
situations where insecurity is
unavoidable by the consumer so that's a
plus if you want to bring a bring a case
and there's instances where insecurity
actually contributes to efficiency or
makes a product possible that otherwise
would not be possible so there's a kind
of cost-benefit analysis in this theory
of action but the main thing to remember
is if you want the Federal Trade
Commission to
intervene about some security practice
you have to convince a Federal Trade
Commission attorney that the act the the
the practice it causes substantial
consumer injury the other cause of
action is is deception and this is an
easier theory to use it simply means a
representation or omission that misleads
an ordinary consumer and causes them
detriment so the lot of things out there
cause deception in the world and what
the Federal Trade Commission has has
argued is that if you're a company and
you collect you collect information from
consumers reasonable consumers assume
that you have some baseline of
reasonable security so a lot of them
want to talk about is what what that
might be so some other kind of dynamics
here the federal trade you read about
the Federal Trade Commission a lot right
and there's this recent case against the
against Facebook they only do they only
do about fifteen or twenty cases a year
right so that is not a lot of
enforcement when you think about all the
companies out there we have the GD GD P
R approach and my colleague is gonna
talk about GD P R and more detail so I'm
not going to say much more than to say
that it's similar to the FTC Authority
in that it operates at a pretty high
level of abstraction the GD P R is what
I would call a principles-based
regulation it doesn't tell you
specifically what to do but it asks you
to jump over hurdles that are pretty
high so they want you to use your brain
and decide you know to make an active
decision about what type of technical
safeguards are needed for your system
and they should be tailored to the type
of data you have the purposes it's used
for and so on there is a very
interesting part of the DDP R that the
security part of the GD P R that talks
about state of the art that I want you
to keep in mind and of course there's
privacy by design into fall
enforcement is one of the interesting
issues in the GDP our it's it's hard to
track this down they actually have been
some pretty significant enforcement
actions a lot of people pay attention to
the 50 million euro fine against Google
but in addition to that there was a
hundred million dollar a hundred million
euro fine against Marriott and British
Airways spectacular fine I think was a
hundred and eighty million euros so the
the the fines are ramping up and that's
going to be a key part of whether the
GDP are is effective um it's important
oops I think I think I've I might I
might have I have my slides out order
but so let me just keep going so on one
hand you have the FTC law you have the
GDP are that speaks at the principles
level on the other hand another kind of
theme of what's happening in
cybersecurity regulation are highly
prescriptive rules that we see emerging
from some sectors I think the most
consequential of them is that is the New
York Department of Financial Services
cyber rules you can if you google these
you can find them there at 23 NY Cir 500
and this is the model where the
regulator tells you very specifically
what they want you to do they want you
to have a custom security policy they
want you to be doing pen testing and so
on that covers this that and the other
thing and they want a pretty broad array
of security incidents to be reported to
the regulator so we have cyber security
rules are moving in these two different
directions
one of high principle and then one of
this high prescription so those are the
types of tools those are some of the
tools that regulators have to police
cyber security but when they police them
they police them in a political
environment so you leave the text of the
law what you think the law is and you
leave you you you come to an environment
where the regulator's have to work
within their institutions to bring
enforcement actions and there's a lot of
really interesting psychology here I
think a lot of the regulators and I'm
gonna be a little bit hard on them today
I think generally speaking many of them
don't understand information as a as a
thing I see them as in my experience
from working with the Federal Trade
Commission for a long time is that most
regulators essentially are solipsistic
they they use facebook right and they
love it they're part of the demographic
that actually uses facebook middle-aged
men and so their experience of Facebook
is what drives their kind of conception
of what these services do and if they
see ads that are misleading and so on
that's their evidence
there isn't a there there isn't a real
demand to think objectively about how
other people sir experience services so
you know one of the one of the lessons
here is that in engaging with whether
it's Federal Trade Commission or state
attorneys general who are very active in
security and privacy is that you have to
think about their technology worldview
and how they might be using they might
categorically not be using the services
that you use so they have no experience
of them they have no idea of how people
could be harmed by them or manipulated
by them another important point is that
annek data is just more powerful and
regulators eyes than data ultimately you
know like it or not you have to conceive
of an enforcement action before a judge
or a jury and judges and juries are
moved not by data by stories so having a
good story is powerful and and here
because I am a lawyer I can I can I can
pick on
a bit a lot of federal regulators fight
with a glass jaw they are really worried
about losing cases because if they lose
any case their entire agency is burdened
by that loss it's not like a plaintiff's
lawyer where you know you losing your
plaintiff's lawyer you lose a case who
cares you bring another but if you're
the Federal Trade Commission you lose a
case it affects every single enforcement
action that you engage in so as a result
there is a defensive posture it's not as
aggressive as let's say Department of
Justice when it charges criminals it's a
it's a different different posture and
then the other thing is that lawyers
fake it
Wow they fake it what are the powers of
being a lawyer is showing up in a room
and wearing a suit and scaring everyone
by your mere presence you don't have to
do anything to get this power you just
have to show up and not say anything and
people get scared if you ask lawyers
just a few a few questions you'll see
that they're faking it they really don't
have a good conception of the technology
and so on and I am one of the more
technically trained lawyers but I tell
you I get fooled all the time this is a
really embarrassing one but you know
there's this idea companies say well we
we encrypt data in transit and we
encrypted at rest and so finally I was
always fooled by this I always thought
that sounds great wonderful until one of
my defense contractor friends said
listen you idiot our data are never at
rest I had never even conceived at that
idea and and I think regulators are
labor laboring under a lot of
misconceptions about what security
analysis does so there's a lot of
specious representations that if you
don't walk through the the consequences
of them they're not likely to understand
a great example you could tell a
regulator that we do is a full source
code review of our software to make sure
that it has no vulnerabilities in it but
of course that says nothing about apple
of implementations of that software and
how it could be implemented in ways
where it become
insecure despite the underlying software
being secured in the abstract so with
all that in mind I look at you know what
security researchers are doing and I
want to give some examples without
picking on anyone too much because I
admire what they're doing now this is um
this is Mudge's work at the cyber ITL
this is a great fantastic effort they
are testing a huge number of Internet of
Things devices and Wow are they finding
they are insecure so in one of their
reports they do this study where they
analyze LG televisions Vizio ones and
Hart and Linux and they show that when
the software is finally implemented in
these in these devices that many of them
are missing basic security measures
there's a report basically says you know
if you look at LG televisions they're
missing these basic protections against
exploitation rate and I can kind of get
why that's wrong but I don't think
regulators would kind of get what the
problem is there so what
so finding vulnerabilities is great and
the people in this room understand what
those mean but for the regulator I think
there's some other questions that you
could put in your papers there's some
other discussion that you can put in
your paper that could be really useful
one can you link the vulnerability to
some demonstrably bad outcome as in this
vulnerability so you know like you might
ask like who cares that LG TVs don't
have a SLR well you might care a lot or
a regulator would care a lot if the
caption of that chart said the absence
of a SLR led to X number of infections
in the Mirai botnet or something like
that
that's the type of resolution they need
to to link to link this together so
other other critical issues recall that
when you argue that a practices
fare the Federal Trade Commission will
do a cost-benefit analysis so inherently
they're gonna in their head is gonna be
the question oh well you know you're
picking on LG because they made these
televisions but what were the
alternatives how much it would have had
cost how much would it cost to put to
properly design the software and what
were the trade-offs so you could talk
about that and then finally and and I
think this is pretty critical
is there any way for a consumer to know
that the LG television is not as secure
as the Vizio one is there any way there
are any signals out there I think the
answer to that is no but you could talk
about what would the consumer what what
is the logical chain of facts would that
the consumer would have to know to be
able to make a decision based on this
graph is quite complex and you know the
federal trick you know the you could
convince the regulator that no consumer
would figure this out on their app on
their own and as a result the market
won't provide the signals needed
therefore they shouldn't intervene so I
I love seeing images like this so these
kind of dns outages but I'm not sure
what they mean and I was thinking you
know if you had if you were talking
let's say about Mirai or another one of
the big botnets out there and we'd be
really interesting to talk about it not
in the sense of the servers that were
affected but rather how many users were
adversely impacted and for how long and
you know I'm sure there are numbers out
there about the amount of Commerce that
it happens on the Internet at any given
second so you know what does it mean if
no one can make a purchase for 30
seconds I think the number is probably
really big I think that type of
information could be very powerful for
regulators and the type of thing that
could change their mind about bringing a
case
um oh now I remember what I have
happened with my slides here okay so I
wanted to talk a little bit about state
of the art um and maybe you'll have
people have comment on this to the GDP
are says that your security has has to
be state of the art but of course state
of the art has at least two different
meanings and American law I don't know
what its meaning is in Europe oftentimes
when you hear state of the art it is
said from the perspective of an
advertiser and it's meant to mean the
best possible or the cutting edge of
scientific advance but more conservative
and when I say that I mean a small C or
careful Juris look at the same term and
they say that's not what that means at
all what state of the art means is state
of the practice this is what people do
commonly day to day having a handle on
that type of nuances and is important
and so the question I would ask and I
have some I have some examples of this
is how might the security community
articulate a start a state of the art
and in some ways in some ways it has
done this but you could also imagine how
you could contribute to public policy by
merely surveying companies about their
practices and documenting what they're
doing on what they're not doing to give
regulators an idea of what is common
business practice out there I think this
is true with privacy by default in
design I'm going to give an example of
give an example of something I did in
the privacy realm so this isn't security
this is privacy the rules governing spam
were recently reviewed by the Federal
Trade Commission so yeah we have a
anti-spam law in the United States it's
wonderfully effective but I I have you
know I have ideas about how we could
make the law more effective what would I
comment syn the proceedings that is try
I'm trying to drive the regulation
toward a place where people who send
commercial email have to use a standard
disclosure in text because I want
filters to be able to look for that
standard disclosure so it can be
filtered okay so among the things I
looked at was readability of commercial
email and one of the things you'll see
is that you know one of the deals one of
the bargains of commercial email is that
spammers are allowed to spam you it's an
opt-out system so every business in the
world is allowed to send you email and
the the bargain is is that you have the
right to opt out well okay
to have a right to opt-out you need to
know how to do it and so I did a survey
of looking at different spams and what I
found was is that a lot of those a lot
of that commercial email is unreadable
in a technical sense so here's an
example from endo Chino this is a
company I love like mainstream company
but you know when you get the
unsubscribe this is the unsubscribe
right here it's kind of like grey on
grey and so what I wrote to the Federal
Trade Commission is this email has a
background color in a text color that is
so similar in hue that the the ratio the
contrast ratio is only 1.6 and so the
standard is supposed to be 7 for
something to be readable they give you
an idea this is basically unreadable and
if you have any type of vision visual
impairment this is you can't be read so
so I wrote it fails all standards for
adequate reliability and then I put in
this last sentence for reference white
on white would have a contrast of 1 so
that's how close it is to just being
white on white so I thought this was an
example of what we might be able to do
in security and that is to show show
examples from mainstream companies not
by fly fly by night companies who cares
like mainstream companies what are they
what's going wrong compare those compare
those those practices with a commonly
recognized standard so disability groups
you
the standard to argue whether something
is readable or not no one really argues
oh no one no one argues much about it I
put in a conclusion right you can't
this isn't readable no matter what
standard do you use it's not readable
and I put in this like reference to give
you an idea how bad it is it's almost
white on white okay I thought this is a
pretty compelling argument right
the FTC should go with me and pass a
rule saying that when you do an opt-out
it has to at least be readable
well they didn't and what they said was
none of the comments and they're
referring to me here provide the
Commission with information about the
cost and benefits of these rule changes
so I thought this was a little
ridiculous I didn't think I had to say
that it doesn't cost any money to change
f5f5f5 to ffffff right but apparently I
did so I didn't follow my own advice
so I especially I mean the lesson here
is especially in the Trump
administration one has to talk
cost-benefit even when even when you
think it's ridiculous so when when a
vulnerability is introduced into us into
software based on let's say a lack of a
flag let's say when they compiled the
software they didn't put in a single
flag and typing that flag in would have
taken 10 seconds you should say that it
would have taken an engineer a competent
engineer 10 seconds to to change this
setting and make this software more more
safe they want to hear that I can't
believe that this was their response
another question that I want to
challenge you on is the the the problem
of expressing norms so for my
cybersecurity course I interviewed a
whole whole bunch of different experts
who who talked to my students and I
interviewed one of the Greybeards one of
the wonderful people in CS and I asked
them you know I asked him here series of
questions and one of the things he
responded was with was we
computer security we know what we need
to do and I listened to that it was
great I believe you but that will not
that type of argument will not convince
any regulator so I don't know if I died
trip to my slide here so the types of
things this kind of appeal to Authority
we know what to do is too vague I think
there's other things that you can do as
security researchers one is to talk
about fixes in engineering time so we
think it would take this many minutes to
fix this problem to talk about things
like if the problem isn't fixed at
design
how many transaction costs and other
other costs are imposed if it's fixed
after the product or services in the
consumers hands so this is an argument
about X posts or X anti interventions
it's almost always a better deal right
if that if that masseur vez is fixed
before the product goes into the
marketplace are there tools to detect or
fix the flaw you might even show them
the specific way the flaw could have
been fixed I so for instance in my spam
conte my spam comment I really wish I
had paste it in the HTML and written the
fix as banal as that would have been I
think it would have been a better way to
express that that change and then maybe
you could talk about trade-offs you know
what are the possible reasons why a
vulnerability remained and on a system
Road one of the possible reasons why it
remained insecure in the marketplace
there's a number of things you can do to
make regulators jobs easier one I think
would be really neat if let me before
sharing this recommendation let me let
me
give some background if if your client
or if your company has a consequential
security breach you'll get a call from
the Federal Trade Commission or from a
state attorney general they call up and
they say we want to know what happened
tell us what happened in those
conversations they're trying to decide
whether or not they should bring a case
against that specific company and more
often than not they don't so they're
screening many many many different
incidents to decide which ones to pursue
I think that'd be really useful for
people in this community to create
checklists of the types of questions
lawyers should be asking technical
experts so this would be a deposition
checklist in in in normal parlance but
you could also imagine specific ones for
let's say security breach the other
aspect where where I think there's been
a pretty effective research-based
information transferred to regulators is
occurring in standards so if you talk to
the Federal Trade Commission people
about what are the types of security
breaches you decide to bring lawsuits
for like you know what
why did you sue Equifax and not another
company well size and damage and so on
but one of the main things they look at
is the wasp vulnerabilities list and the
Federal Trade Commission even says this
in their reports that that the OWASP
standards are important to them and then
here in California when Senator Kamala
Harris was a Trent was Attorney General
here in California she did something
really interesting she collected data on
all the security breaches that occurred
in California that were reported to her
office and what she found was is that if
you looked at the root causes of those
security security breaches many of them
would have been prevented if if you had
applied the the former you know the so
called the CSC controls
and if you look at the Attorney
General's guidance on reasonable
security what they've basically done is
they've copied and pasted the CSC
controls and and that is what they
consider reasonable security here and
here in California and finally I'm gonna
I'm gonna in here in part because I'd
love to hear your your feedback on this
on this last point you know security
breach
laws came out of Berkeley they were
invention of Deirdre Mulligan she she
had this idea that if we had to report
security breaches we could get public
data about insecurity and and maybe we
could do something about insecurity well
when they when when those laws were
conceived of we had no idea how many
incidences and breaches were actually
occurring and in fact I think everybody
was surprised by the number that were
actually occurring the other interesting
dynamic in security breach notification
law is that it's really about identity
theft you think about it like what are
the what are the trigger what what
information triggers a security breach
its social security number a credit card
number and so on
well that's because when that law passed
that was the only harm that the
legislature thought was serious enough
to justify reach notification no that
doesn't make any I mean now we know that
that's that doesn't make a lot of sense
anymore right
there are many consequential security
incidents out there involving
intellectual property trade secret that
you don't have to disclose unless you're
a publicly traded company and there's
other things that happen out there that
aren't covered by security breach
notification laws and so what happens
now in practice is that when a you know
when it likes or horses when a client
comes to me and says we've had something
happen
I say don't call it a security breach
it's not a breach until we have legal
determined that we are required to give
notice we're gonna call this a security
incident until we fully investigate it
and here's the real problem there are
incidents that are far worse than any
breaches right I mean just imagine it if
a search engine company lost all your
search strings that would be pretty
painful it'd be pretty embarrassing
probably more probably more embarrassing
or more problematic than if a search
engine company lost your credit card
number I mean the end of the day you're
insured right against credit card losses
but a search engine strings aren't
covered by security breach laws they're
not a breach they're an incident and
there's many many other examples like
that out there where websites including
websites that have very sensitive
content have incidents and lose their
entire user database and they don't have
to give anybody notice so I would out I
want to invite you to think about how we
we might broaden the aperture of what we
consider consequential security events
maybe for reporting purposes maybe to
talk to regulators about other areas
where where they can intervene so with
that I'd love to take questions or we or
we could ten minutes okay okay great
and I'd love to hear what what you think
about some of this critique yes please
hi I'm the I'm the chief privacy officer
and I start up called humu but I used to
be the global lead
privacy tech at Google so I talked to
FTC people before the thing that I
wonder is you're talking about hey let's
go make a deposition checklist for
lawyers why are we not sending engineers
in to go and try and find these because
I love lawyers I worked with lots of
lawyers most of them are not as good at
finding problems in a system as the
teams of privacy engineers that I've
trained yeah
I'm what we're working on in Berkeley is
we're trying to train the next
generation of what we call Public
Interest technologists and so watch
consul tony was one of my students and
he was at the Federal Trade Commission
consulted on these cases he he had
consequential findings I mean he was the
one who figured out that there were all
sorts of pictures in Facebook that you
could reach through their CDN that were
not password protected and so on and
those totally escaped the lawyers I so I
I agree with you
like in and so one we've been struggling
with is finding people who can really do
the technology and and convince the
regulators that like there's something
important in their findings we need many
more people like that any other
questions or critiques anybody want to
yell at me and argue about what are the
right what should the regulator's be
doing that they're not the types of
things that you think are important or
consequential dev do you I don't want to
yell at you okay thank you
I think you talked about exclaim the I
think you talked about explain the in
the cost benefit like talk about the
cost to add the mitigation add more
security but if they're doing the
benefit analysis how do we argue about
the benefit of turning on a SLR or the
benefit of like in some cases I agree
it's agree it's easy I think like the
unsubscribe from spam yes yes it's like
what is the benefit of like because I
think like that's one of the things the
community also grapples with is it's
hard to measure security it's hard to
really say this significantly improves
security outcomes and so like if you do
that now will we get stuck on benefits
sir that's a great question right I
think I think the anok data is is is is
more powerful and so the examples I
would give is can you point to specific
botnets that spread as a result of that
protection not being in place if you
can't I it might be that that's just not
the intervention that that the
regulators should be pursuing
I aren't gross another former security
person from the big search engine when I
hear it would take only 10 seconds to
insert this compiled flag of course I
think yes
ten seconds to type that flag another
three days to debug the messages that
come from that and another three months
to actually deploy it
so I come from prospective wishing there
were some way to use market mechanisms
instead of tricking regulators into
causing good things to happen out there
sometimes the the tools that I would
hope would help inform the market
mechanisms entail some kind of legal
risk either to the companies involved or
to the people publicly complaining about
the companies and then getting sued for
libel or whatever do you have any legal
thoughts on improving the market
mechanism so I one of the reasons why
I'm a fan of Mudge in this project is
that it did the idea is you know
Consumer Reports since the 1930s has had
people wearing lab coats testing whether
doors open well alright and so on and so
they're they're now going to be looking
at the software so I think that's
important but I definitely don't think
it's enough I think it's the first the
first step out there I you know an
interesting problem with Consumer
Reports is if you if you look at their
average reader they look like me it's a
white dude with gray hair so we have to
not only I think we have to get the
signals about quality into the
marketplace but we also have to make
sure that they reach down to two other
types of consumers thank you
hi Matthew from the University of Bonn
in Germany you you asked for feedback
what regulators could do I think one
awesome thing would be to work more
closely with the usable security
community yeah and tailor the kind of
regulation to what humans can actually
do so living in Germany I'm on the
receiving end of gdpr and it's pretty
horrible
so it it's great on the firing companies
for data breaches it's pretty bad on the
side of informed consent because they
basically the companies design things in
a way that basically you are forced to
consent to everything they want because
otherwise it's just too much work and
anybody in the usable security community
could foreseen that and help regulators
prevent that from being a legal option I
think you know the cookie notice and the
cookie notices are quite tiresome they
are horrendous um but I've helped a lot
of clients deal with gdpr
and I'd say that 95% of the compliance
effort is under the hood and the
consumer would never never know that
they stopped collecting x y&z what I've
seen with a lot of clients is they've
never had a data retention policy so
gdpr is the first conversation you have
with many companies of like so how long
are you going to keep this and and then
another big area where I've seen a huge
amount is the decision to secretly do
face recognition alright so I mean when
I think one of the kind of secrets out
there and the valley is that if you give
your photograph to any service they're
running face recognition on it they just
they may or may not tell you and they
may or may not tagged the gdpr has
stopped tamped down some of that
opportunism don't get me wrong GPR is
fantastic is I'm just saying the those
parts where you're interacting with
humans is horrible so that's that's why
I think there could be improvement with
research we we offer actually I'm
wondering what you think about this
because that to me I think the ICO the
UK ICO led with this cookie disclosure
that I thought this is not what the GDP
are is trying to do but they led with it
and signal that it was okay and maybe
they'll be reformed along those lines
do you have comment on that yeah on the
I mean the I co was courteous that I
thought this is not what the GDP are is
trying to do but they led with it and
signaled that it was okay
and maybe they'll be reformed along
those lines
do you have comment on that yeah on the
I mean the I co was criticized for not
being compliant with its own websites
until very recently and I'm just
reporting this from the press I'm
obviously not taking a position on what
colleague data protection authorities
are doing and when they reviewed their
guidance on cookies and then they
decided actually to become compliant
with their own guidance and so they are
giving credit for that and it's actually
I'm I'm quite surprised that I find more
and more website who have decent cookie
pages so some still have the old style
thing Oh video cookies and that will be
all good for you just admit that it will
be all good for you but now I've
encountered plenty of websites
personally where you have cede the
technically necessary cookies I mean
still a question whether that's still
state-of-the-art but then performance
personalization tracking targeted
advertising cookies can be switched off
one by one explicitly and there's tools
out now from commercial companies who
are offering that and it's taking more
and more and I see it mostly was
companies who don't depend on tracking
and advertising revenue so I mean those
who depend on tracking and advertising
revenue of course are reluctant to makes
a change but those who earn their money
in a different way by selling Allah our
plane tickets or hotel bookings or so
they see that they get better a customer
relationship when they are transparent
and actually respect choice ooh I think
there is a change ongoing which is I
mean we just bit more than one year in
the validity in the full applicability
of cont DPR and
this is going better than I was
expecting to be honest on because maybe
I'm a bit cynical and pessimistic in
that respect
yeah there's dialogue so I find them
frustrating and if you just press X to
get rid of them they treat that as
except hmm yeah important design hair
and I think I have one like one question
and then hand it over okay
William Sampson daydreamer
also a lifetime subscriber to Consumer
Reports and I own an LG Tony television
and I can tell you because I looked at
all of their software that in fact
they're running Linux on top of arctos
they could have had all the security
features they just didn't turn them on
we gave the FTC for Dave Farber was and
then Steve elleven who usually attends
here
Farber does occasionally and during his
first few months there I went and
visited Steve so I already knew you only
take a few cases a year which is really
terrible
but I I could talk about a lot of this
stuff but the main thing is there is no
private right of action okay is that yes
the federal government or state
governments they have some amount of
limited resources but without a private
right of action for the people who
actually have been affected by bad
software or bad you know access points I
mean we've known about distributed
denial there was a tax since 1996 and we
predicted them had papers in 1991 and -
okay before they even occurred so this
is not news you know yes the identity
theft has something to do with money and
so that Congress can say oh it might
affect somebody financially but in fact
all of the kinds of our botnet
they affect you in every way they take
your bandwidth from your home they take
that is those are all losses but without
a private right of action
the real problem is we don't have good
enforcement mechanisms we have perfectly
good definitions for many things but
there is no good enforcement mechanism I
like the fact that GD P R I love lots of
things about GDP are not the fact that
you can only say except about their
cookie policy but the the is that it can
be up to the fine can be up to 4 percent
of the gross revenue of the company
that's a serious fine as opposed to the
slap on the wrist that most of the stuff
that we get now if you're gonna take 20
cases here they should be going for 20
cases a year that causes the companies
to go to near bankruptcy so that they
send a single all the other ones that
they need to take security seriously and
hire more security engineers obviously
and and in that way improve the whole
ecosystem but a private right of action
might also be very helpful because it
informed consumers are the ones who are
more likely to be able to be active and
give good stories that that they will
have the courts on the legislators of
understand let me say briefly that the
California consumer Privacy Act does
have a private right of action for
certain security breaches so it detects
it takes effect on January 1 and it's
gonna be it's gonna be quite interesting
I am afraid there's no question brief
comment three words okay make it I
thought it was ironic that you compared
LG & Vizio and showed LG to be more
secure without pointing out that office
or less secure without pointing out that
of the two companies Vizio was the one
to actually be sued by the FTC for
deceptive practices I this is gonna be
really interesting I think I think what
Mudge and company are doing is really
important because as they compare these
different vendors some of them are
Federal Trade Commission defendants and
a real questions going to be whether
those defendants are any better on
security that's going to be super
interesting
okay thank you very much Chris let's
give a warm applause
[Applause]