hi so I recently found this nice little
survey in my
time line and it basically describes the
core of the problem we wanted to try to
solve in his paper and it says I'm a
programmer looking for a solution on
Stack Overflow to paste into my project
and it has thousands of retweets and ten
thousands of likes so it seems that you
could consider this as common behavior
and we also had a lot of studies over
the last year's that basically looked at
this a little bit more scientifically
and they confirmed this
so as this might speak for the high
usability and utility of Stack Overflow
it also comes with a high risk for
application security and that is when it
comes to security related questions or
usability issues around cryptographic
api's so for instance this Tiger flow
question is about one of the biggest
issues in android how can you accept a
certificate during TLS handshake that is
not part of the custom Android trusted
store so in this this question showed up
on the stack overflow quite a lot had
millions of view counts and thousand and
a lot of uploads and so on and a typical
typical question do this answer was this
null verifier or some kind of variation
of it which basically turns off
certificate verification however it
technically solved the initial problem
so people were quite happy with this
answer and it was you know ups voted a
lot so two years ago we had an Auckland
paper where we basically have shown that
people indeed reuse insecure code from
Stack Overflow and Android applications
from Google Play and those included apps
with high profile apps with billions of
downloads and apps from security
sensitive categories and one of our
co-authors had another paper where they
basically were able to show that it's
possible to attack apps based on these
insecure code
snippets from Stack Overflow to steal
credentials and critical numbers and
other private data so we had another
icse paper this year which basically
showed that all the market signals on
Stack Overflow basically point towards
the wrong direction as they you know
hand in secure solutions on a plate
basically so it seems that it's by the
problem so what to do about it
so over the last year's we had a lot of
really nice studies that basically
investigated different forms of security
advice for software developers and
compared later with stack overflow so
for instance books and formal
documentation study code analysis tools
and also simplified cryptographic api's
so as all of these approaches are helped
in you know producing more secure
solutions they produce less functional
solutions due to some usability issue
and the interesting thing for us was
that from these studies was that
whenever people you know encountered a
usability issue with one of these
approaches they went for you know coach
helping on Stack Overflow once again and
you know this behavior kind of goes in
line with a quote of Richard Thaler
who's the founder of the Nash here II
and it says first never underestimate
the power of inertia but also second
that power can be harnessed and for us
that that sounds sounded quite nice so
it inspired us for our main approach
which was you know maybe it's possible
to kind of exploit this copy-and-paste
behavior and also the apparently
unbeatable usability of Stack Overflow
to you know how people getting security
right but how to do that so one of the
most important findings to answer this
question findings in our paper to answer
this question was that we found out that
um Stack Overflow
for a similar f4 we had psychoville flow
provides similar insecure code snippets
for almost all the VP insecure code
snippets so you might be able to look at
this you might be you might look at this
as a you know decision-making problem
and that and that's when you know this
is such the not Seri comes into play and
so the Nash Theory basically tries to
nudge people towards better decisions
without restricting their options and
here on the right side you can see an
example for this there are two options
you know for getting upstairs using the
stairs is the better option in terms of
health but people you know tend to use
the escalator however if you come up
with a new choice architecture with the
stairs now look like a piano keyboard
that makes sounds when you walk up says
people you know start to favor this
option so our first goal was to come up
with a new choice architecture for a
stack overflow that not just people from
you know from yeah that not just people
towards reusing code examples that
provide stronger security without you
know without interfering with the
usability of psychoville flow so and to
be able to do that the first thing we
had to do was to find these better
alternatives on stack overflow so we
basically had to solve three technical
problems and that was being able to
predict the similarity of cryptographic
api patterns predicting the use case and
of course their security so in our first
step we learned a representation of
cryptographic API patterns by embedding
their code graphs into a vector space
using structure to Beck so the sodium
betting is lunge such that similar
patterns are closer together and
decently our patterns are more far away
from each other in the embedding space
and additionally we had to solve a
problem that was kind of specific for
Stack Overflow and that was you know a
lot of code examples on Stack Overflow
are incomplete programs so they won't
compile so we had to use a fuzzy
compiler to get some kind of graph
representation out of it
which might be unsound so however our
embedding approach takes this into
account and moves these different graph
representation for the same header and
also a closer together in the embedding
space alright so the second problem we
needed to solve was to predict use cases
of patterns so since we already had a
preach a pre-trained similarity model
that already contained useful knowledge
to predict a use case we transfer this
knowledge from the knowledge from the
similarity domain into the use case
domain so we basically added a couple of
layers on top of a representation
Learning Network and a multi-class
classification layer to predict do we
use cases and we did the same thing for
predicting security we applied transfer
learning from trenton to transfer the
knowledge from the similarity domain
into the security domain this time using
a binary classification classifier so
here on the left side you can see the
results of our similarity model for
basically all the Drupal graphic API
patterns we extracted from Stack
Overflow and here the color basically
indicates their use cases and as you can
see the similarity model already creates
some some dense clusters for some use
cases but also sparse clusters for
others and on the right side you can see
the results of our use case model which
kind of corrects this and creates by
creating dense clusters for all of these
use cases
on here in the middle you can see the
results of her assumed similarity model
again however this time the color
indicates the security of a pattern and
this cluster here is a cypher cluster so
the use case of the patterns here are
you know initializing a cipher and this
cluster kind of gives you know nicely
indicates that or a main idea of
matching people from you know in
security secur might actually be
technically feasible so this as you can
see the similarity cluster has a
security boundary so samples that are
close to this boundary might actually
provide very useful alternatives and so
we cherry picked an example for this so
on the left side you can see the
security warning for an insecure pattern
as we showed it on stackoverflow and the
bottom you can see the list of
recommendations and they're ordered by
similarity and use cases so when you
click on the first link you would end up
on a Stack Overflow post shown on the
right and as you can see the the code is
basically the same it only differs in in
the statement that rendered the whole
code snippet insecure before however the
user of the developer might actually
ignore basically everything I just
showed you know copied code copy would
copy be insecure codes again and so
whenever we we kind of you know see that
we trigger a reminder nudge that
basically shows the security warning and
the recommendations again to launch the
you know the the user one more time so
as we now had everything together we
wanted a test or a system design within
a small developer study and we had two
treatments when not the nuts group and
the control group and both of them had
to solve to two different different
programming tasks symmetric encryption
and certificate verification and we had
to
Tricks functional correctness and
security so once again functional
correctness for us was very important
because we wanted to make sure that we
didn't create any obstacles for
programmers such that they you know can
happen we continue copying spaces stuff
so and yes we achieved our first goal
for functional correctness so both
groups achieved a very high level of
functional the solutions of both group
functional correctness and the nudge
group had no significant negative effect
on functional correctness and we also
achieved our security goal as the nudge
group significantly outperformed the
control group when it comes to you know
with respect to the solutions alright so
and now I'd like to discuss a little bit
you know what worked and to be able to
do that we looked at the copy and paste
history of all of not participants and
that includes the what copy what code
has been copied from Stack Overflow into
the clipboard and what code has been
pasted from the clipboard into the IDE
of our participants so first we wanted
to have a look at how security warnings
work on Stack Overflow and yes we had
27% unsecure copies from Stack Overflow
to the clipboard so once again you know
stick you know security warnings are not
enough nothing new however we had 0%
insecure pastes into the IDE so every
each and every paste from Stack Overflow
into the IDE was secure so we concluded
that people drop the insecure copy due
to the reminder notch and reused one of
our recommendations instead
so to wrap up the talk I'd like to
present one of our one of a nice over
nice results I think which was that it
helped tackling all these nasty now
verify is a little bit so short reminder
in a right Oakland paper we basically
showed that ninety percent of code that
was reused from Stack Overflow and
Android applications were all verifies
and 0.2 percent was only 0.2% was code
that God certificate verification right
so our a nudge group here achieved 77
percent secure solutions while still the
control state can be quite behind here
and I think this is quite a cool result
because we consider this problem as the
one with the highest risk for
application security as as shown by fall
at all and at that this was also the use
case where we found you know the less
the the lowest number of secure
solutions on Stack Overflow we kind of
we found I think over 1,000 examples for
an all verifier and only like 50 to 60
examples that it did it right
however there's still you know lots of
questions and open problems one an
interesting problem is or question is
the default notch which is a very very
popular notch in the literature it
basically you know presents the the
better option per default and we
implemented this an on in Stack Overflow
by basically reordering search results
based on security such that people would
see you know the better option first and
it'd be nice to see a large-scale study
on live Stack Overflow with real Stack
Overflow users to test you know several
different you UI in different
to come up with a final design so the
great thing is that Stack Overflow
offers a partnership program with
academia so that might be an opportunity
to actually have impact all right thank
you very much thank you for the great
talk so you might think that I'm
overthinking but consider that I'm an
attacker who wants to spread my buggy
code for malicious purposes so before
these nudges
I need to convince people that my code
is good but after these noises I just
need to convince your model that my code
is good so that it would recommend
people have you evaluated like which one
is easier here we avoided that an
attacker who might put your model as the
target yep
so of course an adverse will attack here
is an interesting question and the thing
that the code on Stack Overflow is is
fuzzy I think makes an adversarial
attack a little bit easier so the code
doesn't have to compile so you could add
you know randomly try to you if you want
to add noise you would try to randomly
add the character somewhere in the code
and try to you know somehow changed its
graph representation such as the
embedding is changed and the model would
make it wrong you know what changes
prediction from from insecure to secure
however on Stack Overflow you would have
to do a lot of things to actually be
able to be allowed to change code on
Stack Overflow I mean you would have to
do the query and to do against a model
and to be able to do that you would have
to change the code and Stack Overflow
and then to be able to do that you would
have to do a lot of things to get the
permission to do that and when you
change the code the code is shown two
different monitors on Stack Overflow
similar to you know reviewing code and
they would have to agree
you know that this change makes sense
because psycho flow has a lot of
problems with people you know just
randomly change different things to copy
stuff you know to create duplicates to
increase their score so there are people
that are looking at this stuff however
if you think this if you think of this
as a general approach you would also
like to use on github or something
something else of course positive
indicators for security are are you know
could be a problem yeah I'm very
interesting work I'm wondering how you
label those cryptography code as secure
or insecure from stack overflow
yeah we we basically reused the labeling
rules from our previous paper so we so
we we did this manually
so we basically looked at all these ten
you know I don't know how many samples
it was I think ten thousand thousand
samples we looked at them and we had
different you know security experts and
they looked at it and decided whether
it's secure or not if this answers the
question great let's thank Felix thank
you very much
[Music]
[Applause]