thank you hi my name is Michael I'm from
UC Berkeley and I'm going to be
presenting wave which is a decentralized
authorization framework with transitive
delegation so authorization is a very
common problem that we all face so it's
kind of useful to ground it in an
example that brings out some of the
nuances so throughout this talk I'm
going to be using an example from IOT
and cyber-physical systems because it
brings out some of the more interesting
parts so the running example let's say
we have a a building owner and they own
multiple buildings and they're now going
to rent a floor of one of these
buildings to a company so they obviously
need to grant the CEO of this company
access to the cyber physical assets on
the floor that they're renting so they
can control the lighting and access the
doors and control the HVAC and so on but
that company also naturally has
employees within it and it's not going
to be the CEO who is managing all of
these these assets in the building it's
going to be delegated to employees so
there's going to be some permission that
needs to be shared from the CEO with the
employees so that the person who's
responsible for controlling the HVAC can
do their job now if this were done in
the traditional approach the way that
we're all sort of very familiar with
there would be some central
authorization server maybe Active
Directory or LDAP or something like that
and all of this authorization policy
would be captured on that server the
problem with this approach is that this
is a central point of attack we have a
system here where there are multiple
buildings multiple tenants within these
buildings and if this one server gets
compromised all of those tenants gets
compromised all of the devices within
the buildings get compromised because
the attacker can manipulate
authorization policy
additionally we can't even trust the
operator of the server so on the left
hand side here the building owner has
granted permission to the CEO but
there's likely other similar grants to
other tenants in other buildings that
they own and that's what a relationship
there is is private between the bullion
and the CEO within the company there are
permission grants to the various
different employees and these permission
grants likely represent some
organizational hierarchy so that's what
information is private and it should
exist only within the company if the
building owner runs the authorization
server they have visibility into the
permission grants that occurred and the
company that can see the private
permission data in the company that they
shouldn't be able to see and likewise if
the CEO or the company runs a server
they can see permission grants that the
building owner is doing to other tenants
that they shouldn't be able to see in
addition in the traditional approach
sometimes delegation is simply
unsupported and you may be familiar with
things like lifx or Netflix where you
simply can't delegate permission to
someone you have to share your username
and password to share your whole account
and even when delegation is supported
it's it's often not transitive so when
the authorization policy is captured in
the central server its manifest as a set
of entries in a central ACL so if the
building owner were to revoke the
permission that the CEO would have that
would remove one entry from the ACL but
all of the delegations within the
company would continue to be valid so
this is very common for example in
Google Docs if you share a document with
someone and they share it with someone
else you can revoke the initial person's
access but everyone they shared with
retains access to the document ideally
what we would want is that when that
initial revocation happened everyone
within the company was was also revoked
so exists basically this comes down to
the fact that existing work sort of
relaxed a bunch of important features
that are that are necessary when you
look at more complex authorization cases
so one of the big ones is that a lot of
authorization systems have a central
authority whether or not that's a
central place permissions are stored or
only a central authority that can verify
permissions additionally a lot of work
out there doesn't have an opinion on how
people discover their permissions which
leads to our banned mechanisms that may
imply additional constraints like
participants having to be online and
most existing work doesn't protect the
permissions they're not encrypted in
storage they're not sort of protected
while they're busy being shared between
people so the operators of the
infrastructure have a lot of visibility
into the permissions so wave is designed
to provide these missing characteristics
it's a cryptographically enforced
decentralized authorization system
and it can be used in place of most
mainstream authorization systems anyone
can delegate permissions or revoke
permissions that they have delegated
anyone could discover permissions that
they've been granted and form a proof of
authorization and anyone including IOT
devices can verify these proofs of
authorization and waive achieves this
using three techniques which I will go
through the first being graph based
authorization then an encryption
mechanism and a storage mechanism so
growth based authorization is not a new
technique this was popularized by sudsy
spooky in 1996 the general idea here is
that you represent permissions as a
graph rather than an ACL table so the
pictures that I gave earlier which
represent delegation actions between
people now actually represent the real
data structure that is used to store the
permissions and this very naturally
represents transitive delegation so in
this model the participants in the
system are entities their collections of
cryptographic keys
these can be devices services or people
and the grants of permissions between
them are attestations these are signed
certificates that are created by the
entities to represent a granted
permissions attestations grant
permissions on a resource and this
resource looks like a URI that may
correspond to a device control points or
it may be an API or something like that
these resources are located within a
namespace which identifies the entity
that created them that entity being the
creator of this resource is the
authority entity for that resource from
which permissions flow a proof of
permissions in the graph based
authorization model is a path through
the graph from a namespace authority to
some entity that's wanting to prove that
they have permissions so you would
assemble two of these attestations
together and concatenate them and that
would be a proof that allows you to show
that you have permissions on something
and the proof grants the intersection of
the permissions of each of its
constituent excitation x' it's
verifiable by anyone at least in our
work not not in such a spooky and it's
attached to messages on all sorts of
interactions to prove that they're
authorized
these attestations and entities form a
single global graph of authorization
even though this is a single global
graph they're obviously multiple
namespace authorities within the graph
and different entities will only be able
to see portions of this global graph
through a mechanism that I'll talk about
next the graph is publicly accessible
and so that obviously leads to the
question of well how do we hide portions
of the graph if this is going to be
publicly accessible the answer is a new
technique called reverse discover rule
encryption and to set this up let's take
the example that we started with earlier
and let's simplify it a little bit let's
say the building owner has granted
permissions on floor 3 and floor 4 to
the CEO and as CEO now needs to grant
permissions on floor 3 to the manager
who's going to be in charge of floor 3
let's also say that the building owner
has contracted a separate company in
janitorial services and they need to
give them access to floor 3 so they can
get you know through the doors at night
to do their job now let's say the floor
3 manager is installing a new IOT
control service and an HVAC controller
in the building and so he gives it
access to some resources on floor 3 and
let's look at this from the perspective
of the HVAC controller that is now
wanting to do the first step which is
discovering the permissions that it has
so if we look at this sort of subset of
the global authorization graph from a
perspective of the HVAC controller we
see that there's really sort of three
categories of added stations the first
category are those that lie on a path
from the authority to the HVAC
controller and all of the permissions
granted by those data stations intersect
so these are the useful at the stations
the HVAC controller could take these
together concatenate them and form a
proof that it is authorized to access
that resource there are also at stations
that do lie on a path to the controller
but they don't have intersecting
permissions so there couldn't be used in
a proof this one grants from flow 3 the
subsequent ones on oh sorry the first
one a flow for the subsequent on floor 3
so it's not useful to the HVAC
controller and there are also some metro
stations that don't lie on a path to the
HVAC controller at all so it's not
really relevant what permissions are
granted on those edges because it it
never leads back to the
tract controller so the general
technique for reverse discoverable
encryption is obviously to encrypt at
the stations but when you do so you
include in that edge station a secret
that allows you to decrypt upstream meta
stations that have intersecting
permissions and that's basically the
first category those that are useful in
a proof that lie on a path and have
intersecting permissions so the HVAC
controller would be able to decrypt this
first attestation because it's encrypted
under a key that it has and when it does
so it learns some kind of secret that
allows you to decrypt this next at the
station upstream and when it does that
it learns a new secret that allows you
to decrypt the next attestation upstream
that has an intersecting permission so
importantly it was unable to decrypt
these other two at the stations in red
because they didn't have intersecting
permissions or they didn't lie on a path
of course the challenge here is that the
encryption mechanism and the secret
that's passed around must somehow
capture the permissions in order to be
able to enable this so the mechanism we
use is to use wildcard identity based
encryption which is a similar to normal
identity based encryption except you can
have wildcards in the key so one key can
match multiple IDs but importantly in
our application there is no private key
generator every entity in the system has
their own ybe system and the system is
used just for our de for averse
discoverable encryption nothing else so
when you create an action when you're
granting permissions you form an ID that
is some function of the permissions that
are that is being granted you then
generate the private key corresponding
to that ID using your own master ybe key
and you include that private key in the
attestation you then encrypt the whole
excitation including the key that you
just included using the same ID but
using the recipients ybe
public parameters so it's a little bit
simplified you can see the paper for
more details and what this leads to is a
graph that looks a little bit like this
where each actor station contains a key
a corresponds to obscene matter stations
so the HVAC controller starts off with
the orange key because it's its own key
you can generate that part trivially so
it's able to decrypt this first at the
station that was encrypted with the
orange lock when it does so
it learns this light blue key which is
sort of tied to the permissions that are
being granted but comes from full three
manager which then allows us to decrypt
the next upstream attestation that is
also tied to flow three permissions but
is comes from the CEO system using that
it can then decrypt the next upstream
attestation which is also tied to the
same permissions and it's not really
important that this contains a secret
key because no one grants permissions to
the authority the permission the
authority already has permissions so
importantly we were unable to decrypt
this association here granting
permissions on floor 4 because it's the
wrong resource so because we're using an
encryption scheme that are sort of
parameterised by the permissions that
are being granted we can ensure that
only the keys that we did with the keys
that we discover are only able to
decrypt sort of intersecting permissions
so this remains undetermined also this
one despite being on a permission that
actually is the same as several of the
keys that the HF controller has
discovered it remains under cryptical
because there is no key from janitorial
services that is granted to the hvac
controller there's no path between
janitorial services and the HVAC
controller so in summary reverse
discoverable encryption allows us to
decrypt these at the stations that are
useful to us that we could use in a
proof but it doesn't require any
out-of-band communication there's no
sort of key setup phase where we have to
communicate it works when these
associations are granted in any
chronological order and we also in the
papers show how you can support expiry
of attestations using this scheme now
the next problem is we have this global
graph and weve encrypted it so that only
portions of the graph are are visible to
entities they can only see the portions
of the graph that are useful to them but
we still need a place to store these
encrypted data stations a bulk chain
very nearly works our initial work did
use a blockchain and we published some
stuff on that it has cryptographically
proven integrity you can store the whole
global graph there people can't tamper
with the graph or remove pieces with of
it and block chains don't really have
any central authorities but it doesn't
scale particularly well if you're trying
to build an authorization system that
sort of has this single graph and
multiple parties are interacting with it
it needs to be able to scale to at least
the load that current authorization
systems are able to handle and
blockchains
don't really go past a few tens of
transactions per second especially if
the transactions are large they're not
financial transactions but they're
storing objects it may be a hundred
kilobytes so we developed this
unequivocal log derived map which is
designed to provide similar guarantees
to a blockchain when you're only storing
objects so it can't do smart contract
execution and it doesn't do financial
transactions but if you're only storing
objects it can get you similar
guarantees to a blockchain
it's a horizontally scalable public
ledger with cryptographic integrity
proofs and it's similar to something
like certificate transparency or key
transparency that you may be familiar
with except that it supports a proof of
non-existence which allows for
revocation it also has very efficient
auditing clients only rarely communicate
with auditors and the auditing load-in
in total scales with the number of
additions to storage not the size of the
storage as you may find in key
transparency and I'll only be able to
give a very high-level overview here you
can go and look in the paper for more
information so you have some storage
servers and you have clients interacting
with them to discover the portions of
the graph that that they need to form
proofs
there are also some auditors which speak
to the servers and are going to be doing
something in order to to check that
those servers are intact and are
maintaining integrity clients and
auditors speak to sort of random subsets
of the total set of storage servers that
exist and the storage service themselves
are constructed using three Merkle trees
the first tree is an operation log the
stores things like add an attestation
add an entity or add a revocation and a
local tree log can prove that it is
append only and it can approve it can
prove that values exist within it this
gets then turn into a sparse Merkle tree
map and Merkle tree maps can prove that
values do not exist within them and also
that values exist within them of course
because it's a Merkel tree it has a root
hash and we take this root hash of the
map and we insert it into a third Merkel
tree log and so every version of the map
that was used to satisfy queries is
captured in this log and this final log
as normal can't prove that it is append
only and values exist within it
the auditors connect to the storage
servers and replay the operation log to
construct a replica map and a
corresponding replica map route log and
they they then communicate with the
clients to share the the route of the
mat root log so the clients will send
this to the auditors and the auditors
will compare that with what they have
reconstructed this has two things the
first thing is it ensures the object map
is properly derived from the operation
log so we know that the operation log is
now both append-only and it has an
anything removed on it and we ensure
that every client is seeing the same
data structure so there's a family of
attacks where service might give
internally consistent views but
different to different clients we
prevent that class of attacks by talking
with the auditors periodically and it
doesn't need to be often it can be daily
or weekly so in summary the unequivocal
log drive map stores encrypted data
stations and entity objects and
revocations and it uses cryptographic
proofs of integrity which force the
server of operators to be honest or
being detected as dishonest much the
same model as certificate transparency
our our auditing however only requires
very infrequent communication between
the clients and the auditors wave is a
fully implemented system it's written in
go there's some crypto that's in C++
we've used various versions of it over
the course of three years securing over
200 devices and their associated
services in 20 buildings across multiple
organizations and multiple namespaces so
we've had a lot of experience with that
and and the challenges that arise when
trying to secure that kind of that kind
of workload and it's pretty fast the
graph changing operations we use sort of
grant permissions or change the graph
are very fast by UI standards granting
permissions takes 45 milliseconds which
is about the length of a perceivable
mouse-click for a user and then the hot
path operations like proof building and
verifications are very fast in our
experience we find that most proofs are
less than five at two stations long and
we find that proof building is less than
fifteen milliseconds and verifying that
proof text less than eight milliseconds
so it's very compatible with existing
systems
so in conclusion wave is a decentralized
authorization system that uses that
office transitive delegation stores the
graph and global storage and encrypts
these at the stations hiding the graph
and it can be used in place in most
traditional authorization systems thank
you
thank you question well I actually thank
you we've been looking for this for a
long time as the original author of
Radiesse and I was involved in spooky
and have you taken a look at how this
could be to available to improve DNS
sack all of these in one you know an
application this is could be widespread
use yeah thank you yeah we do see that
there are sort of many use cases that
you could drop this into many places
where people have stuck a traditional
ization server that you can drop this
into and you gain a bunch of useful
features from it yeah but you haven't
actually looked at expanding your field
yet no so we've actually used this in a
bunch of different places I used the IOT
example running through because it's
quite challenging you cross
administrative domains but we've used
this to secure sort of G RPC api's on
Web Services and we've used this in many
places that you've that would you
traditionally does it handle loops well
like if the HVAC also needed to be
responsible to yeah yeah the loops loops
are fine the graph doesn't actually have
to be a dag you can have loops alerts
they end up being not traversed when
you're doing discovery so it doesn't
cause any problems yeah okay thank you
oh you have a question you got a minute
so about the storages are basically
using the miracle trees aren't the
auditors basically the like the central
authority because without the auditors
in place different clients could see
different things yeah so they can be
what we did to ensure that this wasn't
the case is that the the actual contents
of the map are just the hashes of the
object so when you're constructing the
replicas it's actually several orders of
magnitude smaller than the full data
structure so it's very lightweight to be
an auditor anyone can download the
auditing software started to run them up
so we're assuming that there's gonna be
multiple auditors run by different
people who are unlikely to collude okay
thanks a lot
[Applause]