appreciate Carolina after
speed very hard act to follow I
about me
network double impact
armored secure ok
smart transport were
optical cable us
things like that the penetration testing
I do get into that when I'm ball
30 that's rude architecture on the pen
testing
mostly with this presentation is about
everyone's talking about the all these
advanced threats
talking about help
whenever seems like whenever somebody
gets hurt their plane
really when are getting school
basic just come over term be
to go and lay out this is what people
really you might have some
has a and skills in some cases come in a
lot of the places I go
an broke real basic things
per million really drive home tried
presentations trust relationships
one more mister
export trust relationships
interdependencies
you can take on for
law report in
loves because flatter
hard decide
defaults here's networks rolled out
for smart brought words at the top
control top services
were you CP server your policies are
lawful intercept IP based
art triple servers right
indication
the automated provisioning my up
tell with till provisioning for smart
grid the whole point there
is for from roles connected
from you know all the way smart what
happens there
goal
pay your bill talk to the billing server
the billing server doesn't talk to the
SCADA system around your smart
toward build system
smart power
Notre which is great but the problem
is you see these different layers
different layers we'll go from there
were managed
transferred inside
whatever the core transport network all
the way down into distribution
aggregation where passive optical
words the
in some cases two homes or
traditional side
the problem
wanna drive home was example have all
that
into integration that's available
workflows somebody target network
take over in bigger concern of
educator really gotta go mill now those
the remote access is in her going to
exist
build words because you which
manufactured
ASI typically is cool
to Remo access
to their system application times
organizations
this infrastructure about Sun
launcher you drop your system you can
drop in your
your motorhome Windows box straight to
the Internet bypass all sacred
you soon drop
secure course you get
internal text where
escape the
reference architectures us federal
system
skied talking
manufactured yes
but the ANC standard architecture
we should words secure
pictures corporate word drop
skate the year old
to core
scale work with rows down
next level your RT appeals
devices actually control rule with
camp relays flip switches
X on down
now this looks Rivermark text and
Portugal firewalls between
the corporate network and stadiums
a person till space
when I saw you talk about power
generator talk about the distributors
doesn't exist
the firewalls between
corporate networks in this guide I'm
starting to see the fire was put in
place
record com what you comin
is would
NT 4.0 multi home
one leg in the corporate network 1
is there see talk to some %uh the head
promise me firewall red
firewood
just still
so we'll see things like that and at the
same time
holes
architectures over to the right in the
center the
vendors won't back toward
operators will happen is there if it's
no
legacies their party bowed not still in
this thing
modems USB modems they'll be there
covered in dust hopefully they're being
disabled when they're not
hopefully some remembered
hopefully there's a law
Richard
what will happen many cases marxism
to come so free access
work in
the big concern heavy
unchallenged especially build-up
access or even than whose
control make their own
mater
taxes other water determined their trust
their sister
their trust relations you're inheriting
whatever here
you know how this connection some
questions
Tom no appt
required this is real life
I was talking to you was working
nato transport was working on the Metro
Ethernet
network resolves network issues between
locations
mister talking manager ask to me but you
skated
announcement questions of
yours I'll with architect faster
ok keep with his
no password border
NC head
SCADA system him never
us much all
I'm its
all the free soul you for the low
you need help II
up its to go do some charity work and
I'm not so we
help you it is plain mustard dollar with
I need to go back and say
this is after hour earlier in the day
already had a corner because I because I
discovered on their firewall
that their billing system its it secured
the billing system put in a cloud-based
system for me drop
firewall I you can't make this up
the firewall rules for permit
than only thing protecting
internal what they were doing no static
translations ago then a gold
free the inside about it
about you the paddles works
floor this
like like I said by stop be
base also talk about the
with the basics and
the conversation with the manager
profession
burn ask mister offer my services
to free
would expensive result
is like we think this is secure really
challenged
consider question Arctic
but
the part of the conversation to me
the guys at work for because when they
go hun
on red with when they go honey
stay thank you very monitor this case
her phone
however things up
things brings old
if possible or survivors
Marion
with till really serves surf
transport smart it's good
this is example network management
architecture
for source of
management system
if you have a specific management system
is designed for specific
or column
PubMed been installed
has no clue
take your
integrated
work so that you can talk or protocol
trends side
or into your network architecture
with with northbound faces up
we called operations for systems which
other work
applications furthered
phase 2 enterprise business support
here's an architecture
example users likes utilities
in many cases where smart
were of ever since the polls
and Cicero now for the got all the band
with were also wanna go harder
boys cable TV all these additional
services
polls 1 by the way they can
bonds twenty years used
both energy something's
where the house all switch you have
remains also say
primers back
salsa which office just
report back what's interesting is the
the vendors always walls access
these networks because drop class
college class polls Sol switch
both switches run a hose were used to
running power
could allowed
business bonds will happen
or are gone come in
top cover for me thing their normal
internet connection bpm as
that's great that's okay as long as it
bigger or
traveling technician whose who is
plugged his laptop
telco till every other hostile
work in the world where travels lord
knows what plastic
in when you call be around your
were your secure critter
whatever's on his laptop spread
were I I have personally seen
these networks hi
hi some kind with APT
SSH brute force
is a report on relentless
nonstop this is a report with the lose
they will remote access wherever their
travels
the field engineers are when you call
help
said stay hard
a seal specific location can access
sir have it open where the courage
well if they can reach you so can remain
there look
would for what I've to what i've seen
is when they depart they'd only found
out about
buckles and these cases the these
connections some cases may be more or
very connection what time they only
found out after
some called sees
another example
just heels
stirs Escala
Ring Pop there was a time for ago became
serves about a region green
networks geographic help
was walls
started architect
cell someone throughout this
architecture sry
here so basically
which for SEC for emergency
11 services you have re redundancy
phones were
so what happens if you're for the source
business which
farmer RAM between
lawyers geographic first
architecture calls rod which one strand
one terminated just
from both let's go to class back
problem see this person some copper
sure was wrong art
took upon themselves the plan Coast
polls Cape
two cities are down until
armored trucks from 23 states over
to go response turf whole
10 APT there
but persistent
here's another architecture
basic basic architecture
Togo were
they're offering all kinds services even
offering
transport services to smart there in the
boys are in
service say
except billing system want
whoever does the billing system trusted
no matter how smart you are much
of place miles
work is not secured yes well as
wasn't this case with system
so their extra
all bill paying system
internal bill i'm talking about.
real you name it it's all on this one
system conduit all the way through the
firewall
to the system Road this case got some at
the time record
pursued box
polio the system from there
last stop but what's really scary again
trust relationship center immigration
that billing system how things operate
with make an order
all those all
intelligence great for
over to the right into other systems the
operations
work they weren't or
those top services are set from existed
to more work from that
to go were dominoes just fill
I have never said
taxes please stop
or to stop
but after that after
that happen we always good
architect a recommendation we recommend
tradition
knows split up web services
better based architecture
for online services those system
one or this is secure so we packed
get pictures screenshots taxes which
over
wofford's take the whole those
will make you feel better
billing system understand thousands
who'd
basics no
no flame stocks nations spaces
good telco of
what's services boys
cable TV your by there
which really here
is the transport middle said
strong network architecture there
they break RFC from plans if
the Lancer vid cable TV
I P IPTV multicast
cable channels over were
change with I discovered
as a result as I discovered to me
channel change very very fast they
program ace so the
its Baltic it's more cast hardware
is good him
did cast
or fired so
to give it to them this offer over
what would happen
AXD X provision
internet boys sp
service thousands of users
a provision that over
work though is iPic
traffic because the way design
Harbor automatically start so I get the
call
pairs of sales Cajun
hole transport network dole's this
transport
Worcester on the road own leaders there
followers are trying to get a network
connection
start rights from the one place work
phrases package ever see
I G p ASI capsule
was crazy figured out what was going on
just basic to go
together work stocks
here's an example this was
recent in South America friends
experienced their case
some
this case
people two different cases
this occurred years ago because they did
not have
strong control control management
plane separation services architected
were so that the control plane
security lockdown monitor properly
an individual was able to right scripts
target older so 10 the gas called relief
packet inspection monitoring
capability secured
subscribers self
before thousands sir
the other guy they did not have
monitoring
monitor phones switch slide
realize what happened 6,000 what
happened this case the gym
pop so hours backdoor
passwords secure though
access to management should
so the guy was able to get in there
start changed
ask record were
you
try science ventures
his website to the customers
switch this is
this is a strange voicing this once
again this goes back to the whole
walking down the Control
services all the way from
inner job the core
distribution all the way down to
scrubber
word all
in this case enterprise Corporate
broadband customer
starts the we're
Jeep legacy
be because role router bits
floor
have hot customer problem past route
water put in place so pool
for back in place resources like this
resentful hard
OC 380 connection
pretty much all work
think has was really interested so
somebody go pop hope it was peace
some customer
employees this location
sophistication starter sit in this
traffic directly
legacy BGP router to see people
17 calls crash
taking a lot of services reserves
because I get the world hurry the router
control plane was not logged so someone
like an internal subscriber
user should
basic
here's one game
back on the vendors that utility when
this happens
when used to build
his head terminations see
yes which is a fancy cable router talk
to you
so as its terminated DSL
router turns into a broad accessor
Cable Guy to see tsk cable terminations
me just talk to it's very important
though
who is this a router cake
faces so they're doing the
router this vendor milled
bpm connection router there's for
project that they had back
ralph is what turns out looks like they
got
through that first relationship
whoever pop road crossing pop
billing system integration the locals
time I wasn't
picture about all things
court
rocks the guys drop
once a until review after served
said
my question
so still myself today whoever God
which assisted
established I have not seen this
along this is would
concern we're secured
networks testing works tried
our customers better secure one concerns
I solved
cases if they're if they're able to
if because
how these cases architect
was the stop somebody from attacking
service with you till you're 80
opening of after one
utility Tiger networks stop
going back back used to west into
another
vendors network cases long drop
the same no problem there's no
segmentation
work it's all cool everybody's pack back
source connected as applied
mean if you have a legacy
were if word go back up
Laird
to sing yells
to layer to segmentation
control ability for sir inside
there's a real world scenarios 0
transport in this case were
really good were performed really well
element management system
network specifically for their heart it
was really nice
the customer to
the hardware really easy for the
customer point click
were problem had more people
Paul inside the company with the
organization was so into
the guys who Eunice goals security
devices
understood the gym
stole I'll be home
server call transport network
as over half a million dollars invested
secured harbors and somebody discovered
assisted SSH
Forster somebody else owns the call
transport for the whole were doesn't
matter
happy secure if you're there where to
secure
things like is really get back to
problem
top-down
security policy how things are good
if you don't bring in your system
application bring
network service online here state
security policy
Michael here
sample architecture
reference for plane
yes armored here's an example
in were architecture for managing
could be
all the services same pop segmentation
3 to protect
were I want to suggest
experience seen very strong focus if
this is the way
Arctic work go to
two-factor authentication strong
emphasis on
everything when it comes to you
accessing anything
for monitor question some really strong
anything out there
happens at you to see
because summers commander
commoner is a good chance where
resources
management here's what I prefer
realistic for budget culture
person his culture network devices or
price cultural
sometimes hard but in this case
more secure way
were is to use and obey connections
terminal server
a lot of the routers and switches today
servers management HP
Cisco devices
the first have a ser
inside there
going to be jump did
the whole were infrastructure that way
network of seems system
yes logs extremely secure
so that someone can SwitchEasy this
this is over get back into the
enterprise man
myself this is a top working following
architect
can be repaired this you should
with this is I
if you plug into a network today
typical words the top
top years if it's an it's going to be
intelligent its core support Voice over
IP
schools a poor quality of service your
all
stern for secure Baltic
successor I have yet to see top dollar
words were basic
where two problems week
physical access were we ever
ever see
there too has been properly secure you
can see
spanning tree happening over there were
you can are poisoning missus are poised
top dollar name-brand
you have poor secures dynamic
inspection one other secured
to stop or or where
it's there another one it's always there
really good
work no help done routers
place whenever we see redone rounders we
see
first top
if they've redone routers replace
whether it's a juicer p
your your the it's always
if your gonna it was really no password
between the router or there's a password
is clear text force fall to turn on
authentication
one of how much more
would if
but they never always clear text
georgetown
if it's Cisco networking Cisco
is another ball to cash in on the wire
go
you don't even have to be
X scale download something like
course all importer were short capture
star porn change parameters the
the text if you pack created
router check some replied
service or goes up
rivers which this reference which
typically you're not provide
service typically all the switches
for faster where Spain trees decide
to the user's but there's been no
protections put in place like are
stop somebody from with just very novice
just basic security download
backtrack start you're seeing store
themselves on the wire with our were
for Ridge switched stop
kill switchboards down
so if they're not from for decide
see
number of career
new jobs Cape
switches in their cases performers
secured stop
I see a lot of stop
network itself change were
when you'd
whenever greater ways
as for the a break operating system
operator some things to look at
to stop to threats
about prop
so that you can isolate from
relationships inside
that you can go back said ACLs
something to make yourself aware if
you're not aware
option to problems tracking down
problem panels are coming were
yousef
see server support options what option
is whenever users
CP request will inject into the header
chasing bus
interface port number is coming from so
the
track down very quickly were their
proper their problem
tree dresses source very large campus
University toward looking
where to workflow work and
really good
understand you're in for inflow the
trust relationship
why would your printer to print server
Jordan service for that matter
need how traffic flows out but we go
of turn on
let iraq because
bottom line
what us what I'm pushing really hard
is Tim everybody's talking about wilde
applications agree
store we really need to go
for while just work trust relationships
if something's communicating have heart
document
what to communicate wide doesn't
communique Hills here three layer 2
profit lands
to walk down the first relationship
step further
if you're yes if they're smarter
flexibility yes to go
monitor while the flow
frost should be talkin
anything else data said trust shoe
thrown at work
probably would make the
monitor user that's what I today
question
yeah
I wasn't wasn't marker
what I'm where the Cisco we're Cisco
Partner
I know Cisco hope
I know the ice
there may be some others hours
we Francisco Cisco
buses
of may be smothered
the question
well people people see
disrupted us
a phone rings all done I was answering
the phone
as I was driving
Carolina mountains problem problem
with the reason
probably see really major disruptions
because it's have these things are
happening
not happening at the core the stuff is
not happening
history your sprint
works securities
understand things
offers see these things happen very low
so when I would
go back to work that your man the
network
mange more work with vendors
start asking Park West about about the
accesses halfback up
ask the hard questions just no economics
are pushing them
quite honestly cases take
the better
about was trying to make their stuff
like everybody else p
green works reporting is working
work buildings were good
customers work
the clicker the red
system hope
good information is
questions so stud
or nor requirements roll over the
customers
worked free access
fraud
policy drop
systems
what happens with us talk about
organization
like your 3 he'll support
fingers do the walking that business
card
trust
hope
appreciated