[Music]
[Applause]
ladies and gentlemen welcome the
moderator of the next session Catelynn
Koch so good afternoon everyone good
afternoon to our audience here in
Bratislava and to our many viewers
watching us around the world on Facebook
live I know as you watch that video it's
a bit troubling right so as someone
declared that we're living in a post
truth world of alternative facts where
some for their particular agendas what
is not to believe what we know not to
believe our own eyes not to believe what
we read or see or hear and in our
mainstream media but instead to believe
what someone has tweeted what someone
has pushed out on Facebook now
researchers at the University of
California took a look at a five-week
period in the fall of 2016 in the run-up
to the u.s. election from September 16th
through October 21st they found that
nearly 20% of political tweets were not
generated by human beings but by BOTS in
in France the Oxford University did a
study they looked at the run-up to the
election last month they found that a
quarter of a quarter of political links
that were shared were based on false
information I mean I could go on and on
but I want to get to the terrific panel
that I have here to help us look at this
issue of being fake news disinformation
misinformation propaganda and what kind
of a threat does opposed to the world's
democracies I'd like to start by first
of all introducing my friend Michael
Chertoff executive chairman and falco
founder of the Chertoff group and of
course former Secretary of Homeland
Security the United States James
Stevenson news editor on the end there
for the BBC Gabriela Shea she is
Facebook's head of public policy for
Central and Eastern Europe March of
post-lab who is Google's head of public
policy and government relations
for Central and Eastern Europe and
finally Christopher Walker vice
president for studies and analysis with
a National National Endowment for
democracy in Washington welcome all
before I go to questions I would like to
pull the audience looking back say five
years five years ago either in print or
online how many of you read a news story
now I'm not talking about satire but a
news story that you discovered was
actually false false and deliberately
misleading how many of you five years
ago okay not too many all right let's
say within the last year how many of you
have read a news story online in print
whatever that was fake news okay wow
that is a significant difference that's
unfortunately not surprising mr.
secretary I'd like to go to you first
how great a threat do you think that
this misinformation disinformation
propaganda the explosion and today is it
to our nation's or our world's
democracies the u.s. in and around the
world well it's a complicated answer so
first let's define what we mean by fake
news and there are stories that are
slanted with bias or where the inference
drawn you might think is a false
inference and you know an example for
example might be in the area of climate
change
some people might regard a story that
says there's no correlation between the
weather and climate change and there is
no climate change as a fake story there
are people who actually believe that
then you get into issues of stories
where there's it's completely fabricated
and fabricated with the purpose which is
what I think we mean by fake news and
then you get to what I think is the most
extreme example which is literally
altering a document or photograph and
putting it out there so it's a forgery
or otherwise a manipulated actual quote
piece of evidence so how much of a
threat is at the democracy well in one
way we've lived with this since the
birth of democracy I'm going to go back
to the history of the u.s. shortly after
the founding of the country it was not
uncommon to have scurrilous newspapers
affiliated with a
little parties and they would make
allegations of sexual impropriety or
theft or whatever against the political
opponent of their patron and the
Republic survived what I think has
become different here is two things one
is the social media revolution and
Twitter and other platforms that allow
the dissemination of information have
dramatically a multiply the number of
entry points for even people who want to
deliberately use propaganda secondly
it's made it possible to curate what you
see so that you don't have to see
conflicting or contradictory information
so there's much more potency but is it a
threat well and so the third thing is
you can actually operationally interfere
with for example the police by putting
out false Twitter information that
actually gets people to for example wind
up creating a traffic jam so the LAT the
list would certainly be a threat to the
ability to maintain order on the other
two I would say it's a threat only if
people allow their ability to
discriminate between what is true and
false to erode it's okay to read a false
story if you have the critical ability
to understand why it's false but if you
wind up training yourself only to read
the news you want to read and that
supports your point of view then we do
get into an area that's worrisome
Gabriela you're the CEO of Facebook Mark
Zuckerberg has long insisted that that
Facebook and I know Google believes the
same thing here you are neutral
technology platforms and so you really
don't have a responsibility for the
content that people put on your site
your platform but at the same time you
know and then in after the election in
2016 he still maintained there's a
pretty crazy idea crazy idea right that
Facebook could have actually impacted
the election results in the United
States but then in December Facebook
didn't about vais fais and said okay
well now we're going to take action
against this so good what happened
explain the about-face and what are you
doing we still feel that we are a
neutral technological platform
but it doesn't mean that we do not have
responsibilities and we do not shy away
from our responsibilities and in the
past half year we've been putting a lot
of resources and working very hard to
tackle the issues of a fake news on our
on our side the fake news is not a
facebook specific issue it's a societal
issue but we happen to be the biggest of
information sharing platform so of
course our responsibilities are huge in
the past couple of months we rolled out
several products what if I just counted
very quickly so that now users can
report fake news they can report
disputed news ones and user stories
flagged as a disputed story that is
ranking higher that other users when
they see it shared they are aware that
it's a disputed story they can see the
links connected to the disputed story
which provided the link provided by the
fact checker with the alternative
opinion there are several other products
some are in the pipeline some are
already out there but what is more
important and what we do alone on our
platform is that we are collaborating
with other players because as I said
this is not just Facebook issue
you re finding it's working I mean I've
heard some reports that once something
is disputed it actually gets more shares
I don't have this is a test phase of our
products that are rolled out in some
countries like in the u.s. in the UK in
Germany in France so we don't really
know how the product works and we really
want to have the feedback and see
whether that's really the option that
adduct will be the solution pretty much
feel that there with the solution will
be a layered there is no one bullet that
can kill the whole issue of fake fake
news and false news but will have to
have several several options
that's I'd like to go to Martha come on
go to Google you are often described as
the financial engine of fake news
because for those who don't know how it
works what what tends to happen is that
that people who are trying to spread
false news will
spread it first on Facebook often
setting up false accounts not not run by
actual humans but hundreds and hundreds
of them get people to click on the
sensational news stories go to the web
and share them and then they go to the
website and click and if that particular
website has subscribed to Google Adsense
then with every click on the website on
that story the purveyor of it makes my
and some of they made quite good money
right so but we saw that this was going
on all through 2:16 during the u.s.
election we saw it happening during a
French election and they seem to be
operating with complete impunity what is
Google doing if anything address that's
very briefly I could just say that this
is this is fake news but the problem is
more complicated we are aware of the
mechanism and what we do is every single
year we apply hundreds of changes to our
algorithm when and in which we're trying
to prevent that we're trying to identify
those websites that are aimed at missing
misrepresenting the information and this
is this an ongoing process only last
month we've announced our new change of
guidelines when we do not allow to plant
our ads on those on those websites and
we can we can be a reactive we are
responsible for being reactive and we
see that as the as the way forward but
we also see that that we're only part of
the solution and whatever whatever we're
going to end up with on our side doesn't
mean that the whole concept of fake news
or misrepresenting information will
disappear from the web or overall from
the from the from the from the society
that's why that's why one of the
solutions above all the tech ones that
you can read about in in in the media on
our blogs and and I could leave them
here we really call for changing how we
look at education and we education very
educating our societies and if you know
it's like digital skills that that few
years back everyone would say coding is
what we what we all need to do but
now turns out that critical thinking in
the interaction with the with the weapon
and the internet seems to be the one
that we should all get to know James I
know it's got to be frustrating for you
you come from the media background that
I do and there are a lot of restrictions
on a traditional news organization what
you print has to be factual it has to be
accurate we're breaking all and you can
be sued what do you think there are some
that say Facebook for instance as the
largest disseminator did you realize
that Facebook is the largest
disseminator of news in the entire world
that that makes them qualify as a media
organization that they should have a
news editor that they should abide by
the same standards the BBC does CNN does
well I think that that does I think
you've already heard that that that's
contested ground and that the social
media platforms argue and continue
continue to argue that they are carriers
rather than broadcasters and I think
that is coming under some challenge now
and you can see some of these responsive
measures it's they've moved on as you
were suggesting moved off the territory
of simply saying it's not nothing to do
with us and now to some of these
measures which suggest perhaps there is
a little bit of a shift going on but I
was interested in the secretary Chertoff
where you started with trying to tease
out some of the distinctions perhaps
with with fake news because I think it
is a very useful concept and it's
particularly useful in drawing people's
attention to the difficulty of
inaccurate and misleading news but I do
think it covers a pretty wide spectrum
of things from people who are in
Macedonia famously deliberately you put
it pumping out full stories for
commercial gain actors who are putting
it out for political purposes and I
think we've seen that perhaps well
certainly alleged to be happening in the
in the French presidential context
although I think Sputnik for example
denied that that was happening but but I
think there's another thing which I
think we need to be wary of which is
people casually using the phrase fake
news meaning news they don't really like
and you've done all transference yes I
think that's a different kind of focus
but as I understand
you had accurately characterized just
now what what the situation is with
advertising revenue around social media
posting so I don't think it's helpful to
kind of use that as a fend off when you
do see it increasingly in with with
actors politicians perhaps who are in a
corner and they and they they're
learning this habit of saying fake news
whereas what they mean is Inconvenient
Truth Chris I'd like to ask you what do
you think I mean you have been studying
this and you work on the issue of
democracy and and the threats that that
our democracies in the world face should
we have been better ready for this
particularly in the United States when
when you look at states in nations in
this region in the Balkans and the
Baltic states they've been dealing with
this for years how is the u.s. caught so
flat-footed I would first answer that
the question you posed at the outset as
to whether this is a threat I think it's
a very serious threat the indicators
we've had over the years starting just
with a very clean date of a decade ago
in Estonia when a cyber attack was
launched against that country was one of
the first real clear indicators to all
of us that things were changing and I
think this is reflective of how
dramatically the media landscape has
changed you polled the audience at the
outset and it was probably a factor of
20 to 1 where the hands went up for
those who had consumed fake news in the
last year and I think the the changes
that we're experiencing now have been a
long time in the making but they're
manifesting very abruptly at this point
I think we could have and should have
been better prepared I think we're still
slow on a number of levels to recognize
the depth of this challenge both the
changes to the economics of the of the
news industry the way in which content
is delivered and the way in which malign
actors can participate in the
manipulation of that content Facebook
itself through a white paper it recently
released acknowledged this and so I
think I'd make that required reading for
those who haven't seen it yet because
it's a very important document but it's
reflective of the depth of the challenge
and I
I fear that in the absence of really
concerted collaboration across sectors
urgently that we are not going to be
able to meet this challenge because the
resources that are coming in for example
from Russia in this fight are enormous
and they're concerted and they're
applied in a unitary way and this is
something we haven't been focused on
sufficiently until very recently before
we go to the audience and I do want to
bring you in here real quickly I wanted
to go to secretary Chertoff to explain
to us this new research initiative on
the part of the globe SEC Policy
Institute it's called D for defending
democracy in the digital domain you
remember the International Advisory
Board talk to us about that what are the
solutions well I think as we've
identified just in the in the discussion
here you know the term fake news can
cover a lot of different things and
solutions engage a lot of different
possibilities at one end I've heard
people argue what we ought to just stop
fake news on the two countries that will
be the first ones to sign up to that
will be Russia and China because their
idea of fake news is CNN BBC or anything
that says something bad about the
leadership on the other hand there's the
view that some take that platforms are
totally neutral it's nothing more than
like a highway on which people drive
back and forth and just like the toll
taker on the highway isn't responsible
for what somebody does when they pass
through the toll and if they go rob a
bank afterwards it shouldn't be the
platform operators we're looking at a
lot of different things I think we want
to do the research and really understand
the phenomenon and I think we want to
look at solutions that are focused on
such things as can you attack the
financial incentives that generate fake
news can you distinguish automated
efforts to surge fake news that don't
deserve free speech protection because
BOTS don't get free speech how do you
look at the issue of anonymity
should that be something that's barred
or not barred to be said that that
becomes a tool used in order to prove a
fake news and then how would you deal
with the operational confusion that
could be caused in
of a crisis if people started to use
Twitter to put out information about for
example where there's an outbreak of a
serious illness or where there's a big
problem on the highway and that actually
had impact on the ability to respond so
I don't think that we come into this
with answers but I do think we come into
with a desire to be clear about what the
issues are and to make sure that the
cure isn't worse than the disease
because we could do a lot of damage to
democracy if we invited censorship in
the name of defending democracy let's go
to the audience okay we have a hand back
here or even mic back here Allen Riley
Institute for statecraft the question I
got to ask is surely there was there are
a lot of problems and these are new
challenges there is a lot of history
here which suggests that we've been here
before
and we can successfully with it the
greatest example of this is perhaps
Goebbels in the 1930s Nazi propaganda
was supposed to undermine the ability of
the West defend itself that this is
gonna be a terrible Fifth Column egg
against the Western alliance it was a
problem they had new techniques they had
new approaches they were using new
technology but within three or four
years the western lands had worked out
how to respond and by 1943 1944 all
population of Europe was only listening
to British and American channels and by
1944 there only the German population to
find out what was really going on was
listening to British and American
channels so what's your question and my
point is is that yes of course this has
happened yes we didn't expect it well
surely the point is here it's now a
matter of responding working out the
response and the history suggest that we
can actually come back and effectively
deal with this and whether it's through
authentication and all the other methods
which we mentioned we can deal with this
there is actually a history here of
saying we tend to panic we then try and
work out how to deal with it and we do
deal with it can we drop it
Chris do you think well I think one of
the distinctions today and Michael
Chertoff alluded to this I think the the
velocity
the degree of saturation the intimacy
the ubiquitous the ubiquity of new media
and social media presents some slightly
different challenges and for malign
actors who are figuring these things out
very quickly now the the ability for us
to inoculate ourselves I think is is a
far higher degree of difficulty I still
think it can be done and what you're
suggesting is you need more political
solidarity and more resources invested
into these things in a more meaningful
way that's that's another part of this
discussion it's very relevant to it and
maybe too far afield for the purposes of
this session but I think that's part of
it
but I think we can meet the challenge
the question is whether political
leaders and the democracies have an
authentic commitment to meeting that
challenge I think by the way you're
right and I'm reminded of the fact that
in the u.s. when you go to the grocery
store they usually have newspapers at
the checkout counter like the National
Enquirer and the globe are lovely
tabloids right that have headlines like
aliens inhabit you know Barack Obama's
head or but nobody no one believed well
but so the point is that but the point
is no one believes it and that's because
we know the source and when you're a kid
you're taught by your parents that if
it's a National Enquirer or the
worldwide globe you don't take it
seriously
likewise with gurbles the challenge I
think with social media particularly
when it comes in the form of what
appears to be an ordinary person so it's
word of mouth is that it may come with a
wrapping of credibility because the
sourcing makes it look as if it's just a
friend of yours or just an ordinary
person in question here and if you would
identify yourself please sure sure
thanks very much
I'm honored Feinstein from the wilfried
martens Centre for European studies in
Brussels and one of the proud sponsors
of this event so I would like to focus
on the question of the optimal balance
between government and civil society in
the response to disinformation you know
with for the
for the Kremlin everything is clear it's
it's top-down right it's from the
Kremlin to the TV channels to the last
troll in the 12 factories and BOTS and
whatever that's vertical as one form of
what they call vertical now I would tend
to believe our response should be
bottom-up right but based on civil
society based on think tanks political
parties networks individuals volunteers
and all this what precisely when you say
body oh you mean yeah and then but which
role is to be played by governments and
state institutions and international
organizations like the European Union
NATO in in responding to this
information so without replicating the
the vertical top-down approach of the
Kremlin so when you say responding to do
you mean by maybe Germany is proposing
fines for those who don't fight no sir
you just you're you say propose are you
proposing that we respond in kind
my question is what is the right balance
between government legislation and
people hired by governments on the one
hand and civil society you know on the
other hand what's the proper response of
a free society
okay um who wants to take that guy right
well let's let someone else martyr
Gabriela Smith on I think that the issue
cannot be tackled unless there is a
healthy media ecosystem that is one side
and the other side of the issue is what
we cover by fake news and false news
catchable face and when we are talking
about information operations how that
false news is amplified and how we allow
that being amplified when we are talking
about how the media ecosystem that's
where how the different players like
social media like publishers can work
together but I'm pretty sure that here
there is a big role for governments as
well to play because there is a changing
way how people read news how journalists
write news and how the news is
disseminated of course I don't think
that rushing into regulation
is the right way to do because it's an
extremely complex situation I'm pretty
sure that it's not only Facebook who is
debating extremely heavily that what is
false news whether a piece of satire
that there's a piece of sexual piece
which has in an opinion ended is a fake
news but or something that is true today
and tomorrow something happens or
yesterday's news became false news how
to deal with all those situations and
every time this is a freedom of speech
of someone and it's pretty sure that's
not for operators technical companies to
become the arbiter of shoes there are
billions of users out there and the
billions of users are bombarded with
pieces of information and we need to
help them how to read that news how to
interpret that how to make sure that
they get it better it's whether it's a
false news or not publishers are doing
that since centuries when they are
writing pieces when they are editing
newspapers now we have to educate the
users and there's a huge role for the
government to step up on news literacy
education James I think you had
something just to build on the point you
are making about the the journalistic or
news environment overall I think that is
an important point and I think that
there's a place for in some ways perhaps
trying to address the point you're
raising I think that there is a is some
space which is neither of the two things
you say the top down or the bottom up
but a healthy independent media sector
plural media sector is a big part of the
equation here because if you don't have
trusted news sources people rely on
untrustworthy and untrusted news sources
and we've commissioned some research
which indicates that the UK experience
has been somewhat different to the u.s.
experience I think we all know and part
of the reason we're having this
conversation is the the wake-up call
that people got because of events in the
US election but the UK u.s. experience
was somewhat different and it seems to
have been different in too
principal respects is that we have quite
a strong thriving popular newspaper
culture still so that that's a source of
information that people are familiar
with going to and that those businesses
are migrating online I think the the
issue for them is that is the
sustainability of their business models
and I think there's a whole again
probably outside the scope of this
session but there's a whole concern
there about the people who have
traditionally provided a lot of
trustworthy news are in some sort of
financial difficulty but the other and
closer to home for me is public service
broadcasters because that is a an
intervention and perhaps you'd expect me
to say this but I still believe it that
the BBC in the in the in the British
landscape and to a lesser extent through
its international operations in in in 27
28 languages and growing that that
intervention is in itself part of the
equation because you have then a trusted
source I think you you then have the
issue of in this world digital world
we're moving into can people find their
way into trusted sources in the way that
they have in the past but I do think
that that it's sometimes been a little
bit of a Cinderella in the debate public
service broadcasting but I think it does
it does have a place Chris did you want
to add something cuz I know you and I we
had talked about and I misspoke earlier
I think it was 50 billion euro fine that
the Germans are are considering for any
platform social media networks that
didn't delete fake knows it we were
discussing how Ukraine has just last
week I think pulled the plug on all
Russian or they have decreed that it
should happen I don't know it's happened
yet all Russia in the social media
networks so to if I understood the
question correctly I think the challenge
for democratic societies is to marshal
the key elements of both civil society
the commercial sector the tech companies
and the appropriate role for government
which has to handle some of this either
in a regulatory fashion or in the
national security context which this is
very relevant to because there was one
wake-up call some feel it was the u.s.
election I think the annexation of
Crimea
eeeh and Russia's weaponization of
information to take territory was
principally an information war was a big
wake-up call and you had an enormous
response a very erupt abrupt response
from governments it was halting
piecemeal from civil society but civil
society has a role to play like memo 98
in Slovakia like globe SEC in helping
explain the issues to a wide range of
audiences governments have a role in the
more national security sphere and the
tech companies or the digital the modern
digital companies whatever we call them
today they have a role to to figure out
how they can make sure that politically
consequential information is reaching
audiences in a way that helps these
countries and doesn't undermine them are
you concerned Martha what you hear about
this government intervention regulation
pulling the plug so looking at the role
corporations should play this is a very
general question and I think this role
has been has been heavy revolving but I
still darg you that the role of a
company like Google is to provide best
possible services and encourage free
speech and I don't think that the fines
approach is necessarily the right
approach and part of the problem part of
the response as you as you put it in
your question it's already there and
when you think about what Internet
platforms brink on the positive side is
several sources of information when you
when you go to a search result you don't
only get fake news you may get of course
you may get one but you're gonna you may
also get different perspectives and also
what you get and this is something that
would not happen in under authoritarian
regimes that we saw at the very neo of
this session you you don't you didn't
have a chance to argue with that
and then Internet is also a place that
can give you an opportunity to
immediately respond so and there is
valuing that as well and that's also the
question - what - what mr. secretary
said before that what is what is fake
news and it's not always it's not always
false information sometimes it's
something that we find unpopular or or
something that we don't like don't that
we don't like as a community but
unpopular reviews are also important
to get visibility actually that raises a
question and I know you wanted to
address that Gabriela but speaking of
views you don't agree with that's a
concern that some in the in the
conservative you know organizations in
the United States are worried about as
face book talks about addressing this
problem because they feel like Facebook
is a liberal entity and therefore may
end up violating their free speech
rights by saying oh this is fake news
when it's really just conservative are
you know obviously Gabriela well I mean
either because I just wanted to address
that the journal law but yeah we can we
can take this this angle as well because
fake new or false news many times it's
not illegal lying is not illegal and
something that is a statement truth
statement for me it can be a false
statement for someone else there are
some soft lies that there are some great
areas as well to heat a lot of debatable
areas here when we try to define what is
for cross news so naturally we as
Facebook we want to be unbiased in a
neutral technological platform and only
enable people that they can communicate
with each other that they can connect
with their constituency that they can
debate with each other so that we want
empower people that they can have civic
engagement on our platform and that they
can that we can build an informed global
community of course naturally in the
debate there will be always people and
government who feel that we are not
doing enough or that we are siding with
the other side that means that we are
doing a good job because if nobody feels
that we are siding with someone else
that means that we are not unbiased so
we have to we have to stay there and we
have to be neutral on the German law I
feel really strongly about that because
that law says or that is not a lot
that's a bill there's a heavy debate
around that there are a lot of
international
human rights organizations selective
activities industry groups international
European and in Germany as well we're
contesting that bill because it is
extremely heavy-handed bill and it is
unproportional e restricting freedom of
speech it's and it puts a burden on
companies to make the judgement whether
something is legal or not legal
and whoever if you are dealing with hate
speech you know that hate speech issues
can be sometimes clear-cut most of the
time extremely layered and extremely
complex and no wonder why courts
traditional courts spends months to deal
with an issue and to get all the
background to know who is saying why
seeing what was the context what was the
environment technological platforms is
such a scale there's no ability for them
to do that when there are so huge fines
what do you think what will come what
will companies do when they are
threatened with such fines that they
will settle okay let's move everything
down that is coming closer to being
illegal and then that will mean that
these companies will take down much more
content that they have should've so yeah
I was going to say I mean I think and
this law in Germany would be a disaster
I mean first of all in the United States
this is classic violation of free speech
in the First Amendment and what you'd
rapidly get to the case were American
based companies which they were not
going to obey that and the United States
government would one would expect say to
the Germans excuse us but we're an
independent country you're not going to
regulate what our citizens can hear I do
think there are things platforms can do
though that are neutral for example you
can detect as you do with spam automated
postings and you can block that you can
change the financial incentive structure
that drives people to post fake news not
for pure political reasons but simply
for for financial gain and I think that
would have have an impact to you might
is a little trick you you might deal
with use of anonymity and either
separately cabin
anonymous postings or if you're for
example on Facebook you might enforce
the rule about people verifying their
identity when they go online to post or
you know it is actually you know Michael
Chertoff there you know me as opposed to
someone pretending to be me because part
of what I think that they're trying to
do with Facebook is make the reader
believe his friend believes this so it
gives it a false credibility so I think
there are things that can be done that
are neutral that don't get us into
dangerous places you know it's
interesting on the point of Facebook I
mean I personally just among my circle
of friends on Facebook and I go on there
every day I have seen a real explosion
in the number of people who are trying
to copy my friends identities and poses
them and I I don't know if they are
trying to send out fake news I don't
know if they are trying to exploit their
name and say hey I mean I'm Jane your
best friend I'm in Europe and I've lost
my passport please send me money but but
it you do see this increase in people
trying to pretend to be someone that
they're not but we have let me bring the
audience back and I think we have a
question in the front here yes hello my
name is Iman Hana my there is a
fascinating report by the Center for
international media assistance at the
net so Christopher Walker probably knows
about it that says that there is roughly
only 50 million dollars a year in
overseas development aid that goes to
media development and only a tiny
fraction like in a single digit that
goes to media and digital literacy so
very often we talk about the importance
of building the skills of the readers to
be able to you know detect what
potentially is fake news or unverified
information and median digital literacy
is of course wide but it's a tiny tiny
fraction of an already tiny fraction of
overseas development aid so there is
definitely room for improvement here but
the title is about the floor thank you
defending democracy in the digital
domain and the information revolution it
goes beyond fake news
so my question specifically is about
elections voter data and what can be
done with the voter data with a big data
generated by people's geolocalization
their preferences where they go online
and how it can be exploited for
electoral purposes in
to target specific voters there is a
total absence of regulation around
elections but what to do with the data
can parties by that that I use that data
and how and of course in some countries
the legal system is strong but in others
is completely absent that's a little bit
out of the fake news realm no but
anyways very mention of evolutionism
that's a great question but it is not
this initiative is not just about fake
news it's about defending democracy
against a wide variety of digitally
based press I think you identify a very
good threat first of all we obviously
are concerned about anybody tampering
with the actual mechanics of voting or
registering in in data second I'd be
concerned for example about an effort to
target particular communities with false
information about how you vote or where
you vote let's imagine for the sake of
argument someone wanted to suppress
voting among minorities of Latin descent
and they sent out tweet saying emergency
alert you're going to be deported if you
go to the polls I mean that could have a
real effect in election so I think
there's a wide variety of things which
need to be be solved differently and
finally I would say that again and we
shouldn't only view this as how do you
stop things but it's how do you promote
good understanding and critical thinking
about these things just to let just a
tack on it like it's just a just
directly to that point and the point you
raised we our main TV current affairs
flagship program not just 10 days ago
did a report looking at some of these
issues and highlighted for example micro
targeted messages to voters telling them
that Republicans were meant to vote on
one day and Democrats on another and
that's the kind of thing like fake news
and voters the impression and
manipulation of electoral data so these
things do come back together in some
cases alright and I could we have a
question right over here and identify
yourself please thank you very much Mira
Maxima international Republican
Institute and also organization which is
one of the proud sponsors of this event
the IRI has just conducted the opinion
polls thanks to the
of the NAD on the v4 and we were looking
into the how people I mean there are a
lot of global questions but one
questions are or one set of questions is
related to media and how people use
media and we have asked people we have
given them a list of media which are
normally bringing this information and
those who said that there are regularly
or partially using these media outlets
we ask them why and there was about 1/3
to 1/2 of these people said that they
are doing it because they find these
media outlets funny and they like those
those media and I'm just wondering if we
are having it bearing in a consideration
the change of the human nature thanks to
the technology I mean in policies is
that they are expecting instant
solutions to political challenges and in
terms of information I think this is or
they probably expect more fun and
amusement out of new so maybe that's a
question for Jamie's how do you entice
viewers readers back to the traditional
trusted news organizations and I think
it's especially difficult in countries
like mine the United States where 14
percent of Americans get their news from
social media 14 percent and I think it's
difficult also when you have a president
that's constantly criticizing
traditional trusted media sources
thereby really leveling the playing
field I think for faint news so I think
you see a little bit of an uptick for
traditional media when there's a hunger
for the journalism that they do and I
think you're seeing that now with the
New York Times in the Washington Post
and see it your old station CNN and
others so I think that's part of it but
I guess probably my longer-term shorter
answers your question was will be that
you don't this is a fundamental shift
that's happening and people will
continue to consume news on television
and radio and newspaper but what about
me more and more for generations because
I think you were saying this the u.s.
when you see the ads on American
television networks they are for a lot
of pharmaceuticals for ailments that you
develop when you're over 50 you don't
have a lot of 25
so I think I told CBS News four separate
for some demographics in the UK it's
already the case that social media and
particularly Facebook is the is the
principle as you touched on the
principle news platform and I think that
does raise a lot of questions for us as
an organization about how we make our
material available which which we do on
those platforms and it raises the kind
of questions that we're discussing about
what the responsibilities will be for
those platforms themselves in the future
anyone else so I just one quick word on
something Gabriela mentioned that's
relevant to this point on this notion of
it's not illegal to lie that's true but
I'll invoke foreign minister link
officious from Lithuania who says a lie
is not an alternative point of view and
I think this is something that we need
to be mindful of in the context of
journalism that's accountable and
responsible because I don't think James
has the ability to say I'm going to give
you two sides of the story one is it
evident live and here's something else
to consider and find the space in the
middle that's how propaganda works
actually so I think this notion of how
you ground the delivery of content in
this environment where you don't have
the sort of editorial scrutiny that was
de rigueur when the New York Times in
The Wall Street Journal in the
Washington Post were the were the agenda
setters not everybody was happy with
that arrangement this is the world we
live in today and so we can't go back
but I think these questions need to be
resolved because in the absence of them
were confronted with people consuming
news that is validated by trusted
friends who they get the news from who
looks very attractive it may be fun it
may be silly but these are really
serious issues now given where we are in
so many countries in the established
democracies thank you Chris I think we
had a question down here in the front
you've done down here in the front
please thank you for chips whiskey vie
cigarette inside let me just start with
a short remark that's part of a fake
news is something we all love and that
is the onion news you know the older
humor and maths that are widespread
we shouldn't battle them what we're
battling we're discussing is most most
often the
military or propaganda operations
military operations that influence
decision making and other democracies
and a delight of course we have a 20
century story of combating propaganda
that was rightly pointed out this story
brought up to the spotlight editors but
today and this is these are my questions
today there is no room for editors in
the digital media platforms like
Facebook all and so on or at least this
role is being diminished do you see in
the light of the bail in Germany that
it's not against American companies
it's against military operations by
Russia do you see that companies will be
pushed to introduce more algorithm or
editors or experiment with artificial
intelligence to somehow edit the content
that that is put online
what sort of interference to be is to be
expected from the from the companies and
second point the editors role was to
provide the balanced the critical
approach so we have we ensure that
people actually meet two opposing point
viewpoints instead instead we have a
very often
echo echo chamber in social media how
the technic tech companies may respond
to the echo chamber thank you Jamie okay
I'm our users don't want us to edit
their posts our users let it be ordinary
individuals citizens or let it be
publishing houses who are using our
platform to reach their audience
we are not editing the content but what
we see and I'm now coming back to the
force news issue that false news in
itself wouldn't be harmful
it gets harmful when it is disseminated
and what we see on Facebook when it
comes to information operations and
especially in pre-election period of
times that there are a lot of em
created fake accounts we call them fake
amplifiers because they are amplifying
the the message let it be false news let
it be misinformation that's information
or any other method these fake accounts
can be created by both by machines or
sometimes and what we see often in
Facebook by humans they speak language
they know the local political context we
work very hard in the past months to
tackle this issue and taking down fake
accounts not only it's easier when it's
automated it's much harder to tackle
those which are human created we are
using machine learning and human and
mechanical systems to tackle them and as
a result of that during the French
elections we have removed 30,000
accounts about it
the other issue that what can we do on
our platform with our users enabling
them to be able to reach quality
journalistic pieces and reading things
that we find out maybe you should not
read something that is entertaining you
are funny or misleading without the
source but read the other side as well
read the perspective and that's it
pretty that's something now that you do
right when you when you put the the
little triangle saying you know disputed
don't you you give some alternative
that's as well and there's another one
like the related articles that when
someone is you is reading an article
then we are popping up in the news feed
other articles which are about the same
topic but maybe giving different
perspectives we have to be extremely
sensitive here because people don't want
us to tell them what they have to read
we cannot guide them we can't download
you shouldn't have fun I should never
eat this piece it is a long journey and
I'm pretty sure that we have to work
together with the publishing houses they
might as well have to change the way and
adopt the way how they communicate how
they write news in in this new times
that's why we launched Facebook
journalism project to find the trusted
partnership that we might missing today
and to enable that vie together can find
a way how
users can reach multiple perspectives
and then make up their mind based on
that multiple perspectives
Marty did you want to chime in here just
just to add I think you rated a non
curated media are better together and
they give different opportunities and
they also if they also said different
factors for how we how we how we want to
consume information and I I don't think
that a fully AI automated processes are
anywhere on the horizon and I would be I
would be very cautious and I think
missing out on conceptual analysis when
free expression comes into the
discussion it's too much of a risk so
this this wouldn't be going any third
there and I think this is how we how we
how we look at it at Google went back to
the back to the back to the German bill
I don't I don't think that this is aimed
at war information as you'd like to call
it I think is a very short-sighted
proposal for how to fix a purely
political problem that is that is that
is that is that is currently happening
and there is there is a huge risk of a
very Galatian that is not going to solve
the problem of propaganda that is not
only on my problem having a question I'm
right make sure go ahead
my name is Barry Lynn and I run the open
markets program at the new America think
tank in Washington and I wanted to sort
of build off of something that James
said earlier which is that one of the
best ways to fight fake news is to
ensure the robust health of trustworthy
sources of news and information
now last December will Lewis who is the
publisher of Dow Jones which is the
publisher of the Wall Street Journal
he said that Google and Facebook are
killing the news and he said that
they're doing so because they're
pinching stealing the ad revenue
more recently Robert Thompson who is the
CEO of News Corp said he wrote a
ah pd0 said fake news this is the title
of it fake news and the digital duopoly
and then the subtitle Google and
Facebook have created a dysfunctional
and socially destructive information
ecosystem and he went on to say Google's
commodification of content knowingly
willfully undermined Providence for
profit what's your question
so in short he's saying that the
concentration of power by these two
companies and the misuse of that power
is a large part of the problem behind
fake news so my question is to the
representative from Facebook and the
representative from Google how would you
how do you respond to these statements
by will Lewis and Robert Thompson are
you bringing down traditional journalism
stealing its relatives traditional
journalism is changing and it has
started to change before Facebook
existed naturally our platform has
changed significantly the way how people
consume news and how people consume
information we touched upon this a very
complex issue already and as I said now
we launched the Facebook journalism
project to find out the way what is the
best way how we can work with the
traditional publishers so that they can
reach their audience or not platform but
we as well have a responsibility for the
news consumers our users on Facebook to
make sure that they can share
information with the people whom they
want to share with so this is a very it
is a complex issue it would exist
without Facebook but we take our sharing
that one and you take responsibility it
is our own common interest for the sake
of Democracies that we must have very
strong media ecosystem and very strong
publishing houses and very strong
quality media journalism James is
Facebook sapping revenue away from BBC
by and large no and that's because we
have a different business model for the
one that you described so that we're
we're license fee overwhelmingly license
fee funded which just
underscore a point is each individual in
the UK who has who consumes any TV
content has to have a license so that's
a that's the level of Independence from
government but nevertheless it's a
guaranteed revenue stream so we're in a
different place I think to some of these
other companies that you you touch on
there I think the the the terrain for us
is much more about in a world in which
we've previously been able to broadcast
direct to our audiences that we're now
we need to work in partnership with with
companies that have access to to the
consume of our these social media
platforms and that's a whole nother type
of issue of how do we continue to ensure
that we get our content to consumers so
I think we we've perhaps got a slightly
different basket of issues to the ones
that you described there it is slightly
and be disruptive in responsive the
question actually there's a way it may
turn out that the this problem changes
because the platforms that are currently
setting the ad revenue may wind up
themselves becoming victims of a similar
phenomenon you've noticed that a number
of companies now are refusing to sponsor
particular shows or sites that they view
as associated with extreme views I could
imagine a circumstance where I have
advertised we refused to fund any kind
of platform that allowed its ads to
appear on sites that are associated with
extremists or racist or otherwise
unpalatable views and that would quickly
change the business model of the
platforms because the whole theory is
you're generating ad revenue and once
the a revenue goes away you've either
got to change your business model you go
out of business
and wasn't that how Google was effective
in shutting down some of these up I
don't know if you're aware of the small
town in Macedonia that during the u.s.
election had more than 100 Pro Donald
Trump websites going and it was young
enterprising Macedonian teenagers who
are making tens of thousands of dollars
in a couple month period where they I
think the average income there a month
is about three hundred and fifty dollars
just by putting creating this fake nose
making money from the Adsense the Google
Adsense that they'd signed up for so how
did you find them and why didn't you
crack down on them earlier though I must
say because they did flourish during the
campaign fifteen percent of everything
that happens within Google search every
days and you think to Google
so sometimes we unfortunately need to
experience something so that we can
learn how to react to it and that's one
of the examples of half we've learned
about you a mechanism or a new attempt
to sneak through the diligence while
becoming our advertiser and we of course
shut it down and now we have appropriate
system how not to let that happen happen
again
and under on the journalism point I
think the question that was that was
asked from the audience has very strong
paradigm on looking at news from the
from the news industry perspective and I
think if we put the consumer or Internet
user first I think that Daily Mail has
done much more houses than has done a
great and greater harm to the public
debate than then unlike but first which
actually opened new channels for the for
the debate likewise Facebook Google is
also providing tools for journalists and
and publishers we want digital news
initiatives where we trying to discover
new ways for publishers to grow their to
grow their businesses but of course this
is again only part of the solution and
we just consume differently so so the
question is like do we want to defend
the industry as we've known that for
years or do we want to see so you see
new ways for quality content online all
right and I think we have a question
right here look this is I think to
Michael John McCarthy I work part of the
Mitsubishi group
I'm from Australia look over the three
themes are coming through to me here one
is that there is a domestic problem in
managing domestic news and that is
Hillary Clinton sells weapons to Isis
how do you deal with that a second one
is you know the efforts that some
countries go in terms of lying about
their own societies and about their own
policies that is not something you can
do much about except not believe them
but there is a third area which i think
is very pertinent to some of the
countries here less so to mine and that
is where fake news is used essentially
to destabilize societies it is in a
sense a weapon of war that might be
slightly exaggerating but the Russians
you say very effectively in Ukraine
that's that's certainly one case but
there are other cases it's basically a
destabilization exercise now even to
some degree you might argue that that
was the objective in the United States
in the lead-up to the last election it
seems to me there it moves from how you
regulate news in your own country to how
you essentially protect yourself in a
security sense what would you see as the
best approach for the United States if
for example the examinations which are
currently taking place of the Russian
influence in the election were to come
to a pretty gloomy conclusion how do you
manage that thing as a society and of
course that applies to other societies
but perhaps in a less visible way is the
case right now well you know I agree
with you that I think in many cases the
geopolitical actors are seeking to
destabilize I don't think they really
believe they're going to persuade people
that you know for example Russia is
paradise but I think at some point where
they're hoping is for many people
there'll be so many different points of
view and so many different quote facts
that people will throw their hands up in
the air and their attitude will be I'll
believe what I want to believe so I
agree that is a security
threat but I come back to the point I
made earlier I get very worried when the
cure is to try to shut something down
that we're actually creating a worse
problem I think the reason you can
destabilize a society is if it loses
faith in its own institutions and I'm
sad to say that I think a lot of the
groundwork for what we now see is
destabilizing efforts by geopolitical
foes
was laid within our own societies I mean
over a period of time political parties
have moved to a view that the way you
win elections is by not just disagreeing
with your opponent are arguing
vigorously against his or her views but
by actually saying you're bad if you
don't agree with me if you're winning
and spreading disinformation right and a
classic example of this is a couple days
ago a candidate for Congress beat up a
reporter in front of other people and
was until elected right did not really
so elected now it may be in fairness
that many votes had been cast before the
incident but the point is his attitude
was unapologetic he basically said well
the guy was a liberal and and it
startled I think we've come to the point
that in internally generating societies
is the idea that if someone disagrees
with me I can beat them up so to me I
think we have to spend I hope we spend
time on this project thinking about how
do you rebuild but the positive civic
engagement in societies because in the
best inoculation against destabilization
is to be very stable if you're tottering
from within then a push can be very
dangerous
James for being British which he also
wasn't but yeah the other thing I wanted
to add is just a particular thing of
which I very much agree with what you
said but then it extends to the
denigration of those organizations that
are practicing serious journalism it and
when that when that decry dismissed as
lamestream media or fake news or you
know operating out of
agenda rather than a pursuit of of just
journalistic endeavor I think that is
that is that is a particular example of
what you're describing which is that
feeds back into a place where trust in
the entrust in trusted sources becomes
eroded and I think that that has become
problematic Chris you had something to
add so I think the the need for stronger
journalism is clear but I think that
that's really necessary but insufficient
in this discussion because as the
questioner suggested the spectrum of
threats that are faced and the
information sphere range from an
independent episodes of fake news to
things that wouldn't reach the threshold
of hate speech but nevertheless could be
highly problematic introduced in a
systematic way in an automatic automatic
way to active measures of the sort that
were applied in Crimea as far as we can
see in Germany with the Lisa case where
a whole host of instruments were applied
ranging from fringe Russian websites to
the major Russian TV channels then being
validated and repeated by high Russian
officials this was a Gong goes that were
supported by Russia within Germany this
was a concerted effort that seems to
have backfired and I think in some ways
the Germans are now more sensitized and
aware of the of the threat but it's it's
a much more comprehensive sort of
challenge and I would wish for stronger
journalism in the democracies with good
investigative journalism but I think
we're at the point now where we come
back to the question posed on how civil
society can play a role there's much
more of a need for both immediate and
longer-term education initiatives not
only at schools but for editors who have
to sort through what is a real story and
what's a fake story for media companies
that are struggling this is a it's a
massive massive challenge so I I would
just stress the the scope of the
challenge and the need for a
comprehensive response you know um on
that point there are some young people
here with us right now
with a globe SEC young leaders for him
and if we could get a microphone to them
I believe you have perhaps some
questions for our panel but also you
they actually put out a paper they
looked at this issue and education was
one of the main points the need to
increase media literacy critical
thinking in perhaps our schools
go right ahead introduce yourself please
my name is Ken Vaughn and I lead the
agency for public and social innovation
in Canada I'll be asking a question and
someone else will be giving position um
my question well actually earlier
Gabrielle you spoke about how Facebook
doesn't edit a user's content fair but
you do curate our news feeds and at the
beginning secretary Chertoff you talked
about how curation impacts and enhances
the potency of faith' news and shortly
after Rachel you then spoke to James
about how you know there are rules that
media has to adhere to but given the
role that Google and Facebook plays and
your algorithms in curating content are
you not a media outlet or where do you
draw that line but newsfeed curating the
newsfeed doesn't mean editing the
content we do not make a decision
whether you can post something or not
you can post everything on facebook we
only remove that is against our rules
the news feed all like per day you would
have about thousand posts to read
we know our users don't have time for
that and when you log into Facebook
let's say in the morning and most
probably you will read ten pieces on
your newsfeed it's our task to make sure
that you get the top ten post for you
that you find for yourself the most
meaningful the most engaging and most
relevant this is what we know that our
users want from us they want engaging
relevant and meaningful information for
them the newsfeed is very unique to
every person it's a personalized unique
each of us at each moment in life we
have the news fields but what you said
is extremely important how we can make
sure that
fake news is not upgraded on the
newsfeed but its downgraded we have the
product that we launched or that is in a
test phase now but we identified that
users sometimes read the news then they
do not interact with that for us that is
one of the sign when we see that in
scale that the users find by the time
that they clicked on a sensational
headline they read the news and in fact
that maybe this is fake something is
smelling I'm not interacting with it I'm
not liking it I'm not sharing it when we
see that one that there's a lack of
interesting in reacting with the piece
of news then we are done grading that in
our newsfeed and in another example for
you that because it's extremely
important what security charities well
mentioned about the monetization about
the financing cutting and curbing the
financial in financial incentives behind
fake news in in the past months we've
been reviewing more than hundred
thousand news outlets or news outlets
but we tend to outlets that pretend to
be news outlets outlets that have very
bad quality content that made users buy
ads buy promoted post to click click on
themselves and then took out the users
to their websites which turned out to be
not news outlet but at farms and just
tens of may we've been an imperial nuns
that we are cutting their financial
sources we are making sure that non
existing news outlets cannot use news
domains that's one thing and the other
thing is that we are not allowing as we
are not allowing promoted posts coming
from such dubious and low-quality
outlets let's call it like that so that
we are done grading them as well in the
news field so yes that's an extremely
important issue didn't we have a
question over here right there please
thank you this was wonderful
presentation I speak about Afghanistan
the Twitter account the time I used to
work for the government we had six seven
Twitter account for the Taliban one for
the Ministry of Foreign Affairs so I had
problem in Washington DC to feed the
media especially
the journalists when their some stories
were breaking so they were quicker than
me and then I had to in fact bigging
them that a it's midnight in Kabul I
cannot check in fact with the president
office or there so don't take that
serious so then I didn't have that much
time or education from our ministry side
that's nationwide in fact all the
countries were supporting us that I'm so
grateful they were not educating us in
fact about this technology but the enemy
they were more equipped and educated
than we and Washington so the same now I
would say that this is not a gift of God
human being that knowledge is power and
that's the gift I should kiss the hand
of each one of these guys Google
Facebook Twitter you are doing the
wonderful job I think the prophecies
there in fact if you want in fact reach
that is the wonderful platform you're
doing the wonderful job the problem is
we are not educated
so what should we do what what do you
think means that's a question that I'm
saying that I agree with the gentleman's
hate the last part which is
destabilizing factor that's very
important that that is responsibility of
each individual here on the planet that
we your problem is my problem my problem
is your problem so we cannot close eyes
like some countries that they were
tweeting in fact enemies in their
countries but they say I didn't see that
every post is my responsibility if I
feel that that is not understandable I
need to in fact educate myself so I
would say education I agree with fed
that education is very important but
that cannot happen Google Twitter and
all the other they need in fact a kind
of platform not just waiting for in fact
for for people to tell them this is a
fake news you need to educate yourself
or the law enforcement that exactly what
is fake news what is making
destabilization what is in fact
terrorizing some or for example last
work the tweet in fact the operation in
fact my Pentagon friends are agreeing
with me that we had in fact operations
in Afghanistan that some guys were
tweeting from the local community and
sharing the pictures and the Twitter or
the Facebook account they were not
informed that this is seriously causing
a casualties on a platform well that's
funny actually let me take that point
you brought up a very good point that
I'd wanted to address with a secretary
Chertoff I don't know if anyone here is
read the latest
edition of Time magazine they have a
very very interesting investigation on
the topic we're discussing today
and what they discovered was that in
March that Russians Russia used malware
to try to hack into the phones the
computers and the Twitter accounts of
some 10,000 plus Pentagon officials
members of the US Department of Defense
they were able to block a lot of it and
I think they said at least in the
article they took care of the devices
that were compromised
so our intelligence agencies in the
United States are very worried because
they're saying to what end was this
occurring was it for something just like
those two if there was some sort of
security event if there was a terrorist
attack a natural disaster suddenly would
they try to activate all these fake
Pentagon accounts take over the Pentagon
accounts and start putting out
misinformation incorrect information
causing chaos what's your concern about
I figured that's frightening that goes
back to the issue I raised at the very
beginning about actually interfering
operationally by in the middle of a
crisis or an emergency sending out false
information that actually winds up
impeding what you have to do in in the
physical world and I think it comes back
to an area where I do think the
platforms have a responsibility and that
is unverified the authenticity of the
people who are identifying themselves on
it because in this instance you talk
about impersonation and that is
something which you don't have a First
Amendment right to do so having some
kind of strong authentication and
honestly there are algorithms because I
know you can do this with spam that were
can detect a change in the pattern of
what somebody puts on Facebook or on
Twitter such that you would get a red
flag that says there's something
different here the person's behaving
differently so I'd like to see you some
of the tools that we use for
relentlessly marketing stuff to people
and turn it to the question of how do we
use behavior behavioral analytics to
verify that the people using the account
are who they say they are now speaking
of behavioral analytics I wanted to
address something that Facebook is doing
again with the disputed triangle that
you put
saying this report has been disputed by
PolitiFact or Snopes last year I
moderated a panel on this issue here at
globe sac as well and one of the
panelists Walter
Quatro GOG who is head of Italy's
Laboratory of computational and social
science at IMT Lucca they did a
five-year study of Facebook and they
examined what happens when you do
dispute when you try to debunk a
Facebook news post and what they found
is that those people who initially
believed it or even more inclined to
believe it after you tried to debunk it
so when you said this is big this is
false it made them go well well there
must be something to it because you're
trying to downplay this so I'm going to
believe this more they would like it
more they would share it more so are you
having any success with this new measure
that you're trying and are you worried
it could just backfire as I said I don't
know yet whether we are on the right
path or not because it's a test phase
but these are exactly the very valid
questions and just as we have been doing
research when we've been rolling out our
anti-bullying Center which is a totally
different issue of IR raise it is that
we've been working very closely there
with the behavioral scientists academics
who are looking into the online behavior
of humans and as the secretary Chertoff
said it is extremely important that we
understand how humans how people how we
interact online when we are consuming
news so we are working together we've
established the news integrity
initiative and we are working together
with academics research organizations
and NGOs it's a global partnership and I
hope that many in the audience will join
that and we have the opportunity to work
together to understand better the
phenomenons and the logic because if you
understand better how people react when
they see they offer four different
alternative news we know that from
experts who are dealing with online
extremists some of these experts say
that well when you hear something three
times from different sources and maybe
those some of those three are even
opposing to the idea but the others are
totally trying to tell you
you will start to believe it regardless
what you are reading because it just
fixated into your mind I don't know
there's a thing allies bold often an
omnipresent serious to that but
certainly we have to understand much
better how we are reacting and how how
this fixation process goes on in our
mind everyday news thank you didn't we
have a question up here another one any
more hands ok anyone ok maybe we'll run
this side here thank you I have to be
very old-school here last year a book
was pulled from Cambridge University
Press because there was worried that
libel they were worried about libel
lawsuits because it was making
allegations unfounded allegations about
ill-gotten wealth by Russian oligarchs
is there a role somewhere for liability
or libel law in the publication or
dissemination of laws and on the other
hand is there also a danger of
censorship of good information about say
for example the ill-gotten gains of
Russian oligarchs we'd like to Chris so
the book you're alluding to I believe is
karen dawisha as putin's kleptocracy and
for all the views who couldn't find that
through cambridge university press it
was published and i would encourage you
to take a look at it so that publishers
are encouraged to do the right thing in
the future i think one of the things
that we've seen with the emergence of
the internet is that certainly for
british libel law libel has been
globalized and so the threshold for well
certainly for wealthy Gulf state
potentates and for Russian and Ukrainian
oligarchs they wield this like a big
hammer and there's no question that it
suppresses meaningful scrutiny or as
meaningful scrutiny I should say there's
still people who are very courageous who
look into these sorts of things
but it's a real problem and I think the
the extent to which either reform of
British libel law or other mechanisms to
ameliorate this is very healthy because
in essence it's it's giving more space
to kleptocrats to both steel in their
home countries but in a globalized world
they're just as likely to project this
maligned behavior into London and Miami
in New York through ill-gotten real
estate holdings and offshore accounts
and all the things we're learning more
about with greater speed so it's a very
important issue so we have about five
minutes left and I have five panelists
so how about each one of you taking one
minute to UM summarize your thoughts or
share what you're most worried about
what is keeping you up at night on this
issue as we go forward my talk so I
think that there are two ways to look at
it one is what's going to happen in the
news future as this debate is so hard
that if you go to conference often I bet
that the next one you're going to go to
there's going to be at least one panel
on fake news and and and how to tackle
it there is a Warwick tendency to
provide regulation one that we discussed
today proposed in Germany for for
example and over-regulation now is the
threat then we've got elections coming
up in Europe we've just gone through an
electoral cycle as well and so much so
what keeps me awake at night in in short
term perspective is unnecessary
over-regulation and trying to trying to
impose rules that are not going to solve
the problem but they're going to lead to
is my more long term my Locsin fear and
that's fragmentation of the internet
taking content down is not going to do
to solve real life problems and that's
going to to that may lead to to a
network of networks that may lead to
removing everything that we don't like
or easily go do to two different natural
networks and there is a huge risk in
that the risk is not knowing what's the
extent of many processes
that are happening and that now the web
is giving visibility to let's go to
Chris Chris and I wouldn't mind you when
you and I spoke earlier we talked about
China because I know we've been focusing
a lot on Russia here but they aren't the
only purveyors of fake news and
misinformation disinformation it's it's
a little bit different but it's related
in the sense that the Chinese
authorities are investing billions of
dollars in a wide range of media
platforms both traditional media online
media we know from their domestic
ambitions that they can use social media
to distract and direct their own vast
population in rather effective ways if
you speak to people in Taiwan and Hong
Kong these days you can hear stories
it's very difficult to verify that these
techniques are bleeding into that area
Chinese authorities are very effective
at managing overseas Chinese and places
like Australia where China is taking
over much of the major media they're
both english-language media but also for
consumers of Chinese language content so
is that your concern about this as we go
forward it absolutely should be a
concern I think Russia has been a more
urgent concern and they tend to grab
attention in all the ways we know but I
think what keeps me up at night in the
in the larger sense is that despite what
we know so far we're still not quite
positioned and ready and mobilized to
deal with the full scope of the
information challenges in the way we
should secretary Chertoff so you know
for me I like to take the broadest view
of the topic which is how to defend
democracy and I think that one of the
reasons this fate news has traction is
because we have not reinvigorated our
commitment to democracy you know when I
grew up as a kid there was a theory of
history that basically inevitably the
world was going to progress to liberal
democracy everybody wanted that and I
think that you were in a horse race now
I think if you look at other parts of
the world there's a Chinese model about
you know the government doesn't matter
if you elect your government their job
is to perform and as long as they can
produce economic growth and other
positive values that is a preferred form
of government Russia takes a view that
it's about
nationalism and restoring the greatness
of an empire extremist fundamentalists
says God makes us legitimate so we have
and we've got some health issues with
our own democracy and it's not really
digital and one things I'd like to see
is - and it requires it doesn't it's not
about Facebook or Google or it's about
all of us and all of our institutions is
to move away from tribalism we've now
gotten to the point that for a lot of
people if you're from a different
political party no matter what you say
or do I'm against you and I'm with my
guys no matter what now that is great if
you're a Manchester United fan and
you're talking about football that
should not be the attitude we take to
our politics and we've got to reset
ourselves in terms of our own commits
Gabriela let's go on this path so I feel
that whatever we are in a situation now
but our users experience as well when
there are an authentic accounts and
coming with the sensationalist or
disruptive or violent and hateful images
and posts and people than just saying in
those let's say Facebook groups oh I'm
better I'm better leaving I'm better not
saying anything here so there's an
intimidation but I feel that that
intimidation doesn't only go on
uncertain Facebook groups and in other
platforms but as well here in real life
in this space as well where we are now
and if we let ourselves being
intimidated and have trying to find the
resort in in some easy fixes which are
most probably not the right fixes then
will be not only causing damage to our
own societies and to our own European
and transatlantic democracies but as
well beyond because other countries in
in the world are looking as an example
for this community so if we are not
finding the right answers then we'll the
damaging civilization and societies
outside Europe and outside the stands of
the land again go as well thank you
James you get the last word I guess I
have
two thoughts final thoughts one is it
sort of narrower one in and one is a
broad one the narrow one is I I worry
about being played and taken by one of
these false news stories and you see you
can either just make a straight error
you think something's accurate when it's
not or that all more insidiously that
traction builds up around the story the
disinformation process works it even if
the entry point is is illegitimate it's
it builds up into into something much
bigger whether it's you know the famous
example none of us have mentioned you
know Trump was the the Pope was
supporting Trump but you know these
things can enter the bloodstream of
mainstream news agendas even where the
original starting point was was even if
it's known to have been a sort of a fake
new starting point and I guess my my
broader concern is that the
organizations and the people who are
involved in the proper conduct of
responsible public interest journalism
are they lose traction they lose trust
they lose access to their their
readerships and their audiences and I
think that's a that's a really worrying
dimension as I said before I think it's
it's a it's an element of the wider
picture that Michael just raised as a
sort of overall concern about the the
times we're in thank you and I would
like to end actually on a note of
optimism with a quote by Buddha who said
there are three things that cannot be
long hidden the Sun the moon and the
truth and I I think it's our duty to
keep pushing away the clouds of
disinformation so that the truth can
shine and I want to I have a brief
announcement here ladies and gentlemen
that if you are lucky enough to be
invited to the globe Sikh gala dinner
tonight I hope you all are the busses
are going to be leaving from the front
of the hotel at six o'clock and of
course here in the hotel we will have as
we always do the night almost sessions
an hour later and then tomorrow morning
the first session will be here in the
hall at 9:00
am I'm going to thank you all for
listening for your wonderful questions
thank you to our viewers on Facebook
live around the world and please join me
and thank you our fabulous panel thank
you FC Phelan danke have a good evening