good afternoon everyone this is the
session called digital subversion and
digital restriction and I'll introduce
your panelists for the afternoon so oh
you guys did know you didn't okay how
did you switched on me to my immediately
left is John Felker who is director of
the national cybersecurity and
communications integration Center which
we know in the US and kick it's a
24-hour Center overseen by the
Department of Homeland Security that
analyzing coordinates response to
significant cyber threats next to him is
tell Moses the partner in ernst & young
he's been working in cybersecurity since
1989 and has founded several cyber
security companies next to him is Rado
Danyluk co-founder and CEO of tachyon to
start-up providing data center services
and device hardware and next to him is
Tony an skom global security evangelist
and industry partnerships ambassador for
ESET a cyber security firm based
actually here in Bratislava first of all
I just want to apologize for the red
blotch I've got here I had a little
accident at the train station yesterday
in Copenhagen but everything's fine and
we'll get going so our focus here today
is on critical infrastructure and what
nation-states and private industry could
and should be doing to secure critical
infrastructure and national security and
I want to just sort of sort of set the
tone for what we're talking about what
we're not talking about you know in 2007
there were cyber attacks in Estonia and
a lot of people have termed those in
some cases as critical infrastructure
attacks but they real weren't they
weren't really these were sort of
information kind of warfare influence
operations that are that upset
government systems and media systems the
DNC hacks the hacks against Hillary
Clinton and the DNC servers and even of
Emmanuel Mahone were not critical
infrastructure you know there's talk in
the u.s. of turning voting systems
actual
action systems into critical
infrastructure but the the systems
around there we don't generally
determine determine term as critical
infrastructure but we'll get into a
little more about what we do call it
critical infrastructure but I wanted to
talk about sort of attacks that we have
seen that have been against critical
infrastructure and these were attacks
when we're talking about text against
critical in structure we have three
different kinds you have a denial of
service attack that can take down a
production process or take down systems
you have destruction which can either be
data destruction such as wiping data
from a system or actually causing
physical destruction of the computers
themselves or of equipment that the
computer is control and we also have
something that we actually haven't seen
that much of yet and that is data
integrity attacks where you're actually
altering the data the code or something
in the system that alters that affects
the integrity of system so if you think
about let's say financial systems if
someone can get in and alter the
accounting software or get into the
stock system and change stocks or get
into weapons systems and change code so
that the weapon systems don't work so
that's something that sort of the future
fear that a lot of intelligence agencies
have now and that's something that we
will likely see so a couple of the
examples that we've seen so far are the
shim moon attack which targeted Saudi
Aramco assistance in 2012 in that case
it wiped data from about more than
30,000 systems and we've had of course
the Stuxnet attack which is an example
of critical infrastructure attack that
caused physical destruction of systems
controlled by digital systems and then
we had the this was a denial of service
attack which was the Ukraine power grid
hacks we had two examples of that in
2015 and then a repeat in 2016 just
affecting parts of the grid took out
about power to about 230,000 residents
between one and six hours so those are
the kinds of things we're looking at of
course the electric grid is the primary
critical infrastructure because it
undergirds every else every other
infrastructure so if you can take out
the critical
if you can take out the electric grid
over an extensive period of time days
weeks months which you could do if you
don't just take down the power but you
also destroy the equipment like the
generators there was a test of this in
the US if anyone is familiar with the
Aurora generator test where they were
able to destroy a generator in about
three minutes with 21 lines of code so
if you can take down obviously power for
extensive periods of times and of course
we're talking about affecting Commerce
we're talking about affecting hospitals
and eventually you know some kind of
death so a lot of things are hinging on
the the grid but the kinds of attack
that would take down a grade for
instance of period of time would not
need to be a very sophisticated attack
and you don't need to be sophisticated
to affect critical infrastructure in a
very harmful way and the wanna cry
attack of course is a prime example of
that there's been a lot of talk about
how badly that was executed and how
badly was coded and yet it was extremely
effective in taking down hospital
services critical services including
surgeries and for quite a while so you
don't need a nation state to attack
critical infrastructure when we're
talking about the threats there are a
lot of threats you could have insider
threats but what we're going to focus on
for the purposes of our talk today are
looking at sort of terror elements
terrorist elements warfare offensive
operations by nation states and
hacktivism those kinds of attacks from
outside so I want to talk about first of
all defining what we mean by critical
infrastructure I think a lot of people
were surprised after the Sony attack in
2014 that the US government considered a
motion picture studio critical
infrastructure and in the u.s. we have
16 sectors of critical infrastructure if
you go through that list it's quite
extensive and it covers pretty much
everything and I know that not every
country it defines critical
infrastructure the same so I wanted to
throw this out to the panelists first of
all how are we defining critical
infrastructure yeah
this is tough I think the terminology of
critical infrastructure is a bit
confusing and and limiting the way we
think about it each country will define
it to be differently so there will be a
critical infrastructure like power grid
power plants and so on and secondary
critical infrastructure like banking
system hospitals and so on but I want to
take it into a bit of a wider definition
I don't know if you all agree with me or
disagree with me but as we're looking on
countries gun is not just borders or the
people living in eating critical
infrastructure is supposed to be any
infrastructure which is supporting the
living in the country and everything
that will be a disruption to this
infrastructure will disrupt the country
so the obvious example are the power
grid power plants hospital banking and
so on but what about our breakfast
cereal factory that could be attacked
potentially and let's say the iron
tables will be changed to make it a bit
poisonous is that a critical
infrastructure or not so I think it's a
lot of philosophical issues as well
what's critical and what's not in the
influence of this definition is who's
taking responsibility of protecting that
the government or the private sectors in
some cases that's my two cents regarding
CI yeah so I think I've just presented
actually this week at a GSMA event in
The Hague talking about IOT devices an
IOT most of us would think about being a
consumer you know the things around our
home but that's not what they're talking
about they're talking about the smart
city they're talking about everything
being connected you know the things that
are monitoring water levels the things
that are in our factory is that once we
once we get into a smart city then
actually the entire cities part of our
infrastructure and I'm not sure you can
actually start to make a definition of
this is part of our infrastructure and
this is not because if I can attack your
traffic network bring your city to a
standstill is that is that critical
infrastructure probably what about a
motion picture studio well you know I
saw your note we thought the before our
panel about
then actually broadcasters probably are
part of critical infrastructure because
it's a method for government to talk to
its citizens so maybe that's the
definition that would use their ID and I
Darrin I've specifically John oh butter
covers roughly you know the concept of
critical infrastructure is now being
extended you know for example we have
self-driving cars imagine that State or
non-state actor can cause mass casualty
so critical infrastructure now is
rapidly expanding and we over expanded
infrastructure will be very hard to
basically spend meaningful effort to
control it so we need to be careful to
really define is what we can handle not
overextended because we need a lot of
resources to handle it okay I kind of
agree with rather with it I think it's
too broad then it you know you really
don't defend anything to tells point I
think it's a it may be a national
decision what's critical in your country
and how do you defend what's critical in
your country as opposed to trying to
defend everything all the time mm-hmm so
basically if everything is critical yeah
so let's talk then about who's
responsible of protecting critical
infrastructure is that the government is
an intelligence agencies who are more
likely to actually have sort of an
advanced view of threats that may be
coming down the pike and of course word
word we have to make a distinction
between privately owned critical
infrastructure and government owned
critical infrastructure so I mean the
case of government owned critical
critical infrastructure should it be a
civilian government should it be the
intelligence agencies who should have
the responsibility there I'm not sure
there's a difference between government
owned and privately owned critical
infrastructures all critical I think the
larger question is who's responsible for
defending that that infrastructure and
the way we operate and you've mentioned
a couple of different possible players
that are a part of that equation the at
the end of the day the asset owners
responsible for defending the network
but government the Telus community and
law enforcement all have a have a play
in supporting that defense
for example you know the there are a lot
of rural utilities in the United States
electricity for example and their IT guy
probably also serves as their financial
guy and probably the janitor right so
how how competent is that one person
going to be in defending that so so
those kinds of facilities need need the
intelligence and the information and
support to help do their defense better
so actually every piece of that
infrastructure has one responsibility
because government cannot guarantee or
cannot protect against vendor doing poor
job and living donor abilities
government can set the standards which
vendors has to adhere to so so the
government responsibility is defining
the policy defining the standards
vendors they have to meet the
requirements to the standards and the
owner of the system they need to adhere
to standards of physical protection and
so every piece has own responsibility in
component and but the standard setting
and the governance is really job of
development well are you talking about
voluntary standards are actually talking
about regulation see a lot of critical
national infrastructure it's hard to
rely on voluntary standards because they
are not met and how you guarantee
certain standard of safety relying only
on voluntary compliance so I believe
that role is really in standardization
body in government setting requirements
and policies if they are not set there
is no driving mechanisms for vendors to
complain and accomplish that level of
security so one of the problems with
standards of when governments issue
standards is governments typically can't
keep pace and that's a challenge that's
a huge huge challenge because you've got
to go put it through a legislative
process and you've got to get it agreed
by industry and the rest of the
government and it's it's tough for them
to do so I don't know whether there's
some other way
whether
a more flexible standard approach but it
would seem sensible for there to be you
know what one thing industry is good at
is actually finding innovative ideas for
protection or to do things differently
whereas if you have a written standard
and you corner industry into into a
certain way of doing it then you also
take out some of the innovation which is
not a good thing but you are relying in
that sense quite a lot on voluntary so a
lot of the problems that we have with
critical infrastructure are not
necessarily they are how with the owners
of the critical infrastructure but there
are deeper problems in terms of the
products and the software the hardware
the software and many of these and
particularly industrial control systems
that control power plants that control
chemical plants that even control
traffic lights they were never designed
with security in mind they were designed
twenty years ago and you can't slap
security on them really in order to
secure them you've got to re-architect
and redesign them so is there a role for
government because if the customers
aren't demanding security from the
vendors is there a role for government
to sort of set a minimum standard for
any security product and I'll just give
you an example medical devices we have
the Federal Drug Administration in the
u.s. that oversees the testing and
reliability of medical devices before
they can go on the record they never had
a security component to medical devices
until I think was last year after
researchers found a number of security
problems with pacemakers and drug
infusion pumps and diabetes insulin
pumps and things like that so is there a
role that government can play in
requiring certain products industrial
control system products if they're going
to go into critical infrastructure that
they have a higher level and maybe
that's a way of raising the security for
everyone if you get the product more
secure well you raise an interesting
point because it was an article this
morning in the news about medical
devices specifically about pacemakers
and to bring it back to what you just
said it difference between voluntary and
mandatory 49% of the medical companies
that will talk to by that survey said
they don't adhere to the standard set
I'm sorry they don't they don't add ear
to the
standards that were set by the the drug
agency so though that we have
manufacturers already admitting they
don't because it's a voluntary standard
so somewhere along the line you have to
make your mandatory standard at some
point you have to make that decision it
comes down to a risk decision
essentially and on the part of the
manufacturer I think it's a risk
decision it's based upon what are we
going to how are we going to profit from
making this piece of equipment or the
this set of code to to do what it's
supposed to do and where's the balance
between the prophet and the and the
security that you would build in and how
much risk are we willing to accept and
then the buyer also has to take a look
at all right if these are the standards
and I can prove that view that you've
met those standards that I'm willing to
accept that product but I think if you
if you don't then then I won't or I I
will hold you to them if I'm going to
buy your product I agree and I think the
government's place is to guide and to
help the critical infrastructure from
governmental and private sector to
comply with the certain level of
security but also agree with release
love that it's a shared responsibility
it's about time that private and
governmental sector sector with try
start to require warranty from vendors
from IT vendors security product vendors
for the product so if you sell an
anti-virus and I got hacked by a virus I
want you to be to give me warranty and
be responsible for that so once you
start sharing the responsibility start
raising the awareness for the risks so I
will go slightly slightly further today
concepts are basically reactive that is
full of the
you know of the potential
vulnerabilities and you know we are
trying to build defenses after the fact
you know the systems are not designed by
consent by construction technology and
exists to do that from capability based
system and so on and the issue or it is
there is no enough pressure currently to
build a system in a in more formal way
which has certain provable guarantees
technology and theory exist but there is
no pressure sufficient currently and the
damage from vulnerability is not big
enough to basically go that different
part and I can see the role of the
government in the form of you know
supporting that coming from pushing on
more University the technology to
incorporate that to the system because
UNIX came from the universities
sometimes for example government
directly improves the technology like be
a Linux or NSA invested money to improve
cross the border infrastructure and
start building stronger platform so I
believe that the government role will be
needed and more necessary to push new
methodology which commercial entities
are not deploying but still exist we
also know the government's move really
slowly though and you mentioned the
standards and they can take in the US
for technological standards three or
five three to five years to have them go
through the approval process in the
commenting commenting period
what if we're talking about not critical
infrastructure like what were ordinarily
used to that are providing you know kind
of water services electric grid but if
we're talking about the internet itself
and the infrastructure that undergirds
the internet and communications
infrastructure we've had a number of
major and serious attacks
obviously the DynaTAC which was using
the Mirai botnet using surveillance
cameras to attack a Dyne corporation
which provides DNS services which
resolves where you go on the internet
and of course websites were inaccessible
we've had
bgp routing attacks where entire swath
of communication IP addresses are
basically just hijacked by someone and
sent to another location possibly copied
and then sent on to the location where
they should go the BGP problems have
been known for twenty years and they
haven't been fixed yet and it's required
you know it largely relies on the
telecoms agreeing to make the changes
that they need to make and ss7 which has
been in the news recently ss7 tax
believed to be happening in DC and other
areas ss7 is the protocol that it's part
of the telecom protocol a mobile product
protocol that allows a telecom if you're
here in bratislava but your phone
companies in london the phone company
here can tell the London company that
you're here and reroute your calls here
it's not secure and so someone can
actually if they know your phone number
and they have access to the ss7 protocol
and infrastructure they can route your
phone call to their system record it and
send it on to its location and it was
used by criminals recently believed to
be in Russia where they weren't looking
to get the phone calls but they were
getting the two factor authentication
text messages that were going to mobile
phones for banking accounts so they
already had the passwords through
phishing attacks and they needed the
two-factor authentication
text messages so these are critical
infrastructures the problems have been
known for years in some cases some
entities telecoms have taken some steps
not enough where where should the
pressure be for rewriting the protocols
I mean this is like starting from
scratch rewriting the protocols fixing
the protocols fixing the routers the
hardware who's responsible for that know
that the internet was not invented with
security by design nothing we're using
the Internet is secured as we said
before if everything is critical nothing
is critical we cannot say that
everything is critical and maybe it's
also the mean so stealing our second
factor authentication is got a business
goal behind that and not a terror attack
and it's not
going to disrupt the whole country and
that could be be a responsibility of the
business entity to enterprise while
we're talking about power grids or
communications to people not just for
going to Facebook that could be
governmental as far as I know in most
countries a lot of the security measures
that are in communication channels ISP
and on or being monitored by
governmental in order to see they have
the right security measured and they
have to comply with certain policies
that the government have dictated
usually it's not enough or at least I
know that the government helps the
operators want the being attacked so
there is the cooperation and there is
responsible arm shared responsibilities
already going on actually you're an
interesting time where things will
change so most of the losses today both
economic losses you know we have denial
of service attack
you know incur certain number of dollar
losses and let's define how much money
can be spent to improve the
infrastructure there is some economical
balance that's what's to today and
that's why we are kind of shaky
infrastructure but we need to realize
that this IRT and proliferation IOT the
losses financial losses ten years down
the road will translate to actually
losses of real human life because it's
one thing getting computer down
another thing is basically car in the
middle of the driving basically stop
supplying car stop actually working so
we need to very actively work where
economical balance how much I spend on
security versus how much I am losing
when they are security events that was
let's define the security level today
there'll be not sufficient ten years
down the road when IOT
relating to our life the answer to your
question about the ss7 is just what rato
said it's a balance right now between
how much it's going to cost to to start
from scratch and as you said and and
rebuild that protocol versus you know
what could we do to make it make it
better it it isn't an easy problem to
solve and what what about some of and I
want the audience to start thinking
about questions will coming to you
shortly what about you know the code
that is like the open source code that
has been problematic the heartbleed
vulnerability which was again and years
old
vulnerability and code it's open source
technically people can any1 can look at
it and find the vulnerabilities and no
one did
what about sort of some kind of
government private sector consortium
that funds a project that let's say
funds security researchers who will
examine code like that I mean is that
something that's worthwhile and even
something that could be done
internationally I said everyone relies
on that I absolutely think it's worth
considering that debts on the front end
already we've started in the United
States the cyber threat Alliance which
is looking at the threats which are on
the back end so I can see that as a
possibility is of a way to approach it
from the vulnerability perspective right
now it's there's a lot of security
researchers out there and we all know
they find vulnerabilities every day that
nobody knew before the the youngster in
the in the UK that found the kill switch
on wanna cry is a great example of that
so potentially putting together some
sort of consortium to look at things on
the front end might not be a bad idea
I mean software companies already do
this to a certain degree yeah I mean
yeah but but you have bug bounty
programs and we pay the researcher to to
come to us responsibly tell us about the
issue so we can fix it I just write I
just want to come back and point out one
other thing though when we're talking
about with these attacks on
infrastructure there's a comp there is a
common theme typically involves a person
there's always nearly always human
interaction whether it's an SMS message
somebody clicked
there is an email somebody opened
whether it's a USB Drive somebody put in
the machine I'm not sure I'm actually
not sure how you fix that piece and that
engagement with the end user very very
human nature Tony I refer to those is
stupid user tricks they you know and
that's an inside trap because there are
people that do so many things but I you
know I think it's not I always feel like
it's unfair when you blame the user
because I'm a journalist and I get
contacted by people I don't know all the
time who are sending me things it's my
job to open attachments it's my job to
look at things from strangers and I
think it's a responsibility of the
makers of the software and my assistant
Ben to create configure a system that
secures me even when I do that even when
I need to do that so and also you know a
lot of those attacks are made to look
like they're coming from your boss you
know they're they they're really well
designed these days they don't have
spelling errors and things like that I
try not to answer emails from my boss
good tactic um I want I just go to his
office and talk to him face ok adds
other questions since I want to go into
some ok hi Bert hello Kim it's Edward
Lucas from The Economist um I obviously
know Magic Bullet to this we're going to
have to attack it from every direction
mixture of carrots and sticks and
regulatory pressure and education and so
on but not if you've mentioned
trustworthy software and I'm wondering
whether there's a and there's a very
interesting conference going on on Lang
sac at that at the moment which and I'm
wondering whether there's a role for the
state in setting our mandatory standards
for using trustworthy software which is
not much more expensive than the regular
software but on if it's critical
maybe we should be say you can't do a
self-driving car because of the
externalities that damage it can do to
other people
unless you have that I also wonder
whether you've mentioned the IOT whether
you're really saying we should be
pulling the emergency brake on the IOT
which just shouldn't be going until you
have you can
guarantee that at least the firmware on
these things is are remotely updatable
arm you're creating so many problems the
future both in terms of vulnerabilities
of the devices inside the home or
wherever but also in terms of becoming
part of botnets and so on that we should
be really game for some dramatic
dramatic stop or is that just
impractical can you slow the
proliferation of IOT I don't think we
can and I think at the end of the day it
comes down to making a risk decision
about how far we're willing to go I'm
not sure that the trustworthy software
is going to be pervasive because as you
say it's very expensive although again
it comes down to risk what am I willing
to accept I would point out that concept
of trust chain insecurity trustworthy
software
it's illusion of the sake of the safety
for tourism either state actors or
extreme ideology you know employee can
put into work into company which has
safety which has it is trusted yet they
can plant basically piece of the
software subverting the software so the
methodology of relying on the trust you
know because the so many people are
involved doesn't work very well and
let's look at practical example one of
the largest damage to us was done by
supposedly transported people people
within NSA people like Snowden which
have been cleared and trusted so the
concept of trust chain is as weak as the
weakest link and you know there are
hundred or thousand software companies
we cannot clear every software basically
person in that older chain of the
software infrastructure so I would
basically point out we need to move to a
system designs saved by construction and
that's where basically you know this is
underserved area which basically needs
more attention so instead being reactive
system is saved by design we shouldn't
we can't really stop the progress we
cannot stop biote from happening we
maybe we can explain the risk better but
we should never stop progress and look
at motorbikes people know the risk of
riding motorbikes but it's it's you get
quicker to work and you like right we
like the feeling of riding back you
won't stop even though you don't risk so
once people actually know there is
confusing IOT they can choose the order
to use it or not but you cannot stop the
progress that the security should never
be a disabler it's an enabler look at
the the car brakes what do they invited
the brakes in the cars they didn't
invade the brakes so you can stop they
invented the brake so you can actually
drive faster if you wouldn't have wrecks
you wouldn't drive and this is the same
should be with cybersecurity we should
allow this progress since the river also
the trust thing changes over time I mean
if we look at the the wanna cry issue
recently with the NHS my immediate
reaction was why the NHS still using XP
I mean it's a huge question and then
actually I spoke to a doctor in the NHS
I need to find out that their MRI
scanner uses XP and actually can't be
updated because they can't afford to buy
another MRI scanner now when they
purchased it was that trusted software
it probably was but as time moves on
what do you continually have to update
the trust well you know you have to go
even if you're going to get to that
level you have to go even on one level
lower than that and as the chips
where are our chips design where the
majority of our chips coming from China
and so you've got a trust issue there
with the manufacturing process where do
you stop you know there is no really
trusted source anywhere and yeah
sorry ah you're all using metaphors from
the world of consumer products to extend
that metaphor however I think you need
to remember the role that insurance
companies have played and no one's
mentioned that yes you can ride a
motorbike but if you do your rates go up
and if you're a private company and
you're reckless you can't get insurance
why not just make it an insurance issue
a private sector issue you want a cheap
up be cheap on security go ahead be
prepared for class action lawsuits that
put you out of business so there's a
huge debate about that now in in the
United States anyway the the insurance
companies have started to do those those
things that you described they don't
have the actuarial tables like they
would for life insurance or fire
insurance which go back hundreds of
years to make decisions but they've
stepped out and have started to make
decisions based upon a small amount of
data to to insure I think the bigger
question when it when it comes to
insurance and cyber is what's what's an
acceptable standard of security that has
got to be decided first you know it's
all over the map and it depends it
depends what sector you sit in so what's
the due care that you're going to hold
somebody to when they purchase an
insurance policy and how do you define
that due care and is it different from
and the electric grid as it might be a
Sony or with a healthcare manufacturer
it may be I don't know but I think
you're right I think that that that we
should have that discussion yeah I said
that you talked about the insurance
industry and so there are a lot of
different ways of coming at this and one
interesting example that we had recently
in the US was with the the medical
shorts talking shorting of the stock as
a company that had medical device waters
sorry
muddy waters yes so unsecured the system
and the researchers found
vulnerabilities and they decided to
short the stock
and because it was you know a lot of
companies are told about vulnerabilities
in their systems and they shrug their
shoulders and they'll say it's not a
real vulnerability it's a theoretical
vulnerability or we'll get to it when we
can and three years later the product is
still insecure and so they're going
after it you know in a different kind of
financial way there's there's some
debate about that though I mean the the
vulnerability became known should they
have followed the responsible disclosure
process to allow the company to make a
fix before they went public with it I'm
not sure that that was the case I think
they wanted to profit from it yes before
the there's a lot of context right there
yeah whether it be mothers really
effective yes um yeah hello my name is
kerstin pretty sober katana region
instituto international affairs l'm iíve
been to many conferences about
cybersecurity and usually the word that
pops up very early is resilience and I
haven't heard it yet and usually it's a
kind of magic word that nobody really
knows what means except we all know we
have to kind of bounce back and be a
back copper and running again bit faster
but I assume most of you agree that some
sort of resilience is part of the
solution I don't know if you want to
elaborate on that especially in the
context of IOT if that's really doable
leave it as a concept it basically had
to rethink well security requires liars
yeah and the analogy I would use is
actually you know I think somebody
talked about cars earlier on let's think
about a car you know back in nineteen
fifty something or other somebody
designed a three-point seatbelt then
somebody found that you could contract
the seatbelt into the floor then
somebody came up with a sensor and a
safety device we call it an airbag yeah
and now you have alternated safety
systems in cars that will stop before I
hit the other car the seatbelts still in
the car and that's the important of the
resilience isn't it is my seatbelt is
still there and my hair banks there and
I'm not going to hit the car in front
yeah so Security's mighty always has to
be deployed in layers I'm not sure how
that fits in an IOT world I don't think
anybody truly is at the moment because I
don't think anybody understands what
security should look
you're starting to see some standards
come out but yeah resilience is good
word I think you where you said is how
you define resilience we look at
resilience and etiquette as being able
to continue your business or your
mission and so there are a lot of parts
of that one part is security but other
parts are do we exercise our procedures
when when we have a bad day is the
leadership of our organization switched
on to that exercise and do they know
what to do if it's a really bad day just
recently in the wanna cry incident we
dealt with a health care facility
who first of all important understanding
our mission is asset response so it's
it's mitigation stop the bleeding and so
we were dealing with a hospital it was
very clear to us that that hospital had
done those things their leadership on
the problem the chairman of the hospital
knew exactly what to do and and knew
that this was an issue the the the rest
of the organization did all the right
things when this was sent in their in
their facility so they were able to
segment some of the MRIs that can't
possibly be protected away from the the
connections to the electric electronic
health records to make them usable again
they were able to segment other parts of
their facilities in rapid fashion as
this was going on so that they were able
to be resilient and able to continue
doing what the hospital had to do
significant shift which is starting but
it appears will be in full swing it
almost sounds like the lower causes
device more security needs it sound
completely counterintuitive but let me
make an example we have pcs we have
laptops there are thousand dollar
devices we can afford paying $30
antivirus and service
on that now if I have you know
intelligent microwave I cannot spend $30
of running antivirus on that it has to
just work TV has to just work so the
basically the the model economical model
and balance between money spent on on
basically securing system is basically
even more important in IOT because there
are lower cost devices the things which
work like antivirus we cannot afford on
intelligent by Bob which is one dollar
device we cannot run that so these
systems they have different requirements
and again is driven by economic balance
nothing else economy is the most
powerful force we need just need to
understand and harness that I want to go
back to what we started the discussion
with critical infrastructure and we're
talking about critical infrastructure
and IOT together and most of the
problems happens when you take out the
operational technology and move it into
IOT the water gauge is not used to exist
for 20 years some of them 12 years and
now to making new water gauges which has
an adapter to become more with better
connectivity but this is not where the
problem is yes it's not secured it's
easy to break but nobody can get to it
the problem starts when you make it into
IOT when you can control it remotely and
the good news are that we're still in
the transition of digitalizing critical
infrastructure if you go to the trains
railroads just now in most into the
world the becoming digital as you can
start controlling the railroad from a
computer and not manually like until a
few years ago if you can still now we
can still change it and secure it
because all we have to secure is the
digitalization and not the old
infrastructure so yeah and in many cases
I point out that the government in is
pushing that digitalization free we had
a problem for instance with smart meters
in the US where the government
subsidized they roll out of smart meters
before they were tested for security and
of course they can be remotely shut off
to cause blackouts
so when when you have initiatives that
are under what's the I'm underpaying I
mean when you're when you're subsidizing
through government there has to be hand
in hand without a responsibility to
establish some kind of security model
and standardization before your question
my question is talking about antivirus
and trust and IOT and if an IOT device
or a chip is coming from China the some
concerns there is now the company
Kaspersky under review by the US
government because there's some issues
with just my question is gentleman what
measures do you recommend on a global
level so we don't have to stop at a
country level you know I'm sure there
are some some great Chinese companies
which could be trusted that completes
which could not be trusted Russia as
well so what measures should be
implemented in in terms of auditing
technologies and making sure they're
really secure or not so you cannot
really old it technology it's too
expensive process it exposes IP and but
I would point out you know China and
Russia is kind of convenient basically
supposedly bad guy but in reality
majority of the problems did not
originate in that country we did not
have recent outbreak because there was
subverted chip from the China so we
should really look where is the bulk of
the problem coming is and not try to
politicize and divert the resources in
the areas where
yes you know subversion of the chip is
important if you have weapons and
nuclear weapons and so on but we have to
focus with the really biggest impact is
and where the money is and you know we
should be pragmatic rather than trying
to politicize basically problem I agree
most of the problems that we've seen
from China or commercial problems of
stealing intellectual properties versus
attacking in order to get destructive
but and now it's changed I believe the
China have changed their plans now and
they're acquiring intellectual property
properties more than stealing them and
they actually have a very clear plan of
how take other markets in a commercial
way and I don't I don't think China is
the threat agents that we need to deal
with but I do agree that we cannot
control where all the different parts
are coming from if you're talking about
common factor each car is being
assembled from parts from all the 170
different vendors who should take
responsibility the vendors of the parts
or the car manufacturer I agree it's a
real question that we're still not
facing and I think that we're talking
about towards like there are two
different words the physical wards and
virtual wards but the question is are
there the same world or two different
worlds deal because the car is now part
physical and pathological in this
physical world we have clear rules clear
responsibilities that aren't just just
not that clear in the virtual world and
it's a real question how if you unite us
and responsibilities to share it the way
it is now also I would little bit touch
about China because we have a lot of
things to learn from the China he talked
about a lot about securing national
infrastructure and communication and
planning for that they are actually
doing that in fact in 2016 they are all
basically quantum based encryption
Network for their military and the
financial systems and they actually
deployed it and we still need to do that
so you know we should actually learn
from each other and this is example when
they did writing and we still have to
follow it so you should work rather than
you know trying to basically an
antagonistic relationship we can each
learn from each other and I think that's
that's the way to go I just have a sort
of jump in because we're talking about
sort of adversarial Nations and the
problems that they create and the vendor
problems what about when we're talking
about a nation-state itself that is and
we had a sample of this of course with
controversial example with wanna cry
where it use an exploit developed
supposedly by the NSA involving a
vulnerability that wasn't disclosed to
Microsoft until a short time ago so held
on by a government for years so and not
just the u.s. I mean every country does
this not every country but the major
players intelligence agencies and
governments stockpiling vulnerabilities
rather than disclosing them so that they
can be fixed and leaving millions of
systems vulnerable how do we deal with
that problem and either internally state
by state internationally what's the
solution here I think in order to answer
these questions we need to put it a bit
more accurately that Dennis a did not
develop an exploit its founder
vulnerability and anyone else could have
found this permeability and as far as we
know maybe someone else already Fonts
vulnerability chernobly was an exploit
excuse me eternal blue was an exploit
you talked about wanna cry eternal blue
was the exploit that wanna cry used to
spread yeah but it's there it's a
zero-day the vulnerability that was
found in any expert kit could be
developed and used once this
vulnerability is known now um and the
problem is once r0 the availability that
is not known before is being discovered
who should disclose it to the vendor how
long and the kind of country actually
keep it as a competitive Wolfer mean or
not and i think this is the the question
we're trying to ask you
I'm sorry I think it's a it's a war we
can never win
you always have to fight we'll never win
it's a chase we'll never be able to find
all the loopholes or the zero days and
there are entities which have different
goals like financial goals in the
darkness that sell zero day attacks -
yeah but we're talking specifically
about governments governments
withholding them I'm not talking about
you're never going to find out every
vulnerability but when you do find them
do you do you what is the responsibility
to disclose it so everyone can be
secured or to withhold it so that you
can exploit it yourself so there we we
have a very robust equities review
process vulnerabilities expose all
abilities at vep and it involves all
different parts of the government and
there are I mean just if you suggest
that we should automatically give up a
vulnerability and everything's going to
be fine that's crazy I go to towels
point you know the vulnerability existed
it was located a tool was built to
exploit it it could have been anyone
anywhere anytime that did that in in the
case of the US government that process
will look at that look at each of those
vulnerabilities that are discovered and
make try to make a determination on the
value of that from a from an
intelligence and a national security
perspective anyone else we're running
out of time
well I would just say as and sort as a
software vendor I think I would like to
think that the government would actually
tell you if you if they found a
vulnerability in yourself where it would
seem responsible in the same way that if
we saw somebody attacking a government
institution the first thing we would do
is actually content contact that
institution and tell them they are under
attack or they should prepare for attack
and attack because we've seen that
intelligence yeah the sharing should go
both ways
and there's a tremendous amount of
sharing that occurs in the process I
mean it's I mean if you if you take
Recoleta its quote who's the recently
retired deputy director of NSA 90-plus
percent are disclosed
in that process nothing moreover we've
seen governments that actually enforce
several vendors to lead back doors for
them salted so they can use them later
so it's not only about the disclosure of
it it's about who can use those back
toes right and who can hijack them if
you do install one so we're out of time
I want to thank the audience for your
participation and I want to take thank
the panelists for all their guidance and
wisdom and I have a couple of
housekeeping notes for you all we've got
night owl sessions off-the-record talks
this evening that start at 1900s 7:00
p.m. for those of you attending the
dinner sessions note that the buses will
leave outside the hotel at 1830 6:30 and
tomorrow morning the first session here
in the Danube space starts at 9:00 a.m.
sharp and it will be on artificial
intelligence so please join me in
thanking the panelists thank you
you