to prime ministers and a president on
this stage for you with really the most
important subject that faces Europe
today the future of Europe European
disunion with a question mark at the end
of that I would like to introduce our
esteemed panelists beginning with Prime
Minister feet so our host here the prime
minister of Slovakia as you know we have
Prime Minister Sobotka
as well from the Czech Republic and on
the far right just in the seating order
not politically speaking we have Donald
Tusk the president of the European
Council anyone who has read a newspaper
over the past few years couldn't avoid
the conclusion that Europe might be on
the brink of collapse or very close to
it a book that was recently published in
the u.s. even carried the title the the
end of Europe and yet Europe has somehow
persevered through all of these myriad
crises in recent months we've seen
populist defeated in Austria in the
Netherlands and most importantly in
France so the real question now is has
Europe turned the corner and I think we
would all like to ask our panelists that
question and I will start with a few
questions and then invite you the
audience to come in so please think
about what you would like to ask I'd
also like to welcome our viewers on
Facebook live and on the other live
streams that are available today I would
however like to start with with
president toast if I may who's just come
back from the g7 meetings in Sicily and
president tools from your initial
comments over the past week after your
meetings with US President Trump you
seem to be
somewhat skeptical about the
relationship the transatlantic
relationship in the sense that it was
clear that there isn't complete
agreement in in the u.s. on a lot of
issues as we know there's the climate
issue and there are other issues so if I
could just start with you because the
importance of the transatlantic
relationship for Europe today and
historically with the u.s. being really
one of the drivers of European
integration over the past several
decades and I would just like to start
with you and get your oppressions of the
last couple of days and the state of
eu-us relations under President Trump
thank you first of all I think it's a
maybe the best evidence I mean our
meeting in Taormina F 57 may be the best
evidence that there's rumors about the
decline of the West are it's likely an
exaggeration and this is why I infact I
can't accept this assumption in your
first question your thesis about the end
of the Western world or the U or Europe
it's a quite the opposite in my
impression after g7 meetings is a more
optimistic than then I expected
including our new partners around the
table I mean especially presidents Trump
of course it's I am NOT here to to be a
part of this of this new culture of
permanent leaks and
if you know feel free feel free we're
all friends here sometimes from time to
time we need also some discreet format
and data tapes and but what I what I am
absolutely sure after this meeting is
that despite some extraordinary four
markets of expressions behaviors etc etc
our partners in g7 are much more
responsible then then maybe the first
impression after the election in the
United States it means that in almost
every topics we found a common position
and it was much easier process than than
I expected including our discussions
about climate I know that it was maybe
because in fact the lack of a final
positive decision of President Trump
about Paris agreement it's it was the
most spectacular moment because as you
know only the best news our newest here
but my impression is that after this
meeting our our cooperation and
including our transatlantic cooperation
between Europe and the United States can
be easier than we than we expected just
after the election divided since that is
a very optimistic tone just just a quick
follow-up do you think that the United
States will pull out of the Paris Accord
that is really the key question here
hello it
sometimes too optimistic politicians
look look very naive and this is what I
want to avoid this but if for sure after
after our meeting with President Trump
in Brussels and especially after g7 I
think that that he is ready and he is
able and even determined to to change
this first and rather bad impression
after after his messages especially
during his campaign now privately and
publicly he sounds much more
pro-european and responsibly okay I
would like to go to Prime Minister so
now and and you would like to add
something I would just like to remind
the audience that you have translation
from Slovak and Czech into English
because the Prime Minister's will be
speaking in their native tongues Prime
Minister the floor is yours
sama same Nahuatl producer Chima wait a
kabocha Donaldo v-tach estoy muy macho
be so kissable cabeza Prieta rose to
Bratislava Globe second Ubu Donna
Oprah's convinced Nami do pharmacy
Britta moisture para presidenta
Europe square idiotic East Oh para
primera dama Gabriela yes Adam named
Omashu dodging I believe and it's a
shame that we not do not discussed it in
big detail I think that when it comes to
the relations between the United States
and the European Union the politics
creates a huge chance for the European
Union I wouldn't be nervous at all if I
were to generalize based on the expert
statements of the US administration that
the Europe should be taken care more of
itself we are more than 500 million
people in the European Union and Donald
you remember that when we had the
Bratislava summit we clearly stated that
the European Union has to be a more
significant player though we cannot
always rely beyond what the US
administration will say or whether they
will agree with the Russian Federation
or China therefore I would really grasp
this chance more timely and perhaps we
should discuss at European Council
meetings are frequently how to be
committed in various regions well
unfortunately despite our economic
strength despite our numbers of
inhabitants we do not play the role we
could roll around the second floor and
maybe this will lead to a discussion and
these meetings are about is nothing
whenever the US president was elected
dr. when Donald Trump was elected I was
asked that maybe I caught my attention
in his first statements that he made
after collation and I said that I was
particularly interested by his statement
and I'll be paraphrasing that as ago the
Democrats Yabuki export of democracy has
stopped as it was in the past
exporting democracy to certain countries
and let's be frank at this yeah get up
occasionally at the meetings of the
European Council some prime ministers
and presidents of course stated that in
the past we committed huge mistakes when
we thought like that just out of the
blue we could plant our ideas of
democracy human rights into other
countries there's a we're debris glands
let me give an example of Libya for
example Libya basically doesn't exist
today it's very easy to walk a regime
it's very easy to remove a dictator or
if a bomb but we didn't have a plan B
and the plan B was missing I would be
cautious and I would remind us to be
cautious in relation to Syria there we
could find a solution but do we have a
plan for this region region so on the
one hand we might be disturbed by some
statements from the other part of the
Atlantic but on the other hand I see
them as a great chance for the European
Union as a great transferable body to
complete change in the behavior of
global players such as the United States
Russian Federation and China so this is
what I wanted to add to this well as I
would say in fact that Europe also needs
a plan B for Europe because the current
structure isn't really working out the
way many had hoped I'd like to come to
you Prime Minister so vodka how do you
see the the current state of the
European Union there's a lot of
discussion at the moment about moving
more towards a multi-speed European
Union you come from a country that is
among the most Euroskeptic at least
according to the the latest globe sec
trends report which has just come out
where only 35 percent of Czechs said
they thought that the European Union
was a good thing what does that mean for
the future of the European Union sir
yeah the ketchup or Yakov odds are I
would also like to thank for the
invitation to wish you a beautiful
Sunday and perhaps I will also touch
upon the issue offer the new US
president the climate agreement from
Paris is an important thing but the
topic that has been that we've been
dealing with in Europe is the migration
wave caused by the war in Syria and I
assume that Donald Trump has the
opportunity as a new US president to
find ways how to promote political
agreement in Syria to stop the war to
end the war and perhaps allows at least
some of the people who fled the war to
go back to Syria and this is what we are
vitally interested in in Europe because
the migration mm pressure has been
stopped by the agreement with Turkey but
even the agreement with Turkey is under
pressure so maybe we should go back to
the key priorities that we have in the
security area and to my mind are
continuing a political dialogue in Syria
searching of looking for an agreement
that would end the war in Syria this is
something that we should expect of the
new US president within the role that
the United States play and within the
dialogue that is planned with Russian
President Putin and if the situation in
Europe and the and about the situation
in Europe and the skeptic atmosphere in
the Czech Republic
it's a paradoxical situation because we
worked hard to become members of the
European Union we are prospering we have
the lowest unemployment rate in the
entire European Union we use the
accessible of the easy accessibility of
the European market so we were able to
use it in economic terms for our
economic growth for the modernization of
the country at the European funds helped
us significantly so it's a paradoxical
to see the skeptical attitude that
really is there
well we witnessed recently the eurozone
crisis and degrees which perhaps really
strengthened the skeptical view of the
common or single currency in neurotic
and then we saw the migration crisis and
I think that contributed to these
capital attitudes of our people way and
about the future of Europe we certainly
follow the discussion or the multi-speed
your garber but we do see some years
it's hailed as a country without the
euro as currency we would wish that
decisions regarding the future of Europe
would take place at the table where all
27 member states are represented we have
enhanced cooperation on the possibility
of in hands cooperation and certainly
that would be a natural platform for
closer education reform there but at the
same time we don't want to see new
barriers created within the European
between the eurozone and other countries
we would terrible okay then have it um
it would be more difficult for us to
move forward to these other integration
rules where do we specifically see the
disadvantages to your own country if we
were to move towards this dual track
Europe with a much more integrated
eurozone there's nothing stopping the
Czech Republic from joining the eurozone
for example so what really is the core
the core issue for you there's there's a
lot of discussion in Poland and other
countries about losing money from the
structural funds and and so forth
there's worry about that but from your
perspective where do you see really the
main disadvantage from a multi-speed
here
the Commission's yeah she said she has
any vegetable I think me out there or
before country so do not use hero
servant with Slovakia being down the
exception and I may only congratulate
Slovakia how they have managed but it is
quite obvious that even the Czech
Republic whether discussions will be
more offensive especially after the
French and German elections we made it
back up higher pressure from France and
Germany to come to great the eurozone
will do more and adoption of euro in the
countries where it is is not available
yet and however if we compare our living
standard with the Western countries and
the countries who are using the euro we
have an urge to enhance the situation on
the public budget but we are still
lagging behind as far as the wages are
concerned and I don't say we still need
some day time on the package able to
increase real wages and to reshape the
structure of our empty economy a little
should have in order to focus on over a
tech manufacturing and production with
higher and it values should we manage
this will have of it also a more
positive attitude towards the adoption
alleged that but I think him a bit
romantic trouble sentiment it is very
important how did euro
will cope with the Greek crisis and how
much eurozone even hospitals got a
moment and we will review country such
as black a Slovenia Baltic her countries
and what is their experience with
adopting heroes what is what is your
what is your view on that you've
obviously been in in the Euro for quite
some time some people would say more
precious should be put on countries like
the Czech Republic and Poland to begin
the process of joining the euro what is
your view as a country in Central Europe
that has been a member of the currency
Kalama a curriculum yacht for NATO
program yasuo seems awesome well a very
openly I not agree with you that is
mainly the European Union who needs Plan
B I don't think Europe needs plan B what
Europe or needs is a good open - yeah
Europe the other respect sir not only
sow more respect towards its
international interest among its member
states that was I think that Rihanna
white
- reaction to the ropes cuny LNG's yes
applause communica by positive methods
our problem in the European Union is the
inability to communicate the positive
things well when I am a meeting young
people in BH Drive women Africa region
Rankin and 30 and we are trying to
explain them the importance of Schengen
if they do not understand me they more
considerate that's granted when I'm
explaining that I had to wait for three
hours
when I had my baggage checked any
control community for them it is
something unimaginable horror emailtosh
I miss Madiba emotional student when we
say that we did not have the opportunity
but is studying anywhere da-da-da-dah
good night just sit in the car find a
job in Germany Austria Spain or France a
pedagogy cavity currently McAra
cannot even sell any possible things
that we owe me currently one perhaps for
example the roaming you will you pay the
same price anywhere maybe did not use it
huge commended these are the real things
that we use for real people
this is also a problem of our own
ability to don't ask the positive
message as you know but it should be us
the national politicians who should
promote the European Union on the
national and as far as the two-speed or
multiple speaker Bureau is concerned
this is becoming a tragic comedy we are
speaking about the seconds we could
speed up
but this is quite normal we do have
countries that have Euro and those who
dot and my one of the Prime Minister's
of those countries have Europe and I
wish that every single decision that we
adopt in the eurozone would be done in
cooperation with the countries that do
not have euros because it is up to them
to decide when they enter eurozone on
the other hand I fully expect from those
countries who do not have you know euros
to respective convergence of those
countries who do have a euro so I will
have today a phone call with the new
French president and I will ask him
about these things it seems that there
is a new French German integration
engine under construction and I agree
with them we cannot have one currency
when one country has a balanced budget
the other one has a deficit budget so
those countries who are not in the
eurozone and have significantly better
results than the countries of eurozone
for example Poland or Czech Republic
this countries could serve an example
should they be in the eurozone is our
official position do you know if there
is a new bitch integration engine of
closer convergence of the universal not
only we want to be part of a discussion
we want to be on the train we want to be
in the quality that does in the group
around the Euro will be more convergent
you want to be part of it however we may
not allow this topic to be divisive
before the European Union as a whole you
want to be part of it want to
participate on it but we may not allow
it to be divisive how do you avoid what
Prime Minister Vito has described as a
tragicomedy this discussion about a
multi-speed Europe from becoming
divisive because it is by a state your
divisive and if I think to the reactions
from your own country from Poland
including here over the past couple of
days with foreign minister of a
Tchaikovsky repeating that it would be a
disaster for the EU of this multi-speed
idea were to gain currency how do you
avoid that from happening because there
already is a lot of discussion as you
described Prime Minister about it
there's the white paper from the
Commission and so forth there are all
kinds of ideas floating around none of
them are particularly new these are sort
of the same ideas get recycled in new
packaging and and they are very divisive
which is why they often get kicked into
the long grass and nobody talks about
them until there's a new crisis but
what's the way forward here first of all
I think that we we there's no reason to
panic you know and we we shouldn't panic
because first of all I am absolutely
sure that you remember the very
interesting announcement of marine lepen
it was just two days ago a few days ago
that the biggest mistake in her campaign
was the anti European rhetoric and this
suggestion that France should withdraw
from the eurozone in this part of Europe
we have sometimes a little bit skeptical
public opinion towards Europe like in
Czech Republic and very pure European
government at the same time in Poland
and in Hungary but ok let's talk about
Poland we have a
Euroskeptic are afraid to talk about
hungry yeah you're skeptical government
and with clearly anti-european rhetoric
from time to time and very very true
European public opinion almost 80% of
polls are happy of the fact that we are
in the depo Poland is the member of the
European Union nothing is simple in in
in this context there is no black and
white you know political and social
landscape but I think that we should
also clarify what we what we mean when
we talk about to a multi-speed in Europe
let's actually macro so I take the macro
ideas for example where he's talking
about a eurozone Parliament finance
minister and so forth which is basically
a parallel structure in fact it's
nothing new and nothing extravagant to
talk about specific and different
political or legal formats in the EU
first of all and a group of enhanced
cooperation are foreseen by tricky as
you know and we have maybe the most
spectacular examples of this enhanced
cooperation is eurozone or or Schengen
and it's I think it's quite natural in
this kind of very complex political
system like that you that you have
differences different level of
integration and also we have also the
different political clubs my experience
also as the previous polish Prime
Minister is that it's they were and they
are very useful in the process of when
we are looking for for compromise like
political clubs I mean this kind of form
of like visa fraud group by mark Benelux
Nordic countries etc etc
in fact what is the real threat today
it's not the two or multi-speed or a
different level of integration this is
our reality it will get reality it was
always our political reality in the you
the real threat is not a different speed
the real threat is a different
destination of different direction it
means that what is for me that the
biggest problem today in Europe is that
we have some some political parties some
government politicians media etc etc who
are questioning today the essence of the
you the essence of Europe essence means
liberal democracy freedom tolerance
freedom of speech this conviction that
what we need today to re-establish a
solidarity among other countries with a
liberal democracy like the United States
upon g7 or or including also Australia
South Korea New Zealand because the real
possible and the most brutal conflict
will be between this traditional free
world and new powers which intent it was
absolutely clear I've had it in in
Munich it was a if I remember well
Lavrov intervention in unique I can feel
this during our discussions with our
Chinese partners that that what the
intent is in fact to establish a new
so-called post west order and I think
it's this is the the real challenge and
all the differences between our Member
States in that you but this discussion
between the Member States is often wind
in the sails of the parties that you're
talking about who take a very
Euroskeptic view so is it really a
solution to just sort of you know
continue the status quo and to continue
talking the Europeans are very good at
talking about
future but when it really comes down to
brass tacks it gets much more difficult
are we at five minutes to midnight as
some people are suggesting that if
something but fundamentally doesn't
change that it is in danger of yeah but
you know just run amok that this bits
about about to the future of liberal
democracy all values principles this is
not a dispute between a group of member
states against the other group of
feminists it's a permanent and very deep
divisions and and disputes and arguments
among all European societies we have the
same problem also in a global context
for example today the United States it
means that if this is for me a
civilizational challenge not not only
you know a part of our permanent
negotiations in Europe and avec
historian II know I I thought it may be
my last remark but it this is our in
fact our political heritage this
permanent process of disputes to
compromise and to for example you know
to remember grief versus Persia during
the first and second person well and if
you remember who who on the wall it was
Greece without effective executive power
with constantly disputes and debates
between the city-states police I and
this very complex constantly arguing
organization of Greek police they they
confront with the centralized well
organized in fact authoritarian power as
specialists but Greece won the
confrontation
it means that for me the main question
today is not not the question how can we
reorganize the traditional European
model of very complex sophisticated
checks and balances political system
it's that the real problem and the real
challenge is how we can protect this
very unique model it's not as fast as a
political model in I mean fasting in the
[Music]
making decision process for sure like in
russia or turkey or in other or in china
but I'm absolutely sure that this is one
of the reason why Europe is still the
best place in the world this unique
system of limitation for every executive
power this permanent process of debate
this desire to find it and then every
single day compromise among member
states for me this is not our
disadvantage this is maybe the the
biggest at the best part of our
political rally I would like to come to
the audience in just just a moment so
prepare your questions I just had one
more question for the prime ministers
there is a lot of hope now in some
quarters that Germany and France in
particular after the German election
will take Europe forward that they will
pursue a grand reform plan when people I
find in central Eastern Europe hear this
they're not always they're not always
happy about it it's is it really
possible in an EU of 27 for Germany and
France to act as the motor as they as
they have historically maybe Prime
Minister feet so if you want to start
with that yes so much Pimentel all let's
go opera I already said that the Germany
in France may be the new engine of
integration mainly in relation to the
eurozone I wasn't thinking about some
principal changes in the functioning of
the European Union
and I have to agree with what Donald
said we shouldn't worry about proposals
that appear on a daily basis no we
receive the proposal to have a Minister
of Finance or perhaps there should be
new Institute's which have not existed
in the European Union before photography
is however I would consider it to be
along evil but our union started to only
focus so upon itself institutions are
functions and and disputes which country
will get which functions those are
prestigious posts in the European Union
and I am one of those prime ministers
are not excited about the idea to reopen
the fundamental treaties when we talk
about the Treaty of function of the
European Union for example and I think
the fundamental treaties create
sufficient room to move forward for
example the system of the so-called
enhanced cooperation that's a mechanism
monkey language can give a chance to
some countries to move forward in some
areas and other countries in very very
areas and one more remark if I may
oh sure service RJ Nikki did I ever say
that sometimes it is about methodology
we apply to our work and it's good that
we discussed this methodology at the
summit in Bratislava and then again look
arabic and we arrived at the first
results i would like to appreciate
donald's approach at the last that was
something to when we gave clear
political guidelines how to behave in
the negotiations with the United Kingdom
this document will survive these are big
very well prepared and we adopted in
here in five minutes after 5 minutes of
negotiations we were able to adopt it
and then we were had a general political
discussion but we have to learn and we
do it in the Fischer grant for group and
perhaps the vichy grant you know could
you be a good example
let's not table things that divide us
here it's clear
well the Commission comes with a
proposal today that every country should
pay 300,000 euros for any immigrant they
do not receive or perhaps that there
should be new obligatory clothes it's a
very few throw a stone among a most
water birds it's impossible to agree
from you know for functions on the
principle that this is where we can
agree so let's agree and if we cannot
agree we work on the lower level and we
are really high level I'm not as
skeptical it's a straight knee if you
started but you cannot even imagine what
it means when twenty eight heads of
state and government meet without having
to anything agreed and perhaps we have
eight nine hours of deliberations and
all of the sudden in the morning at 3:00
a.m. or 3:30 a.m. magically the heads of
state and government agree now when th
country's different interest national
interest back in the name of European
Union at the end of the day they can
arrive at a conclusion at an agreement
so on there are obviously things we
could improve but I wouldn't go against
the principles of my opinion I wouldn't
touch the foundations on which the
European Union is based and even though
we are a small country not the decisive
country that we will be very cooperative
we want to be inside we want to have a
say but we also want to bring the
Europeans into that what is what is your
view of this is do you also think that
there might be a need for cosmetic
changes maybe not the kind of deep
reforms that were hearing discussed in
in Paris and Berlin these days
masha'allah de Saavedra Prakriti mobile
government physics has studied that we
are against opening the fundamental
treaties the basic pieces we should
focus on steps that will be
comprehensible to our people and steps
that will be useful for the European
Union and member states
I think strengthening our security is
one of the priorities protecting the
external borders of fighting terrorism
stabilizing regions
in the neighborhood the of the European
Union but obviously there are economic
goals of promoting economic growth
promoting investment in Europe promoting
a technology change so that Europe is a
competitive unit also in future so I'm
happy that we do not go some long
winding deliberations regarding
fundamental treaties and nobody would be
able to understand apart from a few
experts but I'm very happy that the Rome
conclusions and Bratislava and Malta
conclusions the last summits of the
European Council say that we are
addressing specific comprehensible
issues that have practical solutions and
the issues that we encounter in our
daily life you mentioned that we just
discussed here without specific results
but the the agreement with Turkey is a
specific result that is the migration
pressure we have prepared a series of
measures helping us to fight terrorism
for example in the exchange of
information or gathering information for
example about passengers transport in
Europe we can also comment who is
entering the simplified regime in Europe
so for the last two three years we have
encountered many security crises and
we've dealt with them and about the
multi-speed Europa it seems to be not a
greater problem but if you look at the
practical space that we have in Europe
then certainly one of the lines is it a
Schengen then another would be euro zone
and then we have for example Romania and
Bulgaria who apparently are frozen
outside of Schengen and nothing is
moving if we take a look at how to get
to the faster lane for example in a
and this leads to the worries that the
Czech Republic has regarding the
multi-speed Europe yes if there is a
multi-speed Europe then we should have
clear transparent rules for everybody so
that all member states out of the 27 if
they so decide could join the faster
lane and that relates to Schengen that
relates to the euro zone and that
relates to structures that the euro zone
which is to create so a healthy measure
of cactus ism is right Mike I think and
about the franco-german engine or
integration engine I think this will
sort of increase the dynamism in Europe
but on the other hand I would be very
happy if the discussion would not need
to disrupting the single market the
Czechs are a very practical nation and
we appreciate the fact that we have four
basic freedoms in the European Union we
have the single market and we would be
very unhappy if this franco-german
discussion would lead to introducing
some protectionist measures non-tariff
barriers to trade within individual
member states that wouldn't be a very
good I would like to go to the audience
now there was a question in the back
here arm excellencies Europe enjoy the
value that we all could be proud of and
they were wonderful matter of democracy
but now these values are challenged
because different individual or certain
individual or certain European states
are having definitions of terrorism
security and their own and that does not
share with all the other members and
that the way the policy they have for
its money laundering financing
sponsoring terrorism a certain state or
or elements so what measures do you take
or what kind of assurance do you give to
the entire world especially to your own
citizen that you would not support or
you would give the surance to the
minority especially the muslim
minorities in europe that they would not
be stereotyped they would not be treated
differently as part of your own citizens
part of your own countries so this is
a new Europe you need to be clear about
messaging because mixed messages are
given by you and what's actually the
question you'd like to ask what kind of
assurance and what measures EU is taking
in fact to have a clear narrative for
all the European Member States and at
the same time assurance for the Muslim
communities in Europe I think we get I
would like to collect a couple of
questions because time short we've got
another one right here okay thank you I
saw the associate professor my question
is just remember to keep president short
cost exactly what what does the EU
performance in refugee crisis tell us
about the EU in terms of humanitarian
values and in terms of EU as a global
actor and how can an organization claim
global credibility unless it practices
what it preaches when it comes to
humanitarian values thank you okay maybe
then we've got one here microphone
you've got Hold'em I don't get
microphones switched on actually mr.
just
okay and a quick question to mr. tusk in
the event of brexit how long do you
think it might take for an independent
Scotland to rejoin a Europe
it doesn't wish to be okay maybe we
start with those with those three do you
want to start Prime Minister Prime
Minister veto on the the security
question yellow if I may I would focus
on the first question but also he car
that touched on the guarantees
safeguards which the European Union as a
whole should give to its citizens and
safeguards it should give to minorities
in relation to fighting terrorism this
is how I understood the essence of the
question welcome the god you're so
stupid
also I represented the Slovak Republic
also broken I would obscure sudha
problem the European Court of Human
Rights for 80 years in Strasbourg our
balsamic brownies are and I was a legal
representative of the government of the
Slovak nation and perhaps I would ask a
simple question here as well my sauce
Bravo shall we because what do you eat
Ziggler behave - a thief who steals a
bicycle in the same manner as to someone
who is organizing a bomb attack and
killed 50 people on that one of you and
we know that lucky for this person has
information that may lead our to Yahoo
ashing the little networks of other
attackers this is such question which we
have not yet answered at the European
level and I think that we are dealing
with it more individually and that leads
to a high degree of tensions in
individual member states I would reply
to a question
to our first task today is to ensure a
more intensive cooperation in exchanging
information together with the Prime
Minister sub-account we were on TV
recently and he said that this is the
foundation of fighting terrorism and the
safeguards that we give to new citizens
and to minorities based on the
applicable legislation that we have in
the Member States today I wouldn't look
for anything else I'm just replying to
your question with a counter question
shouldn't we perhaps go a bit further in
fighting terrorism in some areas um what
is important to have a good feeling that
I wouldn't have to take my shoes off at
the airport or perhaps that I wouldn't
have to take my belt off at the airport
and then on the other hand have the
unpleasant feeling bad then if despite
these measures someone will blow up an
airplane so the line between human
rights and fighting terrorism is
somewhere else than between human rights
and the classic fight against crime and
perhaps we should discuss this topic in
more detail and then another topic you
are sir ask the question Diavel of
humanitarian approach of the European
Union to migrants or humane and of
course subjective of the women we all
are aware that these people in a very
very difficult situation and they need
our help
well how about just and we have the rich
part of the world if I were to talk
about the European Union as a whole
above that is something else and don't
be angry with me but above the humane
approach on the part of the EU towards
these people before me safety of the
European citizens is first safety and
security of EU citizens everybody so
let's go
and in Slovakia I'm discussing about
Florrick citizens in the case of
European Union I solve your win the
European citizens what happened in
Manchester is incomprehensible and it
will perhaps lead us to other
discussions on the on European level and
I do believe that will not discuss
whether we need a new Minister of
Finance or whether we should open up the
treaties but we'll discuss how to calm
down the European public so that they
feel safe when it comes to measures in
fighting terrorism president tusk if
you'd like to address the question from
the Scottish gentleman and if you could
keep your answer as short as possible
maybe we can then take another couple of
questions if you want to think about
what your questions are in the next
couple minutes sir yeah yep Europe is
still the most open continent or the
most open place in the world for
refugees and migrants and we have
thousands and thousands people
organizations institutions deeply
engaged in humanitarian assistance
there's no reason to complain when it
comes to this very context of migration
crisis Europe is of course not a perfect
one but still the best example in the
world also when it comes to to this
readiness to sacrifice something not
only money but also our time emotions in
did you know during our discussions for
example with our global partners about
migration and I could feel some kind of
fatigue or that they are tired I mean
for example the United States Canada
even Japan on the this discussions about
migration but as you
if you know well when it comes to Canada
we are talking about 20,000 refugees and
migrants I mean that during the
migration crisis Japan close to zero
Europe more than one and half million
this is why I think that of course we
have we have at different approaches we
have a different rhetorics in Europe
about migration and and different
emotions but generally speaking the EU
as a as a group of States and Europe as
a whole continent it is still the most
friendly the most open place for
migrants and and refugees when it comes
to Muslims minority and if this very
visible risk that that some political
elites Mazen maybe it's the worst word
there was definition Alex but some
political groups and they are ready to
to to claim that in fact Islam is a
synonym of terrorism of course we can't
agree with this kind of simplification
on the other hand we should understand
also emotions especially after such an
event like Manchester or other attacks
in Europe
my advice is on my suggestion is that we
have to start but the genuine
discussions with Muslim minorities
representative how can we cooperate
together to exclude Islamic radicals
from our societies - because I think
it's not enough today to show only our I
mean Muslim solidarity after attacks
without deep engagement from Muslim
communities in our countries we have no
chance to to to eliminate this radical
part of of the Islamic world if if we if
we want not only to discuss but to act
something very substantive when it comes
to the radicalization
we need a real engagement from from from
Muslims in Europe without this we will
be as round as helpless as yesterday and
this is my my appeal and if we want to
stop this very dangerous evolution when
it comes to ideas and emotions in Europe
I mean if if we want to stop our
radicals our I mean Christians so we
need massive engagement this positive
engagement in our common fight against
radicalism extremism and and I think we
should instead of course terror we
should leave that subject there thank
you thank you very much we are running
out of time unfortunately I had one last
question but what about Scotland I saw
the I thought I thought that you were
some religion along skillfully dodging
that question I thought but if you want
to address it quickly please little
suggestion yes I still I'm not ready
okay have I just had a very quick
question for for the panel before we end
the subject is European disunion the
future of Europe and my question would
be do you think that we will see some
kind of reform of the EU over the next
couple of years some further integration
some steps to repair the sort of myriad
of problems and I would like to begin
with Prime Minister Sobotka
Takata from Jewish there's me a lady
that I hope that we are already seeing
the changes
so we can influence it we can experience
it and it will certainly regard security
foreign policy economic policy and I
hope that Europe will stay open for
countries which meet the criteria to
join the opinion and I think that in the
Balkans it will be a quite important for
the stability of the region so it's not
about big plans or big starts but we've
already started and we have important
political goals that we agreed upon in
Rome when we commemorated the University
of the treaties of Rome and now we
should not just withdraw into
bureaucratic approaches and we should
try to accomplish things speedily the
final word go to our host Prime Minister
Peter you have before
what povedilla showed us we are the
replies yes we will witness certain
changes let me just express my
conviction that those changes will be
pragmatic rational and I was very
pleased when a Donald was elected for
the first time as a top representative
of the European Union and when he
managed to win again even though maybe
it wasn't as simple as the first time
and I'm saying that because growing
young countries such as the Czech
Republic Slovakia Poland but I have to
include Hungary when we talk about the
Vichy grab group these countries
underwent a unique transformation
process and in other countries it took
much longer and sometimes it seems to me
and excuse us for saying these things
that perhaps we have a molten healthier
common sense when we look at things we
are more pragmatic and I hope I believe
that after Donald's leadership the
pragmatism will win and that we will not
witness just empty words as
and that we will witness solutions that
will help everybody it's not only about
people being more satisfied in their
opinion I see a lot of the nervousness
among young people and it's also
supported by the media and by the
Euroskeptics and therefore that way I
would like to thank the organizers of
this exceptional event Montego Bay mob
that they also give room to these topics
and on the part of the Slovak government
sir I read let me assure you offer our
support for organizing the event next
year and if you manage to implement all
the changes that you've planned you'll
still have our support thank you very
much well let
just we're talking about the organizers
let's bring the the president of globe
sect to the stage Robert Bosch thank you
very much thank you try many circuits Oh
for your excellent support this was the
most powerful panel we ever had at globe
SEC so I know you have a very busy
schedule so you'll probably have to
leave and but in the meantime let me
thank you and clap hands for the very
interesting panel you we are very great
that also the president of the Donald
Tusk has joined us for the second time
as well thank you very much while they
are leaving I will be saying just few
words at the end of corpse ik just to
summarize the three days we had we are
coming to the end of glob sick
conference and I think it was a
watershed in many respects let me share
with you some facts and figures they
show clearly that a lot of people
followed us not only in this room but
fold us closely all over the Europe and
the world let me give you some
statistics we were pleased to welcome
here in this hotel not only one hundred
one thousand three hundred guests from
70 countries 150 speakers we managed to
facilitate meetings that were 135 we had
130 interviews and welcomed more than
210 journalists when it comes to the
outreach outside of this room we had 400
70,000 impression on Facebook the reach
of unique users who have seen our
content has been 3 million 50 thousand
and we had 7 million 700 thousand
impressions on Twitter and think it is a
tremendous following of our debates here
where life of Weber life on
MSNBC AP and the International coverage
was really huge thank you for all the
journalists who were covering this but
2017 was very special for us at globe
SEC this year we introduced for the
first time the second stage where we
were discussing the multiple futures
that were predicted and debated and I
think it was a fascinating to follow
these discussions and we will definitely
continue with that in the future in the
upcoming conferences but also it was for
the first time that the globe SEC Policy
Institute with its new management and
the international team led by jakub
Vishnevsky played such a crucial role in
providing the background research for
all deliberations the initiatives of the
Institute were part of the solution that
were being proposed and considered and I
think that is of tremendous tremendous
success but I want to thank to several
people without whom globe SEC would not
be possible and first of all let me
thank to rusty cell culture whose wisdom
and common sense have guided me but also
the globe SEC team throughout the years
Thank You rostislav for
I would like to thank also to minister
light jack and the Ministry of Foreign
Affairs of Slovakia for a huge moral and
material support it was Minister light
Jack and Deputy Minister Kurtag who have
been helping us every single day in the
preparation so thank you even for that I
[Applause]
cannot forget our corporate partners cup
captains of industries that are showing
us the way to progress and prosperity I
will not tell everybody of those because
we mentioned everybody during the course
of these meetings but without their
support globe SiC would not be possible
thank you very much for all the cultural
partners I also want to thank to our
international advisory board for their
wisdom and counsel but among them let me
specially thank to two special
individuals who were with us for a long
time and who are our longstanding
friends first of all it's General John
Allen
and Secretary Michael Chertoff who are
leading our international initiatives
thank you let me also thank to the
police who kept us safe in this place
and to the hotel staff for the
extraordinary service they've made
during these three days the last but not
least let me mention the great work done
by the globe SEC team with the
leadership of Milan Salah and McHale
chief the smooth functioning of the
conference was due to the quiet work
behind the shades of dozens of
individuals and interns who work for
globe SEC they've been really working
hard not only these during these three
days but for for weeks and months and
months for preparations for these three
days and it is a huge huge thanks for
them and for their dedication that they
prepared
[Applause]
if I have one personal take away from
the conference
it is the conviction that democracy with
all its downsides has one amazing
quality it is able to constantly
reinvent itself bring new ideas and
adapt to the changing circumstances and
we can get ahead of the events we need
to add up to the future but also make it
the way we like it
and it is among us among about this
community which is here so let me leave
you with this thought and I wish you a
safe and happy journey back home and see
you next year at the globe SEC thank you
[Applause]
clewd
come on come on come on come on I told
you I'm going to do this to conclude
conclusions I'd seen the confirmed
conspiracies in the world so nothing is
by an accident by an accident this day
it's also Roberts 34th birthday so happy
birthday
[Applause]
we don't have to choose between trade
and progress