[Music]
we don't have to choose between trade
and progress countries whoever they are
they must have the right to choose their
security relationships for themselves
kind of all we're asking is can
countries in Europe spend 2% automating
the intelligence we see this as a best
way how to solve everything else look I
mean first of all donor money is not
necessarily only coming from the Gulf
states right there is quite a lot of
donor money actually coming out of
Europe we are sure that Russia China
Iran F cyberattacks of savvy espionage
that's false news in itself wouldn't be
harmful
it gets harmful when it is disseminated
I don't think the intelligence is
getting politicized I think you're
reporting about what the intelligence
community says is getting permanent size
[Music]