[Applause]
good good afternoon ladies and gentleman
can you hear me okay
am i clear and I'll try to speak as
slowly as possible giving my giving my
brother regional accent Belfast come for
some complaints about that last night
but I blame that on the very great
Slovak appear so anyway here we are
gonna discuss a very important subject
the lethal nexus between terrorism and
crime and indeed the funding of
terrorism the expansion of the terrorist
war chest through criminality I'm
brought under the subject because I
write about it occasionally over the
last three decades I've worked for
various news organizations from the BBC
to the Guardian and The Observer
newspapers and in many ways what
happened in Northern Ireland in Ireland
during the the conflict called the
troubles in many ways it's a excuse me
why you're from theater it presses what
was happening in the 2020 of 21st
century in terms of the nexus between
crime and terrorism so for example we in
hardened pioneered the whole use of
smuggled fuel to fund the IRS campaign
for instance and a whole range of
counterfeit and illicit goods that again
was pretty much pioneered in areas like
South Armagh North life on the Irish
border during the conflict now we have a
number of experts here today on the
panel who are going to discuss this new
connection between criminality and
terrorism so I'll introduce you to our
panel
they are hansi Akopian blur who is a
coordinator for only United Nations
Security Council no less in operations
against ISIL
- al Qaeda and Taliban the monitoring
team that looks at those organizations
we have Peter Norman here who's the
chairman of
Special Representative on countering
violent radicalization for the OSCE he's
also professor of security studies at
the department of war studies at King's
College London we have up and please
forgive me I will get this right our
visa
Giusti ani who's vice president illicit
trade strategy and Prevention corporate
affairs for Philip Morris International
knowledge management and we have Keith
gross who's groves who is the vice
president of consumer customer fraud
management Europe from MasterCard and he
works with 14 industry experts located
across 10 European countries so if
you've ever had a problem your credit
card you think it's being here or
someone's been hacking into it keeps the
mother talking Keith I would make a
quick exit after this thank you very
really thank you if you could be one
party with queries yeah so um before our
be our panel introduce and start talking
and we have a good discussion in the
studio we're going to have a look at a
video now which shows what we're up
against in terms of the trade in illegal
goods and criminality that funds the
Terrorism of the 21st century so let's
have a look
[Music]
okay so a little visual food-for-thought
there but the the threat and and also hi
it's funded Peter there's a report in
the London Times today which says that
20 are 23,000 jihadists living in the
United Kingdom two questions is that
exaggerated and if it is are we talking
about not just active terrorists with
maybe their supporters especially those
in the financial field the number
strikes me as very high previous numbers
were typically around a thousand five
hundred to two thousand I think that's a
lot more realistic I don't see how that
figure would have increased tenfold in
the last one or two years so I would
have to read the article to figure out
exactly what is meant by that figure are
these actually potentially violent
extremists or are they also people from
this you know kind of supporters
sympathizers or indeed people who may
help sometimes inadvertently with the
funding and Finance can you just hold on
or not inadvertently in what sense oh we
talking about people who collect money
food money do they think is a good cause
a charity that may end up in the coffers
of Isis that's what we used to say I
think one really interesting and as far
as European jihadists are concerned new
phenomenon is that emerging nexus
between crime and terror and people who
are being caught up in terrorist
networks like the people in Manchester
to a very significant degree have pasts
in criminal networks so for example if
we look at official figures from various
countries two-thirds of the German
foreign fighters two-thirds of the
people who went to Syria in order to
join Isis and similar groups two-thirds
have criminal convictions in the case of
the Netherlands France Norway it is over
50% that is different from what it used
to be maybe 10 or 50
years ago when that was the exception
rather than the rule and has important
consequences in terms of how these
people radicalized it has important
consequence in terms of the significance
of prisons as breeding grounds it
facilitates terrorist operations because
these tip these people typically have
easier access to weapons they're used to
violence so radicalization trajectories
happen more quickly and of course in
terms of the funding quite often what we
see in relation to the funding of
terrorist plots is that they are funded
by means of quote unquote ordinary
criminality by drug-dealing
trades and counterfeits and all the
range of criminal activities that these
people in a previous life used to carry
out for profit
now they carry them out in order to fund
terrorist operations haunts the Northern
Ireland experience about fuel smuggling
is interesting because it was one of the
major means to bring in revenue to fund
the IRS armed conflict that may be over
but can you explain how Isis and dice
have zoomed in on the fuel industry to
fund their campion find the Caliphate
and beyond yeah I mean I would not say
that they assumed into the industry on a
global scale right there they assumed in
on the production in Syria by basically
conquering all the oil fields in Syria
and one oil field in Iraq as a funding
stream so the good news is due to quite
sustained sustained military operations
over the last year and a half that has
been cut by half it's still as far as we
can see the the greatest income source
for ISIL core in Syria and Iraq but it's
come down from from from quite
significant levels of hundreds of
millions per month to about tens of
millions per month which is good news
but we are dealing with the war economy
so there is a captured market that
requires fuel and gas inside Syria so so
I so we'll always have a market for that
kind of product and then it of
course while losing territory its income
is diminishing what is always a little
bit under under snot understood is that
also the costs are reducing so if you
are holding Ramadi Fallujah as cities
you of course can extort the local
economy to a large extent but you also
have to run Ramadi and Fallujah which is
significant costs that I involved and so
if eyes now transforms into a less of an
emphasis on holding territory and more
emphasis on external attack and building
a global network to that extent the
income it does have from hydrocarbons
and others it is still more than
sufficient to do that but it seems to me
if that's the case that if they have
tens of millions that's reduced quantity
than what they had before that in terms
of running campaigns and the outside of
the Middle East they come from very very
long time absolutely and it is actually
preparing for for that long run at the
moment so there are a few moves that
we've seen where the organization
adjusts obviously it's communication
internally has gone into encrypted space
which was something that you could
expect they dodged the the command
control downward so it's no longer very
hierarchical operations where the top
knows everything that's going on but
it's delegated a relationship
responsibilities downwards and it is
actually sending out money and
potentially even individuals out of
Syria in Iraq so a year and a half ago
anyone who wants to leave Isis got
executed as a traitor now that's no
longer the case there are first
indication that people are actually
getting coached on what to say if they
cross the border and what they wanted to
be extradited to once they've of Iraq
and Syria in order to ensure that they
are not going to get arrested
so it's placing people around the world
already and it does the same thing with
the money obviously still financing
every single month it's affiliates in
particular Yemen Afghanistan West Africa
as well as Somalia but it's also placing
money outside these areas of conflict
and in trying to invest them in the
licit economy apparently in order to
prepare for the day we're holding
territory in Iraq and Syria is not going
to be the money producing
aspect for the organization anymore
obviously we saw on the video products
and one of them was the product that
your corporation is behind globally in
Ireland in places like Italy we had a
mafia involved in illicit trade in
tobacco how much has an organization
like Isis got into the racket thank you
for the question every just before
answer the question just let me explain
why Philip Morris International producer
cigarette is here today I mean the
reason is pretty simple is that every
pack of cigarettes sold illicit
illicitly it's one pack less that we
sell so we have an interest a business
interest in order to reduce this illicit
trade and the illicit trade like oil or
this little cigarette is a simple and
easy commodity to trade in simply
because they're easily available they
transport very well they are not
perishable you can slow them and
therefore it makes them a very useful
commodity for organized crime to to use
to give you some an example some numbers
if you buy a container of cigarettes in
some place of the world which could be
Vietnam Uruguay Bello Russia Dubai
different place of the world you can buy
a container for maybe 100 or 20,000 US
dollars you smuggle that container into
a high price country like Europe and you
can make two million dollars so the
return on investment is extremely high
and the risk of being caught ending up
in jail is very low so organized crime
use user cigarettes as I mean to fund
themselves that's what we see and
they're expert in this panel which are
more qualified myself to speak about it
very much that the Terrorism are also
getting involved in even if Isis to make
that example are against smoking they
are quite okay if the cigarettes past
the territory and they get a cut on the
on the transit
so I don't think the majority of illicit
trade don't get me wrong is ending up in
the mind of terrorists by all means but
even if it's only a small percentage I
think that's already a very important
and something that we should counter and
it's not only about the the big money
that the terrorists can make but also
the money did the small cell or
terrorists can make if you take the
example of a the one that happened in
France a couple of years ago of a
Charlie Hebdo one of the terrorists that
was financing himself by selling a fake
Nike shoes once again a product which is
easily available easily to find you're
not going to make big big money but it's
enough to fund his apartment food and so
on you're not looking at big money - for
these cells to operate but the product
like a cigarettes
it is something available and so it's
easy for them to use for making a some
money into to finance themselves ok so
it's not only the big money the big Isis
but it also did that terrorist that's a
good point to put the patient at a small
level as well on this tiny cell of
terror unit somewhere in Europe or
beyond Keith's up I covered a court case
a few years ago in Belfast about a
jihadist from Algeria I and he was a
very prominent character but he's very
much under the radar lived in Dublin and
Belfast wasn't carrying out attacks on
the island but was planning other stuff
in Europe and North America two
interesting points about the kiyose one
was he was a master bomb maker we do say
explosives officer shoeing haha he with
his device could destroy a plane but the
second thing was he was he had a mini
factory producing fake credit cards
which would be used around the world by
his Britain me by his comrades in what
was an al-qaeda what is the level of
that kind of abuse of an illicit cards
and the theft of cards how is that being
how did they operate in terms of our
guest transport the question about in
terms of impact that we see with the
MasterCard in terms of through global e
it's such a very very small percentage
and 0.00 something of the value that's
moving in the payment systems but I
guess cervezas point of view you know it
doesn't take a lot of money to commit
somebody
and I recognize that and I think Peter
mentions as well the lot of the the
people to move into terrorism they've
got criminal backgrounds now and so what
would will recognize is some of the
financial crimes are out there so credit
card fraud and the payment for all in
terms of the legal systems has always
been seen as a low impact crime and so a
lot of comers have enjoyed that that
ability to commit crime the risk is
lower all generally high in same it's in
terms of buying tobacco so a mass hub
we're very much about recognizing that
you know we're about financial inclusion
within the community and ensuring that
everybody has access to the payment
system as a security person as a fraud
prevention expert that comes at a cost
sometimes that the more we open up a
network we know that the bad guys the
criminals will political ways of trying
to exploit that so particular to that
particular case in in Belfast you know
here in Europe we've had it for over a
decade now he's we've moved away from
the automatic magnetic stripe technology
we've moved to chip technology and
MasterCard is a technology leader now we
continue to push the envelope on
technology to ensure that we we open up
the payment network in a healthy way
that enables consumers to get access to
it in a way that makes it more and more
difficult for criminality to get in I
mean for me criminals will never shy
away from trying to come after my
payment system it's advantageous to them
we've we've got a very high level of
security in there now and globally the
the in view of the chip technology we've
enjoyed here in Europe it's spread
across the role globally North America's
it's got that as well now so we're
starting to squeeze out a lot of the the
so-called organized crime that try to
exploit the weaknesses in the payment
system as they perceive it and so for me
I'm very interested to see where they go
next they don't move away from financial
crime in its entirety but we're
certainly making it harder and what we
haven't they're having to find their
left work a lot harder to make a same
amount of money so criminals are often
quite lazy and so if they can't make
money they will move into other areas
and familiy
that's where from a mascot perspective
we work very closely with a lot of other
companies and industries around the
impact of financial crime and viste
particularly around sort of brands
damage that's taken in terms of people's
products being counterfeited and our
brand being associated be that well
that's why we're here today is to you
know help mine people
with your MasterCard we take our brand
integrity very strongly and safety
security is at the heart of a lot of
things we do now we want to eradicate
the problem but we also know that it
moves from one industry to another
hunter when we talk about Isis the
Caliphate in Iraq and Syria and okay
it's shrinking we gun clearly it's going
to shrink further physically at least
they do have to work with people if you
have to have allies don't get to sell
this oil I mean who are we talking about
nation-states here are we talking about
companies private corporations or
individuals we now have what's the
evidence in terms of who's helping them
shift the oil and make the profits yeah
I mean that the face where ISIL oil in
in Syria is it sold internationally it's
over it's simply because the volumes are
no longer there right so prior to the
conflict the area that ISIL controls now
produced about one hundred and fifteen
thousand barrels of oil per day during
the conflict of an ISIL took over
everywhere about forty five thousand
barrels a day now we are around 15 to
25th at a thousand barrels of oil so
there is simply not enough volume that
gets completely absorbed in the market
in in Syria by all their everyone in
Syria by soil because that's the
monopoly producer and don't forget the
country is currently under an
international embargo foil so there is
really no other oil to have then then to
buy from the one who produces it but
there are three issues I think here on
the panel that that needs to be
distinguished one is the isakoff
financing this is the big headquarter
right but then there is also of course
local financing this is what what Peter
was was referring to and my colleague
from Philip Morris refers to were sells
financing their concrete operation on
the spot in their home countries and
then there is the transfer of money and
there the values a store of stored value
cards is something that the the
Financial Action Task Force F ETF is
among many other things is currently
looking at at one way to transfer value
from A to B it is to buy stored value
cards and then simply sending them
either in person or by by post to
other party to then get the money off so
that these are three different issues
that I think get muddled up too much and
there is a clear crime terror network
when a connection when we talk about the
local financing there is a clear
connection between terrorism and
organized crime when we talk about the
transport of these Goods antiquities
other goods that they smuggling and that
there is not as strong a connection
between the criminal organization and
al-qaida core in Syria simply because
it's a war situation right so yes
there's a lot of crime going on
perpetrated however not by professional
criminal organizations
Peter I won't spoke to a senior member
of the Ulster Volunteer Force loyalist
terrorist group and he said that the
best suppliers allies they had were true
believers obviously so they had a true
believer in Canada that was supplying
them with weapons in the 1980s but he
said the hardest thing to acquire
weapons is to work with criminals
because they're easily infiltrated by
the state many number agents of various
company country's police forces and so
on is that a kind of a defect that even
ISIL will have half the deal with the
fact is in a way the crime Nexus works
both ways you can work in favor of this
did where criminals can be bought off
and contempo them I sex or the CIA or
whoever sure it can work both ways even
though in Northern Ireland the kind of
the direction was the opposite one in
the case of in the case of European
jihadists we see that they are criminals
fast so they already are criminals but
police records and then they turn into
jihadists and but in fact we've seen
from Isis is that they have in some of
their online publications they are
encouraging their supporters to act and
in fact even dress like criminals so
they are saying to people if you acquire
weapons dress up like a youth from the
ghetto so people think you're criminal
not a terrorist in fact in the case it's
almost a funny story if it wasn't so
tragic
in the case of Charlie a door and the
hostage-taking at the kosher supermarket
that happened afterwards amedy coulibaly
who was the perpetrator of that who had
sworn allegiance to Isis he had bought
his weapons from the guy who had sold
him weapons for years even when he was
still a criminal
and once the attacks happened that
weapons dealer called up the police and
self-reported himself he said I had no
idea I just thought this guy was an
ordinary criminal had I known that he is
a terrorist I would have never sought
phrasing are an ordinary decent criminal
ordinary decent criminals exactly yes
and and and and so that also makes it
problematic because the people who are
involved with these guys who sell them
fake IDs who sell them weapons don't
necessarily know that these are people
who are terrorists that's the difficult
thing about that Nexus are two speakers
from the private sector I'd like to know
hi you also have your own intelligence
gathering networks and you have your own
experts in what way to you work or
connect with the law-enforcement
agencies of of your country or indeed a
global bodies I mean I'm already sort of
channel the information yeah sure being
a working in the tobacco industry we
have a lot of knowledge about the
distribution system we track all our
products so each of our faculty grits
has a unique identifier so it's not like
honor and on a label of the water you're
drinking where there is a bar code which
is the same on all these bottles of
water one on our pack of cigarette is a
label which is which is a single I put
that single for that single packs is a
unique identifier so we get we can track
at this so this is a valuable piece of
information that we have and we share it
with the law enforcement because one the
law enforcement that clearly has a much
stronger and tools to do investigations
which we as a company cannot do
but one advantage we have is that we
have a global footprint and we know that
the product are flowing from one country
to another because we can track it it's
valuable information for law enforcement
so we do cooperate a lot and I think the
the solution is always a having a
public-private partnership because each
act can do part of the puzzle and you
need a comprehensive solution in order
to face and to tackle the problems of
this this magnitude do you think there
should be an overarching global sort of
bridge between private global sort of
businesses and international law
enforcement I am a strong believer that
going forward more than today the
public-private partnership has to be
strengthened simply because the private
sector if you think in some instances
some international company multinational
companies have a geographical footprint
which is very big they have at the
knowledge they have the resources and in
many cases these act as non-state actors
a bigger than countries and I was
reading the Financial Times that you
mention it on the anarchic on the first
pages today so maybe many of you have
read it on the G set on the g7 which
says the gathering on Sicily I agreed to
step up efforts to fight terrorists in
the wake of the suicide bomber in a
Manchester including by pressing big
tech companies such as Google and
Facebook to do more to suppress Arabic
content so I think this is what big
multinational companies should be doing
is to be doing not only because they're
pressed but they should also do it
because it's the right thing to do and
there's a win-win for all all players in
case yeah so I see a very unique
position I guess in terms of MasterCard
as a payment technology company I don't
actually issue the credit cards or the
payment cards the bank's through doubt
in their respective countries just
remember that Foxborough yes so if you
want to come to me about problems in
your card I'd love to help you bike on
you need to go to your bank but that's a
serious point and that's where we sit in
a nice unique position that we aren't we
provide that global network so one of
the things that we did we
we worked very closely law enforcement
we do that the different operations that
we support around the world there's
operation Pangaea that Interpol runs
around the illicit and trading in
counterfeit pharmaceuticals we work very
closely with the European financial
coalition in terms of child abuse and
how that's been commercialized we work
in a number of very specific areas to
deal with that and we work with law
enforcement globally as well and
interesting for me is the point to pick
up briefly on hands meant about stored
value and and this is something that we
hear quite regularly around stored value
cards and prepaid cards as people call
them and for me from a criminality point
of view they enjoy the ability to hide
and disguise their business money
laundering etc cash provides a great
opportunity to do that and for me what
one of the advantages is having those
store value colleges that it leaves a
footprint
they cannot shy away from the footprint
so actually most I do understand that
the point being made the the war on cash
is greater that that's such a much
greater hidden trade that we don't
expect to say so I'm saying from Lois
autumn perspective yes we work very
closely with a lot of agencies to do
that in a very proactive manner as well
and certainly in my industry as payments
continue to grow and and the internet
can change the boom we've all got
payment devices now are now on a handset
it's truly global so we certainly see an
absolute rolling in supporting Loyalton
and at government level as well in that
matters as well Peter I heard a phrase
last night which I thought was excellent
was coined by an expertise police
officer working with 2d radicalize and
prevent young people getting sucked into
the kind of jihadist networks and it was
the cyber caliphate and what he said was
that the cyber caliphate will replace
the physical one if and when the the
readouts in Syria and Iraq are
completely shrunk but the ISIS moves to
cyberspace that directed scampi and if
that's the kiyose and surely there is a
lot of money sloshing around and it's
war chest this is going to go on for a
long time and it will be more Manchester
style attacks rather than you know
taking over the likes of Ramadi and
Raqqa and so on mmm for sure I think
there's a cyber caliphate already and
there has been
for a number of years I think it's
important to kind of understand what's
going on if over the past five years
30,000 over 30,000 people from 100
different countries have traveled to
Syria joined jihadist groups it's
probably the most significant
mobilization of foreign fighters in the
Muslim world that has ever taken place
the second most significant was the
anti-soviet jihad in the 1980s in
Afghanistan and of course what happens
in Afghanistan in 1988 was that the
conflict ended and all these up to
20,000 people who had traveled there
including Osama bin Laden asked
themselves what now what's next and then
as a result of a conflict that happened
in 1980s in the 1990s and 2000's you had
these so-called veterans of the conflict
turn up in other conflicts from Bosnia
to Chechnya to Algeria to the
Philippines typically making these
conflicts worse and more religiously
extreme and you also had some of these
people getting together to form an
international terrorist network that
ultimately carried out the attacks on
9/11 but here's the important thing the
attacks on 9/11 happened 2001 that's 13
years after the end of the conflict in
Afghanistan so we're now talking about
the Manchester attacks and the conflict
in Syria hasn't even ended all these
fighters haven't even had to ask
themselves the question what next the
clock hasn't even started ticking yet so
I don't think this will end anytime soon
I think there will be consequences of
what's happened in Syria for many years
to come
and that's why it's so important that we
think about these consequences and start
preparing ourselves just before I throw
up before I throw this open to the
audience Hans ivz said a very
understanding Arabic Google Facebook and
given that we're talking about the
increasing importance of the cyber
caliphate what come the big high-tech
social media organizations do to be part
of the scariness lists read online and
then in physical
yeah so let me just put the this this
terminology cyber caliphate a little bit
in context right so there was for a
while thinking that if because Isis
emphasis on holding territory if you
take the territory of the organization
you solved your problem right that was
in the mind of a lot of the policy
makers and in rightfully the military
campaign was was initiated to take the
territory of to decrease the funding but
that's not solving the problem that
simply phase one right and so we're now
entering phase two where it's no longer
about the physical territory the cyber
caliphate is simply a means by which the
terrior by which the network will get
directed right so it's not about
conquering space in cyberspace is
looking at the internet as an
operational tool and that's that's what
we are working on at the moment in new
york so obviously there's a lot of
privacy and and and and freedom of
speech issues involved in here but they
are also very clear operational aspects
if we talk about terrorist communication
with each other if we're talking about
dissemination of knowledge and
particularly on ID designs right and
quite a few attacks have now begun also
in europe to use IDs and if we talking
about financing calls for financing
transferring of money using tools within
the internet and that's where i think
there is a great opportunity for a
stronger public-private partnership I'm
not saying it's it's not happening
already you have already here in New
York the in Europe the internet referral
unit at Acura pole that works with tech
companies on issues of terrorists
contents on the on the website but more
can be done right more can be done on
identifying who is using your products
by these companies and identifying what
are the products precisely used for and
what are according to their own terms
and services legitimate and not
legitimate users Peter just wanted a yes
just a couple more things because I
think that's really important that's a
really important area the first is the
mistake that was made in 2011 should not
be repeated in 2011 we mistook a
movement for an organization al Qaeda
central was defeated and everyone in
Washington DC concluded the
is over but in fact of course we're
dealing with a movement the jihadist
Salafist movement I have no doubt that
in five years time there will still be a
movement I do not know what particular
organization will lead that movement I
have no idea I personally I rather doubt
that in five years time the Islamic
state will still be as important as it
is now
but there will still be a movement and
they will perhaps transform into a
different organization and one of the
most important debates and most exciting
and interesting debates that is
currently starting within the jihadist
movement that is not over is precisely
how supporters will respond to the
decline of the Caliphate I mean yes I
absolutely agree it's not the end of the
story but in 2014 the leader of Islamic
state declared essentially a
thousand-year Reich the territorial
strategy was in many ways the unique
selling point of Islamic state two years
later that Caliphate not state is
crumbling and of course there are
supporters of Islamic state who are now
asking questions and while saying how
can it be that something that was
declared to be remaining and expanding
forever is now falling apart and how
will we respond to it what does that
mean for the legitimacy of the entire
project well given that we're probably
going to expect a mutating neo Islamic
state or something else it's going to
need to finance itself so with that in
mind let's throw open to the audience
and for any thoughts on the nexus
between crime and terrorism in the 21st
century so people had this gentleman
here
Thank You wonderful presentation I I'm
surprised that you're using the leaf of
Halawa so easily which is an Islamic
term and has a positive meaning so the
way you're talking it is unfortunately I
hear it that you talk directly to
al-qaeda to ESS to all the extreme
groups who are not even representing one
or two person of the Islamic world so
excuse me I apologize for that one that
this communication is in fact giving
them the grounds to recruit more so it
means you're accepting them as
representative the Islamic world which
is not your intention definitely and we
should in fact be more careful being in
a West and in fact we need to find out
the success story of our own society
here Islam Muslim community in each of
these respected nations they are the
success story they know better in fact
about the Islamic work to come and be
exposed on your front page of the media
not all the time explosion or not or not
all the time coding in fact the extreme
groups don't you think that we are
failing that context we are not doing
much we are not bringing the success
story of our own nations here the
Muslims are not an Islamic world we have
Muslims in each of single countries why
do you address Muslim like in only
melodies Muslims on each country are
your success stories your main partners
most of the panel's I don't see any
Muslims who are really speaking from the
Islamic point of view or being a Muslim
scholar only somebody who did the
dissertation on Islam or some kind of
things they come and speak about this
fate I think we are losing more than the
core we are not having the right people
not addressing that one and more giving
the ground for the extremists to recruit
more thank you and not finding out in
fact the elephant in the room who which
countries are in fact feeding sponsoring
that one instead of exposing them
because of the great man and woman in
your uniforms they die because of this
conflict we are even making deals of
weaponry with them who are not even
having an army or soldiers thank you
handsomely
responded on no I mean I agree with the
fact that you need to engage the Muslim
communities here in Europe stronger and
highlight the positive aspects and that
there is a danger to see that all
terrorists are Muslims and I I hope I
wasn't misunderstood when I was talking
about the financing aspects I wasn't
trying to legitimize a State Building
project of the Islamic group here and
the Security Council has been very
careful in its wording actually as far
as words like Caliphate or jihad is
concerned and you didn't hear me use the
word yeah so it is it is absolutely a
word of terminology and obviously the
work on the root causes is an important
thing however if you look at the
European jihadist not sure Peter can't
talk to this in more detail it's really
hard to find a profile right so it's not
the disenfranchised only or the
unemployed only or the uneducated only
so it's not the ones who are in any way
objectively speaking marginalized from
society that joined but it's also your
university graduate your engineer your
doctors or joining so that is obviously
a problem of identity here right so can
can you be a German and Muslim and that
is a discussion that the society needs
to have what does it mean to be a Muslim
in Germany and that should be done
I take Germany as an example because I
come from there but that's a
conversation that each society has to
have with their Muslim community of what
it means to be European and Muslim at
the same time and there are many success
stories but this this phenomenon showed
that there is really at least in a small
part of society a crisis of identity and
therefore clear-cut extremely radical
ideas that says in the world falls
neatly into good and bad and you know
here are clear ways of what good is and
everything else by definition is
therefore bad it may be an attractive
offer kidding I agree with most of your
points I just want to say something
about the terminology because that's
something that I think we always
kind of make too complicated and having
been in these debates for 20 years
there's always someone who stands up and
says all the true meaning of jihad and
why do you talk about Islam and of
course I'm not speaking to an audience
was likely to be radicalized we are
happy
I hope so at least we're having I'm
speaking to an expert audience and I do
not expect any any of you to to easily
fall prey to the terminology that is
being used when we talk about the IRA
the Irish Republican Army were not by
using that term we're not implying that
they are the true inheritors of the
Irish Republican tradition when during
the Cold War we were talking about East
Germany by its official name the German
Democratic Republic I don't think there
were many who believed that that there
was anything democratic about East
Germany that's how these entities call
themselves and I think it's okay to call
themselves by what they call themselves
and that does not mean that I buy into
it
I absolutely don't but in the case of
Islamic state there is an important
thing which is that this group calls
itself Islamic state we don't like that
but I think we're missing an important
aspect of that organization if we just
refer to it as a terrorist group because
that group sees itself very much as a
state it acts as a state it has a
bureaucracy very complicated burocracy
it has an army or what it sees as an
army when last year those 20,000
documents of Islamic state were captured
journalists were asking me how can it be
that a terrorist organization is keeping
records on its members and my answer was
it's precisely because that group
doesn't see itself as a terrorist
organization it sees itself as a state
and it looks at these recruits as
members of its army so I think the state
aspect whether we like it or not is
actually a very important characteristic
of the group that we're dealing with
with because they see themselves as has
anyone else knowledge any thoughts about
the nexus with crime I mean
and the fact is in many ways that anyone
I suppose who's buying it as a consumer
in the illicit market whatever it is
could be inadvertently guilty of funding
terrorism the 21st century just a
thought to throw out to the audience
sir uh thank you for the interesting
remarks so far terrorist groups have
been fairly entrepreneurial about
adopting high-tech solutions to their
communications needs we talked about
stored value cards but I have to believe
that with everything happening in fin
tech and money laundering by criminal
groups in the high-tech world I'm
surprised that you haven't talked about
the potential for their cybercrime Nexus
and jihad coming together in the money
laundering and criminality space if
anybody has any remarks on that I was
fascinated to learn to each pack of
cigarettes has its own identifier code
but that that opens up all sorts of
possibilities for well many actors
anyway maybe gif I know they say she
could feed that question in particular
so I have to take the first part in
terms of I think for me it's interesting
so I'm a fraud prevention expert that's
how I consider myself today
and for me I'm looking at in a very
simple way someone's trying to break
into my system to somehow take value out
of that and three it's as simple as that
in the last five six years the word
cyber has grown to mean so many things
to so many people I think we're losing
sight of some of the the actors that are
involved in cyber crime so in the car
payment business I hear now a lot of
so-called cyber criminals are attacking
the payment system and here in Europe we
suffered a huge ransomware attack and in
the last couple of weeks certainly I
felt that close to home having being in
hospital the day it happened and and so
the impact of cyber is so broad and
widening I think people don't don't
truly understand what what it means but
in terms of do I see
terrorist groups or so-called terrorist
groups looking at the payment system as
a means of moving money around and and
using that to fund their activities and
I don't recognize that in the waiver we
talked about some of the acts that we're
talking about here I agree as you
mentioned the case in Belfast
I see isolated cases of that but it's
not systemic but what I do see is quite
often cash being used to move moved
around by criminals to move value
between different groups so the stored
value one for me again is is interesting
if I look at the legislation that that's
moving through in certain countries in
Europe my email for is there the value
in some of these stored cards is so
small and so minimal it doesn't really
plane advantage to criminals and again
it comes back to in a moment you
electron if either the value actually I
can trace it I can see where it goes and
I can tell you where it went in and
where it came out so actually from a
criminal and from a terrorist
perspective the the payment systems
aren't useful for them to do that I can
move money round I won't disagree with
that comment but it leaves an audit in
the trailer and if these guys want to
operate in the shadows and not get cold
then then they don't want to do that and
the last comment I will make just fill
out the internet as well we're starting
to see a lot of the mainstream
criminality that the hackers who trading
data and they're getting pushed now into
in the so called dark web and they're
getting pushed into the corners which
from a from a mainstream payment system
that that's good for me because it means
a lot of my customers don't fall victim
to scams on the internet because they
don't trust it and I know with my brand
being misused to supposedly legitimize a
corrupt business offering or a website
whatever it means now that people to
become less and less prone to becoming
victim of that and a lot of still are
but if we're making the job more
difficult within our industry for all
hallows it and pants again and then
we'll another person the audience of go
ahead yeah I think that you have a point
cyber and
as much I understand the cyber tax is a
world which we only started to discover
so your point is very much valid
tracking every pack of cigarettes means
that we're going to have a huge amount
of data which can be hacked so
definitely by the Pointer I'll just add
two things to it first
what you also mention about the value of
each pack is quite small so there's a
disturb which is say is a natural
defense against cyber attacks which we
haven't seen so far on a data basis but
on the other hand the suffice it been
the industry has voluntarily tracked
their products and as of 2019 there's a
European directive on tobacco which will
regulate that all tobacco security in
Europe will have to have a unique
identifier in each single pack so in two
years time in May 2009 T when this
director goes into force then the
problem could really Bologna be much
bigger because it's going to be for all
Europe all tobacco products also valid
point I mean two things on the on the
high-tech issue so obviously there was a
great concern around crypto currencies
right Bitcoin in others for cases
internationally so far right so it's not
yet it's not yet there simply our
interpretation of what's going on is
they just don't need it yet right it's
still much easier much better much
secure to move money by the wire money
money service providers of all adults
who are unregulated in most countries
and then so there is really no clear
overview of how much cash flows in and
out from these on a global scale and by
by money carriers all right so as long
as you keep underneath the international
barrier of ten thousand equivalent in
your local currency of ten thousand US
dollars by entering a country you don't
even have to declare that you bring the
money with you so moving money in small
amount and don't forget this is not a
commercial enterprise this is not about
a time is money time is in unlimited
supplies so if you need to move a
million dollars why are hundred carriers
and that takes you four months that's
the way you do it
because that's simply the safest way to
get your cash across on the on the
stored value cards before we completely
leave this out and yes you can see where
their board potentially by whom if they
don't pay in cash and yes you can see by
where they get out if they don't if they
again try to use electronic means but
you don't know who is behind that right
so it's a transfer mechanism I'm not
saying is a big problem I'm just saying
this is one issue which is fairly simple
because you don't have to devolve your
address details if you buy a stored
value card unadjusted that last night
for 400 euros I had not to present any
identity so yes of course in that job a
stored value card for 50 years worth bob
was bought but by whom no one knows I
paid in cash done right so so there is a
it's a simple mechanism that is there
that that we provide as a society as an
economy that is easy to be misused to
transport small amounts I'm mind you but
when we talked about the financing of
not of ISIL but of individual attacks
small amounts is what counts you don't
need a million dollars for Manchester
you need if I don't remember correctly
one hundred and fifteen thousand dollars
all in including flights and training
for 911 Paris was much cheaper and I'm
quite sure that Manchester will come in
a way beyond that that marks so a
hundred dollars does get you along a
long way in that respect this gentleman
here in the second rope would like to be
scared and might be from others
that's an honor and I'm gonna like you
can keep your questions pretty succinct
thank you what aspects of fighting
financing of ISIL are particular to the
group compared to financing other
fighting groups you know the situation
and the triple front here in Paraguay
Brazil is something that's very often
talked about fund some other militant
groups so what are the things that we
can learn from fighting the financing of
other groups applied to dodge and the
things that are particular to - thank
you
generally speaking there are four means
four types of means by which groups like
that fund themselves the first is
support is getting support from
supporters whether it is state funding
or voluntary contributions by people
they came to represent the second is
income that results from participating
in illicit economies that's where we see
a lot of smuggling for example third
aspect is legitimate income that's what
makes it different from money-laundering
for example because when you're dealing
with criminal money you're trying to
launder it into legitimate money
terrorist fund terrorist funding can't
be legitimate to begin with it becomes
dirty by the purpose for which it is
used so no one questions for example
that Osama bin Laden was wealthy he was
wealthy and his his his his money was
legitimate he inherited it from his
father
it became dirty by the way he used it
not how he acquired it and of course
we've seen that in Northern Ireland in
in a number of cases and the fourth
method of income is what we've seen
particularly in case of Islamic state
which is the exploitation of territory
that's what happens when terrorist
groups transform into insurgencies whole
territory can start taxing there people
can start generating income from natural
resources etc etc etc and the problem
then becomes when these groups hold
territory that the entire structure of
international counter-terrorist finance
stops to work you know because we know
that you know ISIL had a budget of 1.7
billion perhaps in in 2015 but of course
most of that money was completely
disconnected from the international
financial system that's why I'm saying
we have to really rethink how we counter
terrorist financing when we have groups
that hold territory which by and large
do not participate in the international
financial system and then we have the
local manifestations of these groups who
are essentially self-funding
and who carry out terrorist attacks that
basically cost nothing that cost less
than a thousand dollars the most
expensive terrorist act over the past
two years was the truck attack and knees
because that truck cost three hundred
dollars to rent all the other attacks
with knives with cars were cheaper than
that so you have to ask yourself the
question what is the utility of our
current ways of tackling countering
terrorist finance when we're dealing
with a modus operandi that doesn't
involve the moving of a lot of money if
I had if I was a policymaker I would say
instead of putting more layers on it the
international banking system let's fight
petty crime knowing that a lot of these
jihadists have criminal backgrounds
benefit from drug-dealing benefit from
criminal networks that seems to be a
more efficient way of targeting
terrorist finance than trying to look
for suspicious transactions that only
become suspicious if you know that that
person is is a suspect in the first
place okay two more people punch these
two questions together if you wouldn't
mind we'll chop them some simple kind of
the last question is very close to what
I wanted to ask
I've heard I want to hear other schemes
for example I heard using use
automobiles the stored value there and
transfer that across borders but also
the the other transfers through
charitable organizations direct
transfers from other people who want to
do it you know what percent of that is
financing terrorism and how effective
are we in terms of shutting some of
those other types of finance mechanisms
down on this gentleman here that
representing ourselves College actually
I'm surprised that we are talking about
organized crime without mentioning it
Italy and I come from Naples so like I
have like direct experience of certain
things like if we look at the history of
the three major Italian mafias like
Kimura and rangita in mafia they
actually grow in connection with the
state I mean it's not like a secret that
Kabul used Kimura to guarantee Garibaldi
when he was coming
so now and also I mean now we are
talking about the Islamic state but if
we look at order like jihadi
organization I think a QAM we have seen
in the operational shift that Algerian
terrorism as known in the past 10 years
that they turn from like pure jihadist
organization to a sort of hybrid
organization and we either even had
smugglers like Abuja head who turned to
be major leaders without I mean
measuring Belmokhtar of course in those
like do you think there are some state
responsibilities in this rise in the
sense that certain states of the region
in North Africa or in the Middle East
they didn't do as much as they could to
stop these emergence because of lack of
capacities but also because the interest
of some people in like making money out
of these projects and the second point
is I mean in Italy sometimes we're
talking about like ways to stop this
phenomena like do you think there are
experiences around Europe and the word
that can be used as an example Naples in
the 90s was flooded with sea contraband
like cigarettes and now this phenomenon
doesn't exist anymore in any case has
been reduced Italy from this point of
view between like the 90s and the new
century made the number of changes that
allow to like reduce significantly D
this type of traffic's and the third
point is if they are making money out of
drug smuggling
should we liberalize like drugs just to
recap completely this kind I know this
is like a bit of a provocation
electrification let's go oh that's a
very provocative point let me start at
one of the legalization of drugs will
undermine global crime at criminality
and funding terrorism there you go
look I mean if you look at Afghanistan
you do see a very close connection
between the drug production areas and
areas with the Taliban hold control
right so there it really is it's really
hard to distinguish word track Network
ends in the Taliban start Taliban got
financed initially by three of the major
drug dealers in Afghanistan in the setup
of the movement so this has been a very
close marriage on that form but how it
was not the case that when near to try
to clamp down on the poppy production
that the farmers started to support in
Taliban again because they promised
they'd get continued for just I'm not
because the Taliban are very much this
is not about NATO climbing down this is
the Taliban having are involved in all
stages of the production so one thing
that that needs to be understood is that
you cannot generate seeds out of your
harvest so you need an external seeds
provider for your poppy harvest that was
the Taliban then of course you need
money to live on until the harvest so
the Taliban afforded credit schemes to
the farmers which magically always were
less than the were more than the
expected yield of the field and the
profit that the farmer could could
generate so the farmer was in internal
debt to the Taliban and and therefore
you know you see Taliban forces wavering
according to the harvest times to
harvest in Afghanistan and when there's
harvest time there is a significant drop
in violence every single year because
the farmers are now on the fields and no
longer with the Taliban because they are
in a in a dependant relationships to the
Taliban
so it wasn't night or climbing down it
was the Taliban having a grip on that
industry which incidentally is not a
traditional industry in Afghanistan
it started funnily enough in the fight
against the Soviet Union
where in which I hadn't discovered that
heroine production is a neat way to
finance your activities so this is a
long long-standing problem but not as
long as people assume Afghanistan did
not used to be the main product producer
of heroin in the world so that's where
you see very close connection and the
rest is where you see a group there's
groups infusing themselves in the flow
of illicit goods right so you mentioned
multiple Mokpo incidentally and this is
important I know I'm sure the colleague
from Philip Morris knows that is also
known as mr. Marlboro because he was
very much involved in the Marlboro
smuggling activities but not in the
producing of Marlboros but in making
sure Marlboros went from A to B so
that's where we see on
drug side the infusion of of Tears
because drugs flow and illicit
activities flow were governs this week
and where governance this week terrorism
is very likely to happen right another
issue is by one of the members of the
audience was the abuse of charity by
given terrorism on the cheap all your
thoughts on that I mean you know the guy
standing I said somewhere robbing a ten
and you don't know where the money's
going to how important cannot be and
what can be done to monitoring I mean
this is where we see the risk at the
moment um we did not see ISIL trying to
addition a lot of external funding for
the last few years the argument was
always the organization wants not to be
dependent on external funders ie
generous donors who usually give money
with a condition attached to it
however ask now that and then ISIL has
proven the concept this is an answer to
the the other gentleman's question has
proven a few concepts here right so
exploiting oilfields good way to make
money the special conflict zones
smuggling antiquities perfect way to
make money and they're still acting
although they no longer looting as much
as they used before as service provider
for everyone else who lutes antiquities
in Syria in Iraq so you can not only
need to hold territory to make money out
of antiquities so it proved a few very
innovative concepts now as this gets
more difficult as the territory shrinks
and there is of course this danger that
you have again a trying to procure funds
by asking donors in particular misusing
charity organizations so as we've seen
in Afghanistan with biopharm al haramein
where entire NGOs were set up for the
purpose of funding al-qaeda in
Afghanistan the risk that this is going
to happen again and here is where the
current situation is a tricky one
because obviously you want funds in
large amounts flow into areas like
Ramadi Fallujah and other areas then
hopefully soon Mosul in Iraq to rebuild
however as the as these are high risk
areas you will not be able to as a
charity organization get a bank account
which means there is absolutely
no view of the flows that go into that
territory that in combination with ISIL
potentially looking again to misuse
money flows from charitable
organizations is a really dangerous
situation because if you have 100
million dollars flowing in and you have
no idea who how much when and where it's
received then you do have a big problem
on the other hand on the commercial
banking side where the compliance
officers decide to de-risk it's a
situation where no government so far can
give them straight guidelines of what
are the compliance criterias if you have
a multi nation funded a project and you
have as many compliance requirements at
different compliance requirements as you
have nation-states funding the project
so the compliance manager in the bank
has no way to gauge its risk for its
organization so the only logical
conclusion is to completely deal with
any any charity or organization so
that's a big problem showing each one
nervous yeah I just want to do maybe
respond to my Apple Italian compatriot
about all the questions asked
one is what have we learned from Italy
in the last 3040 years on the vigil
contain mafia and the Camorra I think
one is that a lot of was fascinated many
years ago was to seize the properties of
the camorrista the mafiosi and I think
that one actually worked there was an
adduct or one or one of the big bosses
of the remember his name anymore but he
said that put me in prison take away my
freedom but don't take away my
properties I mean when it talks that the
properties is ready you touch the NDA so
this this law
you could know better I forget to him
but anyway ft that was one thing and the
other thing is you say is the connection
between these organization and the
politics I think the answer is obviously
yes and I think in the tobacco industry
we see that as well
I mentioned beforehand and it's nothing
new the the president of Paraguay is
been known to produce cigarettes in his
country and actually there was a
Congress hearing in the Congress the
United States a couple of weeks ago
where mr. Otto legi said exactly that
that the president of Paraguay the
biggest producer of cigarettes he
produces 60 billion cigarettes where the
market absorbs three billion so 60
billion produced three billion consumed
in this country what with the other
fifty seven billion end up smuggled into
Brazil and the other countries and
that's identity at the at the light of
the Sun so everybody can see it but you
have other examples and in Belorussia
which also on the Middle East in Dubai
this plenty of a cigarette producers
Dubai which are producing there to
basically export abroad and and do the
EMAs know it that's a question you can
answer
any other questions audience anyone want
to contribute anything yes someone over
there listen yes we're right at the far
wall
first thank you it's Matheny solutely
from Germany I was we are currently
running some projects on this issues not
that deep as you did Peter Norman but
we're just beginning and we had an
interesting dinner session yesterday on
this issue and first I would like to
make just make some remarks on the
discussions that took already place that
I think it's it's it's a really good
point when you name the people or the
subjects that we talk about with the
names that they give themselves so this
is the model thing if you want to be a
German Muslim you are onto a Muslim this
is a new modern concept of identity we
cannot pose identity upon them if they
call themselves jihadis they are jihadis
in my point of view that's how I treat
people but that when they constitute
their identity the second thing was the
cyber caliphate we headed yesterday yes
we will still have this ideology staying
there and we will still have some
veterans day they they are experienced
in war zones so these two things will
not go away the topic that I would like
to hear maybe a little bit more about is
the the state that you were talking
about that is was different because it
is a state it has a bureaucracy and it
was the first time that that we see that
flood of women because they wanted to
build up a state to have to have a new
community for Muslims and so on from
their point of view more the Muslim way
and yesterday we had a session here
where it was about the middle east so we
heard that terrorism is very cheap I
think radicalization is more expensive
so to keep the whole thing running is
more expensive but when we think that
you have the geostrategic setting in the
Middle East that the is only codes
developed could only emerge and could
only become as big because we had a
sunni-shia divide
reduced complexity now yesterday it was
a whole hour that they were speaking
about that but this that will not change
as long as we will not change Iraq and
the Syria setting so that many people
who gave power to this kind of
organizations in order to be represented
in a kind of maybe sunni state it will
not change and this makes then the
question maybe we related closer to to
the subjects we are talking about today
so terrorist attacks in Europe are not
expensive yes and maybe it makes sense
to look at the petty crime yes but the
the broader movement and the narrative
and the future veterans and the future
conflicts they will be invaded by these
veterans because they are parasites of
war as I call them they appear
everywhere where you have a conflict and
then you have an inflammation and and
how can we how can we cope with a
situation in the Middle East and bring
it in relation to Europe thank you okay
thank you so let's have a reply to that
place Wow I mean having followed the
turmoil in the Middle East for the past
six years I'm very I'm very humble and
very modest when it comes to predictions
because I've seen the past six years so
many experts that I truly respect as
experts get it completely wrong I do
think what happens in the Middle East
and again that is my opinion
is a truly historical transformation
that is perhaps in some ways comparable
to the 30-year war in Europe in the 17th
century and just like no one knew in the
middle of the 30-year war that it would
one day become the 30-year war and what
would be at the end of it I don't think
anyone can say with certainty what will
be at the end of this truly historical
transformation Isis is only one aspect
of it we have as you pointed out a
sectarian conflict we have internal
conflicts within a lot of countries
between author Terry ins Islamists
representatives or perhaps more
democratic ideas we have a number of
countries in which we have no effective
governance and the conflicts seem to be
particularly
bad in those countries where several of
these fault lines coincide so in Syria
you have a conflict about governance you
have a sectarian conflict and you have
the jihadists in Yemen you have the same
situation and I I'm not going to predict
exactly what's going to come out of it I
feel that probably whatever is going to
come out of it will not resemble how we
started in 2011 that I'm certain of and
that's a really difficult challenge for
policy makers in Moscow and in
Washington because a lot of policy has
been geared essentially towards
preserving the 2011 state order if we
now accept that perhaps that cannot be
preserved should be continued to invest
a lot of energy into keeping the borders
where they are or should we embrace and
form and shape a new order I don't know
the answers to that that's what I
started with and that's how I'm gonna
finish can I have someone else you're
all in Sudan fictive get the microphone
please okay on a sec to remind you that
if we can focus on this particular
subject on crime finance and the support
of terrorist entities thank you
it is leastly south course uh-huh yes
sir I want to focus on Peters last
question which is very provocative um
Lisa said from the BBC I wonder if you
could talk more broadly about the flows
of money which are long known to have
come from the wealthy Gulf states at
this point but you mentioned the Afghan
war the biggest movement of them there's
been a lot of money going from wealthy
Gulf states to Syria to Iraq to other
countries and that's both private
through the foundations who fundraising
at mosques and official now we're told
in countries like Saudi Arabia that they
have stopped the official money going
and that now they have tightened up on
their financing so it's almost I was
told in Riyadh it's almost impossible
now to send money anywhere but yet the
allegations both there and in other
countries persist how important are
these flows and of course this is even
more important after the Riyadh summit
where there was a new
Arab in Islam leaders standing together
with President Trump to say they're
going to fight extremism and the
ideology thank you good can I briefly
respond to that because that's a really
important point Li's because it's it
goes back to the question before because
ultimately it really again comes down to
that tired phrase one person's terrorist
is another person's freedom fighter and
there are questions of legitimacy and
certainly we we are quick to forget but
in 2011 2012 the West supported the
so-called rebels in Syria it is true
that they radicalized since then but we
should not be surprised that a lot of
countries in the Gulf region essentially
until 2013 14 essentially viewed the
conflict in Syria as part of the larger
confrontation between Sunnis and Shiites
and being Sunni they basically supported
everyone on their side some of that
money ended up with extremists Salafist
organizations and that's when they
stopped they stopped it a lot of it did
and they stopped it at the point when
they realized that it would come back to
haunt them
but essentially until 2013 it was
essentially seen as supporting our side
in a regional conflict and a lot of the
charity is from Kuwait from Saudi from
Qatar that were involved in funding the
Opposition in Syria did so sometimes
with the explicit support of Western
countries so let's not forget about that
because our view of that conflict has
changed too they bought so I get the
difficult part of the question right
look I mean first of all donor money is
not necessarily only coming from the
Gulf states right there is quite a lot
of donor money actually coming out of
Europe sympathizes off of the Germans of
the French of the Italians of the of the
UK guys who are fighting with ISIL right
and and the Secretary General at the end
of this month in a report that we helped
him draft is going to highlight the
problem of debt
bank accounts where European foreign
fighters maintain their personal bank
accounts and sympathizers put money in
those bank accounts in Germany in UK in
Italy in France and it gets withdrawn
outside the conflict zone by by simply
using their normal bank card right so
that's an easy nice way to transfer
money using the official banking system
where all of the controls fails because
no money moves goes in the account and
out of the account so that's financing
that has nothing to do with the Gulf
states that's coming out of Europe right
simply using the fact that everyone in
Europe has a a bank account in a very
very smart way so it's not just a donors
in in the Gulf it's also donors in the
Gulf and it used to be donors in the
Gulf mainly for al-qaeda but as I said
so far currently and we're talking about
the risk assessment of charities not the
actual ongoing situation so far Aizen
has not put a large emphasis there was
always going donor money towards ISIL
and he continues to do so from
individuals but it has not yet set up a
system like al-qaeda did when it was
running the camps in Afghanistan where
entire charities were set up under the
guise of doing good work in Afghanistan
Waffen foundation right building roads
in Afghanistan and as a side job
building building the camps of al Qaeda
in Afghanistan that has not happened yet
but as the internal financial streams
are going to get more difficult this is
a potential that it's going to happen
again Keith can I just interject with
the question about that particular money
Network supporters in Sheffield saying
getting money from abroad recycling the
money from their own bank account in an
English city somewhere hi is there any
way to trace that and disrupt that
Network well I guess from a technology
perspective one of the things we
advocate at Marcy colonies is improving
on security and a lot that each of them
by how people access those financial
instruments so we're very much behind
biometrics we believe that strategically
where we need to go in terms of
improving security so I guess and I'm
this is not my area of expertise but I
suspect what all starts to see is the
fact that we will
surely false people to be the only
people who can access their bank
accounts which is what I would like to
have happen which means they then can't
share those credentials is somebody else
you can't move your fingerprint or your
your retinas around other people to use
so what we'll see is again by by having
the traditional banking systems the
security improved upon that will have an
impact of squeezing the problem and it
will go somewhere else and if I go back
to the cache conversation but we'll
continue to do that and for me within
within payments and selling MasterCard
this to technology continues to improve
on that it just exposes so much of of
criminality to being seen more obviously
though I think that in this context
we're going to see that start to happen
that's shift where people won't be able
to share those those financial
instruments will go out really will push
them back to going up get our cash it
works and this gentleman here wants to
thank you for that thank you and just
want to follow up on that point because
I was at the previous session on
artificial intelligence and it's we were
talking about pity crime its shadow
economy producing money for terrorism
and I'm sure the text of this the
financial veg dog so many organizations
are dealing with these kinds of social
activities so is it possible that
finally we will produce a software or
anything that can follow up on patterns
of activities that you can showing that
the basis to follow up so that when
philip morris recognizes something and
can you bring some really good examples
what has happened already in the past in
an interagency operation of at that
level that it's really pity crimes not
gulf states
pouring millions into Bosnia but but
then these small things happen in our
own country so we have the legal right
to act and to monitor but still we need
an interagency operation I guess from a
financial perspective is we work very
closely with your functional agency
subject here in Europe with with Europe
oh and they that I conduct very good
organizing coordinating activities and
certainly Interpol play that role as
well so as an example then I will talk
about
the the movement of human beings around
the world and using Airlines to conduct
that and to move people around in
Airlines you need to pay for that and
traditionally you know they don't want
cash they want electronic payments so
it's gonna happen very shortly every
year the payment industry gets together
click collaboratively with the travel
industry and the airline sector and we
law enforcement and we we partner
together to share real-time intelligence
on what we suspect to be people being
moved from from one country to another
either against their will or and be
knowing me what they're going to end up
arriving at to doing that in that sea of
the country and we share that
intelligence that's a model that we
certainly endorse it mascot is a
public-private partnership approach we
mentioned earlier on and then we we do
similar things I mentioned Pangaea and
illegal pharmaceuticals that ability for
us to do that it's very powerful when we
were very good at disrupting those
networks and again what we do with that
is what we learn for some very closely
the byproduct or for that always is that
eventually the organized criminals
working out the methods that we uses it
must be a mineral no and they'll come up
with something else and what we're
seeing in my industry is we're slowly
pushing that out into areas where
general consumers won't go and certainly
some of the work we've done you
mentioned that the shadow economy aim to
cleaning this part of Europe and there's
a huge amount of cash and money being
moved around in shadow economy and that
doesn't touch my payment system and we
certainly advocate for the fact that the
more we can move cash out of the cash
system into the electronic system we can
continue to have that that working
relationship with law enforcement and
any governments and regulators as well
to basically ensure that people who
don't have access to financial
instruments can get it in to the system
they don't have to rely on cash and that
then exposes that money for view of
governments it wasn't where taxation and
that money can be taken back into the
system and redeployed in invested where
it's needed for the bed of the community
so we try to play that that that will
360 view at MasterCard
Wrigley yeah I finally I just remembered
I once asked a former paramilitary how
do you move money a but if you don't
want to use the banking system if you
don't have the beat Reyes and one thing
he said a brilliant place to do this
Neal bars by O'Neill bar because money
is
moving all the time people are getting
their nails in every 15 minutes which is
a great way to recycle the cash quickly
keep it propped up but actually leads to
a question a more serious question but
properly was mentioned there that
somebody's in the audience mentioned
that we have a lot of examples in
Ireland were working active or
underground organizations buy a lot of
property I mean I was in a restaurant in
Belfast two months ago and I imagined it
somebody's next member of the IRA
Belfast for kidney says we will not
guess we own that restaurant right now
that's been known for retirement
purposes they've given someone a job but
it's their restaurant is there evidence
that prop the property market around the
world that organizations like Isis are
moving into as well well there is one
quite striking example it's not ISIL or
qaeda related is actually Taliban they
parked I think about a hundred million
dollars in a country in the specific by
basically using the immigrant community
and making them an offer that they can't
review so you buy a house we give you
the money you can live in the house but
even we need the money you will sell the
house and so the whole scheme broke down
when it was clear that that entire
streets in one town were owned by Afghan
immigrants who had no conceivable
economic way and all houses cost about
half a million Australian dollars had no
conceivable way to actually earn that
money to buy that house so this was a
placement scheme but that's the only one
that I'm aware of what this was done on
a very large scale
not to finance anything but to park
money for the time when it's needed and
to make sure that you have it in a value
that is likely to go up over time okay
fascinating any other questions or
points anyone from the audience what's
the risk as one of the park here
hi there and thank you very much for
your respective inputs and if I may and
focus on the nexus between crime and
terrorism or the man on which ie with
view as the terrorists appropriation of
criminal activities to follow the rims
and I wonder if we should actually be
focusing on the enable us to both crime
and terrorism and to that I'm thinking
about and you've discussed it between
you and those individuals involved are
limited only by their imagination
so how there is their funds will be from
Nike trainers from oil and everything in
between so if you tackle the enables of
transport of finance cyber as an enabler
to our activity and tournament inhabit
us you will impact on both the crime and
terror Nexus the my question to you and
following that theme is how much do you
see corruption as an enabler to both
crime and terrorism yeah I always get
the different questions yeah so it is
corruption helping terrorism absolutely
right what would be the eradication of
corruption go a long way to help the
problem yes M is the eradication of
corruption D going to be the end of
terrorism no because it simply is an
enabler so yes there is a connection
there but I do fully agree with that
that you need to target the facilitators
and that's what what my part of the
Security Council that I'm advising is
doing at the moment I mean we there is
the global sanctions list against ISIL
and al Qaeda that has about 275 plus
individuals at the moment on the list
and the focus at the moment is
distinctly on the financial facilitators
of whatever kind be it um smugglers or
Antiquity smugglers or oil smugglers or
money service providers that they deal
in a systematic way to transfer that
money to put them on a global sanctions
list because those facilities are
supremely vulnerable to publicity so
it's not about what Member States do to
implement the
sanctions is simply the fact that the
name is on a globally available public
sanctions list of the Security Council
that says US ISIL are qaeda sanctions
list that will really greatly reduce the
ability to act as financial enable us
because as the going between between the
terrorist groups and illicit economy
they do need an address they do need the
company potentially to loan the money
and they do definitely need a bank
account at one point or the other and
all of these three things are much
harder when your name is connected with
with ISIL in a public manner so there is
an instrument globally speaking that
that can be used in a far more frequent
way that it's been done so far but we
were trying to target exactly those
individuals obviously what the
Argentinian I think it's a very good
question about the enablers in the
tobacco industry there are quite a few
enablers if you just look at the trade
in the distribution just give you two
examples which happened quite recently
ups big multinational company has been
found find that 247 million dollars in
the United States for shipping
cigarettes from one country to another
or the United States one nation to
another of course the company was not
aware of what they were transporting but
their defense was that they were taking
parcels with two or three bundles or
small quantities and they were not
legally in charge of having to check
those inside the parcels and they got
out the long process they got to find
247 millions and and I think that's
clearly showing that a camp like UPS can
do more to control their supply chain
and what's what they're transporting
they're gonna peel it but I think it's a
sign that these logistic companies can
play a role just like the credit card
companies or another example is the
shipping lines they are quite a few
shipping lines but they're quite that
there's a quite a concentration in
on the freight transportation and this
company signed in November of the CM
Brussels letter of understanding so an
intention of together with many
producers of possibility consumer goods
like Philip Morris but also PNG Nestle
and so on in order to do more to control
what's in their containers and I do
think and it goes to back here what I
was saying at the beginning about the
public part public/private partnership
I think multinational companies have a
duty to do more to to control their
business whatever whatever business
they're doing and whatever problems they
can have it and I do think that using
the typical carrot and stick can help
multinational companies do the right
thing I'm going to see ask the last
question that's something that's
puzzling me we've had everything from
let's say Neil bars right up the oil
production for financing terror and this
is a question and if you want to feel
it's the last question what is going to
surprise us next what area of human
activity and especially the financial
fetus is going to end up funding the bad
guys and keep it brief if you commit to
anyone honey I'll go first I'd more a
personal opinion and omarska Bombur I
think for me say Cuban I think it's the
the rapid growth of technology and
certainly in industry how some of the
financial players struggle to keep up
that growth and I think so I mentioned
early fintechs as well there's new
players coming into the financial sector
who've got no traditional retail banking
or banking knowledge they they're just
they're just moving so fast with
technology and in society the younger
generations are driving it so rapidly I
think for me that will be the thing that
will surprise us most is the way that
technology will continue also rapidly it
will still continues allow the system to
be exploited and that I don't really
understand that you and your surprising
areas are well in my view that was gonna
surprise us to be honest the sort
tip of the iceberg is the cyberattacks I
think that's going to be something which
is going to become much bigger in the
future and I think we're just not
prepared for it everything is much more
you can control your house remotely with
apps on your iPhone and so on your
heater and but that couldn't that the
securities on those on those apps and
those services very very limited and I
think we're going to be finding
ourselves in big big trouble going
forward there are even the rumors
apparently I'm steering that British
Airways might have been under attack to
date from cyber attack to so let's go a
food for thought but it disturbing all
the same but I don't know but you I've
found this fascinating it's opened up a
whole new world a dark market if you
like and so I'd like to thank the panel
and the audience for a fascinating
discussion today on the nexus between
crime and terrorism in this century
thank you just just say finally if you
can have things the refresh ins are
available outside ladies and gentlemen
in the foyer but I'm told remind you to
be back in your seats in half an hour
fifteen thirty that's half-past three
where I come from for the next session
on the fight against theic news a
struggle dear to our hearts I'm sure and
at the same time in the down ups I'm
told just outside the lobby downstairs
the discussion that the globe future
forum will be on the future of defense
thank you again very much for your
attention and the good debate we've had
here today thank you