right up next is Alvaro he's gonna be
talking about lasers and how to shoot
them at things as part of the DEF CON
laser competition he also reverse
engineers drones he actually submitted
to talks and well he's keeping cutting
out don't they he's submitted to talks
the other one about reverse engineering
drones which you can also see an
hackaday i oh that's really cool he
reverse engineered the protocol and uh
slaves them now and then you can get
those little tiny $20 ones he also does
the laser turret stuff and I think I've
killed enough time for Alvaro welcome
Alvaro to the stage
alright
Oh backwards just do that sorry all
right sorry that was the wrong spot
we're gonna do it I'll play sorry
keynote huh yeah are you doing better
thank you that I worse though hello i'm
alvaro i make a robot sometimes so um
talk today's about some things I've
learned making later laser shooting
robots why at least you're shooting
robots to you shouldn't even have to ask
but because they're awesome um this all
started 2006 right out of high school I
found out about def con first of all and
then I found out Def Con has this robot
competition DEFCON bots which back then
was autonomous robot that shoots bb's
add these targets and I had no idea
about robotics or computer vision or
anything because like I'll try it why
not so so I went that happened 2006 come
fast forward 2014 they brought it back
that the Sun was with lasers so the
rules of Def Con bots competition is
filled an autonomous robot with a name
and mechanism and a laser and softer to
accurately aim and shoot at moving
eliminate targets so these were little
ping-pong balls on a train track that
we're moving around and then the robot
had to find them and shoot them um so I
saw this yesterday but another
disclaimer i also have no idea what I'm
doing this is all stuff I've learned and
yeah so I started what service you know
like okay I have to move webcam and a
laser have some hobby servos this was
cut with balsa wood with a knife
um yeah it my mechanical I'm an
electrical engineer and I write code for
living so part of making these projects
was to learn about mechanical things
which I know nothing about and computer
vision which also knew nothing about so
this is more of a learning project so
here so you a webcam with a little later
on top but kind of moved so yeah service
are really easy to use but when you
targets about 10 meters away a little
bit of movement it's going to be half a
meter and you can't really shoot things
that way so here's some of my early
concepts I was like okay could i use
gears could I use like pulleys I'm doing
some math trying to figure out if the
targets 10 meters away a stepper motor
1.8 degree that's gonna be like 30
centimeters it's not good enough so i
need to do some reduction well then i
found out about laser cutters and I'm
like whoo tech shop has laser cutters
let me see how I can use this to my
advantage so here I am testing cutting
the stepper motor mounts here's some
more testing one thing I learned was try
it out on cardboard first with laser
cutter because you run out of material
pretty quick when you're making mistakes
so yeah be careful I started with a
pulley system here of pulley and the
camera so these were more complicated i
thought i bought these different sizes
and i had these little drive belts but
of course they didn't fit so I had to
cut the belt and then super glue it back
together to size instead of trying to
move the things around and I found out
you can super google the belts and I
mostly work I'll stay together for long
enough until the competition then they
break but you just bring super glue so
then okay I learned laser cutting then I
said oh let me start doing some CAD 2d
CAD
um forget a witch cat program in use but
okay let me start making a little more
complicated things laser cutting is
awesome lesson learned so you probably
can't even tell which when I made it by
hand and which was the laser cutter um
but yeah this was the laser cutter one
so just learning of here it is with
stepper motors so I have I found this
super cute little tiny stepper motor and
then a bigger one and I found out that
some of these can't even lift their own
weight so they can move one direction
and then they stay up there so read a
sign again I didn't calculate you how
much torque the thing hat or anything
until I go just plug it in to work no
doesn't do that so think about how much
the thing with otherwise it probably
won't work alright so belts were okay
let me try on gears I hear all these
great things about gears um they'll hold
things up and everything but they're
really expensive but there's programs
out there with open oh no what's called
a openscad I guess s CAD there's some
scripts it'll make the gears for you
just give it a few parameters and you
can release a company which is really
cool so here's some more you have your
stepper motors and some gears just
trying them out now once i move into
gears there's no more just winging it i
had to actually measure where things
you're gonna be otherwise it's not going
to fit if they're too close they'll jam
if they're too far away this is not
great so i actually had to do some math
and well too bad so here's the first
prototype with full with just gears and
actually work pretty well there was some
backlash um and again when i have the
1.8 degree micro or steps it was a
little too much i tried microstepping
which is great but they're not
guaranteed to happen so if you're trying
to keep absolute positioning and you
have no feedback yeah it's it's not the
best but the mechanics were working okay
all right next next step let me try to
do some 3d modeling um
so yeah I tried it I think this was
autodesk fusion I i switched to use
gearmotors so these are like 1000 to 1
or 500 to 10 reduction and I have toy
wheels so now it's a friction drive I
had that problem earlier with the motor
not being able to hold up itself so
instead I have a little some ball
bearings in this little table so most of
the way it's supported there and then I
just have to move a side by side and
then this other motor here just moves
the holder for the camera again lace
your cutting great yay I have to keep
the laser in the camera mounted together
the first generation I basically I know
the targets somewhere I can move the
camera to point towards it and I know
the laser is hitting a certain pixel
position so I sasa picked the laser and
the camera don't move relative to each
other it's very easy to hit targets
unfortunately a lot of these webcams are
terrible for staying in one place the
best one I found had a tripod mount but
the front still moved so a sauce that
didn't move too much it was fine but
they're not great for precision
precision work so this is my next
generation I have wheels and everything
I know if you see there's a very big big
flaw in my plan here I don't have
anything going down the middle very
stable so whenever this guy moves it
just pushes this right out it just falls
right out so not very good then here's
your motor oh yeah limit switches so
hopefully you have open loop control and
you have cables in the back it'll just
keep going tangled self up and break
yeah it's bad so I had to add little
push buttons here to basically detect
why nots move too far and it needs to
stop weeks i had a few times for just
kept spinning except there's a webcam
there so it gets expensive real quick um
next generations like this things
slipping off so let me put more wheels
around it and I did have pieces of the
wood big enough so I had to make them to
several smaller pieces glue and epoxy
are your friend they you have your parts
don't quite fit just put more glue more
epoxy and it usually ends up working out
so here's two generations of the thing
yeah I made two because things break so
this is this is what I actually took to
the competition so I got a smaller
webcam because back then my computer
vision skills were worse than they are
now and that's already saying something
so we got a smaller webcam less pixels
so I could process them faster and that
actually became a problem oh you had so
tolerances I don't know if you notice
there's little shrimps of paper all
around here I laser cut this all in one
piece so the pieces fit together great
but there was a little bit of play in
between and you're trying to use
friction to hold something in place and
there's a little movement it just kind
of ruins your day so I had to put pieces
of paper there to kind of hold it in
place and there's actually rubber bands
going around the the main circle in the
middle because the laser the laser
cutter leaves a lot of little dust and
we try to do friction and guess thus it
just slips and then again that bed so
yeah this was the Deaf khambhat 2014 we
got first place so we got a quadcopter
out of it so it was kind of fun fast
forward to last summer or this summer
yeah 2015 I wanted to improve things so
it was fun last year but I want to learn
something new and the motor is they work
great but they're really slow so what's
faster than motors mirrors and
galvanometers with this system I can
point a laser wherever I want and like
sub-millisecond which is super cool and
it's a lot
on you could do I don't know if you guys
saw Theresa hackaday logo we projected
up there yesterday that was me playing
around with stuff problem is mounting
optics is not easy right now this is a
this is my first step at home I just
kind of hold it in place and hope for
the best the webcam was on a tripod over
there I found out about opening though
and open beam is awesome you just get
this extruded aluminum parts and you
it's great I made my prototyping so much
easier I went back to my cad by hand
because it was easier than trying to it
in software and I had to make a little
amount because I have these Galvan
motors which are from ebay by the way
you can get a whole acer projecting
system for about 80 bucks on ebay and it
comes with the motors the driver is
pretty cool so I made my precision mount
with a more wood I basically printed
this out to size I taped it on top of a
piece of wood and then I drilled through
it and then cut it which is because I
didn't have a laser cutter at the time
so this is kind of what it ended up
looking like you have your your mirrors
here you later these are the two galvo
drivers and the webcam oh yeah open
beams awesome already said that so here
you can see these come with a kit you
basically give them a differential
voltage and you can move the Maris
wherever you want so the main difference
from this system and the previous one is
now the camera the laser are not aligned
at all the camera does not move the
laser does so the math is completely
different before I would move the camera
and just Center the target now I know
where the target is and I have to hit
the laser with it which was a whole
other problem I had to come up with this
calibration routine to get pixel values
and laser positions together but I if I
have time I'll go into it but i probably
don't you can ask me about it later i
tried different designs like a vertical
mount at laser and just to make a
compact
this is my test set up at home I didn't
know how big the competition area was
going to be so I just used my living
room here it is I really like this
picture because you can see the green
laser beam actually shooting I had some
targets as a lot of fun so when building
robots test them out especially when
your competition you test them a lot
before the competition a lot of people
had trouble they showed up and then it
didn't work you news really sad so this
is the brains of my system stm32
discovery board great for prototype
prototyping i use it has two dax so i
can use the dax I to control the the two
mirrors I made oh oh yeah so I'll go
back to that I had to make this forward
to go from the analog 03 volts coming
out of the DAC on the stm32 and make
into a plus or minus or yeah
differential voltage 0 to 15 volts for
the gala controller so I had to make
this little bored this is second
generation because the first I did all
the math I did my op amp calculation i
put the resistors in and it was not
quite right so use potentiometers don't
just you've put the resistors on your
prototyping because i had to mess around
with it a lot because it's ebay parts
they're cheap they're not as advertised
so yeah so you have your microcontroller
i just wrote some code to be a USB
serial terminal and I need to say go to
x and y position and then it would go
that direction so it's pretty easy to
use open beam as well it packs you can
take it apart in pieces thank you to
evil mad scientist for the awesome boxes
I'd had to go to Vegas and an airplane
but laser shooting robots which is
complicated but TSA doesn't always care
I was freaking out but they didn't even
open my bag is I was kind of sad I
wanted to show them some robots but you
know um so this is it a hotel in Vegas
once we got there
always breaks Paris like i said before
you'll see i have like two or three of
everything from experience things break
every single time so yeah bring spares
oh I do have a picture of the
competition okay so this is this year
you'll see here are the little targets
and there's a train track and they're
moving around this year you didn't just
have to hit the target with the laser
because that's easy you have to hit the
target the laser and then send serial
data over the laser at 9600 baud with
your ID that way they knew hit hit the
targets unfortunately I didn't test that
part that well and my laser was
modulating but for some reason I still
haven't figured out why things to do my
power supply when I started transferring
the data it would just brown out and the
targets were in detecting the hits and
this was working fine the first day but
then there in the the second round we
just stopped working so we're like
hitting the targets but not really
hitting them and yeah so test everything
out before going yeah something will
usually go wrong so plan plan Ford still
it's a ton of fun yeah other lessons I
learned I don't know if we have time for
them but computer vision stuff I thought
it was going to be crazy hard it kind of
is but it's not as hard as I thought to
get into it just opencv I started doing
it all in C C++ but then I found out you
could do it in Python and it's actually
pretty fast because all the computer
vision it still happens to see pythons
just gluing stuff together and one of
the most important things i learned
between last year and this year was only
doing the math on the area of the screen
that I need so last year we had a 720p
camera and it was pretty slow we had
almost a second delay because of all the
image processing we were doing this year
I had a full 1080p image I would find
the targets and I already know what the
target kind of is it's not going to move
around the whole scene so I can just do
my target detection on a small area
around
um it and it just made a huge difference
just with the image processing I didn't
talk about service efforts and gear
motor controllers there's a great talk
yesterday at motors so I would you
brought you guys already know laser
voltages so when you buy a not super
cheap like fifty dollar laser online and
they tell you three volts don't put more
than three volts I put more than three
bolts and died within like a second
after I bought it so I had to order more
be careful um software stuff yeah I did
all my firmware for the stm32 it's i use
the GCC compiler it's all online all the
all the code for this stuff is online
that the thing the cad files might be if
not you give your interested just let me
know the software all the computer
vision i did in python and i don't know
how much time we have if anyone has any
questions but that's been some of my
experience making laser shooting robots
let's have one more round of applause
for Alvaro by 80
you