alright so let's go ahead and jump into
it our next speaker is auntie Lucas I've
gotten to know auntie actually through
the hacker channel and then also through
hackaday I owe an amazing FPGA developer
been building FPGA system CP LD systems
since 1979 so he's been in the business
for quite a while worked on the very
first xilinx FPGAs building stuff on the
very first series of design links fpgas
a lot of experience in the FPGA space
and somebody who has absolutely warmed
my heart as a serious fpga enthusiasts
so Monty
ah ok very good I'm not talking about my
projects here okay there are some of
them are on the screen all of them are
open source hardware so all the design
files everything from manufacturing is
available from download com github all
the same RFP shave ice is officially
baseboards so I have to know press the
tab and it doesn't work you see I only
have one slide to the tap you okay I
only have one slide so I have to use
this what I have on the screen my talk
was about past present and future of a
pjs and if you look closer top left you
see wave which is called monkey motivate
which talks about industry trends in
electronics and if you look on the time
scale you see that the time of officiers
depend at 2007 and we are now in 2015 so
if you're not using FB chase today you
cannot use them oops you cannot use them
in the Golden Age of fpga we are already
past that and the next wave is ending
2017 so it's something that I didn't
believe but all I know about past
technology I cannot deny that this wave
actually don't exist it takes some work
knowledge to understand that mr.
nauseous she did change every 10 years
this wave is done by Japanese dr. Mackay
modem which is very big guy in the
electronics industry ok so and it's a it
was used by some presentation ice
keynote
aren't I links bird by the events of
presentation on new technologies iffy
features are in the past wave the
question remains what is now if you look
on the screen until 2017 we have the
wave is called system-on-chip or system
in package so it does include large
processor base plate complicated
pedophiles it trans include processors
which include the cpu and say pga one
die or they may include devices which
include the same devices in single
package so with system in package the
next wave which should start at 2017 it
maybe have different name but by them on
a list on by 22 horizons they have
called it hyper flexible super
integration whatever it does mean
something is happening it should happen
in 2017 or some days some years after
that sorry it's notifying what it is but
it may be the reason why Intel did by
alterra this year I did right yes 2015
Intel da is buying altera and only few
days there for the conference suppose
the news about Intel having a new
technology coming out it's called the
system in in Pakistan origin using an
amoeba which is embedded multi die
interconnect bridge this allows
different type of dies three Packers in
same ETA package is very short delays
between the packages and without some
high cost of wafer bonding ganzer
through-silicon vias and that the first
devices which come out we'll be using
Kaltura start extend devices and civil
bond memory chips to the spca using the
high bandwidth memory boost standard and
it's very surprising the best
acknowledgement it come so quickly after
our interlude bioterror so one more
thing that can explain it this sorry
okay silence is no longer promoting a
species as much as I do as much as they
do promote system-on-chip devices and
tools are on this accolade project link
system on chip from savings on this one
I'm sorry on this one and on this one's
there are three projects make more and
on the top layer some minimum and
maximum parameters was a speech aids
which really scale from very low very
small devices low-power devices to high
powered devices and the price range very
large so it covers very much the last
spectrum of different type of electronic
things it simply motomiya short it will
look so very amazed that it's it is a
nice if I have two more minutes yes okay
oh it's can you see this no
I did rise for different flows for fpga
design flow number a we take a board
which can run lineups we are an open
source tool chain we write we create two
files first file as three lines of
source code second line has two lines of
course and then we hit make and we get
this to be running on this spj in linux
compiling and programming the second
fpga on this board this was floor number
one slot number 2 is X eiling's system
design flow and try to it very quickly
you start by taking a library say you
created library component saying you
create lots of metadata you have to say
use a manual version number a lot other
information single package trees as the
IP core as a library component then you
start again the hardware designer you
put the component onto the converse you
make some mouse clicks and connect
things you export it to software tools
you create first boot loader since I get
crazy boot file see in a cop is a boot
file to a microSD card ready curve you
plug the SD card to the device and you
run it it was very short version of the
system level design the third one is a
glaring store called HP SOC in that case
you don't start the hardware tools at
all you just write a C++ code and you
define which part of the code will be
running on the hardware and you create
one button make and it creates
everything you need to actually run the
code on the arm processor and don't say
fish a the fourth flow is a PCI eight
Express expedite oxygenators for pcr pcs
in that case you'll also write C code on
PC which will be running on the add-on
card in the FPGA software accelerator
and if it does use power to reckon
operational safety shades of the
algorithm's are translated on supply and
move it to the reprogrammable portion of
said piche on the fly that is another
reason why interviewed by Al trader to
get this stuff to work with Intel CPUs
2015 exciting could come with the next
generation of a system-on-chip which it
tells us four times 853 IP cores
processors I thought I have sort of
three USB three lots of high-speed
serial interfaces and it is something we
are getting any few samples this year
they cost several thousand pieces early
early examples and I'm hoping to make a
super computer based on them sorry
filter scale next year thank
for all of you who want to take a look
at aunties boards aunty if you want to
take your boards over there and actually
give people an opportunity to take a
look at him he's got some really amazing
fpgas on in a micro SD card form factor
fpga development boards are absolutely
incredible looking so go ahead and take
a look at him he'll be over there he'll
have a conversation with anybody who has
questions that sort of thing