up next is loose Iseman he's the
director of hardware y combinator prior
to that he's done some really cool
Burning Man projects like Paulson bloom
with Sam who's also here if you he also
built a house he lives in a box in
Oakland
shipping container home in Oakland you
could see it online it's really cool
actually and before that also some some
hardware projects that he worked on and
products so Luke's he'd be talking about
and that just cut out Luke Sammy talk
about hardware Luke to the stage thank
you
oh is that newer version yeah this one
work that's all good okay yeah
see hi so I'm gonna talk about hardware
startups how they get into Y Combinator
and or generally can kick ass in a world
that is way more used to software being
done as a start-up so I'm gonna kind of
talk about a little earlier stage than
what than what Danielle focused on again
disclaimer I am an extremist this is my
home
I have a prejudice towards things that
work rather than things that are pretty
obviously so my advice is oriented
towards okay you want to get something
done you don't have religion about how
you do it or whether it's you know maybe
technically always legal you just want
to bring it into existence and another
caveat I work for Y Combinator Y
Combinator has traditionally funded
companies like these all of which are
software many of which are worth lots
lots of dollars in the three comma Club
even these are these are the standard
terms we offer we give startups a small
amount of money for some percent of
their company so far we've done this
with 940 companies the market value of
which is about 65 billion dollars our
last batch we do two batches a year was
107 company so we fund a bunch of
startups we see a lot of traditionally a
lot of software increasingly like in our
last batch we have so many hardware
companies kind of all of a sudden we
weren't really expecting it you can't
even like coherently fit the slides just
from the lot the logos just from the
last batch on a slide so hardware has
suddenly become something that startups
in the last couple years has become
extremely common for startups to do but
first pause and think about do you want
to do a startup you can sell kids you
can just make something for yourself
that you finance with your normal day
job you should really think about
whether you want to deal with the good
and the bad of entering the world of
high-growth technology startups you
should also pause and think if you want
to do a hardware startup this is one
section this is like one fiftieth of a
trade show called Canton Fair outside of
Shenzhen there's lots of large
machinery and equipment you have to deal
with if you're doing hardware as opposed
to you know typing and clicking a couple
buttons to launch new software but I
would argue that you should in fact
start a hardware startup because a
startup is your lever of archimedes it's
the best way to change the world and the
world shows all signs of continuing to
be made out of this messy stuff called
hardware so all that startups to do is
basically these seven things it's this
it's this simple and it's this
complicated I'm gonna dig in on each of
these and explain what startups in Y
Combinator's last class did that we're
making hardware before they even entered
Y Combinator first and foremost you have
to make something particularly if you
are doing hardware the worst category
you can be in if you're trying to raise
money or convince customers is what I
call man with a plan like somebody who
someday maybe wants to start a startup
and has like a PowerPoint or even nice
printed out graphics or renderings even
of what their product might someday look
like if they ever get around to building
it when you make one of something no
matter how messy it is you become
drastically further ahead than most
people ever like everybody says they
want to do a start-up many people say
they want to make hardware but getting
getting unit-one done no matter how
messy and explosion prone differentiates
you from so many other people great
example of this is a company in our last
batch called body port they applied you
know little quick online application and
told us they were gonna make what
sounded kind of like too good to be true
a scale that you'd step on it barefoot
and it would take your blood pressure in
like three seconds which traditionally
you know it's a cuff on your arm
generally a giant pain in the ass and
people just don't do it but it's an
important signal for improving your
fitness for fighting
you know obesity and other diseases and
they showed us a prototype that worked
like maybe 2 percent of the time I don't
think it worked at all during their
interview but they continued making it
they iterated on it and by demo day they
had you know investors literally
barefoot on there
now working a majority of the time
prototype so it's not there's no perfect
thing that you reveal you create
hardware that people want by showing
them things that are very broken which
brings me to to my next point show your
things to people don't develop in a
vacuum
don't just be in your garage by yourself
if you want to do that that's fine but
you're not going to develop something
that has any relevance to other people
if your audience is only yourself or too
few people teapot did a great job of
this t-bot created a robot that mixes
together different types of tea and lets
you adjust very precisely the
temperature and quantity of each of them
so like six months before we accepted
them they this is prototype number one
right next to their school in Canada
serving people tea on a daily basis or
on an every other day basis because it
was down for maintenance about half the
time but they're getting data way
earlier than any traditionally trained
engineer who's taught to think of
everything as a bridge that has to work
all of the time with a giant safety
margin or everyone dies way earlier than
people academically trained would you
know would be comfortable pushing out
product because they were able to do
that they're getting so much more
feedback so much earlier that they're
able to create something not from day
one but eventually that is way more of a
fit for people that people are way more
willing to use and then the main thing
that everyone spends most of their time
doing is iterating this isn't this isn't
linear we like to tell heroes stories
about startup success and product
launches where there's these these grand
reveals and everything's perfect but as
soon as you dig into the details of any
of those you'll realize that what you're
seeing is you know version 300 of 400
great example is Nebbia they're a $400
showerhead which you're probably
thinking that's ridiculous that's what I
thought the first time I heard it then I
took shower and ordered one and what
they did was throughout their
development process created a whole
bunch of these this is like one fifth of
the prototypes that they went through
before launching of 3.5 million dollar
Kickstarter during
see and you don't get to that magical
you know giant million-dollar-plus
Kickstarter by just launching one of
these each of these they had people
showering in and they were iterating
based on what people actually told them
about experiencing their product a step
that many hackers and engineers miss is
putting a Buy Now button there allowing
people to actually give you money for
the thing that you have created it
sounds silly but this is a huge missing
step I would argue that self-driving
cars self-driving golf carts at least
are basically ready to go and it's just
overly academic engineers who have not
thought of this step of putting a Buy
Now button there yet transcend lighting
did a great job of this basically my
friend Brian built a light for his dad
to grow seedlings indoors and you know
kind of on a lark built two of them one
of them he put a Buy Now button next to
and sold it so then he made a couple
more and they sold then he continued to
basically have a Buy Now button and make
product to meet demand and you know he's
selling quite a few of these now there's
nothing it's technically innovative but
the huge missing step for him and for
other people who had created similar
things earlier than he did was to
actually think to offer it for sale and
then this is this is specific to if you
are doing a high-growth startup and not
just creating products as a small
business if you are not growing both in
depth and breadth both in the features
of your current product and future
products that you will build you are not
a high-growth startup you're like it or
not you're being compared to every
software company out there they are
doing that to remain as attractive to
investors you need to continue doing
that as well clicking grow is an
automated little it was an herb guard
and you put it on your shelf put in some
water plug it in and it grows like
rosemary and basil and we accepted them
into the program because then started to
grow the scope of what what they're
doing to include a new product which is
like a drastically better version of
what they were doing before way more
food weight less cost per unit food and
essentially a drastically better version
they have
nice small to medium-sized business with
their one product and just continuing to
offer that but to really be a
high-growth startup yet you can't
there's no static like static is death
for startups you need to continue
growing and then if you're doing
something that you're selling
particularly to consumers I don't care
how technically innovative it is unless
you have a compelling brand unless
you're telling a story about your
product and why it's unique very quickly
like months not years you're a product
even if it sells you know 20 million
dollars on Kickstarter becomes a
commodity if you don't have a brand
around a b2c product it's a commodity
sooner rather than later and frankly
like life shorte you should do something
better on the flip side a strong brand
can turn a commodity into something that
people pay huge margins for Ella is a
condom company we had a condom company
in our last batch of high-growth
startups and it performed quite well
because Talia the founder was able to
create a beautiful product and tell such
a compelling story around it that
literally like one of the most
commoditized things you could imagine a
condom becomes this thing that is in
fact a high-growth startups very
compelling product for advertising so
good Frid that when she releases a new
ad like a 30-second ad it's so good that
Cosmo Elle and many other Target
publications actually do press around
her putting out a new ad so not only do
you need a brand to take you know a
high-tech product and keep it defensible
as a b2c product you can actually take
something very commoditized and create a
compelling startup by doing very by
telling a very compelling story around
it which is something it's kind of
counterintuitive like you would think
you just put out your amazing technology
and everybody figures it out yeah
doesn't it doesn't work that way in the
world of consumer facing stuff and then
and this is very much like not pivot but
fail pivot I think it's just a stupid
word that nobody should use we need to
literally embrace failure you should be
moving so quickly and you should be
working on things that are interesting
enough that failure is part of the
process
and it's way more common than you'd
think
Luna sleep is a smart mattress pad it
lets you heat and cool individual sides
that's they surveyed like thousands of
people figured out that's the most
common reason why couples fight at
nights they made something that monitors
your sleep helps you optimize it unless
you individually control temperature and
they applied for YC and we rejected them
this is incredibly common a huge number
of the companies that get into IC and a
huge number of the people that get
funding or authors they get published
any success story you want to look at
when you start to dig into it you see a
giant pile of rejections before the
acceptance so we rejected them they you
know continued unfazed launched a rather
substantial IndieGoGo campaign they
pre-sold like eight hundred thousand
dollars worth of these covers applied
again and we happily accepted them and
they they were able to relax in spite of
their failure throughout the program
does emmaandemma dated investors coming
up in literally sleeping on their
product so it's that simple at a high
level and it's that complicated if you
are doing something that is not one of
these that is any of these things you
can you can go and find huge threads of
debate about how important figuring all
of these out are before you ever
launched a product these are all
distractions these are all things that
people's companies die because they are
spending time and money trying to figure
out every single thing on here you can
pre-sell product you can even get
product into users hands before you
worry about any of these if you're not
focused all of these are just an excuse
for debate and excuse for hiring more
people an excuse for wasting money and
an excuse for going out of business or
to put it another way you should just
focus on making things that people want
so if you want to do that with YC we
have late applications open now and if
you have any questions about building
hardware in general email me doesn't
have to be for a high-growth hardware
startup the thing I'm happy to talk
about the things I've hacked together
with varying degrees of explosions
and/or success thanks for your time