>>Ah so today we're here to talk
about 411 a framework for
managing security alerts ah
which we will be open sourcing
after Defcon [cheering] so
before we get started let's do
introductions. My name is Kai,
oh Kai Zhong and I am a product
security engineer at Etsy so I'm
responsible for um helping
developers with running secure
code and maintaining some of the
um internal applications that we
use on the security team like
411 and on occasion I've been
known to wear many hats like you
see in that photo and uh after
this presentation um I'll be
tweeting out links to the slides
on my twitter so follow me
please gotta get those followers
alright oh heh sorry I'm
supposed to make a really really
bad pun here um hopefully you
won't find our presentation to
be unbearable yes you groaned
>>Thanks Kai my name's Ken Lee
I'm a senior product security
engineer at Etsy I'm glad to be
back at Defcon I was here three
years ago for a presentation on
content security policy and two
important facts about me, one my
twitter handle is KennySan and
two I really love funny cat gifs
so I've managed to sneak one
into the slide deck >>Nice!
>>For those that don't know this
adorable cat is Maru so let me
go and start by explaining what
Etsy is, Etsy is a marketplace
for handmade and vintage goods
the security team at Etsy is
responsible for keeping private
member's personal information
such as credit card details,
their addresses, etcetera oh in
addition the Etsy security team
has been successfully running
our own bug bounty program for
the past four years as well
[applause] I'm going to go into
some more detail about what
we're covering in today's
presentation. First we're going
to start by talking a little bit
about the history of our
transition to using ELK we're
going to go delve into some of
the problems that we encountered
during this transition process
and we're going to talk more
about our solution which we call
411 then we're going to dive
into a how we at Etsy do alert
management using 411 we're going
to show you some additional more
involved examples and we're
going to finish things off with
a non live demo I know I really
wanted the live demo but I I
never trust the demo gods to get
it right um first we're going to
go over some terminology for
some of you this must be old
news but we're going to try to
get over this as quickly as
possible. So for those that
don't know this is a log file
logs are typically interesting
messages generated by web server
that's stored in a log file this
is the ELK stack the ELK stack
is consisting of three different
technologies, Elasticsearch,
Logstash, and Kibana and I'm
going to quickly go over what
each of these different
applications do. The first as
represented by our friendly
mustachioed log over here is
called Logstash. Logstash is our
data processor and log shipper
tool, we primarily use it as a
way to identify interesting
fields that we would want to
perform searches on in the
future. In addition we also use
Logstash to ship logs into
Elasticsearch proper, what is
Elastic Search? Great question
me! Elasticsearch is the
distributed real time search
engine created by Elastic dot
CO. It allows for storing
complex nested documents but in
this case we primarily use
Elasticsearch for storing log
files parsed by Logstash in
addition Elasticsearch allows
the generation of statistics of
your data so you can run
interesting aggregations over
the information that you have
stored in Elasticsearch which
lends itself very well to
analysis of the data that you
have. Finally the la- the K in
ELK stands for Kibana and that's
the data visualization web
application front end for
Elasticsearch. Kibana allows for
log discover and more
importantly debugging of
problems in your application and
in addition Kibana provides for
some interesting visualization
options. Unfortunately this was
the best stock image that I
could find of Kibana to show you
what it does um you can do
interesting pie charts, graphs,
eccetera, using Kibana as a
front end. So now let's talk a
little bit more about the
history of how we transitioned
into using ELK so Etsy switched
to using the ELK stack back in
mid 2014 from Splunk and the
work took about a year and
throughout this process we both
learned a lot of good lessons
from the migration process and
we got a bunch of great tools
out of it including 411 but it
wasn't a super easy rode to go
down we were aware of the fact
that we were going to run into
issues when we started to
transition to using ELK and we
had to deal with our fair share
of really annoying performance
impacting bugs with our ELK
cluster. In addition the
security team was concerned
about the usability of the ELK
as a solution for being able to
do some of our alerting and
monitoring. So to give an
example of one of these bugs
here we have two Anitech
articles, ones from September of
2014 and the other from April of
2015 that's a span of about six
or so months basically this
article illustrates the
discovery of uh a bug with
Samsung's line of solid state
hard drives and the fix
acknowledge is coming out about
six months plus later so
unfortunately for us our ELK our
ELK cluster used these SSDs to
power the um ELK cluster and so
we were affected by this
reperformance bug for more than
six months in addition this is
just a small snippet from an
email we had a small issue with
a kernel level bug affecting how
it was handling NSF mounds this
caused a lot of instability with
our ELK cluster and
unfortunately some additional
outage uh downtime as well. So
to say the least you know these
are just two example bugs that
we had to encounter at times it
felt like we were riding the
struggle bus with regards to all
of the bugs and issues that we
had to deal with with regards to
ELK but that aside, Kai is now
going to talk to you about um
some of the actual problems, not
just bugs that we encountered,
when migrating to Elk >>Thank
you Ken, so um like most
security organizations alerting
is a major part of how the
security team at Etsy knows what
is going on on the site um and
some mechanisms that we use for
alerting are um Splunk, or used
to use our Splunk, StatsD and
Graphite and unfortunately um
when we first started this
migration um there we were
making use of Splunk safe
searches to automatically
schedule queries on some sort of
periodic interval and
Elasticsearch didn't offer like
equivalent functionality at that
time and additionally,
Elasticsearch also didn't offer
some sort of web UI for managing
those um queries that we were
writing which is pretty useful
when say it's like the middle of
the weekend and you're getting
spammed with alerts and you need
to make a change to one of the
queries but doing so would
require a could push and you
don't want to like break
something with some sort of web
UI where everything is handled
for you you could just go in
there, change the query and then
update it and you're good to go.
Now the second problem was that
um we were just not familiar
with the new query language that
we were um faced with um our old
queries were built using SPL
which is the language that
Splunk uses and um so the some
of the functionality that we
needed in order to write our
queries simply wasn't available
um in Elasticsearch's Lucene
shorthand. Additionally there
were some things that weren't
obvious coming from um Splunk
like especially with how
Elasticsearch indexes documents
um it has an affect on like
whether or not and how you can
query um the actual fields that
you are searching on. So this
came as a surprise to us at
certain points and because of
these issues the road to ELK
integration was a long one in
order to successfully um
complete the migration we
essentially needed three things,
firstly we needed a query
language that would allow us to
build complex queries preferably
without having to write any
code, uh we also needed a
mechanism to actually run these
queries and like email us with
those results and finally we
would like to have all of this
ready before we turned off
Splunk because then we're then
dark otherwise and that would be
really bad. Alright so as it
turns out the first half of the
solution was provided to us by
um the data engineering team at
Etsy and that solution is called
ESQuery and what it is is it's a
superset of the standard Lucene
shorthand and um it's
intactictly pretty similar to
SPL so it's got like a bunch of
pipelines everywhere that you
can then like take data from the
first one and transfer it to the
second one. I'll provide an
example in in a bit but more
importantly it supports all of
the functionality that we need.
So here's a quick summary of all
of the syntax um when you define
a um Elasticsearch query you do
it via this large json DSL and
we provided the ability to like
in line all of these directly
into the query so you can see it
over here you can specify say
like size or how you're sorting
the results that come back or
just what fields are coming
back. Additionally you can do an
emulated join so you can results
from one query and then like
insert them into a subsequent
query and all the irrigation
functionality that is available
in Elasticsearch is also
available in ESQuery but in
line. And finally you can also
um define variables within
ESQuery um and you configure
them in 411 and then have those
queries get substituted into uh
sorry those variables get
substituted into your queries at
one time so like you can have a
list of values that you can
update independently of these
queries so here's an example SPL
query. Um what this is doing is
it's finding all um failed login
attempts and then giving you the
top ten IP addresses that made
attempts this is the same query
but um when using uh Lost
Searches um DSL and finally this
is the same query but when using
ESQuery so you can see it's
pretty similar to how you would
write it using SPL and way
shorter as well and the two are
actually similar enough that um
someone at Etsy was able to
write a simple query translator
which we made use of during our
migration so what we did was we
would just plug it in, um test
it out, and make changes if
necessary and then stick them
into 411. Speaking of which next
up let's talk about what 411 is
so 411 is an alert management
interface or application and
what it does is it allows you to
write queries that get
automatically executed on some
sort of schedule then you can
configure it to email you with
like email you alerts whenever
those data sources that you're
querying return any results and
additionally you can manage the
alerts that our generated
through the web interface.
Before we dive into 411 let's um
talk briefly about how
scheduling works within um the
system. So whenever a search job
is run it executes um a query
against a data source and then
generates a a an alert for every
single result that comes back
you can then configure a series
of filters on those alerts to
re- like reduce or modify the
stream somehow and then finally
um specify a list of targets
that you can send uh the
remaining alerts to. So an
example of one target that is
pretty neat is the Jira target
which allows you to like
generate a a ticket for every
single alert that goes through
the pipeline. Alright wait oh
sorry additionally if we um take
a step back what happens is
there's a scheduler that runs
periodically and generates those
search jobs which then get fed
off to a bunch of workers that
actually execute them. And now
we're ready to get into 411. So
the first thing you'll see when
you log on is the dashboard
which is this thing over here
it's pretty simple but you see
there's some um userful
information about the current
status of 411 there's a
breakdown of alerts that are
currently active as well as a
histogram of just like alerts
that have come in over the last
few days. Alright moving on um
one of the most important things
you'll want to do in 411 is
manage the queries that you are
like schedule to execute and you
do that via the search
management page which you can
see here the center you've got
all the searches listed out with
like some categorization
information and on the right
you'll you can see the health of
that particular search, whether
or not it's been running
correctly, and whether or not
it's been able to execute. Now
if you want to modify an
individual search you'll get
taken to this page over here
which has a whole like slew of
options that you can configure
um there's a title which is not
too exciting but more
importantly there are all of
these fields so let's go through
all of these briefly. At the top
here is the query which is quite
simply the query that you're
sending off to whatever data
source in this case this is a
Logstash source so we're sending
this to an ElasticSearch cluster
with a Logstash index um you can
also configure we can also
configure a results type so
whether or not you want the
actual contents of the log
inside um match the query or
whether you just want like a
simple count or even an
indication that there's like no
results and finally you can
filter you can apply thresholds
on like how many results that
you want to get back next up you
can you can also provide a
description that um gets
included whenever an alert gets
sent to you so you should
preferably put some information
that allows you allows whoevers
um assigned to the alert to
resolve it and there are a few
categorization options at the
bottom as well for the alerts
that are generated much better
alright next up is the frequency
which is how often you want to
run this search and the time
range which is how how far back
of a like time window you want
to search most of the time
you're gonna want both of these
to be the same value but if you
want say like better granularity
you might want to specify a
frequency of one minute and a
time range of ten minutes and
finally we've got the status bun
which lets you toggle this
search. Cool that's all for the
basic tab next up let's talk
about uh notifications. So in
411 you can configure uh you can
configure email notifications
whenever um it generates any
alerts and those notifications
can be sent out as soon as the
alerts are generated or included
in a hourly or daily roll out.
You can also assign you also
have to assign um these alerts
to an assignee which is the
person or the group of people
that are responsible for
actually resolving and taking a
look at those alerts and finally
the owner field is just um for
bookkeeping so you can keep
track of who is responsible for
maintaining that particular
search. And here's the AppSec
group that we're currently using
here you see it's got a list of
all the users that are currently
on the security AppSec team and
uh whenever 411 generates an
alert for this particular um
search they'll email all of
these people. Alright moving on
to the final tab the here we've
got some more advanced
functionality that's less
commonly used like auto close
which allows you to
automatically close alerts that
haven't seen any activity after
a while so they're probably
stale and we've also got um the
actual configuration for filters
and targets here as well so
again recall that filters
allowed you to reduce the list
of alerts that get passed
through um 411 and eventually
get generated and here is a list
of filter that are currently
available so I'll just highlight
a few of them. Dedupe allows you
to just like dedupe alerts that
are the same and you can
throttle um the alerts that are
generated to like some threshold
for the purposes of this
presentation let's talk about
the regular expression one
because that's relatively
complicated uh you can configure
this particular filter to um
have some sort of key like what
keys you want to match on within
the alert as well as a regular
expression to match on and then
you can specify whether or not
you want matching alerts to be
included or excluded from the
like final list of alerts.
Similarly on the other side
we've got the list of targets
that you can configure and we're
going to cover the Jira target
which allows you to specify a
Jira instance and a a project a
type and a and a assignee and
then any alerts that make it to
this target get turned into Jira
tickets so that's useful if you
want to use Jira as your alert
management workflow cool so
that's about it as far as
managing searches go next up
we're going to get into actually
managing the alerts that are
generated by 411. So here it is
the main alert management
interface you'll notice at the
top there's a search bar for
filtering the list of alerts
that are visible and this 411
actually indexes all of its
alerts into Elasticsearch so all
of your standard like Lucene or
hand queries are valid here um
in the center you'll see all of
the actual alerts that matched
the current filter and you can
select um individual alerts and
apply actions to them using the
search um action bar at the
bottom. Now if you want to drill
down into a individual alert you
can so this is the view for
viewing just like a single alert
and you can see at the center
there's all of the information
that was available before but
also a change log for viewing
all actions that have been taken
on this one's alert.
Additionally you'll see there is
the same action bar that's
available at the bottom and
let's say thank you let's say we
were to investigate investigate
this alert like we took a look
at IP address and then we've
determined that it's just a
scanner so nothing to worry
about we can then hit resolve on
that action bar which will pop
up this little dialog where we
can select a resolution status
in this case not an issue and a
description of exactly what
actions we took to resolve this
alert and then once you hit
resolve there you'll see the
change log has been updated with
this um additional action. 411
also offers a um alert feed so
what you can do is just keep
this open and whatever new
alerts come in um it'll just hop
up on this list and you can also
leave it running in the
background because it's got
desktop notifications so you'll
see that nice little chrome pop
up uh whenever there are new
alerts cool alright next up
>>Thanks Kai I'm gonna talk to
us talk to you more about how we
do alert management at Etsy
using 411. So here we have a
sample email generated by 411
I'm going to go into some more
depth and explain to you what's
going on so the subject line of
this email says login service
five hundreds ah the description
says login five hundreds
investigate for people that
aren't very familiar with it log
in is just basically a process
to essentially log you into a
website, five hundreds is
basically a a message that says
oh something bad is happening
and usually this is pretty bad
to the extent where you would
want to create an alert for it
and be notified about it and we
can see from the time range that
this alert is taken place over
the past five minutes and we
have buttons on the bottom to
both view the alert in 411 as
well as to be able to view this
link in Kibana as well we also
get a short snippet including
the PHP error that was thrown
and as you can see from this
sort of short email snippet
people are sort of taking action
based on this alert. But let's
take a step back a little bit
and think more about what we do
to actually crea- create high
quality alerts and at Etsy the
secret is we create alerts that
have a high degree of
sensitivity. What do I mean when
I say high sensitivity well
let's say that we have an alert
that fires one hundred times
over the course of a day and out
of those hundred times that
alert correctly predicts an
event actually happening ninety
times so what that means is out
of a hundred times that alert
only improperly fires ten times
so there's a one in ten chance
that that alert is misfiring so
ninety percent of the time that
alert is responding correctly to
an event so we say that that
that particular has a
sensitivity of ninety percent
that's a pretty high sensitivity
that we would you know find to
be useful for alerts that aren't
as important we still create
them as searches and alerts in
411 but what we do is we end up
not generating email
notifications out of them and
I'll go into more detail as to
why in just a moment for more
important alerts we still
generate alerts off of them but
what we do is we set them up as
um rollups so every hour or
every day we have this alert go
off and it'll email us the
results and one reason why we
really like doing this is
because it gives us the option
of being able to monitor a
particular search over a period
of time for anomalies. So one of
the reasons why we take this
sort of tiered approach to
alerting is because attackers
hitting your website will often
generate a lot of noise and in
the process of doing so they'll
set off a bunch of different
alerts that you have set up. So
one thing that we often have to
answer when we see an alert on
our phone at three in the
morning is is this something
that I really need to respond to
at three in the morning? Do I
Can I Can I just continue
sleeping? Do I have to you know
can I just answer this tomorrow
or even after the weekend? Well
one way in which we make that
determination is by seeing and
looking at the other alerts that
have gone off in the same period
of time so we look at the high
alerts the low alerts the medium
alerts that have gone off over
this period of time an example
uh a good example of this would
be let's say there is a very
high number of failed login
attempts that an alert a high
alert that has gone off recently
well maybe if we also have a
lower alert that indicates that
we have a low quality uh series
of bots trying to scan us at the
same time maybe that's
indicative that actually this
isn't like a really concentrated
attack that we need to worry
about so we can go back to
sleep. So in addition to
creating alerts one thing that
we also have to be vigilant
about is maintaining our alerts
sometimes we create alerts that
overfit on a particular attacker
and as a result of that the
alerts become less useful over
time one way in which this
happens is the alert simply
generates too much noise we've
sometimes we've created this
search and it turns out we're
the IP address for example might
be shared by some legitimate
users as well um and that can
create a bunch of false
positives so in those cases we
sometimes have to finetune our
alerts and one way in which we
do that is we look at other
fields so another example is
sometimes say an attacker might
accidentally be using a static
but very easily identifiable
user agent when attacking our
website one way in which so we
can create a search off of that
to easily identify that attacker
but perhaps they become a little
savvier and realize that they're
making this terrible mistake in
the first place and they make an
att- they make an effort to
randomize the user agent and by
doing this what they essentially
do is they're forcing us to have
to use other fields to identify
the attacker may be looking at
what data center it's coming
from or IP or other IP addresses
that they're coming from for
example so let's take a step
back we've sort of sold 411 as a
tool for security teams but it's
also a very useful team um a
very useful tool for the average
developer as well and one way in
which 411 can be useful for a
developer is creating alerts
based off of potential error
conditions in your code so a
good example of this would be
when you want to know potential
exception conditions say for
example code wrapped in a tri
catch statement for example you
generally don't want your
application to be running into
too many exceptions so generally
by entering in a log line and
creating an alert based off that
log line you'll get a
notification when something bad
happens in your application.
Another condition under which
you'd want to create an alert is
when you're getting a large
amount of unwanted traffic to an
endpoint that you uh consider
sensitive. A good example of
this would be uh an attack for
example trying to hit a gift
card redemption endpoint or a
credit card number re- uh
entering endpoint you know those
endpoints are probably already
rate limited in the first place
so it's only natural to add
basically an additional alert on
top of that just so you know
that someone's trying to
intentionally brute force this
particular endpoint and finally
the last instance under which
you might want to consider
creating an alert is when you're
deprecating old code. So at Etsy
we have what's called a feature
flag system that allows us to
very easily flag on and off
particular bits of code but
sometimes we need to evaluate
how often a particular code
branch is being exercised before
we can move it entirely from the
code base one way in which we do
that is we sometimes just like
to add a log line and create an
alert just to I with a rollup to
see how many times this
particular code branch has been
exercised throughout the course
of a day or even a week and by
doing that once we have
confidence in knowing yes this
code is not really being used
that often we can go ahead and
actually remove the code in
question. So at Etsy we actually
have a couple different
instances of 411 set up and I'll
explain what they are. Our main
instance that the application
security and risk engineering
teams used is called Sec411 in
this instance it's primarily
used for monitoring issues that
happened on Etsy dot com itself.
The network security team has
it's own instance of 411 called
appropriately netsec411 and this
instance is set up primarily to
aid in monitoring laptops and
our servers and finally for
those compliance loving folks we
have an instance of 411 setup
called Sox411 which is primarily
uh used for sox related
compliance issues. Now I'm going
to go into some more examples of
uh some functionality that we
have present in 411 that we're
going to be making available to
you when we open source the tool
a lot of this additional
functionality was made av- was
made at the request of
developers at Etsy and we found
it useful enough to include in
the open source version of 411
as well. So Kai mentioned
earlier that 411 has the ability
to incorporate lists into
queries here we have a search
functionality that looks for
suspicious duo activity coming
from known TOR exit nodes so
this query looks fairly
straightforward but let's take a
look let's take a deeper look so
we're looking at logs of the
type duo login and we're looking
for the IP address that matches
this TOR exits variable well if
we take a look at what the list
functionality is we can see that
TOR exits is defined as a URL
that just enumerates a list of
IP addresses so what 411 is
actually doing behind the scenes
is it's taking this TOR exits
node variable and expanding the
query out to include all of
those IP addresses in that TOR
exits node list so essentially
when you get when you get any
hit in a log line that contains
a TOR exit node IP address it
matches with the search and
generates an alert. Now I'm
gonna talk more about some of
the additional functionality
that we offer beyond just the
ELK stack with 411. We offer a
searcher for graphite which is
basically a way of storing and
viewing time series data this is
what graphites front end
interface looks like as you can
it's a very nice way of easily
generating graphs, this
particular graph shows an
overlay of potential cross site
scripting over potential
scanners um it's just a really
nice way of being able to
determine when you are when
there are anomalies happening
and so the graphite searcher
gives you a really easy way to
do simple threshold style
alerting uh and because the
graphite searcher basically
directly sends the query to
Graphite itself all of
graphite's data transform
functions are available for you
to be able to use for the
searcher so as an example of
some of the things you can do
you can essentially write a
query to say please fire off an
alert when you see a high rate
of change for failed logins. Now
I'm gonna talk a little bit
about the HTTPS searcher that
we're also making available.
This is a fairly straightforward
searcher what it does is you
provide an HTTP endpoint and if
you receive an unexpected
response code it creates an
alert based off of that. It's
very useful for web services
when you want to know if a
particular service is for
example down or even up and for
those in the devops community
this is very similar in
functionality to the tool called
NAGIOS. Now I'm gonna go to the
non live demo portion let's hope
this works [laughter] okay I'll
be narrating this so for this
demo we set up a very simple
wordpress blog instance called
Demo All The Things and we have
a we have a plugin installed
called WP Audit Log which logs
everything that happens in this
wordpress instance. In addition
we are forwarding the logs to
our own ELK stack so that we can
index the log files um here I'm
just showing off this one nice
blog post that we have uh red is
apparently the best color. Now
we're going into Kibana proper
to actually look at some of the
log files from this wordpress
instance and we can see here
there's an interesting log line
user deactivated a wordpress
plugin okay that's kind of
interesting maybe we can make an
alert off of that particular
phrase that we can use for the
future. So what we're going to
go and do now is we're going to
go into 411 proper we're going
to go into the searches tab
we're going to go and hit the
create button and create a new
searcher of the Logstash type
and we're basically just going
to create a new search to look
for this particular message
we're going to call this search
disabled wordpress plugin and
the query is going to look for
anything in the message field
that contains the phrase user
deactivated a wordpress plugin
and we're going to provide a
little description in the search
to let others that use 411 know
what this search is about in
case they have to deal with an
alert generated by it in the
future. We're going to look back
in the past fifteen minutes and
we're gonna test this alert and
we can see here that 411 has
successfully grabbed data from
um from logstash so we're going
to go ahead and create the
search and to actually generate
a real alert we're going to go
ahead and hit the execute button
which will cre- which will not
just test the alert it will
actually create a real alert for
us in the alert page we can see
here we get the same results
back that we just got from
hitting the test button so now
we're going to go into alerts
we're going to click on view to
take a look at our particular
the alert that was just
generated and we can see here
that in the in the plugin file
information we can see that the
duo wordpress plugin was
disabled well that's not good so
now that we've gotten the
relevant information from this
particular plugin we're going to
go ahead and remediate this
issue we're gonna go into the
wordpress back end we're going
to go into the plugins page oh
and what do you know? Duo two
factor off plugin the plugin is
disabled so we're gonna go ahead
and re enable it and now that
we've taken care of that issue
we're gonna go ahead and hit
resolve and we're gonna just say
that we've taken action to re
enable this plugin and we've
taken care of the alert by doing
that. That concludes the live
demo, not live demo [applause].
>>Cool and that also happens to
conclude the presentation as
well um once again 411s gonna be
open sourced after uh Defcon and
we will take questions now um
there's a mic over there and
over there so if you've got a
question please line up
[movement in the room] >>if
you're leaving you have to leave
out these doors in the back
>>when deciding to move away
from Splunk um how did you guys
scale ELK versus going with
Splunk like so ELK has a problem
when it gets really big it gets
really expensive so was it a
cost decision moving from
Splunk? >>ah the the question
was why did we switch from
Splunk um it was basically a
decision made by our operations
team >>Okay, one last question,
what are you guys using as your
send mail function? Are you guys
using like mail chimp? Um we've
just got everything setup
correctly already so it's
whatever um you provide to PHP
>>The question was what do we
use to send mail in 411? >>So um
yeah I have a question so you're
open sourcing 411 after this
talk or that's the first part
and the second part is do you
have an a is this built on a AWS
architecture such as using a
simple email service is it using
elasticsearch what is it using
as far as your infrastructure
that you can talk about? >>Um
we're going to be open sourcing
this after Defcon and as far as
Gmail um sorry what was the
second question, email right?
>>No is it AWS architecture, so
do you have an AWS architecture
to go with it? >>Uh no it's just
um whatever email like >>No no
no I meant in general the entire
because like elasticsearch are
you using like lando functions
or is it all pretty much like uh
uh internal to itself instances
as far as >>Everything's inside
like our data centers >>Okay got
it thanks >>questions? >>Hey um
I have a question about the
configuration you showed us, the
beautiful UOI but how is the
configuration actually stored
and uh yes there is a change log
on individual pages but would it
be easy to version control the
configuration somehow? >>so the
question was about change log
and version controlling of
alerts uh >>There is no version
controlling of alerts but there
is a change log of all of the
things that have been taken on
the alert so could you also
speak louder because I think the
mic isn't that great. >>oh okay
So the initial question was how
is the configuration stored? Is
it like is it stored in some
text format that you can review
is it xml is it, can we version
control it? >>All of it's stored
in MySql so we're using MySql as
a database. >>Hello Hello Hey uh
so at this point you guys are
probably definitely aware of
Watcher Allasa Searches own
alerting service um what's the
motivation between using their
own uh plugin built in straight
to the you know cluster? >>So uh
at the time when we started um
working on this I don't think
Watcher existed yet >>Yeah it's
super new >>So that's' why we
ended up writing this >>Right um
so is there any point to using
it now as opposed to just
running the plugin? I don't want
to be like that guy I'm just
>>Um I don't know you're kind of
putting me on the spot uh
there's also so it's not just
elasticsearch like you can also
plug in other data searches into
411 for like querying those data
sources >>Okay, thank you. >>Hi
um my questi- I have like two
questions one of them is what
was your motivation to move away
from Splunk and build your own
your motivation to move away
uh >>So that was a decision made
by our Sys Ops team. >>Okay >>So
I didn't really have any like
much input on that >>Uh but any
security concerns they had or?
Was it I mean did they have any
security concerns at all or yeah
>>I don't think so I think there
at one point like uh the
scripting functionality in ELK
was enabled by default and there
were some like serious security
issues with that so that's as
far as I can remember >>Okay and
um just one last question um
does ELK also help like you know
doing log analysis across
multiple servers and senses?
>>Uh >>Or is it like dedicated
to just like one group of >>Yeah
you can setup multiple instances
and have them like connect to
the same database and that would
just work >>Oh okay thanks
>>Okay >>Uh are ya'll open
sourcing that ESQuery as well?
Because Query DSL sucks >>Uh
yeah it's built in >>Oh it's
already up >>Huh? >>Oh it's
already up? Oh it's built in?
Okay >>MMhmm >>My questions on
uh Jira integration in your demo
you showed that you resolved uh
the issue with the user turning
off the the feature in wordpress
does that end up um closing a
jira ticket? >>Um no it doesn't
so uh the Jira like target is
pretty much separate you just
send that data off to Jira and
then like 411 forgets about it
>>Okay thank you >>Mmhmm >>K so
my question is a little bit two
fold >>Okay >>Uh we saw a lot of
web UI about this but uh there
wasn't any real uh uh focus on
any API around it so uh like
consider the use case where
there might be something where
uh the same type of alert
happens frequently but self
resolves uh would it have the
possibility to either escalate
the same type of alert due to
it's frequency or in contrast if
it somehow self resolves all of
the history of those alerts get
resolved as well? >>Um that's
not currently built in but
that's because like it hasn't
been asked for yet so um like
once this is open sourced you
could create an issue and then
we could consider it >>Okay
thank you >>Cool, guess that's
it [applause]