>>Let's give these guys a big
round of applause. [applause]
>>Hi guys so um this is Hendrik
I'm Brian. Um we've been doing
quite a bit of research in the
field of LTE 4G, We actually
started with the thereof talks
uh beginning of 2014 LTE bares a
star when actually showing you
know um the basic problems
behind the specs and did a few
theoretical attacks and now
basically we are back with the
practical stuff. Um we brought
our little toy our eNodeB in the
front here. Um we wanted to put
it up and have it running here
during the day but sadly our
power supply needs at least 160
volts it won't work on 115 so
sadly that won't be happening
but we've got everything else in
the slide so [inhales] Um we to
come from Germany we work for
ERNW we are um we are security
researchers and analysts. We do
quite lot of penetration tests
just a small company so we've
got quite lot of time for
research do quite lot of
interesting projects and ya
basically you know um [coughing]
all of us we're using 4G it's an
interesting topic so we just
decided to have a closer look at
it. Umm 4G brings quite a lot of
new standards bring in new
technologies and as always you
know it's new stuff so it so it
might be flawed and I said
before on the LTE bares a star.
When ya know we um [coughing]
found interesting stuff like the
the great grace nelse ciphering
algorithm. Even though
encryption has to be enabled and
ya basically we'll have a look
what exactly our eNodeB will be
doing. So what we're talking
about is actually a micro eNodeB
so it's not these tiny whimsy um
home eNodeB's that you put on
your desk or in your home or in
your office. We're actually
talking about the real base
stations that our outside in the
field and in the streets. Um
this picture actually comes from
Don Flamingo it's basically a
portal base station by AT&T as
you can see. Um the physical
protection set on the picture
but the fence is actually broken
if you go something like 2
meters to the left and you can
go in and then you've got your
classical 19 inch wrecks
[coughing] with locks on the
side. And if you got back up to
the village get a few lockpicks
basically you know how things
go. Um what actually makes life
really easy for ya us so this is
um the basic 4G network um
you've got the at the top there
S1MME which is the the
management plane and the U at
the bottom which is the user
plane. Um nicely enough the
[coughing] serving gateware at
the bottom actually eh basically
is a simple IP router and our
communication that comes in from
the eNodeB into the back end
network is normal standard IP
traffic so we don't have any
magical signaling proto-
protocols anymore as we had in
2G. [coughing] We can go in we
can lose all our classical
network attack suits and tools
and have a closer look at the
whole thing. So um belittle pot
from our forma talk you know
you've got physical protection
um nice sentences and specs
saying like um you only need to
use a P sec if the site isn't
physically protected that up
there is physical protection
number 1 this is physical
protection number 2. [audience
laughing] Um this actually in
the home town where I come from
I have to admit these aren't 4G
base stations. The one on the
right is an NSN 2G base station
by I think the German operator E
plus and the one on the left is
um by O2 so ya that's what we
see what's physical what
physical protection is. Um so
our basic approach ya know um go
in get a bay station when you
get it you try to go for Ebay.
If you're lucky you'll find one
um price wise let's say
something like um 100 dolla for
the main unit. So that's cheap
it's cheaper than some Cisco
switch. Um ya got the um got the
whole thing up and running and
actually look what's on there
and the classical stuff you know
you buy something on Ebay and
just hope for configuration data
and some real duh um real life
traffic. So the whole setup
consists of the uh the basement
unit which is um usually in the
rec on the ground um it includes
stuff like the power
distribution unit and things
like that to stack off sensors.
Then you've got the remote radio
head which usually are the the
big white boxes that you've got
on the sail mass undaneath the
tow- undaneath the antennas.
They basically just convert um
analog data which comes in by
via fiber into the actual
digital data which then goes all
via RF. Then you've got the
antenna set and all these pots
simply are interconnected. Um
the power pla supply that you'll
need is something like minus 48
volts. When we started with it
we actually thought about
something like plus minus 48's
volts or something like a
different of ninet- difference
of 96 volts luckily you just use
a 48 volt net uh power supply
and just turn around the
contacts then you've got minus
48 volts and everything will be
running. Um the RLU you only
need if you actually want to do
real RF so it's bonus. We don't
have it with us today it's um
about 25 to 30 kilos [coughing]
and ya it didn't quite fit into
our luggage. [inaudible talking]
So um the most important pot of
course is the BBU it's the
basement unit. It's the thing
that actual does um the logical
work so in the end if you can
see it it's on the in the bottom
of the rack. We'll have a few
pictures on the um slides later
on and you've basically got
blades in there so you put in a
LTE blade it's an LTE bay
station you put in a 2G blade
and it's a 2G bay station. So um
quite flexible some of them have
actually have a back plane which
means that you will need the
whole metal case to be able to
run the device. Um with our
Erickson bay station you just
need a few wires in the front so
you can actually just buy the
digital unit itself and you can
start working with it. Is it
here? No okay. Um then of course
a set variance of the eNodeB's
we're looking at the macro sithe
the real stuff outside not plus
S the small stuff. Um eventually
the nice thing about the eNodeB
is that it's actually um the
termination point of most
encryption. So the encryption
between your mobile phone and
cellular network will end in the
field of the eNodeB. On the
other hand all encryption from
the back end that goes out into
the field which should be IPsec
encrypted will yet again
terminate in the eNodeB. So you
know IP set clines are difficult
if you own a box you own a cline
so difficult and who knows what
could happen. [heavy breathing]
So the quick intro to the lab I
said you hit Ebay. [coughing]
Ebay sounds easy but you will
need a few little terms. We've
got em in the bottom here. So
for Nokia um this stuff is
called the flexi BTS for who eva
you'd be you looking for a BBU
an LMPT or a UMPT or both
actually. Um for Erickson you'd
need the RBS which is the 19
inch rec case and then the dul
with is the digital unite LTE
which is the logical part which
will do the LTE. All four I
could tell you losing it's the
NBS. Um bay station power supply
connect everything um quite a
lot of the stuff in telco
networks has magical connectors
so you might actually have to
sit down and create your own
connectors or really need quite
a while to actually get the
correct cables. We luckily
bought the overall box so
everything together in a set so
we we're quite lucky with that.
Um that's one of the first
pictures. Actually up there it's
a little Post-It that um one of
our friends put on there
actually saying um nano BTS so
kind of just for the scale the
antenna is about 2 meters 20
[coughing] so just the best
thing to play with and this is
our final lab set up so um we've
got our Ericsson up here we've
got 2 more whoever IBTS that
we're working with and you know
if you want to get started I
think all the stuff in the rec
should be about um 5 and a half
thousand euros or dollars so if
you're lucky you can go cheapa
otherwise you'll have to spend a
little bit of money. So the um
Ericsson RBS6601 And the dule
that's the part we'll be talking
about today. Um if you look at
it you know it's quite easy
you've got clack classical um
RJ45 sockets or adjusted
ethernet cables and you are up
and running. Um you've got
something like a GPS set up
which is used um you know LTE
base station are self
configuring so you can actually
send a doc out into the field to
actually puts the base station
up connects um and a GPS antenna
and adds um the HTP on the otha
side in the base station where
it gets all it's configuration
data from the co network and
it's work in a few minutes. So
you've got GPS on there um
you've got LMT which is the
local maintenance terminal which
is basically the port you use to
own a base station if you're
lucky. And then you've got the
TNA and TNB ports which
basically are the ports for the
beckett access. You've got the
IDL which is if you have
multiple blades [coughing] for
different cells in the device.
You interconnect em and then
you've got the ports the A, B,
C, D, E, and F which simply are
um jeebix slots actually just to
connect the RLU's and for the
RF. If you start with the whole
thing you do your sniff um
you'll be seeing down here um
we've got 2 VLANs VLAN 2 and 3.
One for the user plane the other
one for the operations and um
maintenance and you can see the
stuff will start talking up. So
what do you do you set up your
box um virtual em stream at the
VLANs and you just [coughing]
you know set upped the IP
addresses that it's looking for.
I think it's actually looking
for 10 IP addresses something
like that. >>Ya about >>And um
you know the moment when those
IP addresses are available
you'll see SCTP prefix
[coughing] which basically is um
the BTS trying to connect to the
beckett network to set up the RF
link. So from that moment on you
can do whatever you want. You
can start setting up your own
immulated core network and
really start attacking the base
station. [Shuffling] >>Good so
um let's start with our
attacking pot so all we've done
um is just to [inaudible word]
(11:24) base stations. So uh
that is the one we bought on
Ebay uh like Brian introduced oh
we um we bought online and that
is one which have been in
production I think think 1 year
ago or something like that so
it's a wheal eh inproductional
environment [low talking] 2
week, 2 years ago. Um soo it was
set up I think we've seen it in
the locked files 2012 something
like that um and whatever it was
a just uh ya we moved from that
and um now we have an example
and to demonstrate um how
attacks could uh look like in
real life unfortunately the
conflict was not a waste. It's a
1 to 1 conflict like it has been
in production. Um so how to do
that we have multiple layers we
can uh do some attacks on. The
fost first one um is the
signaling traffic so all that
traffic which is uh necessary to
set up connection from a phone
and to forward the traffic and
so on. To those one to face that
F 1 MME where the eNodeB stands
in communication with that MME
which is a management server and
is always exchanging farncombe
twelve information. So that is
the first one we can take a look
on. Um then there's was some
local maintenance interfaces
that LMT port. There are also
some remote maintenance
interfaces or eh or um as
operational stuff um like SSH
traffic whateva so if the
engineer don't wants to go on
side and plug in into that eh
yuh that connector. Um there are
also remote possibilities. Um in
this case the local maintain
interface was quite the same
like the remote one so um
everything what we can do with
the eh local interface we now
can do with the remote
interface. Um but there is quite
more um and then of course
because we have direct access to
the device uh we can do some
physical attacks. So just uh we
we move the cova and take a look
inside for example. Um
[coughing] and we have to do
that anyhow because we are we
got the whole box we had have no
credentials um so we try to uh
eh our goal was to understand
the whole box how it is working
uh of course we want to have
configuration access because we
want to use it for our our own
purposes and a finally because
um we are attacking it we want
to get root so we want to
extract maybe some binaries
later um to um take a look on.
[coughing] um again keep in mind
it's a wheelbase station um like
how it is out in the field so
it's not uh a theory or uh one
configured from us. Good um
let's start with the transport
interface so let's see um
connection from the eNodeB to
[coughing] the providers network
easy call Um that connection is
called S1 and ent um as
introduced by Brian that is
split up um in the contouring
plane called S1MME and S1U. Uh
SU1U is just for the user
traffic so that [coughing] means
your calls are um forwarded by
uh that interface so protecting
um for us now not that relevant
but if you have ack access to of
calls you can just access the
calls or SMS whateva or the
internet data um which is
transported uh over that
interface. Um physically it's
the same cable so if you are in
a man in the middle situation um
you have access to both. Um the
MME and introduced um is the
control interface uh this time
um if we just assign the IP
addresses to our laptop as we
have have connected to the
machine um there are a lot of
holes. [coughing] and for
example eh I think there are are
6 MME's configured on uh that
machine um but only one of them
has to be up so it's just for
availability reasons. Um if you
no isn't on our laptop uh that
IP address standing here on VLAN
2 um we could see that um the
device is establishing or tries
to establish a CTP connection
that is at S1 uh there is a
protocol behind called S1AP.
[coughing] Um but anyhow that
should not be possible we should
not be able to do that anyhow
because of the standards say
that uh it is required to
implement IPsec. Um so what we
expected as we have been
connected there uh is an IP set
connection. Um that is something
we have seen on one of the
hallway devices for example so
that is not e easy that easy to
get in of course but in this
case um we can directly talk IP
to it. Um why is there no IPsec
um there is one note in the
standards um like here and
displayed on an 3GP PTS set 3
and 4 oh 1. Um that note means
if the interface is trusted um
for example because it's
physically protected then there
is no need to use IPsec.
[coughing] And obviously em our
one was was physically
protected. And this is the same
for the um contour plane but
also for the user plane so there
was no difference the whole
security is based on the IPsec
here. Um there are also some
interconnections between
eNodeB's there uh again it's the
same. Um good and the same again
is for operation and maintenance
traffic so um it's a kind of
Linux on the box um so there was
an SSH like we will see later
and that one should also be
protected by a via IPsec but
here again it's not. Um let's
take a look 2 as 1 um so there
was a defined protocol called
S1IP the S1IP is used [coughing]
um to do all the necessary
procedures to transport
authentication information to um
establish a veerus so that a
connection from your mobile
phone uh to initiate hand ova's
and so on and so on. That one um
is implemented by uh STTP and
you can see that uh eh it for us
uh 1 IP T uh STTP [coughing]
port 36412 is used. Um that is
exactly that what we have seen
in that first wire shock sniff.
Um just to give you one example
what is possible um via that
interface um here is a list of
all the standards uh implemented
for S1 but also for X2. X2 is at
interconnection of eNodeB's so
from our eNodeB we can
theoretically also talk to uzza
eNodeB's um and we can talk to
uh the the management entity uh
in the core network um or just
ya try to compromise our um
eNodeB itself and effect the
traffic anyhow. Um so we see
[beep] here some functions like
[beep] NAS signaling [beep] that
is [beep] the transport [beep]
of [beep] authentication
information for example [beep]
um we have some [beep] uh trace
functions to just eh take a look
where our mobile count accountly
is uh we also have a
configuration transfer that
means the MME is pushing some
configuration updates ova that
interface to the eNodeB like
changing um the e eh RSTN the
frequency or uh um and so on or
just makes itself louda. Um that
is everything implemented
because um there was eh so
called feature called se self
organizing network or self
optimizing networks so um the
the central [inaudible] will
talk with all eNodeB's in the
country and [coughing] um ma
will also make some load
balances and so on so if ther is
a need or the the uh black hole
of um uh ya if you don't have a
signal um then the power is
turned up at the eNodeB
automatically. Sometimes that un
that uz that the functions we
can um ova that interface. Um
because there is no IPsec
there's only one message uh we
had to simulate to access uh
that interface. It's called the
S1 set up request um or setup
setup response so the eNodeB is
sending that request to the MME
we assigned that IP address and
now we immulated um [coughing]
that MME. We've written uh a
shop 2 uh we also we'll publish
afta afta the talk uh it's
called uh fake MME which is just
uh establishing the connection
and uh making ya the the
necessary configure uh um
configuration to turn that one
up but it's not much necessary
so basically only thats as one
set up request and maybe some uh
configuration changes so that
configuration transfer. Um so
what we have had now wanting is
uh the eNodeB is up and uh we
have uh MME simulated now we can
start attacking. Um for that
again we um made uh a second
script it's an it's a middle
tool where we can inject our own
S1 messages so all the messages
shown in the picture we can
inject. It's just an STTP you
just need to um in the middle
that um while you just can can
use some Python script um and
then uh we modulated some of it
as S1 messages to check if it is
really working. Um who's
interested toward you we use a
um off ef ya ef a thousand crew
kit of us called Dizzy uh which
we use for spoofing of the
messages um some of the scripts
are published on our blog um so
we can do some scanning we can
do tracing of some UE's and so
on. That is uh the main purpose
of that interface. Good um so
that is the main connection for
connectivity um but still we
want to be a route in the
device. We want to access the
configuration itself um so we
need some err possibilities and
to push configuration use the
maintenance tools and so on. Um
that is over the OM network um
here in our N uhP it's a
different VLAN. It's VLAN uh
suite. Um there are again a
couple IP addresses used for
that uh we just picked out one
of them. Um because that one was
used for NTP for example and so
we um an just similithed our own
NTP serva that's although
necessary because of cause of
the eNodeB must have some timing
information otherwise this uh
will not work correctly um so
that's quite easy. Um taking a
further look to the interface eh
though we met an in net scan uh
here you see see the outcome uh
quite interesting of course the
FTP and telnet phone um for a
device from 2012 or something
like that I don't know if that
is really necessary but okay
they have SSH um anyhow but all
interfaces work so and then we
see a port 80 so HTTP serva not
HTTPS but uh I dunno if you
really need HTPS on that
connection um in reality that
should be IPsec again right and
we have some higher range ports
like that 8443 and 56834 which
are used for the uh maintenance
tools um we will show directly
afta here. Um so the maintenance
tools are very interesting
because that are used by the
engineers if they are going
inside so on setup of the
machine for example or if there
is a problem. So the eh for
example if there is a false
state of the base station um an
engineer will come on site plug
into a maintenance port and um
doing something reconfiguring
and getting lock files um
accessing the monitoring with
some magic [coughing] tools that
always depends on the venla. Um
in our case that is also
possible remotely so via the
transport network um but you can
only uh also plug into the LMT
port which is just a different
connector and then you have all
the access to that uh ya
interfaces and tools. Ya um so
that is why we are focused on um
to get access uh to the
environment um if you go on the
web server um so that port 80
you directly have a download
option of that magic tool so um
that's really great that they
provide it to us uh that way.
Very nice. Um unfortunately it's
only running on on the le on the
Windows so uh not that easy for
us um but the most problem was
that JAVA 1 dot 5 was necessary
um so we first had to install XP
again. [speaker laughing]
[audience laughing] [applause]
[whistling] Thank you. [speaker
laughing] [applause] Ya that was
all almost the the um biggest
problem to us to install JAVA 1
dot 5 in XP um eh okay uh if we
have it running uh we could just
connect um that was quite
interesting because uh we
started the tool and then we had
access to some information like
uh the radio frequency
information and so on so that is
how the tool's looking like. Um
so you have different views for
different configuration parts
like the whole rec here standing
in which fans um um arc so the
uh fan controller is inside
there um some debugging
information some monitoring
information and you can also
access lock files like that one
and you see there are a lot of
flaw umffmm uh ya arrows are
popping up of course because em
some other pots of that rec were
that eNodeB was in uh missing um
but okay you can just remove
that pots in the real
configuration and [coughing]
then it's looking um so that's
not a problem. More interesting
is um em maybe you have missed
like us um though again in the
standards there stands something
that the uh that's heading up
and configuring the eNodeB shall
be authenticated um
unfortunately there was no
password for that tool so we
just started that tool like here
you can uh you can set up a IP
address a name and maybe a
comment then you click on
connect and you are in so again
quite too easy. See again the
the mm eh biggest problem was to
just install the tool. Um okay
so we had configuration access
but still um we had no operating
system as access. The
configuration of that one which
the um [high pitch noise] ya
engineer is using but
furthermore over that interface
there are some other services
provided FTP telnet and SSH Um
that is where we also uh wanted
to take a look on but we have mm
so we can also try some exploits
on Java so since 1 dot 5 I see
there was [coughing] quite a lot
um so that is also a good
possibility to compromise a
machine in our case it's
unfortunately not asking for a
password so we can't do some
password google falsing here. Um
and if you connect to with that
tool um it's establishing a
connection to the tyrant port
[mic boom] I showed you in the
end map [mic boom] so that 5 6
establishing connection via D up
so it's um Java um I think Brian
was saying something to that
lata. Um and ova that interface
it's transmitting um the whole
configuration data of the NBTS
and that is also not
authenticated and eh secured
anyhow so there was no umm ya
sequence you can to replay
attacks whateva you just need to
know how the gear up is working.
It is just transmitting the uh
continuation uh directly. So um
next look that was also not that
hot um there were 2 users
configured on the system called
RBS and Cello Uza and za
password for both was RBS. Um
[coughing] and again we could
lock in via telnet and via FTP
and uh via FFH. Um okay there
are some out dated SSH keys used
uh so our system was prohibiting
the connection first and so we
have to enable that algorithms
um manually um but okay then we
are in and had access to the
whole device. Um if ya take a
look to the file system there
was a lot of interesting
information like the past W's so
it's a kind of Linux you see
here. Uh where we can expect
passwords again if there are
otha users configured but
usually not supported. Um but
more interesting is that
security CFG uh and that folder
called IPsec. That's a folder
where the IPsec keys are stored
so if you have access you can
just extract yours uh IP secs in
keys here. So again weally
weally nice [cough] um because
it's also possible remotely um
gives the uh tech here a lot
possibilities right. Good um
then we had access to everything
could take a look to the locka
configuration and also to the um
local web serva and the local
web serva was vulnerable to a
couple of exploits because it
[laughs] again used a maybe
outdated Java SD case O116 um
there are also some otha ones
which so uzza and ya and Java
applications running on which
are using some uzza um outdated
Java's [exhales] um so there's
couple a lots eh possibilities
to compromise a machine.
[inhales] Um and the we server
is just used to um ya provide
the element melon manager which
is it LMT tool um dow to
download um and also some XML
configuration is placed there.
You can also dive the excess
without any configuration you
duh you just need to know the
pass but you see if you're
starting the tool um you see uh
in wire shock. Um while we
discovered the web serva uh
[chuckles] we unfortunately uh
had another vulnerability found
here just in DOS but it was not
a DOS of the web serva it was a
DOS of the whole eNodeB and
because um the web serva is
running with higher privileges
in the operating system itself
so it crashed. While we scanned
the machine or the web serva
with a crawl the whole machine
crashed um but also interesting.
[inhales] Um good so far uh
we've taking a look to the close
uh uh to the the configuration
to the operating system so uh we
had some uh access to um
obviously the whole machine was
not why uh wiped or erased by
the um provider um and obviously
no IPsec is used on that machine
but okay even if it's used umm
you find a way to connect to and
expect the IPsec keys. [inhales]
Um there are some kind of hard
coded or default credentials um
like RBS R er um RBS or cello
user RBS and there was a
possibility to change it um but
I think it's not really used in
uh it was not that easy and even
the lock in was an LM manager is
working anyhow all the time. Um
there was Telnet in use also
interesting because you can just
uh sniffs the traffics in and
then you have to get the real
credentials if somebodies
logging in and you have a lot of
unencrypted maintenance
interface. So um so what's
running on um the eNodeB has an
um uh real time OS running um so
it's very very plain and it's
about uh it's I'll start on an S
on uh a compact flash you see
here so if you just open the
dedevice you have a compact
flash in where the whole
operating system and the file
system is on. Um that's quite
interesting um so there were
just some plob problems here
because it's not easy eh it has
an own file system which um
which is based on Gzip so we you
just have to recognithe it
first. Um but the architecture
is in power PC's so we expect it
um to see the some powerPC
binaries um and the
architectures also its says that
by some FPGAs and also one um uh
processor to do all the radio
stuff and so on. Um the flash
disk [exhales] the first talk um
we removed that from our eNodeB
and plugged it into our laptop
um first it was not that easy
because it's a flipped
architecture so all that uh
little indian big indian stuff
um we see we can see here in
that binary if we made an
analysis um that the alphabet
here is just uh it's flipped so
we had to switch that first to
access the direct information
like that powers PC binaries you
see here. [inhales] Um and then
all the files here are Gzipped.
It It's a small system so it's
an embedded system so they just
want to um ya keep some space.
Or save some space. Um but now
we have access to the uppa layer
operating system could attack
binaries and um start with
reverse engineering. Um and also
because we had access to that uh
volume we can again extract the
IPsec keys. [coughing] Good um
another interesting one if
you're on the machine uh just
for deeba debugging you have
some uh debugging interfaces
enabled there and you have a WAM
lock and the WAM lock um
displays um the whole routing
process so if you want to do
some attacking there you can
just um hold the machine uh on
the white uh places here. There
are also some uh commands for
that and you see here on step 2
that it's mounting that Gzip
volume and powering up and so
that it our volume we extracted
here um so we can just modify
it. Um just small joke uh for us
uh is that line that no magic
found uh that was quite funny to
see that in the lock file. Good
um the rest is for Brian. >>So
um you know you go in and a set
this configuration on there um
you know you got a mobile
country code and a mobile
network code actually finding an
operator. Um luckily you found
the numbers 311 and then we see
660 and turns out it's an
american operator or an old one
metro PCS only one of yous eva
heard it um they were actually
kind of sold or they fused with
T Mobile USA in 20 12 or a
little bit later. Um so we know
where exactly this uh the eNodeB
comes from. Yet again you know
if you actually had a client
certificate that would be
probably the most awesome
combination. Um then you know we
found a few little interesting
things ya know the classical
past WD command for changing a
password um we've got cello user
and we've got RBS and we
actually just wanted to change a
password [coughing] just to play
around with it and actually it
turned ri- um turned out that if
you change the password for RBS
also the password for cello user
will be changed and the other
way around. So for some reason
they actually combine the
passwords for both user accounts
somehow magically even for past
WD's so it looked a little bit
strange. Then um as Hendrik
already said ya know we've got
quite old SSH so we actually had
to go in and go in for our old
diffie hellman group 1 shire 1
um modern SSH simply won't do
this anymore so we had to re
enable it. Um then when you're
on the box um interesting you
had something that was called
cell and MUE tracers. Um sadly
we only had cell tracers so
basically you can see um status
and lock information of the cell
that actually was on the eNodeB
and a few neighboring cells. Um
from the documentation the info
that we found if we would have
had an um UE trace this UE trace
actually locks everything that a
mobile device in the LTE cell
does over a certain amount of
time. So you know if you have
access to an eNodeB in the field
you just kick in the UE trace
command and you basically lock
all unencrypted information that
goes through that mobile device
so rather nice for playing
around with. Then yes um you
know when you you do stuff you
always find really really really
strange things so um all
communication that you've seen
so far went into um private IP
address base which is the way
that you do it in your own
network. Now we found a G up
remote session that was actually
uh trying to find a serva to a
public IP address um we were
able to have it connecting to us
so ya know you've got basic um G
up communication which you could
attack but um if anybody knows
the nature of G up you need
quite a lot of information to
actually be able to push objects
over the line until something
happens. So um you know as it
was the only public IP address
we had a closer look at it and
I've got to say you know um the
next slide is it's vague. You
know we can't guarantee for any
correctness on the next slide
but um you know what you do
you've got an IP address you
look it up and um you remember
metro PCS. the IP address that
we found actually belongs to an
uh Iranian cellular operator. So
you [coughing] we can't
guarantee that um basically the
American tale code simply um
miss used the pu- um a public IP
address but you've got to admit
it simply looks very very
strange and time wise uh if you
go down to the um address base
was actually registered in 20 12
and we know from the lock files
that the eNodeB was up and
running in the field up to 20 13
um so you know for what reason
is this American eNodeB actually
talking to an to the network of
an Iranian operator. It's
strange and doesn't make any
sense [audience chatter] So you
know um I said the information
is vague we've just got the data
that we've got off the eNodeB
we've got no idea if maybe the
IP address base was ya know
snared or something like that or
is that a misused public IP
address but stuff like that
actually just is scary and we
have to say um the port that it
connected to you know um on the
Iranian IP address now a days is
down. So whatever was running
there isn't there anymore so um
ya you knows little bit of scary
shit in teleco networks. >>So
okay so first that was our first
start with our research. We
wanted to um ya present for you
um we could see that there's no
magic behind as the lock file
already has um it's just uh yeh
easy system uh which some else
special characters I would say
um there's it's also very
strange that there most of the
devices have no uh that the
conflict is still not a waste.
Um we also uh uh bought a second
blade for that RBS um just while
we are here um that one is from
T Mobile and it looks exactly
like the same. Um so um that is
quite interesting to do a lot of
stuff where we now also have
acs- en ya access to the
binaries which is some future
work for us we are taking a look
to that um but basically if you
the attack factor for such
devices uh based on that
signaling so you can just um
access that management uh con
control traffic there and to do
some traces of UE's to um ya
establish connection on you own
or also hand ova. There was no
security in reality and um uh
sometimes there was no security
so that IPsec stuff or even if
you are able to extract it
somehow. Um for example like
that OAM and what we've seen
there is not really good so
that's an architectural problem
I think um or a hardening
problem so that is a development
hopefully the uh vendors are
working on um but um that is a
quite new device um uh quite new
2012 so it's an LTE device which
is out in the field so we expect
that there are a lot of base
stations out there which are
exactly configured like that. Um
and if signaling and OAM is not
working even then um with having
physical access to devi device
you can just yelp get that uh
flash disc that compact flash
and put it to a laptop extract
all necessary information like
the password file like the IPsec
information and then you're in
again so there is a lot to do.
Good um so that's it so far um
that is what we wanted to
present to you this time um
thank you. Um If there are any
questions let me know ya.
[applause]