>> So Jake is going to talk
about attribution, um, which I
can only presume is going to be
exclusively about either Russia
or China.[laughter] So let's
give Jake a big round of
applause. [applause] >> Thank
you everyone. Great to see
everyone here. I seriously don't
see enough beverages in people's
hands though, so. Maybe you
should fix that. But my name's
Jake, I'm a CISO with Risk Based
Security. Been doing a bunch of
vulnerability and data reach
intelligence stuff for quite
some time. I want to also
recognize Lee Johnstone for all
the work and creation of data
and everything. So the talk here
is, uh, today, it's "'Cyber' Who
Done It?! Attribution Analysis
Through Arrest History." So we
really are going to play a cyber
drinking game. You guys are just
going to have to get over it,
because we're going to say cyber
a ton through this talk. So, um,
anytime you in the slides that
it says cyber or you hear me say
cyber. You should drink. I only
see a few beverages over here,
so we'll see. Um, and I don't
care if it's beer or Root Beer,
so, no pressure. Alright, so if
you look back over the last five
years. Data breaches keep
occurring at alarming rates.
Right, it's, it's just
ridiculous, uh the amount and it
just shows that it's not getting
better and so it doesn't matter
how many blinky lights, boxes,
we buy from security vendors,
we're still just seeing a
ridiculous amount of breaches.
In fact, 2015 was the most
amount of breaches that we've
ever, ever tracked. When you
look at it from, how are these
things occurring, there's that
old 1970s thought process, I
think from the FBI that says,
the insider, right? But when you
look at the data from 2015, it
shows that 77 percent of them
are actually coming from the
outside. Right? Now, the insider
may hurt you the worst, but it
shows in terms of likelihood the
outside where it's occurring and
then when you break it down by
the breach types, it's just
hackings through the roof,
right? So we're just seeing a
ton of hacking and it's been
that way the last couple of
years. When you look at it from
where it's happening, what
countries, where these
organizations are being
impacted, this isn't just a USA
issue, right? Now while the USA
and the, um, and the UK are
accounted for 46 plus percent of
the breaches, it's not just
there, right? So it is a world
issue. And year to date, we
still suck, right? We're not
getting any better. Uh, over
2000 data breaches confirmed
already and it's the most amount
of records that we've ever lost
in a single year. We're already
over at 1 point 1 billion
records being lost and we still
have a couple months to go. So,
um, not seeing much improvement
at this point. The question we
get all the time when we're
tracking these data breaches is,
who's behind all this stuff?
Right? Who is behind and causing
all of these data breaches? It
comes up all the time.
Specifically the hacking events.
Who is behind it? So this leads
us to this whole concept of
attribution, right? And if you
try to get your head wrapped
around attribution and what does
it really mean, you can start
looking on good old Wikipedia,
right? And that gives us a few
different ideas about what
attribution is and other
disciplines, so in social
psychology attribution is a
process of explaining cause and
behavior events. In copyright
law it's about crediting the
work. In journalism it's about
attribution to a source, right?
So you start to get familiar
there. Now in the cyber world,
we basically just want to know,
who did this, right? We want to
know, what the hell did you just
do? What actually happened? What
was done? And then finally, why?
Why did you do this, what are
the motives, can I have some
reasons? Right? So if you think
about it, you always hear this
saying, you know knowledge is
power, but in these days and
times, it's really starting to
be attribution is power, right?
And this seems to be the case,
we want to know what's going on,
who's behind all this stuff. So,
nothing brought this attribution
debate and problem, um, more
clear than the Sony breach in
December 2014. Right? So we
should all remember this whole,
GOP, Guardians of the Peace,
post credit, taking credit for
this breach. Um, and there was
serious debate over this breach.
What was the motives, who did
it? And it was so ridiculously
bad about the back and forth
lead to just a ridiculous amount
of lulls from the security
community, right? So we actually
created these cyberwar
attribution bingo cards. It
still exists, if you want them,
you can go out to the website
and generate your own cards and
play along, right and see what
happens. But if you're not up
for games, then then there was a
couple of guys who created the
Sony Hack Attribution Generator.
So that you can go to the
website and then sort of refresh
to get what you want. So you go
to this first one and get the
nice report here about a Sony
Manager behind it. I don't like
that one. Uh, Romania
organization. Hmm, that's
better. Welp, now we have North
Korea. Right, here's a nice
detailed report. You can just
keep refreshing, right, so you
guys can get reports. They
weren't the only one, we
actually had another website
created called, who hacked us
dot com. You can get attribution
reports here. Here we get China,
right? Crouching Panda, Hidden
Dragon, so here's your China
reference starting. But if you
don't want a detailed report and
that's just too much, guess
what? We had the industry create
cyber attribution dice. So you
can just roll the dice and get
the answer, right? And why would
you pay for high price forensics
when you can just roll the dice?
Right? That's probably the best
attribution you're going to get
anyway. Some people weren't so
thrilled about the cyber dice
and they said, you know what we
need? We need a magic eight
ball. And guess what? Twitter
answered. We have the
attribution eight ball. Right?
And unfortunately it hasn't been
active here recently, so
whoever's behind this account,
I'd appreciate if you could step
up your game and start tweeting
out some stuff again for us.
But, Twitter's not just enough,
so we have duo that comes up,
right and they create the actual
attribution eight ball. And of
course it's China. And you gotta
love the pictures behind there,
right? It was China and who's
showing, right? so We see that,
then we see good old swift own
security when we talking about
the MySpace breach, and should
we blame Russia or what's going
on. Saying hey, we need another
magic eight ball. And at this
point in time, because we know
the attribution eight ball is so
important, Threatbutt comes to
the rescue and so no offense to
Duo, but Threatbutt creates an
attribution eight ball and if
you don't know about Threatbutt,
you should, because, uh, they
basically provide the maximum
protection from threatening
threaty threats, like China. So
we're really pleased, that they,
uh, were able to help us out
here. So thanks to Threatbutt
for all your hard work. So with
all the lulls aside, I mean it's
a serious issue and people joke
about stuff like this, because
there's something behind it,
right? And the jokes are funny,
but let's get back to the Sony
breach and walk through it. And
the point was who did this
thing? Right, everyone wanted to
know. And for the purposes of
this talk, there was basically
two major viewpoints. One was,
North Korea and the other one
was an insider, also known as
not North Korea. Right? And so,
on the North Korea side, we
predominantly had Crowd Strike
and the FBI and on the insider,
also known as, not North Korea,
we had Norse, Mark Rogers and
Kim Zetter from Wired coming out
with information. So here's from
Norse, right, so Norse basically
was not involved in the case
itself, but they said they were
doing their own investigation
and they said that the Norse
data was pointing toward a woman
that called herself Lena, and
claimed to be connected with
this, the GOP Hacking Group.
Norse believed that they
identified the women who had
worked at Sony in Los Angeles
for about ten years and then was
involved with it. And so what
comes from them is, we are very
confident that this was not an
attack master-minded by North
Korea. Right, so they're coming
out pretty vocal, it's not like,
it may be, it's we're pretty,
we're pretty damn confident it's
not them. Then you have Mark
coming out basically saying, he
wasn't seeing hard evidence
either and he had some really
good articles if you haven't
read you should go to his
website and read, to better
understand his point of view,
but he mentioned things like,
the broken English that was
being used for attribution
looked really too deliberate.
Right, uh, the code that was
written on a PC with the Korean
local, um, makes it actually,
probably not North Korea. Uh,
hard coded paths and passwords
and what not, really did uh make
it seem like someone knew that
information from Sony from the
inside. And one of the other
things that he said to, was
blaming North Korea was an easy
way out for people, uh,
including the security vendors
that were brought in and paid
and Sony management and all that
because of that whole Interview
move and everything, it was just
sort of an easy way to do it.
And you can see here, even after
the FBI started to come out and
saying it was North Korea, he
still saying, I still don't
believe that, that's the case.
Kim Zetter from Wired, she
basically published a story
saying that the evidence was
flimsy. Ah, again it's a great
article if you want to get some
more information about it. And
she was basically saying that
the assertion about who was
behind it, um, you should should
be skeptical of these things.
And it's easy for attackers to
plant these false flags or point
to North Korea and those sorts
of things and a lot of the
evidence that was presented was
circumstantial. Right? And then
here's Dimitri from Crowd
Strike, so he comes in and
basically says, North Korea. And
that's it, North Korea, nothing
else. Now what funny, is at
Black Hat, I ran into Dimitri
for the first time and I sort of
told him, hey Dimitri, your face
is going to pop up several times
in my talk at DefCon and we sort
of had a spirited debate for
about an hour. Uh, he still
believes it's North Korea and
that's that. Right? Now, what
was also interesting was we
started to see this attribution
stuff go really in the
mainstream. Right here you have
Mark Rogers and Dimitri on PBS
doing a live debate on
attribution. Who did it, right?
So we're seeing this isn't just,
you know, in our industry, it's
starting to come out, more and
more people trying to figure out
what's going on. So then we have
Sony and this is sort of
mid-December 2014, they publish
a more official update and a
statement basically saying that
as a result of our investigation
and close collaboration with
other government agencies, the
FBI has now enough information
to conclude that North Korean
government is responsible. So
pretty definitely from the FBI.
No matter even though that came
out, we still are seeing Crowd
Strike Verse Norse quite a bit
and there were a few others, but
those were the most loudest, if
you will, um talking about this
stuff actually FireEye Inc
Mandiant who was hired by Sony,
they also, they were pretty
quiet in the press, Kevin
Mandiant did come out and say a
few things such as, um, the the
the attacks that happened in
South Korea in 2013 were very
similar, the same, that was
being used for Sony, so they
attributed those 2013 hacks to
North Korea, so therefore, it
was Sony, or, uh, North Korea
behind this. So we were actually
at RBS, we were documenting this
whole thing and we've got this
big article, like a breakdown of
it trying to track everything
that was going on. And we
started to think, right, you
have these two, you know, you've
got Crowd strike and you've got
Norse, so these two ridiculously
funded VC companies, the hottest
threat intelligence, with
ridiculously polar opposite,
like, it's an insider and this
is North Korea and they are both
sort of arguing. So it made sort
of start to think, these bold
statements, um, if you make this
bold statement and it turns out
to be wrong, does it mean that
the intelligence you sell sucks?
Can't be trusted? Right? You
come out and say, oh, this is
definitely and in and it's
proven wrong, then is your
product any good? So, what we
happen is is in January, so all
that stuffs going on in December
2014, then we see, um, the FBI
comes out and again says, hey,
look, it definitely is, um,
North Korea behind this. A week
or so after that update, then we
see Krebs come out and say that,
there's some rumors that Norse
is about to implode. Right? And
there the ones remember, that
said it was an insider, not
North Korea. Whether that has to
do with it or not, it's quite
interesting. Further on that, in
March of 2016, you can see this
Tweet, sadness defined, the RSA
booth, it looks like they
through down a huge amount of
money for a booth and then it
was just this kind of deserted
smaller thing, right? So, not so
good. And everyone was
immediately worried, right?
We're going to lose the live
attack map and while most people
that I know could care less
about that, they like showing it
to management to get more
budget, right? Like look at
that, it's serious stuff in
cyber, right, we need help. But
the good news is we have good
old Threatbutt that's come back
to help us again. I'm serious,
right? The Threatbutt Internet
Hacking Attack Attribution Map.
And you can see here by
leveraging the patent Crowd
Strike technology, they've made
it even better. Right? So they
did give credit to, uh, pew pew,
but they make all the threat
stuff better, so. Alright, so
why is this attribution stuff so
hard? And it's actually even
hard to put into words. And this
people that will disagree, if
you're in this space, I'm sure
you're already upset at me or
Tweeting me back things or
whatever, but the reality is,
it's still challenging, right?
So I want to put out a few
things of, why attribution in
the cyber space is a little
tricky. So a lot of the
attributes that you typically
see in the real world just don't
exist in the cyber world. So
that sort of hardcore CSI
forensics investigation work
just isn't as possible, right?
It's considered to be easy to
spoof some of these things.
Plant these things. It's
considered to be easy to embed
other people's work. Tools,
exploits, malware. You know,
just because you see this sample
of this in this particular
attack doesn't mean it was the
exact same person, right?
Someone else could have easily
taken that code. Now for people
in this space, they'll get a
little snippy sometimes and say,
well if the source code wasn't
available, there was no way it
could have been found, I mean,
there's lots of debates about
this stuff, but it makes it
challenging. And then that whole
sort of concept of not having a
a physical territory right, some
markers that you'll hear in the
cyber warfare world or the
traditional warfare world, like
an assembly zone, boundaries to
cross, be able to track things
back specifically on missile
launch. All those sorts of
things, they just don't really
exist in the cyber space, right?
And honestly, I have so many
slides to get through
because as I'm working on this
talk, there's more and more shit
happening. Right, so then we
have the DNC that gets hacked,
right? Um, so right. And then
it's actually so bad that Jeff
in Blackhat have to decide they
gotta raise some money for them
to get better at security it
seems, so. Alright. So, um, this
one we have the, we have the
issue, right and we have
Guccifer 2.0 that comes out and
takes credit for the breach,
right? So now we're starting to
look at attribution in terms of
taking credit for it. So if you
know anything about the original
Guccifer, it was a Romanian man
who hacked, uh, lots of high
profile government accounts,
claimed to hack Hilary's private
e-mail servers. All those sorts
of things. And Guccifer 2.0 goes
onto say, uh, Guccifer may have
been the first one who
penetrated Hilary and other
Democratic mail servers, but he
certainly wasn't the last, no
wonder any other hacker could
have easily got into these DNC
servers, right. So then again
now we go immediately into the
press to, alright, cyber
attribution and questions there,
right. And so everyone's
immediately trying to figure out
who did this and it seems like
an absolute broken record and,
uh, Dimitri's back. Right, so,
uh, he's back. And Crowd Strike
tells us, this time it's Russia.
Now, what's interesting for this
one, it's a little bit different
for the Sony one, there was a
lot of people sort of arguing on
both sides on the Sony one, but
so far, most people seem to
agree and are saying that it's
Russia in this particular case.
Actually the only one so far
that I've seen that hasn't said
it was Russia, was Donald Trump
was being interviewed and he
said something like Russia,
Russia, eh, it's probably China.
So, um, now China's somehow
brought in allegedly. But here
we actually have Fidelis,
they're another security company
and they came out and they
basically said, they are also
very confident that it's Russian
or actors and what they said it
was that they looked at the
code, uh, there was the use of
the Russian alphabet keyboard
and the time zone it was
compiled in. Some of the malware
on those sorts of things. They
also went on to say that the
evidence pointing to Russia was
so convincing, it would have had
to have been a very elaborate
scheme, um, for it to be anyone
else. And so that's a little,
um, I don't know. I look at it
and I start thinking, these are
the things that people
complained about the last time
around that could be spoofed and
all those sorts of problems, so
if it is, the wording that
they're using is a little tough.
Alright, so then the media right
now still isn't clear. There's
another article that's
publishedsaying, hey is this an
individual? Is this a Russian
front. Um, even though I see
most of the security people
agreeing, they're sort of saying
experts aren't so sure, can you
imagine that, we don't agree in
the security world. Uh, Crowd
Strike were the ones hired by
the DNC, but again everyone does
sort of point to Russia right We
have Clinton stating it's
Russia, she draws some sort of
line to Trump maybe, um, it's a
bit confusing because it sounds
like the DNC's been owned for a
very long time, so in my mind,
Trump wasn't even considered a
candidate then, but now we're
blaming him for potentially even
doing it. And my sort of, the
reason why I think this one's
interesting, is because now it's
just not who did it, it's who's
behind it trying to orchestrate
and make people do these hacks.
You know, so we're just getting
more and more of this sort of
stuff. And the conversation of
what is there to be gained and
who can gain from these attacks?
Alright, now we're getting a
little more interesting in the
DNC, because shortly after the
DNC, uh, hack was attributed to
Russia, it's now reported that
there's a professional
cyber-attack that hit the
Russian government. So we start
thinking back back now, right?
And so some articles come out
saying that the NSA is likely
hacking back, uh, due to the DNC
hack. Now most of you are giving
me blank looks, dirty looks
saying, hey, you think this is
the first time that we haven't
been hacking all over the place?
The NSA hasn't been hacking. But
other people will say and start
to believe that this may be the
first major time you know that a
sanction nation state hack back
has occurred, right? So we just
keep going down this path. So it
leads us to the question of,
does it actually matter if we
get cyber hack attribution
correct? Do we even care, right?
For most companies and
organizations where you work,
does it really matter who
attacked you? You've got to deal
with the breach, you got to deal
with the problem. The fact that
you got hacked is the issue.
That's not going to change a
whole lot about financials or
whatever else, right? Uh, but
for other cyber attribution, it
does really matter. Because
after the Sony attack, right,
when the FBI concluded it was
North Korea and the USA imposed
sanctions on North Korea in
response. In February of 2016,
Congress sends North Korea cyber
sanctions bill to Obama, uh,
saying that anyone that's caught
aiding the country's cyber cane,
they're going to get penalties
now as well. So we're seeing the
attribution leading to real
world things. So last month,
North Korea expressed their
thoughts about the US sanctions.
Uh, the foreign ministry issued
a statement carried by the
Korean Central News Agency,
basically saying the sanctions
on Kim and ten other and
officials were peppered with
lies and fabrication and then
went on to say that now that the
US has declared war on the DPRK,
any problem arising in relations
with the US will be handled
under the latters wartime law.
So we're seeing things, even
though there's a lot of rhetoric
that comes out of certain
countries, we're seeing things
escalate base on attribution.
And then just a few days ago,
um, now it's reported that the
United States is considering
economic sanctions on Russia for
hacking, right? The various
activities in cyber space, that
economic sanctions have been
used before and they could
possibly be used in preparing
for response of cyber threats.
So how can we actually figure
out what's going on behind these
hacks? Um, No, or why can't we
might be a better question,
right? Those security firms
typically tend to agree. Uh, we
can't trust when people are
claiming attacks, easy to hide
IP addresses via proxy servers,
Tor, etc. Correlations as we've
already talked about between
certain pieces of malware really
aren't just hard evidence,
although people in this space
will debate that to death. Uh,
information and evidence many
times isn't fully shared, uh to
protect sources. So just say,
trust me, this is what it is.
And then there's this whole
behavioral analysis of of doing
analysis of writings and things
like that, which doesn't come
across to many as very hard
evidence. So then as we go from
there, then the question becomes
do we actually need to improve
our cyber attribution
capabilities. And you know I
don't really care for the folks
that think that they're doing it
really awesome and it's well
enough or perfect, that's great.
There's still, uh, others that
they aren't so sure, but I think
that if we're going to be
punishing countries and getting
more of this act of war
rhetoric, we better be damn sure
that when we come out and say
something that we actually know
what's going on and so
regardless of whether you're on
one side or the other in terms
of how we are with attribution
right now, I think we can all
agree that we need to continue
to invest in and improve a
digital attribution. It's clear
that the impact could have and
there are a lot of smart people
working on this, so I think
that's great. Alright, so this
leads us to the Arrest Tracker
Project. So what we wanted to do
was we want to collect data to
hopefully better understand, um,
what's going on with cyber
crimes, right. Another view
point, of to attribution and of
much different lens, right? And
so, Arrest Tracker was
originally founded by Lee
Johnstone, uh, he's also the
founder of Cyber War News if
you've ever follow any of his
stuff, really smart researcher
and so was founded 2013. Uh and
the project aims to track
computer intrusion incidents
resulting in arrest, detaining
of persons, uh, seizure of goods
and all sorts of other things.
Uh, tracking incidents from all
cyber - again if you have
alcohol, drink. I've been trying
to say it as much as I can.
Also, if you notice in the lower
right hand corner it says cyber
on every slide, so, I wanted to
make sure we were gonna get to
where we needed to for later
tonight. Um, and hacking related
incidents. Um, so right now
there's over 1400 incidents
collected and it's more than
just arrests, but we ended up
finding out that there's there,
if you just say you're only
going to track arrests, there's
a lot that goes on, so there's,
it's it's, it's more than that,
we're labeling it cyber-crime.
And now, uh, as of today, the
project is officially launching,
you can go out and sign up and
check things out, etc. So it's
Arrest Tracker dot com. So the,
uh, fields in there, we're
trying to figure out all the
different fields that we're
trying to track and with any
project, if you've ever done
data work, you start out and try
to track a few fields and all of
a sudden you're like what about
these and you keep adding stuff
on, right? Um, but so far we're
trying to figure out things like
the profile, the name, alias,
gender, age, location are they
part of hacker collectives,
operations, all those sorts of
things. In terms of the
incident, when did it occur,
which country, arrested charge,
rated, all that sort of stuff.
And then even then looking at
things like courts. Um, was
there a deal, was there trial,
fines, fine amounts, convicted,
sentenced, all those sorts of
things. And even some more
things about, um, the legal side
and authorities. Alright, so
what can Arrest Tracker help us
with? Well, first we definitely
need to recognize there's some
limitations with the date,
right? So some quick
disclaimers. So if you're a data
scientist or uh a data security
metrics nerd and you want to
come give me grief, I get it.
But we're trying to start
somewhere and grow this so we
can have some data sets to look
at as we improve and get better,
but you have to remember, uh
there are some limitations. We
have to remember that this is
mostly about arrest data, right.
Arrest incidences is what we
have the most of and so it tells
a story from that viewpoint. Uh,
we've expanded, as mentioned to
cover more cyber-crime, we're
going continue to add as much as
we can. We're using data based
on reported, uh, arrests and
raids, right, so we're gathering
everything we can from the
media. So if the reporting's bad
or wrong it's an issue. Right,
we do source everything in there
to try to have our own
attribution to where we got the
information from. And if the
courts are wrong, which when has
that every happened, right. Um,
that's an issue too, but we're
pulling all the data that we can
in and putting it in. So we also
need to remember that in many
cases the government allegedly
would rather track and follow
criminals instead of arresting
them for various reasons. So
again, we're only, we're only
adding in data here that, that
has had some sort of, uh, some
sort of crime prosecution,
arrest, etc. So with that said,
what can Arrest Tracker tell us?
Well, quite a bit actually, um,
so, detailed statistics about
crime arrests, who's behind
these data breaches and crime,
what are the demographics,
what's going on with
extradition, details on census,
monetary fines. Um, learning
about law enforcement and what's
going on certain judges and how
do they view cases. And then
profile a hacker and I'm sure
anything else that you guys can
think of we can ask the data
set. So most people always are
asking us, you know, what is a
hacker, what's the profile a
hacker and you know the media
basically settled in on the ski
mask behind the laptop, right?
We all agree on that. I sort of
thought it might be funny and
interesting if I ask Google
images of what it was and here
it is and what I found here is
as long as you have a hoodie on,
you're a hacker in Google's
mind. But we also have couple
new faces now with Mr. Robot,
right? So now these new faces of
what a hacker is. But what's
even more interesting is these
are the real faces from Arrest
Tracker behind the project,
right? So we're tracking what
what folks look like and all
those sorts of things as well,
so you can see, uh, this helps
us better understand. So looking
at the timeline. Here's, uh, an
eye chart for people way in the
back. Um, shows that there's
been crime and incidents going
back to the 1970s, right? Uh,
there was some you can see that
over the course, but really not
a lot of activity in this space.
Or incidents that we've tracked
until the 2000s. If you drill in
closer on the 2000s, you can see
that things are on the rise
without a doubt, right, we're
seeing a lot more activity in
this space. So the cyber
incidents over the past decades,
the 70s we saw 2, 80s 37, 1990,
uh 59 incidents and the 2000s
345 and the and current decade
998 incidents. So we're seeing
quite a bit that we're adding
in. Now, that being said, there
is a lot of old research, so,
uh, Jericho Vertrition dot org
has on it's to do list. It's
been on it for a while actually,
I've going to have to give them
some grief, to go through some
of these old books and pull out
some more incidents from the 70s
and 80s, so definitely need more
help and more research putting
in some of the older things as
well. So the oldest incident
from the 70s we actually have is
from 1971. And that's just a
screenshot of what the, uh,
Arrest Profile looks like where
we're trying to capture all the
different bits of data. And so
you can see here, Hugh Jefferey
Ward it occurred in '71. He was
29 years old at the time. He was
accused of breaking into the ISD
computer systems and stealing
data. Uh, trade secret theft,
plead guilty. Fined 5000 dollars
and 36 months of probation. So
that's 1971. Now, does anyone
recognize this picture? That's
laughing, but does anyone really
know it? The guy that had the
most friends on the internet for
a while. This is Tom! There we
go. This is MySpace Tom. So
MySpace Tom, um, maybe people
don't know this, he was a
co-founder of MySpace, but the
media back here reported him as
a real life war games hacker in
the 1980s. And so he was also
known as Lord Flathead, aka
Myspace Tom and so this is his
profile in Arrest Tracker. And
so 1985 he had an issue, he was
about 14 or 16 at the time,
there's some conflicting reports
there. But he, uh, hacked,
allegedlyhacked into Chase
Manhattan Bank, told his friends
how to do it, uh, the FBI, uh
raided him in California and
ceased all of, uh, his
computers. And so no charges or
criminal convictions have ever
been made in related to this
incident. He was a minor at this
time. So again that's one of
those reasons, why we expanded
out the project just saying
these arrests into tracking a
bit more stuff. So 1980s,
MySpace Tom. And what's
interesting about this, as we've
been collecting each of these
incidents about the people and
what's going on. Each incident
in Arrest Tracker has this story
to be told, right? And so, from
the 90s, you know we pulled out
some folks, the Mitnick story's
been told many times, even last
night, you know we had the movie
night of the 2600 stuff. But
there's many other people in
here that each have their own
story to be told. Here's from
the 2000s. Some notables that
you may recognize or not. Um,
but some of these folks that you
may not know what they were up
to and they have their own
story. And then and here some
more recent incidents and then
some of them have some really
bad and sad consequences of our
legal system as well. So there's
lots of other notable arrests
out there for various reasons.
Things like the first
prosecution of a particular
crime, the severity of a crime,
the length of a jail crime, or
what the fines were, potential
overreaching of regulatory
actions, impact to those
accused, etc. Alright, some
specifics on arrests. So we get
asked just absolutely all the
time, anytime we mention Arrest
Tracker, it's the profile of a
hacker. That's the biggest
question that comes up. So we
knew that once we had a fair
amount of data, we need to start
looking at demographic of
things. And so we started with
age. And so the youngest age
that we have is 12 years old.
Believe it or not. Traded
pirated information to the
activist group anonymous for
video games. Um, so. Sentenced
to 18 months. Includes limited
access to internet devices, 30
hours of community service. And
under supervision for 6 months,
uh, the boy must also, had to
choose some sort of structured
activity of his choosing. And
this was in 2013 in in Canada.
So 12 years old was the
youngest. And the oldest though,
was 66 years old. Um, Uh John
McHugh, a guy named Devil Man as
well. Male, busted for selling
cards on the dark web. Uh, this
was in the United Kingdom and he
was jailed for two years. So you
can see this one. And so what
that led us to look at is we
knew we had the youngest at 12
and the oldest at 66, but what's
sort of the breakdown and the
distribution of ages, right?
Most people when you say whose
hacking, whose doing all this
stuff, it's some bored high
schooler or, uh, ya know, or
some college university student
on spring break. Um, but what we
saw from the distributions is
you can see 18 through 25, 349
incidents and 26 through 35, 304
incidents. So were the largest
groups while there were still
other age groups. And that
currently leads us to an average
age of 27 years old. And then we
want to look at that 27 year
olds across all the years to
see, ya know, was it, how was it
year over year and it was, it
was pretty spot on, year over
year in that range. Alright,
gender equality. There's been a
lot talked about this all over
the place and so we though, hey,
we should look at the same thing
to see, ya know, what's the
breakdown in genders. Uh, uh,
for crime and arrests and yeah,
it's all guys. [laughter] So we
still have a little more
research to do here, um, but in
general it was 81 plus percent
were male. Um, and so we're
going to do a little bit more
work in this space, but again,
just trying to get those profile
demographics. So which countries
do most hackers reside in or
what's in our world, what's the
country of origin for the
arrests? Um, we get asked this
all the time as well and
everyone really thinks it's just
gonna be this, ya know, it's
gonna be China, right, this is
what it looks like with just
Chinese hackers everywhere. Um,
but again, if you think about
what we're doing with the arrest
data it's based on arrest data,
right? And so obviously for us,
United States is number one,
right? You can see there. Note
that China's number ten in this.
So there are arrests and there
are crime, uh, things going on,
but because of the data and the
lens that we're looking through,
number one is the United States
and number two is the United
Kingdom. Now collectives, we
wanted to get our heads wrapped
around, do most folks that get
in trouble, um, in a cyber-crime
area, are they sort of solo,
like lone wolf hackers on their
own. Or are they part of some
sort of collective? And also, if
one person gets arrested, does
that lead, does that mean that
like a bunch of others are gonna
follow? And so Arrest Tracker,
there's 58 known collectives
that have had some sort of
confirmed incident. And we see
that anonymous is at the top
with 130. So anytime that we'll
find out about an issue, if it's
related to back to a collective
then we go ahead and add it in.
Same thing with hacker
operations, we want to start
trying to get a better feel,
when you talk about these hacker
operations and what they're
going after, ya know, how many
are they and and what do they
lead to in terms of arrests or
or any crime sort of
prosecution, right now we know
about 21 hacker ops. Um, with
operation payback at the top.
And for some of you old school
folks in there, you'll laugh at
a couple other ones that are
listed up there as well.
Alright, so is an arrest
inevitable? Are you definitely
going to get arrested? So if you
look at it in terms of the data
breaches, right, so in 2016 year
to date we already said there is
approximately 2000 data
breaches, year to date. We've
seen 70 confirmed arrests so far
and 2015 there were
approximately 4000 data breaches
and we saw 134 confirmed
arrests. Going back to 2014 sort
of the same message, right,
approximately 3000 data
breaches, about 47 arrested. So
nowhere are we seeing, um, ya
know the, in terms of a data
breach equaling arrests, right?
Um, and what's interesting is
the data so far shows that
there's 610 days on average from
when a crime happens, if you
will, until the incident, or the
arrest. So there's definitely a
tail from when something occurs
to when there's some sort of
prosecution or raid or whatever
and we're going to continue to
add data and stats in that
regard. Alright, so we then we
started to wonder, maybe silly
things, but when would you most
likely to be raided or arrested?
Which would it be? Anyone have a
guess? [audience responses] I
think I heard it over here.
Hello, Monday! Right. So someone
maybe had a bad case of the
Mondays, could be really bad,
right? Um, we originally guessed
when we thought about it, we
thought it's be on a Friday, but
it looks like looking at the
data, you get to enjoy your
weekend and then on Monday it's
gonna be a real bad day for you
potentially. And then we started
asking other questions like what
part of the year, what month
would it be, right? And Arrest
Tracker could tell us that same
thing. No one ever gets this one
right, so I won't even ask you
guys, but April seems to be when
more showers can come into the
hacker community as well. So now
countries pursuing cyber-crime.
As you can easily guess, USA's
the most active number one,
right. But the top ten's
somewhat surprising in some
cases and and China, no, that
they're not, they're not in the
top ten of pursuing cyber-crime,
ok? Umm, we started to look at
things like extradition,
extradition And we're currently
seeing that only the USA has
any, uh, extraditions that are
tracked and there's 42 of them
that we're aware of and so you
can see the top five countries.
Russia to the United States had
8, uh, Romania to the US 7.
Estonia to the US 6. Canada to
the US at, uh 3 and the United
Kingdom 3 as well. Not every
country allows the USA to
extradite folks, but there are
treaties in place with more than
100, 100 countries out there.
Here's a quick little map of it,
you can see in the darker
purplish, uh color, that's the
USA and all the blue ones are
places that we allegedly,
according to Wikipedia, have,
uh, extradition treaties. So now
we looked at jail time. The
longest jail time that we had,
the worst case, we thought what
would that be and what we found
was it was actually crazy. 334
years. So, uh, a guy in Turkey
he created fake websites and
impersonated banks and I think
the lesson that Arrest Tracker
all of you right now is don't
mess around in Turkey, because
it's bad news there in terms of
jail time. Right. We started
look at fines and we want to
understand things, what's the
average fine, what's the most
common, uh, the largest fine,
etc and what we found is the
average fine that we know of
right now is a million US
dollars, but the most common
fine that we, that occurred 13
times, uh within the database,
was 5600 dollars. The largest
fine was, uh, the world pay
hacker Victor, 8 point 9 million
US dollars and he was convicted
and tried in a Russian court
under FBI charges. The other
thing too that goes on is
there's some people that just
can't help themself, they just
can't stop. Um, so many times
you know, there'll be cases,
multiple cases, that are
consolidated into one case so
this can be a little bit hard to
figure out sometimes, but we've
been able to find Arrest
Tracker, uh, 17 people have had
multiple arrests. And we're
asked all the time, this is
another question we get asked
all the time, is how many people
when they get busted are
assisting authorities. And so we
do have the fields in Arrest
Tracker to track this, however,
it is pretty rare and it's hard
to find this data, but when
looking through the database
right now, there are 30 people
that have confirmed, uh, to
have, uh, assisted the
authorities in some fashion.
Alright, so getting down to this
what is a profile of hacker? So
the data suggests that really
there's no single hacker or
cyber-criminal type, right, that
sort of a bit all over the
place, but if, uh, we were
forced to say what the profile
of a hacker is based on averages
and things that we can find, uh,
genders gonna be a male, age
range is gonna be 18-35 or in
that average 27 age range.
Again, gonna be in the USA, a
lot of that is because again the
arrest data that we source, but
if not USA, it's gonna be UK or
Phillippines. Uh, the crime will
be hacking. If it's not hacking,
then after that, it'd be some
sort of cyber fraud or data
theft that we classify. And most
likely active since year 2000.
Motivation right now, still
having problems tracking that in
a relevant way, so we're still
trying to figure what we can do
in Arrest Tracker to make that a
bit more clear. Alright, most
wanted. Who hasn't been arrested
yet? Well, I'm not sure if
everyone knows this or not, but
the FBI at their website
maintains a listing of wanted
cyber folks. You can go out
there and check it out. There
are 28 total listed as of just
this this week. Uh, they have a
profile basically on everyone
that's listed up there, so
they'll have your, ya know, your
picture and a wanted poster and
an alias and whole bunch of
other information, ya know
weight, eye color, all that sort
of stuff and then details on the
rewards that they'll offer if
you can help bring them down.
Some other remarks. Um, and
there's this other section
that's called "caution" that
I'll put a lot more details on
what they're up to and even
mention things like if they're
considered a flight risk and all
those sorts of stuff. And in
this particular case, uh, offer
a reward up to 3 million dollars
for information leading to the
arrest or conviction of this
particular guy. So you can see
here, here's a listing from all
the images from the website. Um,
the profile looks a little
different than the arrest data
that we've been talking about,
right? Um and what's
interesting, if you had to guess
the total amount of reward money
all added up, uh, it's about 4
point 49 million dollars in
potential rewards if all these
people were, someone informed
them to the FBI. What we're also
starting to see too is that, um,
when hackers or doxed or when
information becomes aware, are
they definitely going to get
arrested? And so what we saw in
March of 2016 is GhostShell,
many of you know. Uh, doxed
himself, he revealed himself, uh
and he described that he's been
active since January 2012. That
he was one of the ones that
started OpRomania. He's attacked
the government, all those sorts
of things. So this is, you know,
March 2016, but then here he's
leaking 39 million accounts in
protest and that was in June,
right, so. All the information
about him, he came out and
basically said everything. Who
he was, etc, but he's still
active. And so it's clear that
for us, we still want to make
sure we understand a bit more
about law enforcement specific
about cases. Are there certain
characteristics of data breaches
or cyber-crime that leads to
more law influence. Um, those
sorts of things. So we're trying
to track more on that, so we can
get a better answer. Alright, so
as we're wrapping up here now.
So what's next for us? Well the
actions are clear for us, is
data quality is top of our mind.
We want to make sure that we
continue to have the best data,
that we can have everything that
we need to so these, we can
answer these questions as as
best as we can, but at the same
time answer all the questions
that people have for us. So if
you find something wrong and you
log into the project, please
tell us. Right, there's no pride
in authorship, we want wanna we
wanna fix things up. We care
about the data, we want it to be
accurate. And we want more data.
We want to increase coverage of
cyber-crime events. We want more
data fields per incident by
person. All those sorts of
things. So if you're interested
in helping out, please do. For
future ideas and features that
we're looking at. We're trying
to add more data, uh, field
about individual persons. So the
ability to handle complex
issues. Things you wouldn't
necessarily think like, uh, a
Romanian national that lived in
Canada for 15 years, but then
was arrested in the United
States, right? We want to be
able to try to track some of
those things. When we ask, we
get asked about location and
profile, we can explain it a bit
more. A lot of, a lot of
thoughts been going in the
ability to track motivation. And
then mapping to known data
breaches so we can understand
impacts and all those sorts of
things. Ya know, are there
certain types of hacker profiles
that go on after certain types
of industries, etc. More work on
the most wanted. Uh, some
thoughts we've had about are, ya
know, are how long are they on
the most wanted before they get
arrested. Um, things like that.
Now how many people that have
been arrested were for security
companies, right? Um and then
even a subsection for piracy and
all those sorts of things. So
what comes next? Are we gonna
see arrests in cyber-crime
prosecution increase or
decrease? We think the answer is
gonna be increasing. Um, we're
trying to figure out what the
legal environments gonna look
like and if that's gonna get
more harsh. Um and then can we
take this data from Arrest
Tracker and actually apply it to
your work, right. Can you use
this to help you, not just, ya
know, laugh about yeah it's
Monday and April and those sorts
of things, but if you're in the
legal space, can you look at how
things are happening. Are there
overreaching regulations in your
day to day job. Can this help
you figure out how to be
offensive, etc. So we're open
for new ideas. If you're
interested in working with us,
we'd love it. If you've got
other ideas, we're open to that
feedback. And if you want to
help, definitely please contact
us. So I want to thank, uh, Lee
Johnstone for all his hard work
founding the Arrest Tracker
project. It's a ton of data,
it's a ton of work. I wanna
thank Brian Martin for all his
help. Um, I want to thank
everyone else that's been
interested and hung out here and
been drinking with us for this
session. And thanks to the
DefCon CFB team for, uh, for the
opportunity to present. So
believe it or not, this was 140
slides and cyber was pretty much
on every single one of them. So
I hope you guys had fun playing
along. Look forward to seeing
you tonight. If you have
questions, I'll be up here.
Thank you. [applause]