>>Alright let's go twelve o
clock. This is Beyond the MCSE
Red Teaming Active Directory I
am Sean Metcalf otherwise you're
in the wrong room but since it's
single track today I think
you're in the right room
[cheering] I am the founder
Trimarc a security company a
microsoft certified master in
active directory one of about a
hundred in the world. And a
Microsoft MVP. I've spoken at
Blackhat last year and this year
and Defcon last year and this
year and I'm very excited to
talk to you about some AD
Security stuff. I'm a security
consultant and researcher and I
own and operate ADSecurity dot
org which hopefully you're all
aware of. So we're going to talk
about some key AD Components
from a security perspective
things I think the security
professional should know about.
Some offensive PowerShell stuff
basically how you can bypass
some of the new PowerShell
version 5 security features.
Effective AD recon and then some
of the defenses you'll run into
as a red teamer and how to
bypass them. And then we'll wrap
up with a checklist. So for the
red teamers in the room, this is
what hacking looks like, right?
Get full access. [laughter]
Score! love hackers right? Or
maybe you've done this, of
course you've you've repelled
from the top of the warehouse
over the server and you have
extracted the information,
right? And of course everyone
has done the Tom Cruise move
when hacking a system [laughter]
you're hanging over the computer
and typing stuff in.. ehh close
to it right? More looks more
like this like PowerShell
empire, Mimkatz. Oh so close. Um
but there's differing views of
active directory. The
administrator the security
professional and the attacker
have different perspectives of
what active directory looks
like. None of them have the
complete picture of what it is.
The active directory
administrator and engineer their
perspective of active directory
is through their tools. AD user
computers, domains and trusts
through policy sights and
services and PowerShell and the
security professional's view of
of active directory is through
their sim tool the vulnerability
scanner the events the event log
the attacker's perspective is
much different. They're getting
a lot of information about
what's going on in the
environment. When you red team
an active directory you do recon
grab some credentials go from
there go from there grab some
credentials and then DA pop the
champagne right? Okay that's
interesting. Wow thanks lady. So
note to future speakers when you
send your slides to someone and
they send them back to you make
sure you check them before you
go to Defcon. Thank you Lee
Holmes [applause] alright, let's
get [laughter] okay let's talk
about active directory security
again, I'm going to try to
recover from that so an active
directory forest is like the UFP
from Star Trek you've got the
united federation of planets
you've got a lot of starships
they're all one part of one
happy family right? And in this
analogy every starship is a
domain joined to the UFP forest.
The executive officers on the
ship are the domain admins for
their ship. Domain. And if a
ship's executive officer domain
admin is compromised then so is
the ship. In the instance of the
USS Reliant. Khan was able to
compromise one of the executive
officers and own that ship and
all the systems on it. And then
since two ships come together
they're all part of one happy
federation and one forest.
They're all implicitly trusted
which can lead to some really
interesting scenarios where one
officer on one ship can control
systems on another like shields.
So Khan was a bit dismayed that
admins in one domain can control
domain resources in another and
effectively become a domain
admin on that other domain. So
if you're a blue team member
don't be like Khan [laughter].
If you're a red team member
that's awesome because that
means that in a multi domain
forest environment you
compromise one domain you
compromise the entire forest. So
let's talk about domain
controller for a moment. We know
that you take a member server
you run Dcpromo it promos up to
domain controller right? You
have, there's a template
NTDS.dit active directory
database file on every member
server that is used to see that
initial database. And that
domain controllers being
promoted will pull the domain
data from other domain
controllers in that domain to
then fill that active directory
database with the domain
information such as usernames
passwords computers have
passwords their passwords in
there also trusts have passwords
it's in there also. And so the
users connect to these domain
controllers for authentication
and directory services as do
applications. So these are the
critical servers in active
directory they host the global
catalogue. The global catalogue
can be thought of as a partition
that goes across and crosses all
the domains in the active
directory forest where it has
information about every object
in the act directory forest but
a subset of the attributes. This
means if you're doing some recon
and you want to know about all
the users in the whole AD forest
you just connect to the GC Port
on the domain controller and
query that instead of connecting
to every domain controller. So
if DNS is used on a domain
controller and the domain
controller hosts it often times
when you have AD integrated uh
DNS this means the DNS
information is stored in active
directory and replicated through
active directory. So then we
have Read-Only Domain
Controllers which is this really
weird animal that Microsoft came
up with in 2008. So it's read
only DC services, read only DNS,
read only SYSVOL, this means
that when you run into a read
only domain controller in an
environment it cannot replicate
or send modifications to active
directory to domain controllers
it's not allowed to. And it has
it's own curve TDT account which
means the cerberus is
cryptographically isolated from
the rest of the domain. And the
read only domain controller does
not have any passwords on it
relating to that domain by
default. You have to actually
add them to a group so that
their passwords can be cached
there. So when a user logs onto
a sight that has a read only
domain controller their password
isn't on that read only. So the
read only sends their
authentication request to a
writeable and then the writeable
services that authentication
request at which point the read
only says well give me the
password for this user and the
writeable will check to see if
that's allowed or disallowed
based on group membership and
then either send the password
down to the read only or not.
This means that there are
certain passwords that will be
on read onlys read onlys are not
trusted at the same level as
regular domain controllers. So
what this means is that if you
find an administrator of a read
only uh read only domain
controller which you can find by
looking at the manage of
attribute for that read only you
can compromise that and then you
can compromise the passwords of
the accounts that are stored on
the read only. There's two
really interesting attributes
with read onlys, authenticated
to account list these are all of
the accounts that have
authenticated to the read only
domain controller. Doesn't mean
their passwords on it. That's
the reveal list. So if you run
into an environment with read
only domain controllers
enumerate the membership or the
values that are in the reveal
list attribute for the read
onlys. And then you'll know all
the passwords that are on there.
Technically the environment and
the administrators are supposed
to add admins to the denied RODC
replication group they don't
often do that. An admin groups
account can end up on read
onlys. So how do clients
discover DNS or I'm sorry domain
controllers? Well DNS, we run
DNS query we get the SRV records
for domain controllers. Or we
can use ADSI if we have
PowerShell which is highly
recommended. But how do clients
do this? Well we have networks
subnets in the real world right?
That's how stuff talks to each
other. We take those network
subnets and you put them in
active directory and you
associate them with sites. And
this maps AD to the physical
world. This enables the client
in one location to communicate
with the domain controller in
that same location or at least
nearby as well as resources like
DFS shares. The interesting
thing is that if a client asks a
domain controller what site I'm
in and the domain controller
can't map that client's IP
address to a subnet DC goes I
have no idea. Try again. That
client goes hey domain
controller what site am I in? It
says I don't know try again. And
it happens several times and
finally the client gives up and
just picks a domain controller.
So this is interesting because
that means logs may actually be
on a totally different domain
controller for that activity for
that computer than what the IR
team or what the blue team is
looking for. If they haven't
configured size correctly. So
group policy is a way to manage
user and group sorry user and
computer policy and security
settings. You create a group
policy you configure the
settings on it you link it to an
OU or domain and you have the
group policy object which is in
AD the computer boots up it
identifies what OU it's in what
group policies are applied
There's a link in that group
policy object in SYSVOL to say
these are where those files are
those group policy files in
settings that need to be applied
so it copies down those files
and applies them. The
interesting thing here and it
works the same for users the
interesting thing here is if you
can insert yourself between that
domain controller SYSVOL share
and that client and get the
client to connect to your SYSVOL
share you can actually have that
client run your own version of
that group policy. Also if you
can modify the group policy
object in active directory or
those setting files in SYSVOL
then you can have that uh
computer apply this policy
settings. Well group policy has
a lot of capabilities this could
be adding local administrators
adding update service so you can
add or update services deploy
and schedule tasks and so on
software etcetera. So let's talk
about some of the more fun
stuff. PowerShell, everyone uses
PowerShell know as an attack
tool it's awesome. Run code
memory without touching disc,
download and execute code from
another system. Interface with
dot net and the window APIs
there's been nothing like it on
the Windows platform before. And
about six years ago at Defcon18
Dave Kennedy and Josh Kelly
talked about PowerShell OMFG I
mean it was amazing and they
talked about a lot of the great
features that PowerShell has for
attackers and for red teamers
and guess what Ransomware I
think the Ransomware authors
have just viewed that because
they're starting to use these
techniques and in 2012 just a
couple years later Matt Graeber
released PowerSploit which is
effectively the foundational
PowerShell attack tool framework
that just about all of the
PowerShell attack tools
leveredge which includes
Invoke-Mimkatz. PowerShell
version 5 great for blue teamers
red teamers you have to tiptoe a
little more carefully once
PowerSHell version 5 security's
enables because what this means
is if they have script block
logging enabled. Even if you've
obfuscated your PowerSHell code
before it's executed by the
PowerShell engine Whatever that
final code is that's been
deobfuscated it gets logged to
the event log in 4104 and if
they've enabled system wide
transcript files this is really
interesting because they'll have
set up a right one share on the
network where everything you
type into PowerShell on the
computer that has version five
with this enables that
transcript file will be sent
strained effectively to that
network share. So it's per
computer per user which means
they'll have an over the
shoulder transcript of
everything that was typed
including any typos which is
always interesting. Constrained
language mode is a conversion of
PowerShell or a language mode
for PowerShell which locks
PowerShell down to the base
elements. So no dot net no API
calls Invoke-Mimkatz will not
work in constrained language
mode. If a environment has
PowerShell version five an app
blocker in allow mode PowerShell
locks down in constrained
language mode automatically. And
in Windows 10 it gets even more
interesting because WIndows 10
introduces the AMSI the anti
malware scan interface where any
PowerShell code or VB script
code before it's executed by the
PowerShell engine it's kicked
over to the AMSI which sends it
over to the antimalware
solution. And the antimalware
solution will give a thumbs up
or a thumbs down if its a thumbs
down Powershell will not execute
that code be it downloaded from
the internet and run in memory
or run from a script Now there's
only a couple of vendors that
support AMSI so red teamers
you're still in good shape
Microsoft supports it and AVG I
don't know why, we're still
waiting on Mcafee and Symantec
to catch up I guess. But there's
also ways to bypass AMSI if
you're using an an executable
that's calling PowerShell code
and you drop your custom AMSI
dot DLL file in that same
location you can effectively
hijack the AMSI calls and just
say no no no this codes okay
don't worry about it or Matt
Graeber PowerSploit author he
figured out how to fit into a
tweet the powershell command
that bypasses AMSI [laughter]
pretty awesome Microsoft is
working on it I mean this is a
year later. Not the tweet the
tweets only a couple months old
the anniversary update for
Windows 10 is out so maybe
that'll fix it. So Lee
Christensen released unmanaged
PowerShell not that long ago
it's been rolled into Metasploit
and basically this allows you to
call a lot of PowerShell
commands and run PowerShell code
without calling PowerShell dot
AXE among other things and one
of my favorite Powershell attack
tools PS Attack is a single
executable which contains some
of the popular and best
PowerShell attack tools that are
out there. It encrypts them into
the executable and there's a
bill tool so you can custom
encrypt your own. And when it
runs it decrypts these files or
these PowerShell functions in
the memory where you can run
them and guess what? Constrained
language mode is no longer a
problem because when you run
PowerShell code from an
executable it bypasses the
standard mechanism that that
handles constrained and language
mode because Microsoft wanted to
makes sure it was compatible for
all the applications that may be
calling PowerShell what about
PowerShell Version 5 Login? It
bypasses that also. Why does
this happen? Well in Windows 7
you have PowerShell version 2 as
your base level Powershell
version and then when you
install PowerShell level 5 or
version 5 it kind of layers on
top of that so PS attack through
unmanaged PowerShell and some
other fun trickery actually
calls the system dot management
dot automation dot DLL that is
PowerShell at that lower level
version which is version 2 which
enables it to bypass and make
sure that those that all of that
ah information the script code
and the result are not logged.
Now smarter organizations will
remove PowerShell version two
from Windows 10 which you can
uncheck the box and when that
happens this log just flows with
data when you run PS attack. So
let's talk about some fun
effective active directory recon
ideally getting more information
about the environment than the
AD admins so I'm going to talk a
lot about PowerView written by
my friend Will Harmjoy so
PowerView has a lot of great
tools in order to get
information about active
directory and i'm going to call
a bunch of them out so that way
hopefully you can start adding
this to your tool kit. At the
top of the graphics is the
PowerView command I'm also
comparing that with the active
directory PowerShell module
which is available on the
Windows servers and the
computers uh the work stations
if it's installed and configured
so that way you can do some
comparison. But we get
information about the act
directory forest we can get the
name of the forest the sites
that are in the forest so that
we can map out what's in that
environment in fact a really
effective way to get information
about an active directory
environment or enterprise is to
pull the site information and
the submit information and you
can effectively map out the
entire network just with active
directory. You can get
information about the domains
that are stored in that forest
the global catalogues Microsoft
recommends that every domain
controller is a global catalogue
so this means that with one
command you've hit a list of
pretty much all the domain
controllers in the organization.
Application partition so this
will show you for example in the
graphic right here you can see
that there's DNS that's
integrated in an active
directory because they're an
application partitions. The
forest mode here it says
2008-R2-forest that tells me
what security enhancements are
not available to those admins in
this active directory
environment and then of course
we see what the uh schema and
the domain naming FSMO are. We
look at the domain information
what forest is it in all of the
domain controllers any child
domains the domain mode again
telling us what kind of security
is is available. The PDC
emulator so if you're a red
teamer and you want to know what
domain controller to connect to
when you do all your activity
you might want to target the PDC
emulator why is that? It is the
busiest domain controller on the
network it is also the mo- the
best connected by Microsoft
recommendations you could also
target one that's alway- you
know gotta branch off somewhere
but the logs on the PDC are
going to be super busy and it's
also typically a best practice
to co host all of the FSMO on
the same domain controller so
it's going to be extra busy. So
we have forests we have domains
we've talked about Star Trek and
how awesome it is but let's talk
about trusts for a minute. If an
organization has trust to other
business de- business units in
their environment they may have
actually and accidentally
compromised their environment
because a lot of times they
create another domain or another
forest because of trust issues
right? They're like I don't
really trust that business unit
RND they kind of do their own
thing they're kinda cowboys
cowgirls we'll let them do their
thing but then they create a
trust and say we trust everyone
in that domain and then they'll
do a two way trust and Will
Harmjoy has covered a lot of
good information about
exploiting across trusts. So
when you dig for joy in active
directory you're looking for
default and weak passwords
right? I've found passwords
stored in user attributes so
check the description fields for
accounts check for the extension
attributes those custom
attributes. Sensitive data can
be stored in active directory
because the administrator
doesn't realize all of these
attributes or at least most of
them are available for
authenticated users to read
there is an attribute called a
confidential attribute which by
default only domain admins can
view that's where sensitive
stuff should be stored that's
where bitlocker keys are stored
by default that's where the LAPS
passwords are stored by default.
Deleted Objects so when an
active directory admin deletes
an object in active directory is
it gone? No no let me hear no no
there you go exactly you know
right? It's not deleted its
marked is deleted its hidden but
the data is still there and so
sometimes admins will create an
account for I don't know a CEO
and put some information in
there like a home phone number
like Oh I shouldn't have done
that delete, guess what it's
still on active directory you
can search for objects that have
the is deleted flag and pull
that and look at it and you
might find some very interesting
information. So I'm going to
refer to Will Harmjoy on most of
the user and admin hunting
activities because he covers it
far better than I do and he has
a lot of sessions on it but
effectively using invoke user
hunter as part of PowerView to
go through and identify user
home directory servers and
shares profile path servers and
shares logon script paths run
Get Net session against each of
them and get information about
where they're logged on and then
you can start mapping out who is
where and uh what rights they
have. But even better than that
go to the Veris Group session on
Saturday at one o clock on
Bloodhound which they announced
at B-Sides Las Vegas just a
couple days ago. Bloodhound
enables you to use PowerView to
eng- to query and get
information put it ah get
information about the active
directory environment put it
into a graph database and graph
out all of the connection points
between users and groups and
computers and very quickly and
easily identify that this user
can go to this crew can have
access have admin access to this
computer has admin access to
this computer where this domain
admins logged on to and now I
have domain admin access. So the
initial gathering information
takes a little while but that
graphing is very quick so I
highly recommend you check that
out it's called Bloodhound. So
there's some interesting user
properties on the user objects
last log on day password last
set admin count is a really
interesting one because if admin
count is set to one it's very
likely that user account is a
member of domain admins or
another privileged group because
there's a process that actually
runs every sixty minutes to
protect privileged groups in
active directory and it stamps
them with admin count equals one
it doesn't go back later and
remove it so you could have some
false positives here but it can
provide some really interesting
information. SID history is
another interesting one. SID
history attribute can contain a
SID from another user And
provide the same level access as
that user it's effectively
permission cloning so if you
find user accounts with SID
history and that SID history is
for another user that has some
really interesting capabilities
and rights you could probably
clone that or use that um
account. Custom attributes
contain some interesting
information a lot of times
organizations code or categorize
users using custom attributes
and if there's data in the
service principal name that
means that this user account is
a service account is a
Kerberoast service account Same
thing for computer objects ah
let me just call out that these
attribute names are specific to
the active directory PowerShell
module ah command lense so they
may not translate exactly. Last
log on date so this was
effectively when that computer
was last rebooted so what you
can do is you can get a list of
all the computers find out when
they last rebooted look at
password last set to see if
they're still active on the
network if a computer hasn't
updated their password last set
attribute in say sixty days
because by default they should
all the Windows computers should
update in around thirty then if
they haven't updated in that
time that computer may not be on
the network but they if they
have updated within that time
frame and the last log on date
is six months or eight months
that system hasn't been patched
in a long time so that may be
something you want to look more
closely at. And Windows
computers by default register
their operating system and
information related information
in active directory but so does
linux so does Mac so do some
storage devices like Netapp and
EMC so you can find information
about what's in active directory
just by asking active directory
for it. Service principal name
you can get the information
about the Kerberoast enterprise
services on these computers and
then the last two are related to
Kerberoast delegation and I
spoken about how to leverage
Kerberoast unconstrained
delegation to compromise a
domain last year at Blackhat.
Did you know that you can do DNS
lookups via LDAP? It's pretty
cool right? I don't have to ask
DNS where it's probably logged
and there's some information
about what people are querying
for I can just look at active
directory and say okay give me a
list of these computers all of
the domain controllers and all
their IP addresses and denell
that call sure here you go. Or I
can get I can do a reverse
lookups what's the site what's
this computer related to this IP
address. Even if there's not a
pointer records configured in
DNS because this is all through
active directory. So in the old
days we had to actually do port
scanning to find enterprise
services nowadays we can use
something that I call SPN
scanning which is much more
efficient because Kerberoast
services have to have a service
principal name associated in
active directory and registered
in active directory so there's a
number of SPN types like
MSSQLSvc, TERMSER, WSMAN,
FIMService, exchangeMDB we can
search for these we can ask
active directory for this
information and it will give it
to us. So we can find all the
SQL servers very easily and the
format has the SPN type server
name and sequel often has a port
number or an instance at the end
so we can get this information
by just asking the active
directory and the main
controller and we can get a list
of all of the servers their port
number the service accounts
associated with them and some
additional information we can
also request all of the user
accounts that have service
principal names associated with
them which are service accounts.
And we can leverage a tool
called Kerberoast that takes
advantage of how Kerberoast
works where we can request a
service ticket for a specific
service principal name or
service principal names and then
the domain controller is going
to look at that user account
associate it with that SPN and
it's going to encrypt that using
that password hash for that user
account. And then send it back
to us and if we've request RC4
encryption guess what? That
password hash is the NT LAN
password hash so we can take
that service ticket encrypt it
with RC4 encrypt it with that
service account and NT LAN
password hash take it offline to
our attacker machine and we can
run Kerberoast against it which
takes a dictionary list goes
through each of those words does
a one way hash function then
gets the NT LAN password hash
and then attempts to decrypt
that service ticket using that.
And if it's right if it can open
it then it's guessed the
password for that service
account offline without any
admin access without it ever
touching the target or
communicating with the target.
So the old school way for group
enumeration finding your domain
admins is what? Right group name
domain admin we have two luke
skywalker ADS administrator we
can also enumerate the
membership of the RODC groups
denied RODC password replication
group because enterprises should
be configuring this so that way
these admins are not storing
their passwords on RODCs
especially if they have RODCs in
the environment. But remember
when I mentioned admin count
equals one gets stamped for
privileged groups in the count
well there's four here krbtgt is
one of those special groups so
we'll put that to the side but
there were two members of domain
admins ADS Administrator and
Luke Skywalker when we look for
admin count equals one we have
another one, Kylo Ren where did
he come from? He's a member of
the administrator's group in the
domain so by looking for admin
count equals one we can get a
lot of information about
potentially privileged accounts
remember there could be some
false positives without any
group enumeration and then one
of my favorite components of
PowerView is the ability to
identify what active directory
groups have local administrator
rights in the environment
because when you have a large
environment it's very difficult
to manage all of these work
stations so what what are you
going to do? You're going to
create a group policy say that
your workstation admins group
back directory it should be a
member of local administrators
for all of my work stations so
we're going to take that group
policy configure it and apply it
to the OU that has all of the
work stations. Well PowerView
can pull that information out
and identify which AD admin
groups or AD groups have admin
access to which computers and we
can do that by targeting a
specific OU and then we can get
a list of what group policies
apply and here is the work
stations admin group, And then
the second command that we run
will give us a list of all of
the computers in that OU and
then of course all we need to do
is enumerate the membership
workstation admins and then we
know who to target. So the I
tried to work in the uh Defcon
theme this year attack of the
machines so computers with admin
rights. Why are people putting
computer accounts in admin
groups I don't know I keep
finding it what does this mean
if you find computer accounts
they have a dollar sign at the
end in an admin group all you
have to do is compromise that
computer account and get system
on it and that point that system
account has those admin rights
and active directory so in this
case they added a regular
computer to workstation admins
we can discover regular users
with admin rights so users
typically have an email address
especially if you're running
exchange in the organization or
they have a specific naming
format like first name dot last
name we can look for admin
accounts or user account and
admin groups this way. Now
exchange admins often will have
an email address associated with
them so you have to filter some
of those out but it's a nice way
to find regular user accounts
that have more rights than they
should. We can also look for
virtual admins hyper-V admins
VMWare Admins that are often
groups in active directory that
have full admin access to the
virtualization platform.
Compromise those accounts you
own the infrastructure. BUt we
can also follow the delegation
and act directory what
delegation has been configured
on the OUs in the domain these
are permissions that have been
configured directly on the OUs
and here we can see that someone
has delegated to the account's
OU help desk level 2 and help
desk level 3 but they made a
mistake both of those tiered
levels have full rights on all
objects an obvious mistake
except for the fact that ACLs
are very difficult to parse
through and look at and identify
so this means level 3 has far
more rights than they should
because they probably should
just have reset password access.
So we enumerate that group we
see C3PO is the user account
that's a member of that group so
we target his account we tell
him we speak Bocce and we're in
good shape right? We can also
use the PowerSploy tool to get
GPP password to identify
credentials in SYSVOL. It scans
the SYSVOL ah share in the
demand controller it identifies
xml files that have a c password
attribute and that gobbledygook
that you see is that encrypted
password strain which we can
decrypt because Microsoft
published the decryption key.
Thank you. [laughter] When an
organization has exchange we can
also get information about who
they commonly email. In outlook
you have your contacts people
should be putting their most
commonly emailed people in the
contacts fields in the contacts
component but we can add
contacts to active directories
so they show up in the gow but
there are objects in active
directory now which means we can
get a list of all the contacts
in the in the organization which
is moderately interesting much
more interesting than me is
actually parsing through that
and identifying what domains
they associate with and what
they email with. And as we can
see here it's empire, rebel
alliance, rebel fleet, star
killer, the alliance first
order, I think they're playing
both sides it's really
interesting [laughter] we can
also get information about the
domain password policies again
at the top using Powerview which
also gives us the Kerberoast
policy the bottom using the
active directory PowerShell
module and this is the default
password policy so if you see
that the min password length is
seven in an organization write
it up and say please don't do
that. If you need to do
something like that use
fine-grained password policies
which of course we can pull as a
domain user and often times the
best way to manage passwords for
administrators and service
accounts is to create a
fine-grained password policy
that says that they have to have
longer passwords than the rest
of the domain. So we can also
discover all the group policies
in the organization that
authenticated users have read
access which is all of them by
default and so we took a look at
them we can see alright there's
a domain Powershell login policy
a full auditing policy, prevent
local account logon that's
interesting. Add server admins
to local administrator groups,
add works, okay. EMET config,
applocker config, and LAPS,
that's interesting. So we can
actually pull the Applocker
whitelisting policy from active
directory now I cheated it's in
binary format I just converted
it to text and parsed it but I
got enough information here that
tells me that they're running
Applocker in the default
configuration settings so now I
know where I can drop
executables and run them from.
These policies should be locked
down so authenticated users
don't have read access. EMET
configuration now I know how
they're protecting their files
their executables. Again I
cheated it's a binary file in
SYSVOL but i converted it to
text but I can get amount of
information from there. And
there's a LAPS policy but it's
not that interesting because
it's just going to say how long
that password is and how often
they change it. More interesting
is using PowerView to pull the
permissions for who has rights
to the LAPS password attribute
where that clear text password
is stored which is MSMCSADMPODB
and with this information we can
identify who has the ability to
view the LAPS passwords so we
can go after those accounts
because once we have that we can
then pull from active directory
a list of all of the local admin
accounts on all the computers
that those users have radio
access to. So I wrote my own
which has a very nice list of
the groups that actually have
LAPS delegation and where they
apply to and I'll be working
with Will Harmjoy to get this
into PowerView so that way you
have some good information as
well because otherwise you need
some crazy command food to type
all that in. So let's talk about
active directory defenses and
bypasses. Organizations say you
shall not pass are they right?
No didn't know Captain john luke
picard was Gandalf but whatever
[laughter] so Fleurian Roth
posted a really great graphic
that shows the common exploit
paths for Windows they posted
this on Twitter. I'm not going
to cover this but it's there for
reference so you run through the
same process you always have
when you run into these defenses
when they're actually setting up
good quality defenses in the
organization. One thing that's
been popped around a lot in the
last year on Twitter is the
concept of Honey Tokens or Honey
Credentials which for the
instance of this talk are
credentials injected into memory
deployed somehow often using the
run as net only but these may or
may not be real on the net work
so if you drop on a box and you
dump credentials and you're like
wow this looks great I got all
these credentials check AD to
see if it's a valid account
check to see if it makes sense
does it pass the sniff test or
is it a trap? >>It's a trap >>So
if they're using the Microsoft
local admin password solution or
LAPS they're randomizing all of
those local administrator
passwords on the computer which
is great! In fact in your red
team report at the end when you
own them completely you should
say yeah use LAPS or something
like that because I used your
local admin accounts to jump
from one to one to the other and
I like my job to have some
challenge and some mystery in it
[laughter] so if they have LAPS
configured you can use PowerUp
to get local admin rights
obviously dump the credentials
look for service accounts the
usual stuff You can find AD
accounts that have local admin
rights you can find AD accounts
with LAPS password view rights
or a lot of organizations deploy
LAPS but LAPS only controls one
password one account's password
which is usually the default
admin account and a lot of
organizations still have a lot
of additional local admin
accounts which may be spread
across the same systems so look
for those. Network segmentation
has become very popular admin
systems are placed in a separate
network segment where you can't
easily get to them but there's
always a way. Find the admin
accounts figure out where they
log on. Compromise the patching
system because they may have
isolated those admin computers
and workstations and servers but
they're still using the same
messy SCCM to patch the
workstations their servers their
domain controllers stop patching
domain controllers with the same
system you use to patch
everything else blue teamers. Or
maybe there's no members in
domain admins but everyone
forgets about the
administrator's account. Domain
admins gets there active
directory rights through being a
member of the domain
administrator's group. Domain
administrator's a full right to
AD domain admins have full
rights to workstations and
servers by default in addition.
So look for custom delegation
like tier or level or
workstation or server admins
because someone has rights
somewhere. Microsoft has a great
whitepaper about the privilege
admin workstation which is
really the baseline for what
should be an admin workstation
environment but organizations
cheat and it's very difficult to
get this right it's difficult to
go through the whole the whole
list of steps and configure it
properly so if you compromise
the install media or the
patching system then you can get
admin rights on their local
admins workstations or you
compromise the communication
you're supposed to be encrypted
using IPsec or something similar
which may not be. Jump or admin
servers are very popular right?
We have this one server all our
admins go to it they log on to
that but if they're not using an
admin workstation they're using
their regular user workstation
all we need to do is drop a
keylogger on there. PowerSploit
has a great PowerShell based
keylogger we can get those
credentials when they type them
into their RDP session. Or if
they have two factor enabled on
RDP two factor often isn't
enabled or possible to my
knowledge for WMI or
WinRM/PowerShell Remoting.
PSExec or NamedPipe. And if you
compromise their Jump Server you
own the domain and if the
organization has not separated
their ad- their admin tiers into
tier zero a active directory
administrators tier one server
admins, application admins, and
tier three workstation admins
where they're not supposed to
login to each other and maybe
they have one admin server for
all of these? Ah that's easy
compromise the workstation admin
and then jump up to domain
admin. So Microsoft's goal is to
get everyone to put their active
directory admins or domain
admins into an admin forest a
red forest and ultimately their
admin accounts that are at lower
tiers into another forest that
way they're protected by the uh
from the protection forest and
all of the legacy stuff that's
there. Most organizations can't
get up to 2012-R2 across all of
their servers and computers
can't get up to Windows 10 on
their workstations. You can do
that in an admin forest it's a
nice recommendation and
Microsoft has a great write up
on it so you can point them to
that it will make it a lot more
difficult to act for the red
teams in the future and the
attacker's to actually get full
active directory to the domain
admin because again you want
your job to be interesting not
easy. So there is a universal
bypass for most offenses get
full access from my first slide,
remember that? No I'm just
kidding. It's service accounts.
Service accounts are the
universal bypass for most
offenses. So even if they put
all of their active directory
admins or domain admin user
accounts into that admin forest
usually their service accounts
that have rights, why? Because
they're over permissioned.
They're not protected like
admins. They're weak passwords.
No two factor and limited
visibility and understanding.
There are service accounts that
have been in that organization
longer than the people that
administering the server and
they have no idea why those
accounts are still there or why
they have that access. So some
interesting active directory
facts. All authenticated users
have read access to most if not
all objects and their
attributes. All authenticated
users have read access to most
if not all contents of SYSVOL
which includes group policy and
scripts and other things that AD
admins just put in there because
they never think anyone will
find them including files with
passwords in them. You're
kidding me. Standard users can
have elevated rights through the
magic of SID history even if
they're not a member of any
group at all. They could even
modify a user or group without
elevated rights with through
custom OU ACLs custom
permissions. Or if they have
access to modify group policy
that's linked to the domain or
an OU could take over that group
policy and control the
organization. So you're a red
teamer you got domain admin in
the organization pop the
champagne woohoo we won right?
That was a nice day's work. So
we pull the domain admin account
hashes well there's a few other
things that you want to get. You
want to get the Krbtgt hashes we
know that we can create golden
tickets with it right? You also
want to grab the domain
controller computer account
password hashes because even if
the organization changes the
first two you could actually
create a silver ticket using
that domain controller hash to
recompromise the organization
and run Mimkatz DC sync to pull
all the credentials and I talked
about this at Defcon last year.
Interesting fun fact NetApp by
default does not change their
computer account passwords in
active directory unless you se-
unless the admin goes in and
schedules it document it on
NetApp site. What does this
mean? I pulled those device
password hashes for NetApps and
other storage devices and I'm
sure it's the same on others and
once I have that I can create
silver tickets and have read
access to all the files on those
shares and I learned recently
from a red teaming friend of in
that NetApps often by default
also share out on NFS in a
Windows environment so you want
to check to make sure that these
other file sharing services are
not enabled when they're not
needed. DSRM account password
hashes are the default
administrator account on the
domain controller the rid500
account if you pull these and
they have a DSRM registry key
set to two you can actually pass
the hash to the domain
controller run Mimkatz and run
DCsync off of it and I talked
about this at DerbyCon last
year. So security pro's AD
checklist identify who has AD
admin rights in the a- domain
forest, identify who has the
rights to logon to the domain
controllers this includes
account operators, backup
operators, print operators,
server operators, by default. If
they haven't changed that a help
desk user may have the ability
to logon to a domain controller
because they put their help desk
groups into account operators.
Identify the virtual host admins
they may be in active directory
they're probably in active
directory and they're probably
not well protected. Scan the
domains, the OUs, the admin SD
holder, and group policies for
inappropriate group policy
permissions. And in your report
say please protect your active
directory domain admins make
sure they only log on to admin
workstations, admin servers
don't make my job easy. And
limit the service account rights
go through all of them and
figure out what accounts they
need go to that vendor and try
to figure out what accounts they
need. So quick PowerView AD
Recon cheat sheet ah these
slides will be posting on AD
Security dot org in about 15 or
20 minutes automatically so
you'll have all of this but
these are all the commandments I
er functions I ran from
PowerView so you can look at
them later. So in summary active
directory stores the history of
the organization, why is this?
Because they've deployed active
directory they've updated,
they've modernized it, it's,
their organization paradigm for
support and business, is changed
so they've shifted things
they've moved things in they've
created new delegation, new
delegation groups, guess what,
most of that old stuff is still
there hiding. If you can find it
you can exploit and you can help
them fix it. If you ask the
right questions of active
directory you can map the active
directory environment and the
enterprise far better than what
the admins know about you can
update their documentation for
them [laughter] if they pay you
for it. But you can quickly
recon the environment hours if
not sooner depending on the size
of the organization But the
business requirements ultimately
subversive security every time.
So in your reports make sure
that you highlight this and say
look if you want to fix this
you're going to have to spend
some money, fix the resources,
do what needs to be done. If you
identify the proper leverage and
apply it you will own active
directory and you will help the
organization fix it because as a
red teamer your job is to make
the blue team better and help
them level up their defenses so
that next time when you get
brought in you run through your
playbook and you go wow, nice
job! And you tell them that, and
they'll love that. Say hey,
great job on fixing these things
we talked about later, we
checked it, you did a great job.
And you'll probably get hired
again. So that's my time, thank
you very much for yours. Any
questions? [applause]