>> Alright, how's everybody
doing? Having a good time?
Alright, how many people here
use Tor? Yeah...alright. How
many people trust Tor? No, there
we go! How 'but that, that's
good to see. Well, these two
gentleman have been working on a
project that is going to help
us, maybe, perhaps, trust Tor a
little bit more. Or at least
find those people that are out
there messing around with Tor,
making it untrustworthy. Let's
give these two guys a big round
of applause. [applause] >> Thank
you for the introduction. Uh, it
seems that we have problem with
the slides not showing up. So,
apparently, they are working on
fixing it. So in the meantime,
we are going to start. I'm
Guevara Noubir and this is joint
presentation and work with, uh,
Amirali Sanatinia, we both from
Northeastern University. We work
on, uh, developing security,
privacy techniques, building
systems to enhance security. We
also interested in, uh,
investigating the potential of
attacks on real-world systems
and therefore, this work. So
unfortunately, you cannot see
the slides, but the talk is
about something called "Honey
Onions" that we developed and it
is about exposing snooping Tor
HSDir relays. And so, this is in
the context of Tor, large number
of people use it. Uh, it's quite
popular. Uh, we're interested,
so, uh, we're interested in
understanding how many of the
Tor Relays, uh, are misbehaving,
these are relays that, uh, host,
uh, what's called hidden
services. And in fact, this
issue that we're going to be
talking about, uh, is known to
the Tor people and they've been
working on, uh, having long term
solution and also short term
solution. Our interest was in
knowing how many today of these
relays are misbehaving. So, uh,
the next slide that can't see,
unfortunately, is about "What is
Tor?" Tor is very powerful and
popular tool for enhancing
privacy. I personally [inaudible
audience comment]...yeah, so.
Uh, so, uh, so it, uh, I
personally, regularly use Tor
anytime, for example, I want to
check something that has to do
with help or any when I Google
something, I don't want to have
the whole world know about it,
so I use it and I feel that's a,
uh, you know, of all the systems
that exist today, it's really
one of the best, uh, systems
that one can use. So maybe one
question to the audience, the
first question was, how many of
you know about it. So, how many
of you use it? Ok, fair number.
So, how many of you run the
relay? Yeah. Uh, so how many of
you have hidden service?	That's
running? Ok. I say, I see, I see
much less numbers. And it could,
uh, mean that, uh, Uh, maybe
some of you don't want to even,
uh, disclose this information.
So this work is about showing
that, when in fact, you can't,
while you can't trust maybe Tor
about various kind of things,
you cannot trust that your
hidden service, uh, the
existence of it is not hidden.
Um, and this is the goal of this
work. So Tor provides, uh, two
types of services, that are
quite well known. One of them is
that you can browse the Internet
anonymously and says that you
can go to some website and the
goal is that, uh, your ISP, the
website, would not know that you
are doing so. Type of services,
called hidden services, it
allows one to run, uh, server,
uh, website, for example, and,
uh, no one would be able to know
what's this IP address and
therefore, it's, uh, physical
location. Uh, so Tor is used by
a large number of people. I
think they have over a million
people every day that would use
it. Uh, most of these users are
normal users. Uh, so most of
them try to browse the Internet,
don't want to reveal things
about themselves. Some people
try to circumvent censorship. So
all these are reasonable
applications. You also have fair
number of journalists whenever
they want to communicate with
their sources or they want to
access information and they
don't want to reveal that. So
that is another type of use of
Tor. You have also activists,
whistle blowers, they don't want
to reveal information about, uh,
themselves, who they're talking
to, what information is being
shared, uh, you also have law
enforcement and military use.
Uh, you know they reveal
information, but what they're
doing, they also, uh, um,
sometimes they also want to hide
amount the group of larger
people who are much more normal.
And also you have obviously
criminals who use Tor their
activities. Um, uh, in fact, I
don't see slides, but, so the
next one is about hidden
services. Hidden service is
basically, uh, this capability
of being able to run this
website Tor server and hide
physical location. It has other
side effects that are quite
interesting. One of them is by
writing your website as a hidden
service, you can hide, you,
you'll have the self
authentication. You don't need
certificates, because they're on
an address itself, uh, includes
information by the public key
and allows you to self
authenticate. It allows you also
to have end-to-end encryption.
And there are many systems,
besides websites, that use uh,
um, Tor hidden services. Secure
Drop, for example, used by the
New Yorker or the Guardian
allows one to communicate with
journalists and provide
information to journalists. But
even mainstream systes like
Facebook, they have, uh, hidden
service. Um, you have also
applications like Ricochet that
allows secure messaging and
every client runs a hidden
service so you can hide the
identity, the clients, whose
talking to whom and they also
get rid of central entities. You
also have other types of people
who use it like the Silk Road,
for example, ran as uh a hidden
service, you have ransomware
like Cryto Locker used hidden
services so that they could hide
the location of the server that
collects the bit coins that
people would have to pay. So
there's a variety of people who
use it. Um, so, maybe to also
clarify, you know, for this
talk, so Tor claims to have set
of uh, um, of a, properties, but
it does not really claim, for
example, that these will give
you, if you go use the Tor
browser, you don't have any
guarantee that you have
end-to-end encryption. Because
if you just browse a website
that is, uh, does not have
https, any traffic going from
the exit node would be, uh, in
the clear. Uh, for hidden
services, when you create hidden
service, there's no guarantee
for you that that hidden
service, it's existence, is
protected. Uh, Tor aims at, uh,
at least in what's they have in
system today is that, you can't
really tell where is the
location, but not the fact that
it exists. And this work was
about finding out, uh, you know,
how many relays misbehaved, try
to get this information as an
indicator of other malicious
activities. Uh, within the space
of, uh, in general looking at,
uh, privacy infrastructure and
attacks on it, uh, so, uh,
whenever you have a privacy
infrastructure, uh, various kind
of entities try to attack it
maybe to reduce it's popularity
or, uh, to misuse it. I mean
cryptography, in general, use
for good things, lot of people
try also to misuse it. And there
has been work related to this
trying to find how many of the
HSDir relays would be snooping
into the traffic of users. Which
is different from what we are,
uh, doing. Uh, other work looked
into all these hidden services,
what kind of information, what
kind of content do they have?
Um, so here, what we want to
know is out of the Tor relays,
the subset of them that can
serve as, uh, HSDir flag,
therefore, they host descriptors
about hidden services. How many
of them, uh, are misbehaving?
And misbehaving, meaning that
they log information that
they're not supposed to do, so
whoever is running, they
modified the code to be able to
log this information. And later
on they might visit, uh, these
websites. And as I mentioned,
this is, uh, a problem that is
known to Tor people and have
been working on resolving and
they have other techniques that
they use to identify these
misbehavior relays. Our
techniques have the advantage
that we can cover larger scale
of, uh, misbehaving devices. So
this is not really about like
breaking the privacy of Tor if
you browse some place, but more
about the hidden service
existence. The questions we try
to address, there are four of
them. The first one is, "How
many of the Tor relays are
misbehaving in the sense that I
defined?" [audience applause]
That makes my life easier. So
there are four questions we try
to address. One of them is, "How
many of them are misbehaving?"
And if you could have a small
number, the lower bound of that
number, we have an idea, but how
much misbehavior is happening in
Tor. The next thing is that,
"Which one of them are
snooping?" And trying to find
out, uh, information that
they're not supposed to collect.
The third one, "What do they
really do, how much, are they
just collecting information, do
they try to attack, uh, are they
aggressive or not?" And the last
one is, "Why they are really?"
Besides, uh, what relay and what
IP addresses. So we have
addressed mostly the first two
questions and a little bit of
the third one, uh, the last one
with really who they are, that
won't really solve and this
might be, you know, nice
community for looking into that
and pushing this war to the next
stage. So, I'll first maybe I'll
explain a little bit how hidden
services work. Uh, this diagram
somehow summarizes that. So to
run hidden service, what you do,
you pick a random public key.
Some people will go and select
one that will end up in an onion
address that they prefer, like
Facebook has a nice one. But
typically you pick a random
public private key. You hash the
public key in specific way that
gives you the dot onion address.
Then what you do, you pick a
subset of the relays, what's
called introduction point, few
of them, and you setup a Tor
circuit to them. These
introductions points will help,
um, people come back to you
later on. Then you hash your dot
onion address with time
information and other things and
that gives you descriptor. A
descriptor ID. And, uh, it also
tells you, which relays with the
HSDir flag you should put this
descriptor information with. And
you can have, find two, and you
end up with a set of six relays
with the HSDir flag where you
put your information. Now, on
the other hand, at the same
time, you give your dot Onion
address to whoever you want to
communicate with you. And that's
in a, and then in step three,
this client, he'll take the dot
Onion address and he will hash
it the same way you did and
every day's gonna give him the
descriptor IDs that will tell
him which HSDir relays he should
come to. So in step three, he
will go to these relays and ask
them what are the introduction
points to be able to talk to
this hidden service. In step
four, the client will also
select something called the
rendezvous point. Some other
relay, he sets up a circuit to
it...relays with the HSDir flag,
which one of them are
misbehaving in the sense that I
defined earlier? So now going
back to, uh, just a little bit
more specific about HSDir. So
you have, uh, these relays, they
have identifiers, uh and that
will show up in something called
the ring of HSDir identifiers.
And your Onion address, once you
hash it, gives you this
descriptor ID and you find the
first HSDir after the descriptor
ID and you pick the first three,
mean the first one, second and
third and then you hash it again
in a different way and it gives
you another descriptor ID and
then you find the other two or
the other three after that and
you have now three and three
relays that, uh, will host
information how you would be
reached. The reason why it
changes everyday and you take
more than one is to put, to have
reliability and protect against
denial of service. Such that, is
you're always hosting your
information same location,
someone who's, uh, who wants to
block you, he might have that
information and won't serve it
to anyone. Uh, the side effect
is that whenever they host that
information, they can log it and
they can go visit your, um,
HSDir, um your system that you
don't want to leak. So our
system, how to detect whose
misbehaving, the idea is quite
simple. We can create a large
number of these things, we call
Honey Onions, like Honey Pot.
Uh, we set them up in a secure
way and sense that we, we follow
all the instructiones that they
are not going to leak. We don't
tell anyone about them. We know
that if someone comes visit our
service, then whoever had the
information leaked it. He logged
it and maybe gave it to someone
and leaked it. So that is the
fundamental idea. But it is not
that trivial because
informatione everyday, you're
gonna give it to six people. Or
six relays. So it could be any
of the six. So you'll have to
find out who out of the six.
Since we want to look at the
global scale, we generate
several batches. Everyday we
generate some number. Every week
another number and every month,
uh, another batch. The reason
for this that some of them will
collect these Onion addresses,
but they won't visit them
immediately. They will wait for
few days to confuse us that it
might be someone else. So we
could compute that we need
fifteen hundred, uh, Onion to be
able to cover 95 percent of
these relays. So everyday we
generate fifteen hundred, every
week fifteen hundred and every
month fifteen hundred. And, um,
and then we see who's visiting.
Some of you remember there was a
peak in the Tor number of hidden
services. So I don't have time
to come out to that, but it is
not us, um, for various reasons,
but, I mean, that number was
much larger than what we
generated. We generated, at any
node, we had forty-fiver hundred
onions in the system. So before
I bore you a little bit with
some math, I just show you, the
reason for [audience laughter],
so we choose this name Honey
Onion, because it made sense.
Then we Googled it a little bit
and we found that, oh, it has
meaning. And it was in fact
quite interesting that the
meaning really matched what we
were doing, so, so we couldn't
resist using it, um, um. So,
how, um, how do you find out
who's misbehaving? The idea is
quite, again, so, we create the
honion, we put it on six places,
if one of those misbehaving, we
know that one of the six is bad.
But then, as we create more,
they might end up in different
locations and now we have that
for these two honion, the
visits, there are two people who
could explain it. Uh and then
later on we put more and you can
tell with these maybe not going,
depending on the assumption and
so on, you can see that there is
some, maybe possible way how to
one could find out who is
misbehaving. So, the
architecture of systems that we
built, in step 1, you generate
all these Honions that we gonna
place. Uh, on these, uh,
servers. jThen some of them get
visited whenever there is a
visit, it gives us information,
uh, that all who knew about it
should become suspicous. We put
them in some graph that we built
that's called a bipartite graph,
that has nodes that correspond
to honions and nodes that can
respond to relays and whenever
there's a visit for the honion,
we we put all the edges to all
the relays that had this
information. So since I'm
running a little out of time, so
maybe get to what we exactly
did, so I'm not maybe going to
talk about details of the math.
The first thing is that we
wanted to know what is the
smallest set of suspicous of
relays that could explain the
visits that we see. That will
tell us the lower bound on how
many of these relays are
misbehaving. If you find the
smallest set that explains the
visit, we know that there should
be more than that that are
misbehaving and there's a way to
formulate it, which I'm going to
skip maybe that math. The, uh,
this is not necessarily a
trivial problem, there's some
heuristics that could, um, give
some approximation and we could
formulate this as something
called integer linear program,
where basically to each relay
we're going to give some
variable, either zero or one.
One meaning that it is malicious
and we want to minimize some of
these x i's, that uh, you find
the smallest set, but we need to
explain every visit. Uh and this
can be solved with something
called a ILP Solver. And before
we tell you what we found, why
we trusted this sol-, this
technique, uh, works, uh,
reasonably well. Well, uh, so we
also did some simulations,
selecting some of these to, uh
malicious and so on and so you
see that, uh, we can get between
ninety-seven percent accuracy
to, uh, eighty-one assuming,
eighty-one means that there was
a significant number of
malicious ones. So now I'm going
to pass the token to Amirali
whose going to tell you the
results of the experiment. >> So
good thing the slides are back,
because otherwise I didn't have
much to talk about. Uh, here we
can see under from left to right
on the bottom you can see our
schedules for daily, weekly and
monthly visits and the reason
behind having three schedules is
if adversary visits a honion,
immediately we can catch them in
our daily, but if uh, but if
they would wait for "y", then
they wouldn't show up in the
daily, but we can still spot
them in the weekly and monthly.
Uh, the other thing as was
mentioned by Guevara, the rise
in the number of Onion services,
the only, at each point in time,
you're only at forty-five
hundred, but the number of
increasing honion addresses was
at least more than a magnitude
much more than what we had. So
we are sure it is not us. And we
started our experiments on
February twelfth and most of the
results, as we explained, are
based on the seventy-two days
that we are running this
experiment although we have them
for further and we discuss them
later. Um, we are sure that the
visits are not a result of the
rise in the number of onion
addresses, because, uh, the
increase was happening on
eighteenth of February and we
can still see visits even
happening on twelve and thirteen
of February. So it happened
before the increase. The other
thing to mention in the daily
graph, you see there are not
many visits during the peak and
one of the reasons is that to
get the HSDir flag, it would
take ninety-six hours or four
days, so after people saw there
are a lot of new onion
addresses, they probably setup
new relays and took them four
days to get the HSDir flag. And
after that, they started
probing. The other things that
you see more visits on weekly
and monthly, because they are
running for longer times, so,
uh, this adversaries or the
malicious HSDir had more time to
visit them. And this is an
example of a typical
connectivity graph that we have,
for example, uh, the gray
circles in the middle are the
honions. The visited honions.
And the black ones above them
are the HSDir's that are picked
by ILP and that explain the
visits. All the other colorful,
uh, nodes are the other HSDir
who have been hosting these
honions. As you can see, for
example, for the one in the
orange one, the top right, that
one is more trivial to peak,
because you only have one HSDir
who visits, both of you are
honions. But the power of ILP
really comes in the cases with
the purple one, top left, then
you have many HSDir who have
been hosting many of the visited
honions, but you want to know
what is the lure about or who
are the most likely HSDirs and
that where really our technique
and ILP comes to power. And we
can peak these four and identify
these are the most likely,
suspicious, HSDirS. Oh and
apparently we are running out of
time. So, uh, the snooping
behavior, we saw some of them
visiting everything, the
variables on Alibaba. Alibaba
this one visiting most of the
honions and the Tor people
identified, they also identified
them, we talked to Tor people
and after awhile they become
more advance and they delay
their visit. The top, uh, the
bottom left graph. And the
geographical location we mostly
see them in Europe and Northern
America is because Tor is more
and it's also representive of
the user of Tor. You don't have
it much in Middle East and China
because it's mostly blocked and
this location doesn't
necessarily mean these are the
countries who are snooping.
These are the relays that are
located in this country. Not the
country themselves. And to give
you more statistic, more than
half of them are hosting on
Cloud infrastructure and they
also have the exit flag about
twenty-fiver person, which is
much more than what you would
have. Uh, and some of them are
doing some attacks and some of
them are less aggressive.
[applause] >> So maybe just one
final comment, so since we've
done this work, in fact, uh,
whoever was snooping, changed
their behavior and now in fact
you can see that most of them
delay, they don't really visit
quite immediately. They wait for
days and sometimes weeks for
them to visit. So is still an
interesting problem. Think we'll
stop here, sorry that we
couldn't really talk about the
last part in detail. [applause]