>> Alright welcome to track 1.
Um, hopefully some of you all
are Windows domain admins,
because this talk should be
interesting to you. You should
pay attention. Um, with that,
here they are. [applause] >>
Thanks Clifton. [applause] So I
made sure I got the right mic,
can the people in the back here
me ok? Awesome, thank you. So we
are talking about six degrees of
domain admin. If you're not
familiar with this phrase,
there's a very common, uh, game
in like the film geek world
called six degrees of Kevin
Bacon, where you can take actor,
any, uh, director, any movie and
just by making six connections,
you can find a way to go to
Kevin Bacon. I don't know why
it's Kevin Bacon, that's what it
is. So we have found a way to do
that in an Active Directory
environment and domain admin is
the most obvious target, so
that's what we selected. Is
there a little bit of feedback?
Maybe I should back off a little
bit. Ok. About us. My name is
Andy Robbins. I've been a
professional penetration tester
and red teamer for 4 years. I
originally cut my teeth in in
the financial services industry.
Uh, I'd really love to talk to
you about ACH files, if you're
interested in talking about
that. Uh, all three of us work
at Veris Group's Adaptive Threat
Division. Uh, with that I will
pass it over to Rohan. >> Hi,
I'm, uh, Rohan Vazarkar. Uh, I'm
another, I'm another penetration
tester at Veris Group. I've
been, uh, doing penetration
testing for about two and a half
years. I'm working on a lot of
opens source projects and I was
responsible for the web UI for
this one. >> Hi, my name is Will
Schroeder, my handle is harmjoy.
I'm a researcher at the
Adaptive, uh, Threat Division
and I've built a good number of
our offensive kind of toolset
that we've used over the last
couple of years. Most notably
Partial Empire and also
PowerView, which kind of acts as
the data collection component
for Bloodhound. >> Any PowerView
users in the room? Lots of you.
Awesome. Yeah, give Will a hand.
Give a Wil a hand for PowerView.
[applause] >> And also this is
their first time at DefCon, so
give them a hand too real quick.
It's their first time speaking.
[applause] >> Alright, let's
talk a little bit about the
current state of Active
Directory. Uh, domain privilege
escalation. Uh, first of all I
want to, uh, talk about this
quote a little bit. This was
stated by John Lambert, he's a
general manager of Microsoft's
Threat Intelligence Center. John
said, "Defenders think in lists.
Attacks think in graphs. As long
as this is true, attackers will
win." There's a great blog post,
where John goes into some depth
about what this concept means
effectively. What I hope that we
can show is that not only are we
going to start thinking in
graphs, we're going to start
using them practically. To
automate a lot of our work. So
first of all, with with Active
Directory domain privilege
escalation. Active Directory is
effective effectively
ubiquitous. In Shawn Metcalf's
talk, he stated that, of the
Fortune 500 in the United
States, more than 90 or more
than 95% of organizations use
Active Director. To the people
in this room, that's probably a
given. But what does that
ubiquity actually mean in the
real role. In the real world.
That ubiquity means that Active
Directory is a subject of
attention. Not only from
defenders, but also from
attackers. So that means that
there is a lot of time, energy,
money, blood, sweat, tears going
into learning how to best defend
Active Directory environments
and also how to attack to them.
As penetration testers and red
teamers, we have the benefit of
every so often getting these
nice Easy buttons, that make us
look like elite hack sores,
because we use the right module
to basically do like a point
click escalate rights. MS08-067,
MS14-068, KiTrapOD, GPP. The
list goes on. What's the problem
with these Easy buttons? The
problem is that they are
femoral. They have a tendency to
go away. Especially over the
past 4 or 5 years, enterprises,
at least in the United States,
have started paying attention to
a lot of the things that people
in this room have been saying
for a long time. Do patch
management. Run vulnerability
scanners. Audit the results of
those vulnerability scanners.
So, those vulnerab- those
vulnerability management
practices are getting more
mature. That means that when you
land into an environment and
they have that kind of maturity,
those Easy buttons may not
necessarily be available to you.
So let's look at this in a
visual way. We have an example
of a very simple Active
Directory environment, where
where we have 16 computers. Now
let's say this red computer is
kind of our initial access.
Maybe it's Cobalt Strike Beacon,
maybe it's Meterpreter, maybe
we're a malicious insider and we
just have access to Active
Directory. Bottom line, we have
authenticated access to AD. Now
thanks to Will's work with
PowerView, it's very easy to
identify systems that a domain
admin has logged onto. In fact,
you can typically find out where
everybody in the environment has
logged onto, which will be very
important later. So let's say we
identify, this is the box where
the domain admin has logged on.
Now, this client organization
that you're in, they don't have
the best patch management. They
don't have the best
vulnerability management. So you
escalate rights on this one
initial machine, you dump the
NTLM hash for the RID 500
system. They've applied the
KB2871997, but they haven't
disabled the local admin
account. What does that mean for
you? That means that all these
computers all of a sudden light
up and now you have kind of
notional administrator access to
them. Including, the box that
the domain admin has logged
onto. So, you use your favorite
piv pivot method. Maybe PSExec
or WMI. You pivot over to the
box the domain admin has logged
onto, you wear mimic hats, you
get the password, you now have
access to the entire
environment. Awesome. Who's
executed an attach path exactly
like that? Like a billion time?
Most everybody. Let's take.
Let's take a look at a slightly
different example. So in this
environment the client actually
does have proper patch
management and vulnerability
management programs. So you're
not going to be able to find
MS08-067. You're not going to
find MS14-068. You're not going
to find GPP creds. However, in
our experience, 99 times out of
100, we are able to gain some
kind of initial privilege access
into an environment. Most
typically this actually happens
with clear text credentials that
are in a file share that anybody
who's authenticated to AD can
use, can view and read. Uh,
logon scripts are probably the
most obvious examples. So let's
say that we find one of those
credentials and, uh, ok so first
of all, we found the DA, he was
logged on, he's in the sandbox.
We use those credentials and we
identify systems that we now
kind of have, uh, notional or
provisional administrator access
to. We find these three boxes
and we find out who the three
people are who are logged onto
those systems. Unfortunately for
us, none of those people are a
domain admin. Additionally, none
of those users have
administrator rights to the box
that the domain admin is logged
onto. So we have this kind of
missing link that we have to
identify. Typically what we do
is we could go into this kind of
credential dance or what
Microsoft referred to in 2009 as
an identity snowball attack. So
what does that mean? That means
that we choose one of these
systems to pivot to. You can use
manual analysis and try to
figure out what system that is,
but eventually you're just going
to have to guess. So let's say
that we pivot to the machine up
here in the top left. We get
this guys' credential. We do the
same thing. We figure out why
system this guy has admin rights
to. Ok, now we have some new
boxes. However, again, not a DA.
And again none of those users
have admin rights in the system
the DA's logged onto. So again,
we have to guess. So let's take
our best guess and we say that
maybe this guy is part of a
helpdesk group. That sounds like
a pretty good group that
probably has some high
privilege. So we pivot to this
box, run the Mimikatz, get his
credential and then we find out,
this guy doesn't have any more
rights in the environment than
what we already have. Hate that.
So we have to go back. We have
to go back to the system at the
top left. We have to make
another guess. Let's say we go
to this system, we run a
Mimikatz again, we get this
guys' cred and then lo and
behold, who should appear, but
the domain admin, in the system
that we have this kind of
notional administrator privilege
to. Now that we've gone two hops
away from where we originally
started. We pivot to the DA, we
run the Mimikatz, now we have
admin rights in the entire
environment. Who's run an attack
path like this? Or who's run a
report where credential abuses,
uh, using that kind of attack
path? A lot of you. Cool. We
refer to this attack or this
methodology as derivative local
administrator. Justin Warner,
uh, who on Twitter you can find
@6dub, he defines this as the
chaining or linking of
administrator rights through
compromising other privileged
accounts. Uh, at MSRC in 2009,
Alice Jeng and John Dunnigan put
a great white paper, uh, about a
method- or a capability that
they had called Heat Ray. That
goes into very extreme detail
about how they kind of
understood this process as well.
Highly recommend that you go
read that white paper. So let's
look at this a little bit
simpler. Let's say we have this
user Bob. Bob has admin rights
to PC 1. On PC 1 is this user
named Mary who has logged on.
Mary has administrator right to
PC 2. Bob derives administrator
privileges to PC 2 via stealing
Mary's credential. Make sense?
Cool. How else can this happen?
This can also happen with Active
Directory group delegation. When
you add a user to a group, that
user gets all the privileges of
that group. When you add a group
to a group, that nested group
gets all the privileges of that
group. Let's say Bob was a
member of this group called Help
Desk. Help Desk is a member of a
group called server admins.
Server admins have admin rights
to PC 2. See a lot of nodding
heads, like this is, this is,
pretty good. This is pretty
basic stuff. This is what the
entire methodology or the entire
core of BloodHound is based on.
Is this concept of derivative
local admin. So derivative local
admin...sorry about that.
Derivative local admin is an
extremely effective attack. But
it has some, uh, very serious,
uh, setbacks and challenges that
we need to be, uh, aware of.
First of all its extremely time
consuming and it's extremely
tedious work. If you've gone
through the process of manually,
uh, going through this method,
uh, you understand this very
well. You have, uh, uh, uh, a a
complexity override essentially
of where each step you go, the
the analysis steps you have to
do grow, uh, exponentially. Uh,
it's not comprehensive. So,
imagine the difference between
taking a report to your client
or the client getting a report
from a pen test firm. Imagine
the difference between reading
this is one attack path that we
identified in your environment.
Versus here are all of the
attack paths in your
environment. Ok? Next you have
limited situational awareness.
You may not even understand, you
may not have the ability to
understand what kind of
privilege you currently have in
whatever user context you're
running in. Finally, the last
thing I will say is, did you
even need DA? If your target is
like an HR system, it's gonna be
simple to escalate the DA and
then go back down to the system
that you actually need. But you
may not even had to go through
this rigmarole of escalating DA
in the first place. Alright,
we're going to talk about graph
theory and I'm going to take a
drink of water real quick. Graph
theory has been the missing
link, uh, in this process, uh,
that has been keeping us from
automating the entire process. I
highly recommend you look at the
history of graph theory with
Leonhard Euler using it to
disprove or to prove that there
was no solut- no solution to the
seven bridges of königsberg
problem. Super interesting
stuff. We're also going to look
at the, uh, design of our attack
graph. So the basic elements of
a graph, first of all a graph is
not necessarily just a visual
thing. A graph is a a construct
of a discreet branch of
mathematics called graph theory.
So in a graph, you have vertices
or nodes. Vertices are used to
represent a basic individual
element of the system that
you're representing. If this is
Google Maps, then a vertex may
represent a city or an
intersection. Edges are used to
represent relationships between
these vertices. If Seattle,
Washington is a vertex and
Portland, Oregon is a vertex,
then Interstate 5 could be
thought of as an edge that
connects those two cities.
Finally, paths, the most crucial
part of graphs. Paths are used
to connect otherwise disparate
nodes, regardless of how far
away they are from each other.
This is where the key difference
between a graph and a relational
database comes into play. Uh,
which we'll talk about later.
Here's a visual way to look at
the same thing. So here's a very
simple graph. We have two
vertices and we have an edge.
This is a directed edge or it's
one way. You can think of it as
one way street. You go to
vertex, you can go from vertex 1
to vertex 2, but you can't go
the other way. Paths. Can you
see a path from vertex 1 to
vertex 4? Yeah. Is there a path
from vertex 3 to vertex 4? No.
Because you'd have to go the
wrong way across a directed
edge. So after a lot of false
starts, we finally landed on a a
tack graph design that works.
And here's how it looks. The
vertices are used to represent
users, groups, computers and
domains in Active Directory. The
edges identify the relationships
between those. So this means
admin rights, group membership,
user sessions and domain trusts.
Finally, paths always lead
toward escalating rights.
Period. Always. This makes
writing our path finding queries
very, very simple. Again let's
look at this visually. Like I
said, users, we have two users
in this graph, Bob and Mary.
Groups. We have two groups in
this graph. IT admins and domain
admins. Computers. We have one
computer. Server 1. First let's
identify group memberships. We
find out that Bob is a member of
this group called IT admins. We
find out that Mary is a member
of this group called domain
admins. Next, we figure out
privilege. Who has admin rights,
where. This group called IT
admins has administrator rights
on this computer called server
1. Finally, let's find out where
people are logged on. We find
out that Mary is logged onto
computer 1 or put another way,
computer 1 has a session for
this user. Is there a path from
Bob to domain admins? Yeah. Bob
is a member of IT admins, IT
admins has rights to computer
server 1. Server 1 has Mary
logged on. She's a domain admin.
We've got our path. This is the
core fundamental concept for
BloodHound. Let's put this very
simply. In order to use a graph,
you need to populate it with
data. What data do we need?
Who's logged on, where? Who has
admin rights, where? What users
and groups are part of what
groups? That's it. That's all we
need. Will is going to take over
now and he's going to talk about
how we actually do this data
collection. >> Cool. Alright, so
I'm going to go over some
stealthy data collection with
Power View. I'll let you guys
read this quote. This was, uh,
extremely kind of weird for me,
we obviously do not advocate the
malicious usage of our tool
sets, but you know, uh, what can
you do. So we have our little
puppet, Phineas Fisher up there.
So PowerView, we saw some
PowerView users in the audience.
PowerView is a power shell 2.0
compatible domain and network
situational awareness tool. I
started writing this a couple of
years ago to automate a lot of
the offensive and some defensive
trade craft that we execute on
engagements. It's completely
self-contained. It's a single
PS1 power shell script, it can
be loaded into memory, there's
no external dependencies.
Nothing has to be added to the
machine. PowerView collects the
data that BloodHound is built
on. What's really cool is that
in most cases, you do not need
any kind of elevated domain
access to gather this
information. And I'll go over
the different components here in
a second. So just as a domain
authenticated user. You do need
a session like that. But no
privileges at all, just in
domain users, the parent group,
you can collect a huge amount of
information through Active
Directory through a couple of
different ways. So, Andy
mentioned the three components
of information we needed. The
first is, who's logged on,
where? We refer to this as user
hunting. So the main function in
PowerView that does this is
Invoke-UserHunter. It was one of
the first one's written. It's an
extremely common one that people
tend to run. It utilizes a
couple of 132 API calls under
the hood. The most useful being
NetSessionEnum to where you can
point these functions remote
systems and figure out who has
sessions established with that
remote box. Again not having to
have administrative rights in
the remote system. So you can
run this against a main
controller or file server and
get a really nice mapping about
who's logged in where. There's
also a stealth option. By
default, Invoke-UserHunger will
enumerate all machines in the
domain and run these enumeration
actions against every single
machine. This can be extremely
noisy in some context in
anyone's doing internal network
based monitoring, but it gives
us a more complete data set.
With Stealth, we use a couple
tricks to where we enumerate all
user objects and we try to pull
out properties that may indicate
highly trafficked file servers.
Something like profile path and
collect all those things in and
run a NetSessionEnum against
each system. So it's much
faster, but we don't get quite
as accurate data. Next, who can
admin what? This is the craziest
thing to me. I I love this. So
as an unprivileged user, we can
enumerate the members of a local
group on a remote machine
without needing administrator
privileges on that remote
machine. I didn't, there was a
couple tools out there that did
this, I I weaponized it up in
PowerView and we use this
function specifically on almost
every single engagement. There's
two ways you can do this, you
can use the WinNT service
provider, which is a remnant of
NT domain deployment. You can
also use this particular
NetLocalGroup members call, just
point it to remote server and it
happily gives you back who the
members of local administrator
are. Their domain SID, whether
they're a group or a user. The
function in PowerView that does
this is GetNetLocalGroup. You
just pass an IP, a NetBIOS name
or a computer name. If you would
like to use the API call, you
can do the dash API flag by
default it does the Win32
provider. We also have a kind of
different new kind of method to
do this, to gather the same
information. So I worked last
year with Shawn Metcalf about
how to kind of structure this
approach. Group policy objects
are just collections of settings
that are applied to computers.
One of, some of these settings
are who are in the local
administrators group for a
particular machine. This is
either through restricted groups
or group policy preferences.
GPOs are linked to OUs and
sites. So if we enumerate all
the GPOs and we numerate all the
other domain containers and do a
little bit of, uh, correlation
magic in the back end. We can
get a mapping of who can
administer what machines through
GPO object modification. Now
this is not gonna be as
accurate, because you're not
touching every machine and
you're not, so if somebody
specifically adds a local user
to a machine it won't show up in
this method. But what's really
cool in this approach is that
you're only communicating with
the domain controller through
LDAP. You're not seeing sending
a single packet to any other
machine. The PowerView function
to this is Find-GPOLocation, be
default it will just give you a
nice raw mapping of everyone who
can administer what machines
through group policy
correlation. The last part.
Who's in what groups. This is
the easiest, we just enumerate
all the groups through LDAP and
pull out all the members of
each. PowerView is just getting
that group piped to getting that
member. This is the PowerShell
pipeline. What's really neat
about this is it will pass fully
serialized objects between all
the different functions you're
running. So it's super super
easy, we do some kind of
variation of this in almost
every engagement as well. And
that's it! So let's bring it all
together. There's a customized
version of PowerView that is
integrated with BloodHound. It
has all the stock PowerView
command lets along with a couple
of extra features. Get tack
BloodHoundData will automate the
gathering of PowerView data on a
domain. By default it will only
gather the data on the current
domain, but it will get the
trust group memberships and all
the things that we talked about.
There's a lot of different
targeting options. If you want
to use Stealth, there's dash
stealth and things like that.
You then take that function and
you pipe it to one of two export
functions. Export-BloodHoundData
will export all those custom
objects, um, package them up
with cypher queries for Neo4j
which is what it uses on the
backend and then shuttle
everything off to the Neo4j
batch RESTful API ingestion
interface. So if the collection
machine can breach the analysis
machine, whether on the same
domain or through something like
a reverse port forward, which we
have done in the field and it
does work, then you can just
shoot the stuff straight into
Neo4j and then BloodHound
without touching disk. If you
can't reach the analysis server
for some reason, you can pipe
that Get tack BloodHound data to
export BloodHound CSV, which
will take all the same, all the
same custom objects and export
them into a 3 or 4 different
kind of custom CSV file, we have
a particular format which we've
documented. The CSV files can
then be ingested offline into
the BloodHound analysis
interface. Ok, now Rohan's gonna
go through a live demo for
BloodHound. >> Alright, so
uh-oh. I'm not I'm not trying to
hide it from you, I promise.
Gonna mirror the screen.
Alright, perfect. So when you
first fire up the BloodHound UI,
you're presented with one of our
favorite views, which is what
are the domain admins inside the
environment you're in and who
are the members of these do-
these groups. Generally
speaking, when we're in in, uh,
assessment we tend to target
domain admins a lot as we talked
about earlier. Uh, they pretty
much have keys to the kingdom
and usually whatever target
we're going after, one of them's
going to be able to get to it.
Any node that is in the
environment can be autocompleted
using the search bar up here. So
it'll help you find stuff you
need. We're going to actually
start with a user. Any user you
click on is going to present you
with a bunch of information
about that user here. So the
first thing we can see is first
degree membership. These are all
the groups that a user is part
of by default. The next thing
you can see is unrolled group
membership. Now a lot of times
this is actually kind of a pain
to enumerate properly.
Especially when groups get
really really nested like the
one you see here. The next thing
we can look at is group
delegated admin rights. If this
user was added to the local
admins of any machine
explicitly, that would be here.
But because we're not, we're
just gonna look here. This is
every single system that this
user has access to based on
their group membership. Now to
keep the graph a little bit more
readable, we do a lot of
collapsing of nodes, so if you
can see there's an 87 next to
domain admins node here. Slow
down alright. There are 87 other
computers [laughter]. I can't
slow down sorry. There are 87
computers that are folded into
the domain admins group. Now if
we displayed all these, the
graph, as it gets bigger and
bigger, takes longer and longer
to lay out. So this is more a
performance thing. Any node that
is collapsed in you can actually
expand by right clicking on it
and hitting expand. Which I'm
not going to do, 'cause it will
totally break graph. So in this
in this, uh, one more thing you
can look at is derivative local
admin rights, which is what we
were talking about earlier. Now
this graph here is showing from
our user, any path that this
user can take to get to any
other computer in the
environment, whether it's
through group membership,
through local admin rights or
sessions of users that are
logged into computers which you
have admin rights to. Now
navigating this graph can be a
little difficult and there's a
lot of nodes here, so we
introduce the feature called
Spot Light. Using Spot Light,
you can search the gra- the
graph you're currently on for
any nodes. So we're going to
look for this research group
here. Whenever you click on the
Spot Light it'll zoom in on the
nodes so you know where it is on
the graph and it'll pull up all
the information on the left so
you can start interacting with
it. Move it around, here you go.
So there you go. It's the node.
Ooooo. You can ask BloodHound to
give you who the direct members
of any group are, you can see
there are 4 more that are folded
here. You can expand this and
you'll see that these are users.
Next thing you can ask
BloodHound to give you is the
unrolled group members of the
group. As groups start getting
nested, it becomes more and more
difficult to find, uh, who the
real members are. So BloodHound
makes it really easy to do that.
You can also ask BloodHound what
direct administration rights a
group has. So we expand this,
you can see there's 28 different
computers that this group has
direct admin to. Just like with
a user, you can calculate
derivative local admin rights.
Uh, it'll use wherever you start
and it will try any path it can
find to any other node in the
domain. Another really handy
feature we have is sessions. Uh,
using this, you can ask
BloodHound to tell you where
every single user that is a part
of either the group or subgroups
is logged in. A lot of times
when you're on an assessment,
you know that there's a specific
group that users belong to and
that group is where you're can
targeting your crown jewels.
Let's say it's an HR group and
you're trying to access their
information. With BloodHound you
can ask, where are all the HR
members logged in? And it it'll
give you every single computer
that it has a session for. Now
on this group we're going to
find ourselves a computer, uh
SQL 2. We'll pretend like this
is something cool here. You can
ask BloodHound who the explicit
admins for a computer are. These
are first degree admins, so if
you run NET Local Group
Administrator on a system, this
is the output you'd get. You can
also unroll the admins on a
computer. In this particular
case, there are 6 groups that
have local admin in the system,
however, once you unroll it, it
becomes 51 users with
administrative rights. As Active
Directory demands expand and
they keep getting more and more
things inside of them. Groups
can get nested, uh, you can
easily lose track of who's admin
on a system, Because of nested
groups just continuing to
obscure what you're looking for.
>> One thing I would add to that
is this example is showing an
order of magnitude difference
between who is explicitly
defined as an admin on this
system versus who gains admin
rights through these nested
groups. And that kind of
difference in an order of
magnitude, we see as very very
common on almost every
assessment that we go into. >>
You can ask BloodHound to give
you the sessions for computer
you can ask who's logged onto
there. It's extra information
that's always handy. And just
like with a group or a user, you
can ask BloodHound to calculate
the derivative of local admin
rights. Provided you started
from that computer. Now getting
into one of the most powerful
features of BloodHound. We're
gonna talk about path finding.
BloodHound provides you the
ability to find the path between
any one node and any other node
provided that path exists in
your database. So just to give
give you guys an example to
start. We're gonna pick a user,
uh, J. Druin and we're gonna ask
BloodHound to take us to the
domain admin group. Now, watch,
go, walking through this path,
J. Druin is a member of a group
information technology.
Information Technology has local
admin rights to all these
systems here. Each one of those
systems has a user session for a
domain admin, so if you jumped
these systems and Mimikatz, you
would have password for a domain
admin. Now that's a, that's a
cool example, but let's let's
amp it up a little bit. We're
gonna take this user J. Nickel
at external dot local and we're
actually going to ask BloodHound
to take us to domain admins at
internal dot local. Now,
internal dot local and external
dot local are two different
domains in the same forest. So
if you follow this path, our
user is a member of a group,
which is a member of another
group. Which gets us admin
rights to several systems. We
can steal a session from one of
those systems and get a
different group membership. That
takes us to another system with
a user in external dot local,
however, the next hop, is in the
internal dot local domain.
Despite the fact that we're
dumping a trust boundary between
two two domains, BloodHound just
is using the data available to
it and it has no problem
enumerating these paths. No
matter how complicated the path
is, if the path exists
BloodHound will be able to
enumerate that path properly. >>
So one, one thing that I would
add to that, a common question
that we've been getting over the
past week, when we're probably
demoing BloodHound for the first
time, is with, uh, regard to
scalability. So we went into an
computers, Windows workstations
and servers. They had about
information manually is just not
possible. So they also had more
than 75 domains, I would say, in
a forest of varying degrees of
trust. With the Stealth option
that Will talked about with
ingestion it took about 20 to 30
minutes to collect all of the
information we needed from this
this global enterprise to
identify attack paths. Doing the
query with Neo4j in a graph
database is just as fast as what
you're seeing here. In that
environment I'm talking about
than 75 domains, BloodHound
found us an attach path to go
from this one smi- this tiny
little domain that was
relatively insecure to this very
high security domain where our
actual objective was across 6
domain trust boundaries, taking
advantage of users that had
relatively low privilege, like 4
machines that they were admins
on. But it just so happened that
one of those machines had a user
that gave us more more privilege
in the environment until we got
to what we needed. Uh, the
[applause] Thanks. [applause] >>
Thank you. Uh, one additional
thing that I would say is I
mentioned the Stealth option
took about 30 minutes, if you're
going to do non-Stealth and
you're actually touching each
system one time, that ingestion
takes between 24 and 36 hours.
For that level of environment -
just demonstrating some more
stuff that we've built in to
make this even easier to use for
everybody, we have several
pre-built queries that you can
access through the UI. Uh, there
are some really good ones here.
Like finding the user with the
most sessions. Let's go ahead
and identify which user is
logging way way way too much. In
this particular case, it's
Antivirus. Which is sort of OK,
but if I get that account, I'm
going to be pretty happy. You
can also find the computer with
the most sessions. This is
demonstrating things that tend
to be used a lot such as IT jump
boxes or terminal servers. These
are high value targets that if
you compromise them, you're very
likely you're gonna get a large
set of credentials. You can also
hit control here to show all the
node labels. Or you can hide
them all. Or you can just show
the default. Uh, these are just,
these are just display options
to help you whenever you're
showing these two other people.
Another thing that was added
very recently, and when I say
recently, I mean last night, was
the ability to query any user in
a domain of your choice and find
what foreign group relationships
they have in other domains.
Historically this has been a
very tedious and time consuming
task. So in this particular
case, query internal dot local
domain, we're given three users,
that are members of groups in
the external dot local domain.
Another query we can do and this
is one of our favorites, is find
shortest paths to domain admins.
When you click on this, you get
a selection, which domain admin
group do you want to use? So
let's say we wanted to use
internal dot local. What you're
seeing here on this graph is
every single possible path that
BloodHound can find to go from
any node in that domain up to
the domain admins group. Now
when we're talking about earlier
showing all the paths to your
client, this is what we're
talking about here. It's really
great, because you can look at
high value targets that if you
remediated would actually cut
off a lot of points, for
example, this node here you can
see has several connections out
to it. If you were to go and
lock down that computer, you
significantly reduce the attack
servers of that domain. Now, any
graph that you generate in
BloodHound can be exported
either to json or an image. Uh,
you can export it to json and
load that into other graph tools
or you can re-import it back
into BloodHound if you have some
particular graphs you like
saved. You can export it into an
image through that directly in
your out brief. It's great value
to show your clients. It looks
really, really cool and
everybody likes pretty pictures,
so. As Will was talking about
earlier, you can export all the
BloodHound data instead of
directly through the database,
through the CSV ingestion here.
When you click this, you can
just pop, give it a file, and,
uh, it'll ingest everything the
same way as if it was from the
PowerShell script itself. This
is great for a lot of
situations, where for whatever
reason, your hosts that you're
running your ingestion from
can't talk back to your
database. Let's say there's
really good firewall rules. Uh,
you can just download the CSVs
directly from the host and throw
them into the web interface and
you're good to go, just like
before. I think that's the whole
demo. [applause] >> Thank you.
So we have 10 minutes left, uh,
one thing that I would like to
briefly touch on that we skipped
is kind of the architecture of
BloodHound because there are
some very important other open
source projects that BloodHound
relies on. First of all
Linkurious.js is the open source
and free version of Linkurious.
If you are developing a web
front end like this, an
interface of B over J,
Linkurious is where you want to
go. It's built on top of sigma
so you have all these things
kind of abstracted away from you
that are otherwise kind of
difficult. If you're not a
JavaScript expert. Secondly,
it's compiled with electrons, so
it is cross platform. Uh and
then most importantly we rely on
Neo4j as our graph database. Uh
and then obviously it's fed by
the PowerShell ingest-or. So,
um, this is the part that
Rohan's been waiting for. >>
Alright, let's do, let's do
this. So we have here the, uh,
BloodHound Repository, which to
this moment has been private
and, uh, we're just gonna go
ahead and YOLO this right now.
[applause] Uh, oh, this is bad.
I'm gonna have to login to
GitHub. I just ruined
everything. Andy why didn't you
make me check this. It's ok.
This is why I use two factor,
right? >> Yeah, so while Rohan
is doing this, the license that
we are releasing this under is
GPLv3. >> No, I'm good. I'm not
afraid of these people. >> Uh,
once we get done with this
[laughter] Ok, here we go. >>
Alright and there we go.
[applause] It's public, I
promise. >> So we have a nice
easy link. Get your phone out,
take a picture. bit dot lee
forward slash get bloodhound,
uh, you can find me on Twitter,
again my name is Andy Robbins.
My handle on Twitter is at
underscore waldo with a zero.
Rohan, oh go back, sorry, sorry.
>> There you go. >> Alright, 10,
9, 8, 7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1. Get
it from your neighbor.
Socialize, professional network.
Meet somebody, please. My name
is Andy Robbins, you can find me
at underscore Waldo with a zero.
Rohan Vazarkar you can find him
on Twitter at Captain Jesus.
Will Schroeder, you're already
following him on Twitter at Harm
Joy with a zero. Thank you very
much. [applause] >> By the way,
we decided to be really nice to
you and we have pre-compiled
binaries for every OS and
architecture, so. [applause] >>
So I think we have 5 minutes for
questions and this gentleman is
first. Can you speak into the
mic, I don't know if it's on.
There you go, we're good. >> The
big one is you have Get-Session.
So it's. >> Get like, get right
in there, yeah, >> Big one is
you have Get-Session, so live
data, they have to be logged in
to see the path. >> Ok, Ok, so
his question was with user
session information. You got a
second question as well. >> Tied
into that, so you have current
sessions to do your jump. You
have your current session to do
your jump. Logged in users. What
about pass the hash of a local
admin hash to jump, does
BloodHound take that, or local
hash match to domain? Where you
can take matching hash and jump.
>> Ok, so his question is with
user session information. When
we're collecting user session
data, the user needs to have a
valid session that is, uh,
currently like, uh, with, uh a
domain controller or a file
share. Um, so you you may find
yourself re-collecting user
session information, uh,
frequently, because of the the
the, the nature of how that
works. Your second question was
with local accounts, with
RID500, with past the hash,
right now, we are only tracking
domain accounts. We are not
tracking local accounts at all,
uh, but we put that in, in the
future. >> Does it jump from
local up to domain with matching
hash? >> Oh, his, oh ok, so also
the question of like reused
passwords from like a local
admin that has a same password
or NTLM hash is a DA. We're also
not tracking that as well. Uh,
you should check out a project
called auto Dane from SensePost.
Uh, that may have what you're
looking for. Yeah, thank you.
Thank you for the question. >>
Hi, do you account for stuff
like, uh, LAPS being rolled out
into the environment. >> So, the
question was do we account for
LAPS being passed out, being
distributed through the
environment? Uh, that we also do
not account for, so any kind of
credential, uh, sharing, like in
systems or, uh, as a matter of
fact, a better answer to your
question, is this was born out
of a necessity to bypass laps
protections. Because we couldn't
pass the hash of a local admin
account, we had to rely on
domain user level accounts. >>
And I'll also say that, we have
a couple going forward we want
to integrate. One of those will
be Active Directory ACL
enumeration and auditing. So, it
will automatically in a few
months when we finish extending
the schema, we will ingest all
Active Directory ACLs into the
graph and everything will be
integrated. So you might be able
to tell, who has read access to
the password attribute for laps
and then integrate that into the
attack graph. >> Awesome thank
you. >> Thanks for the question.
Hey. >> Thanks guys, um, how are
you handling how this stuff
changes over time. Right, so the
date. >> Ok, so the question is
how do we handle this data as it
changes over time. Excellent
question. So we treat, uh, local
admin privileges and group
memberships as relatively static
information. But it doesn't
change that much day to day.
User session information, we
treat as relatively dynamic. So
in our Wiki, we provide guidance
on how you can re-ingest just
session information.
Additionally, we're planning on
adding temporal information to
the user session edges. So what
that means is if you're an
incident handler and you want to
go back and you say, we had an
initial breach on March 16th, I
can tell BloodHound, go back to
March 16th, tell me, from this
computer, to every other system
in the environment, based on the
currently logged on users that I
could get info for. Show me
what, from patient zero, what
was possible and so that I can
clearly define my investigate
scope. That brings me to another
point is that, um, from the
offensive side this is really
cool and we like it a lot.
What's really cool is the
defensive applications. And so
over the next six months to the
next year, uh, we're gonna be
focusing primarily, almost
exclusively on defensive
applications like that. Thanks.
>> So more and more often, the,
uh, people that I'm popping end
up using Macs, so while
obviously their computers aren't
joined at the domain, many times
they have valid LDAP
credentials, is there a way I
can use those valid LDAP
credentials with BloodHound
somehow. >> Uh, yes. Um, so in
our Wiki, we have a section
about data ingestion with other
tools. So, right now we're
talking with, uh, Bite Bleeder,
the author of Crack Map Exec,
uh, to get support for other
tools like that. So if you're in
OSx, if you're in Linux, you
want to collect information, you
don't want to be running in
PowerShell or running on
Windows, uh, we're planning on
getting that in there as well.
We have developer notes about
the CSV format and how to
actually get info into the neo
predict graph database. And
we're gonna have to leave in
just a second. Thanks for the
question. How much time do we
have? [applause] >> One more,
one more question. >> Great,
what are the top three things
you can use defense to help, you
would tell everybody to do. >>
So your question was, what are
the top three things, BloodHound
can do for defense? So I would
say that, uh, number one would
be mitigating the attack baths
that rely on derivative local
admin. So in the Microsoft white
paper, they, the product that
they're describing, the MSRC
developed is called Heat Ray.
They use graph theory and they
also use machine learning to
give an IT admin a list of like,
here are the ten changes that
you can make in the environment
that will most efficiently
eliminate the largest number of
attack paths, based on
credential abuse. Uh, secondly,
I would say, one of the major
benefits is a more clear and
easy understanding of the nested
group memberships and how those
relate to to local administrator
privileges. Uh and then number
three, let's let's talk offline.
We have to go, thank you again.
[applause]