so welcome ss proxy is a tool and
at the same time it tells a bit
what is the story of an activity I
carried out during my work because
unlike alessandro and if
you search my name on google you will find
only bad things then me  I introduce myself
very briefly my name is lorenzo as I
am a security consultant I work in mind
security and let's say what we do is
basically break web applications
and break devices help do some hackers
obviously in a positive sense because then
we report the vulnerabilities the producers
and so on are also a  lover of
python and automation
everything that is boring to do I
try to harlow script or to
make it automatic and this is one of
those cases in short this talk is born a
bit from this need
basically here this is a bit like
the  I think I always start with the idea of
starting to say I do a good project but
then it always ends up in collagen stack
overflow in short, it is a  a bit of a story,
however, because I am here first of
all to talk to you about how to
intercept the http traffic that is
generated by what can be a
device on which we cannot
explicitly configure a proxy you
know that on devices such as our
phones they are quite intelligent
so if I tell him you see that this is the
proxy from which you have to pass
your traffic there he says ok he passes all
the traffic from there and if I am an
attacker and I can intercept him
I read everything you do send
etc. with the  your phone this is
a technique to do a little to realize
this interception will be able to
get in the way between device is
what is internet or what is lost with
which the device wants to communicate
without precisely that this device has a
setting to do this all then
it is developed with the tool I wrote
that automates the various steps of this
technique
so basically the problem is
this
an activity arrives in the office and tells me
ok this is a device you have to do a penta
on this device it communicates in http
very well then I look at it I turn it on
and say ok but where is the proxy to
intercept
eh no there is no how not c  'it is and this is
my face it is a problem because we
are blind
we do not know that device with what it
communicates and how it communicates is a problem and
we must solve it I anticipate that
there is no definitive solution that is
there is no solution  for each case,
however, there is a technique
called invisible pro xing which
allows us to succeed under
certain circumstances in certain cases
to intercept the traffic of a
device
the technique is well described by an
article that was created by post
swiger are  the authors of the toolbar
how many have already heard of
barp ok for those who have never heard of it
imagine a software a proxy
to which we can direct the
http traffic of a device  ivo of
our browser of anything you talk about
in http and this allows us to
analyze it to see it lieder to see
it rl to intercept it so to
stop it before it goes to the final server
to modify it and a whole series of
operations that of operations that in the
field of  caen testing web fantastic
application are on the agenda
so we have this technique how we
implement it how we develop it
first of all we need a setup we need
a mini laboratory as I told you before
we have a device and then we have a
computer the attacker's computer from
which we create a hotspot in this case
let's say for example a wifi hotspot
suppose that our device is
that I know a tablet or a phone ok that
has a wifi device wifi connectivity
for which we create a hotspot we hook
our device this hotspot in
this way the  our computer becomes
the gateway for that device
also becomes the dns provider
so all the traffi  co of the device
will inevitably pass from our pc
so step number one after which on the
same pc we install boats to
our next now what
we can not do is to tell the device
to go directly to talk with
beard what we want to do
we want the device to talk to
bar
with burt we can analyze the
traffic and then we send
it back to the internet correctly
returns the answer from the internet
we send it back to our
device everything comes back
we have the traffic we are happy now if
a device as I said
before does not have this
proxy setting we do not  we can send it to
beard directly but what can we
do then first of all as I told you
all the traffic of the device passes from
my pc including its dns requests the
dns basically what it allows us to
do allows us to know which domain
the device is contacting i.e. which is
the enpa in the final which ours with which
with which our device wants
to talk and we
can see this thing we can intercept the
dns requests are in clear obviously
so we know exactly when
we run an application on a device
that can be for example android is a
tablet
etc.  domain is going to
contact this is the first point to
understand who our device wants to talk to
second point to be able to redirect
its traffic
we must make sure to create a
sort of virtual interface on our
computer in which we are going to map
what the domain is  that our
device wants to go and contact at the
end of all this round we must
also create what is a proxy
lissner inside a bar with
a tool inside our
software to intercept that says I
replace myself I listen to the
'current management interface and I
wait for the device to contact me in
such a way as to steal the traffic from it
quite elaborate and complex let's
go down a little bit in the
technical detail of how
these things are done the various steps then
number one intercept what are
the dns requests the classic tour in
very simple dump types a very
quiet command line
for which I specify the wlan 0  which is
the interface on which I created the
commercial then I tell it as a filter you see that
you have to keep only blue dp and the
requests that go on port 53
because it is the one with which the dns
usually speaks and more to filter
even better the  I give what is
the IP address of my
device which in this case is 10 42 02 28
and specifically I did a test
all those you see are the domains
that have been contacted by the device
there are many things from google because  it was
a device in question is an
android phone among which there is let's say the
target our domain of interest
for which we would like to intercept the
traffic I put it in fat  tto and the corriere.it
so our purpose of the attackers queue
as a tester is to intercept the
traffic that starts from the device and goes
to the corriere.it step number one of
our we know that the device calls the
courier very well step number 2 create
a  virtual interface
even here a simple command with if
config I can create a
virtual interface on a very simple physical
and assigns it an arbitrary ip address
100 100 101 very simple the conflict
among other things has been deprecated
lately but you can use the
same pip  what is easy the same third step
I have to know however that who is corriere.it
what is his ip address before
going to change the areas direct it
so I do a look up of that
domain
and I discover that corriere.it has a
public ip address  and 151 101 etc.
this I then need to get back to
look at the request in the
correct way and then expect an answer at
this point I modify my ethics file
os that p  For those who do not know the file
that deals with resolving names
assigns
an address to a domain name and here said in
simple terms and therefore here in my
specific case I assign
the ip address 100 100 101 to the domain
www.corriere  .it
at this point what happens before
talking about how to configure barp
we stay here and what happens when
the device when the device asks
again which ip address to corriere.it
my computer from which all the traffic passes will
reply bell ip address and
100 100 101
we are ready to configure our bar
so we add a new lissner
we reach it on port at 443
this is because I expect
the connection to be in https then
encrypted and therefore typically
ends up on that port and then I tell it
rightly so that the ip address on which it
must listen and the 100 100
101 below at the bottom right you will
also find the re direct therefore the real ip address
which barp must forward  the
communication
at this point we made it
that is our device makes requests
and through the bar I can intercept them
great victory
ok but what is the problem that this
thing does not scale that is in the sense I
have shown you many hand-made steps
goes  good to do them by hand when we have a
domain
two domains but when we have 40 that
is a bit long it is a bit boring and hence
the idea of automating automated with
a simple tool written in python
python and beige is a few things like this
and such  its characteristics are
obviously to keep an eye on the
resolutions of our device then the
part of tissi p dame that we saw
before
automatically create an interface for
each domain that is
logged by from the domain monitor
print information on how to configure
our proxy in the bar and then two
slightly more particular features that are an
interactive mode that allows us to
choose which domain to intercept
which not
this comes in handy it came in handy
let's say when of the entire device
I wanted to intercept only particular
domains
you think of a phone I want to work
only on an application I don't need to
intercept all the communications that
phone but I want to intercept only
those of those applications
so this mode  it allows me to
say this domain on this other no
finally the possibility of making a backup
is a restore of the configuration
so that if I close the pc at
six in the evening and I leave the office the
next day and return I can withdraw
standing all this ambaradan without the
slightest effort without having to
intercept everything a small
demo of this tool to make you understand
the automation
ok then here you see the spot
I have created a hot spot called
samaritan that is a nandroid a
phone of
course  this phone to
proxy functionality, however, now I
will show you that I have a disability or
imposed as prox  y the nothing
here I put a not so at this
moment I am saying to the device go
quietly to the internet without going
through any proxy I start my tool as
parameters I give it the wlan on which
the spot is currently lit
the ip address of the  device is the
minus mode also allows me to tell the day
to the domain I want to intercept
the example is always that of the courier
for which I am now going to
request the courier's site from
the device the request for ns has started together with the
others
to me  interested only courier so I
start saying no no even google
courier yes I want to intercept very well
the tool is now printing me the
information I need to
configure my proxy so now
if this you can also understand how many
domains are contacted and from an
android phone  as soon
as I have a browser I am not interested in all this I am
only interested in the courier so I am going to
configure port 443 I am going to
configure the interface c  as
the tour tells me the real alps redirect ok all the
various parameters here I also set the
certificate the certified name the same
this is one thing is not mandatory
but some domains and they go crazy for
which every now and then goes to mass every now
and then no and so now refresh went  I am able to
intercept the traffic
I am praying the device I have
placed myself between him and the courier I am able to
intercept him I can modify the
traffic I am able to do all my
analyzes that I will want to do
and this having seen all the steps above
this my tour practically does them
automatically  basically ok ssl I
heard a word sls l then this
tool is not the godsend then there
are conditions before I was talking about
preconditions for the stars the
condition obviously that on the device there
is installed a custom certificate which
is that of bar obviously a '  another
of the conditions that if the device does not
use the dns but goes directly to the p we are
screwed the same if I arc given an ip I
cannot  use the dna while if we are in the
condition of ns no https or I
can install a certificate this
technique works
before closing I leave you with
ideas
a bard extension to automate
even the last step that is the creation
of the proxy
I do not have the most  pale idea because I have not
had time to find out whether or not there is
an ep ai that allows you to do so, however it
could be an excellent
future development dns poisoning it could be
an idea or instead of making the
change on my local computer I can
coexist directly  the answer never
paiola majles felt squat could be
integrated yes yes yes
when now the same l ok my
solved before if you do not have a cia
installed inside the device the asl does not
work and the other question instead was if
you know pyol then you start I heard
speak not the details but yes that is
the idea that I have also thought of something
with the library scape scraping
python schemes for which to do something right
all in python and on the fly so logo and
then edit on the fly is an idea
unfortunately I don't have much time so ok and
the other idea is python 3 because
currently your impact still two but
unfortunately it will die poor thing and
sorry and therefore  the idea was to bring the
whole python 3 and then obviously
this idea is more than good accept
the tool and sauces tab you can download it
you can do what you want it's free
I hope it can be of help to
someone someone who maybe does my
job  to someone who wants to try
this technique who may not have
known it before wants to try to put it
into practice
to me it has solved many problems
especially when
random devices arrive at work and they tell us tested there
so if there are no questions I
thank you
[Applause  ]