one evening then my name is fernando
i am a researcher in the field of
cryptography and i am here to talk about
sight going a bit as it means
cryptographic standards that should
be resistant to attacks carried out
with quantum computers lover there is the
following and this we say l  'the only
really important part maybe we talked about
quantum computers in the past and
now we started talking about
cryptographic standards the united states government
through nist has decided that the
time to standardize to have
software that protocols that are
considered safe and  these
protocols in the next 20 years
will become part of bpm's ssh tls and
any other type of library that
uses cryptography and
since in fact the United States government
decides the encryption that everything more or
less all the  rest of the world uses it is
very important that these standards
are scrutinized before they are
defined  completely and also that
benchmarks are made because it is not certain
that a new standard is good for everyone
possible that there are problems downstream it
would be better to discover them when
the standard is not yet fully defined and
when changes can still be proposed
to make  a bit of a summary a
point of the
situation we talk about
public key cryptography is what allows for
example to communicate in a
confidential manner to authenticate other parts
in order to be sure of who you
are with whom you are talking to and until
now the  problems that existed from the point
of view of security could be
how these standards were used
how these tools were
used how keys were
distributed then how public
key infrastructure was done
or they could have to deal with
concrete problems an implementation with a bug
or with wrong parameters the keys
were too short and therefore the scheme
was not safe there
public key cryptography was discovered in 1976 and
various ways to build it have been proposed since then
but the ones that are actually part
of the code that are
actually used are based
on the difficulty of three mathematical problems
one is called rsa perhaps the best known and  then
there are problems of the
discrete logarithm problems on something
called finite field or on
something else called
elliptic curve and it doesn't matter why they
are how they work why they are
difficult or they are not
with respect to the concept of difficult yes
talks about the fact that if a key
n bits long and the number of operations
required to say to attack
this this scheme to solve
this problem should be
exponential in a number of bits
so that very short keys
allow us to bind an attacker
to  a lot of time
possibly more time than I
have available in 94 and later  97
shore introduces an algorithm that
should make the
discrete logarithm problem rsa problems
easy to solve and yet there is a
caveat there is a problem this algorithm
requires a quantum computer and
quantum computers if we talk about it re-entry
after  the idea was introduced by feynman it is
supposed or made a joke from
some point we do not actually know
who was the first to have this
idea
but in short, if we talk about it it is as if they
will arrive in twenty years but we talk about it
like this  for at least 20 years and therefore there has
been some skepticism for a long time
regarding the feasibility of such a
quantum computer and therefore also
of the need to overcome the
encryption based on arezzo on the
discrete logarithm but in the last
ten years
google has decided  to invest some
money
ibm has decided to invest some money
they also have a small one with two
quantum computers available online for
free if you want to
experiment with it  institutions and then microsoft has decided to
invest a lot of money and
clearly they also all went to
the same web designer for the site
on the computer on quantum computers
but it is possible that by then
their attention is well motivated maybe
now there will finally be really  that
acceleration with respect to which we should
worry the question and we should
worry is already now we should
worry neither between 30 40 to 100 years
when they will actually be built
de michele mosca who is one of the
best known experts in computing
speaks of his supposed theorem that
says well let's imagine it takes y
years to get to implement this
secure encryption against as many
computers as one computer and then
we generate some keys and use them to
encrypt a secret that must live i
would stay the secret for at least
hicks years and hicks it depends on what
we are  hiding if we are hiding
or if we are signing a certificate  that
is to last for the next six months
hicks might be six months but if
we're trying to protect a state secret
that is to last a hundred years it might
be 100 years if z the number of times
years they'll try to
build a computer and  z and
less than xp y then in case of
concern
one could add to this the fact
that if today we have a secret that
should be safe for a hundred years
and today we do not have as safe standards
as a computer and if an
opponent could access the
our cypher text and to put it away for
50 years until it builds as
a computer even if we can
later when we have a poor standard's
how much arinc delay will already be too
late because the opponent will still be able to
attack the old cipher that he
managed to find  for example the
old network traffic that has
captured the boss field at some point in the past
as much as
two-prior cryptography  in this moment one is to
build entry factories for which
data can be encrypted and in a more or
less equivalent way to exchange for
whom to agree on a key to be
used to encrypt and then
digital signatures and certificates and for the rest
of the  top I will talk about piquet and stieg
to refer to in both these two
types of technologies without having to write
the name in full by the way we
also know that there is something that
private key cryptography and indeed
often public key cryptography
is used with that private key
a public key cipher a
very short key which then uses a
private key sends the encrypted private key to the
other party and then uses the
key asymmetric encryption or the
private key because faster to
send terabytes of data or what we
are talking about is  here are let's say two
standard 1 standardized by liszt as and
then there is a de facto standard used
everywhere on the internet that  to this these
algorithms do not seem to be
particularly affected by how many
speed ups exist in computers and they can be
attacked faster but
not dramatically so there
is currently no particular
concern with respect to these schemes
but it is really possible that all  the
cryptography built up to 94 is
completely broken
no in fact there were schemes
proposed since the 70s that are
still safe for pique we can speak
for example of but that the stands and the
writer are two schemes that use
codes for correction  of errors and which
seems not to be attacked by by schemes
since a computer can be spoken of
ntro that a scheme of the nineties
for which we say built at the time
when sean discovered he discovered his
algorithm and then for the signatures there are
signatures  and based on this tris market and
these are not broken but are much
slower or more difficult to use,
for example signatures require  or
maintain that the state is maintained between one
signature and the other for this reason it is much more
difficult trans days actually
required this 20 years ago now
it is no longer the case but at the time they
were not standardized and for this reason
and but that there  if they require
public keys of several megabytes from the writer and
therefore or at least in their
original formulation for which even there they have been
ignored
but some areas are quite recent
some standards of anxiety of
tripoli exist but have not
been adopted en masse  or they are
very recent
this the only slide with jargon and this
i are the new candidate names to
replace the discrete logarithm will remain
we have candidates to be sure against
what a computer built before
those I mentioned but also there
if the writer with the  heroes correcting
code or those at les cayes bay
signatures and then there are those posts
like ntro
which is now often called a
problem ba  if of lattices and then there are
other multi-various problems with
hicks squares where we certainly use
second degree equations on many variables or
problems on elliptic curves but on
sogemes and of which 2 liters which super
singular these are all men
so there is no  it is one called picnic
for example it is nothing these are names
that we started looking for
about this algorithm of this problem
you might find so it seemed
interesting to let them live now the
timeline of what is happening with respect
to this standardization for  understand
who I am waiting for in this process because it
started a couple of years ago and at the
end I would also like to talk about how I think
the research community more generally not
necessarily can
contribute in a decisive way
to this type of
standardization
process.  2016 in reality this
research has been done for twenty years but in 2016
google does the first encryption tests
post as much as that  llo who do and
implement in boring ssl a scheme
called mine or those based on
lattices to do key exchange and
decide to first do a
traditional elliptic curve key exchange
of those we know to be safe
at least until now and then yes  do a
parallel swap using each pop
join the two keys merge xor and
then use that final key as
a shared key the reason why they
did this experiment which was
only enabled on google canary and from
what I remember only on services
google and to see how much
the network is slowed down by having to do an
exchange with coop for micov's hypertext keys
are several times longer than
cypher texas elliptic curves and therefore
it is not clear that it is so easy to
immediately manage the load of extra
data the load  of computation but
also
of communication then in 2016 the nsa makes
an indirect suggestion to the
united states government about the fact
that perhaps it is time to talk about pos
as an indirect crypto because he has
defined them as a set of
cryptographic algorithms which is called cypher sui b
i.e. safer singh there are
public key algorithms which are suggested as
they are considered safe from the beginning and  in
a status update made to the government a they
start talking about the fact that if
some of these companies have not
yet migrated their systems from rsa to
elliptical curves which are the latest
addition to the us air force b maybe it is not the
case that they  they spend all
that energy to do it because they
should already start worrying
instead about migrating directly
to imposed schemes what they leave it to the
institute for science technology they
decide to make a call for proposals
they decide to open and carry out a
standardization process  open as it was done
in 99 for example
in 2006 for others to open the
cryptographic community do not develop it
in secret this this work and ve
what are possible candidates
as much as anyone who has had the opportunity to
send proposals from any
country in the world
the conditions are that it must have must
be there must be a
formal specification and must have a
security analysis on why that algorithm is believed to
be  as safe as
a computer reference code in
standard c 99 that must compile
quietly on linux windows macos
possibly the code optimized
for 64 bit cpu
dt type intel asus and beckton test because
very difficult when one builds
cryptographic corners key since
the car  by necessity it must
have a random aspect it is very difficult
once encrypted what it would say but
that is the correct encryption
exactly as my algorithm
specifies for which it is asked that whoever
top who sends an algorithm
also proposes test vectors so that whoever
presents  can verify that their
correct implementation is something that
I forgot to add this slide
that asked that or specified
that whoever will win this competition
that they do not call competition and do not
call the winners winners but
call selected candidates will have to
issue any type of patent
on their algorithm so that anyone
is free  to implement it test it
study it and use it in industry
without being afraid of
legal repercussions they have also organized a
mailing list that you can see on google
groups to which you can subscribe
freely you can also send
messages safely to update
but also because so the community
cryptographic you can be notified if
attacks or new
implementations come out or if you have any
questions to ask in 2017 and towards the end of
the deadline for proposals arrives and
82 proposals have been sent 69 have
been accepted by nist the others did not
satisfy the  requirements and 49 are for
encryption and the other 20 s  o for
digital signatures and they start a first round
of this standardization process
and they released this a few
weeks before christmas so there were
those who wanted to go on vacation but be
open to the hunt for
more or less safe schemes and some have been
immediately found because perhaps
not sent by academics with a
sufficient background to do this
type of work in 2017 mixed also
suggests a possible timeline it is
thought that starting December 2017
it is thought that in 2019
then it happened January a
second round of  standardization that
there will be a third possible round between
2020 and 2021 and that they possibly
want to have drafts for the
selected standards between 2022 and 2024
for which a 7-year process that will then
require adoption by
industry that usually lasts about twenty days
'years at least in 2018 in April they
did a workshop where all the candidates
who were still running were
inv  itati to go present their
scooter algorithm in their
properties and there were also there
was also an invited tokyo who
instead talked about work without
relative these algorithms without having it
without having sent one in particular
in 2019 the second was announced
round has reduced the cryptographic algorithms from 49 to 17
and from 20 to 9
those for digital signatures and sinis has
required to start working on
hot and rennes pj implementation of
these of these algorithms to see
from the bad point of view how performing they are
or what are the
possible problems of how much ram memory
a you need on a smart card to
make one of these algorithms work for
example klauser together with google have
also launched a large scale head
inspired by that of new co where they
took google channels and  they implemented
others another broader set
of candidate algorithms and they took
they asked claut fair to
implemen  borers the year added boring
ssl asked klaus where did chloe
hurley on their servers so they could
take stats like what is the
average load on servers but also what is
the one percent heavier load
on a server  how much
this can really slow down can slow down a
server and it is curious for example that one
of the schemes that curves
to its genes and between elliptical curves is
known to be the slowest scheme
ever or maybe it is not absolute but one
of the slowest schemes and google
asked please do not enable that
scheme on our domains because they
could be used for a denial of
service against our servers there was
a second workshop in August again at
nis where the
schemes and algorithms still remaining in the
race presented the
eni updates  there is also a suggestion he
said maybe at the end of this second
round which should take place according to them
between 2020 and 2021
maybe we can already sel  select
candidates for example candidates based
on but that the stands and the writer have existed
since the 70s they consider themselves safe since
the 70s so perhaps the case they are
mature has enough maybe they are not the
fastest
but if someone in urgency immediately to
pass  to algorithms pos how much the
possibility to do it at first
with slower algorithms and then to
replace them as the others
are implemented however they feel
they have to do a third round as
regards to contribute to this process it
is possible to use these algorithms
and  doing experiments you are in theory 1
when you have on the nis website download
the reference code of the
optimized code and compile it not all
my files are beautiful to read and
you can do experiments but it is a bit
difficult so there is a project
called open quantum  safe haven when it
makes sense in a library
if I remember mainly
licensed with that it collects  many
of these algorithms to a song a brunch
in particular which is called ninis
brunch where they loaded in
particular the exact versions sent to
miss that unifies the feet all these
schemes in order to make it more
accessible
provide rappers in c insisite initial
splash in python  and lingo a couple
of function for test bench marking to
measure statistics and then integrate
this harmless library into the same attain
open ssl so that if any of
the private servers or a
private infrastructure is able to
replace their own implementation of the
same works  l with this with this
out to test what happens if a
1 1 replacement flaw between the
present standards and possible
future standards microsoft also
fork pn works is at all the same type
of replacement so you can
verify the load on the
different protocol than the wider community
that doesn't necessarily
use one of those  three libraries,
however, you can do an
important job because the problem is that
these algorithms, while for example from
rsa elliptic curves we have passed,
the dimensions of the
ciphers have improved and the execution times have improved
and then move on to what does not
improve both
indeed in general  the algorithms may
be some are faster but in
general they are all much larger as
you know santech it goes from 64
gbyte to 2 kg by for example and therefore it
is not necessarily all the
libraries that are now present in the
industry also in  private settings are
flexible enough to
withstand this change for
example maybe the library the protocol
in general yes but somewhere there is a
buffer span of 128 bytes and there
the encryption must be only the
public key must be and these are  things that
you can only know who works with
these libraries and therefore it is very
interesting that
these queues exist  these free open implementations
so that you can try to
make these replacements already to see if
in the business environment this could
work or not or if there are
problems also because
cryptography is used everywhere so
it is not clear at the table especially from
the academic world where
all possible problems could succeed in a barrel line
and therefore it is interesting that those who
are in the industry can start doing
these things that maybe it turns out a
non-obvious problem but not an email
to the mailing list finally if someone
decides to do experiments they think  of
having discovered something interesting you
can obviously also publish this
work the principles are to send them to jesi
are a jesi arel
international association for cryptographic research
and they manage something
similar to ark and math
where most of the works on
cryptography there are workshops and
conferences at which you can publish  icare
and that they are more reviewed than christ is
the main one for a crypto there
are the workshops of nis but then there are
practically all the conferences now
give they are they manage they have to do
with pos quantum cryptography and if there
are any problems or questions  or results
of experiments that you do not have the time or
the desire to put together
collect a paper you can also
always write an email to the mailing
list or put the results on the site and
share it like
this all I had to say
thank you very much
[  Applause]