I wanted to make a presentation
in the usual way come to
present my research projects
come present my things on
virtual network machines
instead today I want to take you to see
what are the tools I
use daily in my lessons I
bring them to  inside the lesson of the
operating systems of the university of
bologna and let's start from this toy
here
this toy had made it
in the context of rusty boa to play with
pixels I brought it together I took it to the
maker faire loved it attracts
so much attention and among other things I
don't know if you noticed it was written if you
connect to peace play with your
mobile phone using telegram you can
send messages in real time or
write any text will appear here as
soon as you see that  many
are playing when I saw this
thing and I said well if there are any things of
interest let's
bring it to the classroom because that's
what a do is  cente has to do is try to
attract the interest of the students
then I took him in a course project
of virtual systems a
complementary course where o I start from the years
10 18 students and what happened
what is happening now that everyone was
thinking about display  and they no longer thought
about let's say the lesson to the activity
for which it attracted a lot then I said
but we must not throw it away and the idea
the problem is that
for some psychological reason the LEDs
so flashing all the things that
move maybe it will be ours
animal instinct make sure that it gets
our attention too much
and then what did it do
I inserted a bot but done it in a different way
within the classroom equipment
what you see here is not
the image shown but an image of
a  virtual machine that is
working in bologna and this is a
tool that they have been
in the course for many years as I use it I have
discovered that I hate the lights of those stories
more  splash because because one of the
problems I have is that students
are normally passive they would like to land
knowledge or not they
are there getting back is good and now and
very often transparencies make
the student think that that is the
subject to study would be like trying
to understand the work by looking at
the beginning of the booklet the characters and interpreters
that is usually only in transparency it is only
a presentation of the boss s therefore
normally I do orem lesson in the
classroom as they did just once
with the pizzino with the sheet of
topics to play or I put it on
a shared editor and the notes
are generated
and here it is this is found on the top
of the municipality a machine you want to connect
as you wrote on the display
you can connect is upset and change
with me the notes that are on the
screen is of  usually while I speak
the notes
the students continue to take
notes and they see it both on the display and
on the browser man
the other c  dare that there is that some time ago but
let's also stream audio but
actually I believe in the frontal lesson
here is this site you can find it with a
browser look for renzo davoli live that
makes sure that all the screen I have here
here now it does the camera effect one
inside the other but you can have the large
copies of the screen on the mobile phone
on the laptop
this is useful yes because it is in the last
rows it is difficult to take the blackboard but it
is very useful also because if there is
we have built together a program
that interests you and one wants to take it
to study it later
just take the snap shot of the image and
keep it in the clipboard so there is this
tool that other or all
in the bottom right corner or mot
this time  if you want to call if
you want to try them you can connect ar
of 235 bots
and what is what you write
will appear there when I said it around
colleagues friends told me but what are
you doing very dangerous because it knows what
I am writing to you  no on that on that blackboard
it is not true it is not true because
beyond someone who has a
level of maturity and does these things
once it is clear that we are not in
elementary school a dirty word a shot from
bristles no one
at that point the situation  stable yes and
the students understand and participate in
this new method of teaching
what changes having this compared to
the normal interaction changes that the one
is anonymous
the student is afraid to raise his hand to
say I don't understand instead he can write
it is not clear  because he has done this what
happens he is afraid of both the judgment of the
teacher but also of the judgment of
his colleagues there can also be
jokes if you can also have the tone and
then asynchronous because there is always the fear
of interrupting the flow of speech
during the  lesson while instead
the questions accumulate and phillies that the
speech I turn around I see the questions that
have emerged in the meantime and you can
answer by doing what you get
Another benefit is the cell phone enemy
of the lesson because it is used to do
other activities it becomes a tool for
action there was a saying that said
rather than fight it allies and
better ally with these tools is to
make sure that they become tools to be
used.  so the lesson
by doing so becomes a story a
shared construction and it is possible to
follow the flow of the
needs of the students' requests not only
but you make me appear someone will take
the 235 era of 235 bots and write me
something
one says is small if you want it
we have projectors as big as something
perfect except for another
factor a student has to participate
in the lesson it is the best thing is that
they do exercises how to
mentally say exercises on
their own preparation which I know
creates challenges to say but this thing that
we have explained then  this thing is
so and so who votes what they
could  do as public voting by
saying raise your hand who starts that
this thing implemented at
kernel level others your hand too there
would be the fear of saying enough here I
got the answer
normally what happens excel
as the scholar and front row nerd say
to  home the hand all the others
are good and quiet for fear well
integrated inside the vote
there is also a rotation device if
now you know
we find it to do a test
you have to do a bot bar is empty then
half answer bot bar  yes the other
half bar got no
ok if by chance you made a mistake and you want
to vote again if you do another bar vote yes
how to get them give they do not keep track
of ideas but I need you to make
sure that if one cannot notice
twice if one  once twice the second
time cancel your first vote you
change your mind
ok at some point someone
rude me slash qaunto 1 or usually
I do it by doing next to those
results i cont  ii results yes two yes
one it is seen that a written one allows
a hundred assistance if it were a
different house or house
at that point this serves to increase
the discussion and in the meantime see to
self-evaluate to see if the concept is
past or there are
misunderstandings so you see that
such a trivial tool i'm 50 60 line of
python code ago has
really a lot effects like saying useful
inside a lesson because i
came to mind these votes
because one day i went to a
rector's meeting at my
university and with great fanfare  they
announced that in the stand of the in
a historic classroom of the university he
set up a so-called system of
feelings analysis were given to
all present by the remote controls with
keys numbered from 1 to 10
a slide was projected on which there was
written, for example, questions like
does he know what the most important concept is
that why you feel important
in the university didactics research it  a
third issue is one will have to push the
button as a teleshopping
and this thing costs tens of
thousands of euros and costs a lot of
maintenance because there are batteries
break the remote controls this thing
able to do the same at no cost
because  it is in fact use
of telegraph infrastructures and / or a python program
so when the new course starts from tomorrow
I hope it goes well as
last year every year is a
new and a new path every every
class of the student
I am afraid in the first lesson  of each
academic year last year this way of working
also in the evaluation of the
teaching activity was very positive it was
very positive it was taken very
positively by the students
maybe one ok obviously
the bot code is [ __ ] but it is
available on mine  black inside
toads and bon I published it yesterday the
rest of the structure I'd like to
publish it is just a problem of time
this too me  ccanism for this
mechanism to broadcast the
video is not that all of you if you
connect to see this this the
live page connect here because if
I should have a lot of bandwidth to my
laptop there is a reflector in the university
that takes the unc stream and  send it to
everyone who is tuned in there
would also be a chance to
allow some student to get
into writing so use so I can
say at some point you keep
doing this program and we discuss it
together and in the end I don't know if you have
tried it  the mechanism to watch the
vnc flow is a wine client there is written
in javascript blind side and therefore in addition
to reflector a converter to web socket
to be able to send the flow but already the
state works very well even a
class of 150 I do not think that all  they
are connected but 40 50 lessons are
connected etc. to that bit of delay
if you have seen it you notice however it is
enough to have a good
continuity of active
so he brought you we wanted to
bring you into a
work environment of my course I hope you
liked it if someone wanted to reply
would like to have
some ideas as code wants to send me
further
ideas my address is published more or less
however however renza cs not  you want some
and I will be happy to continue
this experience with you I spoke
so quickly that no I went
over 10 minutes
ok you have questions where requested and you want
to try out
thanks
[Applause]