hello everyone my name is maybe
emilians in the dojo i'm eco i'm here to
introduce you zanchin tech probably
many of you already know jean jacques
because i myself met her at desk
five years ago and since then i've followed a
path to become a master of this
new  discipline recognized as a new
martial art
the explanation of the discipline is
contained in the name itself jean shin tech
because the discipline unites the
traditional martial arts therefore jean shin
the condition of the master from the
martial arts master of the stillness of
knowledge and awareness of the
here and now and  of
tech technology was born just five years
ago in genoa today genoa has three schools
of jean shin tech pavia and then
gradually spread mainly in northern italy
with milan rome verona shower from which I
come and from this year also modena
but yes  the numerous new sensors are formed
for which it will surely expand at
a capillary level a bit for the north of
Italy  to
me precisely I come from the doge of
verona for which jean shin tech for now
we are 2 sensei enabled eco and robbie but
we are
not fooled by the height
of the current 66 but we are growing
so we have two new
girls who are enabled for
the  'teaching of the discipline and therefore
we will again expand the dojo
also in Verona
but what do we do if the traditional martial art
deals with
physical conflict the art lozano sheen tech
deals with digital conflict talking about
digital it is impossible not to talk about
internet for which children and adults are asked
what internet is and
are invited to think about how it was
formed on what it is and its
evolution and therefore to understand that
obviously it is a connection network
where everyone is  connected to the other therefore
both socially and through any
type of device and very often we
end up in the news for devices that
those who talk to and the average user do not
make themselves c  onto what is happening is
a constantly evolving discipline
that is based on the study
of cyber attacks and therefore of
digital attacks and
therefore the fact of being able to get out of them
to do what
to gain awareness on the fact
that if the digital footprint in the world
physical is now a well-known and well-known thing
we must realize that we have a
digital footprint of
course that we begin to
train ourselves in the digital world and kids who
have as a gift already at 10 years 11
years before any type of device
do not realize  who themselves begin
to decide
their imprint their digital imprint and if the films of
our times have introduced this
path for which the world to which they have
made nio that already introduced the fact
that one entered a world but if one
died in the world  digital was equivalent to
dying in the world in the physical world
we come from a previous tradition in
which
futuristic films talked about but  cchine
able to speak able to reach
anyone but then the generation
was not ready and said do not believe
everything that is shown to you all
these things do not exist they do not
belong to your world and
a sort of  complete separation gap
between what they were
told and what they lived
for this reason one of the emissions
of sunshine tech is to abolish
making sure that words are used
with awareness
why that phone that device
that connects  a network does not
connect to a virtual world as the virtual is
often mistakenly said to
something that does not exist
so we immediately abolish this
word in starting to differentiate the
physical world from the
digital world and make it clear that if
an aggression occurs  the physical world and
the physical world that must be addressed
if the aggression occurs in the
digital world is in the digital world  that must
be addressed this does not mean
demonizing the technology on the
contrary it is a technological awareness
in order to know what the tool
is using so we do not
demonize technology but rather promote it with
awareness and this is the comparison
that those adults make
if there were adults  in the dojo is
that of a telephone where maybe
we met at the time of our
grandparents all day
and the confrontation was after we went
home and we had the desire to
communicate again and we created alarmism
for our grandparents who  they said but what
are you doing have you seen yourself all
day you still need to communicate
yes because man is a social animal he
needs to communicate and the more devices
we give them to do it the more he will use them and
be happy and the boys live in
this world in  a world interconnected
with difficulty both in the physical world it
was the digital world and very often
passes the news because we come to
talk  of cyber bullying that on the one
hand bullying there was since our
times those who did not have the bully of the situation at school or in the
village where he lived in the house
but today there is
cyberbullying
here is what science tech has done to
everyone  he has cataloged these types of aggressions and
has given them a name because as
happens in traditional martial arts
if I see an attack coming I recognize
the attack coming out of that attack
because for every attack there is a
defense so what jean
shin tech did is to have  cataloged the main
digital attacks giving it a name and
this already takes away the fear because it is no
longer something that I do not know is something
that I can associate and if I
associate it I can have a
possible defense for which in this case
cyberbullying for  us is this signal
the attacks are on those red signals
for us it is a crs attack where crs stands
for continued repeated and systematic and
because it continued because it occurs several
times a  The systematic day because you can be
sure that sooner or later a
new systematic attack will arrive because it
hits exactly where it knows
it hurts the most but unlike
traditional bullying which is physical and takes place in
the physical world and involves direct contact
with that person
the digital continues over time
but this does not hurt what
we teach children to recognize it and to
use defense
techniques defense techniques that are green
with techniques to use that
we teach them and we study them to understand
that it is always possible to stop  an
assault
obviously if it is a
systematic continuous repeated crs attack will be
much more difficult than a fake
friend request that can be
blocked much more easily but it is
always possible to stop a
digital version to ensure that
the wrong word victim is no longer used  very often
we hear on television or in the
news that girl is a victim of
cyber b  bullying in school more and more
victims of cyberbullying no the word
victim does not exist for us because the
word victim we are used to reading
in history books where victims are counted
but the victim is a person
who has given up and a person who has died
a person who died for us are
targets and as long as you are a target you
always have the possibility of getting out of that
type of aggression and therefore that's
why jean shin takes over that's why
martial arts take over we educate a
bit like martial arts to the
repetition of techniques to
repetitions  of gestures to ensure that
everything happens the defense takes place in
an instinctive unconditional way
we should not think about it but it is a modus
operandi and for this we take a cue
from martial arts masters as the
founder of aikido or it is
like the foundation of karate  the
founder of karate or the
founder of judo
here are these founding masters of
the martial arts disciplines  the
traditional ones
we report as examples and guys when we
project these slides in the dojo the
guys say that we understand everything
you have to be old with a beard to
be a martial arts master is not to
be aware of what you
are doing and as an example we bring the
demonstration that  the founder
of judo called in france to
demonstrate the discipline by challenging
the world champion a handsome young man
who as you can see in the attack was
completely rendered harmless but
what we point out that this
discipline is not aggressive is not
a hatred of violence  we point out how
in the face of the master there is peace
and tranquility, awareness because
he saw the attack coming he
recognized that attack maybe he
even gave them a name but above all,
having recognized it, he knows how to get out of
that type of aggression and  opponent
once it is stationary we point out
that it is not a photomontage but here you
have  I love the twist of the foot that
highlights that the person is trying
to free himself from the from the Venetian from the
master and the face of the master there is no
hatred there is no malice but there is only the
desire to get out of that aggression and
then  to enhance even more the last
image to make the zhang xin understand
the last representative image of
this calm this quiet and this
tranquility in living an aggression
with the tsar sheen that is awareness of the
here and now and therefore it is not a
combat system  the scientific is
dancing tech area but it is a path it is a
path that unfolds over time
our goal is
not to how technology evolves
so that we ourselves evolve the
meetings are weekly and
last about a '  an hour and a half with a
maximum number of 15 people divided by
age groups
the group of children from 11 to 18 years and
then from 18 years on any doge
of Italy to the two routes to the
children route then those  who are
forming their fingerprint and
adults who may have already formed
their fingerprint those who practice
science in the who is defined as
a digital warrior and therefore his
level is expressed according to the
bracelets we have borrowed a little from
traditional martial arts for which  not
being able to have belts because most
of the time we are behind a desk and
therefore it would not show we use the
bracelet from traditional martial arts
we must have a white which is an
initial starting level and a black
which is the final level but all the
other levels do not  are random this
case these bracelets are taken from the
connection cable with the
network so with the ethernet cable and therefore the
subdivision of the colors is that of
the ethernet cable and traditional what you do
in the dojo you start and end with a
greeting of traditional martial arts
because the symbol of respect and
entry into a new environment
is part of all  I extend the dojo the dojo is
an empty room that is set up
computers are assembled very often
the kids do not know
we do find
raspberry computers or computers to
assemble is a bit equivalent to
traditional martial arts when you wear
the kimono that is yes  takes off you leave the
clothes you used up to a few
minutes before and entering the dojo you
prepare yourself for a new way a new
path for which
we set up the dojo we assemble the stations and then we repeat
the 5 every time the five
fundamental rules that are the ones you see
here in the banner first rule do not
attack in the dojo we obviously teach
techniques they are used both in defense but
potentially they can also be used to
attack and our goal is not to
create cyber
criminals our goal is to make them able
to defend themselves from cyber attacks
so first rule  it is not to attack
everything you will learn in the dosio it
should never serve you as a led  ere no
other respect than for oneself
respect for the teacher because he is
teaching respect for the group and what is
more difficult than even for those who
are attacking you very often the bully is
a person who has perhaps more problems
than you are experiencing in that
moment for which the aggressor
needs your respect you have to show him the way
the way out
you have to give him the opportunity to honorably come out of the
conscious aggression that he has found a
person capable of overcoming his attacks
what is said in the dojo remains  in the dojo
this serves to ensure that the boys
feel free to
perhaps tell an attack in which they are
living in an environment that is able
to understand it and not judge it and help it
in defense because from the white
orange bracelet onwards
we teach the boys not  only to
defend ourselves that we did it
in the previous path but to
defend others to recognize aggression in others
at least d  two teachers and three
students this obviously has
more meanings than the fact of not
being alone with a minor but our
idea is to create a group for
which we say that the minimum of one group
to be able to work together is three students
and two teachers and  you leave the dojo
as you found it if you have assembled the
stations we answer you this teaches
a sort of respect for the environment in
which you are elections can be of
treatment purely
technical elections I give you an example arrives
at the friend request to one  of
them or anyone on any social
network here for us that is a signal
a signal of false identity
if it is really sure that the person
who is contacting you knows them or that they
are really who they say they are for which
this is a signal of false identity
we teach them techniques for
example to trace a photograph or
to trace a phone number to
understand if who they say they are really is
therefore co  nknowledge and doubt then
identify any attacks and
any counter moves
if I have a friend request and they
have been accustomed to metal
immediately as a reflection to understand
that it is a false identity I can
trace the photo or trace the
phone number and then I
recognized the  'attack
I used a counter move and I can
simply get out of it for example we
call it zeroing that is it means
completely blocking the conversations
case analysis we have studied
hundreds of cases in Italy now
but in America in cases of cyber bullying they
were born much earlier than us so
we have studied hundreds of cases
we have cataloged all types of
attacks because basically the
digital attack pattern is the
same so this allows us, once
recognized, to stop it as soon as
possible.
big of us and is
undergoing an a  digital heel this is the
sweet of Verona if I still have three
minutes or not if I still have three minutes I show you
a video of the state of the art of jean
shin tech is still published on
youtube and of 2018 where we
show you some guys from the dojo who  they do
osint open source intelligence just
to put these into practice
these these the defense of these
attacks
sorry that
's right he made
the audio
[Music]
no this is not the audio but
basically okay it says the
music is somehow  more
captivating more engaging the boys
of different bracelets are divided into
groups an audio file of a
possible aggression is given and the boys are asked
in the shortest possible time of
types to identify and
identify whose that voice is and the
telephone number to which  it is associated who it is for
whom you see this is the timer what you
are using is mal the go to keep
track of what they are doing
and you will see as time goes on
inform them  mations that have therefore are a
voice sample and the
phone number the phone number is not of a
private person but the guys obviously do not
know it and therefore what you see is in
real time they will try to understand
the identity of the person by keeping track
of that  that they are doing
ok they found their name and surname and therefore
completely the registry of the person
who is attacking them
the subject did not know he had an identity card
the boys found it and
in less than ten minutes
here I thank you for the whole day
Roberta and I will be here if you have
any questions or doubts or concerns,
we must turn our t-shirt even if
we sweat we will try not to remove it to
be identifiable
good day to everyone and thanks
[Applause]