welcome to the second talk I'd like to
choose two Jedi Masters for today and
then we're going to Chris my supple
basin okay so we kind of written this
talk in a way that it's kind of two
talks in one so I'm going to start off
right in the first part of the talk here
which kind of talks more about working
with developers and the local management
within an stl sees the people
responsible for delivery and then chris
is going to talk more about kind of
selling and getting executive and
management level buying for application
security I guess that's why I've been
the t-shirt and chris is in the suit
today so we can give it a gable of our
constituents exactly and we kind of
split it up like that because in our day
jobs those are the main areas that we
focus on so I would work primarily with
developers and kind of within the
development team and Chris obviously is
the CTO of an application security
company would work a lot with helping
people understand how to get that kind
of management level by and that
ultimately spend money on application
security ok they give away so i'll start
off here so my name is david cook as you
probably seen on the agenda on the first
slide there my work is a security
analyst for real ex payments and dublin
and my job is full-time application of
securities that would include everything
from kind of getting management to
commit to do an application security
application security results in as well
as things like security code reviews
threat model pen testing and so on and I
guess a lot of people probably know me
better as security ninja on Twitter or
through the security ninja website I do
a lot of other things as you can see on
the screen either the point of the
bottom about a third product nishio
that's when I presents- afternoon if you
want
find out more about that so I guess this
is my the agenda for my part of the talk
it's really how can you work with
developers and how can you help
developers get what they need to help
you so how can you give them information
the tools the process is that they need
to write secure code which ultimately is
what you want to achieve and then
secondly translate and what I call
application security alien into the
business language because as much as I
think most probably don't want to get
involved with business language and
business people they the end the day the
people who sign off on just about
everything so if you want application
security resource and you need money if
you want tools you need not always money
but you need you know the business to
accept the cost of putting those things
into a development life cycle for
example so again there's more of taking
the things we talked about and figuring
out how you put those things into a
former and definitions at the business
cares bug so firstly from my experience
both relaxant and other places and
conferences and so on and maybe that the
first bullet payment there is not
completely true most developers don't
come up to me and say I want to write
secure code but what I found is I've yet
to come across the developer who's told
me they don't want to write secure code
so it's not like you fight it in a
completely uphill battle with the
developers but what you need to
understand is that you need to own the
application security patterns for them
in some ways it shouldn't just be a case
of producing a list of vulnerabilities
and giving it to them and walking away
if your job is to produce secure code
and secure applications you need to help
them achieve secure code and just given
them a report full of vulnerabilities
with severity five or whatever it might
be doesn't give them a feeling that your
your eat as equally eager to get their
Cobra and securely as as you want them
to be so when I talk about own in the
problem with him i don't mean writing
the code for them but I mean help them
understand
the code they need to write to fix the
issues you've come up with and if
developers need a process surrounding
that so whether it's you know the fact
that you have to getting security
ingrained in the sdlc maybe or the fact
that if things like security
requirements aren't in requirements
document in documents are then you could
still actually argue the developer is
doing their job if they don't write
secure code and I know that sounds a bit
confusing but if we don't have security
in there as a requirement because we
have an only application security
problem then they're probably not going
to write secure code something chris
said to me recently to along a similar
vein there was that if they did go like
secure code then arguably they're not
doing their job because they they didn't
build the application as per the
requirements in the design that was
signed off so only now they're making
sure they have everything that they need
in place to write secure cody's is vital
and what you can also try and uses
developers generally like to write
quality code not all of them because
we've all used products which are far
from being a quality application but in
general I found developers like
producing something that is quality
something like they can generally be
proud of and you'll also want a lot of
businesses want to produce quality
products now if you can work too in some
ways change the definition of quality
within your business to include security
then you can use that because if the
developers want the right quality hope
and you can include security as part of
quality I'm not saying that same thing
but if your definition of quality or are
more specifically a good application and
your business includes security then
you'll find it a lot easier to get the
right secure code and then finally what
I found when developers is they want the
right knowledge the right practices
there are a synthesis and the right
tools I know in some ways that probably
sounds a little
obvious that they want the right
knowledge but then for a second think
about if you're a developer or security
person how you do secure development
education or what if you're a developer
what developer education programs have
you been subjected to I you subjected as
the word there specifically because some
are terrible and they don't give the
developers the knowledge they need and
that's kind of this comment recently I
saw on on a blog that I was commenting
I'm kind of really reinforced that with
me that this guy Jim bird come along and
he said that in the context of talking
about getting developers to write secure
po with it's the blog was talking about
he said that he's a software guy and
what he wants is he wants practices and
tools that actually work so not just
saying all your will follow the
Microsoft stl because that might be
great if your Microsoft but if you're a
very small company that probably doesn't
make sense so making sure that whatever
you put in place ad will actually work
in your environment and more
specifically they must help him get it
help them get software out of the door
better software that's more reliable and
more secure so what can we do to help
developers so and we do need to help
developers because ultimately they're
the ones who are determined whether your
application security program produces
secure code or not because they're the
people writing that code so first bullet
point again to me seems like one that's
almost too obvious for me to put in the
presentation but I'm saying make sure
that you help developers understand how
to write secure code and again think
back to develop her education things
that you've seen though you've been
through and how many of them actually
taught you how to write secure code so
if you've gone aren't secure develop
training courses or whatever it might be
how many of them sat you down actually
taught you how to write secure code in
my experience and from seeing what's out
there in the marketplace probably very
few of the developers who we want to
write secure code have actually been
taught and write secure code we teach
them about vulnerabilities and then we
to exploit it something like web goes
then we hope that from there they can
kind of figure out how to write their
secure code or if we do cover secure
podium it's probably for maybe ten
percent of the time where's the other
ninety percent of the time we're talking
about vulnerabilities and exploits you
need to really think about the way
you're doing your training and figure
out whether you're trying to give them a
web app pen testing on a one-on-one
course or whether you're actually
teaching them to write secure code and
really if you if your training doesn't
include some element and secure coding
then your developers never actually
going to write secure code because
you've not told them what they need to
know and then just to reiterate point
about only an application security
problems with them make sure that rather
than being seem seen as an auditor
within the team that you're seen as a
teammate but you're as equally concerned
about getting software out of the door
you've got your own agenda obviously it
needs to be secure software but
understand that the thing that I guess
drives their bonuses and their
performance reviews is whether they're
getting co-produced sometime if you show
concern for that and you show that
you're willing to help them do security
right but also meet their deadlines then
again from my experience that's been
very useful and then the final point
there is is very important don't dictate
them don't go to them with the attitude
of I'm the security person I know about
these difficult security problems so I
better than you we might not all do that
but there are loads of people in
security do have that asked you to go
along with the idler security person you
must do what I say and don't ever dare
question me but the problem is on the
flip side we're talking about
development which means that they
actually probably know more about
actually rising a piece of code to
prevent the issues you'll find in the
new do so in some ways they could come
with that smoke I'm better than new
attitude as well but from my experience
they don't tend to they mock my code
because I'm not developer in a right
hold but not in the same way so rather
than dictating to them and say you
right securecode speak with them and
help all that help to learn from that as
well so you can learn from each other
but then finally when you learn from
them the things you get back from them
try and use that information to improve
things for them and one example of that
regex was that we spoke with our
developers because one of the things we
did is the security staff application
security seat with the developers in the
same team same managers so we just the
same as those guys in terms of our 24
hour performances the department is
measured on getting an application
delivered on time and security is part
of that but to improve things we spoke
with the developers about security
testing and what they said was that when
we go out of the development phase we've
done some level of kind of function on
QA testing so we at least know our code
works in it it's somewhat a way towards
doing what it's supposed to do what the
problem is when when we look at security
testing we've got no idea what you're
going to find two or three phases along
in the sdlc which is a problem for us is
there any way that we can start doing
some security testing ourselves just the
same way as we do functional and kind of
regression testing ourselves as well so
we took that away we had a think about
how we could enable that for them and to
cut a long story short the approach we
toughed was in the threat models the
security staff create kind of at the
design phase the sdlc we write very
clear security test cases not really
clear whereas before they were used by
the same security staff a lot of the
time so they they want that useful to
developers but now they're very clear
and then what we do is we invested in a
license for books we probe for every one
of our developers so all security staff
all tests and stuff and all developers
have a copy of this tool now on their
desktop and they're given to every
single project the test case is that
they should probably run based on the
threats and the risks we've identified
in the threat model so again it's a case
of speak with them and learn from them
and then
prove things from that so then next up
is is like I said what I call
application security alien and I guess
when we talk in terms of things like
injections and jackings and polling is
it probably makes sense to all of us but
ultimately all of us in this room and
probably many other security people
we're not generally the ones who sign
off checks we're not the ones who make
commitments on fixing these issues if
those people don't understand what the
hell we're talking about they won't sign
the checks for tools they won't sign
checks for resources they won't accept
the cost of adding all these additional
deliverables into their sdlc if you go
to them and talk about these three
things that they might think more along
these lines you know we're talking of it
injections and jackings and holdings so
if if in their head if that's what your
findings look like I don't think you're
going to get the the commitment you need
from the business to address your issues
so there are different ways of
approaching this so I guess what I'm
looking at here is more of how you get
kind of delivery managers or whoever's
responsible within like the SCLC for
getting cold out of the door how do you
get them to fix issues you find and
chris is going to cover this a lot more
in his slides of how you take that upper
level in riddick how do you get
management and kind of sea level people
in the business to actually sign off the
checks or to even say look as a business
the whole we're making a commitment to
write secure poul from now on so it the
things I'll talk about is more kind of
aimed at convincing a project manager
that he needs in today's project for a
week because the issue you found isn't
what isn't a golden my little pony but
it's actually something that could
really be a serious issue for the
business ok so it's following on from
that little bit as well as we kind of
sometimes t speed what outside of our
community a weird language
but then sometimes present those things
in weird formats as well formats that
again may make sense to us but again
we're not generally the ones making the
final decision on fixing these things or
invest in an application security so
something that I've spoken about quite a
few times particular on twitter at CBS s
and its use as a way of scoring
vulnerabilities can be useful in certain
situations but probably outside of the
applique or not just the application
security but outside of the security
team your findings probably make very
little sense to the business so let's
take a look at make-believe sequel
injection vulnerability and this is the
CBS s calculator which you just you know
Google for CBS s the website has got a
lot of good information on it I should
say I'm not saying CBS s a way of
scoring vulnerabilities is bad I'm just
saying that it's not probably the way
you want it then present the real risk
of these issues the business so using
the calculator you have look at a base
score so you fill in the baseball which
is mandatory and then you have
environmental and temporal scores which
are which are optional so you can fill
those in there all put together and they
give you a score in fact they give us
you know a few different scores as you
can see there but what it's telling us
is that our secret injection
vulnerability which from fill in these
fields in exploitable via the network
these no authentication could lead to a
cast a catastrophic loss of data to the
business for up to twenty five percent
about systems and a few other things
there and it gives us a score of 2.2 now
I don't use CBS s very much so I really
couldn't tell you what seen 2.2 means
i'd certainly what i could tell you that
was what 2.2 is a score in terms of risk
means and real eggs it means that that's
never going to get looked at and I'll
show you why in a second because you
need to look at well before we move on
to it I just want to put these
in here how those scores are calculated
how do we get to a score of 2.2 one this
is how we calculate the base score which
for us was 8.3 and then we throw in
these as well as this one's actually
i'll be the simplest one temporal
equation and then the environmental
equation so i looked at them and i
thought i'm actually not even going to
try and figure out how we got to 2.2
there and but we did we got a 2.2 but
the things that you need to look at is
2.2 you might make sense to you in terms
of understanding the vulnerability and
how how likely is it to be exploited for
example what is the impact of it but if
you take that score 2.2 to the business
does that make sense to them we'll look
at in the second one I think sometimes
it won't and then again sometimes as a
community which sometimes guilty of
feeling security should just happen
without really haven't adjusted for you
because XYZ company got hacked last week
we might use that as a lever to try and
get ourselves some technologies volatile
results and so on so what you again need
to understand is what's important to
your business and and then use be
realistic about what your expectations
are for security and use good
justifications and again chris is
probably going to give you more more of
a bigger stick to going to be so areas
of the business within his talk is slide
sorry than than mine so ultimately we
need to take this information we need to
speak in in in a business language or
more importantly a language that your
business cares about so it will differ
from from one business to another but in
general a lot of the things will apply
regardless of where you're working so
firstly you need to talk about things
the business cares about they don't care
or even know about my opinion probably
rightly injections and jacking its
opponents or if they do we saw both of
those things might look like in their
heads when we tell them about it which
means that if that's what they think
about it means you're not going to get
what you want so you need to think about
what does the business character and why
should it in
security so they don't care necessarily
that you have a sequel injection
vulnerability but what they do care
about these things like less loss of x
percent of revenue and Chris will give
you more concrete information on how to
start putting those kind of figures in
front of executives in a short while
then you also need to look at things
like you know businesses really care
about damage to Brad massively care
about that probably even more so
nowadays than they would have a year or
two ago with things like social
networking you know if you're breached
you're the news of Twitter and security
at least for a day or week and you're
the example that we always mark until
the next conflict comes along as as hard
as it sounds that's the way it is and
you can you can use some of those things
as real world examples I mean look at
our assay for example that I think if
you google RSA security last week at
least I think about half of the results
on the first page of Google or about me
packed you know that's not you know
using for donuts and that's actually
take him in a real example and saying to
the business you know we're not maybe as
big a brand as RSA but look this is what
happened to our a safe and apps they got
hacked and then make sure that we
present findings in a format that makes
sense and it's important to think about
a format that makes sense to the
business rather than necessarily to us
because the CBS s might make sense to
some of us but that doesn't make sense
the business so we need to translate
that into a language and a format that
they care about and make sense to him so
one of the biggest things I figured out
when we were trying to really ramp up
application security green X a couple of
years ago was the most important thing I
ever did was understand how the business
schools risk and what we found was that
the business in all the other areas of
the business whether its results in in
projects whether its operational or its
finance whatever it might be they all
scored risk in the same way the the
rankings were sliding it from because
they had you know definitions
for a project so you know this project
might sleep set by five weeks or from a
finance point of view might be losing 10
major customers in a month but then
house security rankings were not even
anywhere close to matching up to what
the business spoke about and what they
ultimately made decisions based on so
let's take that same sequel injection
again and look at look at it in terms of
a much simpler very common way of
scoring list you know probability tomes
impact it is a fairly simple way of
scores risk but if that's the way the
rest of your business scores risk and
that's the way you should at least
present your findings to the business
I'm not saying don't things like CBS s
I'm saying when you take a day to and
want to get the business to look at it
put it in a format that they they use
and they care about so if we look at
this if we take we've just making up
numbers here I guess to some degree we
give it a probability of three which
might be this happens every six months
and it's an impact of five because we're
saying when we put it in CBS s that it's
a catastrophic loss of data it's up to
twenty-five percent of our system
doesn't work for authentication that's
also it could be an impact the file and
the impact part is really where you need
to work with the business and understand
what an impact 25 meets for them so a
new pack 25 or finance won't be lost
with a million pounds of revenue or
might be losing the top five customers
all within a month you can put a
security definition in there so it might
be some more an exploitation in the
sequel injection vulnerability drop in
the whole of you David sort Steve in the
problems or whatever it might be in your
business as long as it makes sense and
the business accepts yeah that's a five
then an impact of five makes senses of
mobile they're looking at as a finance
risk of business or an aspirational to
score an application security risk and
if we look at this here we got a total
score of 15 the business has an appetite
at 12 so are immediately getting their
attention if you go in here and say it's
2.2 that look at that and say that goes
to right to the bottom haan get to
we address these other Condon's at risk
we've got so ultimately you need to
speak their language not all the time I
don't think any of us could really cope
with doing at all of the time but at
times when you want them to make
decisions make decisions that you want
them to make make sure that you're
giving them the information that they
need in the format that they want to see
and then ultimately understand that
application security or security as a
whole there's no exception when it comes
to resource it actually doesn't really
matter that there's you know the trouble
we have with the economy at the moment
regardless of that there you need to
justify your results and be realistic
with it don't if you go away from here
today look at your application security
program i implement that then you'll
probably find hundreds of issues if you
go to the business with a list of
hundreds of issues long they might just
look at that and say that's too big for
us to deal or you might look a bit like
the boy who cried wolf so again be
realistic with your expectations score
risk and score those issues in terms
that they care about and take your most
critical issues to them and then you
might start to see things being
addressed and then ultimately try to
keep everything simple what I'm trying
to do whatever I do with application
security is follow the KISS principle so
keep it simple stupid or keep it short
simple depends on I guess who you
explain the KISS principle to and just
try and keep everything as simple as
possible it doesn't matter I suppose in
how you do your analysis now you come up
with your results you can do that
however you want but it's how do you
present that out to the people you want
to make decisions try and keep that as
simple as possible and ultimately speak
with your developers understand what
they need to write secure come it isn't
just a once a year refresher on what the
OS top ten is it's much more than that
but you need to understand and listen to
what they're telling you they need to
write secure code and then lastly you
know work with the business understand
their languages on
sender formats and understand what they
actually care about ok so I'll hand over
to Chris now where he'll kind of carry
on the chain within the business so uh
thanks dear son to you um so if you
don't know me back in the 90s I was well
pond at the loft and I was sort of on
the offense I'd doing vulnerability
research writing tools to act systems
but now I have a professional PR team I
which means that know I can win awards
now because if you don't have a
professional PR team you're never going
to get these right and you know my job
is basically to help people write secure
applications put together application
security programs so their organizations
can produce secure code whether internal
or their vendor and they're selling that
code so you know why do we need
executive Mayan is because to do
application security we typically need
resources we need tools we need training
and also it's going to have an impact on
the business it's probably going to at
least in the beginning change change
development schedules and we don't want
it to be voluntary right we don't want
some development teams to say we're
going to do securecode another one say
it doesn't really matter to us if it
matters to the business it can't be
voluntary so because of this we're going
to need money and we're going to need
authority or it's just not going to work
so this is why we need to get executive
by and we just can't get buy-in from the
development team so it's really a
top-down and bottom-up process to get
application security working within a
business so the David talked about you
know speaking speaking the language of
the business and I'm going to make it
even more simple here this is the
language that CEOs understands CFO's
understand
and cios understands it's very simple
speaking the language of the business
means putting things in monetary terms
this is how executives think how am i
growing my business how am i growing my
top line it's dollars right it's not
like how many states am I in how many
countries mi in its how much how many
what's the revenue number of the
business when they talk about lowering
costs obviously that's money too but
mitigating risk they think in terms of
dollars when we think about mitigating
risk it's really its technical what is
the likelihood that this is going to be
exploited or you know can I make it so
that the impact is less and and then we
speak in technical terms they speak when
they talk about executives talk about
risk it's almost always translated into
a monetary terms so we have to figure
out a way to translate this into
monetary terms or it's not going to make
sense and you know David brought up some
some points of like you know what is the
law sales going to be you know it's got
to be translated into some numbers so
here's some other examples of areas of
risk in that executives need to think
about they think about legal risk right
when they're doing something that you
know might be risky from a legal
perspective the lawyer has his own
language or her own language that they
speak in just like we have our own
language but the end of the day so that
executive can make a decision on whether
to sue someone or not not not run some
part of the business because it's too
risky from a legal perspective the
lawyer puts the risk into monetary terms
what are the court costs going to be
what is a potential fine going to be
what will be the settlement costs of
this so the legal risk is translated
into monetary terms same thing with
compliance risk there's all kinds of
different things you need to comply with
employment regulations environmental
regulations you know we think about
compliance as you know all IT focus but
there's a lot of compliance
have to deal with and if they're not
complying you know what's the lost
business what are the fines that's that
that's what it comes down to and even
even fuzzy things like brand risk
marketing people translate this into
dollars what is my lost business going
to be because our brand got tarnished
somehow you know we're getting sued by
the government you know we're seeing
we're seeing we're measuring how that's
impacting the business of them to the
brand risk so for security risk how do
we do what these other professions are
able to do right there they're probably
more mature as professions but they
figured out a way to communicate what
they want to get done and what they
think has value to the business to
executives so one way that this is a
model I'm working on it's obviously not
not perfect this is a challenging thing
to do but translate technical risk into
into monetary risk using some data data
sources that are that are out there so
to actually take you know the technical
risk which is those vulnerabilities in
your application portfolio because
speaking at a high level here the
business cares about all its
applications not just one which a
development team might care about and
look at expected loss derived from those
vulnerabilities the threats based data
out there in actual breach costs so
breach costs is something that there's
really not enough data out there if your
organization has been breached before
you can you can use that you can
understand what your costs were you know
what were your fines what was your
mediation costs things like that and
then translate it on the vulnerabilities
that led to that reach and translate it
to the other vulnerabilities in your
organization but if your organization
hasn't been breached by application
security you probably don't have this
data so the Ponemon Institute ponymon
Institute did a survey last year of
different industries and they broke it
down into detection escalation
notification ex post response and lost
business and came up with the average
and then per capita which is a record
stones this is kind of record bass was
kind of a PII centric view of the world
which is both good if that's the risk to
your businesses is getting PII expose
it's not so good if if your business is
not that if it's not you probably have
to find some reach costs that are more
related to your business and the risks
in your business but since it's the best
data out there I use that and you can
see the down here I don't know if you
could see in the back but there's
different industries like financial it's
248 dollars per record is the cost of a
breach whereas consumer is only 159
pharma it's 310 so different you can see
right away that this is this is has some
value to an executive because they're
seeing like peer industry verticals what
were their costs from from breaches you
have to make it you have to make it as
relevant as possible and then a way to
make vulnerabilities real is not to not
to deal with them in isolation but to
actually look at Fred space data and see
what our attacker is actually exploiting
that that's actually leading to leading
to compromises that are impacting real
businesses this data comes from last
year's verizon data data breach report
and these were real real real incidents
that had a real impact to the business
they had they had to investigate them
whether they were compelled to do it
because they're regulated or or they
needed to call someone in to you know
actually clean it up and figure out what
happened but verizon collects this data
and these are the different attack types
that are used and one of the attack
types that's used quite often is
hacking and this adds up to more than
100 because a typical attack will have
multiple multiple stages there might be
you know there might be hacking in order
to install malware and then you know so
there's two or might be social
engineering to install malware but 40
about forty percent of the tax hacked
some sort of issue in software and over
here is the root the different root
causes back to our control channel
sequel injection command injection
process scripting authentic
you