I'm like okay yeah okay you're all
responsive yet excellent excellent well
Kamal practical crypto attacks against
web applications so i had a slight
concern just a little bit before as to
whether i was going to be too basic so
hopefully i'm going to strike the
balance between just confusing the hell
out of you for an hour and boring the
hell out of you for now so you know
listen to see how the hell it goes for
those of you who don't know me if I talk
to you fast cousin from New Zealand and
if we can't understand what I'm saying
let me know and I'll slow down you know
Kiwis you know we can talk fast
sometimes we just not initially do so
excellent overview I am NOT a
cryptographer and actually is really
completely anybody who has you know
crypto like you call yourself a
cryptographer in there in the audience
good because we're going to talk about
today is you know if you're not a
cryptographer this stuff is practical
stuff to look at so we're looking at and
there's three particular ones in
particular that I'm looking at which are
repeatable patterns of things that you
can look for which are indicative of and
how you can actually look at kind of
breaking those systems as well and
cryptography is wonderful but if you use
it badly often you end up in a situation
where it doesn't give you anywhere near
the protection that you that you want so
using crypto does not equal security
equally crypto does not equal security
and the reason that I probably wanted to
pitch this one in here and do this talk
is because you know I think there's
probably a certain one certain people in
here who do look for this kind of thing
in fact I ran into port swagger death
just before and he said that the latest
version of of burps wheedle bit pro or
both or okay is going to have some bit
flipping attacks against things like
cookies as well which is exactly the
kind of thing I'm going talk about now
so it's something that you'd be probably
had to do manually up until this point
so we're going to look at the kind of
kind of stuff that we can we can do that
so I mean perhaps this isn't something
which has been well contested if you've
been around
long time you probably have heard of or
you may well be a lot more expert and
some of these things than I am but the
assumption here is that it's probably a
few of you out here could not probably
figuring out that it's quite as easy to
look for these kinds of things as it
actually is so the basics
confidentiality integrity and
authenticity so what are we trying to
achieve I mean it inevitably it's
probably the first one confidentiality
is what we think of you know we want it
to be secret but the other ones and I've
used about their fists instead of
availability in this particular case
just to justify those of you who know
what the CIA actually is but it's often
kind of the audience do the actual
integrity of the data and things like
that is pretty damn important but it's
not something that time that we need to
there's not something that we often kind
of consider and it's often something
that when you're doing something when
you're so we're developer you're
throwing something together you know
you're encrypting it you know the way
you do that can have some impacts on
this kind of stuff as well so what are
we actually gonna look at today so
because we just have 50 minutes and
because i am going to tempt the demons
of fate and try and do live demos of the
stuff which may or may not lead to
massive demo fail or not we could look
at three main kind of ones so we can
look at ECB mode crypto which even
though you hear about the fact that it's
bad people still use we're also going to
look at heading Oracle's and we're also
going to have a brief kind of coverage
on some of the random number generation
stuff here now all three of these
scenarios are ones we find in pin tests
so you know the question is are you
looking for them and let's have a look
at the kinds of things you should be
looking for so if we're talking about
the crypt over two different term kind
of symmetric crypto ones for those of
you who you know don't necessarily
haven't dug into this too and too much
detail we basically have a number of
different ways that these things work
the two ones we're gonna look at today
are probably the two most common ones
across ECB and CBC of those CBC is the
one that you probably should be using
but the trick here is cryptography you
know encryption doesn't equal integrity
can anyone tell me what happens if you
take like you know you know crypto so
you take ciphertext and you flip a bit
and the Decrypter what happens yeah
you'll get a slight change in the clear
text now it's not predictable what
that's going to be but you know equally
you may as well sit there and flip them
just to see if you get anything
interesting so I mean used in isolation
these things don't provide any integrity
and a lot of things that we can talk
about at least especially for the first
part of this talk are directly related
to that so ECB is kind of like the
default mode we're looking at block
encryption so block encryption who can
tell me what kind of common block size
would be what kind of block sizes we're
talking about 64 bit hundred
twenty-eight bit so those probably the
two most common ones will come across so
64-bit very common for things like
Triple DES AES usually hundred twenty
eight bit what does that mean it means
eight bytes or sixteen bytes so if we're
not quite quite familiar with kinda like
thinking of bits versus biots you know
we are talking about discrete blocks
what happens ECB you take the first
block you encrypt it get the next block
you encrypt it next block you've ripped
it why is that bad because it's oh ex
it's not bad because it's using the same
here what happens if the plane tix is
the same you get the same ciphertext
yeah so I mean it's ECB mode it has been
known to be bad for as long as there has
been ECB mode why it's why it's not even
there so here's an example take a
graphic and alerts hasn't turned out
particularly well this particular case
encrypted with ECB mode what do you get
well you don't hide the patents first
art it is encrypted but you know there's
a lot of information
which is exposed it however we continue
to see people using ECB mode because it
is supported in all of the major crypto
frameworks so it's almost as if they
should probably really just take it out
but it does have some you know so people
will continue to use it so what kind of
snows are we talking about so now take
something of this cookie cookie value
for example so we have an encrypted
cookie value and it has various kind of
things that we have user IDs roles names
you know the kind of things that you
know you might end up sticking in a
cookie on a legacy system or something
like that so let's assume that we've
actually encrypted that so you know
we've taken this we've done it on using
64-bit one in this particular case we
have eight bytes and we've encrypted it
so you know that's fine you know it
looks secure its hex it's secure isn't
it yeah in what happens if we actually
swap things around so I mean we're not
talking about anything rocket science in
this particular case but if we have an
element of predictability about what is
actually in these particular things and
there is a direct correlation in ECB
mode between what block is what bit of
data we can just you know have fun and
play with things so in this particular
case was swapped kind of block 7 into
where block tippers and then when we
have the decryption operation heavens
you know we have it something quite
different so in this particular case you
know this is a contrived example of this
case we've gone from roll 3 throw 39
what does that mean well in the context
of the application who knows but it's
interesting that this kind of thing is
not something that we generally kind of
looking for so we have you know a bit of
differentiation there so now we have we
will see if this works so this
particular example is based on a live
example that we did see add a client so
let me introduce a few bits and pieces
so first
of all let me introduce you to the stock
trader application which hopefully is
still working it's probably also yep so
as you can see no license copy so it's
going to have a look and see what we've
got in here so let me just maximize this
because this is a relatively simple
example so this is an example
application one's going to use for a
couple of things now this is an
interesting piece of functionality in
this application which is basically the
self registration functionality and what
happens in this particular functionality
is we just register a user so let me
just put a test and what happens is
nothing actually see that this week look
at the
suffering from resolution a little bit
here as we end up with basically a
single sign off single sign-on pass off
between two different systems so in this
particular scenario we have a system
which does enrollment and it's basically
doing a single sign of pass off to
another system which is authenticating
so this this kind of scenario and does
come when you kind of rolled your own
single sign-on or if you have perhaps a
legacy system where you're logging
somebody in and then you're basically
kicking them over to a new system
probably as part of kind of a rollover
period in this particular case we have
you know the first thing is this like
it's like you know I'm always interested
in anything which is hex but it's like 1
2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 I'm
especially interested in anything which
is divisible into blocks of eights
because it's automatically a little bit
suspicious now this particular case we
have a pure hex value it could also be
basically Ford it could be encoded in a
number of different ways as well so it's
it's something which is of interest I'm
also also very interested in situations
where we possibly have the ability to
put something into something which is
encrypted so if we have the ability to
force the application to equip something
for us and the observed through the
outputs and that's the particular
example in this case so the example that
we have in this case is this let me log
out
now it just skip several stages there is
an account called admin and strangely
enough you can't create another account
called admin because the way that the
authentication for this particular
application works you know it is it is a
login and hand over but what kind of
stuff could we do well let's have a look
and see what happens if we do stuff like
this so I'm just going to do a few of
these and we'll have a look and see what
it looks like it's going to call X admin
it's the X admin I'll do one more
discreet have a look and see what we're
seeing it's exactly
look at sea where are we there's my book
on too many windows okay so let's have a
look and see what we're actually what
we've been seeing so so there's the
second one so 09 another one b7 ah
excellent okay interesting it's now at
longer okay so what's happened in this
particular cases were actually started
another block okay so this is
interesting so generally speaking what
we're going to do is we're going to
continue adding Xers in this winter case
I'm going to skip a few steps because we
actually end up doing about nine other
words particular case what's happened in
this particular case well whatever is in
there by putting the excess is now
spilled over into the next one so we
have you know presumably you know exit
6a and then or maybe exists x 60 x ADM
up in EMI in and then the last the last
block is actually the in so let's just
skip a couple of steps and show you
where we're going with this
you create three more
that's how many that's 1237
thanks
and we'll do one of nine as well
ok
so it's going to have look and see what
kind of results we get with that kind of
thing so okay so it was the last one
that one's was when we just basically
would made Edmund greater than eight
bytes because my invites long so if we
go down and have a look at them so that
was a seven or maybe was at six sixes
letting of seven nixes a texts so and 9
x's ok that's interesting now we have
exactly the same thing so if we're doing
this kind of thing up until now we
probably don't know what that is other
than the fact that seems to be
predictable or seems to be contained
some stuff that we've put in there but
now it's kind of it's pretty clear that
what's what's in that first kind of 16
bytes what is that 3522 if to whatever
yeah it's 8 x's and that's it so because
we still have a TEDx is on the front of
it so likely is not and we see this
because the first block is exactly the
same it's probably ECB mode so what is
if we have a look at 63 what does 4 5
a-9 etc what is that Edmund it's
probably Edmund encrypted and you know
just just because we've got to prove
these things this is when Justin hopes
this this actually works because even
though you test these things the
previous night he never one hundred
percent sure it was going to work on the
day so that's the value that we
extracted which logsdon Edmund so this
is a very simple example but this is
based on a concrete example where we did
exactly this the only difference in the
example that we that we actually
exploited was this was a cookie and the
only other you know cut a bit was
instead of putting basically stuff on
in that particular case instead of
putting stuff on the front of the
username we're actually putting stuff in
the middle of user name and that was
largely because of how they did their
the user names is like that but it's
literally if you see pieces of data with
that you have to play with them and see
what happens so this one's particular
one is a nice easy example but you
occasionally will come across exactly
the kind of thing so it ECB mode it is
generally bad so what about CBC mode so
ECB mode came out and everyone said all
that sexually not a particularly good
idea because we could do block swapping
so what we're going to do is going to do
cipher block chaining so what we're
going to do is we're actually going to X
or in effectively something to make the
the next block dependent on the previous
one so the way that happens to be
implemented in this particular case is
first of all this is where you have an
initialization vector what's the
initialization vector useful and
Vladimir you've been answering lots of
questions initialize the vexation Victor
what's it used for it's where guys it's
made to make that it's used to make the
first block not predictable because we
don't we're not mixing in anything
previously with the first block so the
first block was always the same it would
be always the same would end up with you
know having some predictably about there
so the initialisation vector kind of
mixes some stuff and wipe the start work
and effectively what we're doing is
we're exerting in the ciphertext from
the previous operation with the plane
tix and then encrypting van so
effectively we're building a dependency
so so this looks all really good and I
like these like diagrams which have
pretty boxes and eggs ores and arrows
and plain text goes here in cipher text
goes here but any so we have X or
operations this that's what there is is
it for and it does what it's intended to
do it does mix in and kind of break a
lot of those patterns and things like
that but implementation is a bitch so
decryption operation is effectively
exactly the reverse so we end up with
the initialization vector ciphertext
decrypt X or plain text so we are doing
the XOR operations in reverse
in order to be able to do this what's
what's important about this is we're
actually exhorting in the ciphertext
from the previous one so it's just the
implementation and block swapping will
result in corruption so you can't you
can't talk them around Dueling double
nonsense note this doesn't mean that you
won't be able to decrypt it you can
you'll be able to just arbitrarily stick
whatever you like into an encryption
algorithm for the most part and force it
to decrypt you'll just end up with
nonsense you're not going to end up with
what you start with what you're looking
for but the way people implement systems
based on these can have problems and
this is where the padding Oracle is
particularly good example this so what
does a padding Oracle has nothing to do
with Oracle so we're not going to talk
anything about databases this is a kind
of crypto issue and also crypto sure
which has been known about for a long
time I think the first kind of public
paper on this was maybe 2002 a lot of
you may have heard April last year I
think it was that a couple of chaps
who's named Giuliano and completely ty
presented paper a black hat Europe last
year I'm kind of looking at practical
attacks on on jsf so timber last year we
kept this this really kind of burst onto
the scene because there was a major
padding Oracle to explore it and don't
need so what are we actually talking
about what we're talking about bit
flipping of ciphertext so we have
ciphertext and we have the relationships
between blocks of ciphertext so we can
we can't actually bit flip and just
basically just start changing things to
see what happens but in this particular
case we're looking at a behavior of how
the system is implemented which based on
this behavior we can get more
information and what it leads to is the
ability to actually arbitrarily decrypt
the data without knowing the key without
even knowing the algorithm entirely
based on the behavior of the system
itself so the first thing we have to
talk about when we talk about padding
Oracle's is what is padding so when
we're encrypting stuff
because we're encrypting blocks of eight
blocks of 16 data if you don't have a
block of eight or block of 16 you need
to pet it so you need to stick something
on there in order to have something to
encrypt and this is PK cs5 heading
basically if you have you know three
bits of data you need to pad it in with
five more bits of data in this
particular case you end up heading it
with five lots of x5 and if you have six
you end up heading with two lots of two
if you know seven you end up heading
with one of one and interestingly if you
have if you actually do have eight
you'll end up adding it with eight lots
of eight so this is a very standard
heading behavior it's not the only one
who come across but it's probably the
most common one that you'll come across
and the reason you do this is that so
effectively so you can validate the
decrypted something correctly because if
you decrypt something and it's correctly
padded then it was probably successful
in the decryption operations this is one
of the useful ways you can tell with
you've actually managed successfully
decrypt something or not so PK cs5 and
what are we talking about when we talk
about Oracle's well there is only eight
possible padding sequences you could
have in the situation of having an
eight-block algorithm so first of all
that's interesting so we know for sure
what at least one bite of this data is
going to be or could only be eight
things and depending on what it was we
could no more of them so that's
interesting it's interesting and so what
happens if we do on a bit flip in CBC
mode so say for example in particular
case you know we do flip for example you
know the sixth kind of bite in this kind
of situation well we're going to end up
with that kind of stuff affecting the
plaintext but interestingly it's also
going to end up plant affecting the
plain text of the next block okay so
that's interesting so this is all kind
of like about how it works
and based on how the odds decryption
operation itself is it works and this is
especially how it commonly works in
something like a web application is
we're probably going to end up with a
number of errors if the description
operation fails in some particular case
even better if we know what those zeros
are so the one that we're particularly
interested in is you know so invalid key
is well hopefully you're not going to
get one of those is it an even block
multiple so those ones are only if
you're kind of like feeding an invalid
data the one we were particularly
interested in is an invalid heading
exception so how is it going to be
useful to us so this one this one is
interesting because part of this is we
need to be able to determine whether we
have this error so what happens commonly
in something like we're application if
you try and do something with data and
it fails your web application Europe
maybe it even bubbles up an ear emitted
explicit ear message if you're lucky but
more to the point you're likely to see a
different behavior you might get a 500
era where previously you expecting a 200
so there's some observable behavior if
we manage to cause one of these things
to happen so what are we talking about
with a padding Oracle effect and then
the art this is where the Oracle but
comes in because the Oracle means that
we are effectively we have the
application the system as its
implemented is telling us whether we
have this or not so effectively the
application as it's um implemented is
telling us that the situation does exist
so let's take the example so we're going
to flip the last bite of the ciphertext
so first of all we're going to end up
with rubbish plain text we don't hear
but so we call that one x x so x x maps
to bite why so basically it is eggs
would with the results of the next one
so it does affect the next operation so
what happens if the plane tix doesn't
isn't correctly
we that this is this is the situation
where we have it so previous block we
changed that or actually just put it as
one it is going to affect and it be eggs
ord and at the end of the day that the
plain text which comes out of the next
block if it's not validly padded we're
probably going to get an exception so
here's an example we put in 0 so you
know okay so we put in 0 we get an
exception we put in one we're getting
exception we put into we don't get an
exception what does that tell us what it
tells us is if we stick a 2 into the
cipher text of the previous block what
must that value be if it's correctly
padded what sorts or was it yes it must
be a padding value so it must be a valid
padding value of which there is only
eight and likely as not we know exactly
what that is it must be one so we know
what they value is so we know if we
stick a two in here we get a one out
here so equally we can we can continue
that and because we're talking about
eggs or this means that we know other
stuff as well so more to the point this
it's basically the intermediate kind of
value that the one which comes out of
the decryption and has then eggs Ord
with the ciphertext it means we also
know what that value is as well so means
that we know effectively three different
bits of information so I mean
effectively that gives us the ability to
kind of figure out what that in an
encrypted value is it also gives us the
ability although we're not going to
really talk to too much detail about
this to actually be able to re-encrypt
stuff with their block as well so not
only can we use this particular exploit
to decrypt stuff which is the simplest
of the two examples but we can also use
this exploit to re-encrypt stuff and we
don't know the key we don't even know
what the algorithm is at this point
we're entirely looking at the behavior
of the system and how its implemented so
padding by it was one the bite that we
stuck in which is the two tells us
effectively the intermediate bites you
know must be such and such that haven't
actually figured out what that is give
me something else so in oh we're just
going to call that the intermediate one
because it's effectively a value that we
don't normally look at but it's just
interesting there the tube case so let's
just have a look at a practical example
this who's who's come across pad Buster
had bust a few of you so on the Gotham
dental science website we have a free
tool which I'm going to demo it is open
source its reciprocal public license
feel free to do whatever you want with
it tour which exploits exactly this
stuff as well so let's have a look at
doing that so so I'm going to do this
against this particular application here
so as I mentioned there was a there's a
padding Oracle exploit or a padding
Oracle problem with dot net as of kind
of September 2010 last year so that was
patched so the version that I'm not
going to the vision I'm showing the this
particular case is not patched but i'm
just going to demo it in this particular
case so there's a couple of bits and
pieces in the.net framework which are
susceptible to padding Oracle's okay can
anyone including odious it tell me what
thou you guys are very communicative
today okay view states so view states
are a good one but the one I'm going
particularly look out of this at this
case is results handlers so resource
handlers donít 3.5 don't knit for Ajax
abs are particularly interesting so
there's two of them by default you would
normally come across once called the web
resource handler and the other one is
called the script resource handler now
if you have a look into more detail
about the the padding Oracle tax you can
actually use the script resort handler
to do handy things like download the
web.config off the side which is kind of
cool you kind of just you know pointing
it out something decrypting it re
encrypting it and saying give me the
web.config and it would now
fortunately I couldn't get there working
largely because the this application
here is not an AJAX application even
though it hasn't gotten at 3.51 so what
I'm gonna do is I'm just going to show
you an example of decrypting something
rather through through the web originals
handler so what the hell am I talking
about when i talk about weaves or resort
handlers so let me have a look at the
target thing we would have come across
some of these on break this down we're
talking about this thing so what the
hell is that effectively what it is is
it is a request which returns a script
effectively so this bit of data is a
script or it's a pointer to a script in
fact it actually is a filename in this
particular case it's interesting because
it with the web resource handler you can
actually download any JavaScript files
which are inside an assembly dll in.net
the script resource handler is more
interesting because you can actually
pull down any file on d'box so
unfortunately can't demonstrate that one
in this particular case so let me demo
head buster so hopefully this works so
it's worth pointing out of this point
that pad buster is not a specific tool
for this particular issue it's written
by a colleague of mine Bryan in New York
it is a general tool for all types of
heading Oracle's so it was actually
originally written for exploiting jcf
server faces view states but it works
quite handily with the.net example as
well so main things we're looking at we
need to provide a URL we need to provide
an encrypted sample of data and we need
to specify block size so let's do that
so grab one of these
help i get spell and when we're talking
about encrypted sample effectively it
just needs you to tell it what the bit
is that it needs to play with so it's
going to be that one so two j8 you in
this particular case if i remember
correctly it needs to be 16 with the
block size with a health nut pointer
gone and there's a couple of the things
we need to specify on this particular
case these are donate specific ones
which are effectively telling it what
kind of format the data is in and so
think of a case encoding is dotnet URL
token which is a particularly weird
version of of encoding acid on it has
its own particular one and no IV means
the the you know one of these you know
the IV is not included in this blockage
the particular option for don't yet so
let's see if this works
okay so what is it done it has gone
through and it is flipped effectively
the the last block of that to all 256
values and it's just seeing what
happened now what happens in a web a
patient is going to be is going to be
different depending on the application
you could see 200 s 30 s 500 but more
importantly we have one which is grossly
different to the other ones so
effectively were looking for the air
condition of this at this point so we
can then effectively tell which ones are
accurate much all it's not so it's
Hendley pointed this out that we should
probably select to at this point and
what it's going to do is it's going to
go through the process of decrypting
that piece of information
now I warn you now that the output of
this is not very exciting what's
actually in here is not very interesting
but it is purely just to demonstrate
kind of the output of this kind of thing
yep so the decrypted value is that which
is not very exciting so effectively what
it is reference to s so the way this
particular piece of data works is it's s
is a particular type of resource which
in this particular case is an embedded
assembly resource and then you have
piping which are basically separators
and the resources we have you add
validation GS which is a standard kind
of Ajax being kind of dotnet thing but
more the point you know we still don't
know what this key is and we've just
decrypted it so I'll point out at this
point that some which having chapter
provides from defensive security pad
Buster probably will be on the next
version of backtrack but in the meantime
feel free to pull it down just off our
website GD security com it's sitting
there in the tool thing as well so
that's nice little simple example also
if you have a look on our blog there's
some good examples of pulling down weird
configs if you particular interest in
how that works unfortunate i couldn't
get that demo working for this is noted
so both of the things that we've been
talking about so far are purely because
we have a situation where we have
encryption things where we have the
ability to change stuff so we have the
ability to change the cipher text for
the most part swap things around and it
still works you know it so in these
particular cases largely because it
hasn't been science so you know it might
be worth looking at options for signing
if you were trying to fix one of these
things so there's various types of one's
H max is one of them but have a look
into that interestingly the dotnet issue
that we just looked at is signed it's
just sign the signature is not checked
until after you've decrypted it so we're
actually forcing the error before it
actually checks the signature so in this
particular case although at first past
the design look good because of where
they were actually checking the
signature it was actually after the
decryption operation as opposed to
before so we had that particular one as
well so other things which were
vulnerable this is
forms authentication cookie as well
that's a good one so if you have an
expat which asp.net which has forms
authentication cookies that's another
one which is susceptible to this to our
jsf few states also susceptible to this
I don't think the JSF stuff to be fixed
any won't have any better I'm pretty
sure the JSF is still vulnerable to this
day although got Nets has patched
although I'm not a hundred percent sure
i think i was put as an important patch
which means in some cases it may not
have been automatically picked up so
it's worth it's worth checking to make
sure you're not set book for this and
last but not least because don't want to
run over time talk about just and I
don't have a demo for this particular
one because unfortunately it's a little
talking about runnin random number
generators it's kind of like you need to
you need to run at a half a dozen times
to like have any chance of it actually
working but these kind of situations are
good examples how random is random so
you'd be surprised how often we come
across situations we're people using no
normal super red and um generators and
you know kind of how how do those
numbers come from so typically you know
where they had problems with non random
seed values or we may have kind of
deterministic ones we're going to
predict we'll see what those things are
as well and it's surprising how often
you see situations like this so you know
we have 11 1 series 2 series effectively
what we're doing is we just like
creating red of Nova generator and just
outputting stuff runs you know one after
each other and you know unsurprisingly
if it does it outputs the same thing why
is that so in this particular case that
was dotnet code this particular case we
didn't we didn't even supply a seed
possibly using crappy random generated
in the first place and it seeds it off
the clock okay so if you're running a
random number generator and your seeding
it off the clock hmm how predictable is
is it to be able to figure out what the
clock on your server is it's not their
heart is it you could probably make a
educated guess as to what the clock is
going to be especially if it's a unix
box and it's probably running gmt you
know if you've probably got a very
limited kind of kind of time frame as to
as to what we're looking at and they've
kept those cases and you end up with
like code like this and this is based
off an example we actually did see we're
we have a basically random number
generator for resetting a password so
you've requested a password reset and
it's doing it in a pretty crappy way
from a security point of view and what's
it doing is it's emailing you out your
new password so that's fine but can
anyone tell me what the big problem in
this particular case is well there's no
see well yeah there's no seed and it's a
random what happens if you hit this like
at the same time or close enough what
happens if I just seen a lot of requests
yeah you can end up with the same
password and unsurprisingly that's
exactly what happens in whoopsie-daisy
what the hell happen there okay
unsurprisingly this does is possible and
is reproducible in practice now if
you're doing something over the Internet
needless to say you can have to have an
element of luck to get things turning up
at pretty much the same time but through
a brute force approach and you can amp
or situations like this so there wasn't
experiment I've lost the reference to
the actual paper that they did but
they're actually looking at a site which
had password resets implemented in
exactly the same way that we were
looking at and they found out that some
if they basically just ate lots and lots
of password reset requests pretty much
at the same time they could end up with
it and they could force situations where
they had the same password sent to them
as well so this particular case if you
have the ability to kind of like
arbitrary reset people's passwords and
you can reset yours at the same time you
have an element of predictability as to
what that person's password is going to
be so it's something which is
interesting and something to have a look
at and we were talking about dotnet you
know is Java or any better and that
looks pretty random doesn't it maybe if
we do it two-dimensional plot you know
it looks pretty
them maybe not so so Java has exactly
the same kind of problems although its
default random number generator is a
little bit better it has much of the
same kind of problems so to summarize
implementing cryptography is hard and a
lot of the situations that we just
talked about our usage so none of the
stuff we've just looked at has anything
to do with how strong the crypto we're
actually using is in the padding Oracle
one we don't even know what the
algorithm is let alone what options
there using we don't hear it's all based
on usage so when you are implementing
things and more the point when you're
looking at other things that other
people have implemented and you're
looking at it there from from a security
point of view as well you need to make
sure that you give those things an
element of rigor around kind of how it's
designed how it's implemented in things
like that and when in doubt ask an
expert which by the way I'm not equipped
to expert but hopefully you know within
your organization or you know within
money the people that you rely on or
something like that you have somebody
who can actually take that kind of look
at something you're designing because
crypto is
you