Good morning, how good it is, I am Carlos Garay de Córdobas with space and in
this time I have to present the following talk by alan levy isr
digital bounty hunter making money by reporting vulnerabilities like this
What are you talking about? Thank you guys, everything is fine.
well, very Sunday afternoon I hope you are rested that you do not have
He wanted to take a nap, he caught on commenting on Victor's talks
the many spectacular lessons and it's my turn, it's my turn
the last talk so a great great responsibility so let's
put it cool and let's do I'll share the presentation and see
Let's go there tell me if they are seeing it well I know if we start
then as well says the title house reward if you are making money
reporting vulnerabilities and now let's see what all this means and
what is it about first of all my name as well me
I present as a boy my name is Alan Levy I am the main consult
write consultant in infinite sindh a company here in Argentina worked with
cookie with the time I send you a greeting and I am also a member of the group of
online social research from Argentina good and also justly
August of endurance in free time, those who know me will also know that
I am a curious magician illusionist, no and well, I also undertake others
types of things before starting I want to leave you these photos that are of me
first and I shared in 2011 on the left you will be able to see there that I
I was doing the look picking quality workshop should still follow
doing favors to the workshop and to the right they will see there in it
I think it was a Thursday in the after that was done there in the konex I am all
only hits and the excuse of purpose this photo
because nothing if you were never one of ccoo party I recommend that you go I kiss
to share and I just did not know absolutely anyone
and it was an incredible experience, the truth that changed my life
literally because after year after year I'm coming I made a lot of friends
There are many friends and I began to work passionately, nothing of
this about computer security and well and on top now I have the honor that the
economy invites a talk that is, a perfect circle is closed so that
that more than guests who do not know go to laity unfortunately
This year it will do online for reasons of public knowledge but do not stop
to see to be and to join well a little the agenda of today
goes one and that is a frequent questions bagua anti see suspends this platforms
more known motivation, then we will see how to select a program
analyze and understand the scope how important it is that we are going to touch is
more or less does not exceed us due to time issues but we are going to talk about the
recognition phase which is one of the most important phases and we are going to name
some methodologies and tools something super important the conception of
reports and something that interests us the most is how it is charged when we report
if we consider a vulnerability valid, we will finally mention one
community that we have armed here in Argentina and I will give some than others
details of things that come about
then first tier which is the back want and there will be many people who are in
other side that already knows what saves amount there are many people who may not
know then we are going to define it and more or less the definition that I like is
that it is a mechanism by which a company offers rewards to hackers
for finding and reporting vulnerabilities in your applications
infrastructures etc there are several types of programs for
example are those of programs that are public that anyone can access
hack or you register on the platform and basically access and voila
and then there are the private programs that you can only access by
invitation and then let's see how it is to access an invitation and others
we're going to do this from an answer to questions and answers very quick from
those of what more than the main doubts that can
arise obviously because in the end we will answer the doubts that arise from more
but some I already have them, as is known, they are the ones that first arise then by
example that is a trailer an action suit is a moderator class se
examine the validity of the report then on this platform are these trailers
who are the ones who first receive our report our report of the
vulnerability and they examine if the vulnerability is not duplicated if it is
valid and applies to them and they are skopje etcetera etcetera
who is the activist, there is no activity, they can find him with
different different names of different back mantis platforms
but basically it is the end of the public community that shows the
activities of the hackers basically there are going to show the
reports that were just published and one can see the techniques they will use
the other hackers to be able to exploit and find some vulnerabilities and
other then it is very important to pay attention to the activists and
read them frequently
what is reputation and what are most back platforms for
Huantinos grant reputation every time we find a
valid vulnerability and this reputation are points basically they are points that
one wins or loses according to the validity of the report he is sending if our
report was approved means that the vulnerability was validated then we
they are going to give a certain amount of points it can happen that we are reporting
something that serves us or that is outside the cob then there they will take away the
reputation point basically the size and amount of
points come in terms of the size of the reward and good according to how critical
be the vulnerability reported anyway this is calculated by each platform
in different ways but basically that's what it's about
how to get invitations to private programs I think is the second question
that arises when one starts in the bagual the first one that is baluard and second how
get invitations to private shows well the easiest answer is
the greater the reputation, the greater the number of programs and private, that is,
more invitations that we will receive first we will not have
invitations to private programs but then to go reporting valid things
we are going to gain reputation and that reputation will allow us to access
invitations to private programs then that is why the
reputation anyway on platforms like hacker one we have
some venues to resolve when as soon as we start and with those seven bosses
we are gaining these points and in the end we will also access
invitations only to meet some etc
what is bbb and bbb these are acronyms that did not drive me crazy when
it started and did not understand how the hand was coming and it was basically bdp en
vulnerability text closure program and basically refers to a program in
where they will not pay vulnerabilities
They're just going to accept the reports and they're obviously going to give you credit for the
hacker but they will not pay anything and then there are the bp are the anti bums
programs that are conventional where they offer rewards for
reported vulnerabilities who visited know to start good
the truth is that this is a super broad topic obviously this is not only
a bagua andy theme this is some general computer security so
I recommend starting with the 'top ten' logos obviously if it is as a key
web web security academy de by schwager of reports this that he said about the
feasibility of other hackers and follow the bagua hashtag
tips on twitter is very useful because well there are many hackers share
tips for one diverse péndex this is a whole discussion that even recently
when I had the deco or marathon there was a panel where it was discussed and others is a
I have to give for a while I do both work as a pen tester but in
my free time silly quant and I think the two things are totally compatible
and I do not think that one thing has to replace the other but that there are two
Completely different things, having said this, we are going to differentiate the pendex
as a project of a fixed duration the payment is agreed by the project
reports all kinds of
vulnerabilities from the most critical to later from the forgiveness from the
least critical to the most critical, that is, from things that could be
potential vulnerabilities to things that are actual vulnerabilities
generally there are testing schedules sometimes sometimes the company that hires
puts a schedule where the tests can be done and on the side of endurance
and we can find that there is no preset duration or contracts
pre-established nor anything nor schedules are not paid for results unlike
pentes this is paid only for results to say that you can not
invest 100 hours but if you did not find a vulnerability you will not receive a
weight report of vulnerabilities with impact
demonstrable we can report assumptions or hypothetical cases we must demonstrate
vulnerability demonstrate the impact and good there are policies of
allocate them that we have to tie that are precisely from the scouts and the
policies that put each program the bridge is good precisely in
predefined mode we have what is white hart for white world great box or
black box and good is the most popular platforms in the world of the bum
anti in the truth that every day more come out there are many so that I decided on
put only some perhaps the best known to us are hardware
background and viti and it's wefaq and we have last and puss the boots code
I want to make a special mention for bosco because it is the only one at least the
The only one I know is a Latin American Chilean Trees code
and well this one is good although the software and the
much lower rewards in money compared to the other platforms
there is also much less competition from other hackers so maybe
To start, it is a good starting point to start with a platform like
wins out good motivation we have to have one
motivation to enter this fabulous world and be able to start
observe a tris and so on and basically they immediately come to mind
two types of motivations that a person can have that are the
knowledge learning because one is going to have to read and learn a lot
in order to exploit a vulnerability first find it and then
exploiting them that makes one have to investigate
on many technologies on different types of products and the truth is that
one in the process is learning a lot that is not true on the one hand and
on the other hand we cannot be hypocrites and we have to say what the
another motivation is also money because it is not wrong to want to earn money and
it is a more than valid motivation so it is there
but besides everything if I like to be this phrase how good if one chose a
work that you are not passionate about yet no then you will not work another day no
you want steve jobs basically it's all the same no
you do pentes do bang bang computer security tips and you still do not have it
that you will be passionate because if you are not passionate if you only focus on money you will not
going to get good results I think the main motivation has to
be precisely the passion and wanting to know how things work and the
learning money is a consequence that will come for everything
this
and let's talk well about how much we talk because we are talking about money can
make money on what and how much are we talking about well I'm going to put some
examples of the hacker one platform of some public programs of the
rewards that they offer there is a table of rewards and for example this we
offers the vulnerabilities in the lou 150 dollars we are talking about dollars
Americans even the most critical who pay five thousand dollars here is another
example where the minimum is paid 50 and the critical 12 thousand 500 notice that there is
a big difference here is another where the minimum 100 and the
maximum 4000 here is another where the minimum 50 and the
maximum 2000 and finally we can find precisely hacker one has his
own for a day within your own platform where you have a very
big and notice that he even pays up to 15 thousand dollars facebook
lump has its bound and if the largest compresses are the ones that reward the most
offer but vulnerabilities are also difficult to find in these
companies is not so easy we could make a
kind of grabbing well where the more they offer us, the harder it is to find a
vulnerability you could not get to say something like that
select a good program the importance of knowing what we have
what to set when selecting a program we sign up we sign up
a platform of vantis and now what do we do to where we ran
well, I would tell you to look at first differential public programs
private if you just start up, it is most likely that you do not have programs
private so they are going to have to imply receiving if through a program
public that we are going to have to say if they want to do something web something wire by gol
of reid eject even there is hardware or they will have to say based on their
knowledge or what they want to learn what they want to do
they will have to say if they are going to use a new or old program there
programs that have had their bounty program there for many years and
some newly released programs are continually releasing new ones
programs then you're going to have to ask yourselves what
it is advisable to enroll in a new program where everyone will go
running to hit that program or I should go to a company that makes five
years that you have a bounty program and it is there I have seen good it is two
questions that one has to go asking and analyzing the advantages and
disadvantages
if he pays bounty and if he does not pay we also have to decide that and with the advantage
to go for a program where they do not pay baptize well they will not pay us bounty
but they are going to give us a lot of reputation points in return and you say
good but with the reputation points that I do I want money good but no
let's forget the reputation points are used to later be invited to
private programs and private programs are supposed to be much less crowded
spending time then maybe a good strategy when a resin
starts is to go for the programs that do not pay money to just obtain
reputation points and as they do not pay money there will also be less
competition then perhaps it is a good strategy I leave it to you so that
think is also a good idea is to analyze in
the program the totals of the gloves that have been paid since the program
was launched and the average total bounty that they have been paying because
they may pay the critical 5,000 dollars and the blogs pay them 100
dollars but the mail petro locution program means what others have
paid is the 6,300 dollars so we know that they are only
reporting low and medium vulnerabilities but not many people
reporting critical vulnerabilities then well that's already giving us the
indications about the security of the platform or the program that we are
analyzing us time to trail is a good thing for
note that basically refers to time to the number of hours or days that
take time to give our bone to validate our report from the day that since
the moment we send it, how long the platform will take to tell us and
the report is valid or invalid and time its resolution is basically what
indicates to the word is the time it takes to resolve the vulnerability or
once it was validated that they gave us the tri next is the time that
it takes the program to solve and say ready, it's ready, ready the
vulnerable and then obviously into something no less
It is important to see the cast or not and we are going to talk about the scop but it is super
It is important to analyze the coc and the previous knowledge that each one has
because if I have a lot of knowledge in what good web I will lean towards
that and I will not go to see something else then knowledge
prior to having each one, it will greatly influence the program that
each said analysis and understanding of alcohol and
This is very important because it can cause us to lose points or lose
time which would be worse not then for example we could see domains and their
domains that are in this and maybe we could see a dot asterisk
domain.com and we love to see the 'wild cards' that are the
asterisks in front of the domain because it means that any subdomain
that is in that domain will enter the code so we like that because not
limits us basically tells us in the dotcom exam is the domain and everything
that you find that they are in your domains that point here they are
accepted and we like that a lot, you can find that there are also the
mobile apps earlier today there was a very interesting talk about
precisely to applications in diabetes and the truth is that it is a good niche to hit it
It helps applications once because as many people experience playing games
getting into generating the android world but we can't forget about ios there
very few people making bounty senators I think would be a good tip to
not to rule out we cannot find that there are ranges of the network in
plan also not only everything is about web or mobile applications and well
You have to pay close attention to what Scott's out of the limitations of the
program, for example, something very common is to find vulnerabilities that
programs do not accept and they could be safe ekis ekis ekis cts or
cross sport for fair and in the wing log out or social distributed techniques
with company employees or those kinds of vulnerabilities that they don't
want to receive and therefore explicitly state in their policies that
those practices and vulnerabilities are outside the ico
and an example of a subdomain outside cop will not find that in a certain
part they will say their domain point company contact with this they are out
of the code then it may be that there is a wild-card material point company
dotcom and below clarify everything is fine just like the dotcom company
but your dotcom company domain and we are not going to include it then it is very
important to read companys forum
here are some examples to understand this is the platform with
a part of the scout of grammer live.com here we are going to see what they accept for
point institution domains grammar live.com accept vulnerabilities up to
says the column that we see in the crosses and that is up to what they accept and
On the other hand, if they pay or not, then how can we see the first three cases?
accept even vulnerable critical vulnerabilities which you want
say that all kinds of vulnerability from the lowest to the most critical
they will then accept and consequently as we see in the column at
side they are going to pay it but look at case number 4 they are going to accept
even what you mean millions for reporting something critical and in fact they
they accept critical things notice that there were even clear but those critical things
They are going to pay them like lou, it is worth saying that if in the table
of rewards the critical that pay 5000 and the lobe pay 100 in that domain
particular that they are talking there for more than one report something like a rc
They are going to pay it equal to 100 or low why because well that is their policy and
one is accepting this contract at the time of beginning to work with them and
You can also find this other in this one for example from the high soma too
our public program where you can see that these applications are are
in scouts and they do not pay, notice that the second column says that they are not is not
ineligible cannot be paid, that is, it is not paid but who accepts them are not accepted
not all as a critic and there is a very interesting item that was added that killed as
several companies that if there is an item that you are in a vulnerability
in something that is not put in the score of them that do not have it
explicitly commented you can still report this vulnerability
and the company that you are going to take and then analyze and then you are going to tell the hacker
if it applies for a reward or it applies for points perhaps or if it does not apply
for nothing in case it does not apply at all the company will not sanction you no
it will close the report and you will not lose reputation points like
it would happen normally but on the contrary they will let you close the
report yourself which makes you do not lose these reputation points with
this the company is more transparent and as it just accepts that the sheet
that they report bugs because you are interested in knowing then there are
something that they forgot to put in stock and they are also interested in knowing if
have super important reconnaissance phase vulnerabilities
the better this phase the more information we collect
in rich recognition passes more likely to be successful we go
to have to find a vulnerability and these phases where
we are going to use for different applications to search for example their
domains open ports and services directories files clicks on sources
open using techniques of or without apis web services and others it is
precisely to collect the greatest amount of information from our
objective to end after classifying it and being able to see where we can find a
vulnerability
for what is rich there are no hackers who create a methodology each one means that
has its methodology the big six are haddix
He is a hacker who is closely linked to what the anti bum is and has written a
methodology that the java devised for version 3 was recently going to launch the
version 4 but finally could not attend an event that was held in
lainez that surely next month or so it won't take long
more is going to launch version 4 but I highly recommend looking for it in
youtube and well and study it, notice that it is a video that lasts more than an hour.
to see the techniques that this person uses as he uses them and everything is
the record phase is also targeted so it is super important to me that
You do not give them a recommendation, nothing else is necessary 6 but at the foot of the
lyrics but understanding and seeing how those who already know work is I think a good
kick off and then the tools which tools we use
well the truth that millions of tools are still coming out just
if new tools are coming out but there are some that one cannot ignore
for logical reasons I put the boot suite on the left and I have the
lucky to use the professional version but if not with the version
chrome mini that would be fine too as to boot my advice is
that when they grab some silver from the gloves, the first thing they do is invest
in a work suite license and believe me it is a tool that will give you
many satisfactions and it will simplify your life and on the other hand
I have point of tools that are scripts or
tools programmed in python which the ones I put there are a bit
fair ministers but there are many and it was not like that finder 'to look for their
Test hachette domains to see if you have started web services from
true the one that fixes the urls that are that they were married in the apache web
and aquatron to take pictures of the screenshots to the wings to the pages that
do not have a secret external entity is more is carbon I think it is not necessary
introduce us to more art blocks just to work a little
parameters and the search to migrate mauro soria to dig a little in the
directories and see if we find directories and files
and if we are a little light if they are lazy there is no we do not like having to
throw all of this separately and click on each tool and have to
organize everything we can access this repository lazy corner is made by
a hacker calling nam sec who has a tweet about about computer security
and about something anti and what he did was a very nice script where from behind
thrown two titles and many others more and basically it is good to stretch it as
it says there with less than the domain and not much more my recommendation is that yes
They are in the kitchen starting and do not give much importance to this because
it is precisely about learning and if you are going to go to a script like this
that automatically does everything for you, you will be missing the most
nice that is learning so I have the status maybe even one for
see how it works from behind what are you throwing in what way throwing them but my
advice is that we do it again mein maps is a good way to
organize ourselves and have a mental map to see what is missing
where we can continue our recognition phase this is a main map
what did juan do who is part of our community of bacchus anti singer of
Argentina that later I will mention to you there read a kind of zoom where
you can see that this does not follow a flow but is a mind map is a help
memory of tools that we can pull for the different things we want
do and there is a way where how each tool is executed and then
we have the workflows that these have information where one starts by
a target and then it reaches the good domain then it starts looking for its
domains and you already have the good subdomains you can search for virtual games
c3 packages as this workflow just takes you through the
different stages there are many this is only an example I did not put the
sources because unfortunately I don't remember where I got it but how
I say there is a lot of workflow and well it's good to go analyzing the
several here I also leave a checklist
that good and make the mind thank you very much and it is great to create me
In the main arm for me to also organize it a little with my work
daily and then it seemed appropriate to share it with the community so there
is my repository I keep it updated as I can and
just as the word says it is a checklist to see that we do not
we have forgotten to do something that is interesting in this phase of
rich you don't wanna get rich use gunsan
you want to go directly to withdrawals and look for vulnerabilities
you want to do this good the consequence of doing this
always or in a large percentage it will be to obtain duplicates in the US that is
vulnerabilities that do not apply and they will deduct points from us and in the best of
the cases will close news vulnerabilities
dukes anywhere and we do not want duplicates tips I recommend using it for
everything that is rich from a virtual private server that is a pps of this
way we have many advantages you do not expose clips to a shaft or it will give you
much more speed is what one can have a home connection going to
be a 100% dedicated environment for which one wants in this case to do
bounty then we do not put our hardware or anything we can leave the
machine powered up in the cloud and working all day every day
of the year we do not have to leave our computer connected with the rhythm of
Press the light hard or the internet is cut off and the work is lost and well
If you want, I'll leave you a coupon for $ 100 to spend on the platform.
digital the option is the one I choose to have my bps you have plans from 5
dollars a month I leave them there in case you are interested
preparation of a good report is super important because suppose what already
we find a vulnerability and then now we have to move on to
inform the company what we found and note that this is
extremely important because we have to be able to transmit what
I just found the company because there is going to be someone on the other side who does not
knows what we did and we have to give it the right steps and
necessary to be able to reproduce exactly what we have just found
then we have to be very clear and concise to create another person what
can reproduce and in which the three are fixed that we said are this
kind of moderators and in giving means that they will first find
our report and they will validate it then what is it that they fix well
reports a quality report we can say that it will have a clear title in
the title we can refer directly to the vulnerability
We find it a summary of the finding that is very clear and concise in 23 regions
that what we found the steps for reproduction I think
it is something vital that cannot be missing in any quality report
just access the first step access against the user to this functionality
second step captures the river with a proxy third step modifies the beat
costs to the parameter such another well step by step well detailed
proofs of concept just if we have to give a piece of code or a
fragment of a writing just whatever it is that comes to mind that contributes
I think a proof of concept is super important video screenshots
They serve as proofs of concept and they contribute a lot to an image worth more
than a thousand words and I think it fully applies and a suggested solution is not
something that is super unnecessary but in my view it is something nice something that is not
we can forget that on the other side there is a person just like us who
instead of attacking he will be defending so to speak and he has to
suggest to your development team and others a solution and I think putting a
Suggested solution I think it will speak well of us and I was going to enter that
finally we know what we are doing and well nothing to them
I recommend putting a suggested solution and well it is an impact to demonstrate the
impact always what is spoken then a summary of the impact is I think it is
good for telling the company with this vulnerability
the company could lose x amount of money as the
licenses their dental products in point and waha does it is to demonstrate a
impact that the person who receives it immediately realizes the impact that
can produce this vulnerability is a way to open the eyes of the
to be on the other side and well, everything that you can think of is good
life what does our life not want
well they don't want a lot of kinds of things but they basically don't want this
This is a report of a user who was clearly shot from the of the
hacker platform one look at it reported a big x ss vulnerability
In other words, everything half rare ended up bathed and notice that what it said i play please
me and miami seek amy money or axis, nobody is interested in knowing your problems
You are not going to be begging for money, they will pay you only if
appropriate and these types of reports are generally not going to reach any
good port and the only thing they are going to do is put the person who
wants to talk so bring them to them they don't want this
If you want to know more about what you want and what you don't want a
bring I recommend a youtube channel that is mine that precisely
later I'm going to talk a little about that I have a video called the secrets
from a hardware trailer where gonza was interviewed by a friend who extracts
yesterday and has works as a translator in hacker one for one for a program
and well and there we were talking a lot and the
talk and on the left side they have another video with some friends with jaime dragon
chat and antonio the three of us were talking for the crown with one with whom
did I think it was last month to raise money for the red cross as well as
I did it secular parties it was for Spain and a back want forum and where also
we talked and saw several tips about things that may lead you to interest so
that is the link to antonio's channel and you can enter and watch the video there
well getting almost to the last part which is the interesting thing then ok and how
These are charged from the bounty because I did a good recognition phase
I found a lot of information about the company I started to analyze I found the
vulnerability I could exploit so I made a super report
interesting very clear very concise I sent it with its reproduction step
I grab the trailer the 3rd said see this is a valid report it is not a duplicate no
it is nothing is valid put a civility said that it is critical that it is mean that
balance whatever and finally the company comes says congratulations
we were able to validate your vulnerability we are working for them to spend a few
days there is again a concept of part the company the company corrects the
vulnerability and they tell us very well congratulations you won
the reward and they tell you how many blocks it pays
and then how do you charge well basically there are two common actors in
almost all platforms that are bitcoin on the one hand and paypal on the other
we can charge our under our go by bitcoins and by paypal and from
there some subas actors emerge, so to speak, which are for example
ripio prex local cloud bitcoins air el tien and many other platforms
here I put some of the means because we are going to have the money so much
in tweet as as cover but we are going to have to get that money from some
way so we want to remove it and not leave it here the same these are some of
the solutions that exist in the market there are many others as we know
here in Argentina there are some limitations with what the dollar is and
more so well I'll give you a little research TV but I don't know
worry so much about this, first you have to worry about finding the
vulnerabilities and make them valid
finally I leave you then the [ __ ] night this that means yes that
they are the hacking night good to hakim night they were born at the end of last year
basically it is a tweet that I make weekly there in tweets tv point
wizard bars where we talk about topics related to computer security
most of the time they are beichuán tip themes but there are times like
last week ruth and valen visited us where they told us about
head hunting and it was not a motto specifically to go glove and lose
a very interesting topic that the community liked so much so I invite you to be
tuned in and follow me around and well if you are interested you will be able to see
what are we talking about the previous emissions as you know in
tweets do not delete tweets I think every 14 days the videos so they can find
previous broadcasts on my youtube channel
and well, basically that's what it's about jaquimeyes everyone is
invited to participate I am a kind of presenter on the days that we do not have
live guests it is me who shows something obviously but as always
I say and repeat it hakim night is an open space for the community in
where everyone who wants to show something and share something to the community lets me know
contact me and the space is just for us to do it
Among all no one you stay points great this is one of the topics that
we were playing lately for example we talked about the organizers by
forges and sometimes everything like the issues of specific vulnerabilities
and the wise of terms go want and for people just starting out
unfairly wants to know about some terms that are not understood
we talked about how to make money by automating processes in which
Stamina and well just what I was telling you about last week of triage
hunting and we also had other talks from other super interesting girls denis
and Cecilia talking about hardware hacking and nothing else I invite you to yes
They are interested in looking for it and they are all published and finally talk to them about
the community we have created a community called the anti-Argentine corps the
you can search in telegram this community generally we the group that
we have in telegram it is private but I decided to open it for today so if they are
watching they can search among the great anti-Argentine ship they can join the group and
well we are all for him all here if you are going to see this video
recorded surely and look for bhagwan that Argentina will not find it but
They write to me on twitter and we have no problem adding them
we simply keep the group as private closed for what
I have nothing more or less control of who is there else
of this community and together with my dear family companion I send her a kiss
huge we have organized some events for example in January we organized a
event next to hacker one where 60 hackers and in real time hitting him
together to the same and the same program with very good and starbucks that provided
some gifts and some prizes was more very interesting a few were made
thousands of dollars as a reward that several winners took there there was a
award to the best hacker and charcoal pulse which backpacks stickers good until
starbucks in addition to putting them baptized put a gift cards to drink coffee
we contacted there is a very nice space in word obelisk where we feel very
comfortable and we had a super great lunch on the terrace.
we had an incredible time the idea was to redo some of
these events throughout this year no one had kobe 19 so
obviously the face-to-face events that we had planned to do throughout the
year were temporarily suspended but I can tell you that we are
thinking of doing something online so be connected that surely within
of little and more news we are trying to give you a little
this young woman is one of the photos we take
some go well and two later we went we did an after good that's what
nice of the face-to-face events do all the online events are great
but face-to-face events have this that a wine is great
people from the pampas came people from the sea silver came to people from rosario people came
from uruguay the uruguay team in this photo had both had to go
precisely so as not to miss the ship back but this that was armed with this
community is to build a very nice community of people with all levels of
knowledge and eager to share and learn among all that I think
what is fundamental and what stands out in this community that today we are more than 200
people in their Argentinean masters but there are also people who are not from
Argentina is not a limitation so know that if you are from other countries and
they also want to add they can be added without any problem
people or things or hashtags some hashtag that should follow good to them
I recommend the want factor and tips on twitter and here are some people and what
somehow have some major influence on what is going glove and
computer security in general and there are thousands of people could not put to
all in one slide but I decided to make a selection of some tones does not have some
you contribute some tools some incredible tools 'insiders' and have more some
terrific tutorial videos jason holdings as he told them with with
their hamsik methodologies that have their tweets that also shows things very
interesting everything that is a bit a summary being an albino with his techniques
impressive well nothing I leave you there in your twitters do not forget to follow them
because the truth is that they are people who contribute a lot to the community
And as yoda says, don't try it, no yes, or if you're going to do it, I'll do it or not
do but do not try to get into it fully it is important to be determined to
do it and well put passion into what we are going to do you always have to do the
things with passion and as I said at the beginning the purpose is going to be to learn
and being connected in community and money is going to be something that a
consequence that will come alone well thank you very much and open to
questions that can answer very good the truth magician
I have two cycles without further question is reported things that
They say they don't apply and they don't pay and then I see that the rule says it's possible
that somewhere keep a change and that although it does not work
are things that one will never never know not the background of faith but still believe
many doubts the truth that does not believe are the majority platforms at least
I know that they are extremely serious and handle things in a super way
professional anyway if one believes that one reported something and they did not take it
as valid and you are convinced that this vulnerability is valid can open a
kind of mediation, for example in urban osaka you can ask us for a
mediation has happened to me where a mediation has been opened and I have won it
because well finally the other side are human beings and all human beings
we were wrong in his whole being that maybe it was wrong and speaking one goes
understanding the same I recommend if one is 100% sure that what is reported
It is valid then to ask for a mediation we have there a house work team
rewards or you usually work individually there are many people who work
as a team and in fact there are many platforms that are accepting this from
work as a team and the platform proposes the division of social bounty that
you can invite your partner to the report and automatically that
reward or it will be divided and I think that one can choose the amount is the
percentage give him 20% and give me the remaining 80% because good is the
decision we made and well I think that more and more is pointing to that and
I also believe that there is an intention of at least in hacker one to do something something
similar but with the reputation points that can also be divided
between the different members it has its advantages and disadvantages I believe
that it is very advantageous to work in a team one as one goes by tension
so i only recommend now i have 13 what if one finds
a bar that at the level of an experience level one detects that it is critical
but the company does not want to admit that it is a vulnerability that can be done
I think there is more or less the issue of migration and if it is more or less what
we talked before it is a little mediation for that are the trailers of each
platform then well we will have to talk to them and explain and give them
our reasons why we believe that the criticality of the
vulnerability is higher than what they are finally proposing the
The program will have the last word, they are the ones who pay and that's it, but everyone
we have tools to fight it and demonstrate the impact that
it's finally that's what it's all about with all of us the more we can demonstrate the
impact of a vulnerability, the more likely we are that the
criticality also rises sometimes as active banks are made or it does so in a
station no good there is everything the truth there is
companies that do not have a problem where they are made in their environments
productive there are many times that in the policies they tell you please don't throw them away
you have too limited your quantity of rich is per second to 6 x quantity
rich is per second or they ask you this kind of thing and they ask you to include some
special header in requests to be able to identify where they are from
coming on request or they ask you to register on their platform with an alias
that provides for example the hacker platform want you offers you a guide to
your mail then happy that way they can identify the users
who are doing this work and maintaining many other platforms
that publish a place with a statistics or testing area for the
tests and good act depends on each company
We can see it says we have some blue for water amount in windows I would believe that
that is more oriented to the blue which is used for well wood suite is
cross-platform so I think the answer blames fine having a report of
example to share I have there are a lot of reports examples
I would recommend as I said in the talk to look at the activists
activists all the reports that were made public so read
those reports are going to find out which are the best written reports that
others so the law to go down that path well what characteristics should
have one you ask me to do the lazy anti ram terabyte etc. I am
driving with the minimum that I think is a gig of ram he was wrong 112 gig of
ram is not much more than that, if I'm not wrong about the disk, it has 50 gigabytes.
something very simple because the tools occupy us too much
space we all we want is a machine is turned on with a
good connection and nothing else so with the minimum option that it offers for example
type the option there are a lot of times but with minimal action chests in them
it's going super well what can be done wagon you knowing
little programming knowing a little programming
obviously I do not consider myself the programmer I am studying the car at
who take more advantage of health also people ute n I am just learning
programming obviously knowing programming is going to nurture one on the
knowledge that we have and it will give us more tools but it is not something
It is essential to know the programming more and that I encourage you to learn try
cen but it's still metal
if I get bounty in a virtual machine it is the same as having a pc with
cali on linux
if I do not see a difference, it is basically a bertolo you can configure
the hardware you want to have in and is good I recommend using one
virtual if you do not want to pay a beep and have more one virtual and milk and that's it
good to have separate work machines or the ones we use
to play what the bounty is because we are going to be installing installing
new tools every day and well even good we have out there
differentiated what happened that still bring be saved
vulnerabilities to report it to them if not it did not happen to me and I hope it does not happen to me
I would never speak highly of them and I think that if they realized it they would be more than
sanctioned by the platform because we do not forget that for them it is a
work they work from that it is not that they do it like we do it
for a reward they of their work is that oil also as well as in their
work you have automated the monitoring of your
target I'm starting to put something together actually
I have a video where he talked about it and I tell a little about the tools
automation and I show more or less where what is done not me but
I am currently doing things more manual than automated but the idea
I am putting together something there to do in America, each account does the monitoring
not monitoring basically I have a system that sends me alerts for
telegram when new domains come out and the idea is to grow this
script to process those subdomains a little more if you don't just send them to me
when a subdomain appears but send something more elaborate and power or this
subdomain I found that there is this or that file in this subdomain is the idea
finally having to work as little as possible is what gets us there
more chewed but I'm on the road to health all good to the inside in what
moment you have to stop hitting a vulnerability to avoid problems
in a possible injection you have to get to what point
well that will be defined in the policies basically of each
program but once the injection is already demonstrated, it is already
could you demonstrate the injection ready the injection will usually pay between
haye and critical most of is going to be critical
then well that's it there is not much more to do in fact it will be half almost
It will always be forbidden to climb much more because well we could
get into a problem you have to read well how the policies of each
program to be sure of the kinds of things
I am a beginner, how do I not frustrate myself in case my reports
have already been reported or are not considered risk for the
frustration is something we have to deal with every day and be
beginner or you are not a beginner it will be there
frustration knocking on the door of your house every day and it is something that
we have to drive it will always happen to you that there will be times that
find vulnerabilities that will happen what will happen time where not
find a vulnerability and you will start to rethink if they really are
good for this or do you have this famous impostor syndrome and then nothing
one has to start managing frustration and realizing that good
sometimes there is also a bit of luck in finding vulnerabilities in many
factors, my recommendation is that if they are not going to dedicate 100% to working
doing bound is that they have it as a hobby and that if they are with something very
obsessed and does not go out and well disconnect a little to gain activity
also and if the only thing they are reporting their vulnerabilities are duplicates
Well, we are on the right track, it means that someone found them before
person is paying for it but then they are on the right track they have to continue and
vulnerabilities that are not duplicated are going to appear, well I can get in
in legal problems making this yes clear if one does not respect the cops
just program policies if they can get you in legal trouble
precisely the policies of each program so for that
luckily the world has advanced a lot and now companies allow us to
hack the interns who get in trouble or the companies invite us
to encourage and pay us is for it but we have to respect what the
more company says so if you have to be careful
Well, let's see if we have another question for which percentage you dedicate to a
new company verses a company that you already worked
I particularly like to target companies that already have a certain
amount of time with a bounty program I am not one of those who publishes
a company but in a public company its bounty program and runs
When I see what he finds, I understand that there is a race to see who arrives
first and who first reports the things that may appear but the
Most of what I have reported were things from companies that already had a
some time in with his bounty show so he devoted a lot more to it
time to that are not ways how I say this is
something that I do as a hobby in my free time so I do it 23 hours at
nights and not much more than that we are going to close there are a lot of
questions I invite you to answer if you can and if not you can also
write on twitter no problem so we are
let me let you are not leaving five points so let me then had
project to give a big greeting to all the people of hacker space to the ute n
I do it for the invitation and for the space, the truth was that there were two
Excellent days and well, super happy from the bottom I was able to do
this here I have a I did which dictionaries recommended to use or which ones are
use va want bases and used dictionary choices
he used one called the text point and which is made by jason
haddix which is the one who mentioned the talk in his global gif repository
You will find the dictionaries that the
go buster tool that good now is not being used anymore of this
tool but using maurel's tool from ir search show
Basically use of their dictionaries or that of the being brings a dictionary himself
built-in that like to do a quick detection to see if there are any
little thing is very very viola without passing the dictionary already has as a dictionary
incorporated so equally in my advice is to build your own dictionary
always the best for your own dictionary
look here there is a question that is very good because it is flame at the level of the other
side to company level to company level to make me back bounty that
platform arme recommended well the truth is that I never
Forget I never faced it from the other side obviously for obvious reasons but
I think the hacker one has jacagua novak but they don't have the models of
very well cooked businesses and the largest number of hackers are concentrated
in those two great platforms therefore
3 I guess I don't know I guess their services must be a bit more
expensive perhaps others but also in the amount of hackers that we can reach
Finding on these platforms is superior so I would evaluate it like this
which I think could be a very good alternative and if not there is also ours
Latin American platform fertilizers as Fernando said I have the last one the back
the one that goes first when it starts to make a page
no there is no one first the truth that there is no one first I think it is one
web application searched for some there are two is not all the audios are very easy to
detect I usually look on that side to see if there are problems in what is
authorization and others and if not information leakage information microsoft things
that they should not be public to a link of some pic and that kind of thing but
Well then, it's going to look at the application itself and see what comes up, no, no, no
something punctual and we can have problems if the
ip in the ppc apps if you can get there with reaching the bps wallet but the advantage
What you have to know that it exists is that we destroy it and create another in two minutes
so there would be no problem and we already have a new ip so that is the advantage for
that is the best thing is not to put our ip that bar extensions that are really
useful for the bounty program there are many, the truth is that I invite you to
let them explore later we have talked about those in the hacking
knight but nothing there is one called collaborator
heuer that is injecting hairs of the collaborator that is one or something that brings
the burj that is very useful to us to find vulnerabilities related to
servers airport for haiti and others that is a very good extension and then
It will depend on the technology we are using, we have an active campaign more than
It's like we're going to provide more, more roads, more than other things
there are many many that well I recommend it just as I was saying to
see in the machine that we have talked about that
has in your case are more than finding bucks
critical medium low or you aim for quality or quantity did not aim prime
lopez arena o2 points sincerely not that I'm going to go saying to barabbas and
reported only criticism not the realities that reported what I believe
that can lead to valid vulnerabilities
obviously I try not to report things that do not work or that in my opinion will
be even if they are not applicable but then a critical vulnerability is found
good great but although a 'low I will report it anyway I do not care is
a vulnerability after all, one as a hacker has ethics as ethics
you have to report any vulnerability later if it is
a good review much better to the clear connecting I made them say how much I know
wins and that depends on the record in time devotedly from home is the
time is the program there are programs as we said that do not pay so it is the
time the dedication the knowledge that each has also the share of
luck, as I was saying, no, you can't estimate, you can't, the truth is
something that cannot be estimated in networking programming system
operations than the most important to do an mba with general people protocol
https knowing a little about that is important enough if we are going to hit it
web applications to pee a bit of everything basically have
You have to understand what it is that you want to aim for.
do more some infra good then some network and others that will come very
fine but if you want mobile web applications good to understand https protocols and
others will be fundamental so it depends on what they want to do
good how much do you know that you are studying in n-ii and why years last night
to study a technical degree in programming
I was now half grown up I am 34 years old I had gone through several
undergraduate degrees and I never finished any and I said I have to do something but
because I wanted to learn and do something so I ordered the out n
They have very good technical degrees, they are based in Avellaneda and I am
studying a technical degree in programming and it is two years says the
first year already relevant and now I have finished so good we are studying
there the second year later one can articulate with you can point to a
degree career but I think it's a good ping point and be like for
start with the technique if one does not want to start fully in the
engineering or something that you already know very well that it will be many years
well well let's go thank you very much indeed many of us know that it is a topic
quite requested
we are leaving and we are going to close in a little while I remind you that
It is in the after so everyone stay but I thank you very much thanks to
you for the invitation and open for any type of question contact me
by social networks