to all to all to all thank you very much for joining by participating in the
that this would be the first edition of university talks in this first edition
we have the opportunity to have the university as organizers
national technology of cordoba in the boys of cordoba from 'hackers' space les
I want to say that until yesterday we had 1,780 registered through
even drive and there are a lot more people who are going to be joining
directly to the stream so don't forget to sign up for tweets to
to be able to interact, they can ask us questions there and ask questions to each speaker
me now that they are going to be exhibiting today tomorrow
remember that this morning also starts at 12 noon
let's start a bit with introductions for people who don't
do you know I am matt I am one of the organizers of the whole
context of what it is shared and I am mainly in charge of coordinating the
content with the entire wonderful community that we always have
available at our fingertips and without going any further I will now present to the
boys from cordoba hacker face real and let him introduce himself to them boys
go ahead good how are you all thank you all
My name is Carlos, but here it is a pooch, I am part of the foundation of the
founds founder of psychologists before the space
together with other colleagues so I passed my goat friend thank you very much
well how are you welcome everyone thank you very much for being my name is joaquín
Rodríguez Varela and he is also my ally, he was esteemed and also together with Carlos and
with other members we are the organizers of this space that is the
córdoba hacker space if it seems to you for the people it has it
Hello, good morning, how are you doing, Roberto?
Muñoz tells you about the truth that it is a pleasure to start these activities
I came with waiting in Cordoba so well in my case I am director of the
ute information systems engineering degree at regional faculty
Córdoba and also a teacher in the races so we are at the disposal of the event
and he is accompanying me at this moment in engineer fabián pennini
Hi, how are you? The truth is that welcome everyone and thank you very much for
be and for having had the possibility that we can be present in this
event that for us is very important and good in my case I am
responsible for the systems degree laboratory in which
we increased a lot for the info sector community
good good very good I gave this panel to all the people who
are listening at the moment it would be a bit to comment what is the link with
the organizing team or at least this edition of specifically with the
safe informed tica since I shared it for those who do not know it although still
they had some doubt out there what it is about well today we are a
company that is dedicated to making events related to computer security
to see a question particularly for the guys from 'hackers' page as they think
that you joined that if in the computer security for a little more from
for several years as you think I know that computer insurance was incorporated into the
province of cordoba just a couple of years ago now 15 years had
a community of hacks that belonged to the boys of Córdoba street
we actively had a couple of months doing some talks take the girls
in a bar with a sponsor and for one question or another
it was stopped making and good last year along with frames that they presented to us
Being what korda we were introduced to in las vegas at defcon
We said something we have to have in Cordoba
so luckily we made the first visa in cordoba back to break a
second tell me how it was that they met there in two Cordobeses the smoke
in a niche that is computer security in las vegas if the ships were going to talk
in black hat in the arsenal and well they introduced us in the in the
party at the white welcome party
It was seen and we made visits at night with the symbol at the closing of the visa and
well it was joaquín let's also say we have to have something else
more more often and more guys then get a chance to be a hacker
space in good settings at the time I was working at a company that mcafee and
raised the need and well mcafee gave us the opportunity to have a space
physical and good from October and October
we started the opening and there we already started with the events when with obviously in
all social networks
be active and good today we are in online mode and we already have a good
public that follows us and every 15 days we are trying to do events and
listen to me in what year was the first contact covers and córdoba de por
less from your observable universe no cordoba safe computing is those
talks that take place wherever you want
2002 and 2000 and 2001 and 2011 more or less 2013
enough but we were few and what yes there were many many boys of the favor of
the Córdoba Mathematics Faculty and well they give a lot of talks too
that today they are also members of the
and in games you did not always live there we did not go for a short time for
labor agreements I worked as a tractor with one of the companies that
They used to work in Buenos Aires so I had the opportunity to meet you there
but what was the reason of your life to leave and let alone in that company
what mission has been working but well nothing I was a personal decision for
a matter of living a little more calmly and escaping a little with doing is
many of us know there and play in those relationships will continue in
n share and of course that is what fosters that space
our days we see each other in Las Vegas and I live here
3 km and I do not see it I am quite new so I stopped answering this
ask because I'm pretty new to what the security community is here from
Cordoba before what I mentioned chicho is something
that caught my attention because when they organized the visa
and I said obviously I'm going to go because I want to know the community like that
security here and I was struck a lot but a lot by the amount
of people and I told them I mentioned that to make a first event that
on top of that well they were lucky that let's say that well no luck if not
They made it perfect and it came out great in the after with this one there taking some
beers with them I told them it seems to me that you have to exploit that this community
continues to develop because there are many many people and there is a lot of interest that is
weird to see that so I'm like this just got here trying to do things
I also suggested that we do a 'jam session' or something and well that later
He ended up riding on this which is left wanting face but I from my side and from
my humble vision of someone who has just arrived I believe that Cordoba has a
gigantic potential to man refers to security and people with very
trained and also people with a lot of desire to learn so it is good that
successive developing ok and it was introducing with more in perspective
that you have said, I was talking about the gift of 2011, more or less you of the
university side leave in what time more or less were you seeing it in what
way was introduced and give the error actually in the formal
what is our current curriculum is 2008 and security
is transversal in different curricula in different spaces that we have in the
subjects this is a plan although it is from ute ny shared with voices
regional more currently in what is happening in the universities is
say in our curricula in different ways we have implemented
security and even outside the curriculum are also implemented what
are elective subjects with the central security theme that is not looking at
future, that is, currently the universities and through what the
nation's education ministry approved as reserved activities
for degrees like ours in bachelor's degree engineering that
they are in what is computer science systems we already have specifically
a reserved activity in which in the next study plans of all
the country's universities are going to have to reflect content activities and
compliance with what is security within the study plan that is to say and
Now formally it is a requirement since it is effectively reserved for the
universities, the issue of security carries much more weight than it could
have in previous years in other large studios
and with regard to the races here there is a user who asks if they do not have a
plan from the ute side to implement a career specifically
security or if it has not happened in the past
In reality, what has been done in the formalization of education rather than
everything is done in specializations and masters is currently oriented
mainly to what is the degrees the generation of a curriculum of a
new career, the truth is that it takes a long time to reach different
spaces that have to be approved and given us
the place and the budgets for which this also currently limits
we are mainly in specialization and master's degrees in many
universities in the country the issue of security
does not add
is what I propose is since ute n for several years we come
commenting from the laboratory the possibility of uses precisely in the
mainly free open technologies
and we gradually got into the security aspects
I believe that little by little we have also been promoting the community internally
let's say when it comes to safety and well
I think I saw Saiz was the one who united us together with Marcos and Chicho and Joaquín and
well we were able to move forward together and good also to have the possibility today
to be in this event that for us is very important and
mainly for the infosec community here in Córdoba and this fruit from
left it open I do not know the background of the boys related to the
academic aspects but they can still give their opinion from outside as they believe
both from outside the university and within the institutions that
computer security was cleaning or was modifying influencing the
races races because within the context of what is shared and everything
that at least we try to do within the objectives and visions that
we have as a company what we do is promote what is the
shift left not like inside let's give an example the development cycle
try to explain to people that computer science is not
something that is added later is a security file that should be worked on
from the beginning not before that's why the chipset is like that inside all
the processes further be no matter what kind of methodologies you use to try to
moving it more to the left no more towards the beginning as they think that yes
if it was done that way if it was progressive or how it has been since
their perception that this was being introduced to the academic environment
university student only to me what I think happens to many of us
is that we are in the communities that all the time are wondering how
did you do to learn where did you learn then
that's that great question that has existed for a couple of years, I think I also vote
to what is the university environment then where they realize I think
that there where they realized that if there is here there is something else that is one I will
put more than a schedule has that there are other activities then
from what I see in the universities
are aware that people are interested in safety and I think
that's why they are putting the batteries at this time for a couple of years too
I personally knew what an insecurity diploma is here in Córdoba
which was for me something very strange and obviously it was experimental and today in
day is already a solid diploma
we had not followed the line of what the boy says
and prepare it for the people you get that I think are the eminences in this
issue to me on a personal level it seems to me that as
we say more
and the fact that security is something that is so dynamic and goes
changing with so much speed and that it is true that it is very difficult to
Sometimes a university curriculum will follow the fact of the appearance
security specializations and that those specializations capable and
have a much more dynamic curriculum update regularity than
a career that does not have a process to be approved it seems to me that
are let's say you are allowing the development of security at the
academic is much more advanced but it is also good that there is also a
bunch of non-formal channels to follow too
learning and training and certifications but I do believe that for
at least in recent years it is a very dynamic environment and it is coming
changing and comes trying to conform and again to reach the race with
what is good security development
yes yes in they pose a little to what I am going down here totally agree on at the level
University, as Roberto said two times, the plans have been changing because it is
totally dynamic in the aspect in which all of us are incorporated
and I think that somehow it is being understood not only what the
need and I always said that in each unit of one of each subject one
have the security unit but start incorporating it as boxing
raised throughout the cycle is precisely that need to understand that
We cannot wait for this product to be ready but we have to start from
much earlier which from the academic point of view that they are modifying
We are now incorporating them and that will bring about better
results as well as from the internal groups of the laboratory
collaborates with the subjects precisely to help in aspects that out there
they cannot achieve it because they do not have the expertise and we collaborate so that
students have the necessary level for the job opportunity and I join the
that joaquín raises that it is not only the university but also
suggest that in parallel I believe that having so much dynamism the fact of being
here in listening to security contributions it is important for them
also see the way and taking and good and just new knowledge about
about what they like to learn and others, that is, it is not only formality
university but also being self-taught
and take, let's say, of the different courses that are even free, all that adds up
I believe that this community I fully join a precisely a
list that you have enjoy a text that you have to be armed that is very
well and that I find very interesting to share to feel that you are
just starting up and well there I am going to what to throw in that link in the group in
the chat of tweets and now I'm going to ask a question from roberto de las
several people who are talking to cadel evans as they want to know some
little things is the link that the user just passed
share and in tweets is basically came from a student panel that put together
I echo it about three years ago
that ends up solving, so to speak, the problem or all the questions that
they did us in university settings that when I gave talks several
years and I got together with people that I admire a lot who have also been
doing the same so what we did was basically
there is quite subjective but it has gone from empirically in the experience of
people who are involved and people from the environment answered questions that
We saw that they were repeated so if they enter that link they will be able to see a lot of
You ask how does the word hacker mean that
is to be a hacker who does not work out different mechanisms studies
it is convenient for them to do a career it is not convenient to have a career it is appropriate
being certifications does not agree with other certifications and within everything it has
as a motivational medium tint that is not really necessary as that
Motivation also arises when you read that not necessarily peacefully for the
career in computer science in terms of employment but also motivates women
people to take responsibility for their own and that if there is something that serves you
go that way for example if in my case having the university helped me
like structure but being self-taught and a lot of decision things
computer science that they go to the university name I did not foresee then the
I had to look elsewhere because here in Tandil it is not computer safe
then it's good not to get stuck as if to say new but to the
university is not giving me this and well if there are a lot of things the
University of the structure that teaches you to work with people who by and
not in the legio climbs that are a work environment a lot happens to you
teaches you to have a deadline teaches you to organize yourself teaches you to document yourself
teaches a lot of values ​​that unless you get them by force
working with the possibility of having a work complication
everything is given in a quite interesting and safe environment but if there is
issues that they feel they have to solve and the university not only
plan to look elsewhere you do not have to stay jobs or you work like no
but this, what happened to me at one point, you can see it here
Roberto I have the questions here that there are a lot of interested people
we have 500 beavers at the moment and the truth continues to rise that we are very
happy and happy that they are adding us so if they continue doing
questions I'm going to be passing on to the boys here
and they asked how the programs are evolving or
subjects that try to incorporate safe informed ethics
that's one and let's start with this one and if you believe tdt you
I will do the following after seeing the beginning although our spaces
curricula have certain structures, the truth is that it was very
intelligent the curricular design and the ministerial resolution that gave us
Javier in 2008 our current study plan because within those
spaces there is a series of minimal contents but ultimately with the
chairs with teachers with coordinators and with whom we come
living in the middle we have had the possibility of adapting, that is to say that
within the subjects to say operating systems
upper management that works with databases of information networks
communications in each of these subjects including what is
programming, the security issue begins without the need for a
formal question as a minimum content what I mentioned a while ago is that
already through resolution and editorial if formalized is the need and the
obligation of our careers to incorporate computer security
with a space of its own this that Fabián receives us in our previous plan
Security is transversal, that is, it appears in different units of
different subjects currently the requirement is already one
own existence of security and this we have been talking about in different
academic spaces of which we are taking part
the engineering network in computer bar systems that we have at the
national with more than 35 opportunities that we work careers of systems and
computer science that studies the vehicles arguing and when she did not leave the
draft of the minister of education and the simple interuniversity council the
concept of incorporating security in fact that we saw as logical
load is logical in our environment and in particular in corda the participation of
companies in the middle since the arrival of multinationals or the
creation of what is the short technological plan for more than two hundred
companies are as partners as members of that cluster make Cordoba a
space in which the development of informatics the development of
computing is normal and within that what is
safety as essential and in fact that the thought that we did last year
with the hacker guys you are in the faculty showed the interest of the
students but also people who are working in the middle for
participate and in fact that the registration you have had to share in this
presentation without being in person without being buenos aires and personally in the
grateful to think inside because that is more important and in
definitively it was going to be in face-to-face mode and we hope not
Let's forget about this for a next year of radio cinema shows a very avid medium
safety and to discuss these issues and to share the experiences and
listen to all the people who can provide advice and knowledge
I have a reflection talking a little about what you said why
reminding me a bit in the past I was also in the position and in the
situation of finding myself saying it was a computer security career
I want a career in computer science but then I say if I do
awareness and I say that computer security would have to come as a basis
in all the underlying concepts being taught then it would be wrong and
there was a career in computing because you, as comfortable people, also
you say the computer series in the race you see all the subjects in a
transversal then a difference would have to be made as
computer action is like saying be something that today is like
say i want a computer degree how to say i want a
programming career today because if we are talking about
engineering and computer science development software is obviously
programming will be included and good for us having perspectives on
computing is today security has to be included then in the case
of what is a career more oriented to software development would have to
These come included from the base secure programming policies and in
any case make a career apart no this i'm not thinking too much but
but to make the differentiation a bit not a race part that
be more holistic in terms of non-target-oriented training security
software development but aimed at having a basic concept of programming
and an understanding of the operating system architectures
design and computer security in general to be able to audit I do not know
what would you call it but that differentiation seems good to you, why if you ask us
a computer science election war and after that is to finish elaborating in the
software development if you don't have to do science age no
you have to do careers by specialization is normal is that the
format of our careers ultimately generate training and
sufficient basis so that the students in the course of the
five years begin to visualize the profile that interests them by looking at the whole
panorama that we have and all that software life cycle that we are proposing
you just killed then later you are going to dedicate let's say when one returns
of the faculty says oh and now and now is when you have to put yourself to see in
what and specialize because let's say if you like the topic of hitting positives from
security issue if you like the issue of networks we have a panorama
too broad of what computing system computing and indeed in the
current environment we all live together and those who did not have a career coexist
college who did a course who did a degree who did a
specialization and who did a doctorate and all are in companies
obviously working with different profiles and possibilities out there in
some cases but all are living together in this environment is the reality
It is one more question that has occurred to me because Fabián can answer it to me
ask about the ute laboratory is only for students or can
participate in any way a person other than a regular student by
example in the case of the systems laboratory
we usually concentrate groups that are usually students of the career
systems but we have open a game that is through certain
tools such as people who normally do not attend college
tools through some virtual means to be able to have
communication in which we also have challenges so that they can go
joining the proposal is precisely making a more open game
normally we have always worked with internal students of the faculty
we have been working like this because they are the ones who approach again obviously not
It is not outside staff usually the guys who are not from ute n
They look around in others in other sectors and well we did not find out but
the idea is to open up the community a bit but we also have the community of
hacker space which seems to me to be a totally valid space in this
we also participate as hiding we try to be also present in
the events of them and I think we see a physical place is not necessary
but it is for the community info I know that in Cordoba
you get either the cordoba hacker space or I think we are all
the same and well we go that way but this does not respond to responds game
and now I ask a question to all of you related to this ok
precisely the foot and good that it gave me and fabián shock and to mention that that they know
that if they are also looking for some kind of laboratory and tests that I eat well
said they had this one not only drops space we are an open community and
It has no cost to be part of it you can join we do ctf if we do a
a lot of activities that we go just that what a place of
apprentice learning forgiveness and relaxation
and the idea is that they also build a community with different knowledge
different different parts of the training security that quite broad
is nothing and you are looking for some references that can help
teach these practices to those who are interested in learning the
look just with if I don't know if you want to say something roll if you just add a
detail everything that is an event that has been published since our career since
our faculty are open to the public that is to say one thing is to enter a
laboratory where the chairs normally make use of the laboratories
but any event should rehearse the talk we do with the companies of the
even because companies also offer us the possibility of
buy with their specialists that is always open to the public
then it seems to me that it is also another way of adding and in fact that
acquaintance arose with the boys from caracas well adjusted the question that
I wanted to do it was a little to all and related to this but more specific
How do people get in touch? They are from Cordoba, imagine
No people from Cordoba or people outside at this time too, but how do you do?
someone who wants to enter the world of computer action to
get in touch in Cordoba with someone for what
will accompany its beginnings is a somewhat abstract question I just asked
repairing a little all the questions that people have been asking like I am
student and now that the laboratories are not closed enough to
to introduce myself in the information technology where where do I go if I am in
Córdoba and I want to get together, so if you want you can try a little of all the
information and resources available to them the same as roberto said
of these events that they organize that are open to the public as they do if
They want to see space just as I was saying it is different, juaco not only
we are very active on social media on twitter sda
hacker space and the pointer is cordoba hacker space and
we have the site that is cordoba oscar space point by axis and well now
We also have the YouTube channel where we are uploading all the
activities that are virtual and there you can contact we are
always available to answer questions and is obviously super open
to any query and slack just the part of the most part of
community that we have on twitter we have to incriminate a slack where
we have a lot of channels where all the security issues are
computing and all these things that we are all interested in are discussed are done
consultation we help each other also sometimes someone is left with a
problem and among the whole community we try to help him so it's good
yes they want to join a community
that's a good start I value from the womb
well actually at the ute level the cordoba regional faculty is our
general page of all the depth that is www frc 12 point educ.ar there
all the careers are all that are training in what would be done from
Diplomas courses talks are demonstrated there and within what they are
departments and careers this engineering in systems that when the event out there
It is smaller and does not allow to be published on the faculty page because
really there all elements of the faculty come together we do it from the
department and it is also published so on that page you have efe rd fr s
tn edward there you can search our lanes and also to find
proposals well there he was sharing and
liked in the chat that they are seeing the slack if it happens after the game to
slack lets speight been but if it happened by fact
gonzález the link with the direct invite 16
perfect and now we have a few minutes left but
to close we are going to ask some more questions we are going to take a few
questions from the public so if you want to ask some questions let's go
to be doing them before the closing of
this this first segment I do something related more than anything
to the work environment not because you are not passing from the beginning the
beginnings for people who have a little more experience because of it because
we weren't talking much if you want mining
and it is not necessary either because there are a lot of companies that have the
ability to see that with all the labor demand in the world of
security and here sometimes much more is provided than training a
person who is very proactive self-taught for different periods of several months or
the time it takes before you spend a lot of resources searching
a person with a fairly specific profile and who could not in Cordoba
Would it be achieved or not it would be repositioned that depends on how each company handles it
no, but sometimes there are companies that have that vision
but they see that opportunity to me for example that happened to me so I say that
there are companies that ask such questions that in
How do they consider the current security market to be in an ethical way?
córdoba specifically and says in a way that they can advise you
someone so you can have your first beginnings having knowledge
or without having knowledge
of course please at a business level there are several companies that already have their
security department here in córdoba well in my case I work in a company
telecommunications and we have the security area is prominent and part in
Buenos Aires I also know there are companies that
that they have Jesus has his suggestion also here in
Córdoba also has the digital part in Buenos Aires, well we have a
company that remains of antivirus that is here in Cordoba also good that it is more
space and I think that within the scope of security it was already about
45 years and older as companies are realizing that the
safety is very very important when that where we have more participation
and we also have the possibility of working outside
thus making being remote more what is security that can be worked
freely to go if I would like to stop here to tell a little
at least from my perspective and I know that it is something that I have done has stayed with
compare and that I think something that happened to people who
putting have work experience in the world of computer insurance is that
from the pole minus the point of view of someone who has conducted audits in
the past and worked consulting at the beginning of the companies
at least the clients with whom I was lucky or more fortunate to
bumping me depends on how you want to see it
if they did not have a budget to spare now that they had to spare or did not see the
computer security as something necessary was having a change not of this same
left that I say that it is being done that remains you have to leave it later
what does it share that the community shares and a lot of companies of
computer insurance that are specifically said to raise awareness of companies
and others later they were realizing that it was
something they needed and until the day when many
companies would encourage me from most of the
Large companies today have their own team decided to inform and here
They are even separated into red team and blood in, so good if I don't want to later
expand on that but it's basically 1 defense and another attack for
generate robust security policies within an organization that is
also explained in the fax that we share that is very good because
the game only opens up more to the fact that there are companies hiring roles
about computing without being a specifically computer security company
I wanted to say something not exactly from the hand what you are mentioning
It is true that I also perceived it doing audits
Before really we were the last ear of the jar and if there is a
budget knife there let's see what these guys can do to see if
They find something and that was mutating a lot, it has even happened to me
recently listen to companies that place a lot of importance on it and have
mentioned in calls that I have had for them how good that as happened to their
competition something a similar problem an attack of rands humor or something by the
style and saw the economic impact that was obtained in that company they do not have to
the space so they are beginning to be is being much more forward-looking
and going back to the first part of your question let's say it happened to me
personally, which is precisely from hacker space, many
companies that also wanted to show what they did because sometimes it is difficult
give you visibility and what you are doing that are companies
new and I am also very surprised by the fact that there are so many companies
security that is also stationed in Cordoba not only typical of here from
Córdoba but they are a multinational company and have offices here
also and I think there is a gigantic labor market that is to say there is a lot of
demand and I also know it because a security company works and there is a
very large demand of trained people is security
For this reason, there are also quite extensive training programs and
pretty aggressive I would say so the people who are getting into this
form as quickly as possible and walk away almost immediately
we also from the company where I work we try to train
the best people and as quickly as possible because the end of the job is
very big to the point that sometimes we can't cope
so well yes yes yes your concerns if there is or is not work
in an ethical way know that there is and there is a lot I am talking about the more
of the rating part of the offensive audit part but within all
the branches of computer surfing there is a lot of work if I had to say
the minimum requirements of all these trainings from which the
company has to work like this and peer companies out there maybe that
Cordoba itself, what would be the minimum requirements for all these
different levels of introductions to companies with programs such as so that
people security and well me with being in such a year of university for it
I have this knowledge or I think what it is they would need to know and how good it is
the whole university is that for me or one of the most important things is to have
fairly solid basic knowledge working knowledge understand what
what are the protocols how they work and from there to start uploading a lot
in a lot of areas your lean is supposed to be more to the side of
good audit understand how a web server works how it works different
foreign wars web or how the suction cups work and so on and after
start to see how things fail sun come on I think it is very very useful and
a lot of value to read a lot about security ethical way there are a lot of forums and
a lot of very interesting things one that I usually read a lot is net sec de
network radio and thanks to the fact that it is excellent the excellent grace can
order by priority because people already start making the pattern and we go to this
seems the most interesting of all kinds of skills and quite a lot is very very
because of that, nothing seems to me that they are really interested in the top
computing saying that it is a super dynamic environment nothing gives it a lot is
try to keep up with the mobility that is coming out that is very useful for the
companies because it is true that companies can be affected by old bugs
but the reality is that the most immediate things are always
and of greater impact so nothing I think is also some way to show that
are up to date and are reading and seeing what is happening in the
computer habituation is also making certifications that endorse that
knowledge either a university degree or a certain damage in
the race and well and yes later if they can go
accompanied by certifications that validate other knowledge that you
they are doing it would also be great but good obviously with this no but yes that
they are exclusive things of course that it seems to me that if you somehow
Also in the interviews it will happen that they will see technical tests is
basically like a mini set and a mini caps ref what are those challenges
and they will try to greet him and in that more or less I at least
personally what comes that he does not see so much the result as if he is not going to
to be able to solve that so much does not interest me what interests me is to see
how the way of thinking tries to solve it and even if it cannot solve it
all the things you did to try to solve what you did to me is a lot of value
that shows the way of thinking of the person well and from the side he has it
a bit this in by and have supervised professional practices or some
agreement to a company do not have against a sumo
but in particular we have had several meetings with companies from the medium and
even fabián is an advisor and is working on aspects related to
security and what is not less that has happened within our faculty and
that Fabián is leading is a research group in training in training
we call them within the academic environment until it is approved by the
formal statutes that we have the boards of directors the boards
departmental but in reality in a group in formation with a set of
graduate student teachers that they have already been working on
security and that has it all by participating in meetings with
companies because that also makes our community grow so
could in that it seems to me that it has a lot to hide
become a bit about that experience yeah
Go ahead
well in the case from utm we have a group that we have been coming for a long time
working on research projects that have been presented just this
project with the opportunity to demonstrate it in some cases in visas and
Well, the eneco will also have a representative from the laboratory giving a
of the talks telling their experiences and others that I think are ideal where we have
joined a combination of students with engineers and from there it would be little
towards the market of love doing from transfer of what one goes
working researching relating to the different organizations and
companies which are also related to the subject as I speak
there Carlos the people of mcafee who at times opened the door for us to
also motivate the boys to take them there good that they see a way of
I work a proposal from a company that stood out
and also obviously good services that one can provide through the
precisely systems department where the same companies for that reason
request certain types of advice or where what they require is
some good way like recommending some kind of staff or
people for the necessary resources the truth that we are growing I think not
It is only tn but Cordoba is growing from every point of view of the
safety aspect this totally strengthens the roads we want
marking as a group we have grown a lot it has taken us time it is not a theme
It is not the main theme of the university obviously it is a
university but we have been working to form a strong team with con
I really want to, mainly I think that is the word that I rescue from your link
What did you go through a while ago and I think that's where the
strengthening the desire that not only the engineers but also the
students and well anyone who wants to participate that allows this
grow from the formal point of view in what is research and from the point of view
of view of maybe of knowledge linking us with not only
organizations such as hacker space but also with companies and with other
universities that we have also had the opportunity to be present in
some other types of events with them so hey I think what it is
extremely important is research not how to leave and not be scared with
that word that out there seems to me to investigate is something totally
academic and it is not what you want what you want and dig into that to
get a knowledge and most importantly understand what one is
doing but excellent part of what you want
Fabian who mentioned turn to him the frequently asked questions this re
can give up what happens now I'm going to do it again
throw there in the tweet channel there are many of the questions that we
are asking at this time that they are answered there are several questions that
The answers are if the certifications are recommended or not what type of
profiles are found in the world of work, which will be the basic
you need to be able to run computer security if it makes sense
not go to a conference how we see the future of security matías I saw that
is another question they asked there is also a graphic map that I found no
I remember the name of the person but it is cited in a source that shows
all areas of security form ethical so that they can try to
find out which area you resonate with the most so thank you all
the people who are asking most of these questions in questions
are there is a repository that basically belongs to the community for the
community if you have not used git hub is a nice opportunity to use give
up because you can send me modifications later I can test them and how it is text
They can do it directly on the site so it is a nice approach and for the
people who already know what pull requests are feel welcome from
send me whatever they want that they think brings movie airs from
courses we are adding as it happens in some
of the podcasts we have conferences that are held in Argentina there is a
collection of different types of twitter communities that we have
in adjusted and that is one of the last sections at the end of article iv
Well, who will tune in is that and so soon the first talk starts
I really appreciate the people of the 'u' have the guys from the hacker face for
join us for being co-organizers of this good and some of their faces
they will continue to appear there because they will be moderating
repeated figurines be moderating the following in the following
conferences that will be happening until 4 in the afternoon more or less I think
that starts the last one so thank you very much again guys please for
for attending for cooperating
thank you very much thank you all for participating