hello everybody my name is Aidan
Crenshaw and the presentation I'm going
to be giving today is on recording hecka
cons and how do picture in the picture
on the cheap first of all a little bit
about me I bernanke com hope some of
y'all been at some point that i need the
traffic i have an interest in infosec
education I don't know everything I was
a geek of time on my hands especially
when it comes to video there's a lot of
things I'll probably slightly wrong
something's big in the video editing
will say well now you miss use the term
filter or you're confusing Direct X or
sorry directshow with video for windows
or some little intricacy like that so I
could get a lot of those details wrong
but hopefully this pop give you just
enough information to make videos
similar to the ones i've been doing from
my website i'm also an irregular on the
ISDN podcast every first midnight
generally speaking and also on special
occasions we had a podcast last night
that we recorded in the party room ok so
the core topic for this presentation is
how do I make these and I'm actually
going to go grab some of my equipment I
have and if you like that comment I want
those guys it probably doesn't even need
the microphone but it helps with
recording
now I do various some videos go to hepa
cons also recorded classes that we do
with local Issa and I end up trying to
make something that looks a little bit
like this where you had the speaker in
one corner because the slides in another
and the main body and I really like
doing it this way because how many
people have seen like quoted videos of
presentations and you had no idea what
the hell was in the slides because it
was just way too blurry and I know
another guy who does goes around the
cons and cords it and he once told me
that he gets better image results by
putting a camera on the screen and I did
not with a crap i had maybe maybe we
have some really bad capture devices and
some really bad vga to svideo adapters
that might be the case but i'm gonna
show you how i produce videos that look
something like that and we're also gonna
do a partially live demo of me when
doing hopefully the video that was just
recorded by skydog alright first of all
a little bit what hardware are used and
skydog users we have slightly different
rigs for this conference pretty much all
the video equipment except for one
converter is all skydog stuff and he
hasn't set up to where it's a science
you just screw it down and you get up
and running one of the biggest issues
putting all this stuff to give it a
conference or class is two tons and tons
of crap why did you end up getting
braided together before the end and so
it ends up taking a while to set up the
cool things you need to record videos
the way we've been doing them is the
worst way I've been doing I need a
laptop because i do my captures straight
to a laptop as far as the slide to
concern using a captured dong roll you
also going to need a video camera and
let's fight in fact these two this
bullet point county got combined
together you also need a USB video
capture device now the one i usually use
is about twenty dollars from dealextreme
and it does a decent job what can I say
you also need a vga to svideo converter
now my current one you can see later on
is hooked up there it looks a little
something like this and what that does
is it takes a VGA signal in and throws
out s-video why because s video capture
devices are a lot cheaper than
straight up vga capture devices I think
some the cheaper ones I saw a first-rate
up vga capture like three four hundred
bucks this adapters 20 bucks and it
still gives decent results just not ask
crisp as you can get but I use this to
convert to s-video and this little box
is about 30 bucks then I throw it into a
capture dongle which is costing me
another 20 bucks and into a laptop now
the way skydog does it is a little bit
different and he's got a refined to
where he just froze on this box this box
has a bunch of law be mates in it and
these V mates can take a composite in
and we quote to an SD card and then you
get some mp4s off that you can just mess
around with and it does simplify things
a whole lot the problem is composite you
don't quite as good at image quality as
you do with s-video so s video is a big
drop from VGA and composite somewhat of
a drop from s-video however it does make
things a hell of a lot more convenient
having a laptop out there and it's so
much a laptop capture software that is
buggy as hell I find this out in video
up video in general it's like finding a
video get halfway a foot away through it
and it crashed xiangya you have no idea
why doesn't give you any kind of real
useful information so the estimates are
the be mates are a big help for that as
well as the recording the video the
camera I have is just a fairly crappy
aiptek that doesn't do really good
low-light a few tips I do have for you
if you ever decide to record days a lot
of mine I don't Mike the speaker it's
really nice to Mike the speaker to get
rid of ambient sound and get better
audio quality and another thing is a lot
of my chief of cameras he's got a better
camera as far as a video quality is
concerned probably with low light but
even if those if you can get a light on
the speaker it helped immensely but
you'll see some of my videos especially
the password class were Alex and Martin
of you barely visible because of how
dark the room is all right and I talked
a little bit at the vmail setups now my
course setup is essentially I have a
camera this recording separate to sit
there stand alone and then i have the
presenters laptop hooked up to that vga
to svideo adapter then the SVO adapter
is running into my
USB capture device and then that's going
to my capture laptop as captured him
there and afterwards I combine together
sky dogs wig looks awesome and more like
this sep four it's a little more company
this because he has multiple be made
running because he has the camera
feeding into a V mate he has the
presenters laptop running into a V mate
and he also has another side camera
running into be mate so he can get you
know a little crossing back and forth he
has a fourth one also we mixed that
video in that video so yeah he's his rig
and that is just a lot fancier than mine
so that's since the hard way we have set
up yes oh yes um yeah on both of our
rigs is VJ to a composite objs video
usually it has a way of the kind of a
vga mirror out of it that you also go
hook off to the projector so somewhere
over here you might have to vga ports
once in one's out and you're capturing
up the s-video out and the projectors
hooked up to the vga out anybody wants
to see this later on just you know
carefully look at sky dogs rig and i
have some of my equipment here as well
okay now he's using be mates for
capturing which does simplify things a
lot i usually use a Windows Media
encoder to do my captures why because it
seems to crash less than anything else
I've tried as far as with liability it
means i'm getting WMV files out when i
record but they work just fine it's
fairly crisp and if i remember to make
all my settings correct I usually do 25
frames a second it's a my camera does
like 60 frames a second which is very
actually 59 points something which I
don't really need that many frames a
second and the mainly sighs convert 18
to 25 frames a second is it's just easy
for me to do the math since if I don't
need to lay something four seconds or
add four seconds I can just do it my hat
and head real quick okay
hundred frames nice and simple and I
have good luck with Windows Media
encoder I would provide a download link
unfortunately they seem to replace it
with expressions encoder which so far
what I plate of it I don't like nearly
as well maybe it just takes a little bit
more getting used to if you google
around for it look around for the 64 bit
version of Windows Media encoder and if
you can't find any place email me and
i'll see if i can find you a copy i
don't think i can host it my website
since it is microsoft stuff but since it
was released as freeware I've actually
distribution in between people should be
no issue alright another tool I use for
a lot of my video depending on what you
end up getting the video from sometimes
it's not workable like sometimes I'll go
to a con and I won't want to pack all my
stuff to get on the plane so I'll use
someone else's camera there but the
video they throw out I mean I have all
the right filters on my laptop and begin
to figure out what to do with it so I
might throw it into a Vig mux and throw
it into a different video format that I
can work with and a Vig months is
awesome for that it's got various
filters for resizing cleaning up images
scrap things are subtitling though
generally speaking if I can do it if I
can fill the wrong video into some
description will show you here in a bit
I do that because it streamlines fangs
if I have to take the video from the
camera convert it into an avi of a
special format copy out the audio can
put that to a special WAV file then
float all to my script that's several
extra steps computation why's it may be
the same but if I can eliminate as many
steps to human involved as I can it just
makes you know the process of rendering
all these videos a lot easier and
luckily I've found some filters recently
that's going to streamline the process
of putting these videos hopefully from
today into a finished product in
previous years I actually had to copy
the audio back out and then back into my
videos because whatever reason avi sent
was failing on it and I found the right
plugins now to make that work Oh
virtualdub is another thing I use
sometimes I'm gonna go back and slide
atid mugs for a while there I would try
to my rendering in a PID mux for the
final product i'll be putting up from
the website and make mp4s
unfortunately it does directly work with
a bi of sense scripts which i'll be
showing here in a bit those like a simp
server you can throw in there I had
mixed luck with that and there's
actually a tool where you can take an
API since crib and mount it as a part of
the filesystem and basically it shows
this huge uncompressed avi and a virtual
directory but even then I folded into a
Vig mugs and everything would be upside
down and backwards now you can feel a
filter on that that will automatically
flip it but it's an extra step now a
virtual dub it'll be a VI send scripts
directly your outputs a little bit more
limited I'm saving it as a vis and I'm
going put a generic usually speaking i'm
using a straight-up xvid and mp3 just or
lame as an encoded just because
everybody seems to support it the videos
may not be as small as they could
possibly be but they said super
supported and virtual dub also has a ton
of different filter sorry yeah
virtualdub also has a ton of different
filters you can fly as far as resizing
and messing around up the image another
oil i use from time to time especially
when i've had problems with doing the
video of the work but not the audio is
ida install audacity copy the video into
audacity get just the audio then i can
mess around the audio clean up noise in
it because uh audacity has a nice noise
removal feature or just turn the video
into some kind of sample rate and coding
that I can throw into an avi scream
script to make work luckily I think I
got enough things and abs of cinch now
to uh not even have to use this step but
still something you need to know about
because if you want to clean up sound
like you had a really noisy auditorium
or you know your microphones right next
to an air conditioner so you have that
consonant fan sound you can get rid of a
fair amount that with audacity ok the
main tool I'm using for all this is avi
synth if a synth it's like a scripting
language for video rendering and
compositing and its really really nifty
essentially you just run the script and
you can tell it what to do with videos
and give you the final results and I'll
explain some of its functions here in a
second
another to life sometimes using the past
is a be absent virtual file system which
what you do is you right-click on the
script mount it and it becomes like a
virtual file system where you haven't
already pre generate a VI that's
probably gigabytes and gigabytes and
gigabytes sides because virtually
speaking it's uncompressed it doesn't
actually put on your hard drive but the
thing about this is tools that aren't
designed to work of avi sent can now
look for Ava sense because use this tool
to make it into a virtual avi did pretty
much any tool will work with so it's
just convenient for a lot of things a
tool i found recently it's a plug-in
there's also extra filters you can add
into a avi sent by using plugins and one
plugins i found was that be happy
plug-in set which allows you to mess
amount of audio and allows the weird
audio it's coming off these v mates to
work directly an avi sent without me
having to make the intermediate step of
throwing it into audacity which just
streamlines the hell out of things okay
codecs and filters i need to install
depending on what kind of video transfer
into it you can have to have the right
codec on your machine generally speaking
you need ffdshow to do impact for stuff
right along with xvid i usually do much
my encoding in xvid just because it's a
little faster if I had my druthers I
would try to do a ex I was x 264
encoding and do to pass to get the best
small best quality for the smaller size
but takes a really long time if I
understand the process corrected what
the code is doing in the background we
use x264 which is like an open source
version of h.264 it looks at the first
time and the first pass and figures at
work and optimize then the second pass
it makes the smaller size possible the
way a lot of these are compression
codecs work is it looks for changes for
instance if you have nothing but a black
background and you try to compress that
you can press that down super small
because very few changes to member
basically the codec has to memorize oh
okay black flame black frame black frame
all this and I can they can shrink that
down very small now you have a lot of
different colors a lot of changes it
takes more space by doing that to pass
encoding it can figure out where it can
optimize the video you get the small
size however it takes a lot longer
if you want to be able to try messing
around with x 264 encoding the video for
windows version of the codec you can use
for rendering is out there also to get
in be forced to work right a lot of time
time to use a things nonces halley's
media splitter which allows me to feed
mp4 s into my avi send scripts i use
lame which is lame is not a mp3 encoder
is what it stands for but what it output
is mp3 compatible so I'm not sure what
all the terminology is there another you
notice about la tesis scripts is yet the
Google around for the installs I've
tried to provide the links here
apparently in some cases I don't send
the legality this one way together some
of these tools you can release the
source code for it but you can't release
the binary because of some weird
copyright reason if anybody's
multi-million of that get with me later
I said I know how to get the videos out
and mended and put up on my website all
the details in the background I'm not so
sure about Oh another thing it's really
useful sometimes you install a bunch of
filters and plugins and then find out it
screwed up and you can't rent a video
anymore you don't know what's going on
well I found out after i installed the
k-lite codec pack installed a bunch of
extra credits i didn't need some of them
were taking over my video my video
process and was screwing up and slowing
down the my final windows so turns you
have to go in there and figure out
what's screwing things up and there's a
tool called a DSF manager which allows
you to see what a video filters are
installed and add and remove them which
is really nice with fixing things my
general recommendation is don't install
codec packs install the individual
codecs you think you need the codec
packs may solve some problems but they
can also cause even more there's no to I
don't have on listed on here but I
believe it's called oh I'm trying to
think of what it's called there's a tool
basically it's for visually showing you
what filters click it's called a graph
edit that will show you what filters are
applied whenever you open up a video and
its really nice to figure out what might
be screwing things up in the process
okay well actually a little bit a live
demo to
show how we go to win to these videos so
let me exit add this and actually will
show you a couple those tools real quick
I mentioned this one see that DSF
manager does you see what all filters
you have installed so you can add and
remove them which is offering nifty and
some place in here at I had graph edit
those code versions of this one has an
open source version this is graphs to do
Microsoft's I think s Microsoft's
directx sdk also has a version but let's
say I was to open up some video file in
this it would show me what's actually
using to get it all winded and if I
let's say I think I have one laptop
that's rendering right and when it's not
I can use this as a diagnostic tool to
figure out what particular little codec
i have installed it might be screwing
the pooch but let's go ahead and
actually do some live rendering and I'm
going to be bold and see if I can get
this to work I'm gonna go over with my
cup more complex scripts and i'm gonna
copy a few different files into
directory one which is where i should
have the videos from sky dogs earlier
talk let me see if I got everything I
need there oh I don't want that one I
want this one
and hungry bold and go ahead and run
this and see what happens then we'll
explain how it's actually working Chris
few seconds you say I have an overlay of
the various sponsors and Friends of the
conference that's not bending at exactly
real time here but you see I have my
corner text I have slides and of course
I have the speaker now let's go see how
I actually end up doing all that avi
sent is a scripting language so let's
open that bad boy up and actually I will
do one of a little thing is that just
the intro video game yo is that the
intro and sky dogs talk
so that's actually his okay okay so the
reason I ask is simplify things i did
some text i can copy and paste i'll show
you why i'm doing this in a second let
me close everything down so listen
confuse by everybody's wondering i'm
using notepad plus plus for all my
editing I just falls windows text
editors it's nice convenient okay here's
an avi since script of course premiere
of most scripting language allows
scripting languages just use the pound
symbol as a comment and so I'll give
some explanation in these scripts and if
I want some I think I have versions them
out of my website but the also one of my
can give you one I'll probably go ahead
and link to them off of the video page
whenever I post the outer zone videos
now in this case the first thing I'm
doing is I'm getting a live audio for
whatever reason the videos that are
coming out of these um this isn't always
necessary but in this case it is the
video coming up these V mates the audios
somehow weird so I have to use a special
plugin i mentioned before the be happy
one and you can add that but basically
going out to the avi sent folder on your
machine and copying the plug in the
plugins folder like a lot of other tools
it's basically the same way to install
plugins and what it allows me to do is
grab the audio directly from that mp4
live mp4 then I make another object
called live vid and I grab the video now
it's all its parameters and i'll link
off to in a bit directions from a wiki
on all the different internal functions
and external functions you can add but i
use direct show I grab the mp4 file i
telt use 25 frames a second and convert
to 25 frames a second if it isn't
already i could put the color space to
24 bit RGB just because i won't be fun
other stuff that way i just need a
common way because my stock compositing
videos are using different color spaces
it ain't happy i dub in that live audio
from before and i do that before
everything else and you see how it's
kind of got an object oriented
architecture to it where you say dot do
this to it dot do that to it and so
forth so from left to right these are
going in order
so i dub in the audio i'm probably don't
need this extra convert to 25 / saying
it's a second by have it there anyway
now this trim is i don't i generally
only mess with this first parameter this
0 what this trim does is tell me that i
can tell the fsm script how many frames
to take off of it for instance sometimes
these are from your recording video
you're not going to start the slide
capture the exact time you're capturing
the live person so it'd be a few seconds
off so you guys sit there and time it
that's why I was saying when the earlier
talks it's nice if you have a little bit
of the screen in the live part of the
video so you can sync it all up and so
between this trim and the trim where I
import the slides I can adjust it and
take off just the right number of frames
to make a match up pretty much perfectly
then to make anything smaller the video
coming off these I think it's like 720 x
480 I go ahead and do it look cozy and
resize and that's just one that gives me
better quality when I'm doing shrinking
I think bilinear would be faster than if
I remember which ones which but it
doesn't give you quite as crisp equality
and in here most of my bottle neck seems
to be the actual turning it into an xvid
not necessarily the avi script script so
I will go ahead and just really cozy and
resize then once i have that live video
and the way i want it i create another
object for the slides and i've been put
the slides mp4 and of course most of the
same settings 25 frames a second convert
to mono why I'm doing that in the slides
here I really don't know since I'm not
getting my audio from the slides that's
probably something I had left over from
a previous script because promote the
RPG RGB 24 bit and there after due to
resize to 640 by 480 and 25 frames a
second and of course trim if I need to
then thereafter I also grab the corner
and for that I use an image source and I
have a PNG file now the way I've been
doing these P&G files I don't have a lot
of code here that's probably not
necessarily like I don't want you to be
sighs it since i already have it the
right size I just do it to make sure
things work I kind of have a cargo cult
programming mentality when it comes to
this throwing stuff in I don't
necessarily need but I might use in
future scripts and another function I
have in here is the subtitle function
which I'm going to be using for putting
the person's a title in there so I can
just say skydog mande hacker and I may
need to get back into adjust that to get
the right number of lines but we'll see
how that actually turns out actually
instead I'm gonna put a new line
character now and that's just the same
as C++ and I setting set the halo color
select how it glows and the main text
color but i'ma show you what I've been
doing for images back out here right now
I have a PNG file and for both the intro
part that lasts for a few seconds and
the corner the way I generate those is
i've been using a tool called paint.net
and the thing I like about it is it's
well I don't know I haven't use
Photoshop enough to really be able to
compare but it does everything i need to
do as far as multiple layers
transparencies and all that like almost
open up that intro you know notice how i
set it up there's a slight alpha channel
to that you may not be to make it out on
the projector but you can slightly see
through the title and you see I set up
transparent semi sorry alpha channel duh
translucent dark color behind
everybody's logo that way it shows up
when I put it on top of the slides but
you can still see behind it and it's
really nice with setting all that up the
alpha channel goes through its really
nifty I have multiple layers so i can
replace a title in if i want just makes
things nice and easy to work with from
before for an avi since i just save it
as a PNG file but that's all those
constructed together now let's go back
and let's look at the
the script before we start actually
rendering it with avi set aside a
virtual dub okay next thing I do is I
start adding videos together so this
corner plot a live plus corner i stacked
vertically the live video in the corner
put them together then there after i put
the intro video at sorry let me see what
i got here i overlay the intro image and
get that that's an object don't actually
put any place yet I just grabbed it and
that's that horizontal the live plus
corner plus the slides then I dub back
on the live audio video because
depending on which ones you stack first
it chooses which audio to use to make
sure i'm using the live videos audio i
have to do this little step and then
finally does insert sign now if i wanted
to i could take out that part and we
move everything we move out the rest of
the script this info part that's just
convenient i'm going to uncomment that
for my next part just so you can see
what it does it shows you statistics and
information about what kind of video
you're feeding into it it's useful for
debugging your script so I'll turn it
back on now this is a function i found
in a form system I got it from got some
guy goes by name the fluff and what it
does is it overlays and that's a lot of
functions in here that I'm not as
familiar with but I know it works so
that's basically di sim scripts are
constructed I'm going to save this out
and just you can see what i mean by that
info function I uncommented it and
you'll see it gives me a bunch of info
up here about what frame it's currently
rendering oh I just double click
directly on the Avs file yeah that's the
script file and because I have a license
installed windows media player just
automatically will open with
it not all tools necessarily will like
if I tried dragon droppings in the
virtual dub inside the into VLC it won't
necessarily work I'm going to go back in
and take out that information thing that
basis tells you like what kind of video
you're feeding in it's really nice for
doing debugging so I'm up comp that out
and let's actually show you how I would
win to this if I was about to into it
normally uh let's see some nice on here
i have virtualdub else virtualdub i
don't have to do in this exact order but
it might be easiest to I I can set up
how I want to do my compression the
first thing I normally do is grow and
audio say full processing because I
don't we'll just do a direct stream copy
and go any compression and set lame to
use 128-bit or whatever also I can go on
any video compression and set xvid to do
whatever I generally keep it at four you
have the option of doing a double pass
but for sake of speed and the fact that
I'm not hosting in myself as usually end
up having larger videos and most people
watch it via the video stream anyway now
making that setting every single time
you load of videos of pain so you can
also save out your settings like you say
say processing settings right here i'm
gonna say load processing settings and
point to where i have those processing
settings already saved so it hasn't
memorized that just is a nice little
step to a nice little thing to do to a
save time okay I'm go Jack drag and drop
the script into a Vig mux and once
inside abig mux there I go that's what
the video would look like does the input
on the right is what the output would be
is still too big to fit on the screen I
can go in I can choose to just encode
however much but because of how had that
script constructed
it's putting the overlay on the first
few frames so I'd missed that overlay
but I can choose how much of it to save
another thing I might do is sit there
and try to figure out how many frames I
need to take out by looking at what's up
on the screen here versus what's on the
screen in the live video and try to sync
them out to be exact though in this case
I don't know if you all have any of the
deafening of the screen up inside the
live video on his talk I I can hopefully
try to piece it together by listening to
the audio and get the exact see that's
the part that's the pain in the butt is
to get the two lined up exactly now I'm
assuming you hit both record on both
about the exact same time but even then
sometimes you get off by a couple
seconds so at this point once I have
this video here I could just I want to
unselect everything I'll just select
absolutely if I'm I believe this way I
do file save as an ABI and I choose my
desktop let's say out of zone 1 and put
a stake of speed let's go ahead and just
render the first very small pit of his
presentation save as an avi to my
desktop I'll just called overlay
autozone 1.avi and you see it's going at
about 14 frames a second and increasing
that means it's gonna take me longer to
render it than it did to record it
because i'm actually in putting anything
at 25 frames a second but it's picking
up speed as time goes long more likely
the first roof frames take longer to
render because i'm doing that overlay
with the transparency and all that but
that's taped out an AVI so let me close
down virtualdub and let's go see if that
avi looks at all decent
and if I had audio working right I
should have I should have audio playing
but for whatever reason that's not quite
doin I have turned up I she's already
from this hooked up to the anything okay
that might be why it's not playing it
okay
bathroom or messing around this in the
back and make sure audios functioning
but that's essentially what the finished
video will end up looking like live
that's going to be that's can we make it
to where we record via the live because
otherwise getting lip sync is impossible
it should be but so it should be
recording audio to both okay so it
should be in there whatever it's not
playing right now and I'm gonna go back
there and figure that out there's
something messed up there oh yeah this
look like I see any audio coming in from
that a camera well that's what I got so
far so hopefully they'll actually will
be some audio in that one eventually I
may have to have guy dog looking like he
is enough kung fu film but we'll see how
that all turns out hmm yeah it's
probably not be it perfect and then a is
far enough away maybe I can get away of
it a one of a video apply show is I was
doing a sniffles class last weekend and
I had a problem where one the video
started going really kablooey on me and
me see I had to put a bunch of videos
together to make it work for instance
this avi sim2 we had a problem we're in
the middle of the slide recording the
video failed and i had to replace it
with an image saying sorry we lost this
section and the way I did that got a
little bit more complicated
and we go in here let me open up that
sniffles class essentially what i had to
do there is i had to take video one
before the failure video to asset of
failure i put in a blank PNG that
announced the information and i looped
through and put in a number of frames it
took to get anything back in sync okay I
only have two on here okay but you can
see here how I basically insert a blank
spot to make up for that so you can do
tons of din things and i'm not expecting
people to pick up a vag scripting a BS
in scripting just from this talk because
there's a lot to it but alicia gives you
an idea that the language is itself just
looking at that a lot of the text is
fairly easy to follow and you go out to
the wiki page there's plenty of examples
and explanations on it a lot of times to
give the examples not with the whole
semi object-oriented form where you put
a dot something dot something but it's
still pretty easy to figure out let me
go back and a few less things some
future what I want to work on is
actually being the win of these things
live getting everything synced up after
the fact that such a pain that I'd love
to be able to sit it down have two
cameras and have the laptop
automatically composite everything
together for me there's a few tools i
found it can do that now the better one
I found for doing it is a video blaster
for windows unfortunately it's not free
I'm gonna say 500 bucks it does a good
job and I had one video why test with it
i lost the audio but generally it does a
great job and that's see what it is you
can have that picture in a picture then
you can like make one full screen then
switch back and just do all sorts of
weird effects you can do something
similar the open source tool webcam
studio for linux unfortunately it's
never rendered fast enough to be
practical for that i can save out an odd
video file but it's like a slot where
the entire things like a slideshow
person person person
it's um written in Java it might be one
of the issues there I'm not sure I'm not
sure there's mixed I hear mixed opinions
on job and how fast it is depending what
you're doing it's probably fine I'm not
sure it's fast enough for video
rendering though but it's still a neat
toy to play around with and as newer
versions come out I might be to get fast
and faster if anybody watches this video
anybody at the conference knows of a
good live compositing software that's
free let me know because I'm incredibly
cheap bastard alright more useful sites
to look at it wonder about AVI center of
course check out the wiki if you want to
buy autos I've only showed a subset of
all the stuff you can do a baby i sent
those tons of filters that are built in
and tons more you can add via plugins
for video helped in general to great
forms you can check out is video help
and also do nine and finally a few
advanced I'd like to announce the
Louisville infosec which happens every
year usually around october i think this
year they're doing it in early September
and happening just before der beek on
which is happening in the last month
last week end of sep tember which
becomes the first weekend of october and
of course various other conferences i go
to heaven discard all con yet but I
intend to that hasn't happened yet get
more information from sky doping around
the conference hackathon freaknik go to
every year not accounting primas go to
every year and of course the conference
i'm currently at so no sense and
advertising yet since you already here
know about it finally any questions do i
think i'm about to be fun off stage
anyway alright everybody has any
questions later decide they have to ask
me go ahead and find out the conference
and i'll try my best to answer one
PNG basically your script I can start
rendering Asia is this one happy dumb
ones down once got the one you just hand
it back to me alive I can put the help
we do this put your copy of the ones
there anything I need on here and I'm
send it back to your blank with actually
don't want blank as you whatever your
interest if I need on that and i'll give
you these scripts look what do you mean
I need the live video that has the audio
as the audience and if my no actually
ready I'll take mine too yeah he was
talking Amir end up winning them live
that I'd be overly and you know
you