right so title of my presentation is
going to be called your password policy
sucks this presentation kind of came out
of last year I did some real technical
presentations on on a tool called ocl
hash cat and a lot of people mentioned
that I that I skipped a big part in the
beginning and and that was kind of basic
usage and and how I arrived at the way
that that we use things and so I'm going
to kind of maybe go backwards this year
with this presentation and and hopefully
show a little bit about this stuff Who
am I I'm a security consultant at a key
bought consultants and nice word for
hacker a core developer for backtrack
linux anybody ever heard of backtrack
yes no look and just in case my
presentation sucks is that going to work
backtrack 5 you saw it here first that
was called a teaser and anyway I'm
awesome a founder of a website called
question defense com we do technical
questions technical answers some are
really stupid like how to turn on my
monitor and some of them are really
complex like pentesting type stuff to me
and my friend Alex we do it for fun it's
a lot of fun I'm also a co-founder at
Derby con which is a convention that's
going to be in louisville kentucky that
me Adrian and Dave Kennedy are putting
on and that is the last weekend to
September first weekend of October and
most importantly for this presentation I
was the member of the team that won the
password cracking contest at Def Con
this year or last year I guess trying to
get it together anyway so this company
called corelogic put on a contest called
correct me if you can the basis of the
contest was you could have as many
people as you want it on your team and
there were sixty thousand hashes and
whoever could crack the most of them in
48 hours and so me and my team won that
competition and that's kind of the other
reason that I was doing this talk is a
lot of people wanted to know exactly the
mythology that we used in order to crack
those lists of passwords work so my
disclaimer is I'm not a password expert
I don't know everything frequently wrong
and slow to admit it and I'm not
responsible for what you do with any of
this information so are things that I
want to cover our wire passwords still a
vector of attack one reason is people
are always saying you know passwords one
out four or five years ago as soon as we
made passwords over eight and ten
characters tools like John the Ripper
became useless because it takes so long
for cpu-based password cracking and so
we'll talk about later some of the
techniques that have come back that have
brought passwords back company still
have bad password policies I'm going to
talk a little bit about those I'm going
to analyze a few of the recent most
password breaches and go over a little
bit of the information why those
breaches are so valuable if you're ever
on Twitter or on IRC when one of those
breaches happens you'll notice that you
know a lot of people in the password
cracking community will be in a hurry to
get those lists as quick as possible
before companies like paste bin take
them down talk about the reason for why
we want those and some of the
advancements and password recovery and
then the tools and techniques to crack
passwords obviously I'm biased a hash
cat but there's a lot of new tools that
have come out in kind of the hash caps
sweet and we'll talk about some of those
so what's wrong with passwords they are
the weakest method of authentication
password authentication is just terrible
but unfortunately we're stuck with it
and so so what can we do to make pies
we're going to talk a little bit about
what can we do to make that password
authentication better obviously a lot of
companies go have gone to two factor
authentication although if you've been
paying attention to the news in the last
two days your RSA
might be useless many websites and this
is particularly true of websites not
necessarily internal networks but
websites are notoriously bad for bad
hashing algorithms you know five ten
years ago websites were getting blasted
all over the place for store and
passwords in clear text now they're
still store and hash storm passwords
with weak hashing algorithms the other
thing about passwords as humans are
predictable and I'll talk about that a
little bit later but like one when
you're sitting at your desk at your
company X and you're making up your
password nine times out of ten you're
going to be looking around the room and
you're going to see something that has
to do with company X and that's going to
be the root of your password and you may
add some upper cases and special
characters and that kind of stuff but
many many people will make their
password specific to their environment
and then with the use of GPU password
recovery it's become pretty much a joke
to pass to crack a lot of password
algorithms so you're saying yourself my
company's got a password policy we're
good that's great however what I'm going
to show is that knowing the password
policy of a company can actually help
the password cracking if I know that
you're Paula and I'm jumping the gun
here I'll get into that in a minute and
some organizations impose really
limiting password policies I'm going to
show you a real world one that I
actually found and the worst thing of
all is that many many many companies
never ever change the default Windows
Active Directory password policy because
they feel like it's good enough that's
easy to figure out so here's a real
world example I blacked out the name of
the company not to embarrass them
however this is a real world password
policy that I actually found on the
internet and so if you look at it let's
go through it your password policy is
case sensitive that's fine it cannot
contain any special characters
whatsoever that's a little bit limiting
it can't contain your username well
that's sort of a good policy it can't
can
pain two separated numbers I mean is
that not the most ridiculous thing
you've ever heard so that means that
your numbers cannot be separated
anywhere in the password they have to be
together and then it can't contain
company name or password yeah I'm not
sure this was a website so I'm not
exactly I'm assuming this is some
homegrown coded application this is just
some policies I was honestly trying to
find the worst policy that I could this
is what I came up with so this is wrong
on a lot of levels so there's a 10
character maximum so that's a failure
all by itself anything under 10
characters is easily crackable no
special characters so the US keyboard
has 94 typable characters and 32 of them
are specials so if we eliminate those 32
characters we've eliminated one third of
the possible password characters and
then numbers can't be separated I still
can't get my head around that I'm not
exactly sure how that happened but
anyway so if you worked at my company
which is a coupon you might come up with
some of these passwords based on this
password policy so in the beginning I
got this really common one which would
be one numbers got to be kept one
letters got to be capitalized it's
always going to be the first letter cuz
it's easy to remember and you might need
to append some digits to the end it's
going to be a date like the data was
born you know and then you go down the
list here and so at the bottom I have
with this particular password policy
this is the best possible password that
I could come up with and it's still not
that great of a password because it's
only using 66 of the 94 character 64 of
the 94 character sets and so and it's
going to take character max maximum
using some of the tools we're going to
look at later that password to easily be
broken in an hour and so if that's the
best possible password this website can
come up with you can imagine what
stover like all right so when I talk
about the patterns that people make
password choices on this is really
really really important because when
you're on a pen test and I'm talking
legally here it's important to kind of
profile an organization and what when I
mean by profile an organization I mean
like downloading the entire website
turning it into word lists downloading
the city that they're in the sports
teams that are around there you know
that kind of thing if it's a religious
organization we might want to you know
make a word list out of there what do
you call it Bible or special book or
whatever they got going on and so when
people make passwords they'll always
almost always look around them and and
I'm not just making these things up this
is from personal experience on pentest
looking at the analyzing the passwords
from companies and seeing how many of
them actually have company name
somewhere in them numbers are almost
always going to be in a date format 11
or 2011 if the password policy requires
a capital letter it's almost always
going to be the first letter and if the
password policy requires a special
character it's almost always always
going to be at the end so here's another
policy and this is the type of policy
that I see in place almost everywhere
that I go so your password must be at
least 8 characters it must contain one
uppercase letter it must contain one
number and it must contain one special
character right sound familiar people
got policies going on like that well the
average person like I said is going to
capitalize the first letter choose a
word choose a meaningful date and choose
a random character and most likely
they're going to come up with something
like this if they work in my company so
you're thinking my passwords are leaked
and that may be true everybody in this
room might have awesome passwords but
that is not true in the real world and
so you got to keep in mind that when
we're when we're auditing companies
we're talking about average people and
so like I said these presumptions are
made from my personal experience and
it's also been my experience that most
companies are not interested in security
until they experience some type of hack
alright so this bad password policy
happens for a couple reasons one of them
is lazy network admins which accept the
default Windows Active Directory policy
it can be changed the worst offender i
think is badly coded applications what
I'm assuming that very first policy that
we looked at in the beginning that
didn't allow special characters what I'm
assuming is that whoever coded that
application sucked and he was not able
to create a password validation field
that would take special characters and
so instead of learning how to code
properly they just decided to fix their
policy and I can guarantee you that that
company is going to pay for that mistake
they might have saved a little bit of
money on the application but anyway
another major reason CEOs complain CEOs
as you know run the companies and so if
they complain they don't want to enter
in some big long crappy password they
complain and and they're your boss the
network admins have to fix the policy to
suit the CEOs and another big reason is
that companies don't have regular
password audits in my experience even
with all these password policies in
place it's always a good idea to just
dump your password hash list in your
company and have it audited by a third
party company and then it because even
though even though you have a strict
policy people are still going to make
those patterns based on past are those
passwords based on patterns so if you
audit passwords you can go to those
users one two three four times a year
and say hey we know your password follow
the policy but it sucked it was
predictable and eventually those people
are going to get tired of you coming to
them and they're going to choose a
better passer
nobody likes business from the IT
security department all right so we're
going to talk about how we can leverage
this info in a pen test so what I like
to do is analyze current real-world
lists you know those password lists that
are up on what's a packet storm or
something that I've been you know like
unix-based passwords that were hacked in
1999 or something like that those are
not valid anymore you know those are not
good for much yeah they're dictionary
words but but most applications and
companies have kind of gotten over those
type of passwords anyway they can still
be useful as what i like to call root
passwords which I'll talk about in a
little bit and so analyzing the patterns
from these lists from the new list is
what can help us to leverage against
against new passwords attack and and the
main problem is that people tend to use
the same or similar passwords against
across all their internet accounts and
so here's the little graph of I'm trying
to show if I know what the policy is how
much quicker I can brute force the
password so at the top I got a seventh
character password and i'll know
anything about it so that means i gotta
try 94 94 94 it's actually ninety four
times ninety four times 94 anyway i'm
pretty sure my math is right but if it's
not don't kill me but so anyway if i was
the brute force that's that seven
character password at 250 million
passwords per second they would take me
72 hours to get through the list of all
the possible combinations so that's kind
of a long time it's not
what's the what current I mean it's
possible you know what I mean you might
get a fourth of the way through the list
you might get a third of the way through
the list I mean it's kind of debatable
you know what I mean it all depends on
what application you're using to brute
force it and how it goes through the
combinations this is just this is just
the worst case scenario type of thing so
yeah it might not take this long okay so
but if I'm aware of the password policy
and I know that there's got to be an
uppercase letter and there's got to be a
special character and there's got to be
some digits based on some of that
information I found before the first
character I only got to try twenty six
upper case the next couple characters i
only got to try 26 lower case the next
two characters might only have to try
the 10 digits and the last character i
might only have to try a special and so
that would cut in this particular
situation might act i'm down to six
point 21 seconds at 250 million
passwords per second and so the way
question yeah yeah go ahead well
honestly I just made up the 250 million
for the math but I can go through a
little bit of the hardware at the end
I'm John the Ripper I think does about a
million or two million passwords per
second maybe and I got a graph in just a
little while that will show some of the
GPU based type stuff but but for the
most part with like one average video
card like a new video 295 GTX you can
get about 300 million passwords per
second so pretty much any gamer that has
a spare video card can do this which is
bad
alright so here's what I consider the
top breaches of the last couple of years
and so this is just an example of the
week hashing password algorithms that
are out there everybody remember rock
you rock you yes anyway so their breach
consisted of let me get this number
right 14 million something or other
passwords and they were all hatched in
md5 which is a really bad algorithm
because it does not require a salt salt
and passwords are a little bit better
sure everybody remembers gawkers gawkers
had 67 million passwords which were in
Des which is such an old algorithm that
our gpu-based crash where password
crackers can't even do it because of
some hardware level type of thing but we
still managed to crack that many of them
even which on the Ripper PHP BB which
was a big form board anyway they had a
big week 18 million md5 s armony just
recently had a giant breach 224 million
md fives and then I'm not allowed to say
the name of this site but anyway so they
also had a breach of 38 million md5 s no
no once again I'm not allowed to say the
name of the site no anyway so the reason
that we have these lists is because
these are absolute goldmine of
information because these are real live
passwords that people are using and I
can guarantee you that you know some
lady on eHarmony that's trying to find a
date use the exact same password for her
bank account and you can guarantee it um
so but the reason that that that might
be a nefarious reason for one these
lists the reason that we want these list
is for patterns you know I'm looking for
stuff like our people separating words
with special characters you know for
example like is that a new pattern
that's a
so the things that we can learn are the
most common password links which are
important the most common character sets
the most common masks and I'll tell you
what a mask is in just one second and
the frequency of root passwords what i
mean by the root password is if you take
away all the upper case and the lead and
all that garbage you're left with what's
called a root password and so that's
really all that we're concerned about
because as will look at later we can
apply all these rules to a root password
and so instead of having a word list
that's babka trillion gigabytes we can
just have a little bitty word list and a
lot of effective rules and so that's the
way that that's the way that we attack
password attack passwords nowadays all
right so when I'm talking about password
masks what I'm talking about is
replacing all the lowercase letters with
? L upper case ? EU numbers ? these
special characters ? ass there's also a
question mark h4 hex characters but I
don't have never used it and and I don't
want to put it up there and confuse
anybody so going back to my password
that I had before because i work at
activant and I was you know it's year
2011 and I thought this would be a good
password so my mask would look like this
so that doesn't make a lot of sense
right now but it will in a second so if
we do some analysis I'm not going to do
all the whisks i'm going to do rock you
and then i combined all the rest of them
so if we analyze the rock you list we
can see the first thing we want to look
at is them is the line count statistics
and this is how many characters the
passwords were doesn't matter if they're
upper low or special or anything like
that we want to look at how many
characters so we can see that twenty
percent of them are eight character
passwords so when I complete my first
attack against a current password list
i'm going to use eight characters as the
first you know that's going to be my
first base line because twenty percent
of 14 million bna characters is a lot
and then you can see the next one down
is seven the next one down is nine ten
and so on and so so based on number of
characters this is the
Mac Monmouth ology is going to go into
and there's no one specific special
attack against a password list you
normally have to do multiple multiple
things which will kind of look at later
to kind of whittle your list down one at
a time so the next thing we want to look
at in the statistics of the rock you
list is we want to look at the character
set statistics and so we can see that
forty-two percent of the passwords are
lower alphanumeric meaning all they used
was lower case characters and numbers so
that is close to half so now armed with
these facts now I know that if I do an
eight character attack with numbers and
letters lowercase I'm going to get all
this fifty percent of the passwords so
the next statistic we want to look at is
this particular tool what it does is it
outputs the masks remember the masked we
were talking about so it outputs the
masks in lower up or digits and so
something interesting that you can see
in these top 10 or 15 or however many
masks there are is that there are no use
there's no upper case at all and so what
that tells me is that people are not
using a lot of uppercase letters in
real-world passwords and so you can see
that the most popular mask was eight
lowercase digits which we already
determined from some of the other stuff
but so this type of thing is useful
because once you start adding up with
adding up lists and lists and lists you
can start seeing what the most common
masks are and so keep in mind this is
only one list alright so what I did here
was I analyzed I put all those password
lists of those top five breaches
together and I did a little bit of
analysis and so basically this is
telling me the exact same thing that I
already knew is that eight characters is
the most popular line count and alpha
lower alpha numeric is the is the most
popular character set of passwords
so and then what i can do is i can get
my top five masks out of here and these
masks like this work in OC l hash cat
and hash cat is which is why I use these
masks and why we made this tool to do
this so these are the first 10 or 12
attacks that i'm going to try against
any password list before i even i'm not
even going to get out a word list
because i don't need one because i know
that these are the patterns that humans
are you doing right now alright so how
does all this info help us it eliminates
the needs for a large word lists because
these masks attacks do not require a
word list it's basically a brute force
but it's only a brute force of the
character set that you place in there so
if you put an El it's only doing a brute
force of A to Z lower like I said these
masks can be used with ocl hash cat
these masks allow us to profile password
policies and so every time we analyze a
new breach we get more info for our
attacks the way that that I can profile
a password policy is I might go into a
company and I'm like dump the hash
database and I might only crack five
percent of the passwords with my initial
brief force however what I can do is
then analyzed that small list of
passwords and while looking at it I can
nine times out of ten determine the
password policy of that organization and
then I can retailer my attack just to
that password policy
yes yeah basically i would just redo the
masks to match the policy and like i
said there's no one all super inclusive
attack i wish there was but sometimes
you got to try eight or ten or twelve
different masks but they won't you know
you keep whittling away at the list
eventually you'll get enough of them and
i'm actually at i had a video that was
awesome but we can't see it but i'm
going to try to explain the attack but
anyway so here's kind of my mythology
and this is the mythology that we used
in the contest this is what a lot of
people were interested in the first
thing we did was we brute forced all the
lists for up to five six characters
based on our GPU hardware that really
only took about 10 or 15 minutes and so
that gave us our initial list where we
started to where we started to look at
the patterns the thing about this
contest what that was a little bit
different on that I gotta mention is
that it was not really real world those
guys at corelogic or password cracking
champions and they made this contest as
hard as they possibly could and so some
of these real-world patterns that i'm
talking about weren't in there however
once we started looking at their whist
there were some patterns that they
inadvertently did and so because what
they initially did was they use john
rules to create their list they had a
base list of words and then they use
rules from John and created the list so
once we figured out what some of those
rules were we got a little bit farther
I'm the next thing I would do is
wordless attacks I would do straight
word lists I do not keep thousands and
thousands of gigs a wordless I think I
might have five gigs max of wordless and
and that they are they are useful but
they're more useful with rules which is
what I'll get to you later then I would
go into all my mask attacks that I came
up with with all my you know profiling
policies then I would do what's called a
combination attack which is what we'll
look at an example of that in a minute
the next thing that I would do is the
new version of hash cat has the ability
to create rule files similar to John the
Ripper but they're a little bit more
sophisticated so i would i would build a
policy inside one of those rural files
and then the very last thing i would do
is something that we talked
about called a fingerprint attack and
that's what the video I was going to
show was but you can't see it up here
but but I'm going to try to explain it
even though it's tough I was going to do
it live but I seem to be having some
internet issues that are verizon's fault
yeah i'll be sure to hook up to the
hotel Wi-Fi yeah so so i threw this in
there because this is like a graph of
how we how we progress through the
contest if you'll notice i'm just to
reiterate how hard the contest was i
mean there was ten people experienced
super password crackers on my team and
we only got about 38,000 of the 60,000
passwords or maybe there was 58 thousand
don't remember but you'll notice that
you can see how we climbed really
quickly in the very beginning when we
brute force some passwords then when we
started to use all our mask attacks and
our word lists and everything we we made
a little steady climb but then you can
see right around 30,000 we kind of hit a
plateau and that was the point where we
had to go in and start analyzing the
list and figuring out the patterns about
you know doing it a little bit doing a
little bit more sophisticated than just
running tools at a password list because
we had a what the inside pro guys who
are who are Russian professional they
make a commercial software tool and it's
my understanding they have racks and
racks and racks of servers password
cracking they were actually hot on our
tail they were right behind us the
entire contest and so it was at this
point that we had to really kind of get
down and and figure out some some
password patterns which we did and so
what that what that shows though is that
password cracking is more of an art you
know it's not just slamming tools into
the end of the list and getting as much
as you can even though that's what a lot
of people do if you really want to
recover a lot of passwords you got to
kind of dive into the patterns
alright so using the GPU to crack
passwords this is huge this is what
brought password cracking back in my
opinion at this point passwords under
eight characters are pretty much a joke
excuse me with the hardware we have now
we can brief or say characters in less
than a few hours just ridiculous and the
difference between that is most modern
desktops have about 2 to 12 cores
depending on up here how much money you
have or a game or whatever whatever
whatever you're doing and so if you
think about each of those cores as a
thread in the real simplistic terms you
know so we're working with 2 to 12
parallel threads password cracking well
what they found out about GPUs is that
they have a hundred and 62 240 course
and some of the newer GPUs even have
more than that and so what they found
out is that they could thread those GPU
applications to do parallel tasks just
like they could with the processors and
so that multiplied that the number of
passwords exponentially that could be
that could be correct so what's the best
technology to use new vidya has support
through their Kudo architecture I'm
going to stay at all political debates
about what's better ati support is
through stream both of those are
proprietary formats so the open source
community they got together and they
developed a technology called opencl
which is an open source and supports
both architectures I just like this
picture
so I what's better i don't know i use in
a video because and the reason behind
that is is because the CUDA architecture
has a lot better development ati cards
are actually faster however the
catalysts are the stream development is
not quite on par with new vidya as far
as i'm concerned so I like to sacrifice
a little bit of speed for stability but
your mileage might vary on that one so
you all were asking about the statistics
can't see those on my computer but
anyway so here's a here's a couple of
graphs that show on the top one is a
tuna Vidya for a dgt X's and you can see
on ntlm it does for it does four billion
30 Keys per second so that's a lot
that's only a one hash when you add a
whole bunch of hashes like two million
hashes it does drop down to 2.5 billion
which is still quite a few sorry
yeah that's pot that's per second anyway
yeah so it's per second and so the
numbers are therefore md5 sha-1 my
sequel anyway and then so under that I
have a graph of an ati card I don't know
in an ati card I got this from Adam so
so this is on a HD 5970 you can see that
one hash on ntlm is quite a bit faster
on a single hash but if you look over at
the two million hashes it's
significantly less so based on some of
these numbers you might want to decide
are you're going to be doing one two
three four and five hashes are you going
to be doing lists of hundreds of
thousands of hashes from a company so
like I said your mileage may vary on
cards I use numidia um wordless people
are always asking me where do I store
all my millions of terabytes of wordless
I don't have them you know i like i said
i have like five gigabytes of wordless
because it's all i need there so there's
only so many words out there and
everything else is rule-based
combinations so so i don't have a big
terabyte raid array with all this stuff
i think it's a waste of space using
those masks that i showed you earlier is
much much more effective and using these
root root words with rules so if i have
the word password and I have a rule that
upper cases every letter I have a rule
that appends digits from the end I have
a rule that leads every word you know
have all these rules which is much much
faster than going through a giant list
of words also a large word list is
impossible to manage and maintain I
don't know if anyone's ever tried to
open up more than a two gig word list
and nano or something but it's a it's a
bad situation of promise alright so this
is the stuff i skipped when i was
talking about my sophisticated
fingerprint attack last year i missed
this stuff on how ocl hash code actually
works and
I thought I'd go back and and kind of
talk about it just a little bit this is
so initially I'll just go through the
command a little bit the M is the M is
just a switch for the algorithm that
you're going to use 0 as md5 so and
there's some other flags and stuff and
I'm not going to go all through all
those because I wanted to get that I
wanted to go back to the to the basic
part because a lot of people don't
understand it's kind of hard to get your
head around so the next thing I want is
our list of hashes and then the next two
things is hashed out works on what's
called a left and a right mask and so it
has to do both so there's what's it's
going to do on the left side of the word
of what's it going to do on the right
side of the word and so what I have here
is implemented when I was talking
earlier about the combination attack so
one of the things that we can do is we
can take one of our crack dictionaries
that we you know got from Gawker or
whatever and we can put one dictionary
on the left side and we can put one
dictionary on the right side and so what
that will do is you can see in the
little graph where I got dictionary one
and dictionary too then over on the
right I tried to I tried to implement
all those words will be put together one
in the beginning of one in the end one
at the end one in the beginning and
they'll be combinative through there so
basically what I've done is I've taken a
word list out of six words and I'll turn
that into an infinite number of
combinations that it could possibly be
and I haven't used a terabyte of space
on my hard drive or whatever and I got a
few more examples to try to try to make
that left and right mask make a little
more sense so here's a couple more
examples so in the first example you can
see at the end i have my left mask and
my right mask and so remember my masks
dewas digit right so at this point what
I'm doing is I'm saying take my
dictionary which is dictionary one and i
want you to a pen two digits to the end
of every sing
or and so this is basically a rule that
I'm given ocl hashcode and so I've
exponentially increased my word list and
I've still only got six words in
dictionary one or whatever and then this
can be used in any way and so in the
next example what I'm doing is I'm
prepending for lowercase words or
letters actually a price should fix that
so it's so it's going to try a through z
every single every single possibility a
through z for four spaces and it's going
to prepend it to every word in my
dictionary so that can be effective too
and these are the kind of things that
you just got to play around with and
figure out which ones are the best for
you so the other nice function is that
what if I want to use numbers and digits
because member alphanumeric was the most
popular password so I want to use
numbers and digits you can throw it a
variable so if you can look down here I
got a one and I've given it lower upper
special n digits so that's all 94
typable characters and then what I do is
I just use that one as my mask down
there so at this point I'm saying take
my dictionary word and try to prepend
two places of all 94 typable characters
to the end of the word so that's kind of
how that works kind of hope that makes
sense to anybody and you can play around
with you can play around with the place
settings you don't have you can do more
than one variable you can do a2 and a3
and give it different variables if you
wanted to do something different on the
left mask and the right mask so so
there's also rules I just made two
charts of the rules I'm probably not
going to go through all of them but i'll
show you how to pass the rule so on that
same command line we could pass it some
rules even at the same time as the left
and the right mask so we could pass it
the rule the lowercase to uppercase to
capitalize these aren't groundbreaking
because John has always had rules
but there are some new ones in here that
that uh that aren't exactly that are a
little bit different than John but so
some of the ones I like to use is like
trunk a web and truncate right and
append characters and prepend characters
like for example if it's 2011 if that's
the year I always try to prepend 2011 to
every single word in my dictionary you
know just in case it might work so these
rules you can play around with you can
pass more than one rule to the to the to
the command it takes the first rule
first and then it does the second rule
so there's a way you can play around
with it and the way that you pass rules
is exactly the same as the left and the
right you have to pass a rule to the
right side and you have to pass a rule
to the website you can do one or the
other or both so Jay passes a rule to
whatever is happening on the left side
so in this first example what's going on
is i'm using my dictionary and at the
end of the dictionary I'm appending to
uppercase characters to the end of each
word and at the same time I'm going to
uppercase the first character in my
dictionary so that will give me
something like uppercase you know five
lowers and then two more upper cases and
so if you want to pass a rule to the
right side you give it the case which so
like in this example right here C is
capitalized so what I'm saying is to
take my two dictionaries and put them on
both sides and capitalize the first word
in each dictionary on both sides that
actually probably wouldn't be all that
effective now that i think about it
because it would be a capital letter in
the middle of the word however a lot of
times people have noticed lately people
are separating words with a special
character like because everybody's
talking about we got to use pass phrases
and not passwords and so a lot of times
people will think of a two-word phrase
or a three-word phrase and I've seen
special characters on the inside of
those phrases so putting a special
character in the middle of two
dictionaries come culminating on top of
each other can be effective
and I've seen that be effective uh then
like I said the bracket cuts off the
last cuts off the last character of the
cuts off the last character of the of
the word and so something that's the
reason that i show that something that's
funny is in the beginning there was no
way with this ocl hashmap version there
was no way just to run a straight
wordlist attack so what you had to do
was what you had to do was you had to do
this hack here at the bottom so what you
had to do was you had to give it you had
to tell the K flag to remove the last
character of every word then you had to
give it your word list and then you had
to give it a character at the end in
order to remove it and then it would
just use the word list itself so that
was kind of a failure in the beginning
that nobody thought of so that was a
major complaint with ocl hashtag and
then the other major complaint was that
there was no crypt md5 support and the
other major complaint was that there was
no support for rule files every rule had
to be given on the command blonde one at
a time so instead of recoding the entire
application what happened was oh CL has
cap plus was born it actually did away
with the left and the right side
mechanism and so what it did was it can
use word lists or it can even use an
entire directory of word lists and it
uses rule files similar to John the
Ripper but there's a lot more rules
available and it also supports md5 crypt
and so an example of an example of that
being run would be right here would be
the M flag which is md5 are hashes texts
end is actually kind of a nice level
there's between 1 and 1 60 so it kind of
depends on your GPU and the shaders and
the clocks which nights nice level works
the best for you for me it's 80
generally it's 84 Anna Vidya and 164 a
TI and then so now we have rule files
there in the rules directory it ships
with a bunch of different rules but
you can get in there and make up your
own rules based on any of these lists
and then you can out doubt o is just
output to a file and then and then you
pass it a word list at the end just like
you would John the Ripper or you can
give a slash and a star and it will run
all the word lists in that director you
want after the other alright so what are
some solutions we can look at from some
of these password policy policy things
this talk was originally designed for
something at my work so I got to come up
with some solutions so better
application coding practices obviously
like I said one of the worst things is
lazy coders that don't validate you know
certain characters in their in their web
applications and that type of thing I
encourage all companies to have regular
password audits by a third third party
company definitely definitely more
sophisticated password policies
increased minimum password lengths
there's no substitute for a long as
password I mean there just isn't you
know the longer the better unfortunately
another thing is to complain when you
see bad policies every time I want to
pen test and I see a you know a default
Active Directory policy I always try to
mention it it doesn't always come up
with the best the best response but but
I always try to mention it I feel it's
my duty so this stuff is dope where can
I learn more there's my website question
defense my friend dead ones website
right here Oh B dash security info they
have a ton of he has a ton of hash cat
tutorials and a bunch of stuff on the
rules and how to use them and then
obviously the hashtag website you're an
idiot we cannot complain about this if
you have any questions at all about any
of this stuff you can email me or you
can hit me up on Twitter or you can
I don't know talk to me later thanks how
we have a question I'm sorry
number one I would create I would
enforce passphrases the way that I would
enforce that is i would say that there
has to be a special character or some
type of thing separate you know in the
middle of the word I would not allow the
first letter to be capitals I would not
allow numbers to be at the end you know
I would do the reverse you know that
policy we look at in the beginning said
that no numbers could be separated from
each other I would reverse that I would
say if you have you must have at least
two numbers and they cannot be next to
each other you know it's all about and
then like I said it's about length oh
you know over 10 characters making sure
you use everything available yeah I mean
alternating case is good it it's all
about think about the way that I like to
think about it is think about what i
would do as a password and I'm just as
guilty as anyone else if it says use one
uppercase letter I'm making it the first
letter because it's easier you know what
i mean so if i say you've got to use to
uppercase characters and it can't be the
first letter that's going to force
somebody to put them inside the word
somewhere which which all those little
bitty things added together increases
the password strength exponentially
absolutely i mean random generated stuff
is always going to be better than then a
password however getting your users you
know i might be able to remember that
but the problem is you know it's bad
policy to use your passwords in the same
place all over the place so so while i
can probably remember one two three
maybe randomly generated passwords i
can't remember as many as I need for the
internet totally so unfortunately random
passwords are always better but it's a
little bit unfeasible especially when
you're talking about you know your user
base it
sure shit I don't care about 123456 shit
I kind of care about signs are
complicated I really care about 45
absolutely and so that's the exact same
thing that I do have some high-level
passwords some medium and some low-level
the problem is getting you know us being
involved in technology hacking and
security that makes a lot of sense but
that does not make sense to my mom you
know she could give up she could care
less about any of that kind of stuff and
she uses the password you know same
password all over the place you did
despite what I say because it's easy to
remember yeah
so so best-case scenario this is my big
idea and so the problem is is that I'll
break into things I don't create sort of
policies so if i was going to create a
policy for example if i was creating a
web application I would go to one of
those websites that has like the top 500
worst passwords in the world or
something like that and I would take
that and then I would take the year and
I would take some really you know some
other random stuff because it doesn't
take that long to go through a couple
thousand words real quick and then when
users are input validating that once
again I'm not a web app coder either so
I don't know how feasible this is but I
do think it would be possible to compare
your password very quickly against a
list of just really stupid shit and then
you know what I mean in it and if it
passed the list then it's okay
I start I start with a brute force
because a brute force on our GPU
machines takes like five minutes so I
get everything I can between one and
five characters and so once I get that
what I was going to show you was this
fingerprint attacker if you ask me later
have a video of it online but it
basically does a brute force of the list
and expands it and then puts the two
sides of the expanded list together and
keeps cracking over and over again you
never need a word list ever so so I do
all those types of things but I always
start out with a five to six character
brute force to get the low-hanging fruit
kind of thing Wow
yes can you give me an example of an are
you talking about an application right
I mean nine times I mean nine times out
of ten the easiest way is to is to
manage all your devices with active
directory and they make it that way for
a reason you know for example I was just
on a wireless assessment where they were
doing I had a radius implementation
which is supposed to be secure but it's
not and so the radius implementation was
using MSF chat version 2 so as soon as I
crack the radius not only was on the
wireless network i already had
credentials on the network you know
because they were using ad credentials
so so generally I see ad is being used
across the board so and and the bad part
about that is is that some appliances
store those ad passwords in less complex
formats like md5 than ntlm so sometimes
you can attack that way Cisco for
example if you were using if you are
managing some Cisco devices you know
their hashing algorithm is weaker than
ad and can be pulled down from the
conveyor some some I've seen it before
yeah in the config
ok
you