so welcome my talk this is about pen
testing and performing security
assessments on ipv6 my name is Rick
Hayes I am a security consultant or a
company I'm not gonna say who but for a
company I'm also the host of the episode
daily podcast which you guys that
attended last night we certainly thank
you and so I saw one of them one of the
guys that was on there but anyways what
I'm going to cover today is ipv6 and why
does it matter go through a brief
overview of ipv6 then talk about
assessing ipv6 networks and then
accessing accessing ipv6 networks
assessing ipv6 networks and then I was
going to do a demo but we're probably
just going to swing it and just go
through the demo as we do the
presentation and so just a little
background on how this kind of whole
thing got started was I was doing an
internal assessment at a corporation and
asked to look at their data center so I
came back and said these are the results
that we found he said so just run in map
scans and find out all the boxes that
you can see and I should have known when
he said that it was kind of a test which
I failed because i only found half the
boxes so he said he said show me what
you've got and I said this is this is
the listing you know here's all the end
map results and goes great where's the
others i said what others he said the
other boxes he said our Devon and our
test boxes I said I didn't you give me
the subnet she wanted me to scan and he
said yes he said but I gave you the ipv4
subnet you didn't ask for ipv6 and we
have an entire half of our data center
that is running ipv6 because we're
trying to switch over internally I said
great let me just fire up some tools and
see what I can find so I tried to fire
up
some commercial tools to find those
devices and I failed miserably because
you don't configure them the same way
they don't work the same way so I asked
him what it was his driver and obviously
we know what the driver is for moving to
ipv6 it's the depletion of the ipv4
minus the horse that are keeping the the
blocks that are allocated to them
there's there's none left unless your
verizon and and other companies that but
but as we say that there's going to be a
transition period so a lot of folks are
starting to look at ipv6 they're doing
it internally perhaps not externally but
internally they're doing it and they're
looking to transition so we're in a
period of flux and probably going to be
there for the better part of maybe 10 to
15 years which is kind of cool because
you think about it that's a really slow
learning curve you can kind of get
ramped up very slowly but the idea is
this is what ipv6 usage from the
internet nessus broadband looked like
circa nineteen ninety nine and you can
see it's not that great there wasn't a
lot it was mostly geeks and universities
that were doing it and other people's
doing you know research and probably not
even security research we step forward
to 2011 and we can see that it has grown
by leaps and bounds that's not that that
that's a good transition that you see
there when you see going from that to
this that's a coverage area so that
being said there are a lot of folks that
have some right targets out there if
that's what you're into but that are
running on ipv6 a lot of your customers
or our customers are running ipv6 and if
we don't have the knowledge or the tool
set to go out and assess them then we're
missing half the battle so we got some
changes going on right now we got ipv
ipv4 only devices we got devices that
are ipv4 and ipv6 we've got devices that
are ipv6 only so the issue is that this
change isn't going to happen it's going
to be
hello it should be methodical but you're
going to start seeing companies doing
they're testing for integrating the ipv6
into their current infrastructure rather
than going out to a marketplace and
saying I need to pay some kind of bounty
to get a knife you know ipv4 address or
block I can just cheaply do it instead
of changing over if I'm going to change
over anyways why not just go over 26 and
be done with it so real quick and again
because I started out not knowing a
whole hell of a lot about ipv6 so I
figured I can't be the only guy that
doesn't know a whole hell of a lot about
it but if if I say anything wrong please
correct me if you know more than I do
which I'm assuming it's most of the view
this is probably just rudimentary but I
be feat ipv6 is obviously the the next
generation is the replacement for ipv4
it was developed by the IETF and if you
look and see when it actually came out
it came out in 98 so that's why that map
of 99 becomes important so and again it
does with packet switching internet
working and to end Datagram transmission
here's the significant part I pv6 uses
128-bit address which supports 2128 I'm
sorry it supports 2028 networks and so
that's 340 unit whatever it's just a
shitload I don't know how to pronounce
it so I'm not going to tell you ipv4
supports about you know four billion and
so we've already run through those ipv6
eliminates the necessity to have matting
so we got to start getting back to like
the old universities or current
universities where everything is a
publicly addressable IP address so yeh
but the idea is we don't have to worry
about the exhaustion of those because by
the time we exhaust ipv6 will be at v8
and so we can just continue to start
looking at the next generation probably
256-bit address and nobody will
certainly be able to remember that so
the days of us being able to say go to
you know blank blank that blanked out
blank are over so I say that but yet
what was the premise thought behind it
so they wanted to simplify the the
address assignment so they put in some
mechanisms that allows a device to be
able to essentially auto configure
itself unless you're a mac and and I'll
get to that and so it provides for
network remembering and again all of
this is just basic as part of it as part
of the RFC but the idea was they wanted
to make sure the one mechanism that they
included which was we all know is a
bolt-on type II before was security so
hip SEC is included in it now a lot of
people you'll see the RFC says it's
mandatory but it's not it's actually
recommended you don't have to use IPSec
as part of an ipv6 implementation you
can run things unencrypted and still use
ipv6 because what it does is for
backwards compatibility is allows you to
be able to say if a device talks to
another device and says sorry I don't
speak that lingo meaning if sec then it
says okay well let's talk plain text and
it goes okay and that's fine so all you
have to do is essentially say I don't
want to encrypt my data my datagrams and
it won't do it so one of the significant
changes that came out of that was
obviously the new header format and
we're going to take a look at that in a
second the quality of service and then
they added something called neighbor
discovery protocol which is essentially
ICMP version 6 but it replaces art so
the the notion of doing art poisoning is
gone now we also have router discovery
messages and redirect messages and some
other multicast and unicast messages
which become fairly important as we
start looking at an ipv6 infrastructure
so just to give you a quick comparison
ipv4 is 32 bits versus 128 again you
have the auto configuration for ipv4 is
dhcp but you have to use dhcp version 6
which is optional you have to use a ipic
IP version 6
you have the router announcements and
arp is no longer there so you use ICMP
and again you see where it says
mandatory for ipsec it's actually
recommended at your EV RFC so this is
what an ipv6 address looks like it
shouldn't be any surprise to anyone of
you but there's multiple ways that you
could write it so they figured that all
those zeroes we're going to confuse us
so they said hey you could remove the
leading zeros in the 16-bit block
address and you can make it look like
that or you could just go with a double
colon notation and you kind of truncate
it down so all three of those are
legitimate ipv6 addresses different
operating systems present them
differently to you so it's important for
you to know how about how those work the
all three of them with this all three of
these are the same exact IP address so
on a configuration ipv6 hosts with the
exceptions of max can auto configure
themselves to get an ipv6 address so
what they do is they use a router
discovery message message which is what
actually is required and Apple
implements that but the thing of it is
if it doesn't receive a message back
from a router it says I need to find a
DHCP 6v6 server if I don't see that then
i say i have no capability of assigning
myself an IP address so if you set your
mac or you know any any system to using
ipv6 and you say automatic go and see if
it get you an IP address if you do not
have a router that says this is what you
need to be using because it has no
concept of what the local link is so
again going into IPSec the same thing
for ipv6 applies that was you know
relevant ipv4 it provides that whole CI
a confidential company g ality data
integrity the one thing it does provide
is the authentication so you can
actually go through if it's enabled on
ipv6 and both sides agree to it you can
actually say
are you the one that sent me this packet
I can validate that you're the one that
sent it to me so you I mean think about
that from a man-in-the-middle
perspective that kind of changes the
paradigm a little bit if you have anti
replay again I can't do a packet capture
and just replay those package back over
because I can then go and verify that
those packets were unique and they
weren't duplicated they haven't been
seen out on the wire before so this is
the significant change now when you
start looking at ipv4 header everybody's
seen those we've seen them hundreds of
times so I mean that's nothing new but
the fact of the matter is everything
that's in yellow on that and unless
you're colorblind I will kind of pointed
out it's those those are actually the
ones that are carried over because they
wanted to keep them the same form ipv4
to v6 so you can see that it
significantly changed in the sense that
it's more simplistic so they achieved
what they wanted to so they didn't
include a lot of the other stuff and
there is some the flow label we talked
about quality of service that's the
actual flow label that will go into that
particular part of the header so I
talked about icmpv6 again it's defined
by RFC 2463 this is just what a packet
looks like so you see the previous ipv6
header you have the ipv6 payload
compared to what you would have down so
that payload that is going to consist of
an ICMP v6 header and that message is
all going to go into the ipv6 payload I
just want to say v6 versus IP so the
ICMP v6 provides a multicast listener
discovery and neighbor discovery and
that multicast listener discovery kind
of becomes important but the neighbor
discovery is extremely important because
it tells you what who's your neighbor
who's on the same wire that I am and
what that defines is I am NOT crossing a
router that's what that's defined as so
and again it replaces igmp for those of
you that are interested but it also
makes sure that it has your
ship management for the multicast
segments you're going to be on so you
know for those of us that are used to
dealing with multicast nothing's really
changed assist the addresses have
changed this is what the new v6
multicast looks like so when I want to
paint everybody I actually contain this
address right here FF 0 2 colon colon 1
now if i want to see all of the routers
that are on there as well FF 0 2 colon
colon 2 so you can go through and you
can see that this is sorry this is kind
of cool that you can just ping that
address and I have done I've essentially
done a pink sweep of everybody on that
so they will all reply back I'm here so
neighbor discovery it determines the
link layer addressing so but it does is
think about it it makes sure that I
don't have a duplicate address you're
not going to have the same v6 address
that I have it's also going to make sure
that i know of the routers that are out
there it's going to make sure that i
know all of the neighbors when they come
up when when they come down because they
announce themselves of doing so now when
they go down if it's in like a hard
crash they just won't be there but
generally when they're being shut down
there nice they send out hey I'm I'm
going away I'm going bye-bye I'm not
going to be here one of the things that
the icmpv6 actually has those five main
package which is a router solicitation
who's the router out their router
advertisements I'm the router neighbor
solicitation who's my neighbor and again
advertisements yeah I'm your neighbor
trust me and of course then the
redirects and and again the redirects
are the same thing that we've seen from
before so we talked about dns and this
is where it actually becomes kind of
interesting because we have a records
now with v6 we have quad a records I
don't know why they got some original
that they just came out with quad a but
still and we have the point of records
or the reverse records that are exactly
the same so a lot of applications right
now rely from a v6 perspective rely on
DNS so they're going to query a hostname
so that's problematic if you think about
trying to just say I need to see what's
out there so I'm going to say hey send
me all of the you know neighbor
solicitation who's my neighbor talked to
me and they all tell you and you're like
cool now I want to talk to you but all I
all I've been given is your v6 address I
don't know who you are because it
doesn't announce that the host name in
that so accessing how do you access now
in a local subnet it was fairly easy i
just plugged into an rj45 jack and Bob's
your uncle I was on their network if
you're wondering what operating systems
support it that's the ton that do
most of them by default and some of them
support them ipv6 better than others but
for the majority of them if you think
about Windows 2008 it's enabled by
default 7 by default keep going down the
list of all of the ones that it's
enabled ubuntu all of its on by default
now the interesting thing or the scary
thing is if i go and i actually so how
do you enable it so i'm going to show
you basically you can on a mac and this
is very just matched mac specific so
essentially it's going to I have to go
through and I have to tell it that I
want to add it to all okay now I've
already done it so it's going to come
back with an error but you can see what
I've got there now if I want to see the
firewall list and this is by default
have not changed it does that look good
to anybody and I don't know if you can
see that so I'll read it it's all 65535
ports allow from any to any that's the
default firewall rule that's when if
you're if you're on our side it's bad if
you're not so so that being said there's
some fail built into this so if you have
an is box and you've set up rule sets
for ipv4 you have to do the same thing
for ipv6 and they're not the same
commands
so if you're from coming in from an
internet perspective you don't have ipv6
you don't have a provider ISP that does
it what do you do go to hurricane
electric get you go go find a broker
there's tons of them out there that
support i say tons there's three but
they're geographically dispersed so
there's tons i guess geographically but
you just go it's free this one's free
you can register they ask for your
publicly facing IP address and that's it
there's clients out there okay now here
they are so go go six free net there
they're actually cool except for the
only part is they only cover Montreal am
stern am Taipei and Sydney but damn they
got a great ass client that works well
so what do they support six and 24 which
is ipv6 and 24 and four into six which
is ipv4 which is what we would want we
would want our four networks to be able
to talk to a six network hurricane
electric covers the US and again it
supports well US Canada Europe Hong Kong
Tokyo maybe not so much Singapore in it
does six under four and six is also does
a US brazil in Europe and that's a six
end 24 so that's really what you're
looking for from an external perspective
if you want to assess a customer and you
don't have that capability get a broker
it's fairly easy the eula allows you to
do that in fact most of them include the
tools right on their websites to be able
to assess which ports are open on a VIP
v6 network or internet facing system
because they're assuming it's a regular
laptop or something else that's public
facing so assessing an ipv6 network so
where the rubber meets the road so when
we normally do a v4 reconnaissance
normally when we do reconnaissance we
say hey just run a ping sweep and find
out what's alive and go through that or
we may do a full port scan you know all
65535 tcp and same thing you know so we
may do all of that to find out what's
out there that sounds great we can see
which ones don't respond to a pain we
can go through the whole myriad of
things in a v6 environment you can't do
that because essentially you
be sending whatever that equates to it's
a ton because it's like wait it's
so many zeros it's not even funny the
point being it's not feasible to do in a
pink sweep of an entire v6 network
because guess what if their routing that
you're also talking to internet-facing
systems you're talking to universities
and other folks that are running v6 so
that doing that to find out what's alive
is problematic as you can well imagine
which is kind of what I ran into so
quickly on a droid without the customer
knowing i went and found out how do i
discover what's out there well looks
like you can go in and you can query
those quad a records but you have to
know the dns server to be able to query
them well that kind of sucks you have to
know the IP IP address what i
didn't know that and for the most part
everyone of the all of this required dns
because even if i had to start i had to
start with a hostname and kind of work
backwards and i didn't have any of that
so I started looking at some other recon
tools out there ping six so you can use
ping six its installed by default on
backtrack and I think a bunt to Mac has
it you don't have to have a pink six
version with a windows box paying works
on the ipv6 just natively it works on v4
or v6 so you can use n mount and maps
kind of quirky though and we're going to
talk about that in a few seconds you can
use a half scan six the v6 version of it
metasploit netcat in cat so cat and then
the THC ipv6 attacked toolkit that's the
mack daddy that's the one you really
want to get it's not included by default
on backtrack so you got to download it
install it which can be problematic if
you don't want a customer to know that
you're doing it so that's why we're
having this talk so you'll know to have
your tools a hit you know together ahead
of time pain six does exactly what it
says it paint and so you can actually
but you have to know the the address
that you're going to pinger the hostname
and again if you have a hostname it has
to have
v6 resolvers so the DNS has to come into
play but you can see that i can actually
kind of trick it i can say i want to
paying all of those remember that FF 0 2
colon colon or colon colon one we talked
about earlier for the multicast if i
peeing that it tells me which ones are
alive so i have every one of these and
you can see it's sequentially doing two
of them and then a third one pops in so
i have that just to ignore the fe 80 but
20 c 21 f & a 6 e d that pops in there
so it tells me how many duplicates again
because remember we talked about the
fact that saying how many remember we
talked about replay so it actually knows
and it uses that capability in map and
map has some limitations it's a great
tool i absolutely love it but the only
thing that it's a limiter about it is it
only does TCP connect that kind of blows
you could do a pink scanned you can do a
list scanned you can do version
detection it does all of the other stuff
that you would think it does let's go
here so if i run a in map on it well
here's a here's a here's one that I ran
just like a few minutes ago but
essentially all I'm doing is telling it
that I want to run a visa you know v6 so
I put a dash 6 I wanted to do tcp I tell
it I don't need you to get a response or
assume the box is dead okay and then in
that case then it does the the port
mapping and it comes back and tells me
those the interesting thing is if I run
that and I'm going to get to that way
I'll get to that in a second so that's
the actual results that we would see on
windows 2003 box I think I have yes this
is the same thing this is a metasploit
able box I think yes so if i do a
comparison between a v6 and a v4 scan
and this is a 1025 132 versus the v6 can
you see the difference if you can't i
pointed them out for you because it took
me a little bit of time to figure it out
there's some changes why because there's
rule sets that are set on there by
default that allow certain things to
work and certain things not to work if I
hadn't allowed those so the key one is I
don't have a web server if I'm looking
at it from a v6 perspective so I can't
attack a web server by a v6 the same
thing can be true inversely I could also
have services that are available on a v4
network and then I'm sorry on a v6
network that are not available or
presented on a visa vie for network so
think about if somebody's trying to be
cute see an opera skate or hide what
they're doing by putting in on v6 and
thinking nobody's going to find that ftp
server you can find it so half scan six
you can you can you know look at it it's
I think it's a good product does sin
port scanning it's it starts from zero
goes all the way down through unless you
specify a range so it'll just tell you
it's timed out and keep going and keep
going and then it reports what's open so
I think in map does a better job but
again for completeness just to cover all
the v6 native tools that was one of them
metasploit it supports native natively
supports v6 if the stack below it has v6
enabled so if you don't have v6 enabled
on a box guess what you can run into
you're blue in the face it's going to
it's going to give you some Ruby errors
and some other stuff and when you go
Google it's going to say this has been
resolved in an older version and and
then you realize oh yeah that's right I
just able to ipv6 on that box because I
didn't think I needed it so you got to
go make sure you re-enable it on your
test box one of the things that actually
does is it uses art so you're thinking
whoa ipv6 doesn't use art well one of
the things that actually does require in
some of these is it actually does
require that you have an ipv4 address
added in there and you'll see it in a
second so for a local host you can put
in a v4 or v6 address for the remote
host you can put in a four or six and I
say
six and sometimes and you'll see why in
a minute so what is include include some
discovery modules so it does the the
local ping discovery so I can see who's
out there using the multicast I can do a
neighbor discovery and I can see who you
know basically the router of
advertisements I can see who is the
routers out there so actually I want to
jump back over heat up all right so
remember I said it uses art so it's
discovering the addresses via ARP and
then it says it compares those are
actually says do you have an ipv6
address can you tell me what it is so
that's one of the things it does when
you're actually running the ipv6
neighbor discovery kind of cheating in a
way so if you were to change this and
you were to set it to a mature you were
to set it to a no come on alright so the
demo gods are failing me now there it is
so you can change the rhost to that
multicast address right so if you were
to do that and this shit's got some lag
in it essentially what happens is it
returns nothing it tells you it found
the host but it doesn't return your
information so see if I captured that
because I knew that might happen so
here's what it looks like when it says
hey I found some stuff by art this is
what it looks like and so then it says I
found those two IP addresses and they
map out to this I guess I didn't egg so
we'll work on getting that work so in
cat it's the end map version so or yeah
so it's the end map version i guess of
net cat is the one that supports v6
natively so you can do the same thing i
can do a banner grab I can do whatever I
want I just have to specify it now the
one quirk here is you have to specify
the interface address which becomes
important especially when you're dealing
with max
virtual machines and other devices it
changes so you got to make sure that
you're aware of what you're dealing with
so you can actually grab that you can do
the same thing you can do a you know I
get or whatever you want for our head
for HTTP server find out what it is and
it'll show you all of that and i think
i've got an example yeah so here we just
run in mcat and we're running it against
a web server which is running tomcat and
so essentially if everything works it
should come back and it should say the
same thing that we're seeing you up here
but
yay so it returns a 200 so everything's
okay tells me the server if it was an
IAS box it would return more information
but I wanted to go with with tomcat on
this so essentially it does the same
thing as what we've already seen and
we're used to and then you've got netcat
six which is NC 60 versus running NC you
have to run in c 6 and it does the same
exact thing that the difference here is
nc6 actually supports v4 and v6 so you
can switch back and forth you just have
to specify it now if you don't specify
it'll actually try for and then it will
try six kind of interesting so cat
native tool that supports v6 it's a
great tool if you got tools that don't
support natively v6 or they say they do
you can use so cat to actually to to use
a tool that is not natively support that
nikto so what I've essentially got is a
show cat listener here that is listening
on port 8888 it's redirecting it using
v6 over to the windows box using port 80
via the ethernet interface ethernet 0 so
its use the east 0 and so i can rerun
Nick to and essentially all intelligence
the host is my localhost and I want to
have it scanned port 8888 or 888 which
is essentially going to redirect it over
to the windows box using v6 because
nikto doesn't sport v6 natively doesn't
know anything about it so they should
come back and it should give me some
information and tell me yeah this is
what it is and of course I've got the
screen up above because I knew this was
going to happen so but it identified it
you know Apache coyote one dot one tells
me the target for granted that doesn't
match up but still you can you could
document this very easily to show I ran
this tool i targeted this particular
tool against your box using so cat take
two screenshots you're done move on to
the next target so
uh yeah it's great for tunneling so then
we come to the THC ipv6 attack tool kit
this is a freaking awesome set of tools
I mean this is like if if you don't grab
anything grab this so a live six very
simple just run it it'll say hey tell me
who's out there so it actually has them
by doing a solicitation for a neighbor
solicitation and a router solicitation
tell me who's out there who's alive so
it's very simple comes back returns it
all to you detect new says you can run
that and it will show you when a v6
device comes online start that in a
window throw it aside kind of just keep
it up that way you can see when
something pops up now you can you can
generate neighbor solicitation request
using send PS teen is okay if you want a
hand craft stuff trace is just a version
traceroute them for v6 so this is what a
live the command line looks like that
allows you to run some stuff you can do
you know output all of this which is
great because if you're trying to show
this for a customer it's really cool
actually I got that sooo
hey so that one returned so let me pop
up a new window damn this is slow
alright
so this is whatever this is what they
look like after you get done building it
and I hate that it's green but I do it
for documentation purposes so the
customer didn't have to pronounce it's
all white kind of looks cool but anyways
essentially what are all the sets of
tools and so if I just run a live six I
get that but I can also tell it that I
want to know what the interface what's
hanging off of this and so it'll
actually start telling me what's alive
down here the only thing I had to
specify was my interface so it tells me
I has one system alive which should be
correct because that's the one box we've
been screwing with commercial tools this
is funny when you start talking about
commercial tools to support ipv6 read
the fine print I'm put it actually
supports nessa supports it but Nessus
you have to give it an interface well if
you're running Nessus on a windows box
what's your interface name does anyone
know I'm sorry you have to give it the
whole thing which sucks so if you're
running on a linux box it significantly
easier it's just like f1e to what every
0 open bass has had support next pose as
had support st. all of these support
them supposedly native they're very
quirky they don't necessarily return the
results you think you're going to get
and I will say this from a web inspector
spective if you think that you're going
to be to be able to run the tickle
injector wrong then sported the tool
itself supports you know web inspect as
a whole supports it sequel injector does
not because it's a separate tool it
hasn't been coded for it okay so if
you're looking at that that's great HTTP
editor doesn't work have fun that's not
going to work for you you're going to
find a lot of these tools that say they
support it there's little quirky issues
core impact supports it but it supports
finding vulnerabilities not necessarily
in exploiting them it doesn't
necessarily support all of the things
you would think that it would so it says
I know the and of course they have
listed vulnerabilities and this is what
we look for if you don't have an
underlying v6 tak it doesn't really work
exploitation so if we start talking
about exploitation one of the things
that we start looking at is stuff that's
v6 pacific and so again we kind of go
back to the same thing we've got the
framework for metasploit we've got the
attack tool kit we've got commercial
tools we've got a four to six so if
you're looking at internet and then you
got soaked adam i actually prefer to use
so cap for just about everything because
it's so freaking easy just target the
box start looking at the ports you want
run your tools tell it you want it to
essentially tart you know target
yourself and be done with it so the
attack tool kit comes with some pretty
interesting things parasite six so it's
a neighbor solicitation neighbor have an
advertisement spoofer so if you're
thinking art days that it's a
man-in-the-middle type of attack you can
tell somebody hey I'm your neighbor once
you be my neighbor remember we talked
about the significance of dns and and
from a v6 perspective one of the things
that you have to do is and I and we
generally use this as a course of a
reconnaissance is will brute force dns
servers externally to see what we can
get what names are you not you know
telling us that we can find well there's
a dns dick six which that just sounded
wrong but dipped six that that
essentially is a dns brute forcer does a
dictionary attack against the dns server
so if you're thinking fierce too it's
kind of like that only not as cool but
it still does the job fake router
announcement this is actually my
favorite one in the sense that you can
announce that you're of the router for a
local net and so all their v4 traffic is
going off to the netherlands and having
fun and you're getting all the v6
traffic coming straight to you the
interesting thing is
445 traffic 139 traffic all of that it's
still active on v6 so while they may be
able to see you most tools can see you
on a v4 network they're not going to see
what you're doing so if I've attacked
domain controllers before or try to grab
credentials that's a perfect way to do
it think about the evilness of that
somebody's sitting there going well we
can see you if you're actually doing
this because we're monitoring the v4
network and people are experiencing a
slowdown or a lag and authentication and
we see that you're the guy that's doing
that who maybe I'm not the one doing
that I wouldn't be grabbing credentials
but in this case you can do it and
they're probably not going to be aware
of it but all of that authentications
traffic will still try to use v4 and v6
if the domain controllers use it now
think about native 2008 it's not hard so
reader so you can redirect traffic again
this is kind of another man in the
middle type of attack it's just a
redirects pooper yeah you need to
redirect this particular traffic all
that ACH traffic needs to come to me
please I absolutely have to have the HDH
traffic and exploit 6 that is what
actually scans for ipv6 vulnerabilities
in the stack itself so there are
vulnerabilities and what it does is it
looks for so it's a cool little it's a
cool set of tools you can see that
they've done their homework and added a
lot they've also got a fuzzer so if
you're looking for a buzzer which kind
of led to that whole thing about web
inspect not working if you find a v6
website and you want to fuzz it good
luck if you're talking you know you know
you don't have a tool that works on it
so you have to switch over and you can
use that buzzer then you got some other
stuff so the implementation that does
some checks some sanity checks and make
sure that your implementation or a given
implementation on a boxes is actually
correct so you've got another one which
is fake MLD which is the multicast so it
says hey this is the new multicast group
would you like to join me so you or or
more
gordon lee i'm a member of that
multicast which i'm not i'm not actually
a member of it so but I am I can
actually say yes i'm a member of that so
you can see where the sanity checks and
those vulnerabilities that we talked
about in v6 actually exist and again so
you can go through you can generate fake
router messages so there's there's a lot
of tools I actually like the the fake em
ipv6 so you can borrow the mobile ipv6
address assuming that if zach is not
needed for authentication but you can
you can borrow it kind of cool i guess
if you're out there and you don't have a
v6 or I don't know I guess thinking
nefariously I don't want to use my v6
address I want your someone else's so
I'm going to borrow theirs while while I
do this bo woods mobile attacking type
of fake advertiser i can announce myself
on the network i can say that i'm on
another network or this one again smurf
six are six you got the local version in
the remote version the the remote
version only works against linux at the
moment but they have said that they're
going to update that I think in months
so metasploit so metasploit in addition
to how do we how do you run it because I
mean you know natively you can you can
run metasploit against ipv6 just by
giving it the actual our host value of
that v6 box you're trying to target but
they've included are there some other
modules and and one of them just got
checked in like four days ago and this
is vicious when you think about it if
you don't have v6 natively installed on
your box specifically windows it'll
install it it sets of static v6 address
on it then it creates a bind a blunt a
bind she'll pay load and then installs
that as a service and says it to auto
run now you know the address when you
created it so obviously what's it going
to do
it's going to give you a portal back
into that that's pretty damn cool
because most people would never even see
that so then again you've got the normal
sports that are included all work Oh 60
40 works just as good on before as it
does on v6 so don't forget to try those
when you're starting to map out the v6
networks to look at it to say hey let me
try this and the reason why that becomes
important is because as you start moving
down or as you start moving within a
network most folks have like IPS is I
sensors whatever out there that they're
using to monitor your activities and
maybe be blocking or stripping out some
of the payloads especially with some of
the the more advanced IPS is out there
so in this one particular case involving
that data center the the folks had an
IPS that was only looking at v4 traffic
because that's all it was capable of
seeing so v6 traffic was allowed to pass
natively unfiltered didn't do anything
so while I thought I was going to get a
shell and was getting pretty frustrated
on a couple of boxes when you start
switching over to v6 and trying it lo
and behold what happens you get a shell
returned to you so it's there's nothing
better when you starts knew it you know
sessions you know sessions you know I
one and all sudden you've got a Windows
prompt there so that it's it's a good
way to do it now kind of been doing the
demo as we've been going along so I
guess to kind of bring this full circle
one of the things that you've got is
most organizations have a crap ton of v6
traffic out there think about all of the
boxes that are out there that were in
those operating systems that I listed
how many of them by default have turned
off v6
almost none of them now think about your
IT admins that and I'm not trying to say
anything disparaging about IT admins
because they do a wonderful job in most
companies but think about the guys that
are struggling to get systems deployed
or build an image do they necessarily
disable v6 on those no so you may have
targets of opportunity sitting there
that you're never aware of so if you if
you look at it you've got windows 7
vista to a lesser degree I don't know
very many corporations that are running
vista but you got windows seven you got
server away you've got max out there
that may or may not have it now if they
have a DHCP or a router that can give
them the local link then absolutely they
will get a local address it'll be auto
assign linux and solaris they all ship
with it enabled by default and they all
do auto configuration again that's why I
caveated the max because it's the one
quirky it's the prima donna that has to
be different than you know but the other
ones by default will get it an address
so if you can tell you say tell me who's
alive then you can find them you can
find them you can target them tunneling
so this is something that if you're
looking at so we did a talk it what was
the was the talk that was here in
Atlanta no not shook on the one
that besides don't know why it's cape me
besides and we talked about data
exfiltration and so a lot of folks have
done some research on data exfiltration
and one of the things that we actually
kind of looked at was tunneling traffic
using v6 would it be allowed if I had a
Torito or a six to four or I had my own
broker could I do it and yeah you can
most most folks wouldn't see it DNS
traffic on port 53 is very rarely looked
at ipv6 traffic being tunneled over port
353 is very rarely looked at so yeah it
can be done for data exfiltration
another thing that you have to be
concerned with is if if you're tunneling
traffic does that traffic
include any type of encryption remember
we talked about that it's recommended
but you can use and in encryption if
sack and a v6 tunnel so that's
interesting when you start thinking
about that if I can create a v6 tunnel
between me and my house I can suck off
data at will I mean I'm not only
constrained as the down the download
speed at the end so whatever the choke
point is that's where the limiting
factor would be so again telling the
traffic traffic unless you're a
terminator on that you're not going to
build a look at it and if you did you
probably wouldn't recognize it because
most net flow analysis engines out there
look at v6 traffic especially stuff
that's encrypted as normal v6 traffic
and will flag it as v6 traffic but you
have no idea what's in it another one so
we talked about kind of it's known and
it's out there so you've got that rogue
traffic the stuff that you don't know
about specifically those BOTS the the
CNC type stuff that was using v6 one
botnet specifically used v6 hiding
itself as ipv4 so that it can make it
through routers and nobody was the wiser
so you know obviously there was some
security researchers named Bella and in
Georgia Tech that were involved in
identifying that traffic and figuring
out wait a minute this is actually using
v6 and that's not cool but they were
able to at least figure out that it was
using it and find the C&C server find
the endpoint and then start working on
figuring out what this this particular
bot was targeting what was it being used
for illegal file-sharing so if if your
ISP comcast or Satan whichever one you
want to call them is a is filtering you
or throttling your banquet and you want
to be able to make sure that they're
doing it because you're running a
torrent or downloading torrents or
seeding torrents and let's say it's it's
absolutely legitimate you're just you're
presenting or sharing out like iron geek
does when he gets video shears those out
and and our I so's or whatever so it's
legitimate nothing illegal let's suppose
it is illegal you can use b6 and that
can be you
for peer-to-peer communications and most
folks wouldn't be able to see it so I
guess the main takeaway was and the
biggest kind of crap moment for me was
that you know once a time once upon a
time we only use to be for now there's
v6 out there so we need to be concerned
with more than just one protocol I think
that as times change we need to change
our activity so we need to make sure
that we're aware that our tools work and
how they work and I think the biggest
thing that I kind of took away from it
was pretty much what you can do was
before you can do with v6 it's just a
different way of doing it but but for
the most part it's pretty freaking cool
so that's it shameless plug getting
questions I think beau was first
you
it's a day at a router perspective it's
most definitely not configured by
default which is why when we talked
about why do I need a broker why do I
need to tunnel that traffic through and
really that was the focus of why i was
looking internally because I mean think
about it from that perspective if it's
internet-facing and it's a v6 address
and you put it out there you know you've
made some you know somebody's made
changes somewhere okay but from like a
stack robustness obviously cisco has
been a player a long time juniper is
kind of stepping up from a firewall
perspective and I think they've made it
significantly easier and I hate to say
this but to miss configure something
from a v6 perspective and I think a lot
of people would understand when they
look at a v4 and you're looking at an a
sa that's easy to understand I mean
he'll it's checkpoints interface they
just stole it and threw it on top of it
so it's like hey I know this BAM you
know click click click close that ticket
so you know the idea is it's easier but
that's why I was really targeting
internally because man there are so many
targets out there that are right and
switches will pass it they understand it
natively and in so you talked about like
vlans and stuff guess what doesn't
respect vlans because it doesn't know
the concept of vlans I have to know what
my router is and so that's why it's kind
of a pita when you're using a Mac
because you have to essentially if you
don't have a you know you're plugged in
and you're trying to use native tools on
a Mac to do an assessment I wouldn't
recommend that but I'm just saying if
that's what you're trying to do you do
have to have a router advertisement give
you the local link okay or you have to
have a DHCP six server give you an
address and say this is what we want you
to use for the local link you need to
auto configure the rest of it because
part of that is based upon your mac
address and other things so that being
said if you were using backtrack or a
bunt or whatever your tool of choice was
you know for a distro you could very
easily get on as
get a six net IP address and start
looking at those and and that's really
what I guess I'm angry honest it was
embarrassing standing there having a guy
tell you you missed half hour crap
because you just don't I didn't think
that way I just because you know you
look at targets and you say okay you've
given me these subnets this is what I
need to go after so
it depends because there could be
physical segmentation there okay so that
would be one thing and if you're talking
trunking now you're talking a complete
change because I do have to have there
has to be some configuration that is
made that would not normally be done on
a v6 side that you would do on a v4 to
get that configuration in place does
that kind of make sense so think of it
as in and come on man I'm out speaking
out of school here when I say most
networks are pretty damn flat so it's
not like you're going to have a
difficult time finding some targets but
yeah yeah so did that answer
actually you do know you don't use a
fake ipv6 address you use one that's
built upon built using part of part of
the requirement has to have your mac
address okay so think about if I've been
given a v6 address or subscribe to get a
v6 address how would I deal with
assigning that so for an auto
configuration it creates an ipv6 I mean
dude you're talking that whatever that
large ass number is the idea of you
getting a collision between two v6
addresses is pretty slim to none I mean
think about it it's not going to happen
so no now you would you would then have
a set of IP addresses that are publicly
accessible that you would still be
assigned in and so then but the notion
of using that for because of the fact
that we have to use NAT you don't
necessarily have to in a v6 environment
does that make sense and they said you
have to when we share the university man
most people are going to have to use
some sort of matting in their
environment because they don't have
10,000 or 20,000 or you know 70,000
depending on the size of your company IP
address is readily available and if they
did the Chinese want to buy them because
they're like 40 million short because
apparently they hadn't figured out what
matting is so anybody else
if you want to screw someone you're
basically going to have to either figure
out what their
yes no no so you can actually advertise
yourself as that address and if the
other one was auto configured not
statically assigned or even if it's a
signed by a DHCP v6 it will say wow
there's a there's a collision here you
know we have duplicates I need to get a
new one and so it'll generate a new one
based in part of the generation for an
auto configuration is it uses the mac
address for auto configuration for dhcp
it says these are the scopes that you
have available for you to be able to
sign from same thing as before it
doesn't that doesn't change so to
essentially do you ever see where you
have a duplicate IP address on the
network it's the same exact thing so you
can take over somebody's address if it's
auto configured or it's set to dhcp if
it's static you both back off and then
you get into a pissing contest to see
who's going to win and chances are it's
going to win because then the routers
are actually look at the age that it's
seen that particular IP address and
which board it came through and start
that's where some of the intelligence
built into like Cisco devices will start
saying yeah that's the whole mechanisms
they've got built in that says no that's
you're not who you say you are but but
again that but but again if I'm going to
take over somebody's address it's only
applicable on that local that I cannot
cross a router okay
you mean from a from a v6 perspective no
no I mean I've done it from a v4
perspective but never never had one that
required us to look at that no but we've
done firewall assessments of ones that
were misconfigured that actually did
have v6 enabled and hadn't they had no
idea they had done it it's like whoa we
don't have that and of course you're on
the conference call and they're arguing
with you we do not have this enabled and
this like no trust me that's not a
Photoshop screenshot it is actually the
screenshot of your interface they go
look at it and they go can we move on to
the next point because they realized
that that that now they did screw up and
they had a misconfigured and I'm not
going to say that the company but it was
a Juniper device and it was it was very
easy to see how they made the mistake
oh yeah yeah yeah oh yeah so maybe I
didn't make that clear the same thing
that you do on a v4 network from a
firewall perspective as Windows Linux
Mac it doesn't matter you do the same
thing on the v6 side you just run a
different command to initiate the v6
side so if you're talking to ipfw you're
looking at IP 6fw versus the the ipfw
and so that's why when i pull up the the
mac version you'll see that it is set by
default to allow any any which you no no
no because this is this is ipv6 fw yeah
so it uses different commands to control
the rule sets for the given interface
the first thing you'd have to do is go
through and make sure that all of them
are allowed to use ipv6 a gotcha from
fusion install on a Mac as if you
install VMware fusion it doesn't
natively enable on a Mac on a windows
box completely different eating yes it
does but it doesn't natively enable the
v6 interface for a vm net 0 or 1 so you
have to go through and enabling
no because I target those so I'm not
going to say that at all I would say
make sure you have them enabled and the
default firewall rule set is set in
other words get to any any just leave it
like that and we'll be good to go I can
give you a business card you can call me
will come assess you and have a good
time by the way Red is good for us green
is bad so that's kind of we in verse
that but yeah I say I say that in jest
but I think you you are going to have to
reach the point where you start looking
at getting a transition plan in place
now is it going to be this iteration of
windows 7 or whatever no but when you
know by default there turned on you've
got to take that into consideration and
say I've got a hole here that someone's
going to look at
and that's a fair statement and again
remember I have a myopic view I target
that so that's the one I would not
suggest you turning it off but in
reality if when we write up on us we do
recommend if you're not if you're and it
goes with any service if you do not need
that service disabled that service if
you're not using it turn it off after we
leave you know after after we leave your
engagement so I'm sorry yeah and in fact
one of it that's interesting you should
say that because one of if you look at
the 80 2008 and you start looking at the
DHCP settings natively built into it is
v6 built right into it so it's and you
can you if you've seen it you know how
easy it is to check one box and then I'm
screwed because guess what it's going to
start looking and saying I can allocate
those back out but it'll more
importantly do a advertisement to say
this is this is what you have available
to you
teredo toupees how do you block Torito
from natively building a six tunnel and
so one of the things that you have to do
is you have to look there's their
servers out the Torito servers that
you're going to be connecting to that
you're building the tunnel with are well
documented so you can go to the the
Microsoft's website and find that
they're clearly listed I know that are
certain content filtering things that go
kind of a little bit deeper from a
packet inspection they will block that
natively yeah but what it actually
requires is it it performs an SSL main
in the middle so when you think you're
going to bank of america you're not
you're actually going to the appliance
sitting there on their local network and
that kind of pisses off a lot of people
when they find out that you have the
ability to look at their bank
transactions and that type of stuff but
that is one of the requirements and so
you have to think of the then you get
into that risk evaluation is the risk
worth the risk of losing your job for
you know implementing something without
making sure that you have legal buy-in
to do that so all right man that's it
thanks everybody
the other one would