well everyone so I will be presenting to
a new tool I developed called sniffle
which is a sniffer for Bluetooth 5
so I created sniffle because there are
there already are quite a few sniffers
for Bluetooth le out there but there was
nothing that worked quite the way I
wanted it well the existing low-cost
sniffers they apart from certain feature
limitations they also sniff only one of
the primary advertising channels at a
time and so inherently they're limited
to less than 33 percent reliability and
beyond that there's also they're also
missing some features I wanted so what's
sniffle is is it is Bluetooth low-energy
packet sniffer that includes support for
all the improvements in Bluetooth 5 that
runs on Ti CC 26 X 2 + CC 13 X 2
microcontrollers so out of the box the
firmware except to run on these
development boards here these boards
they are about 40 US dollars and the
firmware it runs on this old processor
here and you could have any other device
that has to say my controller you could
program it can run this firmware but the
easiest device you can get your hands on
are one of these development boards
which are available on t-i-is website
and various electronics resellers as
well so Sifl supports almost all the new
features in Bluetooth 5 including the
new 5 modes or long range and high speed
and it also supports extensions to
advertising in Bluetooth 5 sniffle can
display packets to your terminal in real
time and it can also record data to pcap
files for later analysis or an or
in March our core if you want to pass
them to crackle or decryption or
anything like that and the biggest
benefit sniffle brings over existing
low-cost sniffers is its ability to
capture advertisements from all three
primary advertising channels using a
single sniffer and this makes it vastly
more reliable than other low-cost
sniffers in a room like this where
there's a lot of blues devices out there
any sniffers reliable and likely the
great we'll see how it does in the demo
however in a quieter environment sniffle
gets over 90% reliability in my testing
for connection detection so for those of
you who don't know too much about the
different kinds of Bluetooth there are
two distinct protocols that are both
called Bluetooth there's Bluetooth
classic and there's Bluetooth low-energy
so they're in the middle of the protocol
stack there is what's called a host
controller interface or HCI and that is
interface between the Bluetooth
controller trip and the main host
processor and that is common between
classic and le there's also l2 cap link
layer control and application protocol
this is also common between le and
classic however apart from that all the
profiles at the higher levels of the
stack and the physical layer below these
are completely different different
modulation different channel hopping
schemes different PDU types different
pairing processes there there's
essentially different protocols both
called Bluetooth what's also in common
between these is that they're both
frequency hopping and they're operating
the 2.4 gigahertz band at this point
classic exists mainly for it was the
original Bluetooth and it's commonly
used for audio streaming devices like
headphones or also for calling and in
cars as well as things like the
phonebook and message access profile for
automotive applications the these
profiles are still used because there's
a huge my devices I support them and I
suppose the Bluetooth SIG didn't want to
reinvent the wheel with yet another ink
paddleball standard however all the
development effort in the past few years
has been focused on the low-energy side
of the spec and most iot devices we
encounter nowadays use bluetooth le both
the classic and the low-energy part are
both part of the Bluetooth 5 standard
however there were no significant
changes to the classics side of the spec
Bluetooth 5s enhancements focus mainly
on the low-energy side and as a result
when you often hear of Bluetooth 5
devices they omit the word Low Energy
because what's new and beautified is the
low-energy side so the Bluetooth Low
Energy spec was originally introduced in
2010 as part of Bluetooth 4.0 and back
then it was intended only for low
bandwidth applications that don't have a
lot of data to transfer it strictly
limited the size of packets you could
send and it had a slower fight than
classic so classic supports in addition
to a 1 megabit note it also supports 2
megabit and 3 megabit per second
enhanced data rate modes whereas
historically Bluetooth le only supported
one megabit mode and furthermore the
bandwidth was hampered by the short
packet size now Bluetooth le both in the
original 4.0 form and even in the
current form divides the 2.4 gigahertz
spectrum into 40 channels of which the
logical channel numbers 0 to 36 are for
data transfer and channels 37 to 39 are
for advertising so that other devices
can be discovered now one thing to note
is that these channel numbers don't are
not strictly sequential channel 37 is
actually the lowest frequency Channel 38
is in the middle in between the data
channels and 39 is the highest but they
group them like this just so group
channels are Oh
similarly a similar applications are
lumped together now at the higher levels
of the protocol stack there is the
generic attribute protocol or gap and a
GATT to the user it bluetooth
peripherals will have a number of what
are called characteristics that clients
can write to read from or subscribe to
notifications in Bluetooth 4.0 and 4.1
they entered they had a very weak
pairing process that relied on symmetric
cryptography and as a result of this
there were a lot of research published
on ways you could defeat the pairing
process if you were able to sniff the
key exchange in Bluetooth 4.2 there was
a new pairing process introduced that
uses elect elliptic curve diffie-hellman
key exchange there were some issues in
this too in the spec not requiring that
points in the curve are properly
verified but this has been addressed
however the new lip the curve pairing
process is not mandatory so there are a
lot of devices that still make use of
the legacy pairing process that's in
that's weak and also many devices that
do support the elliptic curve pairing
allow fallback to the legacy pairing
process so this is a common issue we see
Bluetooth 4.2 also introduced an
important feature called data length
extension and this greatly increased the
bandwidth of the protocol just by
greatly reducing the fraction of time
spent and overhead so it increases the
size the max size of a data packet from
31 bytes up to 255 bytes and that
increase data throughput something five
or six fold now Bluetooth 5 which is
quite new was introduced in 2017 and
further extended Bluetooth le to have
performance similar to
or sometimes better than Bluetooth
classic so one of the improvements is
that introduced a new fly mode that has
faster modulation to megabits per second
and this allows transferring a lot more
data through it they also introduced
five modes for long-range communication
with forward error correction so these
actually use the one megabit per second
modulation but there is an excessive
amount of data sent on them that's
redundant so that you could recover the
original data even if there was some
corruption when the data was transmitted
over a long range another change in
Bluetooth five that's is a new channel
hopping algorithm the old channel
hopping algorithm just you started on
one channel and there was just a number
called a hop increment so the next
Channel number is just the last channel
number plus the hoc increment modulo the
number of channels there was another
scheme for when a channel was disabled
from the map but overall was fairly
simple the new hopping out algorithm is
based on a pseudo-random number
generator it's not meant as a security
feature but what it does intend to do is
reduce the chance of repeated collisions
between Bluetooth devices a very large
change in Bluetooth v r is the
extensions to advertising so advertising
is the process through which Bluetooth
devices say that they are here and they
can be connected to where they have
information available for you to scan in
bluetooth for advertisements were
limited to 37 bytes and the
advertisements had to go on the three
primary channels now the issue for that
was that in very crowded environments
like the room were in right now there
was a high chance of collisions between
all these different devices trying to
transmit advertisements at the same time
so they tried to keep advertisements
short with this length limit but even
then collisions were an issue in crowded
environments so what they did in
Bluetooth 5 is they allowed very short
advertisements to be sent on the three
primary advertising channels that
point to a data channel that's channels
0 to 36 and you can transmit a much
larger piece of data on those data
channels without hogging the shared
primary advertising channels there's
also a new process for establishing a
connection on these data channels
instead of doing it on the primary
channels that tend to be very crowded in
Bluetooth 5.1 which just came out this
year there was a couple more optional
features that are called angle of
arrival and angle of departure those are
used for determining the direction in
which data is coming from if you have an
array of antennas receiving or an array
of antennas transmitting by looking at
phase differences you can perform some
triangulation and the other noteworthy
change in Bluetooth 5.1 is that it
allows randomizing the order in which to
advertise on three primary channels now
one thing to note is that all these new
features in Bluetooth 5 are all they're
all optional and as a result there are a
lot of devices you see on the market
that claim to support Bluetooth 5 but
the only support of small fraction of
these or sometimes none of these new
features as technically a valid
Bluetooth 4 device is also valid
Bluetooth 5 device you just have to go
through the certification process again
and you can just say oh I don't support
any of these new features and as a
result there's a lot of phones in the
market it took me a lot of research to
be able to find a phone that actually
supports Bluetooth 5 as there are a lot
of flows that claim they support
bluetooth 5 and they may support one or
none of these features so with the
existing sniffers one of the biggest
frustrations you have with these
low-cost ones these are the only sniff 1
advertising channel at a time and even
in the legacy connection establishment
procedure which is still the norm for
almost all bloobity devices your
encounter currently the connection will
be established in the one of the three
channels and if you're sniffing only one
of these channels and there's only a 33%
chance you'll catch it add to that there
is imperfect fine tuning on many of
these
sniffers and your reliability slips well
below 30% so it can be just quite
frustrating to have to try three or four
times to be able to detect a connection
establishment and sometimes if you
wanted to capture a rare packet that's
hard to reproduce it's just a big
frustration the other issue with the
existing low-cost their first is that
there's nothing with comprehensive
support for Bluetooth 5 when I started
this project last year there was nothing
remotely affordable that support
Bluetooth 5 since then
Nordic has released an update to their
NRF 52 sniffer firmware that supports
the 2 megabit 5 mode but nothing else in
liquid 5 another issue that with many of
these low-cost sniffers not all of them
but some of them are have proprietary
firmware and software and sometimes
their windows only sometimes they forced
you to use an outdated version of
Wireshark sometimes they're hard to
extend or integrate with other things
and the sniffers that were better and
didn't have this limitation it's only
significant one channel at a time are
very expensive there are thousands of
dollars sometimes tens of thousands of
dollars
so what sniffle does is that it uses the
very flexible radio hardware in the TI
CC 13 X 2 and 26 X 2 microcontrollers
they're largely the same except that 13
X 2 also supports sub 1 gigahertz the
communication in addition to 2.4
gigahertz it uses these radios to tune
into the various blue the channels
configures the modulation on them and my
firmware red runs on the microcontroller
with these flexible radios controls the
radios to capture all the Bluetooth
traffic of interest so they can capture
advertisements and the advertising
channels or if there's a advertising
it'll hop from the primary advertising
channels to these secondary the data
channels to gather those advertisements
and if you have it configure to follow
connections then when it detects
connections established and it meet
matches all the filters like a Mack
filter then it will hop along with the
connection and capture all the
communications between two devices so
for filtering it can filter both by the
MAC address of the target as well as the
RSSI so often if you're in a building
with a lot of people you'll see a huge
number of Bluetooth devices and a low
noise you're not interested in so if you
just place a sniffer near the device
you're interested in you can just set up
the RSSI filter and only capture the
devices that are nearby that are more
interesting
the sniffle does support updates to
connection parameters during a
connection things like a hop parameters
the channel map and the five mode a lot
of sniffers don't do support this or
have incomplete implementation of this
and this greatly limits reliability and
usability again so the fact that it
supports these things ensures that it
will always follow a connection even
when the RF environment changes and
connection parameters are updated as a
result the sniffle firmware communicates
with the host over UART on these
development boards that the TI board I
showed earlier there is a debugger chip
that includes a USB to UART bridge so
when you plug into your computer it'll
be a USB port but it's the USB UART and
then I have host side software written
in Python that will display the traffic
do some decoding of it as well as
writing it to a pcap file and I wrote it
in the manner where if you want to
extend it it's quite easy to do it's a
fairly simple API for it now the killer
feature of sniffle is its ability to hop
long with advertising on three primary
channels so the Bluetooth 5.0 score spec
in this is one bit that was never really
publicized much but the spec requires
that when you advertise on the prior
channels you do it in order of 37 38 and
39 the spec says that you must start
with the lowest channel index for our
primary advertising and then end with
the
highest index and in my I did some
research oh I had a bunch of blues
devices around I was trying to see if
the timing was fairly predictable the
spec does not enforce the timing between
when you advertise in 37 and when you
advertise on 38 but I found that
different devices may take may put a
different on a gap between these however
its consist generally consistent for a
device now the exception to this is when
you receive a scan request so what a
scan request the response is that if you
have an advertisement with a small
amount of information and a device a
scanner is interested in that device it
can request additional information with
a scan request and when there is a scan
request the time spent on an advertising
channel is extended however when there
is no scanner quest then there'll be
some fixed amount of time that devices
in practice will spend on each of the
primary advertising channels and when
you detect the scan request you can
adjust for it by just adding some time
to the look postponing the hop to the
net to the next channel so this is what
sniffle does one other thing is that in
the previous diagram what I showed is an
advertising event so an for the legacy
style of advertising which is will still
with most devices you use today an
advertising event will advertise on 37
38 and 39 and then the device will stop
advertising for some period of time and
then again in short succession
advertising 37 38 and 39 now the gap
between these advertising events is
intentionally a randomized by the spec
to reduce the chance of collisions and
as a result of that you can't predict in
advance when the next advertising event
is going to happen so what sniffle does
is that it will wait in 37 once it has
figured out the popping pattern and the
moment it gets an advertisement or
something then it knows and advertising
up and started and then begins the hot
process so by doing
channel hopping sniffle can capture
connection establishment with over 90%
reliability at least in a more calm RF
environment and having performed some
analysis on previous hopping patterns
once sniffle figures up the hopping
pattern then it will just lock on and do
the 37 3 through 9 hop every time it
gets an advertisement on 37 and when the
scanner Quest is received then it will
just extend the time spent on a channel
so this here explains the algorithm for
the hopping though I've largely
explained it oh well here the first step
before you do this though is figuring
out how you're going to be hopping so to
do this what sniffle does is it waits on
channel 37 when it gets an advertised on
channel 3 7 immediately jumps 39
skipping 838 this is mainly for
performance reasons as often that
advertisement 38 will come very soon
offer 39 and there's a chance you'll
miss that initial advertisement 38 so by
huh it'll hop from 37 to 39 the moment
it receives an advertisement channel 39
and waits for a second advertising with
the same MAC address you're interested
in and it'll do this repeatedly and
record the timing between an
advertisement on 37 and 39 and once you
have a bunch of samples some of these
will be including scan requests and
others will not so you'll you'll see a
general bimodal distribution of timings
you'll see some timings that are short
and some timings that are long so that's
why I don't just take the median if the
results but I chose to take the 25th
percentile of the timings I captured and
then I divide that by 2 to get the time
between two channels I captured 37 39 so
37 to 3/8 will be half the time so once
I have that interval then I do the
hopping process I described earlier in
37 when you get it on 37th and do 38 and
39 this works great however Bluetooth
5.1
which just came up this year made life a
little more difficult as it as it allows
randomizing this fortunately in
Bluetooth 5 the new extended advertising
process doesn't do connect doesn't
establish connections on the primary
channels instead the connection is
established on the secondary auxiliary
advertising channel as a result if you
captured the short advertisement on any
of the three primary advertising
channels you'll Jim then hop the
secondary channel as all three primary
advertisements will point to the same
secondary advertisement and when you
were listening on the secondary channel
you will capture connection
establishment so Bluetooth 5.1 shouldn't
pose an issue just because the mudras
5.1 devices are likely to use the new
connection establishment procedure for
the extended advertising feature you
have a short advertisement on your
primary channel that just specifies a
time offset the channel that you want to
do the extended advertisement on and the
five mil you're going to use for it so
it could be that you're using the 1
megabit per second file on the primary
advertising channel and a 2 megabit per
second fie on the secondary channel and
so sniffle will when it receives a short
advertisement indicator is going to be
an advertisement on the secondary
advertising channel then it will
schedule a hop to that channel on the
correct 5 mode when the time comes
once it hops to there then it will
capture any advertisements there and
connection establishment as needed one
big advantage of this is that now you
can advertise with long amounts of data
up to 255 bytes in length and you can
actually go even longer according to the
spec you're allowed to chain multiple
advertisements together if you had a
really large amount of data you want to
transfer support for this in BlueStacks
various iOS the only supports I think
128 bytes for extended vert iseman
androids limited to 255 bytes
in theory the spec allows chaining these
now there's also another feature called
periodic advertising which is for but
sometimes called connectionless data
streaming where it's multicast streaming
of data to devices I don't have to
establish a one-to-one connection in
this process devices are transmitting
advertisements on the primary
advertising channels continuously
hopping between them and there'll be one
advertisement that provides information
sync along with this hopping sequence of
advertisements on these secondary
channels I have not encountered any
devices that currently use this new
feature and a lot of devices Hardwell a
lot of Bluetooth stacks don't even
support this but it may become popular
at some point in the future the main
benefit of this new advertising is that
it avoid it reduces a chance to
conflicts on the primary advertising
channels and allows transmitting much
longer advertisements on these secondary
channels so sniffle will schedule the
channel hopping and capture
advertisements on the exhilaration l's
and it'll also follow connections
establish on these channels i've not
implemented support for periodic
advertising partly because it's it it's
poorly specified in this specification
the specification doesn't even say how
you're supposed to do with the channel
hopping it leaves it up to vendors to
implement so I assume vendors will make
some sort of standard of their own for
this and since hardly anything is
implementing this right now I didn't see
a reason to spend too much time on it
for now so when you're dealing with a
Bluetooth device your options are either
to you be do HCI logging or use a
sniffer
now when HCI logging is possible that's
usually prefer as it's the most reliable
approach so it as an example if you have
an Android phone that's talking to some
IOT device you can configure
HCI logging on the Android phone and
that will can capture all the
communications between the fluoride or
blue droid stack on the Android phone
and the glue to the controller that's
actually interfacing with your device
now one limitation of HDI logging is
that what's going over the HDI is not
what's going over-the-air the Bluetooth
controller is performing a number of
transformations including the encryption
you also have no visibility into the
lower-level
linker layer things it's just black box
to the post side of things and also if
you're trying to troubleshoot issues in
a Bluetooth controller or troubleshoot a
custom Bluetooth stack or finally trying
to find bugs in these things it's useful
to have lower level capture the other
situation where you can't do HDI logging
is if you have two embedded devices
where you don't have much control of
either of them and they're communicating
with each other over Bluetooth le we've
encountered this a bunch of times in
these situations your only option is to
use a sniffer to see what these two
devices are doing between each other for
Bluetooth classic sniffers are quite
expensive the only Bluetooth classic
sniffer I know of that's vaguely
affordable that's affordable is the
Bluebird tooth however uber tooths
Bluetooth classic support is very
limited and Bluetooth classic a part of
the reason it's difficult to build the
classic sniffers is that they are very
fast channel hopping that makes the
synchronization a little tricky so you
can see here in this chart why made
sniffle so there's a whole bunch or
existing stampers there's the over tooth
there were a couple free sniffers made
by Ti both their previous generation and
their current one
Nordic which is the other popular maker
of bluetooth my controllers they have a
sniffle firmware that runs in both their
older and our 51 and their newer NR 52
series devices and there is also
they're researcher friend of mine Damian
cookie who had made a tool called beetle
Jack which has a cool feature of
connection hijacking and in addition to
stiffer capabilities but the issues with
these some of them particularly older
ones don't support daily length
extension almost none of these support
the new five modes in Bluetooth 5 so the
only one other than sniffle that partly
supports Bluetooth 5 five modes is the
Nordic one but it doesn't support the
long range Phi most of these don't
support the new channel hopping none of
these support the new Bluetooth 5
advertising extensions and most
importantly none of these will sniff all
three advertising channels at once
unless you are running multiple sniffers
which can be a little cumbersome at
times so with these extra abilities
sniffled becomes a lot more usable for
newer applications and with these
capabilities sniffle becomes a viable
alternative to much fancier commercial
systems so in the past if you wanted
reliable bluetooth LE capture you have
to resort to systems that cost thousands
of dollars and if you're not working in
bluetooth all the time if you're just an
imp and security researcher you're just
a small-time a start-up building
products you often can't afford tools
like this and these high-end sniffers
are powerful and good there are probably
more compliant with the spec and my
sniffer is and some of these have nice
features like the LSS and the Teledyne
frontline sedara
wideband models these are actually
software-defined radios that can capture
the entire 2.4 gigahertz spectrum and
that's very expensive in terms the hard
room processing power so the costs
aren't fully unjustified however what's
sniffle just with some clever channel
hopping techniques you can get
comparable reliability or a tiny
fraction in the cost
so sniffle is available on github now
it's GPL v3 license
do whatever you want with it under the
license on the readme for the git repo I
have instructions for setting it up I
also have some pre-built firmware
binaries available for those who don't
want to set up a tool chain it's
compiled with GCC also if you're working
with a Bluetooth classic ever and want
to test some profiles that are built on
top of object exchange so obex is the
base for a whole number of other
profiles like file transfer profile
object push profile message access
profile phone book access profile and
some others or if you're testing
automotive head units you can also check
out my know Beck's tool so I will give
you a little demo of what sniffle can do
and hopefully it will cooperate in this
crowded room so just as a demo what I'll
do is I'll set up one phone as a
Bluetooth advertiser and that can also
be connected to and then I will have my
other phone connect to it and you can
see if sniffle can capture them
communicating with each other so the
first step is that you need to find the
MAC address of your target so I'll see
them on the ground there
so for this what I'll do is I'll set up
an RSS I filter and then I'll all set
the are societal to a fairly high strong
signal and then I'll place my phone that
acting as a Bluth advertiser nearby so
that you can see its advertisements so
without specifying any additional
options then it's just listening on
channel 37 on the default one megabit
per second file so I put this nearby
they're capturing a bunch of things and
I can grab the MAC address which is
right here and now like configure the
radio to lock onto this MAC address and
now I don't need the RSSI filter since I
know the MAC and now what the sniffer
will do is that so it's capturing these
advertisements initially it's just
figuring out the hop pattern and once
it's figure out the hot pattern it'll
start hopping along with the advertiser
and now I have my other device here I
will scan for this and try connecting to
it okay there it connected and it's
capturing all the communications here I
forgot to turn on pcap writing but I
record another pcap file earlier and to
demonstrate the reliability of this I
could try this connecting connection
ended if I try connecting again Oh
little capture there capture the second
connection establishment let's see if I
can get three out of three well three
out of three that's a lot more reliable
than most the other sniffers out there
even in a crowded room like this so
I can also give you 100 little demo
which is capturing extended advertising
that all stop this guy rising so didn't
mean to sleep
so here the - L option means to use a
long range Phi and - a means enable
extended advertising that's why do this
here and then I start my advertiser you
can see its caption these advertisements
and you can see that so this here on
channel 37 is an extended advertisement
that's pointing to channel 34 the two
megabit Phi and the advertisement will
come at an offset of 107 thousand
microseconds and so it Tunes this other
channel and captures the advertisements
there and if some other device was
trying to connect to this and it'll
capture the connection establishment and
hop along with it and there is no other
sniffer that's not thousands of dollars
that can do this right now so that's it
you have any questions
[Applause]
what type of demo Bart you will
recommend from T ie based on thirteen or
on 26 that is 13 is better is it has all
the capabilities at 26 series but it
also adds support for sub 1 Meg files
so we're sniffle it makes no difference
however it's more useful for other
purposes if you want to use it for other
things too but for sniffle there is no
different no difference between motoki
thank you so much really interesting
talk thanks you said that equipment is
rather cheap yeah so have you considered
using multiple devices to multiple
channels at the same time and avoid so
many problems that can be done i
actually thought of implementing that
with three of these than just hoarding
them in python it's cheap and can be
it's cheap enough and can be done power
just for the sake of convenience have
been one device is nice and with its
ability to hop between these channels
you generally don't need it with sniffle
with just one device it can do it all
and you could even build the smaller
cheaper device this development board
here is rather bulky however the actual
chip that does it is this tiny little
thing here so you could make a really
tiny simple cheap board that did just
that and though I have a
question about active features the
sniffing is by definition passive but
then when you want to play with device
you want to you would like to have some
active possibilities to initiate
pairings and play with all the options
yeah and one of the tool that dama also
proposed is a good start for that what
do you envision with the the board and
the capabilities of the tool that you
are proposing so I had thought of
implementing some active features in
there it's it's fully doable the radio
here it's fully bi-directional you can
do anything with that one so there are
two types of things you can do one is if
there's an existing connection try and
interfere with that and then the other
is you just initiate in connection to
another device now in my own usage I
found that if I just use I can happen on
an ordinary phone like with with a
purpose-built Bluetooth stack most of
this stuff is not too far outs that
realm up the spec or you could even just
use do you do your own custom Bluetooth
stack but speak HCI with a normal blue
the controller and if you're not trying
to sniff traffic or do some other
non-standard operations it's often
easiest just to use a existing ordinary
Bluetooth stack to do that it's just the
the thing where you need specialized
harder for and low level radio control
is when you're not acting as a normal
personal device as if you wanted to pair
with something and you'll want to just
see what characteristics it has or
visible a GATT server or client you can
just be an ordinary compliant device
what because this is not playing any of
the traditional blue to the roles this
is why I need that local control
so for active operations there's jamming
things there's hijacking things is that
I mean I showed these things have been
done in practice I haven't actually
I need to do that but well it active
features can be implemented as if
someone wanted to do we have any more
questions yes not look thank you
everyone
[Applause]