advanced cases of cyber extortion
against companies types investigation
obstacles and suggestions the
information systems the internet and the
services developed through it are now
integral part of the operation of the
majority of enterprises worldwide this
automatically greatly expands the
cybercriminal scope were able to adapt
their weapons and business in the new
digital environment even though the
level of awareness of cyber threats has
increased and law enforcement act
globally to combat them illegal profits
have reached amazing figures the impact
to society has become unsustainable
considering the global economic crisis
cyber security is often framed as a
matter of keeping up with the rapid
evolution of online attacks patching
software vulnerabilities and identifying
new model programs but cyber criminals
most crucial adaptation in recent years
has not only to do with their technical
tools or their business model they have
started selling stolen data back to its
original owners to keep cybercrime
profitable criminals needed to find a
new cohort of potential buyers and they
did it they found all of us at the heart
of this new business model for
cybercrime is a fact that individuals
and businesses are the ones footing the
bill for data breaches the types of
online extortion that we are dealing
with are considerably more complicated
than the traditional black male in the
real world extortion has a reputation of
being an organized crime but with the
advent of cyber extortion the game is no
longer just for the Mafia such attacks
could be perpetrated by as few as one
person which makes it all the more
threatening in particular there are two
major trends of the time on the cyber
blackmail
on one side will classify cases of
malicious software such as ransomware or
crypto well as the name suggests
ransomware is a type of malware
propagated via the traditional means
phishing emails website drives by or
malbert izing once the victims device is
infected the rancher begins to include
private files and then pops apps a
message demanding a ransom work in
exchange for the encryption key the
devastating case of ransomware was
cryptolocker where the attackers
demanded payment of three hundred
dollars in bitcoins within three days to
not only decrypt the files but to
prevent them from being destroyed
forever today lakia ransomware seems to
be on the top of a threat list within a
company if our computer on a network
becomes infected map network drive could
also become infected on the other side
we classify cases where cybercriminals
require three males large sums of money
from the recipient firms in case of
non-compliance the company is threatened
to the dos attack to its extrovert
information systems which could have a
significant economic damage depending of
all solid and intensity and frequency of
the attack it's unlikely that the use of
the dose for extortion is going to come
to an end any time soon the tools needed
to attack company's site are cheap and
easy to use that attack that the company
is being asked asked to spend let's say
five thousand euros to stop probably
only costs the attacker 40 euros an hour
to launch meaning every time a business
pays its funding 150 hours of attacks on
other targets paying attackers fuels
their capabilities and makes it more
likely they'll continue to attack
business globally
there are two factors that have been
vital in driving this rise in cyber
extortion firstly there is more
opportunity than ever for criminals to
use cyber tools and techniques for
extortion as an ever increasing volume
of business is done online the impact of
a successful denial of service attack
can have a much more significant
business impact for a company moreover
many more business critical systems are
now connected to internet across all
industries from corporate data centers
to industrial control systems any
systems with internet connectivity is
potentially vulnerable to a denial of
service attack so the potential attack
surface has a great increased massively
at the same time around summer has
become more sophisticated it is almost
impossible to recover files encrypted
with modern ransom or without the
decryption key and recent resume over
ions have been designed to cause as much
damage as possible to potential victims
by spreading internally within corporate
networks our opportunity to conduct
cyber extortion has increased the
capability to manch as attacks has
proliferated the capabilities of top-end
cyber criminals are now on a par with
some nation states but further down the
marker the tools and expertise needed to
plan mount and monetize an exclusive
cyber attack are freely available on
underground criminal forums allowing
less technically stitute cyber criminals
to learn new skills or buy-in expertise
the criminal marketplace has now
developed to such a degree that crime
well as a service enables non
technically capable criminals to contact
contracts out ransomware and de dos
attacks with hacker for hire services
also widely available probably there are
two additional factors that are likely
to have some level of impact on existing
cyber criminals diversification in the
extortion firstly the
market for stolen personal and card data
is reaching saturation point with
individual sets of compromised credit
card credentials available for as little
as one dollar per card secondly exertion
is a much leaner business model much of
the effort in traditional ballad data
theft is not expanded stealing the data
itself but monetizing that data in this
scenario criminal as user data to commit
fraud themselves requiring additional
resource and effort or sell it on to
other criminals potentially increasing
the risk of law enforcement attention
conversely extractive attacks generate
direct criminal profit to enter ransom
payment which is usually made in a
cryptocurrency Internet interestingly
there are even indicators that cyber
criminals are looking to maximize return
on investment for extorted cyber crime
by moving away from high volume and low
value attacks such as ransom or attacks
against individual user systems to low
volume and at the same time high volume
attacks such as sorry low volume and
high value attacks such as major denial
of service attacks attacks involving
large data theft or answer attacks
targeted at corporate neural networks in
terms of punishing the perpetrators they
must first be identified and then
arrested and brought before the judicial
and prosecutorial authorities however
cyber criminals exploit all those
possibilities and opportunities offered
by the Internet to carry out their
illegal act to remain anonymous and the
volume avoid any retribution first of
all digital currencies Bitcoin and
sibling seas are anonymous and decide
realize digital currencies that were
designed to escape financial regulation
it's a concept that seems creating a
theory but one major drawback to
non-existent financial regulation
the difficulty of tracing and preventing
financial crime but there's another
layer layer to it digital currencies
have no barrier to entry anyone can set
up a free Bitcoin wallet address without
having to deal with bankers proof of
identity or evidence of residence in
many cases this convenience is desirable
however in this particular case it means
that engine can jump in on the cyber
resume game and cast hard without much
interference all that being said digital
currencies themselves are not to blame
they can be used in legitimate ways for
legitimate reasons however it cannot be
denied denied that digital currencies
design do make it much easier to carry
out cyber crimes with far less risk than
traditional tactics will entail then
cloud computing legitimate organizations
across the globe have been migrating to
the cloud in record numbers to take
advantage of the cost savings
flexibility and massive banks of
computing power cybercriminals gained
the same advantages they get something
more anonymity by operating out of the
cloud they can avoid detection while
gaining the advantages of global
computing systems from which they can
control operations mount attacks and
store stolen data the cloud offer
criminals the platform they need to
launch the type of large-scale
coordinated efforts that the internet
makes possible providing the perfect
venue for infiltrating other such venues
much more dark web the dark web lets
users access the internet with complete
anonymity volunteers around the world
maintain a network of servers that route
traffic while providing preventing IP
addresses from being tracked the
server's hide user information and
resist attempts at monitoring through
the dark web individuals
communicate online without bidding being
connected to their offline identities
the above-mentioned factors when
combined with the non-territorial
limitation of cybercrime the national
borders of law enforcement agencies and
the infrastructure and data controlled
by the private sector can provide an
explanation why it is so difficult to
identify and arrest cybercriminals one
more issue that needs to be discussed
has to do with legislation each country
has its own laws regarding cyber
criminality personal data protection
confidentiality of communications and
data retention when legislation is
different then cooperation between
states is based on bilateral or
multilateral agreements of course cyber
criminals are always far ahead from
legal texts technology evolves much
faster than legislation even the
Budapest convention of 2001 which was an
innovative text at the time was
formulated and has been signed by
several countries from Europe and the
rest of the world has not yet been been
ratified by all parties Greece is now
ready now in the process of ratifying
the convention but how effective can it
be after 15 years after so many changes
in the technological field so what can
companies and enterprises do to prepare
for this threat even the best defended
organization still get breached so being
ready to respond rapidly and decisively
to an explosive attack is vitally
important in responding effectively the
key elements of this approach our first
of all understand the evolving cyber
threat your organization faces at a
granular level who is likely to target
you what would the attack and what is
their capability to do so have systems
in place that allow you to take the tax
even if you cannot stop them this allows
you to get on the front foot in terms of
risk
then ensure your critical data is
irregularly and securely backed up so
you can restore from recent backups if
heat with a ransom or attack ensure
corporate response plans are fit for
purpose for likely extortion scenarios
ensure these plans are tested and
exercised so they operate smoothly in
crisis do not deal with an extorted
cyber attack are simply an IT incident
ensure you manage the business crisis 2
and then ensure that you are able to
call on specialist extort of crisis
response expertise in the event of a
serious extortion another key
consideration is whether you should pay
a ransom automatic gate an exhaustive
incident this is no hard there is no
hard and fast rule here and it will
depend on a large number of factors
including business criticality of the
incident ability to mitigate legislation
in the actual case many individuals and
organizations have paid run small groups
for decryption keys and have
successfully gained access to their
files but other groups has have taken
the money and run likewise in a scenario
where a group is offering to not attack
your systems how do you know a single
payment will end the threat many
organizations have paid ransoms only to
find out that the criminals have
returned with further rounds from
demands to stop denial of service
attacks moreover some cyber criminals
claim to have advanced capabilities such
as the ability to launch crippling de
dos attacks against organization
organizations which of course they do
not actually have so so before paying
the ransom taking the consideration all
the factors
finally the issue that we need faster
response from the part of those who
legislate up-to-date legislation to
include digital currencies and effective
cooperation between law enforcement
authorities of various states by giving
extra powers to joint investigation
teams are equally critical issues it is
worth mentioning at this stage the
effectiveness of the joint cyber crime
action task force of the European
cybercrime Center ec3 of Europe own it
was lunch on September 2014 as a
response to further strengthen the fight
against cybercrime in the European Union
and beyond the jacquard is composed of
cyber liaison officers from committed
and closely involved EU member states
such as Austria France Germany Italy
Spain the Netherlands and the UK non-eu
law enforcement partners such as
Colombia Australia Canada and the US and
European cybercrime Center all of them
are located in one single office to
ensure that it can communicate with each
other in the most effective way how does
it work in practice in order to actively
fight cybercrime the jcat choses and
prioritizes the case to pursue for that
purpose the different country liaison
officers submit proposals all hot could
be investigated the task force members
then select the most relevant ones and
proceed to share collect and enrich data
then they develop an action plan which
is led by the country who submitted the
chosen proposal finally the J card goes
through all the necessary steps to make
the case ready for action which includes
involving judicial actors identifying
the required resources and allocating
responsibilities on the screen you see a
list of successful operations that took
place since the beginning the
establishment of this J cut Action Task
Force cyber extortion is rapidly
becoming a permanent feature of the
cybercrime landscape
and one that has the potential to affect
any organization although all
organizations are potentially vulnerable
vulnerable to cyber extortion attacks
those that work on the basis that they
are likely to be targeted at some point
and adapt their mitigation techniques
accordingly are much less likely to
suffer significantly as a result of
cyber attacks thank you for your
attention