first of all and thank you for being
your ability and remarkable 24
participating in the president
challenged people said it was fun they
liked it so one of the things about the
european site visibility silence
national people we are putting together
something our offshore to be honest who
have already tales just to explain one
of the things that you need to know and
we would like you to pass it along to
your company to your friends whoever is
that in order to do this there is an
onion acquired and put the thumb down
and especially most it has done via as
they get incident and but we won't work
i want to participate us one and coping
and national team to the european
comments and basically rock the roof so
the bus you want again is to explain
everything about it Thank You regarded
go saturday i would just like to say
that this competition and i find is out
the european commission to the agency
it's fine european this year will be
planful member countries that they will
participate that we want to participate
with the national team actually this is
not something about the professionals in
something about they are the young
people so the environmental that
you are until 15 years old and you have
no papers experience information
security or any relative master's degree
so we do the young people so we have
this website just for registration you
can go and register if you are qualified
and we will have the local finals on 299
at the University pillows so from from
this panel we will have the top 10 the
competition is capture the flag CTF in
Jobar people so you can participate by
yourself you want or in teams but if you
are things when you stick the point
stability once you have the arms the
thin members of the team on two
runner-ups and it won't start preparing
for for the finals in a digital which
will be on via on the staff of new
rubber so we will the old it will be
expensed will be covered for the team to
go there and compete with other
companies and hopefully we get a a tooth
placement there like I said information
security Sam security talents lgr or the
ecsc 80 gr are itself possible around if
you know somebody that is from 14 up to
30 years old they are eligible if they
don't have introduced experiencing from
the security and like her very well said
please were looking for for people for
companies to help us a sponsor this
event
erotic speciality so I hope things are
need to mention and those who are going
to meet and if you are a speaker and you
haven't received your certificate please
let us know before we go to panic but
will be driving two thousand or more
find them now that we've participated
besides evidence you are a little for CP
credits so basically if you want see
peace please click on get up and so yeah
em your badge tommy generation in the
morning so again those who left or
missing your butt is a proper
three-track mag stripe which means if
you have a redirected you can actually
pull on your max track of your van
typical you're going to walk out the
door will actually have your debit card
so it's usable we're not saying what I'm
saying if you want to do that it's a
nice I think you should do that but for
all of you who have seen my previous
talks of you we have met them overseas
usually medals on post devices oh yeah
anyway and the speakers and I've had a
few questions about the one it was
announced this morning about the KPS the
quicker you need in the military about
people who are in passaic students who
are in passaic professionals haven't
done their military service the
information is on the army join gr
website
you see on the website so if you need
for gps and you find all the conducted
they also send your cv and instead of
going wherever to dig a military service
you will be picked up and do what you
need to do what nine months and you are
going to enjoyed it and you're going to
get some experience on stuff that you're
going to go trust me so that's about it
and i need to go through the
presentation of DM the challenge guess
you're not together okay there is
because you have kinds of missions and
they charged seven was it difficult or
go to put the books the books are seven
plus to design this is how I had the
Green Zone the Winx carriage so do you
want to see the list is the venture the
names do you have it
it's all actually orchard will give it
fortunately we can't take India okay
please be George
ok the next guy is saying George
Hannigan Hannigan English ok we can
trust George yeah ok the next one is
here is the next guy and you want to be
represented by their username or your
finger because this injection must not
talk ok
so basically the next year I am besides
that we're doing well we want you to get
involved it's not something like we
organized and sconce a won't expand and
we don't you come over sorry we wanted
to come over what do we want you to make
sure that you are going to speak next
year they want you to do a workshop we
want you to build games and challenges
let's let the guys if you have an idea
where foreigners manage working for you
to come and participate we want to do a
t-shirt design competition for this year
so we're giving our logo but we want
some teachers are like a quality and
deductive we want more students to get
involved so let it pass the word we want
to attract next year I won't have
lighting then it talks and we won't be
able to get big we wanted to be open and
we want to say to make sure it's a free
BET basis and we want all the finding
sponsors so if you have a company
no someone has company please contact us
and let's to make the event even better
email us today we will start building
everything for the things for next
year's opening tell different about the
event tricking to social media again if
you have any suggestions if you really
liked say some something day some people
mention that you want facts for example
promises until next year send us some
feedback I hope it's gonna be
constructive feedback let's say again I
will thank you and we thank our sponsors
toxic divine priority Tyga scheme and
sis net Arkansas same integrity I
security professional and application
typically and our after party response
or company you're coming to the after
party listen other hands first England
yeah you have to have your bath with you
all are you in right so you can do what
we want and come back at seven thirty
our going supporters all the events
besides London Manchester 40 home the
interest is here soldiers projects and
security the most our military invested
thank you all your support make this
event a reality for us based on the big
national in Buddhist will compete as the
Europeans are
you Italians and thank you thank you are
volunteers thank our speakers thank our
sponsors this event promote and working
education and participation I hope you
like the hope you enjoyed i hope you had
a fun day I hope the talks were
interesting and what problems to make it
better this next year I hope you like
this all the best thing for coming thank
you for having us over here