so welcome to besides options 2016 this
is first besides happening in Greece we
were very exciting we tried to organize
the best way to you all know that the
besides the community based on criminal
of events there is Wi-Fi you should
already know the key let's besides Wi-Fi
available the key is hashtag and besides
Athens for anyone to connect this is me
and the only reason my heart is up here
is because if there is any problems just
let me know we try to organize it the
best way possible so without a nice team
of people volunteering everybody is a
volunteer and we hope you have a really
good day and you are going to enjoy what
we've tried to a 20 this is our Twitter
please treat please retweet please use
the hashtag let's make a nice present on
Twitter today without our mobile apps
which has the track schedule and rules
of the game respect each other there is
a code of ethics online participate top
each other there are and like-minded
individuals in this room there are
professionals from all around the world
so please talk to each other but the
whole point of what one is for you to
participate in network to educate
themselves make friends and a lot of
good things happen when you meet with
your designs please get your devices if
you haven't done that with Duda be
professional please respect the Vania
respect to Wi-Fi don't try to do my
country stands right now
it's not ours right in the hotel so
without unchecked anything about it so
use it as carefully as you can and the
police keep thing is tiny for us any
issues talk to the people with the flu
like your own anything any problems
anyone has problem whatever you need
just find someone who has a blue lanyard
and tell them what your problem and
we'll sort it out if you have any
suggestions that does happen to fit back
there will be a real kind response don't
send jobs you don't spam are split these
are our sponsors job site is our
platinum sponsor I'll is young and
priority target scheme consistent
tiger-skin got their stuff stuck in a
suitcase in an airport somewhere right
um the airliner and lost the language so
they don't have to start with them but
there is someone downstairs Costa if you
may stand up Costa will go tell you
everything about diagnosing
certifications so if you want to spin to
Costa and about the staff duty to pasta
and we have something ready Ida security
professional and typically and are you
have neither young up here just after
since the tolling is really really
really tall lady right and will care
about that we have the after funny
drinks for everybody right because it's
a big deal so when you thank you and the
other party was up at seven-thirty
upstairs to the roof garden is really
nice hope you can make it you must have
your badge with you'd rather write just
make sure you don't lose it in the
process these are our community
supporters piece at London Manchester
for football the universe is here and
there any chapter of Isis were released
shelters as 20 universal car besides or
South Wales turning off stock for
getting the army and besides events
dinner our keynote speaker has a very
important announcement to make it means
it's a very big deal for tricks trust me
you're going to be excited we have a
tragic we have a game we call it
treasure-hunt right it's very easy to do
it's very easy participate you only need
to be quick and do what needs to be done
you have to run around and scan QR codes
all the information about the game is
online on the on our extra stuff it says
games and then it says you have to find
the blues and you're gonna win prizes so
play the game and capture the flag talk
about it later on but instead of a
capture the flag we've worked with 12
second worker over to some other
governments as well we're going to put
together a national team to compete at
the European cybersecurity talents again
it's a big thing for us so we're very
proud to be a me do this and move talk
about that later on this is what we need
to go to find out how much about a
treasure hunt this is a link with us at
the end right and this is the website
for the European cybersecurity talents
and these are prices we have books from
karate and we have signed books
information work from Andy
don't know what in though and someone
can help in those books as well and they
are signed by the office itself so do
all we like to thank you all for
participating a huge set dancing our
volunteers our precision the speakers
and blow up you know from our own around
where to be here today and our thoughts
are only software open event that it's
been crazy race try organizing the poker
story moving so thank you for listening
to me all my stuff I hope you enjoyed at
the end of fun